<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:17:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Lays Off 55 People at Massive and Stockholm Studios]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-lays-off-55-people-ubisoft-massive-stockholm/</link>
            <guid>1404559</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Ubisoft</strong> will be laying off <strong>55 people</strong> at its <strong>Massive Entertainment</strong> and <strong>Ubisoft Stockholm</strong> studios, a new report from <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/ubisoft-laying-off-55-roles-at-massive-and-ubisoft-stockholm-as-cost-cutting-continues">GamesIndustry.Biz</a> has revealed. It's the second cost-cutting move from the company this month, after it <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-shuts-down-ubisoft-halifax-claims-decision-had-nothing-to-do-with-studio-unionizing/">shut down its Halifax-based studio, which saw <strong>71 people</strong> left without a job</a>.</p>



<p>According to the report, the news was delivered to staff through an internal email that cited the move had nothing to do with the developer's performance at either studio, and had all to do with Ubisoft believing the cuts to be necessary after a "<em>mapping of the future roadmap</em>" for the company.</p>



<p>The email added that the "<em>long-term direction for the studios remains unchanged</em>," as Massive continues to work on several <strong>The Division</strong> projects, including <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-division-3-in-production-will-have-as-big-an-impact-as-division-1-ubisoft-massive/">The Division 3</a>, </strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-division-2-survivors-division-resurgence-ubisoft-gamescom-2025/"><strong>The Division 2: Survivors</strong> and <strong>The Division: Resurgence</strong></a>. There's also a potential fourth project (besides more The Division 2 expansions) with <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-division-definitive-edition-seemingly-leaks-ubisoft/">The Division: Definitive Edition</a></strong>, though it's not yet clear what exactly that project will look like.</p>



<p>These cuts are also hitting Massive and Stockholm despite the fact that the email also reportedly states the studios are working on an "<em>unannounced innovative tech project</em>" that will "<em>play a central role in the development</em>" of the Snowdrop Engine, the game engine built by Massive Entertainment that's been used for recent titles like <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-nintendo-switch-2-demo-this-year/">Star Wars Outlaws</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora/">Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</a></strong>, and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/tom-clancys-the-division-2-loot-capital/">The Division 2</a></strong>.</p>



<p>Last year, Ubisoft kicked off 2025 by laying off <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-closes-uk-studio-lays-off-185-staff/"><strong>185 people</strong> and shutting down its Leamington-based studio</a>. It then followed that up with <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-massive-entertainment-layoffs/">cuts at Massive Entertainment</a> and its <a href="https://wccftech.com/trials-rising-developer-ubisoft-redlynx-layoff-60-developers-amidst-shift-to-small-screens/">Ubisoft RedLynx Studio</a>. It's beginning 2026 in a similar fashion, with <strong>126 people already cut just 13 days into 2026.</strong> Meanwhile, the company <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-announces-imminent-closing-transaction-with-tencent-minority-stakeholder-vantage-studios/">recently closed a deal with <strong>Tencent</strong> to establish a new venture, <strong>Vantage Studios</strong>,</a> which will now house the company's biggest IPs, including Assassin's Creed, Far Cry, and Rainbow Six.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-lays-off-55-people-ubisoft-massive-stockholm/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road Sales Reach 800k, Second Big Update Coming]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/inazuma-eleven-victory-road-sales-800k-update</link>
            <guid>1404553</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road </em>has reached a new sales milestone, developer and publisher Level-5 has announced, and the game will be getting a second major update in the near future as well.</p><p>As revealed in a <a href="https://www.inazuma.jp/victory-road/en/topics/260113_01/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">news post</a> on the game's official website, <em>Victory Road </em>has racked up 800,000 sales since launching last November. The game managed to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/inazuma-eleven-victory-road-sales-500k" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="60aad754-fdd9-4d60-bb74-1251bf703db7" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">hit 500,000 sales in its first week</a>, so that means it's picked up another 300,000 since then.</p><p>In addition to revealing the new sales milestone, Level-5 has also announced that a second major update is on the way for <em>Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road</em>, following on from the game's first big update in December. It's bringing "the opening of the Ares Route, among other features".</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road </em>has reached another big sales milestone.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Level-5 will no doubt be pleased with <em>Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road</em>'s performance, especially given what a long road it's been to get here (and not one with a guaranteed chance of victory, either).</p><p>Originally known as <em>Inazuma Eleven: Heroes' Great Road</em>, the game has been <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/inazuma-eleven-heroes-great-road-delayed-until-2021" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="291efc63-1f35-4892-bcb7-01502230543a" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">delayed</a> numerous times, and a Western release was by no means guaranteed until Level-5 <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/inazuma-eleven-victory-road-will-come-west-new-trailer-details-revealed" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c93004cd-65c8-4edc-afb5-782c92344e4c" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">announced one in 2023</a>.</p><p>Just like its predecessors, <em>Victory Road </em>is an RPG that combines tactical soccer battles with overworld exploration. It takes place around 25 years after the original <em>Inazuma Eleven </em>and follows a new protagonist, Dustin Billows (Sasanami Unmei in the Japanese version).</p><p>Billows isn't capable of hitting the field himself, but he can recruit other students to join his team, and so he serves as their commander, building a team of unconventional soccer heroes to take on all comers.</p>
<p><em>Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road </em>forms part of what is arguably a big comeback for Level-5, with cozy RPG <em>Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time </em>also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fantasy-life-i-girl-who-steals-time-sales-1-5m" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="4638dd4a-d2d1-40e8-b386-03f485297eeb" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">doing pretty well in the sales stakes</a>.</p><p>You can check out <em>Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road </em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2799860/INAZUMA_ELEVEN_Victory_Road/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/inazuma-eleven-victory-road/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/inazuma-eleven-victory-road/9NVX87ZG7WSC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and both <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/INAZUMA-ELEVEN-Victory-Road-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-2950552.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Switch 2</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-download-software/INAZUMA-ELEVEN-Victory-Road-2950387.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Switch</a> right now.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/inazuma-eleven-victory-road-sales-800k-update]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dyson’s Car+Boat Handheld Vacuum Drops to a Record Low, Now Priced Like a Budget Cleaner]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dysons-carboat-handheld-vacuum-drops-to-a-record-low-now-priced-like-a-budget-cleaner-2000659256</link>
            <guid>1404550</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If you have a car or boat, it can be difficult to keep things tidy if you don’t have an appropriately sized set of tools. A handheld vac is just what you need to save the day. We’ve found one that you’ll absolutely love using, and it won’t break the bank. The Dyson Car+Boat Handheld Vacuum delivers strong cordless suction in a compact form factor that’s perfect for tight spaces, using Dyson’s digital motor and cyclone technology to maintain consistent performance from start to finish. This handheld vacuum weighs about 4.2 pounds, making it easy to maneuver around vehicle interiors, storage compartments, and other confined areas without strain.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6749/">Head over to Amazon to get the Dyson Car+Boat Handheld Vacuum for just $229, down from its usual price of $299. That’s a discount of $70 and 23% off.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6749/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Compact Design With Serious Suction</h2>
<p>Designed specifically for mobile environments, the vacuum has super strong suction as well as a mini motorized tool that uses a rotating brush bar to lift dirt and hair from upholstery and carpets. A Crevice tool helps reach narrow gaps between seats or along trim lines, while the Combination tool transitions between a wide nozzle and soft brush for dusting hard surfaces.</p>
<p>These attachments connect directly to the vacuum body, so you don’t lose them somewhere else. Plus, the bin holds about 0.14 gallons of dirt and debris and uses Dyson’s point-and-shoot mechanism to get rid of extra dirt.</p>



<p>Cordless operation plays a major role in how this vacuum fits into real-world cleaning routines, eliminating the need to manage cords or find nearby outlets. The balanced handle design keeps weight centered in the hand, which helps during longer cleaning sessions across multiple surfaces. Two power settings let you prioritize either maximum runtime or increased suction depending on the mess you are dealing with. That means the vacuum is super flexible. It can handle loose dust, sand, pet hair, and embedded debris with confidence.</p>
<p>Battery performance remains consistent throughout the cleaning cycle, with fade-free suction designed to deliver steady airflow until the charge is depleted. Recharging is handled through the included charger, and the vacuum is ready for repeated use without complex setup. Plus, it has washable filters so you don’t have to keep spending money on things like that.</p>
<p>Beyond cars and boats, the vacuum adapts well to stairs, furniture, shelves, and other areas where larger machines feel cumbersome. The compact body makes storage simple, and switching attachments is quick when moving between different surfaces. Dyson includes a two-year warranty, adding reassurance around long-term reliability and support.If you want an easy to use vacuum that’s perfect for keeping your car or boat (or other vehicle or small space) tidy, this is a great choice to get started with.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6749/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dysons-carboat-handheld-vacuum-drops-to-a-record-low-now-priced-like-a-budget-cleaner-2000659256]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Can’t I Play Hytale Right Now? Hytale Server Status, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-server-status-explained/</link>
            <guid>1404544</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Hytale coming back from the dead has revitalized an expectant community and is sure to bring in a lot of players. However, it’s not ideal if the Hytale servers aren’t cooperating, and this guide has the latest.</p>



<p>Servers, servers, servers, you both love them and hate them. Without them, you don’t get to play online games, but with them, there’s the constant headache of relying on them <em>to</em> work. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-expects-one-million-players-at-early-access-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale’s early access</a> is very much a game in its infancy, and initial player count figures are expected to be high.</p>



<p>If you’re struggling to get on Hytale, here’s the latest on the game’s servers and potential issues.</p>



<h2 id="h-are-the-hytale-servers-working-right-now">Are The Hytale Servers Working Right Now?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Hypixel Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>As of January 13, the servers are working and operational, but it might take you some time to get into the game.</strong></p>



<p>Launch day for any new, hyped online game is always a wild one. Having the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/download-hytale-launcher/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale Launcher</a> installed is one thing, but your place in the game’s servers rests entirely on Hypixel’s server’s shoulders.</p>



<p>It was never expected to be plain sailing on day one, and it will take time to iron out the kinks and see just how many people log in at first.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-access-hytale-servers">How To Access Hytale Servers</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Image via Hypixel Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Quite simply, you need to be patient and wait for your chance to access the Hytale servers, as they are overloaded with players and likely working at, or beyond, capacity.</strong></p>



<p>Check for developer updates and comments on X. The <a href="https://x.com/Hytale" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Hytale X</a> page is a great source for new updates and announcements on the game, and you should also check founder <a href="https://x.com/Simon_Hypixel" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Simon Collins-Laflamme</a>‘s X page, as they post regularly about the game.</p>



<p>You should also keep checking back with this Insider Gaming server status page, as it’ll be updated with new tweaks if there are any outages or significant changes to the game’s servers.</p>



<h2 id="h-why-can-t-i-download-the-lastest-update-or-patch">Why Can’t I Download The Lastest Update Or Patch?</h2>



<p><strong>Again, the reason you can’t download the latest patch is that the servers are overloaded, making it difficult for you to get the required space and memory to download the contents.</strong></p>



<p>Are you having any difficulties accessing the Hytale servers? Have you experienced any unusual error messages or login issues? Share your thoughts and scenarios through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>, where you can communicate with other Hytale players to see if there are solutions to be discovered.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Hytale guides, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-controller-support-playstation-xbox/">Hytale has controller support</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-platforms-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">if it’s on PlayStation 5 or Xbox Series X|S platforms</a>, and what its&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-hytale-have-multiplayer-co-op-multiplayer-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Co-op &amp; Multiplayer status</a>&nbsp;is.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-server-status-explained/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Duckov and Tarkov Collab Could Be Coming Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-duckov-tarkov-collaboration-coming/</link>
            <guid>1404541</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Extraction shooter fans everywhere are preparing for a collaboration that writes itself. Recently, the Escape from <strong>Duckov </strong>team posted a cryptic image and message on social media talking about the game’s <strong>first </strong>collaboration event. The image was decoded quickly enough by fans, and it looks like <strong>Escape from Tarkov characters </strong>will be headed into the duck-themed extraction shooter.</p>



<p>Escape from Duckov was released in October 2025 and quickly sold millions of copies, soaring to a peak concurrent player count of 301,000 users on Steam. It’s a satirical, tongue-in-cheek stab at the unwelcoming extraction genre, and it parodies Escape from Tarkov, the hyper-challenging shooter, in multiple ways.</p>







<h2 id="h-are-tarkov-and-duckov-joining-forces">Are Tarkov and Duckov Joining Forces?</h2>



<p>In a recent post on social media, the Escape from Duckov folks from Bilibili and Team Soda posted an image showing one of the game’s duck-like characters studying a whiteboard.</p>



<p>On that whiteboard, we see two perfectly normal ducks turn into something threatening. One is wielding a large hammer and wearing an armored vest, while the other has rippling muscles and a large rifle.</p>



<p>The post was accompanied by a message:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>【Two ……. interconnected memory …… bloodline …… exceptional combat …… instability.】</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This is almost a direct reference to <strong>Tagilla </strong>and <strong>Killa</strong>, two of Escape from Tarkov’s most iconic boss characters. They’re brothers (interconnected memory and bloodline), and one has exceptional combat skills, while the other is somewhat unstable.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>【Two ……. interconnected memory …… bloodline …… exceptional combat …… instability.】</p><p>QUACK! 🦆 Our FIRST in-game collab is coming! Guess what will arrive in Duckov. </p><p>Comment with your prediction — a weapon, an object, a crossover character… anything​ — and get… <a href="https://t.co/oOD86cYMlX">pic.twitter.com/oOD86cYMlX</a></p></div>— Escape from Duckov (@GameDuckov) <a href="https://twitter.com/GameDuckov/status/2010653800777081200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 12, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>







<p>The collaboration effectively writes itself, and it means we could see these two characters emerge in a game <strong>other than </strong>Escape from Tarkov for the first time.</p>



<p>On October 22, Nikita Buyanov, the head of the studio at Battlestate Games, praised Escape from Duckov’s successful launch and one million copies sold in just a few days. Little did we know that would be a precursor for things to come (or potentially come, at least).</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Escape from Duckov has maintained a relatively solid player base on Steam, standing at around 11,000 peak players every day. Escape from Tarkov is primarily played via Battlestate’s proprietary launcher, so it’s hard to tell how many people are playing it, but 26,000 or so were playing at the time of writing <strong>on Steam alone</strong>.</p>







<p>Are you excited to see an Escape from Tarkov and Escape from Duckov collaboration? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> what you hope will happen.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-footage-of-cancelled-monolith-batman-game-surfaces-online/">Monolith’s canceled Batman game</a> has surfaced online again</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
        
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-duckov-tarkov-collaboration-coming/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Code Vein II ‘Overview’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/code-vein-ii-overview-trailer</link>
            <guid>1404538</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Character creation, Partners, combat, Formae, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,821 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> has released a nine-minute overview trailer for <em><a title="Games > Code Vein II [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/code-vein-ii">Code Vein II</a></em>. <span id="more-1018887"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Bandai Namco:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Code Vein II</em> features a deep narrative where players and characters are bound by blood, fate, and destiny, set in a future where the last remnants of humanity and Revenants struggle against a world on the verge of collapse. Following the sudden emergence of a threat known as the <a title="Platforms > Luna [68 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/cloud/luna">Luna</a> Rapacis, Revenants have succumbed to madness, transforming into terrifying creatures called <a title="Genres > Horror [802 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">Horror</a>s. A Revenant Hunter, guided by a mysterious girl named Lou who possesses the power to travel into the past to rewrite the fate of the world. The player, as the Revenant Hunter, will intervene in key moments of history to alter key revenants’ destinies that reveal hidden truths and information to save the future.</p><p>Players will embark on a journey through a world that spans across two eras, where decisions carry weight and every battle tests skill and resolve. <em>Code Vein II</em> features distinctive gameplay for an <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,927 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a>, where players use blood drained from enemies to unlock a variety of powerful skills, build strategy for combat with Blood codes, and use unique weapons and equipment called Jails to overcome challenging foes and epic bosses. Players can also forge bonds with powerful Partner allies who fight alongside them and enhance their abilities. Each Partner offers distinct skills and deep narrative connections that shape the journey. Bandai Namco will reveal many more details about the rich universe and game play in <em>Code Vein II</em> in the future.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In a future world where humans and Revenants coexist…</p><p>Due to the sudden appearance of the Luna Rapacis, Revenants have transformed into mindless monsters called Horrors. As a Revenant hunter, the player shall halt the world’s inevitable collapse by traveling to the past with a girl called Lou who possesses the power to manipulate time.</p><p>An epic <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,812 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> awaits, where you and your chosen partners explore a vast world, face fierce battles against powerful enemies, and uncover an epic story that transcends time.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>A Tale Across Time</strong> – Embark on a journey that spans both the present and the past as you search for clues to prevent the world’s destruction. Alter the fates of key Revenant characters you encounter in the past, while uncovering lost histories and the hidden truths of the world.</li><li><strong>Intense and Satisfying Combat</strong> – Dive into adrenaline-fueled battles where reading enemy moves and mastering your arsenal are key to <a title="Genres > Survival [501 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>. Unleash powerful skills, adapt on the fly, and conquer relentless foes in fights that deliver both intensity and triumph.</li><li><strong>Unique Battle System</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> <em>Code Vein II</em>‘s unique gameplay mechanic, where the player drains and acquires blood from enemies to unleash a variety of skills. With the series’ new build system, you can freely customize weapons and skills to suit your own battle styles.</li><li><strong>Powerful Partner Characters</strong> – Explore the world with trusted and powerful allies who can fight alongside you or enhance your abilities. Each partner brings unique abilities and deep connections that shape your journey.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Code Vein II</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,178 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,552 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,240 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2362060/CODE_VEIN_II/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on January 30. A “Character Creator Demo” is due out on January 23.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Overview Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="CODE VEIN II - Overview Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8MFT2Jo7CN0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/code-vein-ii-overview-trailer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Animal Crossing's Next Update Has Players Revisiting Long-Deserted Islands]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/animal-crossings-next-update-has-players-revisiting-long-deserted-islands/1100-6537314/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1404535</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537314">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2026-01-13T06:45:49-0800">January 13, 2026 at 6:45AM PST</time></p></section>
    


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container" data-in-content-placements="[{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-incontent-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:1,&quot;minElements&quot;:2},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:4,&quot;minElements&quot;:5}]},{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-banner-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:7,&quot;minElements&quot;:8},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:10,&quot;minElements&quot;:11},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:13,&quot;minElements&quot;:14}]}]">
                <p>When Mushy relogged onto her Animal Crossing: New Horizons island after years away, she expected the weeds, cockroaches, and angry villagers. She didn't expect a blast from the past when she checked in on her ex-partner's room, which was designed like a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnimalCrossing/comments/1pxaxut/forgot_my_ex_made_his_home_into_a_jail_sell_over/" rel="nofollow ">jail cell.</a></p><p dir="ltr">"He had a weird sense of humor and once he saw that there were jail items in the game--jail bars, wallpaper, toilets-- he thought it would be hilarious to turn his island home into a jail cell," she told GameSpot. "I helped him gather the items too."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1285581630" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466493,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Animal%20Crossing%3A%20New%20Horizons%20%E2%80%93%203.0%20Update%20and%20Switch%202%20Edition%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:744,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-update-and-switch-2-edition-overview-trailer\/2300-6466493\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466493\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466493\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466493\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;phone&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:true,&quot;allowMutedAutoplay&quot;:true,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466493&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/mobile_web\/gamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466493,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;ssai&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6537314&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;animal-crossing-new-horizons&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;simulation&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch,nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;nintendo&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;animal-crossing&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;animal-crossing&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web\/gamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466493},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466493\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4593895-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/clcRBz0v.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1761831000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="clcRBz0v" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Animal Crossing: New Horizons – 3.0 Update and Switch 2 Edition Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">She hadn't remembered helping him after New Horizons launched in March 2020, but everything came rushing back when she logged on for the first time to prepare for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/animal-crossing-new-horizons-everything-new-in-update-3-0/2900-7399/" data-ref-id="2900-7399">3.0 update</a> coming on January 15.</p><p dir="ltr">"After a little roaming around I came upon my ex's old island home and I remembered how it was decorated. This was extra hilarious and ironic since a few months after our break up, he ended up in jail in real life and is still there to this day," Mushy said with a laugh. "So, all in all, my ex manifested his future in jail on my Animal Crossing island."</p><p dir="ltr">Animal Crossing: New Horizons doesn't reset when you stop playing. It doesn't erase past decisions or smooth over absences. Instead, it waits. Returning years later means confronting creative choices, emotional baggage, and memories left exactly where they were. As players log back in ahead of the January 15 update, many are realizing their islands have been holding onto more than furniture layouts.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15957481/4633819-forgot-my-ex-made-his-home-into-a-jail-sell-over-3-years-v0-hv08qz8jst9g1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4633819" data-ratio="0.56203703703704" data-width="1080" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15957481/4633819-forgot-my-ex-made-his-home-into-a-jail-sell-over-3-years-v0-hv08qz8jst9g1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4633819"></a><figcaption>Mushy hadn't visited her island in 3 years and 7 months | Credit: Mushy</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15957481/4633819-forgot-my-ex-made-his-home-into-a-jail-sell-over-3-years-v0-hv08qz8jst9g1.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Players who stepped away years ago are reopening save files and running headfirst into the past. They're pulling weeds and repairing relationships with villagers, but they're also revisiting islands built during the pandemic and the years that followed. These spaces function as digital time capsules, preserving routines and aesthetics from a period when Animal Crossing felt essential.</p><p dir="ltr">For many players, Animal Crossing wasn't just a game during 2020 and 2021--it was a coping mechanism as the COVID-19 pandemic raged. Islands were structured around daily check-ins, online meetups, and familiar rituals when the outside world felt unstable. Logging back in now means rediscovering those habits without the context that made them necessary. Bulletin boards still display old messages. Homes remain decorated for long-passed events. Villagers comment on absences measured in years.</p><p dir="ltr">Animal Crossing makes time visible in a way few games do. Villagers acknowledge your absence. Weeds accumulate. Neglect leaves a mark. That design choice turns returning into something more personal than simple nostalgia. It's not just about remembering how things were--it's about seeing proof that time moved forward without you.</p><p dir="ltr">At the same time, Animal Crossing: New Horizons never truly went dormant. A dedicated community has continued to play daily, decorating seasonally and maintaining relationships with villagers they've known for years. For those players, the January update isn't a return--it's just the next step.</p><p dir="ltr">That divide became especially visible at the start of 2026. While some players were reopening old islands, others rang in the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/new-years-eve-games/2900-7374/" data-ref-id="2900-7374">new year</a> standing in their town square, counting down the final seconds with their villagers. Screenshots of midnight celebrations spread online, showing islands that never stopped evolving. For these players, Animal Crossing remains part of their daily routine.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15957481/4633885-unnamed%281%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4633885" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15957481/4633885-unnamed%281%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4633885"></a><figcaption>Players are revisiting their custom landmarks</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15957481/4633885-unnamed%281%29.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The upcoming update has brought both groups back into the same conversation. Lapsed players are cautiously reopening save files. Everyday players are preparing their islands for new content. Both are engaging with the game from very different emotional places, shaped by how long they've been away.</p><p dir="ltr">For some, returning has been especially difficult. Over the years, players have used Animal Crossing to build <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/animal-crossing-new-horizons-players-are-remembering-loved-ones-in-game/1100-6482592/">memorials</a>, preserve important moments, and create <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/letters-and-flowers-how-games-memorialize-loved-on/1100-6473761/#comments-block-33482638">spaces tied to people they've lost</a>. Revisiting those areas ahead of the update has been both painful and meaningful. Gardens remain untouched. Homes stay frozen in time. The game offers no prompt to move on--only the option to continue.</p><p dir="ltr">That's what makes this wave of returns feel significant. Animal Crossing isn't just drawing players back with new features, and these islands aren't just neglected towns--they're records of who players were when they last logged off.</p><p dir="ltr">As January 15 approaches, players are reopening digital spaces filled with memory, grief, comfort, and growth. And in doing so, they're discovering that Animal Crossing didn't just wait for them to come back--it remembered everything.</p>
  
                        
        
    
    
                                  </div>


          
  
        <div data-merchant-service-api-link="https://www.gamespot.com/merchantapi/offer/?gameid=487113"><div><p>
      There are currently no available deals
    </p></div><p>GameSpot may get a commission from retail offers.</p></div>  
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/animal-crossings-next-update-has-players-revisiting-long-deserted-islands/1100-6537314/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom Sets Resident Evil Requiem Showcase For Thursday]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/13/capcom-sets-resident-evil-requiem-showcase-for-thursday</link>
            <guid>1404532</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Resident Evil Requiem is easily one of the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/video-podcast/2026/01/09/drafting-our-most-anticipated-games-of-2026-the-game-informer-show" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="76ac02fb-38b3-4fdf-8dc3-0df0a2bcbf85" data-entity-substitution="canonical">most anticipated video games of the year</a>, and luckily, its February release is right around the corner. While a big Game Awards trailer <a href="https://gameinformer.com/the-game-awards-2025/2025/12/11/leon-kennedy-takes-the-stage-in-resident-evil-requiem">finally confirmed the rumors that Leon S. Kennedy would be playable</a>, there's still plenty fans don't know about this game. We'll be getting some more news soon, however, as <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/residentevil.capcomusa.com/post/3mcbhyqjx3s2l">Capcom has just announced</a> a Resident Evil showcase for later this week, January 15, at 2 PM PT/ 5 PM ET.</p><p>The stream will be available on <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/capcomusa">Capcom's Twitch channel</a>. You can also view a short teaser for the event below.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VXQveAdzC74"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VXQveAdzC74" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>"Tune in on January 15 at 2pm PT / 10pm GMT for the Resident Evil Showcase and be one of the first to see brand new gameplay and news for Resident Evil Requiem," the YouTube description for the trailer reads. Capcom's website also reveals that the stream will be <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/twelve-minutes/twelve-minutes-review-stuck-in-hell">12 minutes</a> long. The event is technically just called "Resident Evil Showcase," implying there might be room for non-Requiem related announcements, but 12 minutes doesn't quite feel like enough time to cover multiple games. We'll know for sure when the showcase airs this Thursday.</p><p>For more Requiem, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/12/resident-evil-requiem-devs-say-grace-and-leons-sections-are-almost-equally-split-detail">read about how protagonists Leon and Grace share the spotlight</a>, check out our <a href="https://gameinformer.com/gamescom-2025/2025/08/27/capcom-doesnt-think-of-resident-evil-7-8-and-9-as-a-trilogy">interview with the developers at Gamescom</a>, and then see what we thought about <a href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2025/06/11/back-to-raccoon-city">how the game feels to play</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/13/capcom-sets-resident-evil-requiem-showcase-for-thursday]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New documents and videos give us another alleged look at Monolith Productions’ cancelled 2010 Batman game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/monolith-productions-cancelled-2010-batman-game-new</link>
            <guid>1404529</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/batman-begins_shUnLpR.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/batman-begins_shUnLpR.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/batman-begins_shUnLpR.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/batman-begins_shUnLpR.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/batman-begins_shUnLpR.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/batman-begins_shUnLpR.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/batman-begins_shUnLpR.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/batman-begins_shUnLpR.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/batman-begins_shUnLpR.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/warner-bros-reportedly-cancels-wonder-woman-closes-monolith-and-other-studios">Monolith Productions' closure last year</a> remains one of the hardest gut punches the Western games industry has seen recently. From iconic shooters like <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/r-fear-pc">FEAR</a> to the inventive <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/middle-earth-shadow-of-mordor-review">Shadow of Mordor</a> &amp; Shadow of War, the studio always excelled, no matter the genre. Now, unearthed materials allegedly recovered from a discarded HDD used at the studio have revealed work done on a non-Arkham Batman game for Warner Bros.</p>
<p>MrTalida, a renowned "video game enthusiast and archivist," shared their findings <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mrtalida.bsky.social">via Bluesky</a> on 13th January. Moreover, an Internet Archive upload was made available for anyone curious about the unmade project. Needless to say, those files should only be accessed at your own risk.</p>
<p>According to the user, the materials go back as far as April 2009 and up to January 2010. It all seemingly belongs to a game that never came close to being anywhere near done. The info and videos mostly deal with isolated gameplay ideas, audio systems, concept art, and development schedules.</p>
<p>There are, however, fragments which present an aesthetic closer (if not the same) to Christopher Nolan's Batman movies. If we also take the time frame into account, we can theorize this could've been a tie-in of sorts, or at least a title which existed outside of the continuity started by Rocksteady's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/batman-arkham-asylum-review">Arkham Asylum</a> in 2009.</p><p>This isn't the first time we've seen footage of Monolith's cancelled Batman game. In 2024, more substantial clips of an advanced build of the game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/batman-game-that-became-shadow-of-mordor-footage-surfaces-online">popped up online</a>. However, this new batch of materials gives us a closer look at the studio's overall plans, as well as the iconic tank-like "tumbler" Batmobile from the Nolan movies.</p>
<p>Eventually, the project was scrapped and gave way to what became <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/middle-earth-shadow-of-mordor">Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor</a>, a refreshing take on the Lord of the Rings IP that borrowed more than a few tricks from Rocksteady's Batman playbook, so in the end, the studio's slightly different approach to the Dark Knight survived… kind of.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  




  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/monolith-productions-cancelled-2010-batman-game-new]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Romancing SaGa -Minstrel Song- Remastered review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/13/romancing-saga-minstrel-song-remastered-review/</link>
            <guid>1404508</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Recently, I’ve been trying to work through some issues I have with the way I approach playing &amp; beating video games. For the longest time, I’ve felt like I need to make sure I see every possible piece of content in a playthrough of a game – and that drive to avoid missing anything often leads to me turning games into a checklist of tasks and a monotonous guide-assisted slog. Sometimes, missing out on an item or a boss in a game can be punishing – but punishment and frustration aren’t bad things to experience when gaming. Like any piece of art, entertainment might not always be the goal. Like real life, you’re always bound to miss out on something, somewhere. Romancing SaGa -Minstrel Song- Remastered has ended up becoming the perfect exposure therapy for me to remind myself of and embrace these qualities, and enjoy this one-of-a-kind open-ended RPG experience with no hesitation or remorse.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/JRPG/comments/1pisy3s/romancing_saga_minstrel_song_remastered/">[Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song Remastered International] Now out Physically and Digitally on PS4, PS5, and Switch. New localization options (French, German, Italian and Spanish), and option to select the Japanese dub with Eng subtitles. No save transfer from the previous release.</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/VashxShanks/">u/VashxShanks</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/JRPG/">JRPG</a></p></blockquote>

<p>I love a non-linear story, and I love a story with an ensemble cast who slowly come together in unexpected ways. Romancing SaGa -Minstrel Song- Remastered is built on both those qualities – you have eight different protagonists to choose from who each start in a different part of the massive world of Mardias. You have vague knowledge of the fact that there is a massive evil stirring somewhere in the world, and that there are ten mysterious objects scattered across Mardias that could potentially be gathered to fully revive this evil. </p>


<p>When you pick your starting hero, though, you aren’t given any immediate quest related to this or any clue on how it all connects back to you. You’re simply thrust into a living world, and given the opportunity to explore it and take things one step at a time until you come across companions, and clues, and quests, and eventually an ending.</p>


<p>I love this so much. It can be a little daunting at first, but it really gives you the tools to tell yourself your own story as you play the game – there is no consistent pacing, or expected encounters, and it all kind of plays out like a tabletop RPG campaign. I especially loved the feeling of unexpectedly encountering characters that can be recruited to the party. Alongside your eight primary heroes, dozens of other characters live in the world who can join your quest. Sure, there are probably some incredibly optimized playthroughs you can put together if you follow a guide on where to recruit the best party members. For me, though, it was so rewarding to stumble upon each of them, and even sometimes lose some of them, in a natural way.</p>
<p>The combat encounters and gameplay that tie these moments of immersive and emergent storytelling together are, admittedly, pretty basic. Battles are standard turn-based RPG encounters, with the most unique wrinkle being the fact that you’ve got weapon durability to be concerned about as you adventure. There are a lot of new abilities and skills for your characters to learn as you progress through the game, and plenty of equipment options for putting together specific character builds and battle styles. Honestly, though, it wasn’t the thing that kept driving me to play the game. If you happen to feel otherwise and have a passion for the battles, though, there are a wealth of optional bosses and extra challenges to dig into.</p>
<p>There’s also a lot of new content in this remaster compared to the original PlayStation 2 release. A huge amount of it is quality-of-life stuff that makes the simple act of playing way, way smoother. Almost all of the extra non-QoL content is relegated to endgame and additional playthroughs. As a newcomer to the game, this didn’t stand out to me much. Reading about the content in detail, though, it seems like the kind of thing only a minority of players will ever encounter. </p>

<p>One element is an expanded story arc for a particular newly recruitable character, Aldora. Seeing that content to it’s conclusion, though, requires making specific choices across three playthroughs. There’s also a set of new ultra-difficulty bosses that, similarly, you’ll need to be pretty deep into your first or 2nd playthrough to be prepared to fight. It’s definitely a significant amount of new content, but the main game doesn’t feel any kind of lacking despite all of these elements being so deep into the game.</p>
<p>There’s a few elements of Romancing SaGa -Minstrel Song- that I wish were remastered just a bit better, though. For one thing, the lack of camera control is a frequent issue. Without full control over the direction of the camera, it can be a headache to navigate the more complicated dungeons of the game – especially when the camera ends up moving on its own and muddying my sense of direction even further. </p>
<p>The visuals of the game are also just a pinch away from perfect. I appreciate the weird, almost bobblehead aesthetic of the character models, even though I’m sure some people will end up fully disliking them. There’s a weird disconnect though, where the high-fidelity and resolution combined with the stylized models and just-slightly-blurry textures don’t all fully come together too well. It’s mostly the kind of thing where I imagine the fuzziness of the original version and the CRT you probably would have played it on tie the magic of the art style together.</p>

<p>Flaws aside, Romancing SaGa -Minstrel Song- is an incredible experience. It bucks traditional game design ideas that seem like no-brainers or bare minimums. However, the lack of a traditional main quest or even a standard linear story make for the kind of game that you end up falling so deep into that it ends up being your own story that you end up crafting, instead. Hopefully this remaster helps this game get seen as the classic it deserves to be.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/13/romancing-saga-minstrel-song-remastered-review/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Trek: Voyager - Across The Unknown Beams Onto Switch 2 Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/star-trek-voyager-across-the-unknown-beams-onto-switch-2-next-month</link>
            <guid>1404505</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>A demo will also be available "soon"</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Publisher Daedalic Entertainment has today announced that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/star-trek-voyager-across-the-unknown">Star Trek: Voyager - Across The Unknown</a> will launch on the Switch 2 on <strong>18th February 2026</strong>.</p>
<p>Daedalic has shared a "Combat Deep Dive" (above) from developer gameXcite to mark the occasion. Pre-orders are available now, and it's also been confirmed that a demo – which is up now on Steam, PS5, and Xbox – will make its way to the Switch 2 "soon". The demo is inspired by the pilot episode 'Caretaker' and contains roughly one hour of gameplay, including a guided tutorial.</p>
<p>A Deluxe Edition will also be made available for pre-order, containing the following additional content that will be integrated into the main campaign: "new missions, new recruitable heroes, and powerful technologies drawn from pivotal alien encounters in the Delta Quadrant".</p>
<p>According to the official description, Across the Unknown "blends exploration, ship &amp; resource management, roguelite elements, and meaningful choices. Experience crew dynamics and a fresh take on a beloved sci-fi universe — with what-if scenarios that open up new possibilities."</p>
<p>It sounds like it might be the perfect thing for fans of the series, but we'll have to wait and see for sure when it launches next month.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187287,176111 @ 1768315876 -->
<p><em>What are your thoughts on this one? Are you keen to pick it up on Switch 2? Let us know with a comment. And here's the original gameplay trailer from September last year.</em></p>
</section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/star-trek-voyager-across-the-unknown-beams-onto-switch-2-next-month]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Lore should not be a strict set of rules," says Hytale developer in a tribute to player "archaeology"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lore-should-not-be-a-strict-set-of-rules-says-hytale-developer-in-a-tribute-to-player-archaeology</link>
            <guid>1404502</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It's better thought of as "a set of guardrails"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-tessa.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hypixel Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Minecrafty fantasy sandbox <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hytale">Hytale</a> will finally launch into early access today, a few months after being <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/in-a-rare-bit-of-good-news-hytale-lives-on-with-its-original-devs-buying-the-rights-off-of-riot">rescued from cancellation</a> by Hypixel server co-founder Simon Collins-Laflamme. In development for over a decade, it’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytales-devs-hope-to-redefine-the-block-game-genre-with-their-world-generation-and-theyve-now-explained-how-it-works">a bid to “redefine the block-game genre”</a> that features procedurally generated biomes and RPG-style dungeon delving. Unlike the earliest instalments of Minecraft, it will also ship with some pretty fleshed-out lore.</p>
<p>In a post on the official site, the dev’s lore meister “Joe” has shared a few thoughts on the game’s flexible ideas about canon. Naturally, a lot of the chat invites comparison with other games with mighty codices, from The Witcher to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age">Dragon Age</a>. I’m indifferent to much of Hytale, I confess - I have exhausted my lifetime's supply of enthusiasm for blocks, and in any case, I prefer the drearier tone of <a href="https://www.vintagestory.at/">Vintage Story</a> - but on this count, I’m quite intrigued.</p>
<p>Joe <a href="https://hytale.com/news/2026/1/a-look-at-hytale-s-lore-and-philosophy">begins by noting</a> that Hytale had a lot of concept art, earlier in development, much of which has been dropped over the years in the course of narrative redrafts and other changes of direction, including the discarding of entire factions. However, “since the re-acquisition, many of these changes have been rolled back or re-incorporated in different ways”. This is partly because the developers “have made the conscious decision to return to an earlier draft - one that's far more compatible with the engine we're shipping and the vision we have for the game as a whole.”</p>
<p>In general, the chaos of past year has obliged a hard-headed approach to the narrative convolutions. Certain bits of lore have been shelved, some of them for good, while other materials are being revived. Take various initially “divisive” redesigns for the insectoid, desert-dwelling Scaraks – “with the timeline we're shipping on and the fact that the new designs aren't usable in-game, we can't exactly throw out the old ones anymore,” Joe writes. The devs are working on a method of “bringing both into the lore and making them work”.</p><p>In general, the new draft of the narrative retains “the major aspects of the lore the community has come to love over the years,” Joe goes on. “Characters such as Gaia and Varyn are still very much a part of our canon, and Tessa and Kyros are coming back as well”. The devs also intend “to revisit the concept of Alterverses”, these being parallel planets or dimensions – the main one is Orbis, which looks a lot like Earth.</p>
<p>In general, Hytale’s developers want “to maintain a consistent and coherent narrative while also allowing experimentation. Joe argues that “lore should not be a strict set of rules that everyone on the team is required to follow when designing content”, but “a set of guardrails to ensure we don't get too far off track”.</p>
<p>Hytale has certain fixed “canon foundations”, and the forthcoming Adventure mode will impose more of a narrative. But as regards the initially released Exploration mode, they’re leaving it pretty open. The game will encourage a degree of player “archaeology” that “gives us the flexibility to tell stories from different perspectives, many of which may not share the same understanding of Orbis and its nature”. As you might expect, these clashing perspectives may be faction-based.</p>
<p>As for when Adventure Mode might arrive, Joe cautions that there are currently “no systems in place to support such an endeavour, and there has never been a version of the game that had anything close to a narrative implemented. Even the details of the story itself have never truly been finalized.” So it’ll be up to you dig up the roots, for the moment. There is “a narrative of sorts” in Exploration Mode, tethered to a change in the world generation – Joe ends this section by dropping hints about something called Cursebreaker.</p><p>While a lot of the language here is too fluffy and promotional to get your teeth into, I think Hytale’s evolving lore could be fun to analyse. The early days of Minecraft were a series of improvisations and occasional mishaps <a href="https://archive.org/details/Minecraft_IRC_Logs_2009">discussed on IRC</a>, with minimal suspicion of the massive financial success that would follow – according to Notch, the game’s now globe-straddling Creeper mascot began life as a botched attempt at making a pig.</p>
<p>Nowadays, Minecraft is an absurdly bulky narrative universe, albeit a whimsical one that is rather less supportive of pedantic overreactions than, say, Star Trek. Hytale is sort of trying to follow the same trajectory, surfing the chaos wrought by last year's almost-cancellation, but with the more explicit hope of becoming a behemoth, and I think that puts the backstory writing under interesting stress. What do you reckon?</p>
<p>If you're sold on Hytale, here's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytale-release-time-and-date">how and when to buy and download it</a>. The game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytale-wont-be-on-steam-right-away-as-its-devs-want-to-avoid-overindexing-on-negative-reviews-from-players-who-arent-as-well-informed-yet">won’t release on Steam for the moment</a>, because Hypixel are worried about negative reviews from people unfamiliar with the choppy development history.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lore-should-not-be-a-strict-set-of-rules-says-hytale-developer-in-a-tribute-to-player-archaeology]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GOG’s New (Old) Boss Reaffirms Anti-DRM Commitment, Even If It Costs Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gog-anti-drm-cd-projekt-witcher-3-cyberpunk-2000659280</link>
            <guid>1404499</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>The GOG logo on a background of games.</span> © GOG / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>At the very end of 2025,&nbsp;<em>Witcher 3</em> developer CD Projekt Red announced it had sold its long-running PC gaming store GOG to CD Projekt and GOG co-founder Michał Kiciński. And while Kiciński launched GOG with its anti-DRM ethos, he’s been away from both companies for the last 13 years, and it was unknown if he might take the now independent storefront in a new direction. According to <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/the-new-owner-of-gog-discusses-taking-on-steam-the-devil-of-drm-and-following-in-nightdives-footsteps">an interview with&nbsp;<em>GI.biz</em></a>, there are no fears of GOG backing down from its bold stance, even if it means missing out on lucrative AAA gaming sales.</p> <p>Then known as Good Old Games, the store was originally launched by Polish developer CDPR in 2008, with a focus on selling classic games that had become hard to get hold of, stripped free of old, decaying digital rights management software. As the store developed, it began selling newer games too, but always on the condition that they shipped without any form of DRM.</p>

 <p>In the late 2000s, DRM had become the cause of a huge amount of controversy, with games shipping on DVD-ROM with ludicrous, game-breaking restrictions, such as limits on how many times they could be installed, the inability to run fully installed games without the discs in drives, and most insidiously, online checks that meant games couldn’t be played without an active internet connection. Ostensibly in place to prevent the illusory threat of “piracy,” these restrictions only ever prevented legitimate game owners from playing their games freely, while pirated versions were usually stripped of all DRM by the first day of a game’s release. It was a farce. (And it still is, with DRM software in digital games now severely impeding performance.) GOG has been run for the last 18 years with a refusal to sell DRM-infected games.</p>

 <p>It’s good to know that time hasn’t changed Michał Kiciński’s position on the matter. Speaking to&nbsp;<em>GI.biz</em>, the new outright owner of GOG explained that after a bidding process against an unknown rival company, he succeeded in buying the company he created because he sees “opportunities” for the business. GOG made very little money for CDPR, but Kiciński believes there’s a route to more financial success, and he’s not exactly unambitious.</p>

 <p>“I see huge opportunities for GOG to grow,” Kiciński says. “And somebody might say that having a competitor like Steam with 80 percent of the market share is a huge obstacle, but to me it’s the opposite. I see: ‘Oh, there is one big competitor, it’ll be difficult for them to defend the market, because they already have 80 percent, so it should be easier to take the market from them.”</p>

 <p>The focus to try to do this is not to try to out-Steam Steam, but rather to “just be better at a certain segment.” This is the site’s focus on classic games, but also working with independent developers with big-game games who are willing to sell via GOG. Citing games like&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur</em> and&nbsp;<em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>, which were simultaneously released on GOG alongside Steam, it proves that outside of the mega-publishers, there are those willing to embrace GOG’s ethos. Oh, and as part of the sale it was agreed that CDPR’s games will remain on GOG for at least the next six years—that certainly helps.</p>

 <p>When it comes to refusing DRM, Kiciński tells&nbsp;<em>GI.biz</em> that it remains “a core value of GOG, and there’s no signs that it might die in any visible future,” describing this as both an ethical and pragmatic choice. And, with a refreshing frankness, he says he has no time for publishers who don’t get it. “Most corporate people, they make plain stupid decisions.”</p>

 <p>You can read the rest of the interview, along with details over whey the company was sold and its plans for the future, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/the-new-owner-of-gog-discusses-taking-on-steam-the-devil-of-drm-and-following-in-nightdives-footsteps">over on&nbsp;<em>GI.biz</em></a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/gog-anti-drm-cd-projekt-witcher-3-cyberpunk-2000659280]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Is Offloading TP-Link’s Tri-Band WiFi 6E Router at Its Lowest Price With 42% Off]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-is-offloading-tp-links-tri-band-wifi-6e-router-at-its-lowest-price-with-42-off-2000659062</link>
            <guid>1404496</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Built to improve Wi-Fi performance in large homes, the TP-Link AXE5400 Tri-Band Wi-Fi 6E Router delivers faster speeds and more reliable connectivity. With the addition of an extra 6 GHz band, Wi-Fi 6E expands on the two bands (5 GHz and 2.4 GHz) that have been standard in routers for years, giving each device more space on the airwaves and reducing congestion. The combined speeds of all three bands reach up to 5400 Mbps, enabling smooth, uninterrupted 4K and 8K video streaming while you continue browsing the Internet, chatting, and downloading files on other devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6748/">The TP-Link AXE5400 Tri-Band Wi-Fi 6E Router is now available on Amazon for $116, down from its usual price of $200, for a savings of $84, or 42%.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6748/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A powerful router to improve your home Wi-Fi connection</h2>
<p>With the added 6 GHz band in the tri-band Wi-Fi 6E on the Archer AXE5400, there are three independent paths for traffic, making it ideal for applications such as gaming, video conferencing, or high-bitrate video streaming, where interruptions can be frustrating. Smart TVs, gaming consoles, and laptops typically run on the 5 GHz band, while smart home devices and general web surfing can use the 2.4 GHz band.</p>
<p>This router has true tri-band capabilities and OFDMA (Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiple Access), so it can communicate with multiple devices simultaneously rather than waiting for each device to connect one by one. It also includes a 1.7 GHz quad-core processor and 512 MB of RAM to handle heavy traffic, especially when many devices are accessing the Internet simultaneously.</p>



<p>In addition to delivering the performance gains of Wi-Fi 6E, the router also offers advanced network security features that enhance protection and control. HomeShield tools included with the router include: basic network scans, identification of new devices connecting to the network, built-in Quality of Service (QoS) capabilities, and reporting to display network usage patterns over time. There are also basic parental controls and WPA3 encryption, providing an additional layer of security for compatible devices compared to WPA2-based equipment, as well as support for both a built-in VPN server and a VPN client to protect your traffic or securely access your home network from remote locations.</p>
<p>As for compatibility, the TP-Link AXE5400 Tri-Band Wi-Fi 6E Router works with major Internet Service Providers (ISPs), including but not limited to AT&amp;T, Verizon, Xfinity, Spectrum, Cox, CenturyLink, and Frontier. However, most cable and DSL connections require a separate modem, which must be purchased separately. The router itself provides Wi-Fi, plus wired Ethernet WAN and LAN ports, and a USB port for supported accessories so that you can mix wired desktop computers with wireless mobile phones and streaming devices. Plus, the TP-Link Tether app lets you set up the router from your smartphone. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6748/">Once operational, the router’s relatively small size makes it easy to fit next to your modem, and its $116 sale price is a better value than the $200 original list price.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6748/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-is-offloading-tp-links-tri-band-wifi-6e-router-at-its-lowest-price-with-42-off-2000659062]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Hytale Have Controller Support? PlayStation & Xbox Controller Support, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-controller-support-playstation-xbox/</link>
            <guid>1404493</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Hytale feels like the spiritual successor to Minecraft in many ways, and it could be one of the big games over the next few years. Its early access release has been met with various questions, including whether Hytale includes controller support or not.</p>



<p>The tension building for Hytale’s thought-impossible launch has been seismic. After getting the green light to continue production in mid-2025, Hypixel Studio has been working hard on an old build to ensure the game is in a good state for early access.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-has-secured-development-costs-for-the-next-two-years/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale has secured development costs for the next two years</a>, which is great, but it could mean nothing without controller support for some.</p>







<h2 id="h-can-you-use-a-controller-for-hytale">Can You Use A Controller For Hytale?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Hypixel Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Hytale doesn’t support any form of official controller support for its early access launch.</strong></p>



<p>If you struggle with a mouse and keyboard, you might come unstuck at times trying to negotiate Hytale. The developer has been very transparent over many of the details surrounding Hytale’s early access build, and the official website has even addressed the question of controller support.</p>



<p>Under <a href="https://hytale.com/accessibility" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Accessibility</a>, here’s what the information has to say.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“We are currently missing controller support.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>So, there’s no second-guessing if you can hook up a PS5 or Xbox Series X|S pad to play Hytale—you can’t, and it’s unfortunate, as it will ultimately exclude a handful of potential users.</p>



<p>On the plus side, it’s not all doom and gloom.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-controller-support-being-added-to-hytale">When Is Controller Support Being Added To Hytale?</h2>



<p><strong>Hypixel Studios has said that controller support is a “top priority” that the team is looking to add ASAP.</strong></p>



<p>You might have to hang fire just a little bit for controller support. From the sounds of it, you might not be waiting too long. Once again, let’s check in with the game’s Accessibility page:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“This [controller support] is one of our top priorities and is expected to be available soon after release.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>How soon is ‘soon,’ is anyone’s guess. It could be a week or a month. Time is relative here and affects different groups of players. With <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-expects-one-million-players-at-early-access-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale expecting one million users during the early access launch</a>, stability and a structurally solid framework could be the goal at first.</p>



<p>Hopefully, controller support arrives in the time it takes to get stomped on by a dragon in the game’s world.</p>



<p>Is a lack of controller support at the early access launch a big no-no for you? What other key features is Hytale missing for its debut? Share some ideas via the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>, and start up some Hytale conversations.</p>



<hr>



<p>You should also check if <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-platforms-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale is on PlayStation 5 or Xbox Series X|S platforms</a>, and also its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-hytale-have-multiplayer-co-op-multiplayer-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Co-op &amp; Multiplayer status</a> for more details.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-controller-support-playstation-xbox/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Trek Voyager: Across the Unknown adds Switch 2 version, launches February 18]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/star-trek-voyager-across-the-unknown-adds-switch-2-version-launches-february-18</link>
            <guid>1404490</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Demo and pre-orders now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Survival [501 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> <a title="Genres > Strategy [304 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">strategy game</a> <em><a title="Games > Star Trek Voyager: Across the Unknown [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/star-trek-voyager-across-the-unknown">Star Trek Voyager: Across the Unknown</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,178 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,552 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [861 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,240 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2643390/Star_Trek_Voyager__Across_the_Unknown/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on February 18 for $39.99 / £34.99 / €39.99 / ¥5,940, publisher <a title="Companies > Daedalic Entertainment [59 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/daedalic-entertainment">Daedalic Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Gamexcite [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gamexcite">Gamexcite</a> announced. The Switch 2 version is newly announced. A demo is available now for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, and PC. <span id="more-1018873"></span></p><p>Pre-orders are also available with a 10 percent-off discount. In addition to the standard edition, a Deluxe Edition is available for $49.99 / £44.99 / €49.99 / ¥7,040, which includes five additional missions, two new recruitable heroes, and three new technologies.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Daedalic Entertainment:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Star Trek Voyager: Across the Unknown</em> is a story-driven survival strategy game in which the fate of the iconic starship is in your hands. Take the helm, manage the ship and resources, and make difficult decisions. Will you be able to bring home the ship and its crew?</p><p><strong>“What if?” Scenarios</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Did you ever wonder what would have happened had Captain Janeway decided differently? If an important crew member had followed a different path? Or what the outcome would have been had the crew of the U.S.S. Voyager embraced Borg technology to increase their chances of survival?</p><p>Wonder no more: <em>Star Trek Voyager: Across the Unknown</em> allows players to take control and shape the journey of the U.S.S. Voyager as they want. Take a risky approach or play it safe. Be diplomatic or let phasers do the talking. Research technologies that were shunned by the crew. But: Be prepared to deal with the consequences of your <a title="Genres > Action [3,324 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s! The game features <a title="Genres > Roguelike [407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> elements, so in each run you will encounter different situations and even iconic characters might meet an early end if you don’t react accordingly.</p><p><strong>Deep Ship <a title="Genres > Management [35 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">Management</a> and Research</strong></p><p>After being moved forcefully into the Delta Quadrant, the U.S.S. Voyager ends up heavily damaged and in dire need of repairs as well as internal reconstruction. Restore destroyed rooms, secure life support and energy supplies, and start constructing. Ship systems, crew quarters, industrial and research facilities: You must decide what to build and when, to ensure the ship has what it needs for the perilous journey.</p><p>Expedite research into different fields. New technologies and improved layouts will not only strengthen the ship but also boost your crew’s morale. Exotic and dangerous research, like the technology of the Borg, is also within your reach. As captain, will you embrace it for the potential it offers, or will you omit it for the dangers it presents?</p><p><strong>Exploration and Resource Acquisition</strong></p><p>The dangers and opportunities of the Delta Quadrant beckon to be discovered by you and your crew. Scan celestial bodies to locate precious resources that fuel your journey. Find points of interest and oddities along your way, but beware: While the Delta Quadrant may reward the bold, it punishes the careless just as quickly. As captain, you have the final say in plotting a course and defining an approach.</p><p><strong>Ship Combat and Away Missions</strong></p><p>The journey of the U.S.S. Voyager would not be possible without both combat between ships and away missions to planets or space facilities.</p><p>For away missions, put together a team based on the individual talents of your crew. A team with skills that complement each other might be best suited for the task, but it is up to you to call the shots. Minimize the risk for the team’s members, rush headlong into danger, or take a scientific approach—you decide.</p><p>When diplomacy fails, the U.S.S. Voyager and its crew are ready to enter ship combat at your command. From the bridge, you give commands for offensive and defensive maneuvers, targeting enemy ship systems and using special weaponry. And even during ship combat, the individual skills of your crew members come into play: Assign battle stations to crew who bring precious skills to the table and trigger them in crucial moments to maximize your combat effectiveness.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>“What if?” Scenario and Storytelling</strong> – The ultimate platform to play out your course of action during the iconic journey of the U.S.S. Voyager.</li><li><strong>Complex Ship Management</strong> – Repair, construct, and maintain an efficient and habitable ship to ensure systems and crew operate effectively.</li><li><strong>Exploration and Decision Making</strong> – The Delta Quadrant is a fascinating yet perilous place that awaits exploration and demands decisive action.</li><li><strong>Combat and Away Missions</strong> – Use the talents of your crew smartly to minimize risk during away missions as well as strike boldly during ship combat encounters.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Combat Deep Dive</span></h2><p><iframe title="Star Trek: Voyager - Across the Unknown | Combat Deep Dive" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7K9_Kn6fvEU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/star-trek-voyager-across-the-unknown-adds-switch-2-version-launches-february-18]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Fable Could Come To PS5 On Day One]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-fable-could-come-to-ps5-on-day-one/1100-6537333/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1404487</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537333">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Playground Games is working on two new games, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/forza-horizon-6-release-date-trailer/1100-6535015/" data-ref-id="1100-6535015">Forza Horizon 6</a> and a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fable-4-everything-we-know/1100-6485774/" data-ref-id="1100-6485774">new Fable title</a>, and both are expected to release on PS5--but only one may come to Sony's console day and date with the Xbox and PC versions. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jph13-tKWcY" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VGC's Andy Robinson said</a> he expects Playground's new Fable game to be released day-and-date on PS5 because the team has been "targeting PS5 for a while."</p><p>Forza Horizon 6 is confirmed for release on PS5, but not until after the Xbox and PC versions arrive. According to <a href="https://www.videogamer.com/news/new-fable-expected-day-one-ps5-forza-horizon-6-not-ready/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">VideoGamer</a>, Robinson said he was informed that the game "wasn't ready" for a day-and-date PS5 release. However, he acknowledged that he does not "know how true that is."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1986808955" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464332,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Fable%20Gameplay%20Reveal%20Trailer%20%7C%20Xbox%20Games%20Showcase%202024&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:163,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/fable-gameplay-reveal-trailer-xbox-games-showcase-2024\/2300-6464332\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464332\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464332\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464332\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464332&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464332,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6537333&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;fable,forza-horizon-6&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,pc,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;xbox-game-studios&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;fable,forza&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;fable,forza&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464332},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464332\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4316202-trailer_fable_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/Y1pIn2ut.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1717960440,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="Y1pIn2ut" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Fable Gameplay Reveal Trailer | Xbox Games Showcase 2024</p>
      </div>
<p>When Forza Horizon 6 was announced in 2025, Microsoft said it would come to PS5 after the Xbox and PC releases, but the company did not say what the exact gap would be. As for Fable, there is no word yet at all about a PS5 release, but it would be little surprise, given the belief that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-may-bring-all-their-big-games-to-ps5-analyst-says/1100-6528617/" data-ref-id="1100-6528617">Microsoft will release all of its big games on PS5.</a></p><p>When Fable was delayed to 2026, it was reported that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fable-delay-into-2026-could-allow-it-to-release-on-ps5-at-launch-leaker-suggests/1100-6529719/" data-ref-id="1100-6529719">the delay could allow the game to release on PS5 alongside the Xbox and PC versions.</a></p><p>Fable and Forza Horizon 6 will be shown off at the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-developer-direct-returns-january-22-with-fable-and-forza-horizon-6/1100-6537273/" data-ref-id="1100-6537273">Xbox Developer Direct on January 22</a>. During the showcase, Playground will provide an "extended look" at Fable, which is notable because Microsoft has shown so little so far. Forza Horizon 6, meanwhile, will get a debut of the first gameplay footage.</p><p>Microsoft puts some of its games on rival systems like PS5 to help them reach more people, and to bring in more money. It was recently reported that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-xbox-game-just-passed-300-million-in-revenue-on-ps5-report-says/1100-6537323/" data-ref-id="1100-6537323">Forza Horizon 5 for PS5 passed 5 million units sold and $300 million in revenue.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-fable-could-come-to-ps5-on-day-one/1100-6537333/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Players Get This Free Pickaxe As Game Passes 12 Million Copies Sold]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-players-get-this-free-pickaxe-as-game-passes-12-million-copies-sold/1100-6537346/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1404481</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537346">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nexon has officially announced that Arc Raiders has sold more than 12.4 million units since the $40 game launched at the end of October 2025. The sales number is not a surprise, as the research firm <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-continues-to-be-a-huge-hit-reportedly-achieving-these-new-records/1100-6537168/" data-ref-id="1100-6537168">Alinea Analytics previously estimated sales to be around 12 million. </a></p><p>Nexon president and CEO Junghun Lee said sales at this level, along with the fact that Arc Raiders reached 960,000 peak concurrent players, demonstrates "the potential for Arc Raiders to become another pillar in Nexon's portfolio of blockbuster franchises."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="465214059" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466509,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Arc%20Raiders%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:896,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/arc-raiders-review\/2300-6466509\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466509\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466509\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466509\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466509&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466509,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6537346&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;arc-raiders&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,shooter,third-person&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;embark-studios&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466509},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466509\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1862\/18620770\/4597382-review_arcraiders_20251105_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/c7VTPmjZ.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1762386540,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="c7VTPmjZ" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Arc Raiders Review</p>
      </div>
<p>The Korean publisher, which owns the Arc Raiders IP and developer Embark, further stated that Arc Raiders passed 10 million units sold by the end of December 2025. Nexon said sales accelerated recently, presumably due in part to the game's 20% discount, pushing total figures to 12.4 million and counting. The game has sold well and still has lots of players, as the game<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/these-were-the-top-15-most-popular-games-last-week-in-the-us/2900-7295/" data-ref-id="2900-7295"> regularly ranks at the top, or near it, on the Steam charts.</a></p><p>Anyone who logs into Arc Raiders by the end of today, January 13, will get the "Gilded Pickaxe Raider Tool" as part of the game's new update today.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4634592-golden.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4634592" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1024" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4634592-golden.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4634592"></a><figcaption>Get the Gilded Pickaxe for free right now.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4634592-golden.jpg"></figure><p>This update makes a series of significant changes, including reducing the fire rate for the Kettle from 600 to 450. "The previous fire rate was only realistically reachable by players using macros, which creates an unfair dynamic that favors using third-party software," Embark said.</p><p>Additionally, the Trigger 'Nade has been nerfed. "This nerf aims to make it less usable as a 'trigger-in-air' grenade, whilst keeping its usefulness as a sticky bomb," Embark said</p><p>What's more, the new Arc Raiders update fixes an exploit with key cards that allowed players to retain the room keys even after using them.</p><p>Given the huge success of Arc Raiders so far, it's no big surprise that Hollywood has come calling. Embark has said it's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-has-received-movie-and-tv-offers/1100-6537191/" data-ref-id="1100-6537191">gotten TV and movie pitches</a>, but no deals have materialized as of yet.</p><p>Arc Raiders has been big hit, but it's also been criticized for its use of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-is-my-game-of-the-year-but-its-use-of-generative-ai-really-sucks/1100-6537140/" data-ref-id="1100-6537140">AI-based text-to-speech systems</a>. Patrick Söderlund, the head of Arc Raiders studio Embark, recently shed more light on the situation, saying the studio's goal in implementing AI into its development processes is to make better games more efficiently. He also pushed back against the idea that using AI systems in game development would lead to lower employment at Embark.</p><p>"We don't use AI to not have to hire people or replace people or job groups or voice actors," Söderlund told <a href="https://gamesbeat.com/inside-arc-raiders-a-candid-interview-with-game-leaders-patrick-soderlund-and-owen-mahoney-while-playing-live/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GamesBeat</a>. "People have to take a step back and understand what it is and how it can be a big help to developers and be a tremendous benefit to players. I realize it is an intricate subject and discussion."</p><p>GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/arc-raiders-review-us-against-the-world/1900-6418435/" data-ref-id="1900-6418435">Arc Raiders review</a> scored the game a 9/10. "We can all kill each other in Arc Raiders. The fact that most of us are choosing instead to lend a helping hand, if not a sign that humanity will be all right in the real world, at the very least makes for one of the best multiplayer games I've ever played," reviewer Mark Delaney said.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-players-get-this-free-pickaxe-as-game-passes-12-million-copies-sold/1100-6537346/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Games CEO Tries To Clarify Comments About X's AI Image-Generating Tool]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/epic-games-ceo-tries-to-clarify-comments-about-xs-ai-image-generating-tool/1100-6537332/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1404478</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537332">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2026-01-13T06:12:08-0800">January 13, 2026 at 6:12AM PST</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Epic Games CEO Tim Sweeney has clarified his statements regarding X's AI generation of nonconsensual sexual images of minors and women, saying he merely "criticized a government official" for pressuring publicly traded companies for attempting to "block a speech app owned by their political opponent."</p><p>Right around the January 9 weekend, news broke that X users were turning to Grok, the platform's AI tool, to <a href="https://www.404media.co/groks-ai-csam-shitshow/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">create images of minors and women</a> in sexually compromising outfits and positions. The situation drew the attention of US Senators Ben Ray Lujan (D-NM), Edward Markey (D-MA), and Ron Wyden (D-OR), who <a href="https://www.wyden.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/letter_to_apple_and_google_on_removing_x_and_grok_from_app_store_192026pdf.pdf" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">wrote a letter to Apple and Google</a> requesting that the companies remove the Grok and X apps from their app stores for the "mass generation of nonconsensual sexualized images of women and children." The senators have asked for a written response from both companies by January 23.</p><p>In response to the letter, which <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2026/01/09/senators-apple-google-remove-grok/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">MacRumors reported and shared on X</a>, Tim Sweeney <a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2009732745140871463" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">quoted the post on January 9 and said</a> that senators using their political power to remove these apps for the harm they have caused are "gatekeepers" who are trying to "censor all of their political opponents." He <a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2009753835456156088" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">continued in a follow-up post</a>, explaining that no major AI company is "perfect" because they all have "documented instances of [their tech] going off the rails" and that these companies "make their best efforts to combat this." These comments blew up, drawing criticism from some corners of Elon Musk's social platform and praise from others.</p><p>After <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/epic-games-ceo-tim-sweeney-argues-banning-twitter-over-its-ability-to-ai-generate-pornographic-images-of-minors-is-just-gatekeepers-attempting-to-censor-all-of-their-political-opponents/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC Gamer ran a story on January 11</a> criticizing Sweeney for what it described as a defense of "an unprecedented online sexual humiliation machine," Sweeney <a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2010497254495342610" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">responded to the outlet's reporting</a>, calling the story a "vile lie" that misconstrued his statements.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2010497254495342610" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">This is a vile lie by PC Gamer. I criticized a government official for pressuring Apple and Google to block a speech app owned by their political opponent, deplatforming 500,000,000 users on the pretense of stopping a small number of users from distributing disgusting content.</p>  — Tim Sweeney (@TimSweeneyEpic) <a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2010497254495342610?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 11, 2026</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Tech enthusiast and Autohive CEO John-Daniel Trask <a href="https://x.com/traskjd/status/2010518692036292983" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">replied to Sweeney's post</a>, thanking him for "speaking up on this issue" because it's somehow a "power play." Sweeney <a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2010523813205717499" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">responded</a>, suggesting there might be "some group chat somewhere" of people plotting who to attack, when to attack, and why to attack. He <a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2010498148263776673" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">believes that the story PC Gamer ran</a> was an "absolutely disgusting disregard for the truth and for editorial practices."</p><p>GameSpot reached out to Epic for comment but has not yet received one.</p><p>While Sweeney appears frustrated with PC Gamer's framing of his comments, he also clarified that X's Grok generating child sexual abuse material (CSAM) and other nonconsensual sexually exploitative images is "bad." He also reiterated his position that "every significant AI has instances of this" and that companies "make their best efforts to stop it," but all are "imperfect."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2009751797393502548" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">1) That is bad.<br>2) Every significant AI has instances of this.<br>3) Every significant AI company makes their best efforts to stop it.<br>4) All are imperfect.<br>Thus the combined danger of selective enforcement against political opponents, and distribution monopolies.</p>  — Tim Sweeney (@TimSweeneyEpic) <a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2009751797393502548?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 9, 2026</a></blockquote>              </div><p>According to the <a href="https://rainn.org/get-the-facts-about-csam-child-sexual-abuse-material/what-is-csam/" rel="nofollow ">Rape, Abuse, &amp; Incest National Network (RAINN)</a>, CSAM (pronounced “see-sam”) refers to "any visual content--photos, videos, livestreams, or AI-generated images--that shows a child being sexually abused or exploited." RAINN clarifies that CSAM is not child pornography but evidence of "child sexual abuse--and it’s a crime to create, distribute, or possess."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/epic-games-ceo-tries-to-clarify-comments-about-xs-ai-image-generating-tool/1100-6537332/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam’s Big New Zombie Game Is Tense, But Comes At A Bad Time]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/steams-big-new-zombie-game-is-tense-but-comes-at-a-bad-time-2000658992</link>
            <guid>1404442</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I screwed up real bad in my first few in-game days of the latest Steam hit, <em>Quarantine Zone: The Last Checkpoint.</em> I let an infected person into the safe zone of our military-run camp. They turned into a zombie overnight, and I woke up to dead survivors. The reason I let them in? Right now, the last thing I want to do is hand off random citizens to soldiers in masks who will take them away to get “liquidated.”</p> <p>Before you email me or screenshot this article and share it online, let me be very clear: <a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-5-the-kotaku-review-1845588904">I know I’m breaking the rules</a>. I know I’m not supposed to talk about the real world when writing about video games. That’s a big no-no. To dare connect the dots between a digital game and the real world we all live in is often seen by some of the loudest online as a cardinal sin. Unforgivable. Well, get over it because I find it genuinely impossible to write about<em> Quarantine Zone: The Last Checkpoint</em> without addressing the current state of America.</p>

  <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3419520/Quarantine_Zone_The_Last_Check/">In <em>Quarantine Zone: The Last Checkpoint,</em></a> out now on PC, you play as a commander who has just arrived at a hastily put-together military installation in the middle of New York City. Your job is to help make all the big decisions on this base, including managing resources, upgrades, and the health and safety of personnel. But most of my time in <em>Quarantine Zone: The Last Checkpoint</em> was spent manning a single entry point at the front of the base, where survivors crawl out of a post-apocalyptic zombie-infested city in the hopes of finding shelter, food, and medicine. But first, they have to get past me, the asshole with a flashlight and gloves who decides who lives and dies.</p>

 <p>The majority of<em> Last Checkpoint</em> revolves around operating that point of entry. Early on, you are equipped with a flashlight and a small list of various symptoms and injuries to look out for, like bites and bloodshot eyes, and must use that list to determine who is healthy enough to enter, who needs to hang out in a quarantine cell for a few days, and who might need to be taken over to a non-descript room just out of eyesight of everyone to be shot in the head. As the in-game days go on, you start getting new tools, like a rubber mallet to check reflexes, and an X-ray gun to scan for hidden bites.</p>

 <p>In my first few days, I avoided sending anyone to the kill room. I’ve spent the past few months watching President Trump’s jackbooted thugs in masks, aka ICE, grab people off the street, sometimes at gunpoint, and take them away to places none of us can see. Not everyone comes back. And as I played <em>Last Checkpoint,</em> my phone was filled with photos and videos from out of <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cpv7knz8e8mo">Minnesota</a>, <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/2000-federal-agents-sent-to-minneapolis-area-to-carry-out-largest-immigration-operation-ever-ice-says">where ICE continues to cause mayhem and destruction</a>, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2026/01/09/nx-s1-5672502/minneapolis-portland-ice-shootings">even shooting an innocent woman in the face in broad daylight</a>. So the armed guards decked out in full masks and carrying large assault rifles in<em>&nbsp;Last Checkpoint</em> were hard to trust.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000659009" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000659009"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000659009">©Brigada Games / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>But eventually, as space in quarantine ran out and I sent a few too many infected people into the safe zone and got others killed, I had to start sending people away to get shot in a room for the good of everyone else. There is no cure for the zombie plague in <em>Quarantine Zone: The Last Checkpoint</em>, so once you think someone is infected, there’s not much of an option left. Each time I’d send a survivor away, I’d wait for the message to pop up on the screen confirming whether they were infected or not. When I finally screwed up and realized I’d sent an innocent man to his death at the hands of gun-toting soldiers, I wasn’t sure if I was having fun anymore.</p>

 <p>Tracking symptoms and managing a small military base in the middle of a zombie apocalypse using various tools and having to make hard calls is a very tense experience. And when I could disconnect what was happening in <em>Quarantine Zone: The Last Checkpoint</em> from the world I currently live in, I found myself having a good time succeeding at helping people, something the game also rewards you for and makes clear is the main goal of all this. But then I’d check my phone and see what <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/chicago-immigration-enforcement-children-tear-gas-border-patrol-rcna241629">government-controlled soldiers are actually doing at a time when we aren’t being eaten alive by zombies</a>. The in-game soldiers and officials in <em>Last Checkpoint</em> have more restraint and empathy during a zombie apocalypse than the authorities walking our actual streets do right now. Wild shit.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/steams-big-new-zombie-game-is-tense-but-comes-at-a-bad-time-2000658992]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[KONOSUBA – God’s Blessing on this Wonderful World! Prosperity for this Beloved City! announced for PC, iOS, and Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/konosuba-gods-blessing-on-this-wonderful-world-prosperity-for-this-beloved-city-announced-for-pc-ios-and-android</link>
            <guid>1404439</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in 2026 in Japan.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Kadokawa Corporation [660 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation">Kadokawa Corporation</a> has <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000018596.000007006.html" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > KONOSUBA - God's Blessing on this Wonderful World! Prosperity for this Beloved City!" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/konosuba-gods-blessing-on-this-wonderful-world-prosperity-for-this-beloved-city">KONOSUBA – God’s Blessing on this Wonderful World! Prosperity for this Beloved City!</a></em>, a new game based on the TV anime series with an original story. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,240 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, iOS, and Android in 2026 in Japan. <span id="more-1018867"></span></p><p>Here are a couple of creator comments:</p><blockquote><p><strong><a title="Companies > Natsume [123 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/natsume">Natsume</a> <a title="Companies > Akatsuki [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/akatsuki">Akatsuki</a> – Creator</strong></p><p>“Congratulations and thank you for the new <em>KONOSUBA</em> game! I’d like to aim to be an independent solo player like Yunyun, so I hope the event design won’t exclude those who play alone. I’m really looking forward to starting the game!”</p><p><strong>Kurone Mishima – Illustrator</strong></p><p>“Congratulations on the new <em>KONOSUBA</em> game! I’m truly happy to be able to meet Kazuma and the others again in this form. I hope many people will enjoy playing it! I’ll be playing as well once the game is released!”</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Visit the official website <a href="https://konosuba-machisuba.com/" target="_blank">here</a>. Follow the game on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/machisuba" target="_blank">here</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/konosuba-gods-blessing-on-this-wonderful-world-prosperity-for-this-beloved-city-announced-for-pc-ios-and-android]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cancelled Batman Game Was Aiming To Nail What The Dark Knight Movies Do Best]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cancelled-batman-game-was-aiming-to-nail-what-the-dark-knight-movies-do-best/1100-6537348/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1404436</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537348">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It's no secret that a video game based on 2008's The Dark Knight was in development at one point, before the plug was ultimately pulled. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/more-footage-for-batman-game-that-became-shadow-of-mordor-surfaces-online/1100-6522392/">Footage of the game</a>--which was being developed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-wonder-woman-game-canceled-multiple-studios-closed-report/1100-6529706/">by the now-shuttered Monolith Productions</a>--has surfaced online over the years, and this week, a new video showed how this Batman adventure would have taken a cue from the live-action films with its dynamic soundtrack.</p><p>As part of a treasure trove of materials uncovered by retro games enthusiast and archivist Mar Talida, the footage showcases early cinematic footage, game design documents, concept art, and much more. If you have an ear for video game soundtracks, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ozbdmak67oao253ndqc7qqlf/post/3mcbadrp5ek2v" rel="nofollow ">there's even video of the game's dynamic audio system</a> and how it would change depending on the situation that players found themselves in. Batman live-action films have had iconic soundtracks, and Monolith's game used some of Hans Zimmer's Dark Knight soundtrack to demonstrate this feature.</p><p>It's worth noting that all of this content came from very early in the pre-production of the Batman game--codenamed Project Apollo--as the assets were dated to around 2009-2010 and naturally look rougher than the 2024 leak.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:ozbdmak67oao253ndqc7qqlf/app.bsky.feed.post/3mcba4da5xk2x" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiexnglfrkoagem3zaekq35capabq2ux3cwacqlek5gdc2hwzn35la" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system"><div><p>I've recovered a cache of documents and videos from the pre-production phase of Project Apollo, a canceled Batman game Monolith worked on for Warner Bros. The materials, from 4/2009 to 1/2010, were in deleted sectors of a HDD used at a game company. archive.org/details/proj... 1/9🧵</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ozbdmak67oao253ndqc7qqlf/post/3mcba4da5xk2x?ref_src=embed" rel="nofollow  ">[image or embed]</a></p></div>  — MrTalida (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ozbdmak67oao253ndqc7qqlf?ref_src=embed" rel="nofollow  ">@mrtalida.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ozbdmak67oao253ndqc7qqlf/post/3mcba4da5xk2x?ref_src=embed" rel="nofollow  ">January 13, 2026 at 1:48 AM</a></blockquote>


  






  </div><p>While the project was eventually scrapped and elements of it were used to develop Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor and its signature Nemesis System, Batman fans weren't left out in the cold thanks to Rocksteady's popular Arkham series of games. Since then, things have changed drastically at publisher Warner Bros. Games, as it has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/batman-game-publisher-undergoes-major-shakeup/1100-6532546/">weathered major organizational </a><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/batman-game-publisher-undergoes-major-shakeup/1100-6532546/">shifts</a> and could soon have a new owner <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/netflixs-bid-for-warner-bros-now-looks-more-like-a-sure-thing/1100-6537239/" data-ref-id="1100-6537239">in the form of Netflix</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/paramount-not-giving-up-on-buying-warner-bros-launches-lawsuit/1100-6537335/" data-ref-id="1100-6537335">Paramount</a>. Rocksteady is said to be <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-batman-and-game-of-thrones-games-may-be-in-the-works/1100-6529314/">working on a new single-player Batman game</a>, and DC studio boss James Gunn has said <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/first-dc-universe-game-wont-be-revealed-soon-but-some-really-interesting-projects-are-coming/1100-6529678/">some "really interesting" projects are coming</a> in the future.</p><p>Fortunately, Batman returns later this year in Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight. The new Lego game looks like it's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-isnt-just-another-lego-game/1100-6534151/">taking a few pages out of the Arkham playbook</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-releases-in-may/1100-6536781/">and it'll be released on May 29</a> for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S, with a Switch 2 version coming at a later date.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cancelled-batman-game-was-aiming-to-nail-what-the-dark-knight-movies-do-best/1100-6537348/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Machine Verified requirements will have 'fewer constraints' than Steam Deck, says Valve]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/pc/steam-machine-verified-requirements-will-have-fewer-constraints-than-steam-deck-says-valve</link>
            <guid>1404430</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As interest in Valve's recently-announced </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/pc/valve-goes-all-in-on-hardware-with-steam-machine-controller-and-new-vr-device">Steam Machine</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> continues to swirl, developers have had plenty of reason to wonder what will be needed to attract player interest on the platform. While the company still hasn't released pricing info for the SteamOS-based hardware, it has shed some light on its verification process in a new interview with Game Developer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to Valve designer Lawrence Yang, developers hoping for a "Steam Machine Verified" badge can expect "fewer constraints" than Steam Deck Verification. "One easy rule of thumb is that if your title is Verified on Steam Deck, it will be Verified on Steam Machine," Yang continued. VR developers seeking Steam Frame verification may expect a different process, though Yang said Valve will "be going through the same rounds of testing and providing developer feedback" as it does for the other verification programs.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The "Steam Deck Verified" badge has proven to be more than a mere quality assessor when releasing games on Steam. It's also been a major marketing beat for developers—one so potent companies like Microsoft-owned Bethesda are </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/quake-is-now-steam-deck-verified-223009852.html">publicizing</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Steam Deck Verified status for classic games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Quake</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. A "Verified" badge also means your game might appear on the "Great on Deck" section of the Steam Store, the default store page found when accessing the marketplace on the device.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/pc/hollow-knight-silksong-is-the-steam-awards-2025-game-of-the-year" target="_self" data-discover="true">Hollow Knight: Silksong is the Steam Awards' 2025 Game of the Year</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Valve didn't provide additional technical requirements for earning the "Steam Machine Verified" status—though it did offer some details on why it created the Steam Controller Puck pairing system that reflects its hardware philosophy.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Valve's goal: &quot;It just works&quot;">Valve's goal: "It just works"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Valve's Steam Controller Puck, the device that can both charge and pair a Steam Controller to any PC it's plugged into, was a small surprise in the Steam Machine hardware reveal. Most controller manufacturers have settled on using Bluetooth or USB-C as their main means of pairing controllers. Valve says it created this extra piece of hardware to address issues not with Bluetooth itself, but the environments people play in.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"While Bluetooth is a great wireless connection method, we found in our testing that people’s home wireless environments and PC Bluetooth capabilities are highly variable (clogged networks, wireless interference, increased latency when using multiple BT devices, etc.)," said engineer Steve Cardinali.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Cardinali added that the Puck "addresses these issues."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Another problem we set out to solve was the fact that dedicated wireless receivers that are plugged directly into the back of a PC near other USB ports can create interference issues. Adding the charging capability encourages people to leave the puck in a place where it's likely to have minimal interference while providing a really easy charging experience."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/pc/valve-will-soon-support-android-games-on-steam" target="_self" data-discover="true">Valve will soon support Android games on Steam</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It just works" has become a key strategic philosophy for Valve as it develops products that approach the plug-and-play reliability of the classic console market. Seeing that philosophy expand from the "Verified" badge to the controller pairing system shows there may be more untapped potential in making the PC video game market a less-fiddly and more accessible experience.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' 4X strategy game Zephon, Iron Anchor Studios' Down With The Ship, and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/pc/steam-machine-verified-requirements-will-have-fewer-constraints-than-steam-deck-says-valve]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout: London hasn't developed into a Fallout 4-esque hub of new quest and expansion mods so far, and its lead has theories why]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-london-hasnt-developed-into-a-fallout-4-esque-hub-of-its-own-new-quest-and-expansion-mods-and-its-lead-has-theories-why</link>
            <guid>1404418</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"That’s what we’d love to see"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-london-lead-on-lack-of-quest-expansion-mods-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team FOLON</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Who mods the mods? A bunch of people, or so was the hope of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-london">Fallout: London</a> developers Team FOLON when they released their total conversion of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-4">Fallout 4</a> back in 2024. So far, there've been plenty of tweaks and smaller scale additions to the mod's version of the post-apocalyptic English capital, but no new quests or world expansions of note.</p>
<p>Things playing out that way to this point - despite Team FOLON having <a href="https://www.vg247.com/fallout-london-british-fallout-making-of-interview">been very open in encouraging other modders</a> to have a go at making such creations - is something Fallout: London project lead Dean 'Prilladog' Carter's clearly aware of, and he's offered a few theories as to why it might be the case.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"There are definitely some cut quests which are not planned in any of the DLCs that could have been implemented, which we have voiced, but that just wasn’t in the scope of what we could do before we moved on as a company," Carter told <a href="https://www.esports.net/news/industry/fallout-london-creator-bethesda-elder-scrolls-vi-fallout-5-gta-london/">Esports.net</a> in a fresh interview. "If a modder wants to get involved in them, they absolutely can. That’s what we’d love to see. We’re modders at the end of the day. We’re never going to say no to other modders wanting to do stuff."</p>
<p>He also acknowledged that, while his team have chatted with "quite a lot of smaller modders", there hasn't been a deluge of folks wanting to flesh out the massive mod with their own extra quests or adventures, as is the case with all of the pro studio-made modern Fallouts. Instead, a glance at <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/games/fallout4london">Fallout: London's Nexus Mods page</a> - which I've kept an eye on regularly to see if these sorts of ambitious or creative works pop up - currently turns up just over 600 mods that generally provide handy tweaks to mechanics or fairly compact additions like player homes. There are <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4london/mods/17">a</a> <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4london/mods/613">few</a> <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4london/mods/461">mods</a> by a creator called WitherAwayyy I've dug up which could fit the expansion bill, but they remain exceptions to the rule.</p><p>"I’ve heard of people who have been looking into it, and we give advice and help if they ask, but I don’t know of any new worlds or spaces coming up," Carter admitted in this chat. That's no huge issue - Fallout: London's plenty good played in its 'vanilla' state, as Carter reckons a lot of potential modders may simply prefer. That said, it's still an intriguing thing to see play out, given I can't think many other mods off the top of my head which have offered such an expansive opportunity for modding on top of modding.</p>
<p>Though, at this juncture Carter reckons that may well have been another of the limiting factors the mod's modding scene has bumped up against. "I think people are also well aware that, given the nature of how large we built an entire game on top of another game, it’s not the easiest to mod, and there are stability issues that come from building a game on top of a game," he said. The modder also reckons Fallout 4's age has played a role. "It’s a modding scene for a decade-old game. I think a lot of people have moved on," he theorised. "Even ourselves, when you go back to that question of would we do more, the answer is probably not in Fallout 4."</p>
<p>While this may be one area in which Fallout: London simply can't mirror the Fallout entry to which some have compared what the sort of detour it offers Fallout players - Obsidian's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-new-vegas">New Vegas</a> - there are still a couple of bits of free Team FOLON-made DLC yet to arrive for it. Last Orders is the first of these and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-londons-next-dlc-last-orders-will-be-served-up-early-this-year-if-current-pint-pulling-plans-hold">should arrive pretty soon</a>, followed at some point down the line by a Yes Man-esque questline in the Wildcard DLC.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-london-hasnt-developed-into-a-fallout-4-esque-hub-of-its-own-new-quest-and-expansion-mods-and-its-lead-has-theories-why]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HP’s 15.6″ Laptop at Nearly 60% Off Comes With Windows 11 Pro and Microsoft Office, Priced Like a Budget Tablet]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-hp-laptop-at-nearly-60-off-comes-with-windows-11-pro-and-microsoft-office-priced-like-a-budget-tablet-2000659048</link>
            <guid>1404415</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If high laptop prices have been holding you back from upgrading, now is the time to make the move. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6736/">The 15.6-inch HP business laptop is down to $400 at Amazon, after a massive 56% or $500 discount on its usual $900 price.</a></p>
<p>The bundle includes a Microsoft Office 365 subscription, Windows 11 Pro pre-installed, and a recovery USB. Delivery is free, so you’re saving a bit on that front too, which brings the overall cost down even further. But as you’d expect, the discount is around for a short time. We’re not expecting it to last longer than a day, so it’s best to get your orders in without wasting much time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6736/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Expandable Memory and Storage</h2>
<p>For just $400, you’re getting a sleek laptop that features a nice 15.6-inch Full HD display. With a resolution of 1920 × 1080, the screen delivers crisp details and vibrant colors for an immersive viewing experience. The anti-glare coating keeps it easy on the eyes, allowing you to use the laptop comfortably in all lighting conditions. Working on an important work presentation or just catching up on your favorite show, expect vivid, sharp visuals consistently.</p>
<p>The machine is powered by the latest Intel Core i3-1315U processor that features 6 cores (2 performance cores + 4 efficiency cores) and 8 threads to deliver fast, efficient performance. Intel Turbo Boost Technology helps it reach up to 4.5 GHz, meaning you can rely on the laptop for everyday work tasks, plus casual use (browsing, streaming, checking emails, communicating). Paired with the laptop is a modest 8GB RAM, which keeps everything running smoothly at the backend. It’s not massive, so you won’t exactly be able to multitask, but here’s the good part – the memory is expandable up to 64GB. That means you can always upgrade as your needs grow. The same is the case with the 628GB SSD (128GB SSD+500GB external). It’s sufficient to house important files, work documents, and media content, but the PCIe NVMe SSD supports capacities up to 2 TB. If it ever feels tight, you expand the capacity to keep the system running smoothly.</p>



<p>Port-wise, you’re covered with Ethernet (RJ-45) for speedy wired networking, an SD card reader, USB-C, two USB 3.2 Type-A, HDMI output, and a headphone/microphone combo jack. That’s more than enough to create a productive setup for both office and studies. You can add external drives, and even connect another monitor if you need more than one screen.</p>
<p>Freebies add even more value to the bundle. You’re getting a Microsoft Office 365 subscription, which offers access to efficient apps like Word, Excel, PowerPoint, OneNote, and more. You will also enjoy 1 TB of OneDrive cloud storage, handy AI features, and other useful tools that make remote productivity and creativity a breeze. Windows 11 Pro also comes pre-installed, which means you can get started with using the laptop right away. And finally, there’s a WOWPC recovery USB in the bundle, which offers quick and convenient system restoration in case of software issues.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6736/">This future-proof HP laptop is now sitting at just $400 at Amazon.</a> It’s practically nothing considering all the features the machine is packed with. We highly suggest grabbing it as soon as you can before the price shoots back up to $900.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6736/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-hp-laptop-at-nearly-60-off-comes-with-windows-11-pro-and-microsoft-office-priced-like-a-budget-tablet-2000659048]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Division Might Be Getting Exactly What Destiny Fans Have Long Wanted]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/division-3-definitive-edition-remaster-destiny-2000658970</link>
            <guid>1404412</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/tom-clancys-the-division-the-kotaku-review-1766431754"><em>The Division</em></a> came out nearly a decade ago. You can still go and play it but it hasn’t received a meaningful update since 2018. That could all be about to change. Marketing for “<em>The Division: Definitive Edition</em>” recently appeared in Japan suggesting the Tom Clancy-branded loot shooter could be getting a modern version to bring players back into its snowy, post-apocalyptic New York City.</p> <p>A mural advertising the unannounced version was spotted at the <a href="https://twitter.com/domen0204/status/2010224815131766796?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E2010224815131766796%7Ctwgr%5E03918b0436fb66d4f458378427f25deceae49e55%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ign.com%2Farticles%2Fit-looks-like-the-division-definitive-edition-is-on-the-way-10-years-after-its-initial-release">FPS Day X esports event</a> where Ubisoft shared other info about the franchise, like a new “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3zo5k8xkeHs">Realism Mode</a>” for <em>The Division 2</em> that will make the RPG play more like a traditional shooter with quicker time-to-kills and other more lethal tweaks. The first <em>Division</em> game originally launched back in March 2016, so it’s likely that whatever this Definitive Edition is could become available in just a few months.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="qme" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FPSDayX?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FPSDayX</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TheDivision2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TheDivision2</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%83%87%E3%82%A3%E3%83%93%E3%82%B8%E3%83%A7%E3%83%B32?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ディビジョン2</a> <a href="https://t.co/1ySkfSb98B">pic.twitter.com/1ySkfSb98B</a></p> <p>— Domen🐻Gaming | ドウメン (@domen0204) <a href="https://twitter.com/domen0204/status/2010224815131766796?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 11, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>What a Definitive Edition would actually entail has been the subject of much speculation over on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/thedivision/comments/1q9ywr5/the_division_definitive_edition_spotted_at_fpsday/"><em>The Division</em> subreddit</a>. Will it be a current-gen remaster that brings the game natively to PS5 and Xbox Series X/S? <em>The Division 2</em> never got one, making that theory seem unlikely to some. Others would be happy if the game simply got support for 60fps on console and other quality-of-life improvements. Some fans have also suggested the possibility of new story content, or the merging of certain mechanics and modes from the current game back into the older one.</p>

 <p>Of course, it’s very possible that what Ubisoft might mean by a “Definitive Edition” is that it’s bringing all of <em>The Division 1</em> and <em>The Division 2</em> into a single cohesive package. That would seemingly be a much bigger undertaking and it’s hard to see exactly how it would work. The second game’s Warlords of New York added the first game’s location, but there’s still a ton of missions, story, and other content that could make its way there. A single package would also make it a more obvious candidate for a Switch 2 port.</p>

 <h2><em>The Division</em> seems to be doing exactly what <em>Destiny</em> fans keep begging for</h2> <p>Assuming that whatever this Definitive Edition is, it brings the old game forward for new and returning players to enjoy fresh in 2026 in some way, developer Massive will be fulfilling the dream that many <em>Destiny</em> fans have had ever since <em>Destiny 2</em> wrapped up its big, 10-year story arc with <em>The Final Shape</em>. While Bungie has brought some of the best parts of the old game forward into <em>Destiny 2</em> over the years, it also ditched most of the sequel’s original campaign to make room for ongoing expansions.</p>

 <p>A perennial request of fans is for the Red War and other cut content to return. Another pie-in-the-sky wish is for the old <em>Destiny</em> to return in some “vanilla” form similar to<em> World of Warcraft Classic.</em> It would be the original game but with a visual overhaul and on modern platforms so that players feel like there’s a reason for everyone to go back at the same time. The third request you’ll find in the replies for almost any new announcement from the <em>Destiny</em> social media account is for Bungie to simply start fresh and make <em>Destiny 3</em>.</p>

 <p>https://x.com/blueberriesGG/status/2010713900975902762</p> <p>Those are all very tall orders for a studio that’s suffered tons of layoffs, cuts, and player attrition in recent years, especially as it works on getting its new sci-fi shooter, <em>Marathon</em>, out the door alongside ongoing <em>Destiny 2</em> updates. But this is kind of what fans of <em>The Division</em> are in for right now. Executive producer Julian Gerighty recently teased that <em>The Division 3</em> is “<a href="https://kotaku.com/steam-machine-price-leak-division-3-fable-ps5-2000658489">shaping up to be a monster</a>.” In addition to its recently revealed Realism Mode, The <em>Division 2</em> is also getting its delayed Survivors mode later this year.</p>

 <p>If this Definitive Edition of the original game doesn’t disappoint, fans of the apocalyptic shooter will be eating well. <em>Destiny 2</em> fans might even be envious. Something they’ve never had much reason to feel before, if ever.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/division-3-definitive-edition-remaster-destiny-2000658970]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Footage of Cancelled Monolith Batman Game Surfaces Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/more-footage-of-cancelled-monolith-batman-game-surfaces-online/</link>
            <guid>1404409</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A whole cache of documents and footage from the cancelled Monolith Batman game has surfaced online, showcasing audio systems, character art, game mechanics, vehicles, and more. </p>



<p>Footage and other details about cancelled Batman games have been surfacing online for quite some time now. Last year, we saw <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-concept-art-cancelled-batman-game-appears/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concept art</a> and other <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/potential-footage-for-canceled-damian-wayne-batman-game-leaks-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">potential footage</a> from the cancelled Damian Batman game by WB Games Montreal. Now, much more footage has been released for Monolith’s title, along with additional details.</p>











<p>The cache of footage and documents for the cancelled Monolith Batman game comes through a series of posts by <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mrtalida.bsky.social/post/3mcba4da5xk2x" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">MrTalida on BlueSky</a>. The bulk of the footage was part of “internal-facing and Warner Bros.-facing pre-production milestone deliverables”; however, some files are from an actual build. </p>



<p>The first set of videos discusses the dynamic audio system from the cancelled Monolith Batman game, showcasing how the music reacts and transitions as the player moves in and out of stealth, enters combat, and plays quests. </p>







<p>Then we get to see an example of cloth physics, showcasing how Batman’s cape moves around while walking. We also get to see character art for Gordon and members of the Gotham police, along with a facial animation test. </p>







<p>We were also shown other game mechanics from the cancelled Monolith Batman game, including the caped crusader throwing Batarangs to knock enemies down, using smoke bombs to enter stealth, knocking enemies down, using detective mode to collect evidence, and more. </p>







<p>The last video shows the Tumbler Batmobile in action, maneuvering through various sets of obstacles, using its boosts, and ramming into other elements on the map. Readers should note that this is very early footage, from 2009 to 2010. More files and documents are available <a href="https://archive.org/details/project-apollo-documents-and-videos" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>. </p>











<p>In other news, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-release-date-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date</a> for LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight has been announced. What are your thoughts on the footage from the cancelled Monolith Batman game? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-to-layoff-55-employees-across-the-division-developers-and-stockholm-studio/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft laying off 55 employees across the Division and Stockholm studios</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/more-footage-of-cancelled-monolith-batman-game-surfaces-online/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>