<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 20:13:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty League 2026 Maps and Modes Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-cdl-2026-maps-modes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-league-2026-maps-and-modes-revealed.1364659/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Ahead of the start of the season, Call of Duty League 2026 has revealed the maps and modes that will be present. Furthermore, a new mode will be added, Overload, spicing up the competition further.</p>







<p>With each new entry, the Call of Duty series has been a great multiplayer experience. Despite Black Ops 7 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-player-count-black-ops-7-player-count/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">not doing so hot</a>, one can count on Activision and the teams doing well by the mode. Nothing, though, has said it better than in Esports. Last year, Optic Texas <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cdl-champs-optic-texas-win/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">took home the championship</a>, with Mercules scoring MVP. With CDL 2026, it’s anyone’s game, especially with the addition of a brand-new mode to competition.</p>



<h2 id="h-cdl-2026-adding-overload-to-game-modes-starting-december-5th-7th">CDL 2026 Adding Overload to Game Modes, Starting December 5th-7th</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>In a tweet from <a href="https://x.com/CODLeague/status/1993347588654018822?" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Call of Duty League</a>, the full lineup of maps and modes for the 2026 season has been unveiled. Additionally, the full competitive rules and settings can be <a href="https://callofdutyleague.com/en-us/competitive-settings" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">found here</a>. The full list of maps and modes can be found below:</p>



<ul>
<li>Hardpoint
<ul>
<li>Blackheart</li>



<li>Colossus</li>



<li>Den</li>



<li>Exposure</li>



<li>Scar</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Search &amp; Destroy
<ul>
<li>Colossus</li>



<li>Den</li>



<li>Exposure</li>



<li>Raid</li>



<li>Scar</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Overload (NEW)
<ul>
<li>Den</li>



<li>Exposure</li>



<li>Scar</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p>As mentioned before, Overload is a brand-new mode added to the Call of Duty League. From Black Ops 7, the 6×6 mode acts like Capture the Flag, as teams will try to get the Overload Device to a designated objective. It’ll be interesting to see how it evolves within the competitive scene. Either way, it’s definitely one to watch on December 5th-7th.</p>







<p>What do you think of CDL’s map and modes lineup? Excited to see Overload added to the modes? Which map do you think will be great for competition? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Esports news, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-faze-jersey-rollbit-partnership-fans-angry/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the controversial Rollbit outfit</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-elite-series-announced-with-1-million-prize-pot/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield REDSEC Elite cash pool</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-cdl-2026-maps-modes/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Erosion ‘Gameplay Walkthrough’ video]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/erosion-gameplay-walkthrough-video</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/erosion-%E2%80%98gameplay-walkthrough%E2%80%99-video.1364656/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A four-minute guide through an early quest in the game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Lyrical Games [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/lyrical-games">Lyrical Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Plot Twist [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/plot-twist">Plot Twist</a> have released a four-minute gameplay walkthrough video of <em><a title="Games > Erosion [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/erosion">Erosion</a></em>, the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/wild-west-open-world-roguelike-action-game-erosion-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc">newly announced</a> Wild West <a title="Genres > Open-World [778 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> time-looping <a title="Genres > Roguelike [397 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Action [3,227 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a>. <span id="more-1009368"></span></p><p>The footage guides viewers through an early quest in the game and highlights how the different choices players make ripple across timelines.</p><p>Here is a brief overview of the game, via Lyrical Games:</p><blockquote><p><em>Erosion</em> is a time-looping open-world roguelike that fuses chaotic action and meaningful narrative in a living post-apocalyptic Wild West, where every death advances a decade. </p><p>Journey across time to save your daughter from a ruthless warlord, where failure means another chance, but at a devastating cost. Explore a faction-divided wasteland to build your arsenal and reshape the fates of its eccentric inhabitants across shifting timelines.  Join a chicken cult, steal a slick new ride, race it to earn Cheddar, then gamble it all away in the Al Cashino. Descend into the mysterious Pillar to battle through chaotic, destructible dungeons, fighting to get one step closer to saving your daughter or losing her entirely to time itself.</p></blockquote><p><em>Erosion</em> is due out in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,341 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,869 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3211720/Erosion/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/erosion/9n5rhwd1pbzj" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> in spring 2026, followed by a full release across <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,915 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, Xbox Series, and PC later in 2026.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch the footage below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Walkthrough</span></h2><p><iframe title="Erosion | Gameplay Walkthrough - Time-looping open world roguelike" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/onFUF0D4J3g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/erosion-gameplay-walkthrough-video]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 gets a free trial week starting today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/25/battlefield-6-gets-a-free-trial-week-starting-today/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-gets-a-free-trial-week-starting-today.1364638/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Already a major hit with record-breaking franchise sales, EA has kicked off a <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a> Free Trial. This is live now and running from today, 25th November, until 2nd December at 4 a.m. PT (12 p.m. UTC)</p>
<p>To play the Free Trial, you need to download the free-to-play Battlefield REDSEC, which will have access to more modes and maps granted for the coming week.</p>
<p><iframe title="Battlefield 6 | Free Trial Week" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NllG1jzar4E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The Battlefield 6 Free Trial features a subset of the maps and modes in the full game, putting an emphasis on the Season 1 content, and obviously doesn’t include the single player campaign (<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/30/should-you-skip-the-battlefield-6-campaign/">but you can probably skip that</a>). Free-to-play players will get to check out&nbsp;Siege of Cairo, Blackwell Fields, and the newly released Eastwood, and get to try them out in modes like Conquest, Breakthrough, Team Deathmatch, and Sabotage.&nbsp;Of course, you also already have the free-to-play <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/28/battlefield-redsec-is-the-long-rumoured-free-to-play-battle-royale-and-its-out-now/">Battlefield REDSEC battle royale mode</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks to that, there’s already cross-pollination of unlocks and levels. Anything unlocked in REDSEC can be used in the Free Trial, and anything you unlock in the Free Trial is kept and carried through should you buy the full game.</p>

<p>The timing of this is pretty much perfect for EA to capitalise on the missteps made by their biggest rival, and as we head into the Thanksgiving holiday weekend in the US. It’s a great time to try and convince more people to join this shooter and not the other.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/battlefield/battlefield-6/news/battlefield-6-season-1-free-trial-details-tips-and-tricks">EA</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/25/battlefield-6-gets-a-free-trial-week-starting-today/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Recent Windows Update Caused Substantial Performance Drop in Assassin’s Creed Shadows]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/recent-windows-update-caused-substantial-performance-drop-assassins-creed-shadows/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/recent-windows-update-caused-substantial-performance-drop-in-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows.1364635/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>A recent Windows Update, identified by the code KB5066835, has indeed caused substantial performance drops in PC games.</p>



<p>A few days ago, NVIDIA <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-geforce-hotfix-driver-resolves-lower-performance-bug-windows-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">released</a> a new GeForce hotfix driver, version 581.94, following reports from several gamers of lower performance in some titles. Now, Digital Foundry <a href="https://www.digitalfoundry.net/news/2025/11/proof-that-recent-windows-update-harms-gaming-performance" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has looked into the issue</a> and verified that, without the hotfix and with the aforementioned Windows Update, Ubisoft's Assassin's Creed Shadows takes a major frame rate hit. In Digital Foundry's test, the game ran between 33% and 50% worse on a PC equipped with a Ryzen 7 9800X3D CPU and an Nvidia RTX 5090 GPU after installing that Windows Update. The GeForce hotfix resolves the situation, so you should definitely install it if you are currently playing the game. Another option would be to remove the Windows Update, but the existence of the hotfix makes this redundant.</p>



<p>Anyway, we have sent an inquiry to Microsoft to understand what happened here. It's not the first time a Windows Update creates issues in games, but to this extent, it is perhaps unheard of.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/digital_foundry_ac_shadows_test-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: Digital Foundry</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>In other news, Assassin's Creed Shadows just received its 1.1.6 Title Update. It introduces a special collaboration with the Attack on Titan franchise, featuring a new time-limited quest that will only be available through December 22. Alongside the story quest, an Attack on Titan Dual Pack is also available for purchase from the in-game store. Drawing inspiration from the Attack on Titan universe, this pack will include outfits, weapons, trinkets, and a new mount.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Assassin's Creed Shadows: Title Update 1.1.6 - Naoe &amp; Yasukes New Skills" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TOuk5LTf2VE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>A new regular side quest called A Puzzlement is also available. In this mission, protagonists Naoe and Yasuke will each learn a move from the other. Naoe will learn how to perform her own spectacular version of Yasuke's war kick ability, while Yasuke will learn how to dispatch enemies in a non-lethal, stealthy way.</p>



<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows, which Ubisoft <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-announces-imminent-closing-transaction-with-tencent-minority-stakeholder-vantage-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recently confirmed</a> has performed well so far, will launch next week on Nintendo Switch 2.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/recent-windows-update-caused-substantial-performance-drop-assassins-creed-shadows/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Creepy Horse Game Was Banned From Steam And No One’s Sure Why]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/horses-creepy-horror-game-steam-banned-before-launch-santa-ragione-2000647324</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-creepy-horse-game-was-banned-from-steam-and-no-one%E2%80%99s-sure-why.1364626/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Horses </em>is an upcoming narrative-driven horror game you’ve probably never heard of set to launch next month on the Epic Games Store, Humble Store, GOG, and Itch.io. But you won’t be able to find the creepy indie title on Steam, and the Italian studio behind <em>Horses</em> claims it doesn’t know why Valve is blocking the game from its PC storefront.</p> <p>On November 25, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/developer/santaragione/">indie studio Santa Ragione</a> published a trailer for Horses that revealed the game’s December 2 release date. However, it also sports an interesting badge at the end claiming the game has been banned from Steam. <a href="https://www.horses.wtf/BannedFromSteam/index.html">At the same time the trailer went live, the studio updated its website</a> to include a lengthy FAQ about <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/santaragione.com/post/3m6ht5yj3ss23"><em>Horses</em> being banned from Steam</a>. It claims Valve has provided little clarity on what’s going on and that the whole situation could result in developer Santa Ragione, which made <a href="https://kotaku.com/2022-goty-underrated-hidden-gems-best-games-1849936105">2023’s excellent <em>Saturnalia</em></a>, shutting down entirely.</p>

 <p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/unsettling-horror-game-horses-banned-from-steam-leaving-studio-with-high-risk-of-closure">Speaking with <em>IGN</em></a>, co-founder Pietro Righi Riva explained that in 2023, the studio submitted a request for a Steam Coming Soon page for <em>Horses</em>. However, Valve told the company to submit a playable build. “We were only about halfway through development and had scrambled together a build that could be played start to finish, solely to satisfy Steam’s request for a playable version to open a Coming Soon page, something we had never been asked for before,” Riva said. According to the studio, this is when Valve rejected <em>Horses</em> from being sold on Steam.</p>

  <p>But Santa Ragione was not told why <em>Horses</em> had been banned from Steam. The company’s FAQ claims Steam told the studio that <em>Horses</em> had been barred from the storefront because it found that it featured “<i>themes, imagery, or descriptions that [Steam] won’t distribute.”</i> The message also included a line that Valve won’t distribute games that contain content depicting “sexual conduct involving a minor” regardless of intention or if it is done in a “subtle way that could be defined as a ‘grey area.'”</p>

 <p>The studio called this explanation “deliberately vague and unfounded” and claimed that <em>Horses</em> does not contain any content that would fall into this so-called “grey area.” However, it did admit that initially a scenario in the game did involve a young kid riding on the shoulders of a naked woman in a mask, as horses in the game are depicted as naked people, but that scene has since been changed to remove the child.</p>

 <p>“Steam’s decision came without detailed feedback, and the ban notice did not cite any specific scenes or elements,” Riva told <em>IGN</em>. “For months, we repeatedly asked what triggered the ban and received no answer. We also offered, unsuccessfully, to change any content deemed unfit, especially since the game was still early in development at the time of submission.”</p>

 <p><em>Kotaku</em> contacted Valve, but didn’t hear back before publication.</p> <p>According to Santa Ragione, this ban has nothing to do with the ongoing and recent issues involving alleged pornographic games being removed from Steam due to bad-faith actors pressuring credit card companies and payment processors.</p>

 <p>Santa Ragione claims that <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-is-scary-humiliating-and-patronising-santa-ragione-facing-closure-after-horses-barred-from-steam"><em>Horses</em> not being able to launch on Steam</a> could make it very difficult for the company to recoup development costs, and the studio admits that it might shut down in the near future. The developer has set aside funds to support Horses for around six months after launch, but beyond that, it is unsure of what the future holds, as being banned from Steam will keep <em>Horses</em> away from “<span data-testid="content-text">more than 75 percent of the PC gaming market.”&nbsp;</span></p> <p><em>Horses</em> launches on basically every other PC gaming storefront besides Steam on December 4. It will cost $5.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/horses-creepy-horror-game-steam-banned-before-launch-santa-ragione-2000647324]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7 Ranked Play Release Period, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-ranked-play-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-7-ranked-play-release-period-explained.1364623/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Ranked Play is at the top of the wishlist for many of you. After all, it’s where the best of the best prove they are above the rest. Black Ops 7 Ranked Mode release details are coming your way.</p>



<p>Ranked is a staple of any recent Call of Duty release. Eventually, traditional lobbies can only offer so much competition, and there needs to be something to grind for—outside of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-multiplayer-camo-challenges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">multiplayer Camos</a>.</p>



<p>This is where Black Ops 7 and Ranked Mode go hand in hand.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-ranked-mode-coming-to-black-ops-7">When Is Ranked Mode Coming To Black Ops 7?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Party like it’s 2025. Credit to Activision</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>It’s been announced that Black Ops 7 is getting its long-awaited Ranked Mode in Season 2.</strong></p>



<p>This might come as disappointing news for those of you who want Ranked now. There are a few weeks to go until Ranked Play hits BLOPS 7. The devs have previously announced that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-black-ops-7-season-2-maps-have-already-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 2</a> will see the addition of Ranked Play for both of Activision’s main games: Black Ops 7 and Warzone.</p>



<p>You might be even more aggrieved to know that no one knows when in Season 2 it’s happening. It could be with the season’s launch, it could be midway through, or Treyarch could suddenly announce the day before.</p>



<p>Stay tuned for further updates and announcements on Ranked Play coming to Black Ops 7. If you don’t have it already, you can always use <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/black-ops-7-loaded-xbox-pc/">Insider Gaming to buy Black Ops 7 much cheaper</a>.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">For those asking, Treyarch has previously confirmed Ranked Play for both Black Ops 7 MP and Warzone will launch with Season 02.</p>— CharlieIntel (@charlieINTEL) <a href="https://twitter.com/charlieINTEL/status/1993029985452671461?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<h2 id="h-what-is-black-ops-7-ranked-play">What is Black Ops 7 Ranked Play?</h2>



<p><strong>Ranked Play is a competitive mode where your performances in Call of Duty matches determine your ranking, and good performances and wins are rewarded with skill points and promotions, whereas losing usually can result in demotions to inferior ranks.</strong></p>



<p>For example, in Black Ops 6, you had eight ranks to work your way through: Bronze, Silver, Gold, Platinum, Diamond, Crimson, Iridescent, and Top 250. Think of it like a worst-to-best scale. </p>



<p>It remains to be seen if Black Ops 7 adopts the same ranks, names, and divisions, but this is usually how it works. Furthermore, certain maps, weapons, and equipment are restricted in Ranked. Treyarch will inflict limitations on various aspects of Black Ops 7, meaning you need to be adaptable and prove your skill at will.</p>



<p>Reasons for this include meta weapons, to stop everyone from defaulting to them.</p>



<p>Is Ranked something that should launch with CoD on day one? Are you impatient for Ranked Play right now? Share your thoughts (and frustrations) via the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>You should also read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-sbmm-cod-creator-debunk-conspiracies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">COD’s SBMM Creator Debunking Black Ops 7 Conspiracy Theories</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/treyarch-making-big-changes-to-improve-black-ops-7-battle-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Treyarch Making Big Changes To “Improve” All Black Ops 7 Battle Passes</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-ranked-play-release/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2: Renegades expansion launch trailer, ‘Making of a Renegade’ video documentary]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/destiny-2-renegades-expansion-launch-trailer-making-of-a-renegade-video-documentary</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2-renegades-expansion-launch-trailer-%E2%80%98making-of-a-renegade%E2%80%99-video-documentary.1364620/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A new look ahead of the expansion's December 2 release.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Bungie [231 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/bungie">Bungie</a> has released the launch trailer and a new video documentary for the <em>Star Wars</em>-inspired <em><a title="Games > Destiny 2 [48 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/destiny-2">Destiny 2</a>: Renegades</em> expansion ahead of its December 2 release. <span id="more-1009343"></span></p><p>Here are the latest details:</p><blockquote><p>Today, <em>Destiny 2</em> developers hosted a dedicated Developer Live Stream for Renegades, the upcoming expansion in the Year of Prophecy, created in collaboration with <a title="Companies > Lucasfilm Games [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/lucasfilm-games">Lucasfilm Games</a> and inspired by <em>Star Wars</em>. To mark the expansion’s release next week on December 2, 2025, the team premiered the <em>Destiny 2: Renegades</em> launch trailer and a second ViDoc, “Making of a Renegade,” highlighting their creative process and collaboration with Lucasfilm Games to create an all-new <em>Destiny 2</em> experience with clear homage to <em>Star Wars</em>.</p><p>Renegades introduces an arsenal of new weapons and gear, including the Praxic Blade, <em>Destiny 2</em>‘s lightsaber-inspired kinetic Exotic Sword. This new weapon offers multiple customization paths that meaningfully impact gameplay, along with earnable cosmetics that alter the color of the blade. Renegades also debuts a new weapon archetype, Blasters, which features a heat-based firing and reload system that replaces traditional magazines.</p><p>New Exotics arriving with Renegades include:</p><ul><li><strong>Kinetic Sword</strong> – Praxic Blade (inspired by lightsabers)</li><li><strong>Solar Crossbow</strong> – Heirloom (inspired by Chewbacca’s iconic weapon)</li><li><strong>Strand Machine Gun</strong> – Service of Luzaku</li><li><strong>Warlock Helmet</strong> – Deimosuffusion</li><li><strong>Hunter Legs</strong> – Fortune’s Favor</li><li><strong>Titan Chest</strong> – Praxic Vestment</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>During the stream, members of the <em>Destiny 2</em> developer team dove deep into the Lawless Frontier, a new activity designed for replayability and scalable challenge. In Renegades, players build reputation with shady Syndicate factions through the new Notoriety system, taking on a range of solo or three-person missions commissioned by three distinct factions:</p><ul><li><strong>The Pikers</strong> – An anarchist and atheist biker gang of Eliksni seeking to build a society free from traditional ranks and hierarchy.</li><li><strong>Tharsis Reformation</strong> – A breakaway sect of sentient Vex, driven by a desire to experience personal identity outside the Vex collective.</li><li><strong>Totality Division</strong> – A rogue branch of the Barant Imperium Cabal, operating as a Syndicate on Mars and ruled by psions.</li></ul></blockquote><div id="carousel_1009348"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p>Job types include Smuggling runs to transport valuable goods between Syndicate facilities, Bounty Hunts that track and eliminate high-value targets, and Sabotage operations that disrupt rival Syndicate strongholds. Lawless Frontier features new maps set on Mars, <a title="Games > Europa [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/europa">Europa</a>, and Venus, expanding these destinations with fresh routes and combat spaces. The update also introduces the new Invasion mode, an opt-in feature which allows a Guardian to spawn into the playing field to disrupt progress and earn unique rewards.</p><p>Renegades Abilities are powerful tools that let Guardians bend the rules of combat within the Lawless Frontier mode. Guardians can earn, upgrade, and deploy a wide arsenal of offensive, defensive, and support abilities to enhance their abilities and role in battle.</p><p>The new dungeon, Equilibrium, launches on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20251213T1700" target="_blank" rel="noopener">December 13, 2025, at 9:00 a.m. PT / 12:00 p.m. ET</a>. Fans can tune into the official Equilibrium Dungeon Race stream with Evanf1997 and CBGray starting at <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20251213T1400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6:00 a.m. PT / 9:00 a.m. ET</a> with the pre-show until the race is completed. More information on the race can be found in the <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/Article/twid_11_20_2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This Week in <em>Destiny</em> blog</a>, and for full details on eligibility and requirements for the Equilibrium Dungeon Race, please visit <a href="https://help.bungie.net/hc/en-us/articles/43102" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bungie’s official rules</a>.</p><p><em>Destiny 2: Renegades</em> launches on December 2, 2025. Players can pre-order the Year of Prophecy Ultimate Edition, which includes both The Edge of <a title="Series > Fate [69 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a> and Renegades campaigns, The Desert Perpetual raid, and the upcoming dungeon. Pre-ordering Renegades through this edition instantly unlocks these bonus in-game rewards:</p><ul><li>Renegade Leader Exotic ship</li><li>Starside Introduction emblem</li><li>New Land Beyond Exotic Sniper Rifle with its ornament and catalyst</li><li>Dark Side Legends bundle</li><li>Enneachord Exotic Sparrow</li></ul><p>Players who already own the Renegades Standard Edition or the Year of Prophecy Standard Edition can upgrade to the Ultimate Edition, which grants access to all exclusive content and rewards included in the Year of Prophecy Ultimate Edition.</p></blockquote><p><em>Destiny 2</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,915 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,341 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,547 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,320 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,869 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1085660/Destiny_2/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch the footage and an archive of today’s developer live stream below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/destiny-2/november-25-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Destiny 2: Renegades | Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PqicEwg2qEc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>ViDoc: Making of a Renegade</span></h2><p><iframe title="Destiny 2: Renegades ViDoc | Making of a Renegade" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U_07pVzO5no?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Developer Live Steram</span></h2><p><iframe title="Destiny 2: Renegades Developer Livestream" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nrsypZ-P06o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/destiny-2-renegades-expansion-launch-trailer-making-of-a-renegade-video-documentary]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie Shares Deep Dive On Star Wars-Inspired Destiny 2: Renegades]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/11/25/bungie-shares-deep-dive-on-star-wars-inspired-destiny-2-renegades</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungie-shares-deep-dive-on-star-wars-inspired-destiny-2-renegades.1364617/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Bungie today offered a deep dive look at the new Destiny 2: Renegades release, which is scheduled to arrive for players next week, on December 2. The new major release for the game is an unusual one, as it’s rooted in a partnership with Star Wars. A quick look through the early visuals of the game don’t leave much room for doubt on that, as there are lots of things that look like lightsabers, stormtroopers, and villainous Sith.</p><p>But as today’s vidoc makes clear, Bungie is trying to thread a more nuanced line with this release that it first appears. While plenty of features may look like Star Wars, the team is going to great pains to make sure it remains a true and canon Destiny experience. Those aren’t lightsabers but rather Praxic Blades. Those aren’t stormtroopers but instead members of the surging Barant Imperium. And that’s not a Sith – it’s a dangerous new big bad named Dredgen Bael.</p>



<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="712a188f-967e-4d9d-92a1-a36a41cd3e1b" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.none_original_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
      

  
  
  
</article>

<p>Whether the developer can pull off keeping those distinctions or not will be a matter to decide once we can play the game, but the early descriptions and footage offer good reason to be excited.</p><p>The storyline appears to focus strongly on Drifter as a central character, acting as a conduit into some of the criminal underworld of the solar system. With his scoundrel demeanor, Drifter pretty clearly nods a bit toward characters like Han Solo in the Star Wars fiction.</p><p>We also get to know a character that has been mentioned in the past in written lore entries for Destiny. Aunor Mahal is about as close as the game is likely to have to a Jedi, with her Praxic Blade that she is using to fight against Dredgen Bael.</p><p>Players will pledge to a faction and build up reputation as they fight across the Lawless Frontier, an explorable space with a dedicated social hub in the form of Tharsis Outpost. Factions include the anarchist Eliksni biker gang called The Pikers, the group of sentient Vex call the Tharsis Reformation, and the rogue Cabal called Totality Division. You’ll run jobs for these factions like smuggling, bounty hunts, and sabotage-focused missions.</p>



<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="8fcc796f-e2d1-4bfb-b2a6-b7b81f64d478" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.none_original_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
      

  
  
  
</article>

<p>While Aunor is shown in some pretty slick lightsaber-esque battles, NPCs aren’t the only people getting fun new Star Wars-themed toys to play with. Players will also be able to wield Praxic Blades, and will even be able to try out different fighting styles, very much like a Jedi. With the exotic primary, kinetic Praxic Blade, you can deflect attacks, melee attack enemies, and even throw. And, just to set clear expectations, Bungie has shared that the Praxic Blade won’t be unique to this content drop; it will continue to be a relevant weapon in future expansions to the game.</p><p>Renegades also introduces new Blasters inspired by Star Wars, including several distinct variants, from dynamic blasters that hit harder with brute force, to more fast-firing balanced blasters. Blasters overheat and must cool down, rather than have a traditional magazine reload. We also learned about a special solar exotic crossbow called Heirloom, inspired by Chewbacca’s weapon in the movies.</p><p>Players will also be able to pick up different “renegade abilities,” that seem in some way to tie together with the faction you work for.</p><p>Across all the new content Bungie showed off today, one of the features that stood out the most was the music. By drawing direct inspiration from the Star Wars scores, arguably some of the most extensively varied and beloved of all film music, the new Destiny themes that were part of this preview presentation were, quite simply, riveting. The Renegades experience may be worth returning to play if only to hear more of that great music in action.</p><p>There's plenty more to learn in the complete rundown. Check out the full vidoc below to get a comprehensive look at what Bungie is cooking up. Destiny 2 continues its march into the future with Renegades on December 2.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U_07pVzO5no"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U_07pVzO5no" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/11/25/bungie-shares-deep-dive-on-star-wars-inspired-destiny-2-renegades]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yuji Horii On Final Fantasy: 'When I First Saw Final Fantasy X, I Recall Feeling This Was The Ultimate Perfection']]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2025/11/25/yuji-horiis-thoughts-on-the-differences-between-dragon-quest-and</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yuji-horii-on-final-fantasy-when-i-first-saw-final-fantasy-x-i-recall-feeling-this-was-the-ultimate-perfection.1364614/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Dragon Quest launched in Japan in 1986, and a little over a year later, Final Fantasy launched in 1987. Though the two are now sister RPG franchises at Square Enix, before the 2003 merger between Square and Enix, these series were competitors. And if you ask fans, they might use a word like rivals.&nbsp;</p><p>I traveled to Tokyo, Japan, last month to visit Square Enix's Shibuya offices, play <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</a>, and interview the team behind the remake for <a href="https://gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2025/10/21/cover-reveal-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined"><em>Game Informer's </em>latest cover story</a>. But as part of this trip, I interviewed Dragon Quest creator Yuji Horii for 90 minutes about all kinds of topics, including the aforementioned competition between his franchise and Final Fantasy. He didn't call it "competition," as I did, but admits, "I was definitely paying attention to it."&nbsp;</p>



<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="57adeabc-591e-458e-a27f-a3c2bb42cf1f" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="image:responsive_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;responsive_image_style&quot;:&quot;content_body&quot;,&quot;image_loading&quot;:{&quot;attribute&quot;:&quot;lazy&quot;},&quot;image_link&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
          <picture>
                  <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/body_default/public/2025/11/06/409245bd/dq1_screen.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 851px)" type="image/webp" width="800" height="450">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/11/06/409245bd/dq1_screen.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 315px) and (max-width: 450px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/11/06/409245bd/dq1_screen.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (max-width: 314px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
                  

  </picture>


  
  
  
</article>

<p>"Way back then, when Final Fantasy originally came out, I was definitely paying attention to it because it was something we needed to look out for," Horii tells me. "But there's one key difference that I really saw back then: the protagonists in the Final Fantasy titles, they speak a lot. Whereas for Dragon Quest, the key objective for [the games], or the experience it offers for the player, is that the player becomes the protagonist themselves.</p><p>"In Final Fantasy, you kind of observe the protagonist, but you're not necessarily becoming the protagonist in the games. So I thought that was a really interesting and stark difference between Dragon Quest and Final Fantasy, but I didn't necessarily see them as a rival back then."&nbsp;</p><p>Horii says in Dragon Quest, protagonists don't "just start talking on their own."&nbsp;</p><p>"Final Fantasy, again, [the protagonists] just talk a lot," he continues. "I do like Final Fantasy, though. When I first saw Final Fantasy X, I recall feeling this was the ultimate perfection of Final Fantasy."&nbsp;</p><p>Great taste, Horii.&nbsp;</p><hr><p>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined launches on February 5 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, Switch 2, Switch, and PC.</p><p>In the meantime, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/digital-issue/2025/11/04/the-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-digital-issue-is-now-live">check out this article</a> breaking down everything in the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2025/10/21/cover-reveal-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined issue of <em>Game Informer</em></a>, and be sure to <a href="https://gameinformer.com/subscribe">subscribe here</a> if you haven't yet to access the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/11/04/adventure-doesnt-wait">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined cover story</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/11/04/the-history-of-dragon-quest-as-told-by-creator-yuji-horii">our deep dive into Dragon Quest history</a> with creator Yuji Horii, and so much more.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2025/11/25/yuji-horiis-thoughts-on-the-differences-between-dragon-quest-and]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demonschool’s Credits Show Rest Of Games Industry How It’s Done]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/demonschool-credits-necrosoft-games-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demonschool%E2%80%99s-credits-show-rest-of-games-industry-how-it%E2%80%99s-done.1364611/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <p>It’s an <a href="https://aftermath.site/video-game-credits-battlefield/"><u>all too common story in the video game industry</u></a>: A developer spends months or years working on a game, the game comes out, and despite all the sleepless nights and stressful days, their name doesn’t even make the credits. Sometimes it’s the result of petty political squabbles; other times, companies are trying to quietly incentivize workers to stick around until a project’s completion, <a href="https://kotaku.com/how-game-companies-use-credits-to-reward-or-punish-de-1840905129?ref=aftermath.site"><u>even though they might be dissatisfied</u></a> with pay, crunch, or other conditions. Consider <em>Demonschool</em>, the newly released <em>Persona</em>-inspired tactics RPG from Necrosoft, a course correction.</p><p>Despite a relatively small core dev team, <em>Demonschool </em>lists all 145 people who contributed to it in any capacity over the course of its multi-year development cycle. Not only that, its credits explain, in an uncommon amount of detail, what each developer’s respective work on the project entailed. For example, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/brandon.insertcredit.com/post/3m6fuipkh4k2u?ref=aftermath.site"><u>the credits describe</u></a> Brent Porter, the game’s 3D art lead, as having done “most of the 3D modeling and rigging as well as creating most backgrounds. Also developed the lighting scheme and the visual style used in tiling and texture work. Created a number of the 2D battle and NPC sprites and visual effects, as well as preproduction concept art, including determining the final proportions of battle characters.”</p><p><em>Demonschool </em>director Brandon Sheffield told Aftermath that he’s been chewing on how to solve the crediting issue since the completion of Necrosoft’s last game, <em>Hyper Gunsport</em>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>“We worked [on <em>Hyper Gunsport</em>] with a localization company that refused to give the names of the people that actually did the work; they just wanted to have their company name in there,” Sheffield said. “They say they do that because ‘It's the standard’ and ‘to avoid poaching’ or whatever, but I hate that and think it's total BS. … I've also seen a lot of folks complain about how they weren't credited on a game because they'd left the studio before the game they worked on was finished. And indeed, our lead 3D artist left two years ago. But he's still the first artist credited because he set the style and visual tone for a lot of the game. Not working on the game to the very end doesn't negate the work he did.”</p><blockquote>"Our lead 3D artist left two years ago. But he's still the first artist credited because he set the style and visual tone for a lot of the game."</blockquote><p>The more Sheffield thought about how to meet the needs of so many different types of contributors – and discussed the matter on social media – the more a comprehensive, detail-oriented approach to crediting started to make sense.</p><p>“That had all been percolating in the back of my mind as we got close to finishing, and then it just sort of hit me as it came time for me to write the credits,” he said. “I discussed this approach with the team and everyone was fine with it, so we just went for it. We always want to credit everyone that touched the game, so even though the core team was 7 or 8 people at any given time, we credited around 145 people in <em>Demonschool</em>. Who cares if it's a lot of people? Who cares if it's long? They all did something and they deserve credit. And you basically can tell who the core team was by reading the descriptions. None of us are precious about that anyway.”</p><p>This resulted in some developers getting credited on an individual basis for the first time in their careers: “We made sure to ask every partner we worked with to give us every name of everybody who touched the game,” said Sheffield. “In the case of Bit Egg out of Thailand, they told me this was going to be the first actual credit for some of their staff.”</p><p>Sheffield hopes that providing greater detail than a simple title helps both players and prospective employers understand exactly what goes into a game’s development.</p><p>"We wanted to do this for a few reasons: One is that you don't usually know what a title means by itself,” he said. “Take ‘Artist.’ OK, what kind of art? What part of the game was that art in? It's useful for players to know that if they're interested in game development. But also say one of these people wants to get hired somewhere and is using <em>Demonschool </em>on their resume. Now everything they did is in the credits clear as day. ‘I created several of the enemy sprites and animations’ is more descriptive and useful than ‘I did some pixel art.’ And now what you've done is supported directly by the credits."</p><blockquote>“Take ‘Artist.’ OK, what kind of art? What part of the game was that art in? It's useful for players to know that if they're interested in game development."</blockquote><p>Sheffield is unsure if Necrosoft is the first studio to approach credits this way. He hopes someone else has at least done something similar. Regardless, he doesn’t think there’s anything <em>stopping </em>other studios from following in <em>Demonschool</em>’s footsteps – even if they wind up needing to credit substantially more people.&nbsp;</p><p>“I know in a Ubisoft game, something like this would be unwieldy, but maybe [if you did it] just for the core team of 300 or so?” Sheffield said. “If we can do this for 145 people to varying degrees of detail, a team with 100x the resources can do it for their core team of 300.”</p><p>So far, said Sheffield, the response to <em>Demonschool</em>’s credits has been exceedingly positive.</p><p>“I've mostly gotten responses from game developers saying they like how the credits are done, but I've seen a few things from players too – like ‘So that's what a game director does’ or generally just feeling like they're getting a look behind the scenes when they read this stuff,” said Sheffield. “A few people have asked questions in our Discord or Bluesky like ‘Who did all the art of the demon fish [in the fishing minigame]?’And other players can just answer them right away: ‘Oh, it's in the credits, that was Gustav Samuelson.’ I just think that's neat.”&nbsp;</p><h2 id="recommended">Recommended</h2><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/video-game-credits-battlefield/"><div><p>Everyone Who Worked On A Video Game Needs To Be In The Credits - Aftermath</p><p>I am once again asking you to respect people’s time and work</p><p><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure>
  </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/demonschool-credits-necrosoft-games-steam/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Glory Hunters (Game Boy) - A Glorious 8-Bit Throwback With Some Rough Edges]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/gameboy/glory-hunters</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-glory-hunters-game-boy-a-glorious-8-bit-throwback-with-some-rough-edges.1364593/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Glory Hunters Review - Screenshot 1 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/148295/large.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>We originally published this review in June 2024 with a note that we'd flag if the game ever came to Switch. Well, it did! Published by Ogre Pixel, Glory Hunters lands on Switch today with various extras, including artwork</em> and sketches, a markable world map, and a live performance soundtrack.</p>
<p><em>For this review, George played and captured screenshots on an Analogue Pocket.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>The release of GB Studio in 2019 has resulted in a flurry of games available for Nintendo’s lovely big brick over the last few years, but few have been as ambitious or as widely covered as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/glory_hunters">Glory Hunters</a> – the debut game of Mexico-based 2think design studio. Billed as "a unique Game Boy action-adventure RPG", Glory Hunters smashed its crowdfunding target on Kickstarter in 2022 and launched recently in both downloadable digital (via <a href="https://2think.itch.io/glory-hunters">itch.io</a>) and <a href="https://nintendolife.com/p/26837/167139" rel="sponsored noopener">physical form</a>, the latter coming courtesy of Bitmap Soft. But does it live up to the hype?</p>
<figure><a title="Glory Hunters Review - Screenshot 2 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/148297/large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>During the build-up, Glory Hunters was often likened to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/legend_of_zelda">The Legend of Zelda</a>, and right off the bat we see a large, celestial body (<em>not</em> a moon!) on a collision course with the land, followed by a positively <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/legend_of_zelda_the_wind_waker_hd">Wind Waker</a>-esque slideshow detailing an ancient tale - imploring a hero to rise up and summon a slumbering God to avert disaster.</p>
<p>But the similarities with Nintendo’s iconic franchise more or less end there. We’re thrust straight into the action. Sort of. We have a sword but there are no enemies, just some bushes and a path blocked by a suit of armour and a friendly little NPC, who lays out the premise that sets Glory Hunters apart from its forebears. The suit of armour is called a ‘Glory Knight’ and progression in the game is achieved through the collection of ‘Glory Points’ (GP) awarded by completing ‘glorious deeds’. We can use these to pay off the Glory Knights and open up new areas of the map. It’s a sort of levelling up, map expansion, and currency system rolled into one.</p>
<figure><a title="Glory Hunters Review - Screenshot 3 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/148290/large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>At an impasse and with little else to go on, we do what any action-adventure veteran would. We start chopping bushes. Once five bite the dust, a notification pops up - we’ve achieved a glorious feat (apparently) called ‘Cut Starter’ and have a shiny GP for our troubles. We could pay up and move on but instead we keep chopping, curious as to what’s necessary to further this achievement. In doing so we unearth, to our delight, a different feat by picking up a certain amount of item drops.</p>
<p>Learning by doing is something of a lost art in modern games but Glory Hunters excels at this. It knows the tropes — we’re going to read signposts, peer down a well, relentlessly chop grass — and it rewards us for it. But it also steers us effortlessly toward more obscure feats, drip-feeding points to encourage repetition and exploration, constantly fuelling the compulsion to keep probing and trying new things. It’s setting us up to understand the deal from the very beginning – everything in this world is transactional. Succinct tutorial over, we’re then free to explore the open world of Glorianta any way we want, constrained only by the number of points in our possession and armed with the knowledge that reaching one of its four corners will allow us to complete our quest.</p>
<figure><a title="Glory Hunters Review - Screenshot 4 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/148293/large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>Easier said than done. Glorianta is a behemoth. At a grid size of 17x19 it’s more than four times bigger than Link’s first pocket adventure - and just as gorgeous as Koholint, too. In fact, the whole visual and audio presentation of the game is sublime. The boss designs are a particular highlight and there are cute cutscenes scattered throughout the adventure. The different regions of the world have a strong sense of identity while the music underscores each area perfectly, thumping anthems akin to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/mega_man">Mega Man</a> power us through the overworld while cosy relief is provided as we bustle about towns meeting inhabitants. It’s never overbearing and most importantly, <em>very</em> hummable. It’s not all work either, with some excellent minigames dotted about to both waste time on and collect GPs. Double win!</p>
<p>Exploration is hampered by the fact that the overworld map is only accessible in said towns. With such a huge space to explore, it’s a little overwhelming not to have a reference point at our fingertips; fortunately, the enemies are varied enough in pattern and design and the puzzles and hidden secrets sufficiently engaging to keep exploration interesting – though it does chug a bit if there’s more than two foes on the screen.</p>
<p>Saving the game and replenishing health is also restricted to specific areas and for a game that relies on repetition to drive exploration, this can be a real problem. Remember those bushes we chopped down at the start of the game? We chopped them down <em>a hundred times</em>, then died before finding a save point, which meant chopping them down 100 times again. This was quite discouraging at times – particularly at the start of the quest.</p>
<figure><a title="Glory Hunters Review - Screenshot 5 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/148283/large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>Another gripe we have is death resulting in us being returned to the world with the amount of health we had at the last save point, instead of replenishing it. More than once we came through a hard stretch, saved, then faced a tough challenge or needed to go back and became locked into a pretty dire situation where advancing or retreating punished us over and over again.</p>
<p>Having said that, the balance of GPs earned/required is pretty well judged, with minimal amounts of grinding necessary to press on. But GPs are also used as a currency to upgrade your armour, sword, amount of health, or give hints, so you're playing a constant guessing game about spending without knowing if a big blockade of Glory Knights lay ahead that would require hard-earned GPs and if amassing more would be achievable or even enjoyable should that be the case.</p>
<p>Over time, our thinking adjusted to the idea of chasing points to bolster ourselves, instead of bolstering ourselves and then chasing points, but this involved a lot of backtracking and there were definitely times when we just wanted to get on with it. There’s a whole host of other collectibles which felt a little underused and we couldn’t help but think maybe those might have been better suited to the role of currency.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Glory Hunters is a package that has had a lot of love poured into it while remaining a little rough around the edges. We weren’t always sure when we were taking damage or even dishing it out – particularly when facing larger, noisier bosses, and some beats within the game felt a bit flat. Some translation quirks and grammatical errors also popped up, but these were never substantial enough to bother us (we actually thought they added a bit of charm to proceedings). <em>[Update: These have reportedly been addressed in the Switch version.]</em></p>
<p>All in all, Glorianta is a rich, deep world that is enjoyable to explore and successfully taps into nostalgia for Game Boy experiences while providing a fresh and interesting take on the formula. Proof, if there was ever any doubt, that there’s life in the old Boy yet.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/gameboy/glory-hunters]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/25/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-review.1364590/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>It’s pretty staggering just how consistent the <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/call-of-duty">Call of Duty</a> franchise has been over the last two decades. A new game every single year, bouncing back and forth between studios and sub-series, it’s remained at the top of the FPS genre for three console generations. But maybe that crown is slipping? Maybe we need to start thinking of them in terms of even and odd-numbered <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/star-trek">Star Trek</a> movies? <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/call-of-duty-black-ops-7">Black Ops 7</a> is not an even number…</p>
<p><iframe title="Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 | Launch Trailer (PC Features Spotlight) [UK]" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yX8T2nqPjno?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>Black Ops 7 Multiplayer</h2>
<p>Let’s start with the real heart of the Call of Duty franchise and Black Ops 7’s multiplayer. A year on from <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Black Ops 6</a>, and this is largely a continuation from <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/31/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-review/">the highs</a> of that game. You still have the omnidirectional movement that keeps everything fast and fluid, you still have the solid loadout system with perk synergies building to specialisations, and you’ve got plenty of maps that generally lean in on <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/treyarch">Treyarch</a>‘s strong lane-based design style.</p>


<p>Many of the maps also take advantage of the main addition to this year’s gameplay: wall-jumping. We’re far from the excesses of the jetpack era of Call of Duty, but this is a nice nod to those sci-fi infused titles, giving a little more verticality, a snifter of additional movement flexibility. Of course, the near-future setting means you’ve also got more turrets, robot DAWGs, active camo, and a killstreak that gives you a gun to shoot through walls – it’s feels filthy to see yourself get sniped like this on a deathcam, but compared to other killstreaks, it’s really no more or less lethal.</p>


<p>In general, the TTK does feel a little faster again, which combined with the speed of motion could be pushing this game out of your comfort zone, but if the 6v6 Call of Duty multiplayer is all you want in life, then Black Ops 7 has you covered. But what if you want something bigger, with vehicles and more tactical? No, please don’t leave! Uh, there’s the 20v20 Skirmish mode!</p>
<p>This tries to cover off that large-scale battle angle, with two big maps, vehicles and a rolling set of capture, destroy, takeover and escort objectives. If anything, it ramps the pace up even further, since you spawn high in the sky and can wingsuit to pretty much wherever you like on the map, even barrelling straight through windows and into objective zones. Far from being an antidote to <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a>, though, it’s all too often just madcap and finds itself in this no-man’s land between these rival franchises.</p>

<h2>The Co-op Campaign &amp; Endgame</h2>
<p>After the good, even great showings in the last two Black Ops games for their single player campaigns, Black Ops 7 is a major misstep. We’re jumping ahead from the Cold War and Gulf War to a decade after the events of Black Ops 2 and returning to David Mason and his team. The story tugs on narrative threads from across the series, mixing in the Cradle from Black Ops 6 for a twisted sci-fi psychological thriller. Except it’s just not even remotely thrilling.</p>

<p>The campaign bounces back and forth between sections set in the open world map of Avalon, which is filled with bland human and robot soldiers for The Guild, and then nightmare reimaginings of events from each character’s past. That means revisiting plot points from Black Ops 2, such as a version of the Battle for LA with roads twisting through the air all Inception-style, or fighting a giant version of Harper on the deck of an aircraft carrier, but it even goes back to fighting zombies in a rerun of the Vorkuta prison break.</p>
<p>I’m all for Call of Duty experimenting with the format of the campaign, and the Black Ops series has done this more often than not, with narrative branches, side missions, hubs, and more. Black Ops 7 just misses the mark, from enemies having health bars, to not having AI buddies when playing solo, and just how bland The Guild are as enemies and how rote the horror monsters are.</p>

<p>It soon becomes clear that this was, in part, about leading into the Endgame co-op mode, taking the template from Modern Warfare III’s Zombies in a different thematic direction. This gives you the full map of Avalon to play in as an extraction shooter, gating areas behind the level and gear of your chosen Operator, doling out missions and then having you get out safely with everything you’ve found.</p>
<p>It’s purely PvE, with dozens of other players able to team up on the fly and take on the higher-level missions and scenarios, and there’s some fun Cradle effects, like a random little game of prop hunt. But it’s really not exciting building up to the end of the Endgame events, as you’re largely fighting against fairly boring enemies and completing basic missions. There’s also the tonal whiplash you felt throughout the campaign, as zombies and other fantastical elements are thrown in for the heck of it.</p>
<h2>Black Ops 7 Zombies</h2>
<p>The more traditional home of co-op in Call of Duty is its Zombies mode, with Black Ops 7 picking up the convoluted Dark Aether narrative from last year’s game. The Ashes of the Damned map is huge, with six key areas to reach and explore, joined up by a bunch of roads and other smaller points of interest shrouded in The Fog. It’s big enough, in fact, that you need to hop into a pick-up truck –&nbsp;nicknamed Ol’ Tessie –&nbsp;to get around. She’s a battered workhorse of a truck, able to smash through hordes of zombies, but only for a limited time before she takes too much damage and needs repairs. Later upgrades, though, put a mean turret on top and Abomination Heads that can blast streams of zombie-frying lightning.</p>

<p>The problem with this, of course, is that it means your co-op party really needs to be on the same page. Anyone can jump into the truck and just drive off, leaving others with a sprint through the danger-filled Fog, unless they happen to be at the garage in the Ashwood area, where you can summon Tessie back or teleport to her for a fee. You really want to play this mode with friends and voice chat, especially if you’re trying to follow the Easter Egg story path.</p>
<p>Thankfully, there’s other ways to play. If you prefer the classic Zombies feel, you can play Cursed mode and start off with just a pistol, while a Directed mode for the main quest is coming soon. There’s also a pure Survival mode, which takes the Farmyard section of Ashes of the Damned, and simply gives you waves to battle through. No frills, no nonsense, just classic Zombies on a pretty confined map, and since I’m really not invested in the story, it’s really my preferred way to play this mode.</p>

<p>There’s also the return of Dead Ops Arcade, the top-down zombie shooter which puts over-the-top weaponry in your hands at every opportunity and progresses through a nonsensical quest with apes and chickens. You can actually play it in first person the whole time now, and some power-ups will still switch you to this view anyway. There’s tons of rooms to battle through, tons of excess, and it’s easy to slide into, but it doesn’t really feel novel anymore. Dead Ops Arcade was a secret mode for a secret mode just as indie games and retro aesthetics were coming into their own in the early 2010s, but 15 years later and the indie scene has moved on to explore many more genres, mash-ups and riff on these ideas in more engaging ways.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/25/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Steam Deck Accessories 2025: Holiday Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-steam-deck-accessories-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-steam-deck-accessories-2025-holiday-guide.1364584/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Since releasing in February 2022, Valve’s Steam Deck has become the most popular gaming handheld on the market. One of the first accessible ways to play your PC games on the go, the Steam Deck is close to being a perfect device for many, but there are some ways it can improve. One way specifically that you can make your Steam Deck experience better is with some accessories and add-ons.</p>



<p>Whether you want to protect it, upgrade the comfort, or just get more out of the device, there are tons of great accessories available. Some are even on the more affordable side, as well. These are the best Steam Deck accessories available for the 2025 holidays.</p>



<p>Below, you’ll find a list of the best options available today, from protective shells and screen protectors to docking stations and thumb grips. Everything here is compatible with both the Steam Deck LCD and OLED models. If you want to get more out of your handheld, these are the accessories worth checking out this year.</p>







<h2 id="h-the-best-steam-deck-accessories-for-2025">The Best Steam Deck Accessories For 2025</h2>



<p><strong>JSAUX PC0104 Shell Case</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The first Steam Deck accessory to check out is one that brings durability to the handheld. This shell case from not only protects it when in use, but it comes with a full shell cover for transportation that protects the screen, joysticks and face buttons. There’s even a kickstand for those that want to plug it in simply via the USB-C port and a strap if you want to attach a power bank. It’s <strong>available for $23.99 for the holidays</strong>, and costs $30 throughout the year.</p>







<hr>



<p><strong>Syntech Soft Case</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>When shopping for a case, sometimes you want something practical. This case will cost you <strong>less than $25</strong>, and goes around the entire Steam Deck without adding too much bulk. It doesn’t interfere with any of the buttons and sits as snug as any chase you’ll find—it’s been used by senior editor Mike Straw for a few months now, actually. </p>







<hr>



<p><strong>Cooling Fan</strong></p>



<figure></figure>







<p>If you feel like the Steam Deck runs a little too warm, there are options to keep it on the cooler side. One option comes from JSUAX. This cooling fan snaps right on and helps with overall circulation. It even has a kick stand, allowing you to set it up nicely on your table or desk. If it’s something you’re interested in, you can pick it up <strong>for $30 on sale</strong>, or <strong>$40 at regular price. </strong></p>











<hr>



<p><strong>Back Button Enhancements</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Feel like your fingers slip off the back panel buttons? These rubber grips come in two different sizes to make the buttons feel thicker on the fingers and avoid any possible slip or mis-click. Currently they are <strong>on sale for $12</strong>, but regularly run <strong>about $14.</strong></p>







<hr>



<p><strong>Thumb Grips</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Sometimes the grip on the handheld isn’t what you want it. These Skull &amp; Co thumb grips come with three styles in a pack to help match your preference. They are <strong>available for $10</strong>.</p>







<hr>



<p><strong>IVANKY Docking Station</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>There are a lot of docking stations for the Steam Deck, but this one might be one of the best. It features a USB-c connection that goes to the device while the dock itself has HDMI 2.1 output that supports up to 4K@144Hz, three USB-A 3.0 ports, a 1GB Ethernet port, and a rapid-charging USB-C port to keep your device fully juiced. It’s normally $39.99, but you can<strong> buy it now for $28.</strong></p>











<hr>



<p><strong>PlayVital Rubber Pads</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Want to add some style to your Steam Deck while improving functionality? These rubber pads come in different varieties and not only look great, but they give you added grip as well. <strong>For less than $15</strong> you can get designs ranging from basic black hexagons to waves and space. </p>







<hr>



<p><strong><strong>Sony INZONE E9 Wired In-Ear Monitor</strong></strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Sony built these IEMs specifically for competitive gaming, so they’re all about clean, accurate sound and great positional audio. They’re lightweight, block out noise surprisingly well, and come with a small USB-C DAC that lets you tweak EQ and surround settings through the INZONE software. If you want gaming headset-level detail without wearing a bulky headset, these are a fantastic pick.</p>



<p>One underrated feature of the earbuds is just how good they are at blocking out the outside noise. It’s absolutely perfect when on a long flight that happens to have children on it that are a little bit upset. That alone is worth <strong>the $149.99</strong> price point.</p>







<hr>



<p><strong>Screen Protecto</strong>r</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>With any portable device, the last thing you want to do is damage the screen. These tempered glass screen protectors cover the screen from edge to edge and protect both the LCD and OLED models. The best part is that you can still use the touch screen despite the thickness. Right now, a <strong>two-pack is $10</strong>, but you can often find it for <strong>as low as $8</strong>.</p>







<hr>



<p><strong>Samsung PRO Plus microSD</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>For those on the go that need more space in their Steam Deck, the Samsung PRO Plus microSD is one of the best cards on the market without completely breaking the bank. This card offers read/write speeds up to around 180 MB/s for reading and 130 MB/s writing. The card starts at <strong>$26.99</strong> for 256GB but is also available in 512 GB for<strong> $49.99</strong> and <strong>$79.99</strong> for 1TB.</p>







<hr>



<p>Are there any accessories for the Steam Deck that stands out to you that you may pick up this year? Leave your picks down in the comments and join us over at the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<p><em><strong>NOTE:</strong>&nbsp;Insider Gaming may earn affiliate commission if you purchase items through links on Insider Gaming. Read more about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/privacy-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">affiliate commission here</a>.</em></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/best-steam-deck-accessories-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Black Ops 7 Update Adds Disconnect Protection For Endgame]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-update-adds-disconnect-protection-for-endgame/1100-6536513/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-black-ops-7-update-adds-disconnect-protection-for-endgame.1364578/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536513">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/" data-ref-id="5000-681591">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a> received a small update on November 25, and the patch notes revealed a much-needed fix for the campaign's Endgame mode. The update added a new protection for disconnects that previously caused players to lose all of their progress in the mode.</p><p dir="ltr">Black Ops 7's Endgame works much like the high-risk/high-reward structure of extraction-style shooters. Players grind matches of Endgame to level up their characters' abilities and combat rating, and failing to successfully extract from the map means they lose everything. Unfortunately, players were losing everything to random disconnects and game crashes as well.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1757491423" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466537,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Call%20of%20Duty%3A%20Black%20Ops%207%20-%20Nuketown%202025%20Gameplay%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:88,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-nuketown-2025-gameplay-trailer\/2300-6466537\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466537\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466537\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466537\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466537&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466537,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536513&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty-black-ops-7&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,pc,playstation-5,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;activision,microsoft&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466537},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466537\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4607268-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/7km9zOUj.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1763579100,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="7km9zOUj" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 - Nuketown 2025 Gameplay Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Treyarch said it heard the feedback from players, and the new update adds a disconnect protection. Now when players drop into matches of Endgame, the game snapshots the player's Combat Rating at the start of the match. This means players will keep their progress that was snapshotted at the start of the match even if a disconnect or crash occurs.</p><p dir="ltr">"We're exploring additional and more robust forms of disconnect protection and will look to share more in the future," the developer said.</p><p dir="ltr">The full patch notes can be found below, <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/patchnotes/2025/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-preseason-patch-notes" rel="nofollow ">as shared by Activision</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">This update arrives ahead of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-black-ops-7-and-warzone-season-1-adds-more-maps-weapons-and-warzone-integration/2900-7281/#2">Call of Duty Season 1</a>, which adds new world events to Endgame. Treyarch has confirmed the zombie T-Rex from Black Ops 6 and the giant Origins robot from Black Ops 2 Zombies as new boss battles for Endgame.</p><p dir="ltr">Season 1 of Black Ops 7 and Warzone arrives on December 4. The update is packed with new content, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-black-ops-7-and-warzone-season-1-weapons-and-how-to-unlock-them/2900-7284/#1">seven new weapons</a> to unlock, more maps, seasonal events, and Black Ops 7's integration into Warzone.</p><h2>CO-OP CAMPAIGN / ENDGAME</h2><h3>Disconnect Protection</h3><p>We’re thrilled with the response to Endgame so far and have enjoyed watching new players deploy to Avalon to explore, complete quests, and begin the journey toward the Genesis Mastery Camo. We’ve also seen the feedback: disconnect / crash protections are needed to help protect your Combat Rating.</p><p>So, now when you deploy to Avalon, we'll snapshot your Combat Rating at the start of the match. Earn progress and extract to grow your Combat Rating; fall in combat or fail to escape, and you'll lose it all. However, in the event that a disconnect does occur, you'll now begin your next match at the Combat Rating that you entered your previous match in to continue back on your path of reaching CR 60.</p><p>We’re exploring additional and more robust forms of disconnect protection and will look to share more in the future. Until then, keep growing your Combat Rating and get ready for World Events coming in Season 01.</p><ul><li>A new Disconnect Protection mechanic has been added to Endgame.  <ul><li>Players who deploy to Avalon in Endgame will have their initial Combat Rating snapshotted at the start of the match. Players who disconnect will be able to start their next match at that previous Combat Rating.</li></ul></li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-update-adds-disconnect-protection-for-endgame/1100-6536513/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subnautica 2 Voices from Beyond first episode released]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/25/subnautica-2-voices-from-beyond-first-episode-released/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/subnautica-2-voices-from-beyond-first-episode-released.1364560/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The first episode for Subnautica 2’s tie in audio drama Voices from Beyond is now available to listen to, and this episode is called Don’t Fear. The Voices from Beyond story follows a family from the universe who are settled in a Mongolian settlement, as they work out how to live in a constantly shifting world unaware there is a big threat hurtling towards them.</p>
<p><iframe title="Subnautica 2 | Voices from Beyond - Don’t Fear (Episode #1) ????️" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9On9vY7bJNM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Subnautica 2 Voices from Beyond stars Griffin Puata as the Dad/Mongolian Politician, Hester Lee as Mom/Alterra Engineer, Jessika Van as the Daughter/Singer, Nell Barnes as Baby/Young Daughter, Dan Gordon as Ryley Robinson/Podcast Host, Emily O’Brien as Radio News Host #1 / PSA Announcer / Admiral Rathine Studaber, and Townsend Coleman as Radio News Host #2 / Alterra Advertiser.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/10/subnautica-2-delayed-to-2026-just-a-week-after-krafton-fired-studio-co-founders/">Subnautica 2 early access was delayed to 2026</a>, a few months ago with lots of drama surrounding the studio and the game. Krafton replaced the co-founders and leaders of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/subnautica-2">Subnautica 2</a> developer Unknown Worlds. Krafton accused studio founders Charlie Cleveland and Max McGuire of effectively abandoning <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/subnautica-2">Subnautica 2’s</a>&nbsp;development to focus on other projects – including&nbsp;<a href="https://www.abyssal.co/nutmeg-mistletoe">an independent movie by Cleveland with a podcast and… uh… AI-generated movie posters</a> – despite repeated requests by Krafton for them to return to work. But in another twist, &nbsp;Jason Schreier suggested that along with the Christmas film, Cleveland was also working on a Subnautica film for Krafton. “In the lawsuit, they argue that Krafton was aware of their roles and that Cleveland was working on a Subnautica film — that Krafton requested.”</p>

<p>All of this has ended up with Charlie Cleveland and Max McGuire suing Krafton, with new allegations that the Krafton CEO used ChatGPT to find ways to avoid paying a £250 million bonus, and also discussed a company takeover in Slack. It will be a little while before we know the final outcome of the court case.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9On9vY7bJNM">Subnautica 2 | Voices from Beyond – Don’t Fear (Episode #1)</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/25/subnautica-2-voices-from-beyond-first-episode-released/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Goodbye Volcano High Developer KO_OP Shadow-Drops New Game, Young Suns, In Early Access on Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/goodbye-volcano-high-developer-ko-op-shadow-drops-young-suns-xbox-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/goodbye-volcano-high-developer-ko_op-shadow-drops-new-game-young-suns-in-early-access-on-xbox.1364557/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>KO_OP, the studio behind <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/goodbye-volcano-high/">2023's Goodbye Volcano High</a>, has just revealed and released its latest game, Young Suns. The new title is an early access release that's been shadow-dropped on Xbox Game Pass as a Game Preview title, though it'll arrive on other platforms at some point in the future.</p>



<p>Like Goodbye Volcano High before it, Young Suns is a narrative-driven game, though this time it is a 1-4 player narrative sim that takes place in space, in a distant future where you step into the space boots of Sundog, one of the last remaining ship owners following a revolt that drove back a predatory corporation.</p>



<p>Now, with the people of Jupiter recently freed, you have to step up to try and build the better world they all just got done fighting for, and meet the 30 "<em>full realized</em>" characters to learn what problems they're dealing with and how you can help them.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Young Suns Reveal &amp; Presentation" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rVEWbp1FiKg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>On the game's <a href="https://www.youngsuns.com/roadmap">official website</a>, on its roadmap, KO_OP says it'll focus on new features like character and friendship tracking, an overhaul of the workbench, new cosmetic items like clothing and furniture, and, of course, bug and balance fixes. </p>



<p>Releases on new platforms like Steam, which is currently the only other platform we know it'll be coming to, as there's no word on a PlayStation or Nintendo release, are left for the "<em>In the future"</em> section of the roadmap.</p>



<p>Ahead of that, even more features, like introducing wildlife on the planets you explore, mini games, new story quests, and a photo mode, are currently planned to arrive shortly after the initial friendship tracking and workbench updates.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/goodbye-volcano-high-developer-ko-op-shadow-drops-young-suns-xbox-game-pass/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Goes Beyond Laptop Deals, MS Office Pro 2021 Lifetime License Is Nearly Free at 90% Off for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/act-fast-to-snag-the-microsoft-office-professional-2021-at-a-180-discount-at-stacksocial-today-2000647013</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-goes-beyond-laptop-deals-ms-office-pro-2021-lifetime-license-is-nearly-free-at-90-off-for-black-friday.1364551/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Top tech, kitchen appliances, outdoor gear, and games aren’t the only things going for less during Black Friday and Cyber Monday. It’s also a great time to grab some useful subscriptions and software for less. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/">StackSocial has dropped the price of Microsoft Office Professional 2021 for Windows to just $35, after a massive 84% discount.</a> It’s a lifetime license, so you won’t have to worry about paying an additional monthly or yearly fee after your purchase, ever.</p>
<p>It’s one of the many early Black Friday deals by the retailer, but it’s selling out fast. At the time of writing, over 20,000 licenses have been sold at the discounted rate. We don’t know how long it’s going to stay around, so it’s best to grab it quickly.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at StackSocial</a></p>

<h2>Instant Access to All the Essential Programs</h2>
<p>It’s more of a one-and-done purchase. You’re going to receive access to your software license keys and download links instantly after you complete your purchase. The code needs to be redeemed within 7 days, or it’s going to expire. The licensing type will be connected with your actual device and not your Microsoft account, so you won’t exactly be able to transfer it across multiple machines.</p>
<p>There are some system requirements you need to know about. It runs on Windows 10 and 11, and doesn’t support older systems like Windows 7 or 8. The retailers recommend installing it on a device with at least 16 GB of RAM, plus having 4GB of available storage and a screen resolution of at least 1280×800. Most standard PCs already have these built in, but we still suggest peeking at your system settings before you proceed.</p>
<p>Once installed, you’ll have access to the full Microsoft Office Professional 2021 suite. This includes Microsoft Office Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Outlook. Whether you’re someone who needs to write a bunch of documents or create long, never-ending spreadsheets at work, it’s all covered. PowerPoint lets you create stunning, professional-level presentations with a whole bunch of useful tools built right in. Accessing your emails and communicating with the team will be just as easy with Outlook. You can even use it to manage your everyday calendar and stay on top of your tasks for better productivity throughout the day.</p>



<p>Support for Teams (free version) lets you take meetings on the go. Students will appreciate OneNote, a program that makes it both fun and easy to take notes, mark documents, create diagrams, and organize everything into different categories. Publisher and Access are available, too. The former can be used to develop your very own publications, while the latter is great for creating databases and automating tasks. The entire suite is great for work professionals looking to manage tasks better, students wanting to study more efficiently, creatives who need to organize their workflows, and even casual users who want to enjoy better efficiency.</p>
<p>This isn’t the latest version of Microsoft Office, but it still delivers all the basic features you can possibly need to get through your busy, demanding days. Just note that it does not work like Microsoft 365, so you won’t get access to cloud-based storage or features like real-time collaboration. It’s more suited for solo, offline use.</p>
<p>On a regular day, this Microsoft Office Professional 2021 for Windows license would set you back around $220. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/">The current deal takes $180 off and offers it for just $35, which is practically nothing for the convenience it brings.</a> You also don’t have to worry about entering any long coupon codes or following complicated checkout processes to score the drop. Just add it to your cart, receive the credentials, and follow the suggested steps to complete the process.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at StackSocial</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/act-fast-to-snag-the-microsoft-office-professional-2021-at-a-180-discount-at-stacksocial-today-2000647013]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HORSES launches December 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/horses-launches-december-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horses-launches-december-2.1364548/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>First-person horror adventure from Santa Ragione.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>First-person <a title="Genres > Horror [774 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,721 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > HORSES" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/horses">HORSES</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,869 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/horses-004d87" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/horses" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOG</a>, <a href="https://santaragione.itch.io/horses" target="_blank" rel="noopener">itch.io</a>, and <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com/store/horses" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Humble Store</a> on December 2, developer <a title="Companies > Santa Ragione [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/santa-ragione">Santa Ragione</a> announced. It will not be available on Steam, as the game was <a href="https://www.horses.wtf/BannedFromSteam/index.html" target="_blank">banned from the platform</a> without a detailed explanation by <a title="Companies > Valve [202 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/valve">Valve</a>. <span id="more-1009338"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Santa Ragione:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>An enigmatic first-person horror adventure that blurs the line between reality and the darkest corners of your imagination. Fourteen days, a horse farm, and a few rules to follow.</p><p>Take a break from your college coursework and spend the summer helping out on a secluded farm.</p><p>The air is warm, the horses are quiet, and the people are down-to-earth. Each day brings new tasks, and the work itself is simple, even if the goals are a little unclear. Sometimes, after the sun sets on a productive day, there are even activities to be found in the evenings.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Over the course of fourteen days, it welcomes you into encounters that test your obedience, complicity, and restraint.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Immerse yourself in the eerie fusion of gameplay and full-motion video intermissions.</li><li>Witness the farm’s unspeakable horrors through daily unique interactions.</li><li>Heed the farmer’s warnings or face consequences (?)</li><li>Withstand 14 days of spiraling dread as the reality of the farm unfolds.</li><li>A full playthrough lasts three to four hours.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="HORSES Launch Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JYewjNYxV-8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/horses-launches-december-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Expedition 33 Actor Says He's "Truly Grateful" For Outpouring Of Support After Charlie Cox Spoke Out]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/expedition-33-actor-says-hes-truly-grateful-for-outpouring-of-support-after-charlie-cox-spoke-out/1100-6536509/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/expedition-33-actor-says-hes-truly-grateful-for-outpouring-of-support-after-charlie-cox-spoke-out.1364542/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536509">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Recently, actor Charlie Cox <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/expedition-33-star-reacts-to-tga-nomination-says-he-doesnt-deserve-all-the-credit/1100-6536464/" data-ref-id="1100-6536464">reacted to his nomination for Best Performance in Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> by saying the credit should also be shared with the performance-capture actor, Maxence Cazoria. Now, Cazoria has <a href="https://x.com/maxence_cazorla/status/1993339680608465405?s=46" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said</a> he's receiving an outpouring of support after Cox spoke up, saying what Cox said about him was "incredibly generous."</p><p>"Thank you for all the messages these past few days. Charlie's words were incredibly generous, and I'm truly grateful," Cazoria said. "Bringing Gustave to life was a team effort, and I'm honored to have played my part in it. Thank you all so much for the love and support. Tomorrow comes."</p><p>Cox said he was "thrilled" to be nominated, adding that Cazoria should get the credit. "I believe the performance of that character is really down to him and my voice was just a part of that process," he said.</p><p>Cox was nominated for Best Performance alongside two other Expedition 33 actors, including Ben Starr and Jennifer English. Erika Ishii was nominated for Ghost of Yotei, Konatsu Kato for Silent Hill f, and Troy Baker for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle.</p><p>The Best Performance award is not just for voice-acting, as it also includes motion- and/or performance-capture. Given that, it would appear that Cazoria would have been eligible, too.</p><p>Expedition 33 led all others this year with 12 total nominations, including a nod for Game of the Year. With 12 nominations, that makes it the most-nominated game in the history of The Game Awards.</p><p>The Game Awards take place on Thursday, December 11, but it's expected there there will be teases ahead of that, so keep checking back with GameSpot for the latest.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/expedition-33-actor-says-hes-truly-grateful-for-outpouring-of-support-after-charlie-cox-spoke-out/1100-6536509/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earliest Known Super Mario Bros. Cartridge to Go Up for Charity Auction Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/earliest-known-super-mario-bros-cartridge-auction</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/earliest-known-super-mario-bros-cartridge-to-go-up-for-charity-auction-next-month.1364518/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The earliest known cartridge copy of&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros.</em>, which may also be the iconic platformer's master copy, is going up for auction next month, with the proceeds entirely going to benefit a major gaming preservation charity.</p>

<p>Auction house <a href="https://www.christies.com/en/lot/lot-6566468" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Christie's</a> will play host to the auction, in which a 1985-era&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros.&nbsp;</em>cartridge will be up for grabs. The price will be pretty steep, though; Christie's estimates the cart will cost you somewhere in the region of £100,000 to £150,000 (about $130,000 to $200,000).</p>

<p>The auction is being held to benefit the Video Game History Foundation (VGHF), a charity organization that's involved with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/simcity-nes-prototype-digitized-and-dissected-by-video-game-history-foundation" rel="nofollow">preserving</a> some of the most <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/video-game-history-foundation-computer-entertainer" rel="nofollow">important</a> (and esoteric!) artifacts from throughout gaming history.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/super-mario-bros-cartridge-auction-shot.jpg?itok=5q1pvI1f 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/super-mario-bros-cartridge-auction-shot.jpg?itok=SeT4JrqA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>It may not look like much, but this could be the master copy of&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>The Video Game History Foundation says that this cartridge was created at Nintendo before mass production on&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros.&nbsp;</em>began, and that while the charity can't be certain, "it is possible that this was the original master copy of the game", i.e. the one on which all retail copies were based.</p>

<p>Of course, given the cartridge's age, it's possible that the game wouldn't work if you were to slot it into a Famicom console, but I don't suppose anyone picking this up will be buying it so they can play&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros.</em>; it's more of a collector's item.</p>

<p>This is far from the first&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros.</em>-related retro gaming auction. During 2021 alone, two&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros.&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/super-mario-bros-sells-for-over-600k-at-auction" rel="nofollow">cartridges</a> sold for eye-watering <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/super-mario-bros-copy-sells-for-record-breaking-price" rel="nofollow">amounts</a>, and other games in the franchise have <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/super-mario-bros-3-most-expensive-game-ever-sold" rel="nofollow">commanded incredible prices</a> at auction as well.</p>

<p>As for&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros.&nbsp;</em>itself, well, the game needs no introduction; as the Christie's lot essay for the above cartridge says, it's "the most influential video game of all time", or at least a strong contender for that title.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/super-mario-bros.-wonder-charity-auction-original-game.jpg?itok=BKtxOInJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/super-mario-bros.-wonder-charity-auction-original-game.jpg?itok=9XclmwQg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros.&nbsp;</em>franchise is still going strong today.</figcaption></figure><p>If you'd like to bid for what may very well be the&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros.&nbsp;</em>master copy, bidding begins via the Christie's website on December 11th. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/earliest-known-super-mario-bros-cartridge-auction]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Python Commandos Warbond Brings a Minigun and More Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/helldivers-2-python-commandos-warbond</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-python-commandos-warbond-brings-a-minigun-and-more-next-week.1364515/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Arrowhead and Sony have announced Python Commandos, a brand new&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2&nbsp;</em>Warbond, and it's bringing an honest-to-god minigun and more next week.</p>

<p>As revealed in a new PlayStation Blog <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/11/25/helldivers-2-python-commandos-premium-warbond-airdrops-dec-2/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a>, Python Commandos launches on December 2nd (that's next Tuesday at time of writing), and as has been the case with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/helldivers-2-control-group-warbond" rel="nofollow">previous</a>&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/helldivers-2-force-of-law-warbond" rel="nofollow">Warbonds</a>, you can expect new weapons, new armor, and new emotes to bring with you into the field.</p>

<p>First off, the M-1000 Maxigun is a belt-fed, ultra-high-capacity minigun that should let you tear through bugs, bots, and whatever else gets in your way with aplomb. Just try not to turn it on your teammates.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/helldivers-2-python-commandos-warbond-minigun.jpg?itok=Z7NgMf0G 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/helldivers-2-python-commandos-warbond-minigun.jpg?itok=Uhnai22j 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Helldivers 2</em>'s new Warbond has a minigun for you to lay waste to your enemies with.</figcaption></figure><p>A new Guard Dog drone equipped with a flamethrower is also being added, but once again, you'll need to make sure it doesn't accidentally set your teammates on fire (or perhaps they'll need to make sure they're not in its way).</p>

<p>Hacking your way through&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2</em>'s jungles just got a lot easier, too, as the aptly-named CQC-9 Defoliation Tool (which, yes, is basically a machete) can cut through everything, be it brush, bugs, or, uh, buddies.</p>

<p>You can also get to grips with a brand new primary weapon in Python Commandos, namely the AR/GL-21 One-Two, a "combination assault rifle and grenade launcher" that lets you switch between these two modes depending on what you need.</p>

<p>All of this is, of course, in addition to brand new armor sets with a passive that makes your Helldiver harder to ragdoll, as well as two new capes, a new emote, and a brand new camo pattern for your gear.</p>




<p>You'll be able to get your hands on <i>Helldivers 2</i>'s Python Commandos Warbond when it arrives across all platforms on December 2nd. The game is available right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/553850/HELLDIVERS_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/helldivers-2/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/helldivers-2" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and you can read our <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/helldivers-2-review-fighting-for-managed-democracy" rel="nofollow">review right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/helldivers-2-python-commandos-warbond]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Predicting Steam Machine prices would be a lot easier if RAM costs hadn't gone horribly wrong]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/predicting-steam-machine-prices-would-be-a-lot-easier-if-ram-costs-hadnt-gone-horribly-wrong</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/predicting-steam-machine-prices-would-be-a-lot-easier-if-ram-costs-hadnt-gone-horribly-wrong.1364512/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Memory shortages chuck a grenade into PC and console production</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Machine-wood-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Machine-wood-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Machine-wood-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Machine-wood-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Machine-wood-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Machine-wood-1.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Machine-wood-1.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Machine-wood-1.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Machine-wood-1.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>This week’s most popular game is not a robovoiced extraction shooter or a buggy martial arts RPG, but Guess The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hands-on-with-the-new-steam-machine-valves-square-shot-at-steamos-pc-redemption">Steam Machine</a> Price: a well-meaning (if largely speculative) timepasser wherein whoever most accurately converts <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-confirm-the-steam-machine-will-be-priced-like-a-pc-with-similar-specs-rather-than-a-console">Valve’s teasing</a> into a final street price for the resurrected SteamOS mini-PC wins. In 2026, when it launches.</p>
<p>I feel left out, so will have a go myself below, though there’s quite a serious kink in mine or indeed anyone’s plan to ticket the Steam Machine by speccing an equivalent DIY PC. Alas, RAM prices have gone stratospheric, in a manner not seen among computing components since the Great Graphics Card Dumpster Fire of 2020.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>As then, but now, the cause is an industry-wide shortage, only this time trigged by – <em>you again</em> – artificial intelligence. In short, AI data centres are rapidly expanding, eating up memory output and leaving scant RAM supplies for consumer PC building. What’s left has, broadly since October but this past week especially, been slapped with obscene markups: this unremarkable <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CTHXMYL8?th=1">Crucial DDR5 32GB</a> kit, for example, was £88 a month ago. Now it’s £206. A bog-standard Corsair Vengeance DDR5 32GB set? Was £100 in September, now yours for just <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CBRJ63RT?th=1">£350</a>. This premium 64GB kit was already pricey at £210, again back in September, and now sits at <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0C5M9P5GK/">£557</a> – more than an RTX 5070, a base PS5, or 1,011 packets of M&amp;S extra cream Bourbon biscuits. 1,011! Makes me <em>sick</em>.</p>
<p>Hardware manufacturers can purchase at scale, and may have enough RAM sticks squirreled away to maintain production, potentially for the several months that shortages are expected to continue. But those who haven’t stockpiled parts will end up feeling the crunch – Microsoft are <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-could-be-forced-into-raising-the-price-of-xbox-consoles-again-given-global-ram-shortage-leaker-claims">allegedly considering yet another price hike</a> for their Xbox Series X/S consoles to cover the higher memory costs.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>None of this bodes well for the Steam Machine. Worst case, Valve must pay top dollar for its DDR5 modules (these are smaller, laptop-style sticks rather than desktop DIMMs, but the type in question still appears affected) and bump up the Machine’s price to compensate. Best case, they have enough memory from the pre-crisis days for a more affordable launch. But, at some point that stock will run out, and Valve will need to choose between supplying more Steam Machines with this AI tax in play or wait it out while those digital shelves grow cobwebs.</p><p>For now, though, nobody actually knows what the situation will be in early 2026, likely including Valve themselves. Indeed, it wouldn’t be remotely surprising if fluctuating parts prices are among the reasons why they didn’t just announce pricing for the Steam Machine, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valves-new-steam-controller-aims-to-entice-a-broader-field-of-pc-players-which-i-fear-already-includes-me">Steam Controller</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-steam-frame-is-real-and-valve-want-it-to-be-the-last-vr-headset-youll-ever-buy">Steam Frame</a> as part of the initial reveal. In any case, I wouldn’t put too much weight on anyone’s Steam Machine price estimates just because they’ve totted up the cost of a similar home-built PC.</p>
<p>Anyway, here’s my Steam Machine price estimate, based on totting up the cost of a similar home-built PC. I’m specifically going for parts that would closely replicate the Steam Machine’s <em>performance</em>, based on my testing of it at Valve HQ last month, and not necessarily its <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-announce-a-new-steam-machine-steam-controller-and-the-steam-frame-vr-headset-and-ive-played-them">on-paper specs</a>. Partly because it has something akin to a custom-built laptop CPU and nobody’s going to bother putting something like that in a DIY desktop.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Case:</strong> Lian Li A3 mATX Wood Edition (<a href="https://zdcs.link/QWEbNd" rel="noopener sponsored" target="_blank">£60</a>)</li>
<li><strong>CPU:</strong> AMD Ryzen 5 7600X (<a href="https://zdcs.link/9ZM3rM" rel="noopener sponsored" target="_blank">£162</a>)</li>
<li><strong>GPU:</strong> Zotac GeForce RTX 5050 Twin Edge (<a href="https://zdcs.link/aN8eV3" rel="noopener sponsored" target="_blank">£219</a>)</li>
<li><strong>RAM:</strong> Crucial DDR5 1x16GB (<a href="https://zdcs.link/aDrXvN" rel="noopener sponsored" target="_blank">£103</a>, ouchies)</li>
<li><strong>SSD:</strong> WD Blue SN500 500GB (<a href="https://zdcs.link/Qdp4ev" rel="noopener sponsored" target="_blank">£60</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Motherboard:</strong> ASRock B650I Lightning WiFi ITX (<a href="https://zdcs.link/aM8e54" rel="noopener sponsored" target="_blank">£140</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Cooler:</strong> Cooler Master Hyper 212 Black (<a href="https://zdcs.link/akwmBg" rel="noopener sponsored" target="_blank">£30</a>)</li>
<li><strong>PSU:</strong> Corsair RM850e (<a href="https://zdcs.link/zEJeR2" rel="noopener sponsored" target="_blank">£95</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Total: £869</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Hope that was helpful. It won't be. But I hope.</p>
</div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/predicting-steam-machine-prices-would-be-a-lot-easier-if-ram-costs-hadnt-gone-horribly-wrong]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam’s Black Friday Sale Features A Lot Of Great 2025 Games You Still Don’t Have Time To Play]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/steams-first-black-friday-sale-best-biggest-deals-new-games-battlefield-borderlands-2000647275</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam%E2%80%99s-black-friday-sale-features-a-lot-of-great-2025-games-you-still-don%E2%80%99t-have-time-to-play.1364509/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Valve is running a big Black Friday sale for the first time in Steam’s history. Normally, around this time of year, we get a Fall sale and a Winter sale. Now Valve has decided to join in with every other online retailer and treat Black Friday as a week-long sales event. But hey, cheaper games are always nice, especially when they are new releases.</p> <p>On November 25, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/specials/?flavor=contenthub_topsellers&amp;offset=74">Valve surprised many by announcing a large Black Friday sale</a> on its hugely popular PC gaming storefront, Steam. The sale runs from now until December 1 and features a large list of games across basically every genre and sub-genre you can imagine. Better yet, a lot of the discounted games include titles, both big and small, that launched in 2025.</p>

 <p>For example, you can grab <em>Battlefield 6,</em> one of the biggest games this year, for $10 less than usual. If you are looking for something big to sink into over Thanksgiving, the remastered <em>Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</em> is just $34 this week. Or maybe you want some puzzles to solve with your family and friends? Well, good news: <em>Blue Prince</em> is discounted to just $20 during Steam’s big sale. And if you crave a fun zombie game, this year’s <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em> is excellent and even better at $45.</p>

 <p>And it’s not just games that are on sale. <a href="https://kotaku.com/steam-deck-black-friday-sale-discount-pc-gaming-2000647222">Valve has also marked down the Steam Deck, too.</a> You can get the base LCD model for $80 less than usual. It might be a bit old now, but the Steam Deck is still a damn fine way to play most indie games and smaller titles in 2025.</p> <p>Of course, with a sale this big, we here at <em>Kotaku</em> want to help you find a good deal. So our crack team of experts (me) used advanced algorithms (I spent an hour digging through deals) to assemble a handy database of big discounts worth checking out. (I made a list for you.)</p>  <ul> <li><em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em> – $56 ($70)</li> <li><em>Silent Hill f</em> – $56 ($70)</li> <li><em>Split Fiction</em> – $40 ($50)</li> <li><em>EA Sports FC 2026</em> – $35 ($70)</li> <li><em>Of Ash &amp; Steel</em> – $24 ($30)</li> <li><em>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</em> – $34 ($50)</li> <li><em>Blue Prince</em> – $20 ($30)</li> <li><em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em> – $49 ($70)</li> <li><em>Battlefield 6</em> – $60 ($70)</li> <li><em>Moonlighter 2</em> – $25 ($30)</li> <li><em>Dying Light The Beast</em> – $45 ($60)</li> <li><em>Borderlands 4</em> – $56 ($70)</li> <li><em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>– $21 ($30)</li> <li><em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> – $26 ($40)</li> <li><em>Hellclock</em> – $14 ($20)</li> <li><em>Mars First Logistics</em> – $13 ($20)</li> <li><em>Metal Eden</em> – $20 ($40)</li> <li><em>Wildgate</em> – $15 ($30)</li> <li><em>Camper Van: Make It Home</em> – $11 ($15)</li> <li><em>Chip ‘N Clawz vs. The Brainioids</em> – $21 ($30)</li> <li><em>Time Flies</em> – $12 ($15)</li> <li><em>to a T</em> – $13 ($20)</li> <li><em>Tron Catalyst</em> – $17 ($25)</li> <li><em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> – $70 ($35)</li> <li><em>Jackbox Party Pack 11</em> – $24 ($30)</li> </ul>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/steams-first-black-friday-sale-best-biggest-deals-new-games-battlefield-borderlands-2000647275]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASUS ROG Strix G16 Gaming Laptop (RTX 5070) Crashes to a No-Margin Price as Amazon Clears Out 5-Star Bestsellers for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/the-asus-rog-strix-g16-gaming-laptop-with-an-rtx-5070-dropped-by-500-ahead-of-black-friday-2000645223</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/asus-rog-strix-g16-gaming-laptop-rtx-5070-crashes-to-a-no-margin-price-as-amazon-clears-out-5-star-bestsellers-for-black-friday.1364503/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Following the success of the Steam Deck PC gaming handheld, Valve announce an all-new lineup of gaming hardware including a Steam Controller, a VR kit called the Steam Frame, and the Steam Machine. The last of those is a retread of Valve’s attempt at having a home gaming console, but the company is in a much better position to be an Xbox killer now given current hardware capabilities along with the work put in to make the Steam OS into what it is now. That said, the big question is price. We currently have no clue what it will sell for nor when it will come out. So if you’re aching to get some gaming in right now, maybe go with a gaming laptop.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5674/">This Asus ROG Strix G16 gaming laptop is currently on sale at Amazon Black Friday, for 19% off.</a> It’s normally listed at $2,100 but the discount ends up bringing it down by a full $400. You end up only having to pay $1,700 for a limited time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5674/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>Diving into the specs, this 2025 premiere gaming laptop is working with the AMD Ryzen 9 9955HX processor alongside an NVIDIA GeForce RTX 5070 Laptop GPU. You can expect cutting-edge performance all on a portable device. It’s packed with 32GB of DDR5-5600MHz memory and a storage capacity of 1TB PCIe Gen 4 SSD for your gaming library.</p>
<h2>Stunning Visuals</h2>
<p>The laptop is employing a premium ROG Nebula display, capable of ultra-fast 240Hz refresh rates with an input time of just 3ms. The screen measures across at 16 inches and has a 90% screen-to-body ratio to help maximize it’s workable area. It’s covered with an ACR film which helps to both enhance contrast as well as reduce glare when gaming in brightly lit spaces. NVIDIA G-Sync is supported, helping to eliminate screen tearing while playing fast-action games such as a first person shooter.</p>



<p>Advanced thermals work to keep your system cool and quiet during intense gameplay. The unit features three fans working in unison along with a heatsink the full width of the laptop and vents on all sides, all helping to keep the Asus ROG Strix G16 gaming laptop cool.</p>
<p>And it wouldn’t be a capital-G Gaming laptop without customizable RGB. The light bar can be set to synchronize with your keyboard and other ROG peripherals. And with the touch of a button, switch it to stealth mode to turn off the RGB lighting. Great for professional settings.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5674/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/the-asus-rog-strix-g16-gaming-laptop-with-an-rtx-5070-dropped-by-500-ahead-of-black-friday-2000645223]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign The Forsaken Hollows DLC Release Date—Everything Included In Nightreign DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-the-forsaken-hollows-dlc-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-the-forsaken-hollows-dlc-release-date%E2%80%94everything-included-in-nightreign-dlc.1364500/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Bandai Namco and FromSoftware are teaming up at least one more time to deliver Elden Ring Nightreign’s anticipated The Forsaken Hollows DLC. If you thought you were done beating the night, you can think again.</p>



<p>The Nightreign updates and content haven’t stopped since launch. The game <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-is-about-to-get-even-harder-in-new-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">got even harder</a>—which was brutal—and then <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-the-forsaken-hollows-expansion-dlc-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the first expansion was revealed.</a> The developer has no intention for you to go outside and see the light anytime soon.</p>



<p>If you want Elden Ring Nightreign The Forsaken Hollows DLC release information, Insider Gaming has the dates and details you seek.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-elden-ring-nightreign-dlc-coming-out">When Is Elden Ring Nightreign DLC Coming Out?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The night never ends. Credit to Bandai Namco</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Elden Ring Nightreign’s The Forspoken Hollows DLC is currently scheduled to release on December 4.</strong></p>



<p>This would be quite apt as it would be nearly one year on from Nightreign’s announcement at The Game Awards 2024. With no word on how much content Nightreign is expected to get—especially with FromSoftware resources being diverted to The Duskbloods—this could end up being the only major DLC expansion for Nightreign.</p>



<p>This guide will be updated if any late announcements indicate a delay to The Forspoken Hollows.</p>







<h2 id="h-everything-included-in-elden-ring-nightreign-the-forsaken-hollows-dlc">Everything Included In Elden Ring Nightreign The Forsaken Hollows DLC</h2>



<p><strong>Nightreign’s The Forspoken Hollows DLC includes new playable characters, new bosses, a new Shifting Earth, and much more on top of this.</strong></p>



<p>FromSoftware is a master of its craft. It doesn’t short-change gamers and constantly provides value for money. These are the full details that have been provided for The Forspoken Hollows DLC so far:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“This product is an additional&nbsp;DLC&nbsp;for&nbsp;ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN. It includes&nbsp;2 additional Nightfarers,&nbsp;2 new Bosses, and&nbsp;1 new Shifting Earth, and more.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The two new Nightfarers are <strong>Scholar </strong>and <strong>Undertaker</strong>. Here’s a brief explainer provided for each new character:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Scholar:</strong> “An&nbsp;academic&nbsp;who walks the&nbsp;Lands Between.&nbsp;Boasting impressive arcane levels, he gains incredible advantages through battlefield observation.”</li>



<li><strong>Undertaker:</strong> “An&nbsp;abbess&nbsp;who was mandated to slay the&nbsp;Nightlord.&nbsp;Boasting impressive strength and faith, she sends enemies to the afterlife with ruthless efficiency.”</li>
</ul>



<p>Whereas the Shifting Earth brings about gorgeous crystals in an enchanting locale. The rest remains to be seen on December 4. As usual, the content is playable on PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p>



<p>You can see tidbits of new content and a snippet of what’s to come in the official gameplay reveal trailer for the DLC expansion.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN The Forsaken Hollows | Official Gameplay Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z5ASspHK398?start=1&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Will you be buying the Elden Ring Nightreign The Forsaken Hollows DLC? Is it a case of crossing fingers and toes for more content after this? Head to the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server</a> and let everyone know—but keep your digits crossed while you do it.</p>



<hr>



<p>You should check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/holiday-gifts-for-pokemon-fans-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Best Holiday Gifts for Pokémon Fans In 2025</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cheap-gaming-gifts-under-25/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Best Cheap Gaming Gifts Under $25 For Holiday 2025</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-the-forsaken-hollows-dlc-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Walmart's Black Friday Video Game Sale Is Better Than Amazon So Far]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/walmarts-black-friday-video-game-sales-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/walmarts-black-friday-video-game-sale-is-better-than-amazon-so-far.1364497/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It's a Black Friday miracle!</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Walmart has officially joined the party of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-black-friday-sale-2025-early-deals">Black Friday sales</a>, bringing a massive selection of video game deals. If you've been hoping to fill up your library with some new picks to play as early nights and colder weather sets in, now's your chance to score <a href="https://Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> for just $30, or <a href="https://Elden Ring" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Elden Ring</a> for a mere $15. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You read that right. Only $15 for a game we gave a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-review">10 out of 10</a> to and called <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2022-winners">Game of the Year</a> back in 2022 is a stellar offer, and what better way to spend your holiday break than becoming Elden Lord? There's no better time to journey to the Lands Between, truly.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Walmart Black Friday Video Game Deals</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, Walmart's Elden Ring deal doesn't include the expansion, Shadow of the Erdtree. The good news is, you can pick up the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-is-under-20-again-and-nightreign-has-a-big-discount-too-for-black-friday">Shadow of the Erdtree Edition instead at Amazon</a> for $49.99, a $30 discount. That's a touch cheaper than buying the two separately, even with the $15 deal on the base game. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-review">Elden Ring Nightrein</a> is on sale, too, if you happened to miss FromSoft's co-op adventure take on the series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Walmart's sale also features some nice Switch discounts. <a href="https://zdcs.link/aXVMPZ?object_uuid=e36ba8b0-e8be-491a-bfa5-b43362b61f2f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</a> is also down to $30 there, as is <a href="https://zdcs.link/9yGEvn?object_uuid=e36ba8b0-e8be-491a-bfa5-b43362b61f2f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Princess Peach: Showtime</a>. Switch 2 users certainly aren't being forgotten about, either. <a href="https://zdcs.link/QVEde1?object_uuid=e36ba8b0-e8be-491a-bfa5-b43362b61f2f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Star Wars Outlaws Gold Edition</a> for Switch 2 is marked down to $30, and if the delightful co-op adventure <a href="https://zdcs.link/QmOENN?object_uuid=e36ba8b0-e8be-491a-bfa5-b43362b61f2f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Split Fiction</a> has been on your list, it's also down to $30 for Switch 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Outside of Walmart, other retailers are offering some excellent discounts on video games right now, too. Be sure to check out our breakdowns of the best deals on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-5-best-games-already-on-sale-black-friday-2025-updated">PS5</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-black-friday-sale-is-officially-live-2025">Xbox</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-best-games-already-on-sale-black-friday-2025">Nintendo</a> games and accessories.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more discounts available, check out our guide to the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/walmart-black-friday-sale-2025">best Walmart Black Friday deals</a> available now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 25, 2025 5:24 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/walmarts-black-friday-video-game-sales-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>