<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 13:54:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VA-11 Hall-A Dev Sukeban Games Announces .45 Parabellum Bloodhound]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/45-parabellum-bloodhound-sukeban-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/va-11-hall-a-dev-sukeban-games-announces-45-parabellum-bloodhound.918009/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/45-parabellum-bloodhound-sukeban-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>VA-11 Hall-A&nbsp;</em>developer Sukeban Games has announced&nbsp;<em>.45 Parabellum Bloodhound</em>, a new and rather strange-looking game that marries turn-based combat with real-time gameplay.</p>
<p>In an <a href="https://sukeban.moe/index.php/2024/07/03/parabellum/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announcement on the studio's official website</a>, Sukeban's Christopher Ortiz, otherwise known as kiririn51, describes&nbsp;<em>.45 Parabellum Bloodhound&nbsp;</em>as an "Active Time Action" game, playfully following up by saying that descriptor "sounds a little bit like nonsense but we like nonsense".</p>
<p>In a similar way to the<em>&nbsp;Parasite Eve&nbsp;</em>series, the game will feature combat in which you move and dodge in real-time while you wait for an action bar to fill up, and once it's full, you can pause the fight and plan your attack.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/45-parabellum-bloodhound-combat.jpg?itok=HRVhef_k 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/45-parabellum-bloodhound-combat.jpg?itok=os8WHopP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Sukeban Games' newest title blends real-time combat with turn-based strategic planning.</figcaption></figure><p>Although the combat might boast some similarities with&nbsp;<em>Parasite Eve</em>, Ortiz says that's where the similarities end, although&nbsp;<em>Parasite Eve&nbsp;</em>is a personal favorite of his.</p>
<p>Instead, he's building a game with "highly atmospheric environments" and "hand-placed encounters", one that's full of secrets to discover and a "unique cast of characters" to meet, as well as bosses to fight at the conclusion of each level.</p>
<p>According to Ortiz,&nbsp;<em>.45 Parabellum Bloodhound&nbsp;</em>will have seven chapters to play through, and right now, five of those chapters are playable from start to end, although we're likely a long way from release.</p>
<p>Ortiz says that he doesn't know when&nbsp;<em>.45 Parabellum Bloodhound&nbsp;</em>will be released, and that in order to avoid repeating <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/n1rv-ann-release-date-delayed-indefinitely">"a&nbsp;<em>N1rvannA&nbsp;</em>situation"</a>, he's not going to give a rough timeline for release either.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/45-parabellum-bloodhound-stairs.jpg?itok=1Bdk5u5N 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/45-parabellum-bloodhound-stairs.jpg?itok=FzRLvLgG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>.45 Parabellum Bloodhound&nbsp;</em>has some pretty evocative-looking environments to explore.</figcaption></figure><p>Between this and games like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/spy-drops-metal-gear-stealth">Spy Drops</a></em>, as well as&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/signalis-review">Signalis</a></em>,&nbsp;<em>Yellow Taxi Goes Vroom</em>, and many others, you're quids in at the moment if you're nostalgic for the PlayStation era of gaming.</p>
<p>While we don't have a release date for&nbsp;<em>.45 Parabellum Bloodhound</em>, Ortiz and his team have promised monthly development updates to showcase how work on the project is going. They'll likely be released via the official Sukeban Games website, so check back often for those if you're interested.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open door policy: can an escape room be queer?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/open-door-policy-can-an-escape-room-be-queer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/open-door-policy-can-an-escape-room-be-queer.918006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/open-door-policy-can-an-escape-room-be-queer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/pride-week-2024-florence-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Katherine Crighton/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<em>Hello! Eurogamer is once again marking Pride with another week of features celebrating the intersection of LGBTQIA+ culture and gaming in all its guises. Today, Florence Smith Nicholls explores experimental escape room Memoirscape and its tale of queer love in the 80s.</em>
</p>
<p>"This room is very gender."</p>
<p>We're in a teen bedroom - the exact location and date is a little hazy, but it's somewhere in Queens, New York City, in 1986. All the hallmarks of adolescence are here, posters on the walls, a brightly covered duvet, knick-knacks. The space is bathed in warm light. I sit down on the bed and pick up a romance novel left nearby. It's comfortable, one might even say cosy,  but we're not alone. Another group is huddled around a cassette player, listening to a recording of a private conversation between two young women. When I look closer at the photographs on the walls, some of the faces seem to be crossed out. Oh, and the novel is <em>extremely gay</em>.</p>
<p>This is Memoirscape, a self-styled 'cosy escape room' created as part of the Design of Interactive Experiences course at Massachusetts' Worcester Polytechnic Institute. Its slightly sci-fi set-up casts players as participants in a live demonstration of Dr. Julia Adler's work on interactive memories. For this particular experiment, they step into one of Adler's own memories, exploring a happy summer she spent in her grandmother's NYC apartment before heading off to college. Here, in an experience combining elements of immersive theatre and environmental storytelling, they're free to interact with Adler's childhood living room and bedroom as they please, learning more about her past - and her long-lost love - through the ephemera in each room. As <a href="https://escaperoom.wpi.edu/">Memoirscape's website</a> puts it,"Let your curiosity guide you, and notice the narrative unfold."</p>
<div data-domain="www.youtube-nocookie.com"><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/A8Jeyfyk4Ck?si=ReXG5q1E89FWrg2n" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p></div>
<p>Like other escape rooms, Memoirscape features puzzles to solve. Players are tasked with finding a series of cassette tapes and noting down corresponding letters to form a code, for instance, while other clues, such as a cryptic message on the TV, prompt them toward further solutions. Unlike traditional escape rooms, however, there's no time limit and the "escape" is less literal; the ultimate goal is to work out how to help Dr. Adler by leaving the cosy living room behind, finding her office, and figuring out why she's so fixated on reliving the summer of 1986. "It's an experience, like childhood, you'll eventually have to leave behind," continues the official description. "How you choose to do so, what you do when you leave, and how you feel about your memory of it… that's what's up to you." There are even four different endings, none of which diminish the player for not getting further.</p>
<p>Given Memoirscape's billing as a space you can enter, soak up, and leave whenever you feel like, its sense of atmosphere is key - and its recreation of a cosily nostalgic corner of 1986 is certainly impressive. Memoirscape's design is built on what its narrative and production consultant Katherine Crighton calls "asynchronous storytelling through ephemera" - inspired by Punchdrunk's immersive experience Sleep No More and Henning Nelm's 1969 handbook Magic and Showmanship - and, as someone who studies archaeological approaches to games, I was fascinated by this material culture.</p>
<p>The rooms that make up Dr. Adler's memories of her grandmother's apartment are stuffed with authentic 80s bric-a-brac, including carefully curated bookshelves and vintage board games. There are even 80s-style video games programmed specifically for the experience by Samin Shahriar Tokey using a Raspberry Pi and touchscreen. But amid all this richly authentic detail, there's perhaps one element that truly gets to the heart of Memoirscape: the novel I mentioned back at the start, author Nancy Garden's groundbreaking 1982 queer young adult love story, Annie on My Mind.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/pride-week-florence-lounge.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>There's lots of knick knacks to distract you-even sweets! | <span>Image credit: <cite>Florence Smith Nicholls</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As Crighton tells me over email, Worcester Polytechnic Institute's Interactive Media and Game Development program - which Memoirscape was created for - has a vibrant community of queer students, "and so the development of Julia Adler... into a young lesbian in 1986 was a definite 'write what you know' moment". And woven between Memoirscape's more familiar escape room elements is a queer love story that Annie on My Mind mirrors almost serendipitously. "As I started digging into the book to make sure it still fit within our cosy gameplay," Crighton explains, "I discovered connection after connection with not just the characters our students had created, but our larger worldbuilding as well. After that, choosing to make the main thrust of Memoirscape be the love story between Julie and Steph, and the persistence of memory fueled by that love, felt like being given the key to a door we hadn't realised could be opened."</p>
<p>Indeed, Memoirscape's very specific 80s nostalgia goes beyond mere aesthetics. On the path to uncovering Alder's past, for instance, players use genuine, old-fashioned audio cassettes to gather clues - a process Crighton believes encourages them to "practice patience and mindfulness" as they interact with unfamiliar analogue technology. But its 1986 setting also creates a certain kind of tension for a queer person who might be nostalgic for the era, despite it being a less accepting period. I was disappointed but not surprised to discover Annie on My Mind has been the subject of controversy over the years, and even burnt in Kansas City in 1993 just because it's a story about two young women in love.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/pride-week-florence-bedroom.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>A teenage bedroom through the looking glass. | <span>Image credit: <cite>Katherine Crighton</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Ultimately, Memoirscape invites a different kind of escapism beyond timed metrics, accommodating a range of playstyles to suit different tastes. For me, combing through its carefully curated period-appropriate books and ephemera was a joy, but other players might choose to simply hang out with their friends, play chess, and soak up its period atmosphere. Or they might opt to speedrun the puzzles and discover Adler's secrets as quickly as possible. Without spoiling too much, the way to progress the story and find Dr Adler's office is always hidden in plain sight and there's nothing stopping players from leaving and finding her lab, even Adler herself. In this way Memoirscape perhaps subverts one of the fundamental principles of escape rooms; it isn't that players are prevented from leaving, they're presented with a space so cosy they don't <em>want</em> to leave.</p>
<p>Given Memoirscape's emphasis on set design and exploration, it reminded me of video games with similar themes. An obvious parallel would be developer Fullbright's walking simulator, Gone Home; as in that game's tale of slowly unfurling familial revelations, Adler's story is told as an epistolary narrative, allowing players to discover more at their own pace. I can't help but wonder what it would look like if other games with rich environmental storytelling like Elden Ring created challenge through distraction rather than conflict. Just imagine if all the books in Elden Ring's Raya Lucaria Academy were readable - it would certainly add a new kind of difficulty for the lore enthusiasts!</p>
<p>With the new wave of dark cosy games like Grave Seasons and Wanderstop upon us, it seems there is an appetite for experiences that question the comfort that they provide. Memoirscape proves that an escape room can be queer not just in terms of subject matter, but through challenging players by creating a literal comfort zone that they need to break out of. It's a cosy escape room that isn't afraid to engage with the complexities of queerness and nostalgia, especially in terms of how we can idealise the past, both on a personal and wider level. As Memoirscape's director-producer Kathleen Morrissey puts it: "You need the darkness in order to huddle closer to the hearth, after all."</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Server Outage Highlights Yet Another Major Problem]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-server-outage-highlights-yet-another-major-problem/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-server-outage-highlights-yet-another-major-problem.918000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-server-outage-highlights-yet-another-major-problem/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>On Tuesday afternoon and through Tuesday evening, many Xbox owners were upset to find that <a href="https://x.com/XboxSupport/status/1808256771640766610" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">they couldn’t sign in</a> to Xbox Live due to a server outage. While a service being down isn’t new in the world of gaming, it’s another case against the always online nature of where we are with it.</p>



<p>This wasn’t a situation where servers for games were down. According to Microsoft’s Xbox status page, the Microsoft store was functional, multiplayer gaming was online, cloud gaming was online, and more. What wasn’t was the ability to sign in to your account. This stopped players from pretty much playing anything they had. That includes single-player games.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Persona 5 Royal, which Twitter user <a href="https://x.com/nitpicktim/status/1808229756707787091" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">nitpicktim</a> shared a video of, was completely unplayable despite having no need to be connected. It’s a single-player game. Another game that would’ve been unplayable had it been available during this time is Neon White. Yet another title with no need for online. However, because you couldn’t sign in, you were screwed. </p>



<p>Want to play Elden Ring? Nope. Assassin’s Creed? Tough luck.</p>



<p>This may come across as a, sort of, “old man yells at cloud” type of argument, but I’m on the side of the player here. If you own a game – well, license nowadays – and you just want to play it, you should always be able to play it. It’s pretty straight forward.</p>



<p>I’ve said this countless times and I’ll continue to beat this drum. Forcing an online connection to play single-player games is anti-consumer and absolutely ridiculous. I get it for multiplayer games, obviously. But for games that don’t have any benefit aside from patches to be online, what’s the point?&nbsp;</p>



<p>All this does is restrict people who spend their money on your console and on games. We know the days of buying a game, putting it in your system, and just playing it are over. There’s no going back to that. But with how Xbox is currently set, if you lose internet connection or the Xbox servers drop, you’re completely out of luck no matter what. You shouldn’t need the internet to play a game that’s installed locally on your console. It turns your system into a paperweight.</p>



<p>So, why does Microsoft do this? It feels like it’s for no other reason than control. It’s unfair to everyone who you claim are the backbone of your company.&nbsp;</p>



<p>An Xbox on every screen doesn’t mean a thing if you restrict them from playing on said screens.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>What are your thoughts on the state of Xbox always being online and not being able to play single-player games during a server outage? For more Insider Gaming, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tales-of-kenzera-zau-studio-hit-with-layoffs/">layoffs at Tales of Kenzera: Zau developer Surgent Studios</a>, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 PC Performance Patch Arrives This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-pc-performance-patch-arrives-this-week/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-pc-performance-patch-arrives-this-week.917997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-pc-performance-patch-arrives-this-week/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Arrowhead Studios’ CEO has confirmed that a PC performance patch for Helldivers 2 should arrive this week. Shams Jorjani, the new CEO, recently took to X (formerly Twitter) to inform players about the developers’ increased activity on social media platforms such as Discord, Reddit, and X. </p>



<p>Jorjani was then bombarded with questions about the Helldivers 2’s PC performance issues. He replied that they would focus on ‘performance’ in the next patch.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">update coming this week by the looks of it! hope it does the trick! but we'll keep at it regardless</p>— Shams Jorjani (@ShamsJorjani) <a href="https://twitter.com/ShamsJorjani/status/1807829995781333360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>If you head over to the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">r/Helldivers</a> subreddit, you will see players constantly raising issues with PC performance. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1dn86eq/its_time_to_acknowledge_pc_performance_issues/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">A massive thread</a> posted nine days ago discusses the number of PC issues players have faced since the first patch, with hundreds of players reporting new problems or agreeing to other issues. Players have been waiting for Arrowhead to acknowledge these performance issues with Helldivers 2, and hopefully, it will all be solved through the next patch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Currently, Helldivers 2’s player base is rapidly declining, with only 10% of the original players still active. The game reached an all-time peak of 458,709 players on Steam four months ago, but this number has plummeted to 34,278 in the last 24 hours, according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/553850/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>. </p>



<p>While this doesn’t signify the end of the game, it does underscore the urgency for developers to address the pressing issue of PC performance, which is what the players are eagerly awaiting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Speaking of Helldivers 2, have you explored the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/where-to-download-the-helldivers-2-star-wars-mods/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Star Wars mods</a> available for the game? Also, it’s worth noting that a story mode for Arrowhead’s third-person shooter <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-story-mode-not-happening/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">is not on the horizon</a>. What specific performance issues are you hoping to see resolved in the upcoming Helldivers 2 PC performance patch? Share your thoughts in the comments below.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-is-going-after-more-people-with-lawsuits/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">&nbsp;Nintendo going after more parties over piracy</a>&nbsp;of its games, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive content.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2.5D rhythm action puzzle platformer ANTRO launches in 2025 for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/2-5d-rhythm-action-puzzle-platformer-antro-launches-in-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2-5d-rhythm-action-puzzle-platformer-antro-launches-in-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.917994/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/2-5d-rhythm-action-puzzle-platformer-antro-launches-in-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Published by Selecta Play.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>2.5D rhythm <a title="Genres > Action [1,984 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> puzzle <a title="Genres > Platformer [479 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > ANTRO" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/antro">ANTRO</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,401 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,650 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1861250/Antro/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [339 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store in 2025, publisher <a title="Companies > Selecta Play [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/selecta-play">Selecta Play</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Gatera Studio" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gatera-studio">Gatera Studio</a> announced. <span id="more-896638"></span></p><p>“The exciting blend of action, puzzles and platforming with urban music makes for a really thrilling gameplay experience, so for us, <em>ANTRO</em> was a title we really wanted to help bring to market,” said Selecta Play head of gaming Javi Puertas in a press release. “Working with the talented team at Gatera Studio has been a great experience and we can’t wait to share more news on the release of <em>ANTRO</em> in the coming weeks.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Selecta Play:</p><blockquote><p>After The Collapse, only one percent of humankind survived and was forced to take refuge underground. Under the old city of Barcelona stands ANTRO, a dirty and dark hole divided into geographical strata. The inhabitants of the lowest levels fight for survival by working forced labor, while the ones in the higher levels rule over the new underground world. </p><p>ANTRO’s government has become a totalitarian system, handing power over to a corporation based on technological overproduction and the automation of sectors known as La Cupula. Freedom of speech has been censored, art and music are forbidden, and a rebellion seems to be coming to life inside the den in which they’re living.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_896681"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p>Journey through the most remote places in the underground metropolis of ANTRO, and join the protagonist, Nittch, as you embark on a mission to deliver a package to a mysterious, unknown recipient. While you’re at it, how about overthrowing the totalitarian government of La Cupula? Play with urban music in a thrilling adventure full of action, puzzles and 2.5D platforming.</p><p>Explore ANTRO to the rhythm of hip-hop, drill, R&amp;B, and electronic music, and move around the city overcoming obstacles in your way, be it by resolving puzzles or traversing the environment using parkour. But be prepared to run at full speed, as the pursuits in ANTRO are plentiful and both you and the scenario will move in synchrony with the music. But remember: the enemy is always lurking.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/antro/july-3-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Publisher Announce Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="ANTRO Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MvYX9qpAv5o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead story trailer shows off snippets of noisy gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/03/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-story-trailer-shows-off-snippets-of-noisy-gameplay/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-story-trailer-shows-off-snippets-of-noisy-gameplay.917973/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/03/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-story-trailer-shows-off-snippets-of-noisy-gameplay/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Saber Interactive and developer Stormind have shared a new trailer (via <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DC2rNzzmhXw">IGN</a>) for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead">A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</a>, their horror game based off the popular film franchise. Check it out:</p>
<p><iframe title="A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead – Official First Story Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DC2rNzzmhXw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>As you can see from the trailer, there’s a snippet of incident from Day One of the alien monster invasion, setting up the relationship between protagonist Alex, an asthmatic college student, and her boyfriend Martin. We then skip ahead to Day 105, with Martin and Alex exploring the devastated world looking to scavenge from a house that mysteriously still has power.</p>
<p>There’s some nice touches here like using basic hand and head communication to direct one another, messages saying not to scream even in the “safe” room, and we see how opening doors works – you latch on and then can move it open slowly before releasing. Unfortunately it seems that the world was also in the grip of a fictional shortage of WD40 and oil-based lubricants, and North America in the very real shortage of decent sex education, because all of the hinges in the world are very creaky and Alex is very, very pregnant. That’s not good because things related to babies and baby making are famously not quiet.</p>
<p>Other things that aren’t noisy? Cars, shotguns and alarms.&nbsp;Oh dear…</p>

<p>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead is in development by Stormind Games, who are best known for the psychological horror <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/10/19/remothered-broken-porcelain-review/">Remothered: Broken Porcelain</a> and Tormented Fathers, as well as action RPG Batora: Lost Haven. This looks to be a big step up for the studio, but they’re leaning into the right ideas and tropes that will fit well with a video game, though the trailer clearly plucked out some of the more action-y moments that put the Quiet Place monsters in frame. I’d expect the overarching pacing to be much more considered and slower paced, though.</p>
<p>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead is set to release for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X|S</a> and PC later this year.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DC2rNzzmhXw">IGN on YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How a musical indie game went against the grain to explore the Deaf experience]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/24190846/harmonium-the-musical-developer-interview-deaf-culture-experience</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-a-musical-indie-game-went-against-the-grain-to-explore-the-deaf-experience.917970/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/24190846/harmonium-the-musical-developer-interview-deaf-culture-experience<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><p>Before I even touched the demo of <em>Harmonium: The Musical</em> at Summer Game Fest earlier this month, I started bawling. It’s about a young deaf girl, Melody, who wishes to participate in the musical traditions of her hearing family. That desire leads her to an adventure in the magical land of Harmonium where music and sign language are the primary means of communication. But what really got me about this game is the dedication from its development team to not only make this game but make it <em>right</em> — with all of the costs and risks that entails.</p><p><em>Harmonium</em> is the latest project from <a href="https://www.theoddgentlemen.com/">The Odd Gentlemen</a>, an LA-based studio known for its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/3/6/8160509/kings-quest-remake-2015-gdc-pc-xbox-ps4">revival of the Sierra Entertainment point-and-click adventure classic <em>King’s Quest</em></a>. Studio founder Matt Korba told <em>The Verge</em> that <em>Harmonium</em> was inspired by theater troupes like <a href="https://www.deafwest.org/">Deaf West</a> that incorporate sign language into their productions. But in developing <em>Harmonium</em>, Korba said he wanted a game that went beyond what he felt most studios do when tackling representation. “Usually on projects like this, the script will be written in English, and [developers will hire] a consultant at the last minute that knows sign language, and they’ll just translate,” Korba said.&nbsp;</p><p>To Korba, <em>Harmonium</em> required a “ground-up approach” that, from day one, integrated the people with the same lived experiences as the characters created for the game. That included engaging the Southern California Association for the Deaf and recruiting deaf developers and artists. This led Korba to Matt Daigle, a deaf artist, performer, and graphic designer notable for creating the international symbol for breastfeeding and his webcomic <a href="https://handsail.net/home-tdg/"><em>That Deaf Guy</em></a> depicting the everyday life of a mixed-hearing family. He also found Søren Bro Sparre, a deaf animator from Denmark whose hiring introduced the challenge of communicating not only in English and American Sign Language but in Danish Sign Language as well.</p><p>For Daigle, <em>Harmonium</em> is a way to share more of Deaf culture, including dispelling what he called the cultural myth that music isn’t for deaf people. “I relate to Melody because I grew up in a family of musicians, and I played the clarinet,” Daigle signed in our interview with helpful translation from his interpreter. “It’s good to show that a person who was hearing who became deaf can still enjoy music, and that deaf people enjoy everything in their own way.”</p><div><p>“It’s good to show that a person who was hearing who became deaf can still enjoy music, and that deaf people enjoy everything in their own way.”</p></div><p>Though Daigle’s role was to inform Melody as a deaf character, there were other elements of her character that he could not speak to. Melody is Filipino, Korba explained, and her experiences as a person are influenced by her cultural heritage as well as her deafness.</p><p>“As we got deeper into development, we realized there was a cross-cultural difference,” Korba said. “We had to laser focus and try to find people with lived experience and the [right] background, so we ended up finding two actresses who are both deaf and Filipino that we use for reference accuracy.”</p><p>That level of specificity took work; the game’s story had to be rewritten three times. But Korba also explained that all those little steps taken in service to authenticity made the game better than what it would have been without it.</p><p>“One of our early passes on the script had a lot of deaf struggles in it,” Korba said. Originally, Melody’s father wasn’t going to use sign language, emulating a common problem between deaf children and their hearing parents. But in testing this story with deaf participants, they found that despite the fact this was a common scenario for deaf people, they rejected it anyway, telling the developer that “I don’t want to see that in a video game.”</p><div><figcaption><em>Melody signs with her father, who, in the original script, did not use sign language.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: The Odd Gentlemen</cite></p></div><p>He said their deaf playtesters explained that they didn’t want their children to grow up expecting to always struggle with their hearing loved ones. “We discovered it’s okay to show challenges, but you also have to show the benefits.”</p><p>That benefit is something Daigle explained as “Deaf Gain” — a philosophy that shifts the perspective on deaf people to the unique things they can do versus what they can’t. “This is about people speaking with their eyes,” Daigle signed. In the opening moments of <em>Harmonium</em>’s demo, for instance, Melody is stuck inside practicing for a recital when her friend stops by to speak to her through her living room window — something only deaf people can do.&nbsp;</p><div><figcaption><em>Melody’s deaf friend Matt communicates with her through a window.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: The Odd Gentlemen</cite></p></div><p>Hearing about all the things it took to bring <em>Harmonium </em>to life, I couldn’t help but wonder: “Isn’t this all prohibitively expensive?” Game development is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/20/24009903/the-cost-of-aaa-development-is-too-damn-high">time-consuming and expensive as it is</a>, even without <em>Harmonium</em>’s level of specificity. Expensive games that take a long time to make face a significant challenge to recoup that cost and make a profit. And even then, merely being profitable <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24151047/xbox-shuts-down-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-microsoft">isn’t enough to ensure a studio’s survival</a>.</p><p>Daigle and Korba credited their partners at Xbox and Netflix who encouraged their team to continue down their unique, if complicated, path even though it ran contrary to modern game development sensibilities. “We have had time to let those things incubate and develop, bringing them to an audience that includes everybody,” Daigle signed. “Does that sound expensive? It sure is. But it’s worth it.”</p><div><p>The video game industry has been beset with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24172733/summer-game-fest-video-game-announcements-layoffs-labor-live-service-fortnite">unprecedented layoffs, studio closures, and project cancellations</a>. Publishers are largely choosing to spend money on developing massive, live-service, multiplayer, multi-platform games from recognizable IPs, <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/the-game-industry-is-fed-indie-devs-are-dying-off-because-getting-funding-is-a-battlefield-right-now-even-for-critically-acclaimed-veterans/">leaving smaller studios and games to languish for lack of funding</a>. Meanwhile, underneath it all is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/18/24104799/gamergate-2024-sweet-baby-inc-diversity">a vigorous and virulent current of toxicity</a> that seeks to amplify the fringe notion that in order for the video games industry to survive this upheaval, they must appeal to as broad an audience as possible.&nbsp;</p></div><div><p>“Does that sound expensive? It sure is. But it’s worth it.”</p></div><p>Given all this, it feels like a miracle a game like <em>Harmonium</em> exists — and its developers know it.&nbsp;“We all just did it one step at a time,” Korba said. “And everyone’s like, ‘How did you get here?’ I don’t really know.”</p><p><em>Harmonium </em>is but one example of how diversity and inclusion combined with authentically and empathetically executed scope results <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24135151/hades-2-technical-test-impressions">in</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24082252/balatro-review-poker-roguelike-videogame">better</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24152153/animal-well-review-switch-ps5-steam-videogamedunkey">games</a> — the kind audiences will embrace.&nbsp;</p><p>I’m not deaf or Filipino, but I could still connect with Melody and her story. I grinned like an idiot when I solved one of <em>Harmonium</em>’s puzzles, matching Melody’s signed descriptions to their correct instruments so I could open a locked door. I laughed when Daigle explained some of the Deaf humor in the game, like a joke about a deaf tree that wouldn’t fall unless someone signed “timber.” And it all made me cry because even though it would have been easier, cheaper, and safer for the developers at The Odd Gentlemen to not include any of these things, they did it anyway.</p><p>“We’re not just building a game for deaf people,” Daigle signed, “but a game that is fun and engaging for everybody.”</p><p><small><em>Harmonium: The Musical</em> launches in early 2025 on Netflix and Xbox Game Pass.</small></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another Round of Layoffs Hit Microsoft]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-new-round-of-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/another-round-of-layoffs-hit-microsoft.917964/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-new-round-of-layoffs/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Throughout the past 24 hours, several people have taken to social media to announce that they have faced layoffs at Microsoft.</p>



<p>It’s currently unclear the exact number of those affected or if they’re part of the 1500 estimated to be laid off in June. Insider Gaming has found four people announcing their departure from the company.</p>



<p>Angela Viness, a Senior Product Manager at Microsoft <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7213952816183222272/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a>, “Hello friends –&nbsp; In light of the recent layoffs at Microsoft, my position was eliminated, and I am now on the lookout for my next career adventure. It was an incredible ride and I’m extremely grateful for the opportunities I was given.”</p>



<p>While Jessabirdy on X (formerly Twitter) <a href="https://x.com/Jessabirdy/status/1808238301062877612" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>, “Sad to announce that my role with Microsoft has been eliminated. To all those who have been a part of Team Xbox. Thank you. Hope I made you proud. &lt;3”</p>



<p>Cory Ebert, a Technical Program Manager <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7213966580261486592/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>, “Well, this isn’t how I thought today would go. After nearly 15 years (seriously, two months shy), Microsoft has made the decision to end our working relationship effective immediately due to changes in the business direction and landscape.”</p>



<p>Earlier this year, Microsoft announced that it would be <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-microsoft-layoffs-affect-1900-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">laying off 1900 employees at the company</a>. In May 2024, it was also announced that Xbox would <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-shutting-down-four-studios-including-tango-game-works-and-arkane-austin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shut down four of its game studios</a>, including Tango Gamewords and Arkane Austin.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Microsoft for comment.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-battlefield-game-ever-going-offline/">the&nbsp;Battlefield games being taken offline</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive content.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VA-11 Hall-A developer Sukeban Games announces ‘Active Time Action’ game .45 PARABELLUM BLOODHOUND for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/va-11-hall-a-developer-sukeban-games-announces-active-time-action-game-45-parabellum-bloodhound-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/va-11-hall-a-developer-sukeban-games-announces-%E2%80%98active-time-action%E2%80%99-game-45-parabellum-bloodhound-for-pc.917961/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/va-11-hall-a-developer-sukeban-games-announces-active-time-action-game-45-parabellum-bloodhound-for-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Playable at BitSummit Drift.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>VA-11 Hall-A</em> developer <a title="Companies > Sukeban Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sukeban-games">Sukeban Games</a> has <a href="https://sukeban.moe/index.php/2024/07/03/parabellum/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a> <em>.<a title="Games > .45 PARABELLUM BLOODHOUND" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/45-parabellum-bloodhound">45 PARABELLUM BLOODHOUND</a></em>, an “Active Time <a title="Genres > Action [1,984 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a>” game featuring a mix of real-time and turn-based combat. It will be available for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam. It will be playable for the first time at BitSummit Drift from July 19 to 21. <span id="more-896639"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Sukeban Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A new world and characters from the award-winning studio that brought you <em>Cyberpunk Bartender Action: VA-11 Hall-A</em>.</p><p>This is <em>.45 PARABELLUM BLOODHOUND</em>.</p><p><strong>Evade Attacks, Stop Time, and Kill ‘Em All</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Featuring a mix of real-time and turn-based combat, <em>.45 PARABELLUM BLOODHOUND</em> offers a captivating experience for players of all levels.</p><p><strong>Getting <a title="Series > Persona [81 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/persona">Persona</a>l</strong></p><p>Follow the raw tale of Reila Mikazuchi; a killing machine emerging from depression looking to rebuild her life doing what she knows best. A path well-traveled where the consequences are known, but is her biggest foe really in front of her gun?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the tightly designed “Active Time Action” battle system, suitable for both newcomers and veterans.</li><li>Explore seven meticulously crafted, atmospheric stages with hand-placed encounters, dialogues, and riddles.</li><li>Enjoy detailed lo-fi visuals that enhance the texture of this rich cyberpunk world.</li><li>Immerse yourself in a gripping storyline waiting to be uncovered.</li></ul></blockquote><p>And here are some additional details, via Sukeban Games’ <a href="https://twitter.com/kiririn51" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Christopher Ortiz</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>What is <em>.45 PARABELLUM BLOODHOUND</em>?</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/45-PARABELLUM-BLOODHOUND_2024_07-03-24_007.jpg"></a></figure><p>An “Active Time Action” game, which sounds a little bit like nonsense but we like nonsense.</p><p>tl;dr, you move and dodge in real time while you wait for an Action bar to fill at a speed determined by character and weapon stats. Once that’s done you can then stop time and plan your offensive.</p><p>The genesis of the battle system can of course be traced back to a personal favorite of mine: Parasite Eve, but that’s about where comparisons end.</p><p>I’ll talk about this some other time.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/45-PARABELLUM-BLOODHOUND_2024_07-03-24_005.jpg"></a></figure><p>The pitch: You play as Reila Mikazuchi; a washed out mercenary whose glory days are long gone. In a last attempt at grabbing life by the horns she decides to go back to the life, only to realize the real enemy isn’t in front of her gun.</p><p><em>—The game’s heroine Reila. Designed by me with help from Merengedoll.</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/45-PARABELLUM-BLOODHOUND_2024_07-03-24_008.jpg"></a></figure><p>The whole game plays out inside these highly atmospheric environments peppered with hand-placed encounters. You’ll be roaming around finding secrets hidden all over the game’s world, as well as talking to quite the unique cast of characters. Not to mention cool boss fights at the end of every level.</p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title=".45 PARABELLUM BLOODHOUND - Ambience Video" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/41yKilj0jfI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>We’re currently aiming for seven chapters; five of which are currently playable from start to finish. Most of the features are already locked in, as well as the story. We highly doubt things will change much from this initial description though we never know… There’s always something we can get rid of to ship it within this lifetime.</p><p><strong>Release When?</strong></p><p>No idea. I don’t wanna give any time tables here as to not repeat a <em>N1RV Ann-A</em> situation (though we do have an internal one), but we hope it’s sooner rather than later. I was actually gonna wait until we had the entire game built before announcing it Officially, but selling games has become much harder. It’s not 2016 anymore, so if we want this game to have a chance we gotta start now and hoard those wishlists and shit.</p><p>In short: when it’s done.</p><p>Do expect monthly devlogs (I’ve been writing them for years now, though I’ve been behind for Very Good Reasons), and progress shots over at my Twitter account and Sukeban’s.</p><p><strong><em>N1RV Ann-A</em>?</strong></p><p>No news in that front. Sorry. I know that’s the main event everyone wants to see, but <em>.45 PARABELLUM BLOODHOUND</em> is significantly ahead in development, and I decided to dedicate my full attention to it for the foreseeable future. Once we ship it then the sky will be the limit.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/45-PARABELLUM-BLOODHOUND_2024_07-03-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Who’s Working on This?</strong></p><p>That would be me as writer and director, with a friend who prefers to be anonymous as the programmer and co-creator (we came up with the story, gameplay and characters together maaany years ago). Merengedoll (of <em>VA-11 Hall-A</em> kids! fame), always the soldier, has been helping me out with character, enemy, boss and production design. Juneji (also from <em>VA-11 Hall-A</em> kids!) is doing the soundtrack and some 3D work; and for the first time ever we have someone managing our asses to move things forward at a nice pace.</p><p>If you’re familiar with my solo outing then you kinda know what to expect in terms of vibes and story; for better and for worse.</p><p><strong>Stray Notes</strong></p><ul><li>Spanish, English and Japanese localizations are being planned for day one (hoping for more, but these three are the ones within our current bandwidth).</li><li>No downloadable demo planned as maintaining a separate build will probably drive us crazy.</li><li>After a couple reboots the current incarnation of the project has been under development for roughly two years, but if we wanna get cheeky, me and the programmer have been talking about doing something like this since high school. It really makes you think.</li><li><em>VA-11 Hall-A</em>, when it came to my contributions to its visuals and atmosphere, was very much a pastiche of inspirations both subtle and in-your-face. This time around I’ve been trying to isolate my brain from external influences as much as possible outside of the initial spark for the battle system and other mechanics. Games take a lot of work to make, so I’d like to deliver a uniquely “Sukeban” experience; whatever it may entail.</li></ul><p><strong>For Those in Japan: Play It at Bitsummit Drift!</strong></p><p>Lucky people in the Kyoto area can get a taste of the game’s first chapter at this year’s BitSummit Drift. July 19 (business day), 20, and 21.</p><p>Do come check it out!</p><p>We plan to exhibit the game at more events around the world in the coming future but we don’t have many details at the moment. Stay tuned.</p><p>For those who can’t attend, we’ll be releasing the game’s first trailer on [July 19]! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@sukeban498" rel="noopener" target="_blank">This is our YouTube channel</a>.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/45-PARABELLUM-BLOODHOUND_2024_07-03-24_006.png"></a></figure></blockquote><p>View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/45-parabellum-bloodhound/july-3-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_896640"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Training the game designers of tomorrow (part 1 of 5)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/training-the-game-designers-of-tomorrow-part-1-of-5-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/training-the-game-designers-of-tomorrow-part-1-of-5.917955/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/training-the-game-designers-of-tomorrow-part-1-of-5-<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Many schools offer quality training in game design, but being trained in game design is not enough to become a game designer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To fully integrate into a team and thrive, a game designer must develop soft skills and new skills that are not systematically offered in school training.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This publication series aims to better prepare future game designers for their missions. I draw on my experience as a game designer, lead designer, and trainer.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="To be or not to be …">To be or not to be …</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If there is one aspect that differentiates veterans from novices, it is mastery of soft skills. What is it about?</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Soft skills correspond to an individual's personal qualities and behaviors within a team. Called soft skills in English, they become more and more important when recruiting a future member of a development team.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">You will easily find generalities on essential skills in the studio, such as being a team player, respecting requests to the letter, or being very demanding regarding your own work. But today, I would like to share with you other very concrete soft skills that are the fruit of my 28 years of experience as a game designer.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Soft skills 1 - Always follow the implementation of your design">Soft skills 1 - Always follow the implementation of your design</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Just because you have written a design document does not mean it will be developed to the letter. The reasons may be multiple: The programmer or artist may misunderstand your design intentions and not ask you for an explanation, a technical requirement may prevent its implementation exactly as you envisioned, your design document may be missing of clarity, or quite simply, not to be read! I have personally experienced all of these situations.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In such circumstances, your most conscientious colleagues will ask you questions or seek instructions, but not all will do so. It is, therefore, your responsibility to ensure that your design is correctly understood and implemented. Never forget that you will be blamed if the gameplay is mediocre, not the team members who put it in place, even if they did not respect your specifications!</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Good practices">Good practices</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To avoid this type of problem, the best practices are as follows:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Write design documents that are as precise as possible AND easy to read</span></p></div></li></ul></div><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Don't develop a huge design document; no one will read it. Instead, write several design documents, each focused on a game experience, and implement them one after the other.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Don’t just send your design documents to the appropriate team members; present the main lines of your design to them orally and with diagrams.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Check that the functionality developed corresponds to what you have defined</span></p></div></li></ul></div><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Spend a lot of time testing, testing, and testing the game again.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Case study">Case study</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To illustrate my point, I will share situations I have witnessed or experienced with you. Of course, the names are fictitious to preserve each person's anonymity.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Luigi is a game designer for an action-adventure game in which the main character is accompanied by a teammate. He designs the mechanics that manage the teammate's behavior, the places he goes, the attitude he adopts, and the actions he takes. This mechanic is based on the positioning of waypoints by the level design team.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Luigi simply wrote a detailed design document and trusted the rest of the team to correctly implement his design.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>But the artistic team goes after the level designer and modifies the map's topology: Certain passage points are found under the ground or hidden by added decorative elements.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>As a result, the functionality works poorly, and the gameplay seems inconsistent. Luigi doesn't realize what happened because he doesn't spend enough time testing the new content. Poorly highlighted, the functionality is ultimately abandoned.</span></span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Soft skills 2 - Prepare intelligently for the meetings to which you are invited">Soft skills 2 - Prepare intelligently for the meetings to which you are invited</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If a meeting is well organized, it has an agenda and a list of topics to be discussed. If you are invited to a meeting, it is because your contribution is considered valuable. Your ideas and opinions are, therefore, expected.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If, during the meeting, a subject is put on the table and you have not had time to think about it beforehand, your contribution will be superficial or even counterproductive. You risk coming across as someone who “counts for nothing”, a simple performer who brings no added value. And if you improvise a response to show presence, you risk saying something without any point, something which will ultimately tarnish your image.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Good practices">Good practices</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If you are invited to a meeting, here are the best practices to follow:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Read the meeting agenda carefully. If there is none, ask the meeting organizer to specify the topics that will be covered; you will then be able to prepare yourself and give yourself the image of a good professional.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Take some time to think about the themes that will be covered, and that fall within your expertise. The simple fact of thinking with a clear head will allow you to make more relevant proposals but, above all to construct an argument to defend them.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Case study">Case study</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Here is a new illustration of what to do...and not to do:</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>John is invited to a meeting organized by the project's creative director. Other game designers will also be present. The agenda specifies that we will discuss a feature in the game that is not satisfactory: cooperative action between two players from the same side.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>When the creative director puts the subject on the table and asks the game designers present for their opinion, John, who has not really thought about the problem, is uncomfortable and settles for a very general proposal. But Emma, the other game designer, makes another proposal and illustrates it with a diagram. A drawing is much more understandable than a speech, and she reinforces her proposition by citing games that use the solution she proposes.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>John weakened his position on the team, while Emma emerged as making a better contribution to the project. His solution is chosen not because it is better but because it is presented in a more convincing manner.</span></span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Soft skills 3 - Be humble and open to changes">Soft skills 3 - Be humble and open to changes</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A game designer is always attached to his work to his ideas. It's normal. But a game mechanic remains a mere figment; we can never be sure of its interest until it has been developed and integrated into the game. In other words, an idea may seem very good on paper but may turn out to be disappointing once implemented.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This situation is common.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Indeed, the quality of the player's experience results from the interaction between many aspects of the game: its mechanics, settings, rhythm, the player's objectives, complexity, etc. A mechanic can effectively contribute to a quality experience in one game but be detrimental in another.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Therefore, a game designer must demonstrate modesty and develop a spirit of self-criticism. He must objectively analyze the relevance of his design choices. He must listen to the opinions of other members of his team. Above all, he must take into account the feedback from the playtests.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Therefore, he must be ready to start from scratch if a game mechanic is not satisfactory. Experience shows that if a game mechanic does not work, simple improvements may not be enough; it is often preferable to start again with a new mechanism.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Some young game designers tend to defend their ideas against all odds; they make it a personal matter. They are wrong. Their interest is that their name is associated with a published and effective game rather than their ideas being retained in a mediocre or never-published one.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Common sense advice? This is not the case for everyone. Here is a new illustration of the consequences when a designer persists in defending “his” vision of the game.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Case study">Case study</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Igor is the lead-level designer on a multiplayer game for home consoles. The first playtests, carried out with players from outside the studio and representatives of the targeted audience, validate the game mechanics but point out problems in the maps: They are too large in relation to the number of players, the latter get lost easily, and they have too many bottlenecks.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The playtest sessions follow one another. Each session comprises players who have never played the game and all report the same problems related to level design. The problems cited by the playtesters are nevertheless systematically reported to Igor after each playtest session, but the modifications made to the maps are minor and do not change the feedback from the playtesters.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>After several months, faced with Igor's reluctance to fundamentally change the maps, the studio management removed him from his position and replaced him with another team member.</span></span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="To be continued …">To be continued …</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the next part of this publication, I will discuss the other essential skills, in my eyes, for a game or level designer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pascal Luban</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game designer &amp; creative director, freelance</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">28+ years of experience serving game developers and publishers</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://www.gamedesignstudio.com/">www.gamedesignstudio.com</a></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Photo credit: Poca Wander Stock</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Blogger</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pascal Luban is a freelance creative director and game designer based in France. He has been working in the game industry as a game or level designer since 1995 and has been commissioned by major studios and publishers including Activision, SCEE, Ubisoft and DICE. In particular, he was Lead Level Designer on the 'versus' multiplayer versions of both Splinter Cell: Pandora Tomorrow and Chaos Theory, he designed CTF-Tornado, a UT3 mod multiplayer map built to showcase the applications of physics to gameplay, he was creative Director on Wanted – Weapons of Fate and lead game designer on Fighters Uncaged, the first combat game for Kinect. His first game for mobile platforms, The One Hope, was published in 2007 by the Irish publishers Gmedia and has received the Best In Gaming award at the 2009 Digital Media Awards of Dublin. Leveraging his design experience on console and PC titles, Pascal is also working on social and Free-to-Play games. He contributed to the game design of Kartoon, a Facebook game currently under development at Kadank, he did a design mission on Treasure Madness, zSlide's successful Free-to-Play game and completed several design missions for French and American clients. Pascal is content director for the video game program at CIFACOM, a French school focusing on the new media industry.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spy Drops Is Randomly-Generated Metal Gear Solid for the Modern Era]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/spy-drops-metal-gear-stealth</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spy-drops-is-randomly-generated-metal-gear-solid-for-the-modern-era.917931/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/spy-drops-metal-gear-stealth<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Rainy Frog and solo developer Rainy Night Creations have announced&nbsp;<em>Spy Drops</em>, a 3D stealth-action roguelite very heavily inspired by late-90s stealth classics like&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Syphon Filter</em>.</p>
<p><em>Spy Drops&nbsp;</em>casts you as a member of the titular Spy Drops team, a counter-terrorist organization dispatched to prevent an "eco-terrorist organization" from "wiping out all digital records and sending the world back to the Stone Age".</p>
<p>In true&nbsp;<em>Deus Ex&nbsp;</em>fashion, however, what begins as a simple mission quickly becomes more complex, and it's not long before you're questioning your mission objectives and "uncover[ing] a deeper conspiracy".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/spy-drops-announcement-gameplay.jpg?itok=Q2h33Uxt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/spy-drops-announcement-gameplay.jpg?itok=55xDk-BB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Spy Drops&nbsp;</em>isn't shy about its&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid&nbsp;</em>influence.</figcaption></figure><p>Gameplay-wise, if you've played&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid</em>, you'll know roughly what to expect from&nbsp;<em>Spy Drops</em>; it's a pseudo-top-down 3D stealth-action game with an emphasis on remaining undetected and using non-lethal methods to deal with guards.</p>
<p>Unlike <i>Metal Gear</i>, however,&nbsp;<em>Spy Drops</em>' levels are randomly-generated, which strikes me as a bit of a shame; one of&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear</em>'s strengths was its iconic level design, so it seems a bit sad to throw that aspect of the game away.</p>
<p>Still, Rainy Frog says randomized missions guarantee a "tense gameplay experience", as you don't know what awaits you around each corner, ensuring that each player's "game will be different". Hmm. I'm not sure how true that is in practise.</p>
<p>To complete your mission, you'll have access to a host of gadgets, including drones, night vision goggles, mine detectors, and more, and you'll be able to take a variety of approaches to each mission as well.</p>

<p>As a huge&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear&nbsp;</em>fan, I've got my eye on this one, although I'm slightly troubled by the disclaimer on the Steam page that the developer has used generative AI "for dialogues (audio) and icons". Yuck.</p>
<p><em>Spy Drops&nbsp;</em>doesn't have a release date yet, but when it does arrive, it'll be available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3034070/Spy_Drops/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor">PC</a> and Nintendo Switch. Watch this space for more info.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster Has Classic Frank and Even Chuck Skins, but Only if You Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-has-classic-frank-and-even-chuck-skins-but-only-if-you-preorder</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-has-classic-frank-and-even-chuck-skins-but-only-if-you-preorder.917928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-has-classic-frank-and-even-chuck-skins-but-only-if-you-preorder<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster completely refreshes the original game but fans who don't love the revised character design of protagonist Frank West can switch back to the original — as long as they preorder.</p><p>The wholly single player game, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-release-date-revealed-will-run-in-4k-and-60fps-in-re-engine">which arrives September 19, 2024</a> at $50 or $60 for the Digital Deluxe Edition, comes with preorder bonuses too, publisher Capcom revealed in an X/Twitter post. Players gain access to the Frank West 2006 skin, the Chuck Greene Skin (from Dead Rising 2), and the Willamette Parkview Mall Bee skin alongside three music tracks.</p><p>This bonus content isn't included in the Digital Deluxe Edition content by default either despite it including myriad skin packs including ones from Resident Evil and Mega Man. Capcom hasn't announced post launch pricings for additional content but the original Frank West and other skins will likely be available for an additional cost.</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Dead Rising (@DeadRising) <a href="https://twitter.com/DeadRising/status/1807912242991477189?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 1, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>While this is fairly standard for a 2024 video game, many fans have already expressed dislike for the updated Frank West model so will likely be frustrated to hear they can only mitigate that grievance by committing to buy the game early (or perhaps paying extra later).</p><p>"2024 Frank West looks like 2006 Frank West in 2024," one fan commented on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/1dtdef3/for_some_reason_capcom_decided_to_age_up_frank/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a>. "This Frank West 2006 outfit genuinely fixes the main issue I have with the remaster changes, so it's a bit mad to hide that behind a preorder bonus," X/Twitter user <a href="https://x.com/Toadsanime/status/1808202938226978905?t=034t2YZak3bSlU9DfGKo3A&amp;s=03" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Toadsanime</a> said. "But at least it's here."</p><p>The look isn't the only thing changing, however, as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/original-frank-west-voice-actor-says-capcom-didnt-ask-him-to-return-for-dead-rising-deluxe-remaster">original Frank West voice actor Terence J. Rotolo isn't returning for the remaster</a>. "I simply wasn't called for this mission," he said.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-release-date-revealed-will-run-in-4k-and-60fps-in-re-engine">Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster launches </a>with 4k graphics and 60 frames per second support and running in the RE Engine. Capcom has made quality of live improvements too, "fine tuned" the interface, added autosave functionality, and more.</p><p>In <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2006/08/07/dead-rising-review-2">our 8/10 review of the original Dead Rising</a>, IGN said: "Though Dead Rising may seem like a simple, mindless game when you first pick it up, it eventually reveals itself as a deeper experience."</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Plague Tale: Requiem headlines Humble Bundle's July Choice games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/a-plague-tale-requiem-headlines-humble-bundles-july-choice-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-plague-tale-requiem-headlines-humble-bundles-july-choice-games.917916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/a-plague-tale-requiem-headlines-humble-bundles-july-choice-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>The bundle building team at Humble has detailed the games included in July's Choice bundle, with A Plague Tale: Requiem being a highlight.</p>
<p>Humble Choice is a subscription service which offers a monthly set of PC games for its members to own forever.</p>
<p>This month's selection of eight games are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>A Plague Tale: Requiem</li>
<li>Ghostrunner 2</li>
<li>Starship Troopers: Terran Command</li>
<li>Sticky Business</li>
<li>Zoeti</li>
<li>Figment 2: Creed Valley</li>
<li>Heretic's Fork</li>
<li>Hyperviolent</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="A Plague Tale: Requiem - Gameplay Overview Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aaT4Q4NGm-A?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>A Plague Tale: Requiem - Gameplay Overview Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aaT4Q4NGm-A?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/aaT4Q4NGm-A?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>A Plague Tale: Requiem - Gameplay Overview Trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aaT4Q4NGm-A" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As with previous months, five percent of Choice membership will go towards charitable causes.</p>
<p>This month, Humble is supporting Covenant House, which is "dedicated to supporting young people facing homelessness and survivors of trafficking through unconditional love, absolute respect, and relentless support, in 34 cities across six countries". You can <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OjsV5BvoJPc">find out more about what Covenant House does here</a>.</p>
<p>(And a quick note - Eurogamer has covered Humble for years, but the company is now also a part of the same parent company, IGN Entertainment.)</p>
<p>As for the games themselves, A Plague Tale: Requiem (pictured above) is an incredibly emotional stealth action adventure, set in 14th century France.</p>
<p>Our Bertie called it a "brutal, spectacular adventure of love and sacrifice" in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-plague-tale-requiem-review-a-brutal-spectacular-adventure-of-love-and-sacrifice">Eurogamer's A Plague Tale: Requiem review</a>. "Requiem, simply put, is one of the finest adventures around," he wrote in 2022.</p>
<p>Ghostrunner 2 (pictured below), meanwhile, is a first-person slasher from One More Level. Bertie also gave the Ghostrunner sequel a whirl on its release, having been a big fan of the original.</p>
<p>"On the one hand, everything I like about the original is back. It's got the moves, it's got the sounds, it's got that garish cyberpunk cool, and it's got pace... Great," he wrote <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-weve-been-playing-134">after a few hours with Ghostrunner 2</a>. </p>
<p>"But on the other hand, it has a lot more stuff," Bertie continued, adding things such as the story "makes it all seem a bit messy and convoluted".
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_7ed2c1ee19d4b6f9d09959e5197349e6ce69e4f7.1920x1080.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>One More Level</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>You can check out this month's <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com/membership">full Choice bundle collection via Humble here</a>. Has anything taken your fancy?</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Banjo-Kazooie Game Is Currently on the Cards at Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/no-banjo-kazooie-game-is-currently-on-the-cards-at-xbox/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-banjo-kazooie-game-is-currently-on-the-cards-at-xbox.917913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/no-banjo-kazooie-game-is-currently-on-the-cards-at-xbox/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ever since Rare was acquired by Microsoft in 2002, fans have been pining for the revival of its trademark IPs, such as Conker and Banjo-Kazooie.</p>
<p>Truth be told, Xbox did attempt to do something with those franchises in the first few years since the acquisition. Rare released Conker: Live &amp; Reloaded (featuring a remake of the original installment Conker: Bad Fur Day) on the original Xbox in 2005, while Banjo-Kazooie fans had to wait until 2008, when Rare released the brand new Nuts &amp; Bolts game for the Xbox 360.</p>
<p>However, Banjo-Kazooie: Nuts &amp; Bolts largely diverged from previous games in the platform franchise. Its gameplay was more focused on vehicle construction (which was excellent for the time, powered by Havok physics) rather than traditional platforming. The game's focus on building/crafting was certainly way ahead of its time, and it didn't sell nearly as well as Microsoft and Rare had hoped.</p>
<p>To this day, Nuts &amp; Bolts remains the latest entry in the series. It has been repackaged in Rare's Replay, released in 2015 for the UK studio's 30th anniversary, but there's been no more solace for Banjo-Kazooie fans from Rare, unless you count the Bear &amp; Bird Figurehead <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-sea-of-thieves-update-1-1-5-banjo-kazooie/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">added</a> a few years ago in Sea of Thieves. Thankfully, a few ex-Rare developers founded Playtonic and created a fairly successful spiritual successor, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/yooka-laylee-on-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yooka-Laylee</a>, which is now getting a remaster called Yooka-Replaylee with improved art, animations, moveset, camera, controls, and soundtrack.</p>
<p>But are Rare and/or Microsoft planning to do anything with Banjo-Kazooie? According to Windows Central's Jez Corden, absolutely not. Speaking on the subject <a href="https://youtu.be/EbOmQqPNpsU?si=ZnxwFb-YbmGdU5qq&amp;t=1246" target="_blank" rel="noopener">during the latest XB2+1 podcast</a>, he said:</p>
<p><em>I can tell you right now, categorically, there is no Banjo game in development. As of the recording of this podcast, there is no Banjo game in development.</em></p>
<p>Rare is certainly busy with the continued support of Sea of Thieves, especially following the launch on PlayStation, and with the development of Everwild, which remains a mystery. Microsoft would have to choose an external partner to make a game based on the IP.</p>
<p>Would you like to see the dynamic duo return in some capacity, or should they be left in the past?</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam isn't the only place having a summer sale, as Itch.io launches its own sunny deals]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-isnt-the-only-place-having-a-summer-sale-as-itchio-launches-its-own-sunny-deals</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-isnt-the-only-place-having-a-summer-sale-as-itch-io-launches-its-own-sunny-deals.917907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-isnt-the-only-place-having-a-summer-sale-as-itchio-launches-its-own-sunny-deals<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/itch-vs-steam-summer-sale-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Graffiti Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>You might have seen that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-how-were-all-spending-our-last-tenner-on-the-best-deals-in-the-steam-summer-sale">£10 will go a long way in the Steam summer sale</a>, but let me do you one better. Indie game store Itch.io has begun <a href="https://itch.io/sales">its own summer sale</a>, and for those willing to delve into its rainbow-coloured heap of throwaway toys and fun experiments, plenty of deals await.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The sale starts today and ends July 12th. There are quite a few tasty nuggets deep in the creases of this bargainous sofa. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/turnip-boy-commits-tax-evasion">Turnip Boy Commits Tax Evasion</a> sees a <a href="https://graffiti-games.itch.io/tbcte">hefty price slash</a><a></a>. Surreal JRPG <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hylics">Hylics</a> gets <a href="https://mason-lindroth.itch.io/hylics">the same</a>. Comedy browser censorship sim <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hypnospace-outlaw">Hypnospace Outlaw</a> has <a href="https://jay-tholen.itch.io/hypnospace-outlaw">a chunky discount</a>. Architecturally unnerving refugee simulation <a href="https://gabriel-helfenstein.itch.io/north">North</a> has a <a href="https://gabriel-helfenstein.itch.io/north">big price cut</a>. And mildly unsettling Zelda-like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/anodyne">Anodyne</a> is also <a href="https://han-tani.itch.io/anodyne">going cheap</a>. Yes, some of these are also currently discounted on Steam too, but I know some of you loathe Valve enough to never set digi-foot in their digi-mart. So this is a good alternative, a local car boot sale that will probably see creators get more money per sale. </p>
<p>Aside from games, Itch has also long been a good place for hobbyist developers to pick up <a href="https://itch.io/game-assets/on-sale">assets</a> and ultra-specific tools for game development. The bright <a href="https://johanpeitz.itch.io/picocad">low poly modeling tool PicoCAD</a> is on sale, for example, and so is chiptune music maker <a href="https://1oogames.itch.io/lovely-composer">Lovely Composer</a>. </p>
<p>One little tip: if you see nothing but sex games when you log into Itch, that's no surprise. Like Steam, it's a wild west of boobs in there. This can make it hard to find the stuff you're after. To hide the hodgepodge of horniness you can go to your <a href="https://itch.io/user/settings">user settings</a> and untick a box that says "Show content marked as adult in search &amp; browse". Or don't, I'm not judging. Some of that stuff is on sale too.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Xbox Layoffs at Microsoft Inbound This Week, Tom Warren Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/more-xbox-layoffs-at-microsoft-inbound-this-week-tom-warren-claims/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/more-xbox-layoffs-at-microsoft-inbound-this-week-tom-warren-claims.917904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/more-xbox-layoffs-at-microsoft-inbound-this-week-tom-warren-claims/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following <a href="https://wccftech.com/four-months-after-the-merger-with-activision-blizzard-microsoft-is-laying-off-1900-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">layoffs this January</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-shuts-down-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-a-couple-more-bethesda-softworks-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">studio closures in May</a>, Microsoft is cutting more Xbox jobs this week, the Verge's Tom Warren has claimed.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Xbox's Jessie Thomas announced on X that her role at Microsoft was "eliminated". After this post on X, Tom Warren responded that more Xbox layoffs will be happening this week. While many suspected that it was just Thomas&nbsp;that was let go, Warren has now clarified that more individuals at Xbox will be losing their jobs. "more Xbox layoffs happening this week", Warren <a href="https://x.com/tomwarren/status/1808346995473433069" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> some hours ago. "Microsoft laid off Jessie while she was on vacation". For those in the unknown, Thomas has been with Microsoft since 2015, and served as&nbsp;Senior Business PM of Culture Programs as of 2022.</p>
<p>An hour ago, The Verge reporter <a href="https://x.com/tomwarren/status/1808446740200149347" target="_blank" rel="noopener">clarified</a>, "as per my tweet, it’s not just one person".</p>
<p>While we haven't seen messages from other Microsoft/Xbox employees having been laid off today or earlier this week, it's likely that we'll be hearing more in the coming days. As always, we'll update you as soon as we learn more about this matter.</p>
<p>Earlier today we already reported that&nbsp;Tales of Kenzera ZAU Developer Surgent Studios <a href="https://wccftech.com/tales-of-kenzera-zau-surgent-studios-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">was hit by layoffs as well</a>. According to the studio, a dozen of people had to be let go.</p>
<p>Following the massive wave of layoffs at Microsoft this January, Microsoft announced the closure of three Xbox studios this May - affected studios included Tango Gameworks, Arkane Austin and several other Bethesda Softworks studios. After the announced studio closures, we <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-will-cut-more-jobs-arkane-tango-pitching-new-projects-before-closure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported that its expected that Xbox will be cutting more jobs</a>. Games Industry Analyst Rhys Elliott from <a href="https://www.midiaresearch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MIDiA Research</a> suggested that Xbox is refocusing on something more bigger. <em>"Xbox, despite its smart PR over the past years, likely sees these studio closures as a ‘’you need to break a few eggs to make an omelet’’ kind of situation" </em>he said back in May<em>. "It is a massive shame that those eggs are some of the most talented developers in the industry, and now their lives have been uprooted. "</em></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero Pre-Load Details Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/zenless-zone-zero-pre-load-details-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-pre-load-details-revealed.917901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/zenless-zone-zero-pre-load-details-revealed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Zenless Zone Zero, the upcoming action RPG by Genshin Impact creators Hoyoverse, arrives tomorrow, July 4, 2024, for PlayStation 5, Android, iOS and PC via Epic Games Store.</p>



<p>Interested players can pre-load Zenless Zone Zero through their respective platforms, which comes with a special bonus of up to <a href="https://zenless.hoyoverse.com/en-us/?no_entry=true&amp;reserve=true&amp;utm_source=sns&amp;utm_medium=CM_Twitter&amp;af_sub5=sns&amp;pid=CM_Twitter&amp;is_retargeting=TRUE&amp;af_reengagement_window=lifetime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">100 free pulls and 80 Boopons</a>. These pulls and Boopons are valuable in-game resources that can be used to acquire influential A-Rank Agents, A-Rank W Engines, and more, giving you a head start in the game.</p>



<p>Hoyoverse recently highlighted the content you can access in New Eridu, the post-apocalyptic city from Zenless Zone Zero. This city is a sprawling metropolis with several distinct districts offering unique challenges and rewards. Players can explore ‘Random Play’, ‘Sixth Street’, ‘Lumina Square’ and ‘Scott Outpost’. The reception rate for limited Agents Ellen, Zhu Yuan, and W-Engine Deep Sea Visitor has also been boosted, making this the perfect time to jump into the game.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Zenless Zone Zero New Eridu Popular Content</p><p>Dear Proxies,<br>Zenless Zone Zero officially launches on 2024/07/04 at 10:00 (UTC+8).<br>Thank you all for your patience! The entrance to New Eridu is about to open!<br>Get your gear and keep hold of your Bangboo. Let's go!</p><p>※ For Proxies… <a href="https://t.co/ezN4JcZnX2">pic.twitter.com/ezN4JcZnX2</a></p></div>— Zenless Zone Zero (@ZZZ_EN) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZZZ_EN/status/1808433058628161711?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Furthermore, the game is packed with new content, including three thrilling story chapters, including the newly updated Chapter 3: The Midnight Pursuit. Players can also look forward to engaging in new Agent Story missions, such as ‘Koleda’s Story’, ‘Rina’s Story’, and ‘Lycaon’s Story’. </p>



<p>And that’s not all! There are four exciting new events to keep an eye out for when Zenless Zone Zero launches, including ‘Friendship Supervision’, ‘Watch Your Step’, ‘141 Exclusive Bazaar’, and ‘Don’t Get Greedy, Vicious Dogs Within’.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we gear up for the release of Zenless Zone Zero, check out Insider Gaming’s reports detailing the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/zenless-zone-zero-pc-requirements-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">system requirements</a> for the game and providing an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-kind-of-game-is-zenless-zone-zero-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in-depth look at what kind of game it is</a>. Are you planning to pre-load Zenless Zone Zero? We’d love to hear your thoughts in the comments below.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tales-of-kenzera-zau-studio-hit-with-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">layoffs at the developer of Tales of Kenzera: Zau</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring's new Thrusting Shields make Shadow of the Erdtree difficulty trivial, players say]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-new-thrusting-shields-make-shadow-of-the-erdtree-difficulty-trivial-players-say</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-rings-new-thrusting-shields-make-shadow-of-the-erdtree-difficulty-trivial-players-say.917898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-new-thrusting-shields-make-shadow-of-the-erdtree-difficulty-trivial-players-say<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ELDEN-RING-Shadow-of-the-Erdtree-_-Official-Gameplay-Reveal-Trailer-2-32-screenshot-(2)-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-tips-and-tricks">Elden Ring DLC</a> Shadow of the Erdtree introduced <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-thrusting-shield-locations">Thrusting Shields</a> as a new weapon type, but some players believe they're overpowered to the point of being "absolutely busted".
</p>
<p>
You may have spotted in the DLC's gameplay trailer the player character leaping through the air with a spiked shield. This is one of many new weapon types, with two shields to choose from: the Dueling Shield and Carian Thrusting Shield.
</p>
<p>
Both shields have the Shield Strike skill that uses the shield to attack. And if attacking and blocking at the same time seems overpowered, well it is.
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree | Official Gameplay Reveal Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8GDtwdMBhhI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>

"New Thrusting shields are the strongest weapons in the entire game and it's not even close," wrote DamnHare on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dtks1t/new_thrusting_shields_are_the_strongest_weapons/">Elden Ring subreddit</a>. "NG+ DLC was absolutely obliterated. Thrusting shields can be enchanted with any affinity/damage type that makes them extremely versatile. And it's just so much fun to slap the grace out of every single boss!"
</p>
<p>
Many others agree. As <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-players-are-sleepwalking-through-bossfights-with-the-dlcs-silly-pointy-shields/">PC Gamer</a> points out, the shields can be modified with any damage type and scaling and work particularly well with certain talismans like the Spear Talisman for extra counterattack damage, and the Two-Handed Sword Talisman for a two-handed damage boost.
</p>
<p>
You can also throw in the Sekiro-esque Deflecting Hardtear too to strengthen guard counters and voila, the ultimate tank build!
</p>
<p>
One response to DamnHare's post claimed the Thrusting Shields are "absolutely busted" and how that player beat the final boss. "Being able to guard counter to break poise while not worrying about timing and only taking chip damage is insane. Being able to just spam attacks and tank through everything only taking chip damage is insane," said Drstrangelove899. "The stamina drain from attacking through attack seems really minimal even against massive boss attacks. And its damage is really good as well, especially as its attacks are considered thrust and benefit from the spear talisman."
</p>
<p>
Here's Japanese X user pirochanbanzai showing just how effective this build can be.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aE0FmjAPc8g">YouTuber Larry Puss</a> has also put together a video of the build, explaining how it just requires players to spam two buttons (beware of boss spoilers in the video).

</p>
<p>
Of course, some players will prefer a different fighting style and may consider these tactics as cheap. But if you're struggling with bosses, you could consider changing your build to this. At the least, it's amusing how Soulsborne games have slowly moved away from tank builds only to find shields might just be the strongest weapons in Elden Ring after all.
</p>
<p>
It's also your cue to change up your weapon tactics from the base game and try one of the new weapon types. I, for one, have slapped bleed on the Dryleaf Arts to pummel dragons in the face - it's a lot of fun.
</p>
<p>
Many Shadow of the Erdtree players criticised the DLC for being too difficult and the game received a negative rating on Steam for this and performance issues. However, it's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-has-recovered-to-a-mostly-positive-steam-rating">since turned this around and now has a "Mostly Positive" response</a>.


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard difficulty options let you turn off death, and manually adjust enemy health]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-difficulty-options-let-you-turn-off-death-and-manually-adjust-enemy-health</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-difficulty-options-let-you-turn-off-death-and-manually-adjust-enemy-health.917895/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-difficulty-options-let-you-turn-off-death-and-manually-adjust-enemy-health<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"To make sure players of all abilities can show up."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Dragon-Age-The-Veilguard.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>BioWare</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dragon-age-dreadwolf">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> will let you escape death entirely as part of its extensive difficulty customisation options, which will also let you manually adjust player and enemy health.
</p>
<p>
As detailed to <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive/2024/07/01/a-look-at-dragon-age-the-veilguards-difficulty-options-and-gameplay">Game Informer</a>, BioWare has included a range of set difficulty levels and a further option that offers more granular customisation of your play experience. 
</p>
<p>
The Veilguard's base levels are named Storyteller, Adventurer and Nightmare - the latter of which is a permanent choice, while the former options can be flitted between. There's also a further option, Unbound, which offers difficulty editing on the fly.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Official Gameplay Reveal" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Official Gameplay Reveal</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Dragon Age: The Veilguard gameplay reveal.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CTNwHShylIg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Unbound options include enabling aim assistance or auto-aim if you so choose, adjusting the difficulty of parrying enemy attacks, upping your own damage output, and even tweaking the general health pools of enemies and how much they'll press you in combat. Finally, there's an option to disable death entirely, so you'll never see a Game Over screen. 
</p>
<p>
"[None of these options] are a cheat," game director Corinne Busche told Game Informer. "It's an option to make sure players of all abilities can show up."  
</p>
<p>
BioWare lifted the lid on Dragon Age: The Veilguard last month after years in development. There's still no launch date, but the suggestion seems to be that the long-awaited role-playing game is now very close to release.
</p>
<p>
Eurogamer went hands-on with the game last month, and came away thoroughly impressed. "Whisper it, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/whisper-it-but-dragon-age-the-veilguard-has-me-thinking-the-unthinkable-it-looks-like-bioware-is-back">Dragon Age: The Veilguard has me thinking the unthinkable</a>: it looks like BioWare is back," our Chris Tapsell wrote. 
</p>




        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wuthering Waves was unleashed on the Steam Deck, but only for one day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuthering-waves-was-unleashed-on-the-steam-deck-but-only-for-one-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wuthering-waves-was-unleashed-on-the-steam-deck-but-only-for-one-day.917892/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuthering-waves-was-unleashed-on-the-steam-deck-but-only-for-one-day<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Updates giveth, updates taketh away</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Wuthering-Waves-Steam-Deck-gameplay.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/wuthering-waves">Wuthering Waves</a>, that recent gacha <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> of anime styling and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuthering-waves-dialogue-and-writing-is-kind-of-bad">impenetrable jargonblasting</a>, just <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuthering-waves-really-really-doesnt-want-to-run-on-steam-deck">didn’t work on the Steam Deck</a> when it launched in May. It also doesn’t work right now. But for one brief, debatably glorious day on June 29th, it did. And thus, Deck owners who’d persevered through a slightly fiddly installation process (explained <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SuP-MtGV1IY">here</a> by YouTubesmith Deck Wizard) could finally take their first joyous steps into Wuthering Waves like a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SNpCn0nAlR0">David Hasselhoff-buoyed</a> East German in 1989.</p>
<p>Unlike the Hoff, it wouldn’t last. Within hours, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-games">Steam Deck</a> players were being booted back out of the game by a hitherto-unseen anti-cheat failure. What gives? Or gave?</p>
<!--more-->
<p>In short, Wuthering Waves’ 1.1 update seemingly altered said anti-cheat in such a way that enabled the game to launch on Linux-based operating systems, including the Deck’s SteamOS. Previously, it was possible to install the Windows version of the game launcher, but actually getting into the game itself proved impossible. Version 1.1 not only allowed the launcher to launch Wuthering Waves, but for the game to become fully playable, if by most accounts a bit slow on the Deck’s modest processing bits.</p>
<p>Still, before you could say "Absorption is only possible when your Data Bank’s level is equal to higher than the Tacet Discord’s level", or indeed understand whatever the fuck that means, a scary-looking "Anti-cheat system works error" message appeared to forcibly close Wuthering Waves back down. A follow-up update, it turns out, changed the game’s anti-cheat to again block out Linux devices. Only, after a few seconds of playing, as opposed to blocking the game launch entirely, which is a kind of progress? I guess?</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Wuthering-Waves-Steam-Deck-anti-cheat.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>That brings us to the here and now, where Wuthering Waves can still launch on the Steam Deck, and might even provide a few moments of wandering around in-game, but from what I’ve tested it’s only a matter of seconds before the anti-cheat message arrives. There’s no overt threat of a ban (or any other punishment), but yeah, I wouldn’t risk pushing it even if you spent that single day of freedom with a smile.</p>
<p>I nonetheless feel compelled to keep an eye on this (and indeed, thanks to reader Scotty for the tip). While I’m not particularly keen to play more Wuthering Waves, on the Steam Deck or anything else, I’ve now pumped enough of my time into setup and launch attempts that this specific game/hardware combo has become the blubberiest of white whales. You think another solo-manned <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-amazon-prime-day-pc-gaming-deals-2024">Prime Day</a> will kill me? Nah mate, it’ll be trying to trying to launch the magic waifus game on my handheld. Someone take over the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-academy">Steam Deck Academy</a> when I’m gone.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RoboCop Developer Teyon Is Recruiting for a New Action RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/robocop-developer-teyon-is-recruiting-for-a-new-action-rpg/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robocop-developer-teyon-is-recruiting-for-a-new-action-rpg.917889/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/robocop-developer-teyon-is-recruiting-for-a-new-action-rpg/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/robocop-rogue-city-gets-new-gameplay-trailer-september-launch-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RoboCop: Rogue City</a> developer Teyon is already recruiting for a new project, and it looks like the studio is planning to switch genres. The developer is known for making shooter games (they also released <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/terminator-resistance-enhanced-new-paint-over-rusted-chrome/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Terminator: Resistance</a>), but this time, they are making an action roleplaying game, as <a href="https://teyon.elevato.net/en/regularsenior-c-game-programmer,j,127" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a> in a job offer.</p>
<p><em>Teyon is an experienced development studio with numerous titles to his credit. We employ over 100 employees, and apart from Krakow, we are also located in Łódź, Warsaw and even Tokyo.</em><br>
<em>Teyon is looking for talented people who will support us with their skills, knowledge, and ideas in our upcoming project. This new action RPG game for PC and console will be developed by the team responsible for our previous titles, Terminator: Resistance and RoboCop: Rogue City.</em></p>
<p>This job ad also reveals that the unannounced action RPG project is being backed by a 'major publisher'. Both RoboCop: Rogue City and Terminator: Resistance were published by Nacon, which, however, cannot really be considered a big publisher. As such, Teyon (an independent studio) may have partnered with some other company for this one.</p>
<p>Both Terminator: Resistance and RoboCop: Rogue City garnered acclaim from fans due to their faithful adaptation of the source material from the respective sci-fi franchises. The latter game, in particular, was hailed by Nacon as the publisher's biggest-ever launch, exceeding sales estimates.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Banjo Kazooie is Not in Development, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/banjo-kazooie-not-in-development/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-new-banjo-kazooie-is-not-in-development-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.917886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/banjo-kazooie-not-in-development/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Over the last couple of years, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/a-new-banjo-kazooie-game-is-coming-insider-claims/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">various claims have suggested</a> that a new Banjo Kazooie game has either been greenlit or in development. However, according to one reputable journalist and insider, that is simple not the case.</p>



<p>According to WindowsCentral’s Jez Corden in the latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EbOmQqPNpsU&amp;t=1246s&amp;ab_channel=JezC" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">XB2+1 podcast</a>, a new Banjo Kazooie is not in development. “I don’t know if never, but I can tell you right now, categorically, there is no Banjo game in development as of this podcast on the 26th of June 2024. There is no Banjo game in development right now.”</p>



<p>In the past, NateTheHate (under NateDrake on ResetEra) has made several claims that a Banjo Kazooie game has been greenlit and is in active development. In late 2023, he said, “It’s still an active project, but it didn’t get the green light until early last year.” He continued,&nbsp;“There is a lot to do, and development can change a lot (abandoned ideas, internal reboots, etc.).”</p>



<p>Banjo-Kazooie hasn’t seen a true main console entry since 2000’s Banjo-Tooie. There were a couple of handheld games in the early-mid 2000s — Banjo-Kazooie: Grunty’s Revenge and Banjo-Pilot for the Game Boy Advance. There was also Banjo-Kazooie: Nuts &amp; Bolts in 2008, but that game was such a deviation from the first two games, that it’s regarded more of a spin-off than anything else.</p>



<p>There seems to be a high demand for family-friendly games as of late, though. PlayStation’s Astro Bot “2” reveal saw tremendous traction online earlier this year, so we wouldn’t be surprised if Xbox is also floating around ideas on what they can do with its family-friendly IPs.</p>



<p>Would you like to see a new Banjo Kazooie game? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-battlefield-game-ever-going-offline/">the&nbsp;Battlefield games being taken offline</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive content</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Descendant Enjoys Big Player Numbers on Steam Despite ‘Microtransaction Hell’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-enjoys-big-player-numbers-on-steam-despite-microtransaction-hell</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-descendant-enjoys-big-player-numbers-on-steam-despite-%E2%80%98microtransaction-hell%E2%80%99.917883/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-enjoys-big-player-numbers-on-steam-despite-microtransaction-hell<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Nexon’s free-to-download looter shooter <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant</a> has enjoyed a huge launch on Steam but players have hit out at ultra aggressive microtransactions.</p><p>The First Descendant is a Warframe-esque action game designed to be played co-op with friends, with progression tied to a deep-rooted grind that involves completing missions and defeating bosses. Check out IGN's <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant review in progress</a> to find out what we think of the game so far.</p><p>But it’s the monetization that has sparked debate during the early days of The First Descendant’s launch, as well as issues giving players rewards they're owed that have forced Nexon into offering compensation.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The First Descendant Screenshots </h3></div></output><p>Korean company Nexon, which is behind other multiplayer-focused free-to-play games such as Kartrider: Drift and Maplestory, launched The First Descendant with a packed cash shop that sells everything you’d expect from a game of this type: a premium battle pass, new characters, premium character and weapon skins, and even experience boosts and increased inventory capacity.</p><p>New characters, called Descendants, are sold for real-world money, but the premium virtual currency, Caliber, is sold in bundles that come in just under the cost of a new character itself, forcing players to buy more virtual currency than they need and, thus, having some left over.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/03/screenshot-2024-07-03-101622-1719998219426.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>The First Descendant has a premium currency sold for real-world money.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Caliber can only be obtained by buying it with real-world money or by buying the premium battle pass. There is currently no way to earn it through gameplay alone.</p><p>While you can grind (a lot) for new characters, you can save time by spending money to buy them. You can also pay to gain immediate access to an ‘Ultimate Descendant’, which is a Descendant with better stats and an exclusive skin. Expect to pay upwards of $55 for one.</p><p>The First Descendant also locks a paint to a skin, which means if you want to re-use a paint you’ve already obtained, perhaps from the premium battle pass, you have to spend real-world money on it again.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Some players have called The First Descendant “predatory” because of its monetization, while others have said it’s par for the course when it comes to games from Nexon. On Steam, The First Descendant has a ‘mixed’ user review rating, with many of the negative reviews focusing on the microtransactions, but others are also delivering their verdict on the gunplay and mechanics. One Steam user called the First Descendant “microtransaction hell.” Another said: “This game released with more real money purchasable items than actual gameplay mechanics.”</p><p>Even those who have spent money on microtransactions are having a tough time, Nexon apologized to players who have yet to receive items they paid for by offering compensation. “We will continue to strive to provide a more stable service,” Nexon said.</p><p>Here are the compensation details:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Gold Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</li><li>Kyper Shard Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</li><li>Descendant EXP Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</li><li>Weapon Mastery EXP Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</li><li>2 x Matte Red Paints</li></ul><p>Despite all this, The First Descendant hit a Steam concurrent player count of 229,257, which was enough to put it in the top five most-played games on Valve’s platform. The game also launched on PlayStation and Xbox consoles, but Sony and Microsoft do not make player numbers available.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legend of Zelda fan jailed for carrying six-inch Master Sword in public]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/legend-of-zelda-fan-jailed-for-carrying-six-inch-master-sword-in-public</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/legend-of-zelda-fan-jailed-for-carrying-six-inch-master-sword-in-public.917874/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/legend-of-zelda-fan-jailed-for-carrying-six-inch-master-sword-in-public<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>A Legend of Zelda fan has been sentenced to four months in prison, after being found in possession of a small replica of the series' Master Sword whilst out in public.</p>
<p>In June, Nuneaton resident Anthony Bray was arrested for "carrying a bladed article". CCTV operators noticed Bray with the Master Sword replica, which had a total blade length of six inches (see images below).</p>
<p>"The blade was inside a sheath and could be released from the sheath with the press of a button," reads the <a href="https://www.warwickshire.police.uk/news/warwickshire/news/2024/july/anthony-bray-sentenced-to-four-months-for-possession-of-replica-master-sword/">police press release</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FQg2NCp1bQU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>When questioned, Bray said the Master Sword replica was purchased online as a fidget toy. Officers explained that despite this being the intended purpose, the blade "was in fact a sharply pointed item which could be used as a weapon and might put others in fear of it being used against them".</p>
<p>Bray maintained he would not have used the Legend of Zelda sword replica as an actual weapon. Bray did, however, acknowledge it could have been perceived as threatening.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/02-07-24-anthony-bray-topimage-lores-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Warwickshire Police</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"We take a zero tolerance to bladed articles in public, and Bray has fallen afoul of this," said Sgt Spellman of the Patrol Investigations Unit. "It is possible to find fidget toys that aren't six-inch blades. It is possible not to walk down the street holding them out in front of you.</p>
<p>"With a bit more self-awareness, Bray could have avoided contact with us completely."</p>
<p>Bray is now required to pay a victims' surcharge of £154 in addition to serving the aforementioned prison sentence.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nexon say sorry for The First Descendant launch bugs and performance issues with free cosmetics and boosters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nexon-say-sorry-for-the-first-descendant-launch-bugs-and-performance-issues-with-free-cosmetics-and-boosters</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nexon-say-sorry-for-the-first-descendant-launch-bugs-and-performance-issues-with-free-cosmetics-and-boosters.917871/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nexon-say-sorry-for-the-first-descendant-launch-bugs-and-performance-issues-with-free-cosmetics-and-boosters<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>And a round of Kyper Shards for all my friends!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-First-Descendant-Alpha-cutscene.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Nexon</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Nexon's free-to-play looter-<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooter</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant</a> - "Nexon's Warframe", as the wags are calling it on Steam - launched this week and has <a href="https://tfd.nexon.com/en/news/2594639?headlineId=1015">encountered a few snags and snaffaroos</a>, including beta rewards not showing up, Easy Anti-Cheat not running correctly, frame-rate drops for people who downloaded in advance of release, and players finding their merry way to servers where no other players exist. Nexon are even now patching the game, and have plied players with in-game bonuses and cosmetics as an apology for the inconvenience.</p><!--more-->
<p>The bonuses basically consist of being able to level up faster and paint your guns red. Here's the rundown.</p>
<blockquote><p>- Gold Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</p>
<p>- Kyper Shard Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</p>
<p>- Descendant EXP Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</p>
<p>- Weapon Mastery EXP Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</p>
<p>- 2 x Matte Red Paints</p>
</blockquote>
<p>These boost items will activate immediately upon your claiming them from the mailbox, so you might want to save them for a happier time when you understand what the hell a Kyper Shard is. For context, The First Descendant pits you and up to three friends equipped with sci-firearms and accessories such as grappling hooks against the snobby alien Vulgus and a bunch of cursed war golems called Colossi. The latter are after the Ironheart, a mystic energy source said to lie somewhere on your home planet, Ingris. It sounds like Kyper Shards will help with all that. I think the red paint is more of a fashion thing.</p>
<p>All the talk of percentages might suggest a game of making numbers go up in proportion to the implosion of your grey matter, but speaking to Nic last week, the developers insisted that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-descendants-endgame-wont-be-about-meaningless-dps-or-piling-on-specs">The First Descendant's endgame won't be about "meaningless DPS" or "piling on specs"</a>. </p>
<p>While I don't have a review to share just yet, our hardware editor James Archer laid hands and eyes on a near-final preview build a week or so back, and concluded that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-descendant-pc-performance-best-settings">The First Descendant's performance could still use a bit of love</a>. He was mixed, much like the current Steam user reviews, as to whether the game itself is worth the time. "I don't dislike The First Descendant," James wrote. "It has a good grasp of the numbers-go-up-yay appeal behind looter shooters. Sometimes you get to grapple onto a vast robot crab. The first evil alien overlord you fight is named Greg. Not bad, not bad."</p>
<p>James has also written about <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-descendant-steam-deck">The First Descendant's Steam Deck optimal Steam Deck settings</a>, commenting that "a mixture of Low and Medium seems like the best compromise".</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield Reaches New Level of Immersion on Consoles With New Interplanetary Travel Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/starfield-interplanetary-travel-mod/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starfield-reaches-new-level-of-immersion-on-consoles-with-new-interplanetary-travel-mod.917868/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/starfield-interplanetary-travel-mod/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Starfield has just been made much better on Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S, thanks to a new mod that finally allows seamless interplanetary travel.</p>
<p>The<a href="https://creations.bethesda.net/en/starfield/details/473137ab-9f9a-42fa-8d4b-6b7536d63be0/IMPROVED_Sublight_Engine_Boost"> IMPROVED Sublight Engine Boost mod</a>, which is also available on PC, not only allows seamless interplanetary travel between planets and moons but also introduces tweaks for ship engines to make traveling more enjoyable, such as giving every engine extended boost time to make ships accelerate to great speeds. The ship's speed depends on the mass of the ship itself and how many engines are attached, but only Starborn ships are the ones capable of traveling at the fastest speed.</p>
<p>While this Starfield mod is still in early development, online reports say it already works great, so bearing with some of its issues is definitely Worth it to make the game more immersive than ever. Hopefully, Bethesda will take note and introduce a proper interplanetary system in future updates.</p>
<p>Starfield was updated multiple times since its release last year, but the best is definitely yet to come, thanks to the <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-crossed-14-million-players-will-get-annual-story-expansions-shattered-space-set-on-single-planet-is-far-harbor-sized/">annual story expansions</a> Bethesda is planning to release. The first one, Shattered Space, will be set on a single planet and will be as big as Fallout 4's Far Harbor DLC.</p>
<p>Starfield is now available on PC, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. You can learn more about the game by checking out my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/starfield-the-elder-space-scrolls/">review.</a></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA sunsetting three Battlefield titles on Xbox 360 and PS3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-sunsetting-three-battlefield-titles-on-xbox-360-and-ps3</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-sunsetting-three-battlefield-titles-on-xbox-360-and-ps3.917865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-sunsetting-three-battlefield-titles-on-xbox-360-and-ps3<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA is sunsetting three Battlefield titles on Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 later this month.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The publisher confirmed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield 3</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield 4</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield: Hardline</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will be removed from digital storefronts on Xbox 360 and PS3 on July 31, 2024. DLC and "all extra related content" will also be pulled from sale.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Online services for these titles on these platforms will end on November 7th, 2024. While the online components of these titles close for these platforms, if you own the game, you will still be able to play the single-player component," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1806689437352341764">added EA</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield 3 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">will remain playable on PC, while </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield 4</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield: Hardline</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will remain playable on PC, Xbox One, and PlayStation 4.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA regularly delists older titles and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://help.ea.com/en-gb/help/faq/list-of-ea-games-that-have-gone-away/">on its website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> explains that "some games go away for legal reasons, or because players are asking for resources elsewhere."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The publisher maintains a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.ea.com/en-gb/legal/service-updates/a-h">regularly updated list</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of titles facing an online services shutdown and will be giving others the chop in the coming months including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>FIFA 22</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Disney Sorcerers Arena</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">News of online service shutdowns that render key multiplayer components unplayable or result in products being pulled from shelves often prick the ears of game preservationists. Fortunately, all three Battlefield titles remain playable on other platforms (for now).</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s customisable difficulties look genuinely great for accessibility]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-the-veilguards-customisable-difficulties-look-genuinely-great-for-accessibility</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard%E2%80%99s-customisable-difficulties-look-genuinely-great-for-accessibility.917850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-the-veilguards-customisable-difficulties-look-genuinely-great-for-accessibility<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Invincibility is "an option to make sure players of all abilities can show up" says game director</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/combat_1.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Alongside the usual standard and nightmare modes, upcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-dreadwolf">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> (née Dreadwolf) will ship with a fully tweakable set of difficulty options called ‘Unbound’, letting you customise everything from parry timings to invincibility.<!--more-->
</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive/2024/07/01/a-look-at-dragon-age-the-veilguards-difficulty-options-and-gameplay">Game Informer</a>, the list of adjustables includes options to change “how wayfinding helps you in-game,” an aim assistance feature including a full-on auto-aim option, and combat timing and parry windows split into easy, normal, and harder selections. You can make enemies hit stronger or less so, and give them more or less health. There’s an option to adjust what the GI piece calls “enemy pressure”, which I’m assuming is how aggressively and frequently they attack. You can also make yourself invincible at any time, like I used to do as a small annoying child inventing the rules to games as they went along. Ah, but I think you'll find I have infinity plus <em>two</em> laser guns, actually. </p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Official Gameplay Reveal" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Official Gameplay Reveal</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CTNwHShylIg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"[None of these options] are a cheat," game director Corinne Busche told GI. “It's an option to make sure players of all abilities can show up." Alongside these options, Busche told GI that players can additionally “can look forward to similar accessibility and approachability options” as those you might expect, although there’s no exact confirmation yet on what these might entail. Either way, there’s a real advantage to these sort of difficulty options even if you never plan on using them, I think. Keeping things like wayfinding as a tweakable parameter frees up the default experience to be a little less overt with its signposting, and perhaps a little more interesting with its combat.</p>
<p>“I am definitely in mourning for the less kinetic, more strategic Dragon Age that might have been, but I'm more excited for Veilguard than I thought I'd be after copping the first trailer,” Edwin wrote of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-45-minutes-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard-feel-as-much-like-mass-effect-2-as-inquisition">45 minute hands-on-seat-rests preview</a> he bore witness to at this Summer Games Fest past. “If Veilguard can carve out the cruft without reducing party members to sidekicks, it could be the soft reboot this long-absent RPG series needs.”</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Citizen devs Cloud Imperium fined for discriminating against autistic programmer over work-from-home request]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-citizen-devs-cloud-imperium-fined-for-discriminating-against-autistic-programmer-over-work-from-home-request</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-citizen-devs-cloud-imperium-fined-for-discriminating-against-autistic-programmer-over-work-from-home-request.917847/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-citizen-devs-cloud-imperium-fined-for-discriminating-against-autistic-programmer-over-work-from-home-request<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>UK tribunal finds that company "treated the claimant unfavourably" due to disability</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-citizen_d2yRJaM.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Cloud Imperium</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>A UK employment tribunal have ordered <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/star-citizen">Star Citizen</a> developer Cloud Imperium to pay around £27,748 - approximately $35,230 - in compensation for discriminating against former senior programmer Paul Ah-Thion, who was dismissed in 2022 after his requests to work from home following an office move were denied.</p><!--more-->
<p>Ah-Thion, who is autistic, joined Cloud Imperium in 2018. As reported by <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/cloud-imperium-games-discriminated-against-disabled-employee-with-return-to-office-policy">Game Developer</a>, he was based at the space sim developer's former offices in Wilmslow, before Cloud Imperium instructed employees to work from home in line with UK Covid pandemic lockdown requirements. In 2021, following the cessation of more stringent social distancing measures, Cloud Imperium opened a new headquarters in Manchester, and required staff to return to the office.</p>
<p>Ah-Thion, however, had found that working from home allowed him to avoid what he describes as the exhaustion and distress of working on Cloud Imperium's premises. The article doesn't go into detail about this, but it's worth noting here that many autistic people have <a href="https://employmentautism.org.uk/managing-workplace-sensory-issues/">great difficulty</a> with the sensory environment and social expectations of in-office work, unless proper accommodations are made.</p>
<p>Ah-Thion applied for a permanent remote working arrangement following the mandated return to the office, but was quickly denied by Cloud Imperium. The two parties went back and forth over the request, and Cloud Imperium eventually dismissed Ah-Thion in July 2022, citing performance issues related to his remote working setup. During the <a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/654cfca75d60950011bec8aa/Mr_P_Ah-_Thion_v_Cloud_Imperium_Games_Limited_2406047_2022.pdf">subsequent employment tribunal</a>, Cloud Imperium claimed he was unable to meet certain job criteria, such as mentoring junior staffers, when working remotely.</p>
<p>The tribunal, however, rejected many of Cloud Imperium's justifications for the dismissal, noting that in the absence of a formal investigation of Ah-Thion at the time, "concern about the claimant's performance seemed rather retrospective". According to a Cloud Imperium witness at the trial,  the company never formally asked Ah-Thion to return to the office, despite their alleged misgivings about the impact of remote-working on his performance.</p>
<p>The tribunal also found that Cloud Imperium "failed to give any evidence to suggest why they could not monitor [Ah-Thion's performance] successfully remotely whilst he was working from home" and that "there is no evidence that working from home would have failed to achieve the respondent's legitimate aim of ensuring the acceptable performance of a senior gameplay programmer". As such the tribunal's conclusion is that Cloud Imperium "treated the claimant unfavourably because of something arising in consequence of his disability", and that the company could have offered the <a href="https://www.autism.org.uk/advice-and-guidance/professional-practice/employment-adjustments-tips">reasonable adjustment</a> of letting him work from home.</p>
<p>"We find there was a failure of the respondent to understand the nature of the claimant's autism," the judgement comments. "It was a condition of his autism that he struggled with his duties to act as a coach, reviewer and mentor to the junior members of the team. The evidence shows that the claimant was struggling to do this when he worked in the office."</p>
<p>Game Developer also has some comment from Ah-Thion himself, who calls attention to what he calls a "tick-box mentality" to looking after disabled workers at companies who think that "sending a manager on a two-hour course about a disability is all they need to do". 

"I've been fighting this by myself for two years, and being autistic made the whole process especially challenging," he told the site. "But we're lucky to have the employment tribunal system, where an ordinary person can actually find justice without having to bankrupt themselves on legal fees."</p>
<p>"It was clear to me from the start that CIG didn't want people to work from home after the expense of their new Manchester office, and worked backwards from that to retroactively conjure up reasons why my request should be denied, something they continued to do right up until the final tribunal hearing - all while ignoring disability legislation. It was gratifying that the tribunal saw through them as easily as they did." The legislation Ah-Thion refers to here is presumably the UK's <a href="https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2010/15/contents">2010 equality act</a>.</p>
<p>Cloud Imperium are far from the only company to have shed staff in the course of ordering a return to the office. In December 2023, Activision Blizzard announced plans to end hybrid remote/in-office work for QA staff based in Minneapolis, Austin and El Segundo, in what the ABK Workers Alliance <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activisions-ending-of-hybrid-working-for-qa-staff-leaves-our-most-vulnerable-employees-behind-says-union">described as a round of "soft layoffs"</a>, with some staff potentially forced to leave due to being immunocompromised or the sheer financial cost of the commute. Rockstar announced <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockstar-reportedly-orders-gta-6-developers-to-end-hybrid-working-in-the-name-of-quality-and-polish">the end of hybrid working</a> in February 2024, citing a mixture of concerns about "quality and polish" together with security considerations in regards to GTA 6. By contrast, Crytek <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crytek-make-working-from-home-a-permanent-option-for-staff">made working from home a permanent option for staff</a> in April 2022.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>