<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:06:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embracer closes Alone in the Dark remake developer Pieces Interactive]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/17/embracer-closes-alone-in-the-dark-remake-developer-pieces-interactive/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/embracer-closes-alone-in-the-dark-remake-developer-pieces-interactive.903252/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/17/embracer-closes-alone-in-the-dark-remake-developer-pieces-interactive/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Pieces Interactive, the studio behind this year’s <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/03/20/alone-in-the-dark-review/">Alone in the Dark</a> remake, has been closed by Embracer Group.</p>
<p>The news comes from a statement posted to the Pieces Interactive website, saying “Thanks for playing with us” and that “Our last release was the reimagining of Alone in the Dark.”</p>


<p>Unfortunately for Pieces Interactive, while it had grand ambitions to emulate the Resident Evil remake revival and brought in some popular actors to lend their performance and likenesses, Alone in the Dark failed to meet expectations, both in terms of critical reception and with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/24/alone-in-the-dark-and-outcast-reboots-both-underperform-for-embracer/">“softer than expected” sales</a> after the game’s eventual March 2024 release. The studio has already been hit with layoffs a month later, but is now being completely closed by Embracer Group.</p>
<p>Founded in 2007, Pieces produced a number of original games, such as Puzzlegeddon, Fret Nice and Leviathan Warships, and work-for-hire games that included <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2015/06/03/magicka-2-review/">Magicka 2</a>. The studio was acquired by Embracer in 2017 and initially worked on expansions for Titan Quest – Ragnarök and Atlantis – before getting the opportunity to reimagine survival horror classic Alone in the Dark.</p>

<p>They join the long list of studios closed by Embracer Group over the last year – 44 studios have closed including <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/12/11/free-radical-design-shutdown-timesplitters-cancelled/">Free Radical Design</a>, Onoma and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/08/31/saints-row-studio-volition-has-been-shut-down/">Volition</a> – amid layoffs that have affected over 4,500 employees. Embracer has also sold off studios and sub-groups, such as <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/03/14/embracer-has-officially-sold-off-saber-interactive/">Saber Interactive</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/03/28/embracer-sells-off-gearbox-to-take-two-for-460-million/">Gearbox</a>, and announced a plan to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/04/22/embracer-group-plans-to-split-into-three-separate-companies/"> split into three separate entities</a>.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.piecesinteractive.se/">Pieces</a> via <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/embracer-shuts-down-alone-in-the-dark-developer-pieces-interactive">IGN</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PSA: There Are Elden Ring: Shadow Of The Erdtree Spoilers Out There]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-spoilers-warning-1851543600</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/psa-there-are-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-spoilers-out-there.903249/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-spoilers-warning-1851543600<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>With tiresome predictability, action RPG <em>Elden Ring</em>’s first and only DLC, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-dlc-release-date-trailer-1851275659&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-dlc-release-date-trailer-1851275659"><em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em></a></span>, is already being spoiled online, four days ahead of its release. This warning comes from no smaller a source than its own developers, FromSoftware. (There are <em>no spoilers at all</em> in this post.)</p><div data-video-id="195502" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="307" data-playlist="195502,195624,196773" data-current="195502"><div><p>The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20979.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>In a statement posted to the official <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-fromsoftware-review-hidetaka-miyazaki-dark-s-1848694257&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-fromsoftware-review-hidetaka-miyazaki-dark-s-1848694257"><em>Elden Ring</em></a></span> X (formerly Twitter) feed, the team warns players to be “mindful” in the week running up to the expansion’s release. And it’s done in the most gentle, non-accusatory way imaginable. </p><p>“Please be mindful of spoilers,” says the tweeted JPEG, “for those who want to tread into the Realm of Shadows with nothing but their determination and their minds unclouded.”</p><p>The subtext of course being, “Please don’t be a dick and spread the leaks.” Because of course some who’ve somehow got their hands on early copies have done exactly this.</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-lore-messmer-miquella-1851492064&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-lore-messmer-miquella-1851492064">Here’s What I Think <em>Elden Ring: Shadow Of The Erdtree</em> DLC Is About </a></span></p><p>One such leak on Reddit involved someone saying their friend had a review build, and posting alleged videos of boss fights, then angrily refuting those who claim it to be fake. (Given FromSoft has acknowledged there are leaks, it would suggest there’s some validity to the claims.) After a certain amount of goading, the anon account uploaded a better quality, much longer video of what they purport to be the final boss fight. Although adds, “My friend sux so I have no idea. He told me this was the final boss, but it wouldn’t surprise me if he missed something.”</p><p>Elsewhere the same account has posted three-minute videos of significant fights with named characters in the subject lines, thus removing surprises even for those who don’t click past the spoiler warnings on the clips. (I don’t know a thing about <em>Elden Ring</em>, and so don’t mind at all that I’ve seen this stuff, if you were worrying. It might as well be in Klingon.)</p><p>So, be warned. A lot more of this will start to appear as Friday approaches, so if you’re looking to truly protect yourself, just set up a VPN that blocks all web traffic but for <em>Kotaku</em>. We promise we won’t ruin a thing.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Quiet Place The Road Ahead is Coming 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-coming-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-coming-2024.903246/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-coming-2024/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Saber Interactive has just released a new <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=91zi75E_SA8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reveal trailer</a> for A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead, which included a release window for 2024.</p>



<p>The new game, based on the popular A Quiet Place horror film series, will be available on PC via Steam, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>



<p>The trailer features first-person exploration gameplay, ending with a jump scare. It also states that the footage was captured in-engine.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead - Reveal Trailer" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/91zi75E_SA8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>The trailer description says that “the road ahead is paved with sound decisions.” This play on words could simply refer to survival mechanics, or possibly that player decisions can impact the story. </p>



<p>Developer Stormind Games, mentioned at the beginning of the trailer, did work on the choice-driven adventure Batora: Lost Haven.</p>



<p>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead also has an <a href="https://aquietplace.game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official website</a> with further details. It confirms players will “strive for silence when hiding from, and sneaking by, horrific creatures who hunt using only sound.”</p>



<p>It also reveals that this will be a new story set in the universe established by A Quiet Place, rather than a direct adaptation. The plot will center on “a young survivor trying to navigate the new, eerily tranquil, post-apocalyptic landscape.”</p>



<p>It may also have open world elements, since players can “discover your own path through the world by observing your environment and leveraging the tools in your surroundings.”</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming updates, you can read about Alone in the Dark 2024 studio Pieces Interactive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/alone-in-the-dark-2024-developer-pieces-interactive-shut-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shutting down</a>, and sign up to receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yet Another Game Studio Is Shutting Down After Making A Good Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/yet-another-game-studio-is-shutting-down-after-making-a-good-game/1100-6524304/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yet-another-game-studio-is-shutting-down-after-making-a-good-game.903243/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/yet-another-game-studio-is-shutting-down-after-making-a-good-game/1100-6524304/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524304">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>So far, 2024 has been a brutal year for the video game industry, and it's not showing any signs of letting up. Now, Galvanic Games, the developer behind <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wizard-with-a-gun-launches-a-day-early-to-avoid-clash-with-diablo-4s-steam-debut/1100-6518427/" data-ref-id="1100-6518427">Wizard with a Gun</a>, is the latest studio to shut down.</p><p>Galvanic Games founder and president Patrick Morgan shared the news on social media. And he noted that despite the fact that Wizard with a Gun was well-received, the game's sales weren't high enough to save the studio.</p><p>"It is with a heavy heart that I announce the closure of Galvanic Games," wrote Morgan. "Despite the promising start of Wizard with a Gun, sales are not strong enough to sustain our studio. The last year has been particularly tough for games. While we had numerous encouraging conversations at DICE and GDC, the process of signing new projects, in a good year, takes longer than the runway we had left."</p><p>Morgan also included a link back to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7207451502972477440/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the studio's LinkedIn page</a>, in order to help some of his now former employees find work elsewhere in the gaming industry. But with so many people across the industry already looking for work in the wake of multiple closures, many of those ex-employees are now facing an uncertain future.</p><p>This year has already seen the closures of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-partnered-studio-from-ex-cod-devs-has-closed/1100-6521774/" data-ref-id="1100-6521774">Deviation Games</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/firewall-ultra-developer-closes-down-after-eight-years-due-to-lack-of-vr-support/1100-6520087/" data-ref-id="1100-6520087">First Contact Entertainment</a>, Microsoft's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-is-shutting-down-four-studios-including-arkane-austin-and-tango-gameworks/1100-6523227/" data-ref-id="1100-6523227">Arkane Austin, Tango Gameworks, Alpha Dog Games, and Roundhouse Games</a>, as well as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/just-cause-developer-closing-two-studios-including-one-thats-only-been-open-since-october/1100-6523899/" data-ref-id="1100-6523899">Avalanche Studio Group</a>'s New York and Montreal studios. That's not even including the large number of layoffs that have hit everyone from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-parent-company-to-cancel-games-and-lay-off-5-of-staff/1100-6522706/" data-ref-id="1100-6522706">Take-Two</a> to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/video-game-industry-layoffs-are-worse-than-ever-how-did-we-get-here/1100-6521799/" data-ref-id="1100-6521799">Sony and EA</a>--and the year is not even halfway over yet. </p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shovel Knight Sequel And Shovel Of Hope DX Are On The Way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shovel-knight-sequel-and-shovel-of-hope-dx-are-on-the-way/1100-6524302/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shovel-knight-sequel-and-shovel-of-hope-dx-are-on-the-way.903237/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shovel-knight-sequel-and-shovel-of-hope-dx-are-on-the-way/1100-6524302/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524302">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Ten years ago this month, the retro side-scrolling action game Shovel Knight made its debut. To celebrate the anniversary, Yacht Club Games live-streamed an event that featured two big announcements. The first was a new definitive version of the game, Shovel Knight: Shovel of Hope DX. And the second piece of news was confirmation that a Shovel Knight sequel is also in development.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cbpEXPSvFtc" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cbpEXPSvFtc" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Shovel of Hope DX is coming to Steam, and it features a number of enhancements that weren't present in the original Shovel Knight. To start, gamers can choose between 20 playable characters, from Shovel Knight and Shield Knight to their adversary, the Enchantress. Those aren't simply cosmetic changes, as each character has their own abilities and play styles. The game is also adding a rewind function, as well as 300 cheats that can be applied for a unique gameplay experience.</p><p>Additionally, Shovel of Hope DX will include Challenge Stages, Custom Knight, and the Battle Ghost Arena, as well full Stereoscopic 3D. Online and local multiplayer options are also supported.</p><p>As for the sequel, Sean Velasco, a designer for Yacht Club Games, said that it will feature "groundbreaking innovative gameplay mechanics," before adding that it will bring Shovel Knight "into an entirely new dimension of gaming." Velasco also hinted that clues have been left in previous Yacht Club Games titles that will shed some light on the Shovel Knight sequel.</p><p>Neither the Shovel Knight sequel nor Shovel of Hope DX have release dates yet. However, Shovel Knight: Shovel of Hope DX can be added to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2661310/Shovel_Knight_Shovel_of_Hope_DX/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">your wishlist on Steam</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Quiet Place Game Finally Revealed And It Looks Terrifying]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-quiet-place-game-finally-revealed-and-it-looks-terrifying/1100-6524309/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-quiet-place-game-finally-revealed-and-it-looks-terrifying.903234/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-quiet-place-game-finally-revealed-and-it-looks-terrifying/1100-6524309/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524309">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Back in 2021, Saber Interactive announced it was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-quiet-place-is-becoming-a-single-player-story-driven-horror-adventure-game/1100-6497384/" data-ref-id="1100-6497384">making a video game based on the film series A Quiet Place</a>, and now the game has been officially unveiled. A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead is a new atmospheric horror game from Stormind Games and Saber, and it's set for release in 2024.</p><p>The eerie announcement trailer shows that the game follows the formula of the film series, which is that players must remain quiet to prevent the aliens from detecting them. The Road Ahead is set for release on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S later this year.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1721328537" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464412,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;A%20Quiet%20Place%3A%20The%20Road%20Ahead%20-%20Official%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:105,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-official-reveal-trailer\/2300-6464412\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464412\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464412\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464412\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464412&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464412,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6524309&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464412},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464412\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4320023-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/PRTETnIl.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1718629800,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="PRTETnIl" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead - Official Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>The Road Ahead doesn't re-tell the story of A Quiet Place or A Quiet Place 2 (or the upcoming prequel Day One) but instead tells an original story inspired by the movie series. Players take on the role of a young survivor attempting to make their way through a very scary post-apocalyptic world.</p><p>Stormind Games previously made Batora: Lost Haven and the Remothered series. Back in the 2021 announcement, Saber said it was partnering with the developers iLLOGIKA and EP1T0ME on a game based on A Quiet Place. So it's not immediately clear if this is that game or something else.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320010-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.04am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4320010" data-ratio="0.55685618729097" data-width="1196" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320010-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.04am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4320010"></a><figcaption>A scene from The Road Ahead</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320010-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.04am.png"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320013-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.10am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320014-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.16am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320015-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.25am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320016-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.31am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4320013,1300-4320014,1300-4320015,1300-4320016" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4320013-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.10am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4320014-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.16am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4320015-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.25am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4320016-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.31am.png"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320013-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.10am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320014-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.16am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320015-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.25am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4320016-screenshot2024-06-17at9.10.31am.png"></figure><p>As for the film series, the prequel, Day One, releases in theaters later this month. After that will come <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-quiet-place-part-3-announced-for-2025-spin-off-still-coming-next-year/1100-6500730/" data-ref-id="1100-6500730">A Quiet Place 3</a>, continuing the narrative from A Quiet Place 2. The story and conceit was created by writers Scott Beck and Bryan Woods, and the film project gathered steam when John Krasinski--who was better known for his comedic work on The Office--came aboard to co-write and direct.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Destiny 2 Exotic missions in release order – Listed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/all-destiny-2-exotic-missions-in-release-order-listed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=all-destiny-2-exotic-missions-in-release-order-listed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-destiny-2-exotic-missions-in-release-order-%E2%80%93-listed.903231/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/all-destiny-2-exotic-missions-in-release-order-listed/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=all-destiny-2-exotic-missions-in-release-order-listed<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="289" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">At this point in time, <em>Destiny 2</em> has absolutely no shortage of <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/all-destiny-2-raids-in-release-order-listed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Raids</a> and <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/all-destiny-2-dungeons-in-release-order-listed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dungeons</a> to choose from, with more being added to the mix on a seasonal basis. It’s easy to forget, then, that there’s a <em>third</em> important category of challenging content in this game, too: Exotic missions.</p> <p data-characters="377" data-current-count="377" data-injectable="false">Note that I’m not referring to Exotic <em>quests</em> here: we’ve got too many of those to keep track of in the first place. No, our topic for the day is specifically Exotic <em>missions</em>. The type of stuff that was praised even during <em>Destiny 2</em>‘s many lulls in content and popularity; those missions that, once upon a time, weren’t even <em>announced</em> in the first place.</p> <p data-characters="150" data-current-count="527" data-injectable="true">So, from those legends onward, here’s the full and comprehensive list of <em>all</em> of <em>Destiny 2</em>‘s Exotic missions in the order of their release!</p>
 <h2 id="h-all-destiny-2-exotic-missions-in-the-order-of-release" data-injectable="false">All Destiny 2 Exotic missions in the order of release</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-1-the-whisper-july-2018-original-april-2024-reprised" data-injectable="false">#1: The Whisper – July 2018 (Original) / April 2024 (Reprised)</h3> <p data-characters="462" data-current-count="762" data-injectable="true">The ultimate blueprint that all the other Exotic missions are compared with, The Whisper came about mostly as a surprise in the early years of <em>Destiny 2</em>‘s lifecycle. Basically, it all began with a mysterious anomaly appearing on the now-sunset Io, and what came about as a result was a remarkably creepy and parkour-heavy adventure. Its reward? A Taken combination of the Black Spindle and the Black Hammer sniper rifles from the first <em>Destiny</em>. Good times!</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-2-zero-hour-march-2019-original-may-2024-reprised" data-injectable="false">#2: Zero Hour – March 2019 (Original) / May 2024 (Reprised)</h3> <p data-characters="556" data-current-count="856" data-injectable="true">Zero Hour was the second standalone Exotic mission released for <em>Destiny 2</em>, and it leaned even more heavily into its maze-like structure than the Whisper, which made it a fair bit more challenging on your first try. It, too, was a time-limited ordeal you see. Zero Hour was (and still is) quite special due to its setting – the Tower itself – its penchant to keep players coming back for more – the unique cosmetic rewards – and the coveted Outbreak Perfected. Oh, and TR3VR, too, the loveable bot. You’ll meet <em>him</em> soon enough.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-3-the-other-side-june-2019" data-injectable="false">#3: The Other Side – June 2019</h3> <p data-characters="446" data-current-count="746" data-injectable="true">While The Other Side wasn’t quite as iconic as The Whisper and Zero Hour, few things ever were in the context of <em>Destiny</em>. It’s a solid mission, regardless: under the tutelage of the now-deceased Emperor Calus, Guardians dive headfirst into the Ascendant Plane to extract none other than the Bad Juju pulse rifle. Cool! What’s not so cool is that The Other Side is no longer playable, as of <em>Beyond Light</em>‘s sunsetting spree.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-4-harbinger-november-2020" data-injectable="false">#4: Harbinger – November 2020</h3> <p data-characters="396" data-current-count="696" data-injectable="true">The Harbinger was initially supposed to be a <em>secret</em> Exotic mission tucked away in one of the most often overlooked places in the European Dead Zone region, though it didn’t take long for players to suss it out. Its reward? The fabled Hawkmoon handcannon, courtesy of the Crow’s slow climb upwards following his <em>Forsaken</em>-era misadventures. The Harbinger is currently sadly unavailable.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-5-presage-february-2021" data-injectable="false">#5: Presage – February 2021</h3> <p data-characters="526" data-current-count="826" data-injectable="true"><em>Destiny</em> doesn’t often foray into full-fledged horror territory, but when it does, you know it’s the real deal. Presage came about as a celebration of this niche, pitting players against one of the first in-game realizations of Darkness proper. The result is an impeccably grim atmosphere with appropriately disturbing lore, and the delightfully chunky Dead Man’s Tale lever-action scout rifle. Just a joy to play all around, though the lack of unique enemy encounters does diminish the experience a tiny bit.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-6-a-hollow-coronation-august-2021" data-injectable="false">#6: A Hollow Coronation – August 2021</h3> <p data-characters="442" data-current-count="742" data-injectable="true">Released as part of the Season of the Lost, A Hollow Coronation was a deep dive into the lore of Queen Mara, Uldren Sov, and his Light-infused alter ego, the Crow. This was a solid enough showing, though the mission itself couldn’t really hold a candle to the true greats of this category, such as The Whisper and Zero Hour. Still, it’s a bit of a shame that the Hollow Coronation is no longer playable, as of the <em>Witch Queen</em> DLC.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-7-parasitic-pilgrimage-february-2022" data-injectable="false">#7: Parasitic Pilgrimage – February 2022</h3> <p data-characters="437" data-current-count="737" data-injectable="true">The Parasitic Pilgrimage mission is no secret, unlike some other Exotic missions on this list, but it sure is a must-play for anyone unfamiliar with the depths of Hive lore. Parasitic Pilgrimage is all about shoving Savathûn’s Worm into the deviously powerful Parasite grenade launcher. Along the way, you get to learn some tidbits about the sorry creature, its history, and the history of the Queen of Lies itself. Good fun, overall.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-8-vox-obscura-february-2022" data-injectable="false">#8: Vox Obscura – February 2022</h3> <p data-characters="519" data-current-count="819" data-injectable="true">While many seasonal Exotic missions did get seemingly permanently taken out of the equation as years went by, some of the notable highlights – like the Vox Obscura mission – have been shoved back into the game via the Exotic mission rotator. Good thing, too, because Vox Obscura is a high-octane romp directly through the Emperor Calus’ loyalist Cabal to take down a dangerous Psion commander smack-dab in the middle of a heavily protected operating base. Tank combat on the face of Mars? Yes, please.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-9-operation-seraph-s-shield-december-2022" data-injectable="false">#9: Operation: Seraph’s Shield – December 2022</h3> <p data-characters="493" data-current-count="793" data-injectable="true">Operation: Seraph’s Shield is one of the few previously-sunset Exotic missions that have been re-released in an updated format. Is it a party trick? The unique Revision Zero Exotic pulse rifle has several different upgrades you need to work through by playing Seraph’s Shield. The mission is, therefore, uniquely suited to repeat playthroughs, taking players through almost half a dozen unique combat encounters and puzzle rooms in one go. Solid stuff, albeit hardly revolutionary.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-10-what-remains-february-2023" data-injectable="false">#10: What Remains – February 2023</h3> <p data-characters="522" data-current-count="822" data-injectable="true">A <em>Lightfall</em> Exotic quest, What Remains is a visually striking mission that takes players on a mad dash through the Black Garden itself. Though it’s not mechanically challenging in the same way that secret Exotic missions were, What Remains is absolutely beautiful and memorable throughout, being one of the relatively few highlights to have come out of the <em>Lightfall</em> DLC proper. Your reward for its completion? The hard-hitting Deterministic Chaos machine gun and oodles of Vex/Black Garden lore. Who could complain?</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-11-the-variable-avalon-february-2023" data-injectable="false">#11: The Variable (Avalon) – February 2023</h3> <p data-characters="509" data-current-count="809" data-injectable="true">The Variable is, arguably, one of the hardest Exotic missions we’ve seen yet, featuring the Vex Network and the appropriately voxelated Vexcalibur glaive as its reward. Neon-laden and about as punishing as it gets in the Master version, The Variable pulls no punches in any category, with challenging parkour sections and an extremely aggressive version of Brakion waiting for you at the very end. Great fun on your first go, though you may be hard-pressed to go back for more when all is said and done.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Dorje Bellbrook</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-12-starcrossed-november-2023" data-injectable="false">#12: Starcrossed – November 2023</h3> <p data-characters="501" data-current-count="801" data-injectable="true">The second Exotic mission set in the Black Garden, Starcrossed plays host to the admittedly middling Wish-Keeper Exotic bow. This mission is a part of the ongoing Exotic mission rotator that’s available in <em>Destiny 2</em> since Season 22, but its reliance on long-range combat and punishing encounters means most players aren’t itching at the bits to replay it. It’s a solid offering, to be sure, but even I have to admit it doesn’t come even close to the heights of, say, Zero Hour.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie YouTube</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-13-wild-card-june-2024" data-injectable="false">#13: Wild Card – June 2024</h3> <p data-characters="597" data-current-count="897" data-injectable="true">One of the newest and most narrative-heavy Exotic missions to date, Wild Card takes you on a delightful little side-adventure during the bigger <em>Final Shape</em> story. During it, you’ll set up camp with the Crow and Cayde-6, dwell a bit on what this entire schtick means, and do some skeet shooting. The mission is unlike any other in <em>Destiny 2</em> due to its several time-skips, where the overworld changes and delivers new encounters during each of these intermissions even though you’re, technically, just playing this one mission in one go. Your reward? The awesome Still Hunt sniper rifle.</p>
  <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <h3 id="h-14-dual-destiny-june-2024" data-injectable="false">#14: Dual Destiny – June 2024</h3> <p data-characters="575" data-current-count="875" data-injectable="true">Yet <em>another</em> unique Exotic mission released as part of <em>The Final Shape</em>, Dual Destiny is a secret side-activity that’s purpose-built specifically for <em>two</em> players, which is quite uncommon in <em>Destiny 2</em>. Consider it a mini-raid, really, as it requires some very good communication and coordination to get through all the puzzles. Not everyone’s been a fan of Dual Destiny’s precedent-breaking approach to the battle-tested Exotic mission formula, but it’s good fun regardless, and the reward – the Exotic Class Item – is well worth the trouble!</p>
 

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Still Wakes the Deep Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/17/still-wakes-the-deep-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/still-wakes-the-deep-review.903216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/17/still-wakes-the-deep-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/17/still-wakes-the-deep-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Still Wakes the Deep Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Tuffcub">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-06-17">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-06-17">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The Chinese Room are probably best known for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2016/09/20/dear-esther-landmark-edition-retells-the-birth-of-a-genre/">Dear Esther</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2015/08/12/everybodys-gone-to-the-rapture-review/">Everybody’s Gone To The Rapture</a>, a pair of games where you gently wander through the countryside and gradually uncover a deep mystery as you go. Still Wakes the Deep is the polar opposite of that game, a tense, cramped horror title that will have you on the edge of your seat.</p>
<p><iframe title="STILL WAKES THE DEEP | Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JmLNTFofED8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It’s December 1975 and the decorations are up on the Beira D, an oil rig off the coast of Scotland. Our character, Cameron “Caz” McLeary, is not in a festive mood, though. Before he arrived on the rig something happened back on the mainland and it has now caught up with him, the police are here and he is about to be fired. As if Caz’s day couldn’t get any worse, a huge explosion then rips through the oil rig as some mysterious monster is released by the drilling.</p>


<p>The story feels like a mashup of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_Rising">Deep Rising</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/01/26/dead-space-remake-review-ps5-xbox-series-x-pc/">Dead Space</a> and a prime time ITV drama – the last point mainly because all the cast are from northern England or Scotland, which makes the game seem genuinely authentic to the setting and time period. The flashbacks to a story on the mainland which really could have been lifted from a TV show. It also helps that the characters talk like real people and that means a lot of cussing, there’s more C-bombs ten minutes of Still Wakes the Deep than in the whole of Bulletstorm.</p>


<p>The game is totally linear, guiding you from one location to another as the story plays out and rather surprisingly there’s a touch of Uncharted in the mix as you clamber around the wrecked rig, albeit in first person. Caz has to hang from the ceiling, slide through tight gaps and make leaps of faith, many of which require a quick presses of a secondary button to stop him from falling to his death. There are a few puzzles alongside, but these a really simple and I think this actually adds to the game – having a “search and collect four gubbins in different areas to fix a whatsit” type of quest would have really broken the tension, while the simple solutions here mean you can keep on moving along with the story.</p>
<p>While some crew have survived the event, there are other things on board with a number of stealth sections where you must avoid some of the best designed monsters since Dead Space. They are truly nasty, eldritch horror creatures that bring forth screams from the depths of hell as they try and find where you are hiding. You can’t hide forever, though, and other parts of the game have you being chased by creatures and racing along obstacle laden paths, or swimming through flooded corridors desperately searching for pockets of air.</p>

<p>It is never boring, but it does feel like things have been padded out to reach a 6-7 hour playtime. I’ve never been on an exploding oil rig and I am sure the many tasks you have to perform to stop it from sinking are accurate, but after four hours of clambering around and turning on pumps and winches, it does start to remind you are playing a video game and break the otherwise superb atmosphere.</p>
<p>To say the game looks good would be a understatement. Built in Unreal Engine 5, Still Wakes the Deep is almost photorealistic at times and has some simply fantastic lighting. The sound design is also excellent with thumps and bangs raising the tension, while the monsters are deliciously wet and squelchy and talk directly to you while they are hunting – they are not afraid of good cuss word either.</p>
<p>While Still Wakes the Deep is much more than a ‘walking simulator’, this is very much story with a game built around it. The graphics and sound generate an amazing atmosphere drenched in tension and while all the cast put in superb performances, Alan Newman as Caz should be picking up all the awards. The script really does feel like it has been pulled from a high quality drama and doesn’t feel like a video game at all. It’s the small things, like when a character is shouting instructions at Caz from a distance and asks him to make some signal, any sort of signal, to show he understands, Caz flips him the bird. It’s exactly what I would have expected his character to do.</p>

<p>So much work has gone in to the game to create the tense atmosphere it’s a shame there are two glaring issues which really drag you back to reality. The first is loading sections – moving between interior and exterior has the screen fading to black and a very short break while the game loads which is just long enough to break the atmosphere. The second is running, as Caz will briefly flail his arms in front of the screen like he is voguing at high speed before settling down to pump his arms in a weird jog. It just looks a bit silly and completely at odds with the gruff oil rig worker character.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Treat Still Wakes the Deep like a Netflix mini series and you will have a whale of a time. Its excellent script, acting, and atmosphere make it just as good to passively watch as to actively play, so grab your partner, turn off the lights and binge it over a few evenings. 	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Superbly atmospheric</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Excellent script and acting</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Horrific monster designs</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Loading sections break the tension</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Feels a little padded</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Very stupid running animation</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA CEO Made Over $25 Million Last Year Despite Hundreds of Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-ceo-25-million-income-layoffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-ceo-made-over-25-million-last-year-despite-hundreds-of-layoffs.903213/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-ceo-25-million-income-layoffs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>EA CEO Andrew Wilson earned more than $25 million in the 2023-24 fiscal year, a new report shows, with the studio's NEOs (named executive officers) collectively taking home over $60 million across the financial year.</p>
<p>Per EA's 2024 <a href="https://d18rn0p25nwr6d.cloudfront.net/CIK-0000712515/f0be0a59-dd50-4247-b36e-0513336b6c1f.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Annual Meeting and Proxy Statement</a>, Wilson's total earnings for the fiscal year come to $25.64 million, which is spread across salary, stock awards, and "non-equity incentive plan compensation".</p>
<p>Collectively, EA's NEOs raked in $60.06 million for the fiscal year, with EA entertainment and technology head Laura Miele bringing in $12.1 million as the company's second-highest NEO earner.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ea-andrew-wilson-layoffs-immortals-of-aveum.jpg?itok=oGGC8mdH 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ea-andrew-wilson-layoffs-immortals-of-aveum.jpg?itok=-WWvEcbR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Immortals of Aveum&nbsp;</em>was just one of the games released by EA in the last fiscal year.</figcaption></figure><p>These numbers come after a year of heavy layoffs for EA. Back in February, the studio announced it would let go <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/electronic-arts-to-lay-off-5-of-its-workforce-amid-refocus-on-owned-ip-and-sports-games">around 5% of its workforce</a>, which means hundreds of staffers found themselves out of a job earlier this year.</p>
<p>Among those layoffs were <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/apex-legends-developer-respawn-hit-by-layoffs-among-cuts-at-electronic-arts">several employees</a> at&nbsp;<em>Apex Legends&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Titanfall&nbsp;</em>developer Respawn, and a&nbsp;<em>Star Wars&nbsp;</em>FPS in development at the studio was also canceled.</p>
<p>When combined with EA's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/electronic-arts-announces-strong-financial-results-as-ea-sports-fc-and-madden-revenue">assessment in January</a> that its financial performance for the third quarter of the fiscal year was "strong", awarding this much money to executives while also letting hundreds of employees go is not a great look, to say the least.</p>
<p>Somewhat ironically, the Proxy Statement praises Wilson for a year of "record high talent retention" and "strong talent attraction". Somehow, I think the hundreds of employees let go this year would probably beg to differ.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ea-star-wars-jedi-survivor-2024.jpg?itok=ZUzFgbMd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ea-star-wars-jedi-survivor-2024.jpg?itok=6Wqe2Fgn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>EA's 2024 fiscal year also included hits like&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>The layoffs at EA came during a particularly difficult year for the gaming industry, which also saw a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/disco-elysium-developer-zaum-confirms-game-cancellation-and-layoffs">number</a> of other <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/supermassive-games-layoffs">studios</a>, both <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/hasbro-layoffs-targets-20-of-workforce-resulting-in-1100-jobs-lost">big</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bossa-studios-and-archiact-hit-by-layoffs">small</a>, either <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-shuts-down-saints-row-developer-volition">closing</a> or <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/playstation-layoffs">downsizing</a>.</p>
<p>Given that the total number of layoffs in 2024 has <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/this-week-in-gaming-business-june-14th">already surpassed that of 2023</a>, however, that wave is showing no signs of slowing down, and it's likely that more big studios like EA will be letting employees go before the year is through.</p>
<p>Of course, this is the same company that <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-layoffs-share-buyback">recently announced a new share buyback scheme</a> to cheer up its shareholders, so perhaps we shouldn't be surprised at the exorbitant incomes of its C-suite. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead revealed for PC and consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-revealed-for-pc-and-consoles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-revealed-for-pc-and-consoles.903210/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-revealed-for-pc-and-consoles<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Standing on the shoulders of silence.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Quiet-Place-The-Road-Ahead.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Saber/Stormind Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Publisher Saber Interactive has today given us a look at the upcoming release, A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead. 
</p>
<p>
This narrative-driven horror game is inspired by the film series, which includes two John Krasinski-directed releases as well as an upcoming prequel spin-off. </p>
<p>It was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-quiet-place-is-a-new-single-player-story-driven-horror-game-based-on-the-film">first announced to be in the pipeline back in 2021</a>, however at this time all we had was a logo and the promise of an original story and gameplay that "captures the compelling suspense, emotion and drama for which the series is famous".</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: For Xbox, could this year finally be the one where it all pays off?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mPVhT_7O0iE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Saber says the upcoming game, which is being developed by Stormind Games, is designed for fans of the films and horror. "Experience the journey of a young woman struggling to endure not only the nightmarish creatures of the apocalypse, but also the anguish of interpersonal family conflicts and her own inner fears," reads the official blurb. 
</p>
<p>
"With nothing more than your wits and the simple tools you can scavenge, you'll have to overcome the many treacherous challenges and obstacles that lay ahead, all while trying to survive an ever-present threat of the unknown enemies."
</p>
<p>
You can see how it looks in the trailer below:
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead - Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/91zi75E_SA8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead - Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/91zi75E_SA8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/91zi75E_SA8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=91zi75E_SA8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
As you would expect given its inspiration, silence will play a key part in A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead. Saber warns that even a single noise can be all it takes to give away your position. So, to put it <em>Bluntly</em>, tread cautiously.
</p>
<p>
On its release later this year (exact date TBC), A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead will be available across PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S. Those interested can add it to their wishlists now. 
</p>
<p>
A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead is one of several projects still in the works from Saber after the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/saber-confirms-a-number-of-titles-still-in-development-following-todays-embracer-sale">publisher was sold by Embracer earlier this year</a>. Other upcoming releases include Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/jurassic-park-survival-will-revisit-locations-from-1993-film-but-also-introduce-new-ones">Jurassic Park: Survival</a>. 

</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Still Wakes the Deep Review – Surface-Level Scares]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/still-wakes-the-deep/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/still-wakes-the-deep-review-%E2%80%93-surface-level-scares.903207/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/still-wakes-the-deep/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
				<main>

					

					<!--<div class="ads-container banner-ad floated p-0">
						<div data-pg-ad-spot='div-gpt-ad-wccftechcom38564' style="min-height: 280px;"></div>
					</div>-->
					
										<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Still Wakes the Deep</h5><p><span>June 18, 2024</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC, Xbox Series X/S, PlayStation 5</span>
						</p></div><div>
							<h5>Developer</h5><p><span>The Chinese Room</span>
						</p></div></div></div>
					<p>A key ingredient to a successful horror story is a good setting and <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/still-wakes-the-deep/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Still Wakes the Deep</a>, which takes place on a massive deep sea oil rig off the coast of Scotland, has a pretty killer one. The game also has a critically acclaimed, if somewhat divisive, creative team behind it in <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/the-chinese-room/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Chinese Room</a>, the British developer behind past indie hits such as Dear Esther and Everybody's Gone to the Rapture.</p>
<p>In other words, Still Wakes the Deep would seem to have quite a bit going for it at first glance. So, does the game successfully tap into its unique setting? Or does it come up dry when it comes to terror?</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/WCCFstillwakesthedeep3.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Set in 1975, Still Wakes the Deep places the player in the boots and slicker of Caz McLeary, a rough-and-tumble Scot who’s shipped off to the isolated North Sea oil rig Beira D after getting into a wee bit of trouble on the mainland. In fact, he seems to have gotten into <em>more</em> trouble and is about to be fired when the rig strikes… something… mysterious at the bottom of the ocean. The exact nature of what besets the rig is never really explained, but suffice to say, it’s soon overgrown with fleshy mind-altering growths, and the crew begins to transform into Lovecraftian tentacled monstrosities straight out of John Carpenter’s The Thing. Caz must find a way to escape the rapidly deteriorating rig while thoughts of the wife and children he left behind frequently intrude on these thoughts.</p>
<p>Given some of the past games The Chinese Room and director Dan Pinchbeck have worked on, you may be expecting Still Wakes the Deep to offer up a deep level of characterization, interesting twists, and/or narrative tricks, but it… never really does. For the most part, this is a straightforward, point-to-point, event-driven story. Go activate the lifeboats! Oh, they’re damaged? Go find the chopper! Oh, it crashed? Go fix the generators… and so on and so forth. Caz has a somewhat sketchy past, but it isn’t really particularly unique or surprising. The game occasionally offers a brief flashback to his life before coming to the rig and I kept expecting them to reveal something more juicy.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/WCCFstillwakesthedeep4.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Don’t get me wrong, the oil rig setting remains interesting, and all the characters mercilessly ragging on each other in their oatmeal-thick Scottish accents is fun (I think this game may set the record for most uses of the c-word). And yeah, without giving anything away, the game’s final moments will likely tug at your heartstrings, particularly if you’re a dad. That said, overall, I’ll admit I was expecting a bit more from Still Wake the Deep’s narrative.</p>
<p>Still Wake the Deep’s story not being particularly memorable would be a big issue if it were like some of The Chinese Room’s past games, as the studio has, fairly or not, become somewhat synonymous with the “walking simulator” genre. Games like Dear Esther were pretty much <em>all about</em> exploration and story, but that isn’t really the case with The Chinese Room’s latest.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/WCCFstillwakesthedeep5.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Still Wakes the Deep is more about the moment-to-moment action, and while you’ll be doing more than just walking, things are still relatively simple mechanically as you won’t be wielding any weapons, tools, or inventory items. The game takes place entirely in first person, with Caz running and jumping around the rig to get where he’s going and escape pursuers. The right shoulder button is used to grip onto things (ladders, ledges, etc.), and occasionally, you’ll need to quickly press the left trigger to regain your grip on something. Various levers, valves, and other devices can be interacted with via a combination of button presses and directional inputs. Simple stealth sections ask you to get by tentacled beasties by crouching and sneaking and tossing loose items as distractions. Occasionally, you’ll have to put out a fire with a nearby extinguisher, and later in the game, a fair amount of swimming is foisted on you.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/WCCFstillwakesthedeep7-1.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>And that’s really it in terms of gameplay. First-person platforming is never going to be <em>ideal</em>, but, for the most part, the game’s controls feel good enough. The stealth mechanics are very limited, but so are the enemies you face – simply scoot from one bit of cover to the next when they’re not looking and you’ll be fine. Unfortunately, things do fall apart a bit when it comes to the underwater swimming sections, which can be disorienting and a bit frustrating.</p>
<p>While Still Wakes the Deep takes place on a large oil rig, don’t expect any sort of Metroidvania-style level design here. The game confines you to a very linear path, with boxes, rubble, fires, and an endless succession of locked doors keeping you from straying. And really, there’s no need to explore anyway, as the game doesn’t have any ammo, healing items, collectibles, or even much in the way of journals or other bits of supplementary info to find.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/WCCFstillwakesthedeep6.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Finding your route forward can be occasionally frustrating, but usually not, as the game’s devs <em>very</em> clearly signpost where you’re supposed to go. I usually find the debate about “yellow paint” a bit overblown – I think it’s a perfectly legitimate mechanic used sparingly, but Still Wakes the Deep <em>doesn’t</em> use it sparingly. Sometimes, the game almost feels like a parody, a worst-case scenario for people who complain about yellow paint online. I think the makers of Still Wakes the Deep may realize they’ve gone a bit overboard because PR made sure to tell me there will be an update that adds the option to remove much of the yellow paint. That might reduce the razzing this game will get online, but I’m not sure how playable it will be without it. The fact is, this game was clearly designed around the yellow paint, so simply letting people turn it off might not actually improve the experience.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/WCCFstillwakesthedeep8.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The overuse of yellow aside, this is a solid, but not remarkable-looking, game. There are some visually striking moments when things really go to hell late in the game, but for the most part, this looks like a pretty standard last-gen game despite being built on Unreal Engine 5. Speaking of UE5, the performance issues common to many games built on the engine are also present here. The game’s Fidelity mode feels unplayably sluggish (and I’m usually not a stickler about 30fps gaming) and while Performance mode feels better, it has its share of hiccups.</p>
<p>Despite my complaints in the previous paragraphs, there’s no denying Still Wakes the Deep delivers a good amount of excitement, whether you’re clinging to the underside of the rig in the midst of a raging storm or dashing through ruined corridors with a tentacled beastie on your tail. That said, the extreme linearity of the game ultimately gives the proceedings a straightforward rollercoaster-like feel. Without any player choice or strategy in the mix, there just isn’t all that much tension. And hey, once you’ve seen one writhing mass of flesh and tentacles, you’ve kinda seen them all.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Still Wakes the Deep PS5 4K Gameplay - Performance Mode" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LU5KUmuqrvc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Much like a rollercoaster, this particular ride is also over rather quickly. I rolled credits in around 4 to 5 hours and there isn’t much built-in incentive to play through again, making Still Wakes the Deep’s $35 asking price a bit hard to swallow. While some may be willing to ship off again just to re-experience the ride, I have a feeling most will opt to remain on dry land.</p>
<p><em>This review was based on a PS5 copy of Still Wakes the Deep provided by publisher Secret Mode. </em></p>

					
					

<p>While Still Wakes the Deep offers up its fair share of thrills, railroad-style level design, a short runtime, and a surprisingly superficial story result in an experience that may entertain in the moment, but will likely be forgotten rather quickly. Still Wakes the Deep may well float your boat at a discount, but there are better, scarier fish in the sea.</p>

<div>
		<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Pros</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>A cast of charmingly salty Scots
</li><li>Solid platforming and stealth
</li><li>Steady flow of thrills and chills
</li><li>Ending lands well</li>		</ul>
	</div>
			<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Cons</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Story rather simple overall
</li><li>Underwater bits not so solid
</li><li>Level design extremely linear
</li><li>Short without much replay</li>		</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

					
				</main>
			</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead Is a Single Player Horror Game Out in 2024, Made by Stormind Games]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-a-single-player-horror-game-out-in-2024-made-by-stormind-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-a-single-player-horror-game-out-in-2024-made-by-stormind-games.903204/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-a-single-player-horror-game-out-in-2024-made-by-stormind-games/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, publisher Saber Interactive has announced A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead, a first-person single player horror adventure game set in the film universe created by John Krasinski.</p>
<p>The title is being developed by the Italian studio Stormind Games, known for the horror franchise <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/remothered-broken-porcelain/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Remothered</a> and for the action RPG Batora: Lost Haven. It will be released by the end of 2024 on PC (Steam), PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>
<p>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead aims to capture the unique mix of frantic terror, chilling atmosphere, and engaging human drama that popularized the movies. Players will experience the journey of a young woman who must not only survive the nightmarish creatures of the apocalypse but also the anguish of interpersonal family conflict and her own inner fears.</p>
<p>They'll have nothing more than wits and simple scavenged tools at their disposal to overcome the many treacherous challenges and obstacles that lie ahead, all while trying to survive the ever-present threat of the relentless alien enemies. Here's the official feature set shared in the press release:</p>
<p><em>• <strong>A New Story in the A Quiet Place Universe:</strong> Embark on a dramatic new adventure in the world of the blockbuster A Quiet Place saga. Discover an untold tale of fear and courage as a young survivor trying to endure the eerie new nightmare of the apocalypse.</em><br>
<em>• <strong>Feel the Unnerving Terror of Silence:</strong> Experience absolute horror as you hide, distract, and sneak past the ultimate predatory creatures. But beware: even a single noise can give you away.</em><br>
<em>• <strong>Survive the End of the World:</strong> Discover your own path forward through the disquieting remains of human civilization, using your wits and ingenuity to observe each environment, leverage whatever tools you can find, and overcome the dangers all around you.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead - Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/91zi75E_SA8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You can check out the first batch of in-game screenshots for A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead in the gallery below.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>It is presently unclear whether there's a direct relation between this game and the previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/a-quiet-place-game-in-development-at-illogika-due-in-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> A Quiet Place horror adventure game in development at ILLOGIKA. The most likely scenario is that Saber Interactive switched development to Stormind Games.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[House of the Dragon leaves no room for theories — they’re all doomed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24178745/house-dragon-season-2-premiere-review-episode-1</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/house-of-the-dragon-leaves-no-room-for-theories-%E2%80%94-they%E2%80%99re-all-doomed.903201/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24178745/house-dragon-season-2-premiere-review-episode-1<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="YKXfUB">The season 2 premiere of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/house-of-the-dragon"><em>House of the Dragon</em></a> does viewers a kindness. Instead of following up on nearly every thread from the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23419108/house-dragon-aemond-lucerys-vhagar-battle">season 1 finale</a>, “A Son for a Son” mainly concerns itself with one: the shocking death of young Lucerys and his dragon Arrax at the hands of his <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23419041/house-dragon-aemond-targaryen-death-dragon-sapphire-eye-villain-meaning">uncle Aemond</a>. Perhaps it’s strange to call this grim opening “kind,” but in doing this the show is able to lead with feelings, not lore or politicking, although there’s plenty of that, too. Mostly, it’s a story about everyone realizing they started a war, and kind of regretting it. </p>
<p id="ciYgmh">This is in spite of <em>Dragon</em>’s opening moments on the Wall, hundreds of miles away from King’s Landing, where the bulk of the episode takes place. In this first scene, Jacaerys “Jace” Velaryon (Harry Collett) meets with Cregan Stark (Tom Taylor) to see what men of the Night’s Watch will join his mother Rhaenyra’s cause in the coming civil war. Cregan acquiesces, but not before musing a bit about the Wall and its purpose. The Night’s Watch in this show is not a dead-end job, as it is in <a href="https://www.polygon.com/game-of-thrones"><em>Game of Thrones</em></a>, but a noble calling, and its members remember what the Wall is for, at least symbolically: keeping Death itself at bay, with a line that even dragons fear to cross. </p>
<p id="w341LW">With this callback, <em>House of the Dragon</em> reminds viewers of its mission, and how it differs from <em>Game of Thrones</em>:<em> </em>This is not a show about existential threats. This is a more contained story, about the small and often petty grievances, misunderstandings, and ambitions of a small group of people painfully aware of history’s weight, or desperate to slip its bonds. </p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1718632823_6581_37477" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25491936,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GNS-L_UuDff2BaHwhzQUjnJCkhY=/0x0:1920x1280/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yZZtLTLqVO2WurnRsKRrz4Rig0Q=/0x0:1920x1280/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wIywTKQkvUZalEZFcKKiX6qrBiQ=/0x0:1920x1280/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t6X04QDmnGZyjttXvGneNjT3i5Q=/0x0:1920x1280/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ibpoy6tfpg4e_6j2cG2165UhCEs=/0x0:1920x1280/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/marZqYL6G5QqnXaDrqlv8PWXdAo=/0x0:1920x1280/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/azrEcYIm51XRvXOqKAB1Su62J1w=/0x0:1920x1280/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hJmMIWZ2dLz16XIgMMxgmHjDqN4=/0x0:1920x1280/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Hd2IEWY4ycdUIwdyIEkD_VL_S-c=/0x0:1920x1280/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491936/harry_collett_tom_taylor.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Ollie Upton/HBO</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="2955cT">To that end, “A Son for a Son” is about the many players in King’s Landing and beyond feebly fretting over how to avert open war, or fiending for it. Young Aegon, the new king, wants to be a kind and magnanimous ruler, but is checked by his Hand, Otto Hightower, who reminds him that his every word sets a precedent. His brother Aemond knows that no amount of goodwill the young king is able to curry will dissuade those who back Rhaenyra’s claim to the throne, and craves action. Rhaenyra herself has withdrawn in grief, seeking the remains of her son and his dragon, while those in her circle — like her husband/uncle, Daemon — impatiently prowl in their chambers, eager to assert the justness of their cause to the denizens of the realm. </p>
<p id="XkE36y">But scale is not the only way <em>House of the Dragon</em> differentiates itself from its predecessor. What makes it such a fascinating spinoff series is its source material, and how its showrunners have chosen to adapt it. <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23057740/read-fire-blood-house-of-the-dragon"><em>Fire &amp; Blood</em> is not a novel</a>; it’s an in-universe historical account, complete with differing perspectives on pivotal events. Showrunner Ryan Condal and <em>House of the Dragon</em>’s writing staff have decided to leverage this aspect of Martin’s work as <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23423671/house-dragon-season-1-review">a source of dramatic irony</a>. As <em>Game of Thrones</em> and A Song of Ice and Fire used sheer distance and time separating characters to engineer tragic arcs, <em>House of the Dragon</em> finds moments of imprecision or chaos to lean on character flaws and introduce uncertainty. Do two characters <em>actually</em> understand one another? Why would they? Why wouldn’t they? </p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1718632823_6510_37478" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25491939,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6cZApn7h8AXDrCf9Pkl-z0C0GXc=/0x0:1920x1280/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f9J_1ZvEeAxdNoY84c_RBBX6AcA=/0x0:1920x1280/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WgZOhDbcnffCZtIkXjYF7fqmAQs=/0x0:1920x1280/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mqm2Po4TS6wH6PYfvzATXpzcnMY=/0x0:1920x1280/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B9ziycEECljZJddwHd-3gQA2B7A=/0x0:1920x1280/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iy5Fwdj5Xq51TO6ztzJHV56kHSg=/0x0:1920x1280/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CO3ouez85H0QGpANx4Xh3CkTqHQ=/0x0:1920x1280/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jj5rcC-zB7xzphv0CpaK0fULoKY=/0x0:1920x1280/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yJg6tDITVSKpsWYS6HuMySgTW0k=/0x0:1920x1280/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1280):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25491939/tom_glynn_carney.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Ollie Upton/HBO</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="h7NhKP"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/e/23942690">The final act of “A Son for a Son” hinges</a> on such a moment of uncertainty, as Daemon (Matt Smith), unwilling to let Lucerys’ death go unanswered, hires a ratcatcher to assassinate Aemond in his bed. But he is careless, arrogant, simply interested in a blood debt being paid, and his brief instructions reflect that. Someone else dies as a result, and the course of history shifts again. </p>
<p id="78bm0h">It’s all so human, so <em>trivial</em>, the lapses in judgment or thoughtless acts that turn the gears of power and sweep up countless lives in their wake. <em>House of the Dragon</em> feels built to ruminate on these moments, to leave the viewer bitterly wondering how simply things could have gone another way, if not a better one. <em>Game of Thrones</em>, in its adaptation of an unfinished work and grander storytelling priorities, rarely felt this top-to-bottom reminiscent of Greek tragedy. But in <em>House of the Dragon</em>, fate itself lurks in the halls of King’s Landing. The Iron Throne will rust. People will make terrible choices that will tear through the lives of innocent people. But we will also see, with terrible clarity, the very moments those people nearly chose differently. </p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alone in the Dark 2024 Developer Pieces Interactive Shut Down]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/alone-in-the-dark-2024-developer-pieces-interactive-shut-down/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alone-in-the-dark-2024-developer-pieces-interactive-shut-down.903198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/alone-in-the-dark-2024-developer-pieces-interactive-shut-down/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>The <a href="https://www.piecesinteractive.se/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official website</a> for developer Pieces Interactive reveals that Alone in the Dark 2024 reimagining was their “last release,” confirming the studio will shut down.</p>



<p>The site also posted an image citing the studio’s years of activity lasting from 2007 to 2024. This included the message “thanks for playing with us.”</p>



<p>However, the page does not give an official statement regarding the shutdown itself. Instead, it mentions its long history of clients, titles, and the Embracer Group acquisition.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Besides Alone in the Dark, fans will recognize Pieces Interactive for their work on the Titan Quest and Magicka series.</p>



<p>The studio’s take on Alone in the Dark launched in March 2024 to solid reviews. It started with Mostly Positive on Steam, and still has a user score of 7.5 on Metacritic.</p>



<p>However, just one month ago, Embracer Group said that Pieces Interactive’s Alone in the Dark title <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/embracer-group-says-alone-in-the-dark-failed-to-meet-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">failed to meet expectations</a>, which may have contributed to getting shut down. </p>



<p>In an earnings report, Embracer stated the game had a “mixed reception from critics and ultimately performed below management expectations.”</p>



<p>Embracer Group also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/alone-in-the-dark-developer-pieces-interactive-lays-off-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">laid off employees</a> at Pieces Interactive in April 2024. This occurred around the same time that Embracer split into <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/embracer-group-splitting-into-three-separate-companies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">three different companies</a>. </p>



<p>Embracer did not give an immediate statement after laying off staff at Pieces Interactive in April, nor about the developer getting shut down this month.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about Indiana Jones and the Great Circle <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/unseen-footage-create-the-great-circle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">using unseen movie footage</a> for research, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.903195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Developed by Stormind Games.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Saber Interactive [285 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/saber-interactive">Saber Interactive</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Stormind Games [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/stormind-games">Stormind Games</a> have announced single-player <a title="Genres > Horror [431 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,570 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead">A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</a></em>, a spin-off of the horror movie series, for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,306 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,588 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,475 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2233120/A_Quiet_Place_The_Road_Ahead/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch in 2024. <span id="more-892559"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Saber Interactive:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead </em>is a single-player horror adventure game inspired by the critically acclaimed blockbuster movie franchise that highlights a unique survivor story after an invasion of deadly creatures. In this exclusive spin-off, experience the journey of a young woman who must endure a treacherous apocalypse in the midst of interpersonal family conflicts, all while coming to terms with her own inner fears.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Unnerving Atmosphere</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> absolute terror as you strive for silence when hiding from, and sneaking by, horrific creatures who hunt using only sound.</li><li><strong>Untold Story</strong> – Embark on a dramatic adventure inspired by the <em>A Quiet Place</em> movie franchise as a young survivor trying to navigate the new, eerily tranquil, post-apocalyptic landscape.</li><li><strong>Uncanny Ingenuity</strong> – Discover your own path through the world by observing your environment and leveraging the tools in your surroundings.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead/june-17-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead - Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/91zi75E_SA8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_892558"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Todd Howard Discusses Next Fallout Game And How Bethesda Is In No Rush To Make It]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/todd-howard-discusses-next-fallout-game-and-how-bethesda-is-in-no-rush-to-make-it/1100-6524308/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/todd-howard-discusses-next-fallout-game-and-how-bethesda-is-in-no-rush-to-make-it.903192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/todd-howard-discusses-next-fallout-game-and-how-bethesda-is-in-no-rush-to-make-it/1100-6524308/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524308">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>With a well-received TV adaptation leading to a resurgence in popularity for Fallout video games, 2024 has been a pretty good year so far for Bethesda. Now that a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fallout-season-2-release-date-trailers-news/2900-5269/" data-ref-id="2900-5269">second season of Fallout has been greenlit</a>, the expectation for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-5-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6522412/" data-ref-id="1100-6522412">Fallout 5</a> is higher than ever, but Bethesda's Todd Howard says that there are no plans to rush out a new mainline Fallout game just yet. Thanks to the ongoing popularity of Fallout 76--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-76-skyline-valley-expansion-has-arrived-check-out-the-patch-notes/1100-6524268/" data-ref-id="1100-6524268">new DLC for the game has launched</a>--the company plans to bring the franchise back in a more meaningful way.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2ew8LQFGNWU" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2ew8LQFGNWU" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>"For other Fallout games in the future, you know obviously I can't talk about those right now but I would say sort of rushing through them or we need to get stuff out that is different than the work we're doing in 76, you know we don't feel like we need to rush any of that you know right now," Howard said in an interview with MrMattyPlays. "The Fallout TV show fills a certain niche in terms of the franchise and storytelling. [I] totally get the desire for a new kind of mainline single-player game. Look, those things take time. I don't think it's bad for people to miss things. We just want to get it right and make sure that everything we're doing in a franchise, whether it's Elder Scrolls, Fallout, or Starfield, that those become meaningful moments for everybody who loved these franchises as much as we do."</p><p>It's worth noting that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-fallout-games-are-being-planned-todd-howard-says/1100-6523813/" data-ref-id="1100-6523813">new Fallout games are being planned</a>, but in a previous interview, Howard said that these will take a "good five-ish years" to still be made. Another fascinating tidbit from the interview was that Bethesda has no plans currently to bring the modernized versions of Fallout 1 and 2 to console, and looking to the stars, the company is planning to release annual expansions for Starfield that will answer some of the game's biggest mysteries.</p><p>"We want to, more or less. How long that continues? Hopefully for a very long time, but that's what we're planning for," Howard explained. "The one after this, there will be another one. and I don't know that our goal is to answer every question we sort of look at it and say 'Hey what's what's a good angle,' what do we want to add to the game as far as an experience or a tone, or those kinds of things, if that makes sense."</p><p>Starfield's first big expansion, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfield-dlc-shattered-space-gets-a-trippy-trailer-new-content-launching-today/1100-6524080/" data-ref-id="1100-6524080">Shattered Space</a>, launches later this year. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfields-june-update-adds-new-missions-bounty-scanning-and-creation-kit-but-no-vehicles/1100-6524109/" data-ref-id="1100-6524109">The game's big June update</a> added new missions, a new bounty-scanning mechanic, and opened up the Starfield Creation Kit to all modders, although some players are upset that the new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bethesda-is-charging-7-for-a-new-starfield-mission-and-players-are-upset/1100-6524221/" data-ref-id="1100-6524221">Track Alliance missions cost $7 to access</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Embracer shutters Alone in the Dark dev Pieces Interactive]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/report-embracer-shutters-alone-in-the-dark-dev-pieces-interactive</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-embracer-shutters-alone-in-the-dark-dev-pieces-interactive.903189/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/report-embracer-shutters-alone-in-the-dark-dev-pieces-interactive<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>The reimagining of the 1992 survival horror title released just last March and didn't meet sales expectations</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Embracer has reportedly shut down Pieces Interactive, the studio behind the recently released Alone in the Dark.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/embracer-shuts-down-alone-in-the-dark-developer-pieces-interactive">IGN</a>, the <a href="https://www.piecesinteractive.se/">studio's website</a> now shows an image of its logo and the text: "2007 - 2024, Thanks for playing with us."</p>
<p>A couple of paragraphs also go through the studio's history, saying: "Pieces Interactive released over ten titles on PC, console and mobile since 2007," and finishing on: "Our last release was the reimagining of Alone in the Dark."</p>
<p>Pieces Interactive was acquired by Embracer in 2017, and reports of layoffs at the <a href="https://x.com/HelenaEHHansen/status/1782781965885722950">company emerged on social media mid-April</a>.</p>
<p>Its version of 1992 survival horror classic Alone in the Dark released last March and didn't reach Embracer's sales expectations.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/embracers-lars-wingefors-on-the-brutal-truth-of-the-aaa-market#:~:text=%22Whatever%20you%20produce,get%20those%20right.%22">Talking to us last month, CEO Lars Wingefors said</a>: "I believe Alone in the Dark was a quality product, and [the developers] went all in to deliver on that. It's very unfortunate to see that it didn't catch enough consumers out there willing to engage again in that IP and product. It's just a brutal truth. It was a big investment and, ultimately, we need to get those right."</p>
<p><em>GamesIndustry.biz</em> reached out to Embracer for more information.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead is a narrative-driven first-person survival horror title launching later this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-a-narrative-driven-first-person-survival-horror-title-launching-later-this-year/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-a-narrative-driven-first-person-survival-horror-title-launching-later-this-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-a-narrative-driven-first-person-survival-horror-title-launching-later-this-year.903186/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-a-narrative-driven-first-person-survival-horror-title-launching-later-this-year/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-is-a-narrative-driven-first-person-survival-horror-title-launching-later-this-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="328" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Publisher Saber Interactive has announced that <em>A Quiet Place: The Road</em> <em>Ahead</em> will be coming to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S later this year. The game takes the cinematic universe from the films you know and love and crafts a narrative-driven adventure you’ll need to play through from an intense first-person perspective. </p> <p data-characters="523" data-current-count="523" data-injectable="true">Developed by Stormind Games, A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead takes what makes the franchise so fascinating and terrifying and brings it to PC and consoles where it can achieve the same levels of thrill and horror. It’s a first-person game driven by an intense story that sees a young woman faced with the reality that she’s going to have to venture forth into the world from her place of safety and somehow avoid the fast-paced monsters that have all but wiped out humanity and react to even the slightest sound. </p>
 <h2 id="h-embrace-silence-in-a-brand-new-a-quiet-place-story-in-a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead" data-injectable="false">Embrace silence in a brand new <em>A Quiet Place</em> story in <em>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</em> </h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Saber Interactive</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="357" data-current-count="657" data-injectable="true"><em>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</em> is a new story within the<em> A Quiet Place</em> universe that sees people try to cope with the new threat that suddenly lands on Earth. These monsters are well-armored and incredibly fast. They can’t see, but they react to any sound, quickly seek it out, and put a stop to it by breaking whatever is making it, including people. </p>
 <p data-characters="328" data-current-count="328" data-injectable="false">Much like in <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-alien-isolation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Alien Isolation</a></em> and the <em>A Quiet Place</em> franchise as a whole, you’ll be sneaking past the giant predatory creatures and causing distractions to draw them away from you or where you want to go. A single noise could give you away, and if you’ve seen either of the movies, you know that spells doom for you. </p> <p data-characters="397" data-current-count="725" data-injectable="true">To progress, you’ve got to work with the things you find in the environment. The game isn’t about beating the aliens, it’s about living to sneak under the next car or into the next building. Having watched the movies and adored them, I can’t wait to see how the tension translates into a game that puts you right in the heart of the most pulse-pounding bits of the action. </p>
 <p data-characters="345" data-current-count="345" data-injectable="false">The game’s <a href="https://youtu.be/91zi75E_SA8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trailer looks interesting</a>, and I can’t wait to experience the blend of survival and hide-and-seek gameplay combined with sections that force you out of your comfort zone to the point that it feels like you’re about to die. If done well, <em>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</em> could be a fitting follow-up to <em>Alien Isolation</em>. </p> <p data-characters="449" data-current-count="794" data-injectable="false">The <em>A Quiet Place</em> universe is absolutely terrifying. Earth is living through a quiet apocalypse, with survivors unable to make a sound lest they give themselves away and be killed by one of the aliens lurking somewhere in the distance. No part of this timeline is easy to live through, and being trapped by one of the creatures, having them hunt around the environment looking for somethign scuttling nearby, is honestly one of my worst nightmares. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All of Vegapunks’ revelations in his final speech in One Piece]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/all-of-vegapunks-revelations-in-his-final-speech-in-one-piece/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=all-of-vegapunks-revelations-in-his-final-speech-in-one-piece</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-of-vegapunks%E2%80%99-revelations-in-his-final-speech-in-one-piece.903183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/all-of-vegapunks-revelations-in-his-final-speech-in-one-piece/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=all-of-vegapunks-revelations-in-his-final-speech-in-one-piece<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="414" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">It is common knowledge that Dr. Vegapunk is the brightest mind in the entire <em>One Piece</em> universe. At least, no one has topped his genius yet. Unfortunately, possessing knowledge isn’t always a welcomed notion in the eyes of the World Government, and Dr. Vegapunk may have become too smart for his own good. If you don’t understand what I mean, be warned. You will likely get spoiled if you read further.</p> <p data-characters="287" data-current-count="287" data-injectable="false">Fans have been questioning Dr. Vegapunk’s alignment since his introduction to the series. He seems to be villainous due to his allegiance to the World Government, yet so many good characters speak fondly of him. It turns out the mad genius is just a seeker of truth and knowledge. </p> <p data-characters="299" data-current-count="586" data-injectable="true">With the World Government hunting his behind, he didn’t want his accumulated knowledge to be buried with him. The moment his heart stopped beating, a pre-recorded video feed was broadcast across the globe. Here’s everything he revealed, solving <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/10-mysteries-in-one-piece-that-still-have-no-clear-answers/">some of the series’ great mysteries</a>.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via MangaPlus</figcaption></figure> <h2 id="h-the-world-of-one-piece-is-sinking" data-injectable="false">The world of One Piece is sinking</h2> <p data-characters="413" data-current-count="713" data-injectable="true">According to Dr. Vegapunk, the world of <em>One Piece</em> is slowly sinking. Interestingly, this revelation doesn’t come as much of a surprise. There have been signs and hints even during the earlier arcs of the series, with the most obvious one being Water 7. After all, a good portion of the Capital of Water has already sunk under the sea. However, Dr. Vegapunk’s first revelation doesn’t stop there.</p>
 <p data-characters="345" data-current-count="345" data-injectable="false">The genius scientist predicted that the world would experience gargantuan earthquakes, raising the sea level by a meter. And he was spot on. The more surprising piece of information, however, is that these earthquakes aren’t a natural phenomenon. They are man-made, which leads to the next revelation and will be expounded on the last one.</p> <figure data-current-count="645" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via MangaPlus</figcaption></figure>
 <h2 id="h-dr-vegapunk-s-two-sins" data-injectable="false">Dr. Vegapunk’s two sins</h2> <p data-characters="281" data-current-count="281" data-injectable="false">During the video feed, Dr. Vegapunk confesses to two sins he apparently committed. The first one is creating an eternal source of energy, the Mother Flame. The second one is digging deep into the Void Century — the history that the World Government is strenuously trying to bury.</p> <p data-characters="565" data-current-count="846" data-injectable="true">Dr. Vegapunk’s motivation for his inventions has always been for the betterment of the world’s denizens. He wanted an energy source that could fuel every corner of the world. The manifestation of his hard work and research is the Mother Flame — a flame that never goes out. However, a piece of the said flame has been stolen and utilized to activate an Ancient Weapon to wipe out Lulusia. The manga already revealed that the culprit behind both instances is the World Government. Nonetheless, Dr. Vegapunk blamed himself for the loss of so many lives.</p>
 <p data-characters="287" data-current-count="287" data-injectable="false">As for this second sin, it is much simpler. He confesses to studying the incomplete records of the Void Century, which are primarily from what is left of the research of the archaeologists of Ohara. But despite his limited information, Dr. Vegapunk has learned enough to shake the world.</p> <figure data-current-count="587" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via MangaPlus</figcaption></figure>
 <h2 id="h-the-truth-behind-void-century" data-injectable="false">The truth behind Void Century</h2> <p data-characters="351" data-current-count="351" data-injectable="false">The main culprit behind the exploits done in the Void Century is the ever-so-enigmatic Joyboy. Dr. Vegapunk reveals that Joyboy was born in an era wherein technology was more advanced. Like the Sun God himself, Joyboy possessed the ability to stretch and contract his body. But most importantly, Joyboy was the very first person to be called a pirate.</p> <p data-characters="344" data-current-count="695" data-injectable="true">While Joyboy’s goals are unknown, his enemies are known to be called the Alliance. This alliance ultimately became the Celestial Dragons that would establish the world government. The two sides fought harshly, ending with Joyboy’s defeat. That is also when the Void Century ended. Then, it all connects to his first two revelations.</p>
 <p data-characters="461" data-current-count="461" data-injectable="true">While the battle between Joyboy and the Alliance came to an end, the aftermath of their battle is still visible to the present world of <em>One Piece</em>. Dr. Vegapunk proceeds to explain that the world during Joyboy’s time wasn’t as watery as the present. Since then, the world has sunk 200 meters. The current geography is nothing more than a few pieces of a continent from long ago. Furthermore, there may have been a number of sunk, unknown continents. </p>
 <p data-characters="503" data-current-count="503" data-injectable="true">The sudden rise of sea level is a hypothesis that Dr. Vegapunk already proved. Despite suffering defeat, Joyboy left the three Ancient Weapons for the future. Even though Dr. Vegapunk did not expound on this topic further, we, the readers, are already aware of their existence. Pluton remains in Wano while Poseidon is Princess Shirahoshi. That only leaves Uranus. With the stolen Mother Flame as fuel, Imu activated Uranus and obliterated Lulusia, which then led to the one-meter increase in sea level.</p>
 <p data-characters="151" data-current-count="151" data-injectable="false">Alas, Dr. Vegapunk would have made another important revelation relating to the Will of D. Unfortunately, his feed was cut off before the grand reveal.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alone in the Dark Developer Pieces Interactive Shut Down]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/alone-in-dark-developer-pieces-interactive-shut-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alone-in-the-dark-developer-pieces-interactive-shut-down.903177/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/alone-in-dark-developer-pieces-interactive-shut-down<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Alone in the Dark&nbsp;</em>developer Pieces Interactive has seemingly been closed down by its parent company Embracer Group.</p>
<p>Heading over to the official Pieces Interactive <a href="https://www.piecesinteractive.se/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">website</a>, at time of writing, simply displays a graphic which shows the studio's logo, as well as the text "2007-2024" and "Thanks For Playing With Us".</p>
<p>The studio then points to the work it's done over the years, including original titles like&nbsp;<em>Leviathan Warships&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Robo Surf</em>, as well as "work for hire" games like&nbsp;<em>Magicka 2&nbsp;</em>and several of its DLCs.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/alone-in-the-dark-pieces-interactive-gameplay.jpg?itok=7rmdzuK4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/alone-in-the-dark-pieces-interactive-gameplay.jpg?itok=E50y_Wip 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Alone in the Dark&nbsp;</em>developer Pieces Interactive is apparently no more.</figcaption></figure><p>Pieces Interactive goes on to say that its "last release" was this year's&nbsp;<em>Alone in the Dark&nbsp;</em>"reimagining".</p>
<p>Over on his LinkedIn page, character artist Gustav Pethrus <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7208340178204078081/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">confirms</a> that Pieces Interactive has been shut down and that he's looking for new work as a result.</p>
<p>Poignantly, Pieces Interactive's last post on X before <a href="https://x.com/PiecesInt/status/1802612988286804218" rel="noopener" target="_blank">sharing the shutdown notice</a> was a <a href="https://x.com/PiecesInt/status/1770814977005293983" rel="noopener" target="_blank">message</a> entreating fans to "enjoy" the&nbsp;<em>Alone in the Dark&nbsp;</em>remake.</p>
<p>The writing has probably been on the wall for Pieces Interactive since&nbsp;<em>Alone in the Dark</em>'s release, unfortunately; earlier this year, when Embracer Group released its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-financials-70-projects">yearly financial statement</a>, it admitted that&nbsp;<em>Alone in the Dark</em>, as well as a number of other titles, had underperformed.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/alone-in-the-dark-pieces-interactive-emily.jpg?itok=bto6QtS1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/alone-in-the-dark-pieces-interactive-emily.jpg?itok=5HgDfdi6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Alone in the Dark&nbsp;</em>didn't do well enough to save Pieces Interactive, it seems.</figcaption></figure><p>Embracer Group hasn't released exact sales figures for the game, but it didn't just underperform commercially.&nbsp;<em>Alone in the Dark&nbsp;</em>also <a href="https://opencritic.com/game/16050/alone-in-the-dark-2024-" rel="noopener" target="_blank">received middling reviews on release</a>, with reviewers frequently pointing to its lack of polish and innovation as major drawbacks.</p>
<p>Not everyone felt that way, though. Our very own Tyler rather enjoyed the game, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/alone-in-dark-review-southern-gothic-hospitality">awarding it an 8.0 in his review</a> and citing its "foreboding" atmosphere and "challenging" gameplay as highlights.</p>
<p>Pieces Interactive's closure seems to be part of a wide-ranging restructuring effort at parent company Embracer Group (which will <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-splitting-three-companies">soon split into three separate entities</a>). Although CEO Lars Wingefors told investors in April that the <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/embracer-ceo-says-restructuring-is-over-no-other-studios-for-sale" rel="noopener" target="_blank">restructuring was over</a>, it seems that doesn't mean Embracer is done closing studios.</p>
<p>The company's restructuring effort has also seen studios like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-shuts-down-saints-row-developer-volition"><em>Saints Row&nbsp;</em>developer Volition</a> and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/probable-images-of-free-radicals-timesplitters-game-revealed-after-studio-closure-by"><em>TimeSplitters</em>&nbsp;studio Free Radical</a> closed down, as well as the sale of entities like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-saber-interactive">Saber Interactive</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/grand-theft-auto-publisher-take-two-to-acquire-gearbox-from-embracer-new-borderlands-in">Gearbox</a>.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more info on this and all other things Embracer Group-related.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bethesda's Todd Howard confirms at least one more Starfield expansion after Shattered Space]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesdas-todd-howard-confirms-at-least-one-more-starfield-expansion-after-shattered-space</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bethesdas-todd-howard-confirms-at-least-one-more-starfield-expansion-after-shattered-space.903174/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesdas-todd-howard-confirms-at-least-one-more-starfield-expansion-after-shattered-space<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>In it for the long Va'ruun.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Starfield-Shattered-Space-trailer-screenshot.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bethesda</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Todd Howard has shared more about Bethesda's future DLC plans for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-guides-tips-tricks-9352">Starfield</a>. 
</p>
<p>
Speaking with YouTuber MrMattyPlays, the Bethesda exec spoke about the studio's "annual story expansion" approach. When further asked about his comment and whether Bethesda was taking this approach with Starfield, Howard replied: "I would say we want to, more or less, yeah. How long that continues? Hopefully a very long time." </p>
<p>He then added the studio was already "planning for the one after this", confirming "there will be another one" after Shattered Space.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Starfield: Shattered Space - Official Trailer - Xbox Games Showcase 2024<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93dtPInrIMg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Howard went on to say he didn't believe the goal of these expansions was to "answer every question" in Starfield. "We sort of look at it and say, 'Hey, what's a good angle? What do we want to add to the game as far as an experience or a tone or those kinds of things', if that makes sense," he said, but refrained from adding more. 
</p>
<p>
Elsewhere in the interview, Howard said Starfield has 14 million players with an average play time of 40 hours. He also said development on Shattered Space started back in September, when Starfield first launched. </p>
<p>Since then, the studio has introduced a number of updates, as well as the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-fans-arent-happy-bethesdas-charging-6-for-a-single-creation-mission">game's Creations storefront</a>.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
We got our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/first-look-at-starfields-shattered-space-expansion-but-still-no-release-date">first proper look at Starfield's Shattered Space expansion</a> earlier this month, when Bethesda released a space-horror flavoured trailer during the Xbox showcase. You can check it out in the video above.
</p>
<p>
Shattered Space will offer a fresh mystery involving the snake-loving House Va'ruun, at some point later in 2024. 

</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alone in the Dark reboot developer closed by Embracer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/alone-in-the-dark-reboot-developer-closed-by-embracer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alone-in-the-dark-reboot-developer-closed-by-embracer.903171/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/alone-in-the-dark-reboot-developer-closed-by-embracer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Thanks for playing with us."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/alone-in-the-dark-david-and-emily-driving-to-derceto-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer / THQ Nordic</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Pieces Interactive, the developer behind the recent Alone in the Dark reboot, has been shut down by Embracer.
</p>
<p>
The developer's website now reads "thanks for playing with us" and the dates 2007-2024. "Our last release was the reimagining of Alone in the Dark," it concludes (thanks <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/embracer-shuts-down-alone-in-the-dark-developer-pieces-interactive">IGN</a>).
</p>
<p>
Embracer acquired Pieces in 2017 after working on a number of Titan Quest projects. The Swedish conglomerate has closed a number of developers over the past year, resulting in layoffs.
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Alone In The Dark Showcase Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bbrcx46Zl60" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>

Pieces released over 10 games across PC, console and mobile since it was founded in 2007, including original projects and support for other games from Paradox, Koei Tecmo, Arrowhead, Koch Media and more.
</p>
<p>
The studio is the latest casualty from Embracer, which <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/embattled-publisher-embracer-sells-off-saber-assets-withdraws-from-russia">sold off its Saber assets</a> in March and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/take-two-acquires-borderlands-studio-gearbox-from-embracer-for-460m">sold Borderlands developer Gearbox to Take-Two</a> the same month for $460m.
</p>
<p>
The company has shed thousands of staff after a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/embracer-shares-plummet-after-proposed-2bn-partnership-collapses">major $2bn investment fell through</a>.
</p>
<p>
This was all part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-the-human-cost-of-embracers-restructuring-programme">restructuring programme that's seen Embracer's headcount reduced</a> by 4532 employees in the past financial year, 44 studios closed, and 80 in-development projects dropped.
</p>
<p>
Embracer's quarterly financial report in May stated the programme was "successfully finalised". It's unclear if Pieces was part of this programme, or if the decision to close the studio was made separately.
</p>
<p>
Alone in the Dark released to lukewarm reviews in March and "softer-than-expected performance" from Embracer management.
</p>
<p>
"Great ideas and a storied history are mired in mediocre combat and a disappointingly unpolished delivery," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/alone-in-the-dark-review-1">Eurogamer Alone in the Dark review</a>.


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shovel Knight is getting online co-op as part of a new Shovel Of Hope DX edition for its 10th anniversary]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shovel-knight-is-getting-co-op-multiplayer-as-part-of-a-new-shovel-of-hope-dx-edition-for-its-10th-anniversary</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shovel-knight-is-getting-online-co-op-as-part-of-a-new-shovel-of-hope-dx-edition-for-its-10th-anniversary.903168/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shovel-knight-is-getting-co-op-multiplayer-as-part-of-a-new-shovel-of-hope-dx-edition-for-its-10th-anniversary<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/shovel-knight-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Yacht Club Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Well, shovel me timbers! <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/shovel-knight">Shovel Knight</a>, the retro <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-platform-games-on-pc">platformer</a> that started it all (it all being everything from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/shovel-knight-dig">a roguelike spin-off</a> to a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dead-cells">Dead Cells</a> cameo) turns 10 this month, and Yacht Club Games are releasing a ultimate edition to celebrate. Entitled the ‘Shovel Of Hope DX’, this definitive-me-doo bundles in the original game with old and new features like saving and rewinding, over 20 playable characters, local and online co-op, and new modes. Grab your shovel and prepare to dig for the trailer, then look foolish as you realise it’s directly below this paragraph.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Shovel Knight: Shovel of Hope DX Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cbpEXPSvFtc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Shovel Knight: Shovel of Hope DX Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cbpEXPSvFtc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cbpEXPSvFtc?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cbpEXPSvFtc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>I apologise for that rogueish act of wanton bamboozlement, and I hope we can still be friends. Not least so we may one day play Shovel Knight together. I’m such a proponent of couch co-op being included wherever possible that I once lobbied RPS to introduce a ‘Holy gherkins! It’s got couch co-op!’ sticker to sit alongside ‘Bestest Best’. I even made a mock-up in Paint. It had two anthropomorphic gherkins sitting beside each other on a couch. Alice Bee (RPS in peace) did not care for it. On reflection, she was probably right. Still, it’s a fine feature, and one Shovel Knight introduced to PC in their ‘Treasure Trove’ edition. Now, it’s being joined by online multiplayer.</p>
<p>The other big newness in this edition - which doesn’t yet have a release date - is the ability to laugh in the face of chronology itself. “Use the power of Rewind to perfect your platforming skills or use Save States to pause and plan your next moves,” boasteth the trailer’s doobly-doo. This sits alongside over “300 classic gameplay-twisting cheats,” and extra modes. Specifically “Challenge Stages, Custom Knight, and the Battle Ghost Arena.”</p>
<p>“It's also our way of preserving the game's historical functionality, ensuring these elements remain available for future generations of players. And with the new multiplayer features and other enhancements, we hope it includes everything on your wish list,” say Yacht Club Games. A noble goal for a noble knight. Back in 2020, Alex Wiltshire <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-shovel-knights-last-boss-was-designed-four-times">spoke to</a> designer David D’Angelo as part of his fantastic series of deep-dives, about how the game’s final boss was designed four times. It’s great to see Yacht Club still thriving off of a well-loved project they clearly poured an incredible amount of passion and attention into.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alone in the Dark reboot studio Pieces Interactive shuts down]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/alone-in-the-dark-reboot-studio-pieces-interactive-shuts-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alone-in-the-dark-reboot-studio-pieces-interactive-shuts-down.903165/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/alone-in-the-dark-reboot-studio-pieces-interactive-shuts-down<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Closed down after 17 years of development.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Embracer Group has closed <a title="Companies > Pieces Interactive [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/thq-nordic/pieces-interactive">Pieces Interactive</a>, the Skovde, Sweden-based studio behind this year’s <em><a title="Games > Alone in the Dark (2024) [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/alone-in-the-dark-2024">Alone in the Dark</a></em> reboot. <span id="more-892543"></span></p><p>Here is the full message posted on the developer’s <a href="https://www.piecesinteractive.se/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">official website</a>:</p><blockquote><p>Pieces Interactive released over ten titles on <a title="Platforms > PC [20,475 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, console, and mobile since 2007—both our own concepts such as <em>Puzzlegeddon</em>, <em>Fret Nice</em>, <em>Leviathan Warships</em>, <em>Robo Surf</em>, and <em>Kill to Collect</em>, as well as work for hire titles such as <em>Magicka 2</em> and several downloadable contents for <em>Magicka</em>. Our client list includes <a title="Companies > Paradox Interactive [100 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/paradox-interactive">Paradox Interactive</a>, <a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,004 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo</a>, <a title="Companies > Arrowhead Game Studios [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/arrowhead-game-studios">Arrowhead Game Studios</a>, <a title="Companies > PLAION [576 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/plaion">Koch Media</a> and RaceRoom Entertainment.</p><p>In 2017, Pieces Interactive were acquired by Embracer Group after working with the expansion for <em>Titan <a title="Platforms > Quest [104 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a></em>, <em>Titan Quest: Ragnarok</em>, and third expansion for <em>Titan Quest</em>, <em>Titan Quest: Atlantis</em>.</p><p>Our last release was the reimagining of <em>Alone in the Dark</em>.</p></blockquote></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Embracer studio Pieces Interactive has shut down]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-embracer-studio-pieces-interactive-has-shut-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-embracer-studio-pieces-interactive-has-shut-down.903153/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-embracer-studio-pieces-interactive-has-shut-down<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pieces Interactive, the Embracer-owned studio behind the recent </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Alone in the Dark</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> remake, has seemingly shut down.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.piecesinteractive.se/">shared an image on social media and its website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that reads "Pieces Interactive: 2007–2024. Thanks for playing with us."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One former employees appeared to confirmed the closure on Linkedin. "Hello everyone! Unfortunately Pieces Interactive is closing down, so I'm looking for new opportunities," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7208340178204078081/">wrote former character artist, Gustav Pethrus</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pieces released over 10 titles on PC, console and mobile including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Puzzlegeddon</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fret Nice</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Robo Surf</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kill to Collect</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It also worked on multiple expansions for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Titan Quest</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The company's latest release was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Alone in the Dark</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Swedish studio was formed in 2007 and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://embracer.com/releases/thq-nordic-acquires-pieces-interactive-ab/">acquired by Embracer in 2017</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for roughly SEK 2.8 million ($265,000). Embracer described the deal as a "long-term commitment in the studio and in the area of Skovde."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://embracer.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Embracer-Group-publishes-Interim-Report-Q4-January-March-2024-Adjusted-EBIT-increased-by-56-to-SEK-1426-million-240523.pdf">In its latest fiscal report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Embracer claimed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Alone in the Dark</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> failed to meet expectations and delivered a "softer-than-expected performance."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Embracer acquired Pieces during an era of mass expansion. The Swedish company spent years expanding through high-profile mergers and acquisitions, but </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-s-m-a-era-is-ending-with-job-cuts-and-game-cancellations">last year abruptly changed tack</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in a bid to become a "highly cash flow generative business." At the time, Embracer said it would ditch its "current heavy-investment mode" to become a "self-sufficient company."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It followed that announcement with studio closures, mass layoffs, project cancellations, and high-profile divestments–including the sale of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gearbox-is-officially-out-from-under-embracer-group">Gearbox Entertainment</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-group-divests-core-saber-interactive-assets-in-deal-worth-247-million">Saber Interactive</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. After </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-freezes-acquisition-drive-as-its-restructure-program-comes-to-an-end">bringing its restructuring program to an end in March 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-splitting-into-three-standalone-companies-to-search-for-winning-formulas-">split into three standalone, publicly-listed entities</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in a bid to find a "winning formula."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's currently unclear whether Pieces was closed down following the conclusion of Embracer's restructuring program or how many employees have been impacted by the apparent shuttering.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Embracer for comment.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surprising MW2 AR is actually one of Warzone’s best SMGs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/surprising-mw2-ar-is-actually-one-of-warzones-best-smgs/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=surprising-mw2-ar-is-actually-one-of-warzones-best-smgs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/surprising-mw2-ar-is-actually-one-of-warzone%E2%80%99s-best-smgs.903150/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/surprising-mw2-ar-is-actually-one-of-warzones-best-smgs/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=surprising-mw2-ar-is-actually-one-of-warzones-best-smgs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="261" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">If you’re looking to dominate opponents at close range in <em>Warzone</em>, then you’d be forgiven for immediately opting for your favorite SMG. However, <em>CoD</em> expert WhosImmortal has revealed an <em>MW2</em> assault rifle that can give them all a run for their money. </p> <p data-characters="261" data-current-count="261" data-injectable="false">For a long time, <em>Modern Warfare 2</em> guns have just been so weak that it’s not worth even considering them when putting together a loadout. In fact, it’s gotten so bad that players don’t want to see <em>MW2</em> or <em>MW3</em> weapons when <em>Black Ops 6 </em> releases. </p> <p data-characters="234" data-current-count="495" data-injectable="true">This might change your mind though, as WhosImmortal has revealed that with the right class, the M13C can be just as effective in close-quarters combat as the meta SMGs, even though WZRanked shows it ranked 87th in terms of pick rate. </p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="WARZONE: New CLOSE RANGE META LOADOUTS After Update! (WARZONE Best Weapons)" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_kg-8Gr9kbw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="331" data-current-count="631" data-injectable="true">In his video about the current weapons dominating the close-range meta, WhosImmortal said: “The M13C is surprisingly good as well. This thing’s close-range TTK is very, very competitive.” This is good news for players, but you’ll still need the right class to make the most of it according to the YouTuber. </p>
 <p data-characters="204" data-current-count="204" data-injectable="false">As for how he would use it, he stated that it is a “slept-on” sniper support option, which is the gun you switch to when your sniper rifle isn’t the correct weapon for closer gunfights. </p> <p data-characters="43" data-current-count="247" data-injectable="false"><strong>WhosImmortal’s M13C close-range class</strong></p> <ul data-found-items="5" data-current-count="447" data-injectable="true"> <li><strong>Muzzle:</strong> Scratch 20-L Suppressor</li> <li><strong>Underbarrel:</strong> FTAC SP-10 Angled Grip</li> <li><strong>Optic:</strong> MK.3 Reflector</li> <li><strong>Ammunition:</strong> Blackout High Grain</li> <li><strong>Magazine:</strong> 45-round mag</li> </ul>
 <p data-characters="231" data-current-count="231" data-injectable="false">With a pick rate of just 0.02%, you could truly get a jump on the rest of the community by picking this weapon up early, and WhosImmortal is convinced it can hang with the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/the-best-smg-loadouts-in-warzone-ranked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best SMGs</a>, so it’s definitely worth trying at least. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Could Get Final Fantasy XIV, But It May Not Happen For Years]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-final-fantasy-xiv/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-could-get-final-fantasy-xiv-but-it-may-not-happen-for-years.903147/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-final-fantasy-xiv/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 console could be getting one of the most popular MMORPGs of all time, Final Fantasy XIV, but it could only happen some time after the system launches.</p>
<p>Speaking in a new interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@EasyAllies">Easy Allies</a>, Final Fantasy XIV's producer Naoki Yoshida was asked about a possible release of the MMORPGs on the next Nintendo console. According to Yoshi-P, it's been his dream for over ten years to make sure the game could be played by as many players as possible, regardless of the platform. As such, the development team would love to have the game on a Nintendo platform, but it may take some time for this to happen. Mentioning the Xbox Series X|S version of the game, Naoki Yoshida highlighted how this version of the game happened years after they started talking with Microsoft, so we should definitely not expect Final Fantasy XIV to be available close to the Nintendo Switch 2 launch.</p>
<p><iframe title="Dawntrail Media Tour - Naoki Yoshida Interview - Switch 2, Cross DC Duty Finder, PVP" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cUqkL0aGL4M?start=367&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>When it comes to third-party support, the next Nintendo console should see a fair amount of support in its first <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-ports-issues-next-gen/">few years</a>. According to Infuse Studio's co-founder Jacob Stutton, developers won't have trouble supporting the system as they already need to take the Xbox Series S into consideration. Things, however, may change after the next-generation consoles are out, as the Nintendo Switch 2 specs will be considerably lower, and developers may have to make some sacrifices to get their games running on the system.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 has yet to be officially revealed. More information on it should finally be coming in the next few months.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embracer Group kills yet another studio after its Alone in the Dark remake underperformed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/embracer-group-kills-yet-another-studio-after-its-alone-in-the-dark-remake-underperformed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=embracer-group-kills-yet-another-studio-after-its-alone-in-the-dark-remake-underperformed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/embracer-group-kills-yet-another-studio-after-its-alone-in-the-dark-remake-underperformed.903144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/embracer-group-kills-yet-another-studio-after-its-alone-in-the-dark-remake-underperformed/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=embracer-group-kills-yet-another-studio-after-its-alone-in-the-dark-remake-underperformed<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="432" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Last month, Embracer Group CEO Lars Wingefors assured that the company’s restructuring efforts, which saw it shut down multiple studios and lay off roughly 27% of its staff, had ended and had “created a stronger foundation for improved profitability, cash flows and long-term value creation.” Yet as of today, Embracer has closed Pieces Interactive, the developer behind this year’s <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/review-in-progress-alone-in-the-dark/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Alone in the Dark</em> remake</a>.</p> <p data-characters="522" data-current-count="522" data-injectable="true">Although there’s been no announcement by Embracer itself, Pieces Interactive has confirmed its closure on <a href="https://www.piecesinteractive.se/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">its own website</a>. The studio was founded in 2007 and, in its 17-year history, launched over 10 games. After working with THQ on the second expansion for action RPG <em>Titan Quest</em>, it was acquired by Embracer (THQ’s parent company) in 2017. Under Embracer, it handled another <em>Titan Quest</em> expansion and then the aforementioned remake of the original <em>Alone in the Dark</em> from 1992, which launched this past March.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Embracer Group/LinkedIn.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="578" data-current-count="878" data-injectable="true">No reason has been given for Pieces Interactive’s closure, but it should be noted that the <em>Alone in the Dark</em> remake was apparently not a big hit for Embracer. There are no exact sales figures but, in <a href="https://embracer.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Embracer-Group-publishes-Interim-Report-Q4-January-March-2024-Adjusted-EBIT-increased-by-56-to-SEK-1426-million-240523.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Embracer’s report on its 2024 fiscal year</a>, it said <em>Alone in the Dark</em> “saw a positive reception from users, but a mixed reception<br>from critics and ultimately performed below management expectations.” Regardless, the shut down of Pieces Interactive is another contributor to the already <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/the-games-industry-has-already-laid-off-more-people-this-year-than-in-all-of-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">dire number of games industry layoffs</a> to have taken place this year.</p>
 <p data-characters="521" data-current-count="521" data-injectable="false">Other studios to have been closed by Embracer in the past year or so include <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/embracer-group-is-closing-down-volition-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Saints Row</em> developer Volition</a> and Free Radical, which was in the process of <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/the-timesplitters-4-prototype-is-a-stark-reminder-of-what-weve-lost/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">making a new <em>Timesplitters</em></a>. Others, <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/embracer-group-reportedly-cancels-deus-ex-game-lays-off-workers-at-eidos-montreal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">such as Eidos-Montréal</a>, were impacted by layoffs, while <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/take-two-is-buying-gearbox-from-embracer-next-borderlands-is-in-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gearbox</a> and <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/kotor-remake-developer-saber-interactive-to-leave-embracer-group/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Saber Interactive</a> have been sold off. Despite the layoffs, Embracer <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/after-selling-and-shutting-down-studios-embracer-group-wants-to-release-over-70-games-by-march-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">intends to launch 70 projects</a> (which includes DLC) by the end of March 2025. It will also be <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/embracer-group-is-ditching-its-name-and-splitting-itself-into-three-separate-companies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">splitting itself into three separate companies</a>, though none of them will keep the Embracer Group name.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Latest RPCS3 Version Offers Greatly Improved Performance on Low-End CPUs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/rpcs3-performance-low-end-cpu/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/latest-rpcs3-version-offers-greatly-improved-performance-on-low-end-cpus.903138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/rpcs3-performance-low-end-cpu/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The latest version of the popular PlayStation 3 emulator, RPCS3, allows for greatly improved performance on low-end CPUs.</p>
<p>The team behind the RPCS3 project has released a new build of the PS3 emulator, version v0.0.32-16614, and the performance gains on lower-end processors are quite major. <a href="https://x.com/rpcs3/status/1802423797670109438" target="_blank" rel="noopener">According to</a> the team behind the project, C++ developer Elad Ashkenazi has implemented additional SPU optimizations, offering "great" performance gains. We've included some screenshots showing framerates within Demon's Souls and Persona 5 running on a setup with a 4 cores/4 threads CPU below. As you can see in the screenshots, the performance gains are quite noticeable (101% performance gain in Demon's Souls, and 30,4% in Persona 5). We've also included two videos of Twisted Metal and Armored Core using the new RPS3 version (courtesy of 'Val').</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p><iframe title="Twisted Metal | 60fps RPCS3 Perf Test v0.0.32-16614 | Ryzen 7700X" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/33TgjBChCWg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><iframe title="Armored Core Verdict Day (PCVD) | 60fps RPCS3 Perf Test v0.0.32-16614 | Ryzen 7700X" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_r0H6PIq530?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Those interested can download the latest version of the PS3 PC emulator <a href="https://rpcs3.net/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>. The RPCS3 project kicked off back in 2011 and has since made great progress. At the moment of writing, the emulator is able to run over 2500 PS3 games (69,17%). Some months ago we covered that the emulator is able to <a href="https://wccftech.com/rpcs3-gt5-60fps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">run Gran Turismo 5 at 60FPS on PC</a>. Aside from ongoing work on RPCS3, the team is also working on the <a href="https://wccftech.com/rpcsx-ps4-emulator-now-supports-audio-and-gamepads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RPCSX PS4 emulator</a>.</p>
<p>We've included some info from the RPCS3 emulator's FAQ below:</p>
<div>
<p>
<h2><strong><em>Can I play multiplayer games online with real consoles or other RPCS3 users?</em></strong></h2>
</p>
<p><em>Online multiplayer is something we're thinking about and that already works on a very small amount of games with simple network code. We may not focus on it until RPCS3 is as stable and as accurate as possible. Playing games online with real PlayStation 3 systems will require the user to connect to a PlayStation Network server in many cases, thus requiring private PSN servers to be made first.</em></p>
</div>
<div>
<p>
<h2><strong><em>Can I play local-multiplayer games with RPCS3?</em></strong></h2>
</p>
<p><em>Local-multiplayer is completely supported. We support up to 7 concurrent controllers at any given time, just like original PlayStation 3 hardware on both Windows and Linux. The controllers can be assigned with a wide range of configurations. For example, one player can use a keyboard while another can use a compatible gamepad. To learn more about compatible gamepads, please refer to the&nbsp;Quickstart Guide.</em></p>
</div>
<div>
<p>
<h2><strong><em>Can I import my save data from my real PlayStation 3?</em></strong></h2>
</p>
<p><em>Yes, saves can be imported from a real PlayStation 3 system using the standard USB flash drive transfer method. Due to how the user account system works on a real PlayStation 3 system, in some cases, you may need to re-sign your save. For more information on how to manage your save data within RPCS3, please refer to the&nbsp;Quickstart Guide.</em></p>
</div>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA execs earned $60 million in 2024 despite layoffs and office closures]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-execs-earned-60-million-in-2024-despite-layoffs-and-office-closures</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-execs-earned-60-million-in-2024-despite-layoffs-and-office-closures.903135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-execs-earned-60-million-in-2024-despite-layoffs-and-office-closures<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">U.S. publisher EA has revealed how much its executives netted during FY2024, a 12-month period that saw it </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-reports-annual-net-revenues-of-7-56-billion-amid-layoff-spree">deliver annual net bookings of $7.43 billion</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> but also </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-will-spend-over-125-million-laying-off-5-percent-of-its-workforce">cut 5 percent of its global workforce</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As noted in the company's annual </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://d18rn0p25nwr6d.cloudfront.net/CIK-0000712515/f0be0a59-dd50-4247-b36e-0513336b6c1f.pdf">Proxy Statement</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which details its executive compensation plan, EA's named executive officers collectively earned over $60 million during the last fiscal year. That total includes individual base salaries, stock awards, and incentive plan compensation.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The biggest earner was EA CEO Andrew Wilson, who took home over $25.6 million after helping the company execute on "key strategic and operating objectives" such as restructuring the business around the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-restructure-divides-business-into-ea-entertainment-and-ea-sports">new-look EA Sports and EA Entertainment pillars</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and launching the EA Sports FC brand.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Wilson was also lauded for overseeing "a year of continued employee satisfaction scores above industry benchmarks" and strategically aligning studio leadership to "support franchise development and success."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For those curious how compensation shakes out at the very top of a company like EA, Wilson earned a base salary of $1.3 million and received $20.4 million in stock awards. He then netted another $3.44 million via a non-equity incentive plan. Other payments included almost $500,000 in personal security benefits.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA explained that during the 2024 fiscal year, the annual total compensation of its median employee was $148,704. That means Wilson earned 172 times more than your median EA worker. Wilson also earned significantly more in 2024 than in both 2023 ($20.6M) and 2022 ($19.8M).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The second-highest earning EA exec during the last fiscal year was Laura Miele, president of EA entertainment, technology, and central development. Miele received over $12 million, including a base salary of $820,385, stock awards worth $10.05 million, and non-equity incentive plan compensation of $1.2 million.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">She was credited with overseeing the delivery of new titles including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, leading the central development services and technology organization, and overseeing plans to "deliver AI-driven business and development efficiencies."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We've taken the liberty of posting EA's full executive compensation table below. You can read the full breakdown on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://d18rn0p25nwr6d.cloudfront.net/CIK-0000712515/f0be0a59-dd50-4247-b36e-0513336b6c1f.pdf">EA's investor relation page</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lords of the Fallen sequel set for 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/lords-of-the-fallen-sequel-set-for-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lords-of-the-fallen-sequel-set-for-2026.903132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/lords-of-the-fallen-sequel-set-for-2026<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
Lords of the Fallen publisher CI Games is gearing up to release a sequel in 2026.
</p>
<p>
The announcement comes from a filing from CI Games, shared by Polish site <a href="https://www.bankier.pl/wiadomosc/CI-GAMES-S-E-Podpisanie-Binding-Term-Sheet-z-Epic-Games-Inc-8765997.html">Bankier</a>, which also confirms Epic will have the exclusive worldwide distribution rights to the sequel on PC.
</p>
<p>
Elsewhere, the rights to publish and distribute the game worldwide "on all other platforms, including the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S platforms for which the game is currently in development, will remain with the company".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Lords of the Fallen - Version 1.5 - Master of Fate" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WE8LNahjW8Q?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Lords of the Fallen - Version 1.5 - Master of Fate</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WE8LNahjW8Q?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WE8LNahjW8Q?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Lords of the Fallen - Version 1.5 - Master of Fate<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WE8LNahjW8Q" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>

Little else is known about the game at this point. CI Games is working on a number of projects, with the Lords of the Fallen sequel given the working title 'Project 3'.
</p>
<p>
Lords of the Fallen was a technically ambitious Soulslike that released in a rough state both on PC and consoles last year, developed by Hexworks and published by CI Games. It was developed in Epic's Unreal Engine 5.
</p>
<p>
Since then it's received plenty of updates to improve its quality, as well as various features. Its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lords-of-the-fallen-final-update-introduces-modifiers-for-rogue-lite-challenge">most recent update added modifiers for a roguelite challenge</a>.

</p>
<p>
Perhaps, with Epic publishing the next game on PC, it will release in a more stable state to show off its engine technology.
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lords-of-the-fallen-joins-hellblade-2-on-xbox-game-pass-this-month">Lords of the Fallen joined Xbox Game Pass last month</a>, alongside Hellblade 2. 


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard strips your RPG party down to two companions, but they'll be "deeper" with a lot more banter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-strips-your-rpg-party-down-to-two-companions-but-theyll-be-deeper-with-a-lot-more-banter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-strips-your-rpg-party-down-to-two-companions-but-theyll-be-deeper-with-a-lot-more-banter.903129/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-strips-your-rpg-party-down-to-two-companions-but-theyll-be-deeper-with-a-lot-more-banter<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>"Two's company, three's a crowd," the saying goes, unless the first two are warriors and the third one is a priest, in which case the superior proverb is surely "three's a moderately balanced squad, two's a massive liability"? Here to put such kitchen wisdom to the test is BioWare's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-dreadwolf">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a>, which "only" allows you to bring two companions into the fray, one fewer than 2014's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-inquisition">Dragon Age: Inquisition</a>. It's another indication that this will be <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-45-minutes-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard-feel-as-much-like-mass-effect-2-as-inquisition">more biffy action game than thinky party-based RPG</a>. The upside, assuming you find that last sentence disappointing, is that exploration and combat will be more "intimate", and individual characters will have more screentime to bounce off each other and flourish as personalities. All this comes care of a BioWare Discord Q&amp;A from late last week, which you can watch in full below.</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="DA: The Veilguard: Discord Q&amp;A with Developers!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mAuTF3Cs0dQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>DA: The Veilguard: Discord Q&amp;A with Developers!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mAuTF3Cs0dQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mAuTF3Cs0dQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mAuTF3Cs0dQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>If you don't have time to watch an hour's worth of BioWrangling first thing on a Monday, Keywords Studios staffer and noted scuttlebutter Shinobi602 has done <a href="https://x.com/shinobi602/status/1801703748311408736">a quick Xeet round-up</a>. Some highlights: BioWare are saying that Veilguard will offer their "deepest" companion arcs yet, and that your interactions with them may go as far as angering them so much they go AWOL for a while. They're also capable of falling for each other, not just the player, which I'd welcome former Dragon Age scribe David Gaider's thoughts about in the wake of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-ages-former-lead-writer-has-many-mostly-positive-thoughts-on-veilguards-romance-options-story-and-environments">his thread last week</a> on how difficult it is to endow <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> companion characters with agency, when they're designated as player love interests.</p>
<p>BioWare are also promising/threatening the largest quantity of Dragon Age party banter ever, so much banter that you will never wish to speak to another human being again, that you will shriek and beg for silence. What's more, characters will dynamically break off and resume their bantering should they be interrupted by a rogue Pride Demon or because you've thrown yourself over a cliff to escape the relentless small talk. No more shall you miss out on the whimsical incidentals of character relationships: this banter will follow you everywhere, like a hungry dog or curse.</p>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Dragon Age: Veilguard   New Discord Q&amp;A Details</p><p>🔷Asked about the world🔷</p><p>▪️Takes place 10 years after Dragon Age: Inquisition<br>▪️The Inquisitor will definitely be part of the story<br>▪️You can go back to previous locations you visited, do side content, etc<br>▪️Everything is... <a href="https://t.co/413CWAlL5y">pic.twitter.com/413CWAlL5y</a></p></div>— Shinobi602 (@shinobi602) <a href="https://twitter.com/shinobi602/status/1801703748311408736?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 14, 2024</a></blockquote></div> <p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>There's a lot more in the video so please accept this runner-up handful of Veilguard trivia: mages get healing spells again. There's no campaign progression block akin to Inquisition's power mechanic. Your new base of operations is called the Lighthouse. Tavern songs return. There appear to be fewer fetchquests. You can pet the griffin.</p>
<p>Anyway: thoughts on the new party size, everybody? I compared Veilguard to Mass Effect 2 in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-45-minutes-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard-feel-as-much-like-mass-effect-2-as-inquisition">my first look preview</a> and this certainly chimes with that analysis. Personally I'd like the extra body, but I must admit I always felt that one member of my Inquisition party got left out of the chinwaggery, which made me anxious. So thank you BioWare, I guess, for lowering the odds that I will feel like an Xmas host trying to ensure that nobody ends up in the corner of the room pretending to check their phone.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xenogears HD-2D Unreal Engine 5 Fanmade Remake Looks Incredible in New Video]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xenogears-unreal-engine-5-remake/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xenogears-hd-2d-unreal-engine-5-fanmade-remake-looks-incredible-in-new-video.903126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/xenogears-unreal-engine-5-remake/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Xenogears is among the most popular JRPGs ever released on the original PlayStation, but Square Enix doesn't seem interested in releasing the game to modern platforms, leaving it to fans to remake it using modern technologies.</p>
<p>3D artist <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@vitor3dartist" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vitor Maccari</a> is currently working on an Unreal Engine 5-powered remake of the classic JRPG using the HD-2D style made popular by Octopath Traveler and expanded by last year's Star Ocean: The Second Story R. Using Maya, Zbrush, Houdini, Substance Painter, Megascan Textures, and SpeedTree alongside Unreal Engine 5, the artist was able to make an incredible recreation of the village of Lahan, making us hunger for a proper remake even more.</p>
<p><iframe title="Xenogears Remake Gameplay Reveal" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sBG5zhPtp2E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>While an official remake or remaster won't be coming anytime soon, there are still ways to experience Xenogears with improved visuals, thanks to an <a href="https://wccftech.com/a-xenogears-unofficial-hd-remaster-is-now-available-for-download-overhauls-ui-over-90000-textures-and-more/">unofficial HD remaster</a> that reworks the game's interface, sprites, and over 9000 textures.</p>
<p>Xenogears was originally meant to be part of a bigger series, but the project ultimately was not realized due to its creator, Tetsuya Takahashi, leaving Square Enix, SquareSoft at the time, to form Monolith, who went on to develop the Xenosaga series, which explores similar themes, and Xenoblade Chronicles franchise. The third entry in the Xenoblade Chronicles series was released in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/xenoblade-chronicles-3-aionios-finest/">2022</a>, followed by the Future Redeemed expansion, which launched last year.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MW3 devs are finally nerfing the overpowered Kar98k, but not everyone is happy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/mw3-devs-are-finally-nerfing-the-overpowered-kar98k-but-not-everyone-is-happy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=mw3-devs-are-finally-nerfing-the-overpowered-kar98k-but-not-everyone-is-happy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mw3-devs-are-finally-nerfing-the-overpowered-kar98k-but-not-everyone-is-happy.903120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/mw3-devs-are-finally-nerfing-the-overpowered-kar98k-but-not-everyone-is-happy/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=mw3-devs-are-finally-nerfing-the-overpowered-kar98k-but-not-everyone-is-happy<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="257" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">The Kar98k has been one of <em>Modern Warfare 3</em>‘s most controversial weapons, with its powerful one-shot nature drawing huge criticism from the community. Now, Sledgehammer has confirmed that it’s getting nerf, but not everyone is pleased about it. </p> <p data-characters="303" data-current-count="303" data-injectable="false">Introduced in Season 4, the Kar98k has been the subject of intense scrutiny, with plenty of <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/mw3-players-are-begging-sledgehammer-to-nerf-broken-kar98k/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">players begging Sledgehammer to make it less powerful</a>. Finally, we now know that the Kar98k will be tweaked with the Season 4 Reloaded patch, with the developer posting a comment on Reddit to announce the move. </p> <figure data-current-count="603" data-injectable="true"></figure>
 <p data-characters="210" data-current-count="210" data-injectable="false">Instead of universal delight though, a group of players is voicing their unhappiness at the decision, with many claiming that the other weapons in the game and aim assist are the problem, not the sniper rifle. </p> <p data-characters="297" data-current-count="507" data-injectable="true">“Please just nerf the aim assist and make the last damage range not be a [one hit kill]—It’s still 50 meters, that’s perfectly enough for a marksman rifle,” wrote DeminoTheDragon, while l4derman agreed: “Nerf all controller assistance not individual weapons.”</p>
 <p data-characters="370" data-current-count="370" data-injectable="false">“Why not just buff the other guns?” asked Necessary-Travel-683. “This seems like a really poor decision, people will complain about a particular item that the masses use when they continuously get killed by said item. More people enjoy the Kar98k, the issue is the lack of other viable guns at the moment, we need more buffs not nerfs all round.”</p> <p data-characters="247" data-current-count="617" data-injectable="true">Beneficial-Yam4306 concurred, writing: “The reason the Kar98k is so dominant is that every other gun sucks! Stop getting in the way of other people’s fun time. You guys took forever to give us a good sniper, stop screwing it up!”</p>
 <p data-characters="371" data-current-count="371" data-injectable="false">While these guys make some convincing arguments, I have to admit that I’m heavily in favor of the nerf, as I’m sick of getting no-scoped by guys running the Kar98k on small map moshpit. The weapon is simply too strong when compared to others, and while buffing everything would be nice, it’s more reasonable to tweak one weapon rather than one hundred. </p> <p data-characters="95" data-current-count="466" data-injectable="false">I for one can’t wait for <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/mw3-and-warzone-season-4-reloaded-release-date-new-game-modes-and-weapon-expansions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 4 Reloaded</a> now, which is expected to release on June 26. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring creator Hidetaka Miyazaki still hasn't made his "ideal fantasy RPG"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-creator-hidetaka-miyazaki-still-hasnt-made-his-ideal-fantasy-rpg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-creator-hidetaka-miyazaki-still-hasnt-made-his-ideal-fantasy-rpg.903114/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-creator-hidetaka-miyazaki-still-hasnt-made-his-ideal-fantasy-rpg<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GORM-eDWcAAyA1Q.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/elden-ring">Elden Ring</a> creator Hidetaka Miyazaki is "still in the process" of creating his "ideal fantasy RPG", despite the huge success of the game and the previous Souls games.
</p>
<p>
When interviewed by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/shadow-of-the-erdtree-miyazaki-interview-cover-story-preview/">PC Gamer</a>, Miyazaki discussed the influence of tabletop games on his work. "You might say that trying to capture that excitement of those old tabletop games and game books was one facet of making Elden Ring," he said. 

</p>
<p>
"But I think more than anything it's just my personal preference when it comes to RPGs and exploring fantasy worlds, so you might see some of my personal idiosyncrasies come into play. I'm still in the process of making my ideal fantasy RPG. While Elden Ring is not quite it, it's pretty close. It's getting close."
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree | Official Gameplay Reveal Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8GDtwdMBhhI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>

It's true the Souls games have gradually given players more choice, with the character customisation of Dark Souls developing into the open world approach of Elden Ring. 
</p>
<p>
Does that mean FromSoftware's next game could move further towards player choice, expression, and agency? Whatever it ends up being, we also know <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-will-feature-poison-swamps-because-miyazaki-loves-making-them">Miyazaki's "personal idiosyncrasies" includes poisoned swamps</a>.
</p>
<p>
It's unknown what the studio's next game will be, but Miyazaki did hint in the same interview, in which he admitted "making a game as large and ambitious as Elden Ring was obviously not without its troubles".
</p>
<p>
He continued: "Every time there's things that go well and things that don't go so well. Taking those bits that didn't go so well this time with Elden Ring and incorporating those and improving those in a future title - that's something I'm really excited for."
</p>
<p>
We know for sure that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/shadow-of-the-erdtree-brings-further-depth-and-grandeur-to-fromsoftwares-masterpiece">Elden Ring DLC</a> Shadow of the Erdtree will <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-is-fromsoftwares-largest-expansion-ever">blur the line between open field design and legacy dungeon</a>, as the team explored the open world design further.
</p>
<p>
Shadow of the Erdtree will release this week on 21st June. Are you prepared to die yet? Time is running out, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/time-is-running-out-to-prepare-for-elden-ring-dlc-shadow-of-the-erdtree">here's what you need to get up to speed</a>.

</p>
<p>
A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-base-game-is-getting-new-hairdos-and-other-improvements-ahead-of-its-dlc">free update will also be added for all players</a>, including a number of new features.


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[While you're waiting for Shadow Of The Erdtree, Elden Ring has some free hair for you]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/while-youre-waiting-for-shadow-of-the-erdtree-elden-ring-has-some-free-hair-for-you</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/while-youre-waiting-for-shadow-of-the-erdtree-elden-ring-has-some-free-hair-for-you.903111/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/while-youre-waiting-for-shadow-of-the-erdtree-elden-ring-has-some-free-hair-for-you<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>The free update also brings summoning pool and inventory tweaks on the 20th</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-free-hair.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>This once verdant ground is now wrecked by the passage of time. My terrible nemesis looms before me, inevitable and devastating. Many have fallen to it, but I will overcome. Oh, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a>? I was talking about male pattern baldness. It will eventually destroy all that was once beautiful about my hairline, but at least I’ll have five fancy new hairdos to pick from when the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a>’s newest free update releases this Thursday, 20th of June. There’s also some QOL tweaks to inventory management and summoning pools, but I can’t wear those, can I?</p>

<p>As decreed by the <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1801616168299499599">official Elden Ring</a> twonker account, the voluminous goblet of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-how-to-start">Shadow Of The Erdtree</a> is getting a pre-release appetiser in the form of a free update patch for the base game. This will no doubt plump the code-pillows for the majestic expansion to plonk itself down comfortably on, but it’s also bringing some more substantial changes. There’s those aforementioned hairdos - five of them, in fact. There’s also some inventory tweaks. Newly obtained items will display an exclamation mark, and a new ‘recent items’ tab is getting added, presumably to soothe potential inventory bloat after the expansion pieces out its new lore revelations on to several dozen pairs of trousers, each less illuminating than the last.</p>
<p>Good news for people with mates, too. Summoning pools - to my understanding, the groups of summonable allies in each region - can now be enabled or disabled individually through a new Map Functions menu. Active summoning pools will now be carried over to new game plus, too.</p>
<p>As you may have surmised, it’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elden-ring">Elden Ring</a> frenzy at the treehouse this week. You can barely move without someone whispering cryptic prognostications at you. Just this morning, I asked Ollie how to get the new coffee maker working, and he told me to seek the ‘three unclosing eyes of the eyeless one’. Took me twenty minutes to work out he was talking about the plug socket, by which time he’d disappeared in a fit of manic laughter. A slippery one for sure, although you could do worse than booking up on his complete guide to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-lore-story-explained">Elden Ring’s lore and story</a>. He writes as smooth as Vaati narrates, say I.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Fallout Games Won’t Be Rushed, Says Howard; Bethesda Game Studios Had 25 Million Players Last Month]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-fallout-games-wont-be-rushed-says-howard-bethesda-game-studios-had-25-million-players-last-month/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-fallout-games-won%E2%80%99t-be-rushed-says-howard-bethesda-game-studios-had-25-million-players-last-month.903108/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-fallout-games-wont-be-rushed-says-howard-bethesda-game-studios-had-25-million-players-last-month/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following the massive success of the Fallout TV show and subsequent resurgence in sales of previous installments, <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-5-might-be-here-sooner-than-we-thought-at-microsofts-behest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rumors</a> that Microsoft was interested in fast-tracking the next mainline single player game. Even Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer subtly <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-5-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hinted</a> at that possibility in a recent interview.</p>
<p>However, in a lengthy video chat with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2ew8LQFGNWU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MrMattyPlays</a>, Bethesda's Todd Howard clarified there's no interest from the studio in rushing out a new Fallout game.</p>
<p><em>I agree with the statement that Fallout has never been more popular, looking at the number of players coming into those games and obviously the popularity of the TV show. We give a lot of thought to franchise management. I spend a lot of time thinking about franchises I love and what I've seen out there in terms of content. For us, it's sort of game planning out, number one, making sure Fallout is relevant in the world. I think, well, clearly it is, and people are hungry for even more.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>We've never stopped doing Fallout work. A lot of that work goes on obviously in Fallout 76. We have just had the Skyland Valley update, so we're really, really excited with where that game is at. We feel really fortunate and the team, I'm so proud of the work that's been done there.</em></p>
<p><em>For other Fallout games in the future, you know, obviously I can't talk about those right now, but I would say rushing through them, or we need to get stuff out that is different than the work we're doing in 76... We don't feel like we need to rush any of that. Right now, the Fallout TV show fills a certain niche in terms of the franchise and storytelling. I totally get the desire for a new mainline single player. Look, these things take time. I don't think it's bad for people to miss things. We just want to get it right and make sure that everything we're doing in a franchise, whether it's Elder Scrolls or Fallout or now Starfield, that those become meaningful moments for everybody who loves these franchises as much as we do.</em></p>
<p>Todd Howard also shared that Bethesda Game Studios titles registered 25 million players last month, a new record for the developer.</p>
<p><em>Our games have never been more popular. Last month we had 25 million players in our games. It's just a staggering amount of people and players that we hear from where our number one job always is: how are we serving that audience on a month-to-month basis so we're taking care of them while also developing new products.</em></p>
<p>He also talked about the future of Starfield, chiefly its first annual expansion; you can read more about that <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-crossed-14-million-players-will-get-annual-story-expansions-shattered-space-set-on-single-planet-is-far-harbor-sized/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>