<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 13:22:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Limited Run Games Showcase Brings Back Retro Delights Galore]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/limited-run-games-showcase-gex-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/limited-run-games-showcase-brings-back-retro-delights-galore.907677/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/limited-run-games-showcase-gex-more<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Limited Run Games has announced a slew of retro re-releases as part of its LRG3 summer showcase, including cult classic platformers, PS1-era action games, and more.</p>
<p>Over the course of the roughly 37-minute showcase, Limited Run revealed its intention to revive games from franchises like&nbsp;<em>Gex</em>,&nbsp;<em>Tomba!</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Fighting Force</em>, and we also got a new look at upcoming titles like&nbsp;<em>Rugrats: Adventures in Gameland&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Clock Tower: Rewind</em>.</p>
<p>The show also saw Ubisoft finally unveiling&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil: 20th Anniversary Edition</em>, which was probably one of the company's worst-kept secrets prior to the reveal. It's landing on June 25th across PC and consoles. Sadly no news on the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/beyond-good-and-evil-2-lead-michel-ancel-leaves-video-games">still-AWOL&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil 2</em></a>, though.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/limited-run-games-showcase-beyond-good-and-evil.jpg?itok=jcIFW9Cs 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/limited-run-games-showcase-beyond-good-and-evil.jpg?itok=UmacOdNA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Shock horror!&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil: 20th Anniversary Edition&nbsp;</em>is arriving next week.</figcaption></figure><p>Also revealed during the showcase were new Carbon Engine releases for cult PS1 platformers&nbsp;<em>Tomba&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Tomba 2</em>. The former is coming to PC, PlayStation, and Switch on August 1st, while the second doesn't have a release date yet.</p>
<p>Those two games were far from the only fifth-generation strings to Limited Run's bow, however.&nbsp;<em>Fighting Force Collection&nbsp;</em>will include Core Design's two&nbsp;<em>Fighting Force&nbsp;</em>games and is coming to PC, PlayStation, and Switch in 2025, as is a Carbon Engine version of&nbsp;<em>Fear Effect</em>.</p>
<p>Of course, we also finally got confirmation that a long-missed hero of gaming is making a triumphant return. That's right:&nbsp;<em>Gex Trilogy&nbsp;</em>is coming to PC and consoles, and it includes the first (and only) three&nbsp;<em>Gex&nbsp;</em>games.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/limited-run-games-showcase-gex.jpg?itok=gCQ3T_ta 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/limited-run-games-showcase-gex.jpg?itok=HxyILOMt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Finally, the hero returns.</figcaption></figure><p>The showcase concluded with the announcement of&nbsp;<em>Bubsy In: The Purrfect Collection</em>, which includes several remastered&nbsp;<em>Bubsy&nbsp;</em>games (including the much-maligned&nbsp;<em>Bubsy 3D</em>) as well as interviews and artifacts from the troubled mascot's history.</p>
<p>It's well worth checking out the full Limited Run Games showcase to see everything else the company announced. Though Limited Run has <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/limited-run-games-3do-releases-controversy">not been without</a> its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/limited-run-games-fires-community-manager-over-transphobic-tweets">fair share of controversy</a> over the years, these efforts to preserve gaming ephemera should be celebrated.</p>
<p>Here's the full showcase in case you missed it and want to catch up.</p>

</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox's Matt Booty suggests leadership change was a factor in Tango Gameworks closure]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/xboxs-matt-booty-suggests-leadership-change-was-a-factor-in-tango-gameworks-closure</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xboxs-matt-booty-suggests-leadership-change-was-a-factor-in-tango-gameworks-closure.907671/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/xboxs-matt-booty-suggests-leadership-change-was-a-factor-in-tango-gameworks-closure<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Exec confirms Hi-Fi Rush "did well for us" but factors behind previous success "may not all still be in place"</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Xbox executive Matt Booty has offered more insight into the platform holder's decision to close Tango Gameworks, suggesting the studio's recent change of leadership was a key factor.</p>
<p>Speaking on <a href="https://variety.com/2024/gaming/news/xbox-studios-matt-booty-podast-game-pass-fallout-studio-closures-1236038120/">Variety's Strictly Business podcast</a>, spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/matt-booty-implies-tango-gameworks-closure-was-partly-due-to-leadership-change">Eurogamer</a>, the head of Xbox Game Studios was asked whether Microsoft sought another buyer before closing the Japan-based developer.</p>
<p>Booty declined to share the "nitty gritty details" out of respect for the people affected by the studio's closure, but did note that "a lot of work went into delivering Hi-Fi Rush," which he described as a "great game" that "did well for us."</p>
<p>"I think the thing to be considered is that for us, it's as much a forward-looking situation as much as it is looking back at one certain game... There are a lot of things that go into success for a game," he said.</p>
<p>"What leadership do you have? What creative leadership do you have? Is the team the same team that shipped something successful previously?</p>
<p>"And we have to look at all of those things together and then ask ourselves, are we set up for success going forward? And while there may have been factors and situations that previously led to success, they may not all still be in place as you look at what you're doing going forward."</p>
<p>His comments seem to refer to the leadership changes at Tango Gameworks over the past year, following the <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/tango-gameworks-founder-shinji-mikami-to-leave-the-studio">departure of studio founder Shinji Mikami</a> in 2023.</p>
<p>Tango Gameworks was one of <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/xbox-reportedly-shutting-down-four-bethesda-studios">four ZeniMax-owned studios that Microsoft closed in May</a>, alongside Redfall developer Arkane Austin, Mighty Doom maker Alpha Dog Studios, and Roundhouse Games.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/phil-spencer-on-studio-closures-i-have-to-run-a-sustainable-business">Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer was also questioned</a> about the reasons for these closures on stage at IGN Live last month, who said that "hard decisions" needed to be made "to run a sustainable business."</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The VGBees Podcast – Episode 4: Nintendo Direct Recap with Merritt K]]></title>
            <link>https://vgbees.com/the-vgbees-podcast-episode-4-nintendo-direct-recap-with-merritt-k/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-vgbees-podcast-episode-4-nintendo-direct-recap-with-merritt-k</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-vgbees-podcast-%E2%80%93-episode-4-nintendo-direct-recap-with-merritt-k.907653/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://vgbees.com/the-vgbees-podcast-episode-4-nintendo-direct-recap-with-merritt-k/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-vgbees-podcast-episode-4-nintendo-direct-recap-with-merritt-k<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p>John and Niki take a deep dive into a very strong Nintendo Direct, featuring discussion of:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</em></li>
<li><em>Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</em></li>
<li><em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</em></li>
<li><em>Marvel vs. Capcom Fighting Collection: Arcade Classics</em></li>
<li><em>The New Denpa Men</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Later, they’re joined by writer, author, and budding miniature painting YouTuber Merritt K to chat everything <em>Warhammer 40,000, </em>including:</p>
<ul>
<li>What’s in the heads of the guys from <em>Space Marine 2</em>?</li>
<li>Do Space Marines have balls?</li>
<li>Why did the Squats go away?</li>
<li>and much more!</li>
</ul>
<p>Don’t forget to <a href="https://vgbees.com/join" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Join the Hive</a>!</p>
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Megaton Musashi W: Wired Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/21/megaton-musashi-w-wired-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/megaton-musashi-w-wired-review.907650/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/21/megaton-musashi-w-wired-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/21/megaton-musashi-w-wired-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Megaton Musashi W: Wired Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Miguel Moran">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-06-21">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-06-21">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Mecha games have an easy path into my favourite games list, whatever form they might take. Whether it’s an emotional, non-linear narrative like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/09/15/13-sentinels-aegis-rim-review-ps4/">13 Sentinels: Aegis Rim</a>, or a Gundam game packed with smooth combat and an overwhelming amount of customisation like Gundam Breaker 3, or an addictive high-octane competitive combat like Mobile Suit Gundam Extreme VS. Maxiboost On, I’m totally in.&nbsp;So when I heard that Level 5 had released a game that combines all of those qualities called Megaton Musashi W: Wired, I was foaming at the mouth to check it out.</p>
<p><iframe title="MEGATON MUSASHI W: WIRED – OP “MUSASHI English Ver.”" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CXVebBlsb2E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Now, this isn’t technically the grand debut of Megaton Musashi W: Wired. The series kicked off a few years ago with what was originally a Japan-exclusive premium game, which was followed by an alternative free-to-play version that saw seasonal content updates, famous anime robot DLC add-ons, and collabs with Yokai Watch and Hololive vtubers. Alongside those games, a two-season anime version of Megaton Musashi aired globally. Yet despite the anime being available in English, it isn’t until now and this third iteration of the game that overseas fans can experience the mecha action for themselves.</p>


<p>Knowing that this was, at one time, a free-to-play game, I expected there to be a light focus on story and a heavy emphasis on repeatable, grindathon missions. Instead, I was pleasantly surprised to see that Megaton Musashi W: Wired mirrors the slow, peaceful pacing and character-focused interactions of 13 Sentinels: Aegis Rim. Before you set off on combat missions to defend the last bastion of humanity from giant aliens using your rogue Musashi mech, you’ll spend a lot of time wandering around the city, checking in on rivals, companions, mysterious figures and innocent neighbourhood denizens. Just as much of the game is about talking to people and investigating the overarching mysteries of your place in a constantly growing sci-fi conspiracy. As you do so, you’ll fill up a robot-shaped meter at the bottom of the screen, and once it’s full, it’s time for you to head out to a major story-related battle or boss fight.</p>


<p>Admittedly, I was frustrated at first by how infrequently these combat encounters happened because of how the first few hours of the game focus so much on story and info-dumping. That frustration only stemmed from the fact that combat is so much fun. Combos are smooth and impactful, your Musashi mech flies across the combat arena gracefully, and after just one battle you can immediately get a sense for the full potential of how deep this game’s combat can go. Eventually, thankfully, you’re permitted to explore those depths and combat is a more frequent occurrence as you get further into the game, especially as you unlock bonus missions and multiplayer encounters that can be infinitely repeated.</p>
<p>Plus, as you get further into Megaton Musashi W: Wired, the massive breadth of customisation options fully exposes itself to you. There’s fun flashy stuff, like the dozens of unique equippable arms, legs, chest, and head pieces for your mecha. You’ve also got multiple base melee and ranged weapon types, and within each type there are a bunch of unique variations.</p>

<p>It’s easy to fall into a favored build and strategy for your robot, whether it’s running battles close and fast with a shotgun and knuckles or keeping things focused on aerial maneuvers and long-distance gun-fire. Equippable modifiers and a daunting motherboard customization menu let you steer your build even further into perfection. If the depth of customisation puts you off or overwhelms you, you can automatically optimise your mech based on specified parameters so that you can have the best version of your bot without having to learn what every stat and piece of gear means.</p>
<p>By the time the full scope of Megaton Musashi W: Wired revealed itself to me, I was hooked. I fell into that hole of mecha action and sci-fi intrigue happily, and came out of it feeling like I had experienced the ultimate mashup of all my favorite mecha games. It’s slow to start, but once things get in gear, you’ll be hard pressed to put this game down at all.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Megaton Musashi W: Wired is every giant robot enthusiasts dream game. Whether you want a character-focused sci-fi adventure, a combat bonanza full of fully customizable mechas, or addictive multiplayer engagements, this game can happily provide.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Fun, fast combat</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Delightful focus on characters and sci-fi intrigue</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Daunting and addictive amounts of customization</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Slow and tutorial-heavy opening hours</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy passes huge sales milestone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-passes-huge-sales-milestone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-passes-huge-sales-milestone.907647/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-passes-huge-sales-milestone<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Crash Bandicoot's N. Sane Trilogy - which comprises the remasters of the first Crash Bandicoot, as well as Crash Bandicoot 2: Cortex Strikes Back and Crash Bandicoot: Warped - has certainly not crashed and burned.</p>
<p>Last night, the Crash Bandicoot team revealed that the trilogy has now sold through 20m copies worldwide. "Whoa! Thank you to our community of Crash players for this memorable milestone," the team wrote on social media platform X. </p>
<p>To celebrate, a number of Crash Bandicoot games are now on sale on PlayStation, with deals running until 3rd July. For example, you can currently scoop up the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/EP0002-CUSA23470_00-CRASH2021BDL0002">Crash Bandicoot - Crashiversary Bundle</a> for £43.99. It usually retails at £110.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: For Xbox, could this year finally be the one where it all pays off?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mPVhT_7O0iE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The N. Sane collection of remastered Crash Bandicoot games initially launched back in 2017 on PlayStation 4. It went on to do incredibly well for itself on release. In fact, on its debut in July of 2017, it became the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-biggest-single-platform-launch-of-the-year">biggest single-platform release of the year</a> - beating even Horizon: Zero Dawn.</p>
<p>After a stint as a PS4 exclusive, it arrived on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2018-crash-bandicoot-nsane-trilogy-face-off">Xbox One, PC and Switch the following year</a>.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Our Donlan went <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-is-nostalgia-done-right-and-that-includes-the-irritations">hands- on with the Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy</a> on its release in 2017, and said it was "nostalgia done right - and that includes the irritations".</p>
<p>"I don't think these will ever be first-tier platformers - compared to what other developers were doing back at the same time, even the best Crash level feels a little shapeless and lacking in imagination - but they're clearly great memories," he wrote. "And the N. Sane Trilogy delivers the memories intact."</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk Life Simulation Game Nivalis Has Been Delayed to Spring 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-life-simulation-game-nivalis-has-been-delayed-to-spring-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-life-simulation-game-nivalis-has-been-delayed-to-spring-2025.907644/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-life-simulation-game-nivalis-has-been-delayed-to-spring-2025/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>German developer ION LANDS and publisher 505 Games announced a delay for Nivalis, a cyberpunk life simulation game set in the same world as 2020's <a href="https://wccftech.com/video-games-coming-out-april-2020/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cloudpunk</a>.</p>
<p>Nivalis was first announced in 2022. The following year, we learned of a 2024 release window. However, ION LANDS has now set the launch for Spring 2025, citing the desire to provide the best possible experience.</p>
<p>Here's what you can expect in this peculiar game:</p>
<p><em>Making it in this cyberpunk city isn’t easy. The gangs want to harvest your organs, the Corps will fine you for breathing, and the whole time, the ground under your feet is crumbling. This city could fall into the ocean tomorrow, so you better make your fortune today. You’ve got to start small: a food stall, a noodle stand, a stim store. Build your way up to a bar, a restaurant, or even a nightclub. </em></p>
<p><em>In Nivalis, you choose how to spend your time in the city. In this unique slice-of-life sim with realistic weather simulation and night and day cycles, you can grow your business, meet strange and diverse characters, form friendships, and experience the danger and wonder of this cyberpunk voxel city.</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Experience&nbsp;your&nbsp;simulated life in Nivalis, and choose how you spend your time each day.</em></li>
<li><em>Manage businesses like restaurants, ramen stands or night clubs.</em></li>
<li><em>Buy or grow your own ingredients.</em></li>
<li><em>Explore the city with your own boat and go fishing.</em></li>
<li><em>Decorate your home or buy and customise a new one.</em></li>
<li><em>Discover the stories of the people you meet in the city, your friends, your customers, and maybe even find love.</em></li>
</ul>
<p><iframe title="Nivalis | Official Summer 2024 Trailer [PEGI]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VYykZ9RBo3w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Nivalis will be released for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1488490/Nivalis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/nivalis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>. There's no mention of a console release in the press release. However, Cloudpunk eventually launched on PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch. It's likely the same will happen in this case, too.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree Doesn't Have Trophies or Achievements]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-doesnt-have-trophies-or-achievements</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-doesnt-have-trophies-or-achievements.907638/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-doesnt-have-trophies-or-achievements<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>If you're concerned that a little "ting" of euphoria didn't sound when you beat that really hard boss in <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring">Elden Ring</a> expansion <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree">Shadow of the Erdtree</a>, it's actually intentional. FromSoftware's highly anticipated expansion doesn't have PlayStation Trophies or Steam or Xbox Achievements.</p><p>The downloadable content, which adds a wealth of new content to beloved role-playing game Elden Ring, is available today, June 21, 2024, and some fans are surprised to see that, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-long-is-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree">despite its roughly 25 hours of additional exploration and bosses</a>, Shadow of the Erdtree doesn't feature a new set of Trophies or Achievements.</p><p>Releasing an additional set of digital rewards is the norm for big DLC expansions. The DLC for Fallout 4, Horizon: Forbidden West, God of War: Ragnarok, Halo: Infinite, The Elder Scrolls 5: Skyrim, and many more all had additional Trophies or Achievements, for example.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree DLC Review Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Even <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2015/11/23/bloodborne-the-old-hunters-review">The Old Hunters DLC for FromSoftware's Bloodborne</a> had additional Trophies, providing an additional reward for players who beat its myriad bosses and acquiring the fancy (horrifying) new weapons. The inclusion of Trophies here may have been related to its PlayStation exclusivity, however, as FromSoftware hasn't included them in its other DLCs for the likes of Dark Souls and Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice.</p><p>The same is true for Shadow of the Erdtree, meaning those who enjoy Trophy and Achievement-hunting will need to find their own fun in the expansion. That shouldn't be too hard, of course, as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-review">IGN awarded it a 10/10 in our review</a>.</p><p>"Like the base game did before it, Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree raises the bar for single player expansions," we said. "It takes everything that made the base game such a landmark RPG, condenses it into a relatively compact 20-25 hour campaign, and provides fantastic new challenges for heavily invested fans to chew on."</p><p>Those still eager to explore every inch of the expansion can check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring/Shadow_of_the_Erdtree_DLC">IGN's extensive guide</a>, which covers <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring/Shadow_of_the_Erdtree_New_Weapon_Types">Shadow of the Erdtree's new weapons</a>, its various quest lines, and how to defeat those pesky new bosses.</p><p>Those who've not yet jumped into the DLC can <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring/How_to_Prepare_for_the_Shadow_of_the_Erdtree_DLC">make sure they've ticked off all the requirements to access it too</a>, as it involves more than just forking over money to FromSoftware. Make sure to check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/maps/elden-ring/lands-between">our Elden Ring interactive map</a> to ensure you're not missing any <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring/Scarab_Locations_and_Rewards">important collectibles</a> too.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Nintendo Switch Cases to Buy in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-case</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-nintendo-switch-cases-to-buy-in-2024.907635/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-case<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The best Nintendo Switch cases protect your handheld console from accidental drops and breakages. Not to mention, some cases offer ample room for the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-accessories#switch"><u>best Switch accessories</u></a> and games, so you can take them with you on-the-go. </p><h2>TL;DR – These are the Best Nintendo Switch Cases:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/gdgdn" target="_blank">Orzly Carry Case</a><strong> </strong>- Best Switch Case<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/MY614" target="_blank">Game Traveler Zelda Nintendo Switch Lite Case</a><strong> </strong>- Best Nintendo Switch Lite Case</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/gL3oy" target="_blank">Amazon Basics Carrying Case</a><strong> </strong>- Best Budget Case<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/LXjAM" target="_blank">tomtoc Carrying Case</a><strong> </strong>- Best Compact Case<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/1PBYn" target="_blank">Zadii Hard Carrying Case</a><strong> </strong>- Best Rugged Case<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/3Zb62" target="_blank">Timbuk2 x Astro CS03 Crossbody Sling</a><strong> </strong>- Best Nintendo Switch Sling Bag<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/8vqPv" target="_blank">tomtoc Sling Shoulder Travel Bag</a><strong> </strong>- Best Shoulder Bag<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/LGoBo" target="_blank">Mumba Dockable Case</a><strong> </strong>- Best Always-On Protective Case<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/leRjd" target="_blank">NEWDERY External Battery Station</a> - Best Charger Case<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/njq3l" target="_blank">Bionik Power Commuter Travel Bag</a><strong> </strong>- Best Play-While-Charging Case<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/EvV1X" target="_blank">Controller Gear Animal Crossing Backpack</a><strong> </strong>- Best Nintendo Switch Backpack<strong>
</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/1KZj3" target="_blank">Waterfield Designs Slip Case</a><strong> </strong>- Best Nintendo Switch Sleeve Case<strong>
</strong></li></ul><p>Whether you’re looking for a Switch case that charges your console, provides protection, or even acts as a grip, there’s something for everyone in our favorite Switch cases roundup. We don’t know if these cases are going to support the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/switch-2-predicted-to-arrive-in-2024-at-less-than-400"><u>Switch 2 which is rumored to arrive later this year</u></a>, but we know they are plenty suitable for the Switch, Switch Lite, and Switch OLED. </p><h2 id="cases"><u><strong>The Best Switch Cases</strong></u></h2><h2>1. Orzly Carry Case</h2><h3>Best Switch Case</h3><div id="162275"><p><h3>Orzly Carry Case</h3></p><div><p>A hard outer shell and soft fabric interior with a microfiber tongue protect the Switch from damage, while pockets can store additional accessories.  </p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>10.71 x 5.39 x 2.52 inches</p></div><div><p>Storage for games and accessories</p></div><p>The Orzly Carry Case is our number one choice for the best Nintendo Switch case, regardless of which version of the Switch you have. Its hard outer shell provides plenty of protection, ensuring your console, Joy-Cons, games, and accessories avoid accidental damage. Inside, the microfiber screen cover and microfiber lining offers soft cushioning, preventing scratches to the Switch’s screen.</p><p>Thanks to the EVA outer shell being water-resistant, you can feel safe in the knowledge that no spillages will leak into the case. If you don’t want to store your Switch in a bag, then the Orzly Carry Case is incredibly easy to carry thanks to its rubberized handle. There’s also storage for up to 8 games, so you won’t be with out your favorite titles on vacation.</p><p>The inner mesh pocket allows you to store a range of accessories, including cables, SD cards, and so on. If you’re looking for a secure case to store your Nintendo Switch in, this is an absolute steal at under $20. Plus, it comes in 9 different colors like midnight blue, red, and pink.</p><h2>2. Game Traveler Zelda Nintendo Switch Lite Case</h2><h3>Best Nintendo Switch Lite Case</h3><div id="185407"><p><h3>Game Traveler Zelda Nintendo Switch Lite Case</h3></p><div><p>Designed for the Switch Lite, this compact case offers a hard protective shell, soft interior, adjustable stand, and plastic holder for four games. </p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>9.45 x 1.77 x 5.51 inches</p></div><div><div><p>Hard outer shell with a soft interior lining</p></div><div><p>No extra space for accessories</p></div></div><p>With smaller dimensions than the original, you’ll want to grab separate <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-lite-accessories"><u>accessories designed for the Switch Lite</u></a>, especially a case, to ensure it’s secure. The Game Traveler Zelda Nintendo Switch Lite Case will keep the compact console safe thanks to a hard outer shell made with ballistic nylon, a soft interior lining, and a durable handle. It doesn’t stop there, as cutouts and a large tongue to protect the screen hold the Nintendo Switch Lite tightly in place, preventing any major movement, which could lead to damage while on the go. </p><p>You won’t find much extra space for accessories, but you get a plastic game holder ready to hold up to four games that will remain secure in a recessed area underneath where you place the console. There’s also an adjustable viewing stand, which can come in handy. That’s it for extras, though the case does have subtle nods to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-review"><u>Zelda</u></a> with the logo on the front and zipper.</p><h2>3. AmazonBasics Carrying Case</h2><h3>Best Budget Case</h3><div id="141901"><p><h3>Amazon Basics Carrying Case</h3></p><div><p>Save with this compact case offering a mesh pocket for extra storage and a sleeve for ten game cartridges. </p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>10 x 2 x 5 inches</p></div><div><p>Mesh pocket for accessories</p></div><p>You don’t have to spend tons of money on a carrying case, as the Amazon Basics Carrying Case gets the job done for around $15, giving you more money for <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-game-deals">game deals</a>. It is more than up to the task of keeping your precious Switch safe with a design that won’t dramatically reduce your console’s portability. This option keeps compact dimensions and zips up, wrapping your device in sturdy protection that will keep it safe from short drops, debris in your backpack, and even a bit of water—just don’t dunk it. </p><p>The Amazon Basics Carrying Case does more than just protect your Switch; it’ll also hold some additional accessories. There’s a mesh pocket inside to house some extra cables, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-wireless-earbuds"><u>earbuds</u></a>, Joy-Cons, or even a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-portable-power-banks"><u>portable charger</u></a>. Plus, a cartridge sleeve can hold up to 10 games, letting you bring a large gaming library on the go. Cleverly, that cartridge sleeve doubles as a stand to prop up your Nintendo Switch when playing in a tabletop setup.</p><h2>4. tomtoc Carrying Case</h2><h3>Best Compact Case</h3><div id="141902"><p><h3>tomtoc Carrying Case</h3></p><div><p>Don’t sacrifice portability with this case that keeps your device and ten game cartridges safe in a hard EVA shell and cushioned interior while keeping small dimensions.</p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>12.2 x 7.1 x 1.7 inches</p></div><div><div><p>Hard EVA shell with a water-resistant finish</p></div><div><p>10-slot organizer for game cartridges</p></div></div><p>To keep your Nintendo Switch or Switch OLED protected while on the go without sacrificing portability, grab the tomtoc case. Rather than a large carrying case that’ll fit your console and all its accessories, this one wraps up just the Switch and maintains a snug fit. There’s almost no extra bulk, and it weighs less than half a pound, making it perfect for tossing in your bag, backpack, or even a larger pocket. </p><p>You might be concerned that your Switch’s joystick and buttons will have unnecessary pressure placed on them or be accidentally activated. Luckily, tomtoc includes raised sections to accommodate those controls. The case totes a soft exterior layer and interior that helps cushion the blow if dropped, while it’s built around a hard EVA shell and has a water-resistant finish to keep your Switch safe inside. tomtoc tops it off with one extra bit of kit: a 10-slot organizer for game cartridges.</p><h2>5. Zadii Hard Carrying Case</h2><h3>Best Rugged Case</h3><div id="141903"><p><h3>Zadii Hard Carrying Case</h3></p><div><p>A precut foam slot for Switch, and additional slots for accessories, including a Pro Controller, come with this bulky but durable case. </p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>11 x 9.5 x 15.1 inches</p></div><div><div><p>Ample padding with a precut foam slot for the Switch</p></div><div><p>Storage for controllers, Joy-Cons, dock, and more</p></div></div><p>If you plan to take your Switch with you when your travels get a little rough and tumble, you'll want the Zadii Hard Carrying Case. This rugged case is surprisingly affordable and offers plenty of protection. There’s ample padding and even a precut foam slot to snuggly tuck your console alongside your Switch controllers away, ensuring the console and accessories safe from any potential damage when on the go. </p><p> The Zadii Hard Carrying Case holds a lot more, as it has room for pretty much everything that comes in the box with your Nintendo Switch and then some. Beyond the space for your Switch, there are additional foam slots to hold a second set of Joy-Cons with the Joy-Con grip, Joy-Con straps, a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/03/13/nintendo-switch-pro-controller-review"><u>Pro Controller</u></a>, a Nintendo Switch Dock, and a power adapter. The lid of this carrying case also provides a pocket for an HDMI cable and a set of sleeves to hold 21 game cartridges, while a detachable shoulder strap makes carrying the whole thing easier.</p><h2>6. Timbuk2 x Astro CS03 Crossbody Sling </h2><h3>Best Nintendo Switch Sling Bag</h3><div id="145142"><p><h3>Timbuk2 x Astro CS03 Crossbody Sling </h3></p><div><p>This crossbody bag has a three-liter capacity and plenty of pockets to keep your Switch and its accessories organized.</p></div></div><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/ee3pX" target="_blank"><strong>See it on Astro Gaming</strong></a></li><li><strong></strong><a href="https://zdcs.link/1rJb8" target="_blank"><strong>See it on Timbuk2</strong></a></li></ul><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>11.61 x 7.09 x 3.14 inches</p></div><div><p>Front pocket with a magnetic closure</p></div><p>Timbuk2 knows bags, and Astro knows gaming, so the two companies joined forces to create the Timbuk2 x Astro CS03 Crossbody Sling for the Nintendo Switch. This sleek bag goes on quickly, takes up little space, doesn’t add much bulk, and provides easy access but solid protection for your gear while on the move.</p><p>The CS03 bag has a three-liter capacity giving you room for your Nintendo Switch, a smartphone, a number of accessories and cables, and even 14 game cartridges or SD cards in individual slots. To keep things organized, there’s a front pocket with a magnetic closure for easy access to some of the gear, while the main compartments are protected and secured with weather-resistant zippers. And to further ensure the bag holds up against wear, it uses a combination of 600D polyester and 4mm-thick ripstop nylon. </p><h2>7. tomtoc Sling Shoulder Travel Bag</h2><h3>Best Shoulder Bag</h3><div id="194733"><p><h3>tomtoc Sling Shoulder Travel Bag</h3></p><div><p>A bag with an adjustable shoulder strap, W-shaped padding structure, and extra storage to take the Switch and its accessories on the go and keep them safe. </p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>11.02 x 6.69 x 4.13 inches</p></div><div><div><p>Adjustable shoulder strap</p></div><div><p>W-shape padding holds the Switch in place</p></div></div><p>If you want the simplicity of a bag you can sling over your shoulder, then tomtoc Sling Shoulder Travel Bag should do the trick. This bag comes with an adjustable shoulder strap to fit the bag exactly to your liking. It’s also built to withstand the outside world with a splash-resistant polyester material and high-quality zippers. </p><p>Inside the tomtoc Sling Shoulder Travel Bag, you’ll find a soft lining to prevent scratches alongside a removable W-shaped padding structure and a 20-game cartridge holder. The W-shaped design hugs your Switch in place, preventing accidental joystick presses and separating the console from other accessories in the bag. You can even slip a portable charger in and run a charging cable between compartments to charge on the go. An additional pocket at the front of the bag is perfect for smaller items you might need, like earbuds or charging cables.</p><h2>8. Mumba Dockable Case</h2><h3>Best Always-On Protective Case</h3><div id="141906"><p><h3>Mumba Dockable Case</h3></p><div><p>Keep this a shock-absorbing, rubberized case on the Switch 24/7 thanks to cutouts for all the ports. </p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>16.1 x 8.7 x 2.5 inches</p></div><div><div><p>Shock-absorbing, rubberized design</p></div><div><p>Difficult to dock Switch with case on </p></div></div><p>Mumba’s Dockable Case offers full-time protection for your Switch and its controllers, and there’s little to no reason to ever take it off. If you want to use your Joy-Cons separately from the console, you can slip them out effortlessly, as the case doesn’t interfere with any of the controls. Specially placed cutouts ensure you have access to all the essential ports, and it’s even possible to leave it on when docking your Switch, hence the name. </p><p>If you’ve got butterfingers, Mumba’s 24/7 protection is what you need. This case wraps your Switch in a shock-absorbing, rubberized material that’s easy to grip and will keep your console safe from bumps, scratches, and drops. And it’s available in multiple colors, so you can choose one that best fits your aesthetic. </p><h2>9. NEWDERY External Battery Station</h2><h3>Best Charger Case</h3><div id="181248"><p><h3>NEWDERY External Battery Station</h3></p><div><p>This case has an integrated 10,000mAh battery to keep the Switch topped up without interfering with your gameplay. </p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>10.47 x 4.45 x 1.71 inches</p></div><div><div><div><p>Integrated 10,000 mAh battery</p></div><div><p>Cutouts and air vents prevent overheating</p></div></div><div><p>Adds heft to the Switch​​</p></div></div><p>If you take your Switch everywhere, battery life might be your top concern. The NEWDERY External Battery Station has an integrated 10,000 mAh battery, which can extend gameplay considerably—an extra 1.6 charges or around 8 hours of gameplay. You’re not limited to just juicing up your Switch, as it also works as a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-portable-charger"><u>portable charger</u></a> to top up your phone or tablet.</p><p>This <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-battery-cases-for-the-nintendo-switch"><u>Nintendo Switch battery case</u></a> is rocking some handy extras, like a kickstand in the back to use your Switch in tabletop mode, and a slot behind that kickstand is ready to stow two game cartridges. It also offers an 18W PD, ensuring your Switch’s fully drained battery is back to full in under 2 hours. There’s even a smart chipset to help protect your device against overvoltage and short-circuiting, while cutouts and air vents on the case prevent overheating. </p><h2>10. Bionik Power Commuter Travel Bag</h2><h3>Best Play-While-Charging Case</h3><div id="141908"><p><h3>Bionik Power Commuter Travel Bag</h3></p><div><p>Take your Switch on the go in a durable, spacious case with a 10,000mAh battery that’ll charge up your Switch and other devices. </p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>10.8 x 2.2 x 6.5 inches</p></div><div><p>10,000 mAh battery with USB-C charging cable in bag</p></div><p>Bionik’s Power Commuter Travel Bag has a beefy 10,000 mAh battery. But rather than charging directly in the case, like the NEWDERY External Battery Station, this option includes an integrated USB-C charging cable to plug in when you stop and play.  Of course, that means it’s easy to use this battery to juice up your other devices, and the bag even includes a USB-A connector. </p><p>Beyond the battery, the Power Commuter Travel Bag features a durable canvas exterior, and you can wear it across your shoulder or strap it to other luggage. Inside, this bag is padded and plush to keep your Switch safe. It’s also spacious and ready to house a slew of Switch accessories, including slots for game cartridges and Joy-Cons. </p><h2>11. Controller Gear Animal Crossing Backpack </h2><h3>Best Nintendo Switch Backpack</h3><div id="162277"><p><h3>Controller Gear Animal Crossing Backpack</h3></p><div><p>A roomy little backpack with an Animal Crossing-themed design full of pockets for the Switch and its accessories.  </p></div></div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>9.5 x 7 x 4.5 inches</p></div><div><p>Dedicated sleeve for Switch</p></div><p>Who said you had to keep your Nintendo Switch in a little case? The <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/animal-crossing-new-horizons-review-for-switch">Animal Crossing</a> backpack from Controller Gear offers plenty of room for your Nintendo Switch and won’t set you back too many bells. You can even throw in a few of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-switch-controller">best Switch controllers</a> and other accessories, like the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-headset">best Switch headsets</a>, since you won’t be limited to stuffing everything into tiny compartments.</p><p>Your console can slide into a dedicated sleeve, and there's even a holder to toss in your dock with its associated cables. Maybe you're going to get the <a href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nitro-deck"><u>Nitro Deck</u></a> for your Switch so you can take advantage of the deck’s comfortable-to-hold form factor with reliable sticks and remappable buttons. Well, don't worry, the backpack offers plenty of room for it and much more. </p><h2>12. Waterfield Designs Slip Case</h2><h3>Best Nintendo Switch Sleeve Case</h3><div id="170731"><p><h3>Waterfield Designs Slip Case</h3></p><div><p>This lightweight carrying sleeve keeps things simple with water and stain-resistant fabrics and a case-length magnetic strip to keep the Switch secure. </p></div></div><div><div><p>Dimensions</p><p>10 x 5.2 x 1 inches</p></div><div><p>Game slots</p><p>10 (optional extra)</p></div></div><div><div><p>Water and stain-resistant fabrics</p></div><div><p>Magnetic strip rather than zipper secures Switch</p></div></div><p>You can keep your Nintendo Switch safe while still being super easy to access by gearing yourself up with a sleeve-style case. Waterfield Designs delivers with its Slip Case for the Nintendo Switch or Switch Lite. It’s a lightweight carrying sleeve that keeps things simple with a case-length magnetic strip to ensure everything is secure but also lets you slide your console out to be gaming in seconds—no more fussing with zippers. </p><p>The Waterfield Designs Slip Case is made with quality materials, as you get water and stain-resistant fabrics, while a bottom grip made of leather makes it easier to pull your Switch out. Inside is a fuzzy lining to stay gentle on the Switch's screen, and there are two pockets to house a few accessories that are also designed to protect the console's controls from impact. This sleeve is available in various colors and has optional add-ons, like a game cartridge holder or a carabiner to attach the case to your backpack.</p><h2>How to Choose a Nintendo Switch Case</h2><p>There is no shortage of cases for the Nintendo Switch, with dozens showing up on Amazon and a wealth of other options, including boutique-made cases on sites like Etsy. And there are different sorts of cases as well; you can choose from travel cases, protective snap-on cases, charging cases, and more.</p><p>If you need something to carry your console around in, a carrying case or travel case is where you want to look. There are a lot of decorative cases that bear images of game characters or logos. That’s fine, but whatever you choose, make sure it can meet the minimum requirements of being a carrying case; it should be padded well enough to protect your investment from routine impacts.</p><p>It should also have a way to protect the screen from scratches (usually with a flip-down cover or sleeve) and be able to hold as many game cartridges as you want to carry around. Likewise, consider what you need to carry. Perhaps all you need is the console itself, but if you’re traveling home to see the parents, you might need a case large enough to hold the dock and an HDMI cable.</p><p>Some cases step up the game with an integrated battery. It’s probably not worth considering a charging case with less than about 10,000 mAh of power, as that’ll power your Switch through just short of two complete charges. Bonus points if the battery charges quickly, and can also charge other devices in your inventory.</p><p>Remember that these are cases you’ll need to cart around in the real world. What, exactly, do you want to be seen wearing or carrying? Some cases look a little goofy or childish, which is fine if you’re a child, and less so if you’re a grownup who takes a Switch to work to game on a lunch break.</p><h2>Nintendo Switch Case FAQ</h2><h3>Does a Nintendo Switch Need a Case?</h3><p>Unless you’re playing your Switch exclusively at home–and one free of kids and pets at that—then you will absolutely want a case to ensure the longevity of the device. Although the portable console is relatively durable, when you toss it in a bag or accidentally drop it, you always run the risk of cracking the screen, damaging the joysticks, or breaking other key components, essentially bricking the device or needing to fix it for far more than the cost of a case. </p><p>Beyond protection, cases also add convenience, as many come with extra storage for game cartridges and accessories and straps for easy carrying. You’ll even find options that serve as grips to make gameplay more enjoyable or cases offering integrated batteries, ensuring you’re never without juice during crucial moments in the action.   </p><h3>Do New Nintendo Switches Come With a Case?</h3><p>Unfortunately, none of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-nintendo-switch-consoles">Nintendo Switch models</a> come with a case. In some instances, there may be a bundle deal that includes a case, but for the most part, you’ll have to seek out a case on your own. That’s why we’ve created this guide to help in the search.</p><h3>What Size Does a Switch Case Need to Be? </h3><p>A Nintendo Switch is relatively compact at 4 inches high by 9.5 inches long and 0.55 inches thick with the Joy-Cons attached, which means the case used to protect it doesn’t need to be massive. You’ll need to account for the material required in the case’s design, about 0.1-0.2 inches or so. Sleeve-type cases, like <a href="https://zdcs.link/1KZj3?_ga=549648315.1689878480" target="_blank"><u>Waterfield Designs Slip Case</u></a>, are ready to house and protect the console while keeping slim dimensions.</p><p>If you’re looking for a hard-shelled case to boost protection or want additional storage for accessories, the case size will increase more drastically. You can expect to add an inch or more to the Switch’s size to accommodate these additions. When putting accessories into a case, it’s also important they don’t press up against your device, causing accidental misspresses or damage to the fragile screen. Pockets and separate storage areas can help prevent this. </p><p><em>Dave Johnson has been writing about gaming and tech since the days of the Palm Pilot. See him shout into the Twitter void </em><a href="https://twitter.com/davejoh" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@davejoh</em></a><em>.</em></p><p><em>Danielle Abraham is a freelance writer and unpaid music historian.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Be sure to tune in for Zenless Zone Zero’s pre-release livestream for new details and in-game rewards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/be-sure-to-tune-in-for-zenless-zone-zeros-pre-release-livestream-for-new-details-and-in-game-rewards/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=be-sure-to-tune-in-for-zenless-zone-zeros-pre-release-livestream-for-new-details-and-in-game-rewards</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/be-sure-to-tune-in-for-zenless-zone-zero%E2%80%99s-pre-release-livestream-for-new-details-and-in-game-rewards.907629/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/be-sure-to-tune-in-for-zenless-zone-zeros-pre-release-livestream-for-new-details-and-in-game-rewards/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=be-sure-to-tune-in-for-zenless-zone-zeros-pre-release-livestream-for-new-details-and-in-game-rewards<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="401" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em>Wuthering Waves </em>may be all the rage at the moment among fans of free-to-play action-RPGs, but <em>Genshin</em> <em>Impact</em> and <em>Honkai: Star Rail</em> studio miHoYo is on the verge of launching yet another one to compete for your wallet’s attention: <em>Zenless Zone Zero</em>. So, in preparation, it’s putting together a pre-release livestream that anyone eager to get into <em>Zenless Zone Zero</em> won’t want to miss.</p> <p data-characters="341" data-current-count="341" data-injectable="false">Announced via the game’s <a href="https://x.com/ZZZ_EN/status/1804001325786763623" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">official Twitter account</a>, the livestream—titled Welcome to New Eridu—it will be airing on Friday, June 28, and broadcast on <em>Zenless Zone Zero</em>‘s Twitch, YouTube, Twitter, and Facebook accounts. As for the exact air time, here’s a short list of when you can start watching in each major timezone:</p> <figure data-current-count="641" data-injectable="true"><div> <blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Announcing Zenless Zone Zero's Pre-Release Special Program</p><p>Dear Proxy, Zenless Zone Zero's Version 1.0 Pre-Release Special Program, "Welcome to New Eridu," will air on June 28 at 19:00 (UTC+8).<br>Follow the Livestream Channels:<br>Twitch: <a href="https://t.co/IPPYiS7jqK">https://t.co/IPPYiS7jqK</a><br>YouTube:… <a href="https://t.co/hYDDRQryBw">pic.twitter.com/hYDDRQryBw</a></p></div>— Zenless Zone Zero (@ZZZ_EN) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZZZ_EN/status/1804001325786763623?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 21, 2024</a></blockquote> </div></figure>
 <ul data-found-items="6" data-current-count="240" data-injectable="false"> <li><strong>Pacific Time (PT):</strong> <ul> <li>4 a.m. PT on June 28</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Central Daylight Time (CDT):</strong> <ul> <li>6 a.m. CDT on June 28</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Eastern Time (ET):</strong> <ul> <li>7 a.m. ET on June 28</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>British Summer Time (BST):</strong> <ul> <li>12 p.m. BST on June 28</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Central European Summer Time (CEST):</strong> <ul> <li>1 p.m. CEST on June 28</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Australian Eastern Standard Time (AEST):</strong> <ul> <li>9 p.m. AEST on June 28</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p data-characters="357" data-current-count="597" data-injectable="true">Exactly what will be shown hasn’t been confirmed, but miHoYo has already promised it will reveal new playable Agents, and there’ll be reward drops like redemption codes and livestream prize draws. So, tuning in means you can earn new in-game content for when you start playing the week after. As a reminder, <em>Zenless Zone Zero</em> <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/zenless-zone-zero-is-launching-on-july-4-so-are-you-ready-proxy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launches on July 4</a>.</p>
 <p data-characters="573" data-current-count="573" data-injectable="false">I’m interested to see how well <em>Zenless Zone Zero</em> performs upon launch when compared to miHoYo’s previous efforts. It already promises to start off strong since it has <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/zenless-zone-zero-is-open-for-pre-registration-and-over-30-million-have-already-signed-up/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over 30 million pre-registrations</a>. By comparison, it took <em>Wuthering Waves</em> <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/wuthering-waves-hits-30-million-download-milestone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">three weeks to get 30 million downloads</a>. Personally speaking, while the likes of <em>Genshin Impact</em> and <em>Wuthering Waves</em> never caught my interest, I’m half-tempted to give <em>Zenless Zone Zero</em> a shot thanks to its urban fantasy setting. Plus, one of <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/all-playable-zenless-zone-zero-characters/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the playable characters</a> is a talking bear; how can anyone not love that?</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nivalis is a cyberpunk slice of life RPG coming out in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/21/nivalis-is-a-cyberpunk-slice-of-life-rpg-coming-out-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nivalis-is-a-cyberpunk-slice-of-life-rpg-coming-out-in-2025.907620/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/21/nivalis-is-a-cyberpunk-slice-of-life-rpg-coming-out-in-2025/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>ION Lands has announced that Nivalis, the cyberpunk slice-of-life RPG, is slated for release in Spring 2025. Set in the same universe as the developer’s prior title, Cloudpunk, the game shifts from a neon-noir detective and delivery story to an open-world RPG, with the primary goal of establishing a thriving hospitality business.</p>
<p><iframe title="Nivalis | Official Summer 2024 Trailer [PEGI]" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VYykZ9RBo3w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In Nivalis, you begin with a small business, such as a noodle stand or a small nightclub. Your goal is to grow from these modest origins into a huge enterprise that Nivalis’ citizens will rave about and want to spend their time and money at. However, there’s more to Nivalis than just building up a business. You can get to know some of the city’s inhabitants, go fishing, or just dedicate time to home decoration. Delving into the underworld of Nivalis is also an option, but details on what that would entail have not been given.</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/11/05/cloudpunk-review/">Cloudpunk Review</a></h3>
<p>In our Cloudpunk review, Gareth said, <em>“Cloudpunk delivers the look and feel of a cyberpunk city, it just doesn’t fill the city with anything of interest. The story is okay and there’s some side conversations to keep you amused, but once the novelty of driving around Nivalis wears off, you’ll recognise that this is a game made entirely of fetch quests. The city looks gorgeous, it’s just a shame it doesn’t have more attractions.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VYykZ9RBo3w">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft for PS5 is finally here]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/minecraft-for-ps5-is-finally-here</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-for-ps5-is-finally-here.907617/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/minecraft-for-ps5-is-finally-here<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>A native version of Minecraft is finally coming to PS5.</p>
<p>Acknowledging that until now, "the only way to play Minecraft on a PlayStation 5 is by purchasing the PlayStation 4 version of the game", Mojang says that "by developing a native version of Minecraft for PS5, we'll be able to make the game run more effectively on the PS5's hardware, so you can lose your inventory in lava in the smoothest possible way!"</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Minecraft - Late to the Party" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9AuJWRNrqh8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Minecraft - Late to the Party</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9AuJWRNrqh8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9AuJWRNrqh8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Let's Play Minecraft - Late to the Party.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9AuJWRNrqh8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>To get involved, you'll need a PS5 – naturally – and the PS4 version of Minecraft. Fire it up, and you'll be able to access the PS5 version by navigating to Settings, and then hit Preview.</p>
<p>After that, you'll be able to access the Tricky Trials Update, try out the trial chambers, visit Realms, meet a breeze, craft a mace, and more.</p>
<p>The preview version is essentially a test build, so you may encounter glitches and bugs that you don't usually see, and you won't have access to the Minecraft Store. You will also be restricted to who you can play multiplayer with – crossplay is only available for friends playing on PS4 and PS5 consoles, although Realms is still available to play with pals on other devices.</p>
<p>Did you catch the news that a new <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/minecraft-animated-series-announced-for-netflix">animated Minecraft series has been announced for Netflix</a>? The series – revealed as part of Minecraft's 15th-year anniversary celebrations – was revealed by way of a trailer showing a lone Creeper making its way onto the scene, and then exploding. The camera then pans through a blocky lava-filled cavern in the Nether, before it comes to rest on Netflix's large red 'N' logo perched atop a rock. Bats fly overhead.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Direct and the year ahead | GI Microcast]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/nintendo-direct-and-the-year-ahead-gi-microcast</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-direct-and-the-year-ahead-gi-microcast.907614/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/nintendo-direct-and-the-year-ahead-gi-microcast<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Latest episode available to download or watch now</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>
You can now download or watch the latest episode of the GI Microcast, which covers (among other things) the latest Nintendo Direct.
</p>
<p>
We discuss the line-up shown with <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/metroid-prime-4-and-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-headline-nintendo-direct">new Mario,  Zelda and Metroid titles on display</a>, and ponder what this says about the Switch's final year before its successor arrives. We also look at the untapped potential for the Metroid franchise.
</p>
<p>
From there, we weigh up the showcases from each of the platform holders and the implications for those businesses as well as the wider market. And, inevitably, the conversation turns to ongoing turbulence felt across the industry, and when we might start to see signs of recovery in the wake of various layoffs and studio closures.
</p>
<p>You can watch via the player below, <a href="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/GNL9224053295.mp3?updated=1718969740">download the audio podcast version here</a>, or subscribe to our podcast feed, available via <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5j0BepJk2cQOud04zhAMem">Spotify</a>, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/the-gamesindustry-biz-podcast/id1195829295">iTunes</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/The-GamesIndustry-biz-Podcast/dp/B08K5Y9H9L/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2CWPIGJCPDUN7&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.HsgsVZya9W2_Qtb-PQJdNA.8gtqhkNuJFcziQubIMwfHGmFi4dDvsXEuUtAhihoCRs&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=games+industrie.biz+podcast&amp;qid=1715091676&amp;sprefix=gamesindustry.biz+podcast%2Caps%2C114&amp;sr=8-1">Amazon Music</a>, <a href="https://www.castbox.fm/channel/id5296137?country=us">CastBox</a>, <a href="https://player.fm/series/the-gamesindustrybiz-podcast">Player FM</a>, <a href="https://tunein.com/podcasts/Media--Entertainment-Podcasts/The-GamesIndustrybiz-Podcast-p952109/">TuneIn</a> and other widely-used podcast platforms.</p>
<p>Video versions of the Microcast can be found on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCe8Uo0kzZFsnaa4gYspWAjg">the GamesIndustry.biz YouTube channel</a>, or via <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uaJdhO7Yqqw&amp;list=PLp0EH6WpyzdN-dmZ5N0o1lH5-Bf1Rg9DI&amp;pp=gAQBiAQB">this playlist</a>.</p>
<p>Episode edited by Alix Attenborough.</p>
<figure>

<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=moTOwv8ay9Q" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft developing native version of Minecraft for PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/microsoft-developing-native-version-of-minecraft-for-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-developing-native-version-of-minecraft-for-ps5.907611/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/microsoft-developing-native-version-of-minecraft-for-ps5<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-template="layout" data-theme="theme2"><nav data-module="navigation" aria-label="navigation"></nav><div data-testid="article-base-body" data-template="article"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Microsoft is working on a native version of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minecraft</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for the PlayStation 5. The company has launched a preview of the new version and is asking PlayStation 5 owners to help with testing.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"If you own the PS4 version of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minecraft</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for your PS5, you’ll be able to access and test this early version by navigating to 'Settings' and then 'Preview' within the game," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/article/minecraft-playstation-5">reads a post on the </a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/article/minecraft-playstation-5">Minecraft</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/article/minecraft-playstation-5"> website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"As this is a preview version, we'll need your help in hunting bugs (and we're not talking about the silverfish spawning from trial spawners), as well as gathering any feedback."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As Microsoft noted, PlayStation 5 owners can already access the PlayStation 4 version of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minecraft</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but the new release is expected to provide a smoother experience on current-generation hardware.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We believe that </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minecraft</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is better when more friends can play together, however they want, on whichever device they like. We even welcome players who like to dig straight down into the nearest lava block," continues the post.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Currently, however, the only way to play </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minecraft</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on a PlayStation 5 is by purchasing the PlayStation 4 version of the game. By developing a native version of Minecraft for PS5 we'll be able to make the game run more effectively on the PS5's hardware. So you can lose your inventory in lava in the smoothest possible way"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minecraft</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is currently available on a vast array of platforms including Nintendo Switch, iOS, Android, Windows PC, and more.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The franchise represents one of Microsoft's most prolific first-party titles, and it's clear the company remains keen to support the franchise across multiple platforms–including those owned by rivals like Nintendo and Sony.&nbsp;</span><br></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div><p>You May Also Like</p><hr></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LXD Red Honey is an astonishingly good free metroidvania that owes something to psychedelic bees]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lxd-red-honey-is-an-astonishingly-good-free-metroidvania-that-owes-something-to-psychedelic-bees</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lxd-red-honey-is-an-astonishingly-good-free-metroidvania-that-owes-something-to-psychedelic-bees.907599/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lxd-red-honey-is-an-astonishingly-good-free-metroidvania-that-owes-something-to-psychedelic-bees<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>My pick of Metroidvania Month 24</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_DfQSPDW.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>sarn / OvergrownRobot</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Sometimes I have proper critical thoughts about games and sometimes I am Marge Simpson giving her opinion on a potato. Take LXD Red Honey, a free 2D metroidvania created in just 18 days for the <a href="https://itch.io/jam/metroidvania-month-24">Metroidvania Month 24</a> jam by sarn and OvergrownRobot, with playtesting by Oroshibu. I just think it's neat. So neat. 
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Let me try to flesh out the ways in which it is neat. Firstly, the world is sort of Loco Roco by way of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sonic-mania">Sonic Mania</a> - clean shapes and flat colours that may look like a pastiche of modern abstract art pilfered from VectorStock, but which reveal themselves in motion to be wonderfully tactile and bouncy and clattery. Secondly, it has an enemy who juts its head out of the ground like a garden eel, screws up its face and shoots squeaky, slow-moving rainbow beams at you. These beams richochet, sometimes catching you out if you try to hop over them, and thus, encouraging you to consider the layout before approaching. Neat! 
</p>
<p>
In broad strokes, it's both a condensing of metroidvania staples such as ye olde aerial dash, and a witty platformer in the spirit of Mario, except that instead of a tenacious plumber you play a small white square with an evolving ability set. You can shoot short-ranged energy blasts from each side of the square, which means you can only attack (initially) across the horizontal and vertical axis. Enemies, however, come at you from all directions and indeed through surfaces. Going by the 30 minutes I've played, beating the game is an exercise in wrestling with this disadvantage and then acquiring abilities that let you bypass it. Neat!</p>
<p>It's got a story, sort of. Here's some preamble from the Itch page: "A strange machine appeared in the sky, breaking down much of the plant life across the region into their core elements, including your humble garden. Collect and harness the power of these fragments in order to rebuild your world piece by piece. Explore 6 unique areas in order to find and defeat the evil that sought your world's destruction." The need to gather elements also gates your progress: you'll need to find enough water drops to grow a plant you can jump on to reach the next area, for example.
</p>
<p>
As for the title, LXD stands for "Liquid Xtal Dream", and red honey, I gather, refers to a kind of honey produced when bees feed on rhododendron flowers. In real life, red honey contains grayanotoxins, which confer hallucinogenic effects in small doses. Guzzle down a lot of red honey, however, and it may kill you. Neat? You can <a href="https://saturnyoshi.itch.io/lxd-red-honey">download LXD Red Honey from Itch here</a>. It's really good. It's definitely worth donating to the developers, if you have cash to spare.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Creator Would Like to Make a JRPG, But It Wouldn’t Be a Sequel to Enchanted Arms]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-creator-would-like-to-make-a-jrpg-but-it-wouldnt-be-a-sequel-to-enchanted-arms/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-creator-would-like-to-make-a-jrpg-but-it-wouldn%E2%80%99t-be-a-sequel-to-enchanted-arms.907596/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-creator-would-like-to-make-a-jrpg-but-it-wouldnt-be-a-sequel-to-enchanted-arms/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Elden Ring gets its first and only expansion, Shadow of the Erdtree. As part of an interview <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/hidetaka-miyazaki-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-1235042903/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with Rolling Stone</a>, game director and FromSoftware president Hidetaka Miyazaki took the opportunity to discuss some other games he'd like to make in the future.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, the Elden Ring creator would like to make a traditional JRPG. Long-time FromSoftware will certainly remember Enchanted Arms, the turn-based JRPG made by the studio and published by Ubisoft in 2006 for PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360. However, it doesn't sound like Miyazaki would be interested in a sequel, mainly because he doesn't believe in following up on franchises that were created by others. An exception is Armored Core, as explained below.</p>
<p><em>I think a lot of these games are so intertwined with the directors who almost invented that style of game. I don’t think there’s a scenario where I myself would make a King’s Field. The same can be said about Otogi and Enchanted Arms. I worked on Armored Core 4 and Armored Core: For Answer. It enabled me to put my own interpretation on <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/armored-core-vi-fires-of-rubicon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Armored Core VI: Fires of Rubicon</a> and develop that.</em></p>
<p>It would actually be very interesting to see what Miyazaki and his team can come up with in that genre. Perhaps a mix of turn-based and real-time dodge/parry as proposed by <a href="https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-a-reactive-turn-based-rpg-was-easily-one-of-the-most-impressive-reveals-of-xgs-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>? Meanwhile, fans of his work can dive into Shadow of the Erdtree, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-worthy-of-the-greater-wills-blessing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">got another perfect score here on Wccftech</a>.</p>
<p><em>It did not take long to get back into the engaging adventuring loop of the Elden Ring experience, searching for map fragments to get a better look at the map, placing markers where points of interest are seemingly located, and getting amazed by beautiful vistas, immense castles, and sprawling haunting forests, unaware of the dangers that lurked inside of them. With open-world fatigue setting in earlier this year due to the many open-world games released in 2024—like Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, Rise of the Ronin, and the PC versions of Horizon Forbidden West and Ghost of Tsushima—Shadow of the Erdtree's open-world design stands out as a testament to how the Elden Ring experience still surpasses anything else on the market. As such, I believe a perfect score is justified, even with the evident lack of significant innovation and some technical hiccups.</em></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Displate Reveals Stunning and Rare Shadow of the Erdtree Metal Poster]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-displate-limited-edition/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/displate-reveals-stunning-and-rare-shadow-of-the-erdtree-metal-poster.907593/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-displate-limited-edition/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Displate is one of the most recognisable names in the collector space – and it has been that way for a few years. For those not in the know, Displate offers a staggering range of ‘metal posters’ or ‘prints’ that are created in celebration of almost every franchise or series in pop culture, be it a movie, video game, comic book, or television show. These metal posters are stunning, and in recent months, the team at Displate has innovated, applying 3D-style layering and unique textures to the prints that bring the art to life.</p>



<p>Recently, Displate unveiled a super limited edition Shadow of the Erdtree poster as a tribute to the new Elden Ring expansion that’s out <strong>today</strong>. As someone who owns Displate posters, I can firmly attest that they’re well worth the investment.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-sublime-in-the-shadow">Sublime in the Shadow</h2>



<p>The limited edition Shadow of the Erdtree poster from Displate boasts intricate 3D detailing and a shimmering gloss finish that’s sure to make it pop on any wall in the house – or workplace (it’s entirely up to you where it goes). It’s a gorgeous piece that’s limited to just 1,500 copies, so you’ll need to act fast if you want to secure one. It’s the perfect item for any streamer backdrop or to adorn the wall of a gaming room.</p>



<p>Going above and beyond a standard paper poster, a Displate poster is the pinnacle of durability and quality. On the Displate site, there are <strong>thousands </strong>of designs to choose from – and I recently picked out a couple of Fallout posters to go on my wall. They’re adorned with the ‘Textra’ finish that adds a strategically-placed 3D detail to appropriate surfaces on the poster, giving it much more depth than a flat finish.</p>



<p>Here’s a snapshot of my Displate posters:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It was hard picking out these two from the hundreds available – I’d have brought dozens if I’d had my way. There’s such a stunning range to choose from, it’s unreal. I’m a huge Fallout fan, so securing these gorgeous posters was a no-brainer, but if you’re partial to an Elden Ring-themed collector’s item, you’ll need to move fast to <a href="https://displate.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">secure the limited edition Displate poster</a>. </p>



<p>And if you’re curious about how you install them, it’s dramatically easy. Every Displate poster comes with a unique ‘sticky magnet’ that won’t damage your walls and takes seconds to fit – simple! </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-good-asus-rog-ally-one-year-later/">our one-year review of the Asus ROG Ally</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond Good & Evil - 20th Anniversary Edition Has a New ‘Narrative Link’ to Beyond Good & Evil 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/beyond-good-evil-20th-anniversary-edition-has-a-new-narrative-link-to-beyond-good-evil-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beyond-good-evil-20th-anniversary-edition-has-a-new-%E2%80%98narrative-link%E2%80%99-to-beyond-good-evil-2.907590/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/beyond-good-evil-20th-anniversary-edition-has-a-new-narrative-link-to-beyond-good-evil-2<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Ubisoft has insisted it's committed to the Beyond Good &amp; Evil franchise and even mentioned its long in-development sequel as part of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/beyond-good-evil-20th-anniversary-edition-officially-unveiled-at-lrg3-2024">the reveal of Beyond Good &amp; Evil - 20th Anniversary Edition</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/beyond-good-and-evil-2">Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2</a> is considered vaporware by many fans after an incredible 16 years since <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2008/05/28/ubisoft-announces-beyond-good-evil-follow-up">it was announced back in 2008</a>. Despite Ubisoft’s many vague references to it being still alive, no video game has materialized thus far.</p><p>But this week's announcement of <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/beyond-good-evil-20th-anniversary-edition">Beyond Good &amp; Evil - 20th Anniversary Edition</a> has sparked renewed hope that Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 is real and may even be re-revealed sooner rather than later.</p><p>This remaster includes a brand new mission in which players can discover more about protagonist Jade’s past and collect exclusive cosmetic rewards. Crucially, Ubisoft included a note to press that this new mission “also reveals more about the narrative link to Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2, showing Ubisoft’s enduring commitment to the franchise.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>That line strongly suggests Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 is not just still alive but closer than ever to launch. The question of course will be what form the game takes, given how many times development has stopped and started over the years. At E3 2017, Ubisoft revealed what looked like an incredibly ambitious project, promising a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/06/15/e3-2017-beyond-good-evil-2-is-a-massively-ambitious-rpg"><u>multi-planet world populated by dynamically-generated characters</u></a>.</p><p>In the meantime, Beyond Good &amp; Evil - 20th Anniversary Edition launches June 25 on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X and S, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, Amazon Luna, and PC through the Ubisoft Store, Epic Games Store and Steam, with a physical version from Limited Run Games out July 12. It features the aforementioned new mission, an anniversary gallery, a re-orchestrated soundtrack, support of up to 60FPS, and other "exclusive new content."</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega has no Sonic Central showcase planned for the blue blur’s birthday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/sega-has-no-sonic-central-showcase-planned-for-the-blue-blurs-birthday/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=sega-has-no-sonic-central-showcase-planned-for-the-blue-blurs-birthday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sega-has-no-sonic-central-showcase-planned-for-the-blue-blur%E2%80%99s-birthday.907587/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/sega-has-no-sonic-central-showcase-planned-for-the-blue-blurs-birthday/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sega-has-no-sonic-central-showcase-planned-for-the-blue-blurs-birthday<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="373" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Although the summer of gaming showcases wrapped up with <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/everything-shown-in-the-nintendo-direct-for-june-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">presentations from Nintendo</a> and Limited Run Games this week, <em>Sonic the Hedgehog</em> fans had been hoping to see Sega air one of its Sonic Central showcases, especially with it being Sonic’s birthday on June 23. Unfortunately, the company has recently confirmed it has no such presentation planned at all this month.</p> <p data-characters="403" data-current-count="403" data-injectable="true">As spotted by <a href="https://www.sonicstadium.org/news/sonic/no-sonic-central-planned-for-june-2024-sega-confirms-r2270/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Sonic Stadium</a>, social media and community manager Katie Chrzanowski made a point of confirming this during <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/h77eJwjcTWA?si=g_PhNyW6khEOwfwI" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a recent livestream</a> to celebrate the anniversary of the <em>Sonic</em> series. That’s not to say there couldn’t be one later in the year but, for now, “There’s not one happening this month… We don’t have news on when a Sonic Central is going to be.”</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Sega</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="409" data-current-count="709" data-injectable="true">You can’t blame fans for expecting a <em>Sonic</em> showcase of some kind in June considering Sega has been holding them regularly the last few years, with last year’s one even taking place on Sonic’s birthday. Admittedly, these showcases don’t quite rival the hype of a Nintendo Direct, but they’ve still offered some neat updates on whatever <em>Sonic</em> related projects were in the pipeline.</p>
 <p data-characters="861" data-current-count="861" data-injectable="true">The second half of 2024 is slated to be a big one for the franchise since not only is there <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-locks-in-an-october-launch-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a remaster of <em>Sonic Generations</em> coming out in October</a>, but <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/jim-carrey-returns-for-sonic-the-hedgehog-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the third live-action movie is scheduled for December</a>. And both of these projects will prominently feature fan-favourite Shadow the Hedgehog, who’s making quite the comeback this year. Admittedly, Sega debuted a new trailer and further details on <em>Sonic X Shadow Generations</em> during Summer Game Fest this month. As much as I want to see even more of that game, we’ve probably had our fill for the time being. However, details on the third movie are shockingly slim; there hasn’t even been a proper trailer for it, meaning we know next to nothing about its general plot. A brief trailer was shown to attendees at CinemaCon in April, but it was never uploaded afterwards for everyone else to see.</p>
 <p data-characters="578" data-current-count="578" data-injectable="false">Even if a Sonic Central had taken place this month, though, it’s unlikely it would’ve included a movie trailer based on previous showcases. The first movie had already premiered before the first Sonic Central ever aired, and the second movie’s debut trailer was shown during The Game Awards 2021. As such, any June Sonic Central may have teased the upcoming movie, but not shared any major news about it. Although this only begs the question of when and where Sega and Paramount intended on talking about the movie, especially with it coming out in six months.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Matt Booty implies Tango Gameworks closure was partly due to leadership change]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/matt-booty-implies-tango-gameworks-closure-was-partly-due-to-leadership-change</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/matt-booty-implies-tango-gameworks-closure-was-partly-due-to-leadership-change.907584/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/matt-booty-implies-tango-gameworks-closure-was-partly-due-to-leadership-change<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Is the team the same team that shipped something successful previously?"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Chai-in-Hi-Fi-Rush.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Tango Gameworks</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Xbox's Matt Booty has spoken more on the closure of Tango Gameworks earlier this year, and, while he did not name names, it appears that a change in leadership at the Hi-Fi Rush studio was a factor in Microsoft's decision.</p>
<p>In conversation with <a href="https://variety.com/2024/gaming/news/xbox-studios-matt-booty-podast-game-pass-fallout-studio-closures-1236038120/">Variety's Strictly Business podcast</a>, the Xbox executive was asked about the closure of Tango Gameworks, and whether Microsoft had tried to seek another buyer for the studio.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Is the closure of Hi-Fi Rush and Redfall's studios a sign Xbox Game Pass publishing is failing?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Dx4fu4H6us" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"I won't get into the real sort of nitty gritty details on you know, what went into the decision, mostly out of respect for the people there, just because you know, there was a lot of work that went into delivering Hi-Fi Rush, which was a great game and you know did well for us," Booty began.</p>
<p>"I think the thing to be considered is that for us, it's as much a forward looking situation as much as it is looking back at one certain game... There are a lot of things that go into success for a game. You know, what leadership do you have? What creative leadership do you have? Is the team the same team that shipped something successful previously?</p>
<p>"And we have to look at all of those things together and then ask ourselves, are we set up for success going forward? And while there may have been factors and situations that previously led to success, they may not all still be in place as you look at what you're doing going forward."</p>
<p>Booty seemed to be referring - at least in part - to the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/shinji-mikami-leaving-tango-gameworks-after-12-years">departure of Tango Gameworks founder Shinji Mikami last year</a>. Mikami established Tango Gameworks in 2010, with the studio going on to develop The Evil Within series and Ghostwire: Tokyo. Prior to this, he worked at Capcom on the Resident Evil series.</p>
<p>Booty also seemed to suggest closing down Tango Gameworks wasn't the only option Microsoft considered. He gave examples of previous Xbox-owned studios that have since gone independent, such as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/activisions-skylanders-crash-bandicoot-studio-toys-for-bob-going-independent">Toys for Bob</a>, which now has a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/spyro-studio-toys-for-bob-secures-deal-with-microsoft-for-its-first-independent-game">publishing deal in place with Microsoft</a>.</p>
<p>"I think back to a studio called Twisted Pixel in Texas that we acquired and then for a sort of change in goals, it wasn't a perfect match anymore, but that studio today is still thriving," Booty continued. "We wanted to set them up for success. So we absolutely look at what the possible business options are to keep a studio open or to keep you know, perhaps have it change hands. And it's just one of the things, of course, that we look at across the board."</p>
<p>Booty closed: "Sometimes those things come together, sometimes they don't."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hi-fi-rush.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Tango Gameworks/Microsoft</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As well as Tango Gameworks, Redfall and Dishonored developer Arkane Austin and Mighty Doom studio Alpha Dog Games were also impacted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-shuts-slew-of-bethesda-studios-including-redfall-hi-fi-rush-developers">Microsoft's closures in May</a>.</p>
<p>Many were quick to condemn the company's decision to shutter these studios, with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arkane-lyon-boss-leads-widespread-condemnation-of-bethesda-closures">Arkane Lyon boss Dinga Bakaba calling it a "fucking gut stab"</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII New Glitches Continue to Get Discovered, 27 Years After Its Release]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-new-glitches-continue-to-get-discovered-27-years-after-its-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-new-glitches-continue-to-get-discovered-27-years-after-its-release.907581/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-new-glitches-continue-to-get-discovered-27-years-after-its-release/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>New Final Fantasy VII glitches continue to be discovered over 27 years after the game's release on the original PlayStation.</p>
<p><strong><em>(There will be some spoilers below, so avoid reading if you have never played Final Fantasy VII and don't want to get anything spoiled.)</em></strong></p>
<p>The new glitch, showcased in a new video shared by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@4-8Productions">4-8 Productions</a> on YouTube, allows players to retain Aerith in the party even after the events at the Forgotten Capital. What makes this glitch fascinating is the complex procedure to activate it, which essentially requires the user to "confuse" the game so that it doesn't know exactly at what moment the story actually is, only to rectify it at the Icicle Inn location, the first location Cloud and his companions visit after the Forgotten Capital, to keep Aerith in the party.</p>
<p><iframe title="HUGE FFVII Discovery Brings Aerith Back To Life!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/May-fRmdWNA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The events at the Forgotten Capital also mark the end of Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, the second entry in the remake trilogy released earlier this year on PlayStation 5. Built on some of the mechanics introduced in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-fixed-doors-and-flying-ninjas/">Remake</a>, Rebirth greatly expands them, doing away with the predominant linearity of its predecessor to present one of the best JRPGs released in recent times. You can learn more about the game by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/">review.</a></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turning down Elden Ring's difficulty would "break the game itself", says Miyazaki]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/turning-down-elden-rings-difficulty-would-break-the-game-itself-says-miyazaki</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/turning-down-elden-rings-difficulty-would-break-the-game-itself-says-miyazaki.907578/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/turning-down-elden-rings-difficulty-would-break-the-game-itself-says-miyazaki<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"That wasn't the right approach".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-patch-notes.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
FromSoftware's Soulsborne games are notoriously difficult to beat, but creator Hidetaka Miyazaki has said it would "break the game itself" to turn down the challenge.
</p>
<p>
In an interview with <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/article/2024/jun/21/hidetaka-miyazaki-fromsoftware-elden-ring-shadow-erdtree">The Guardian</a>, Miyazaki discussed how high difficulty is not only creatively part of the game, but also has led to its success.

</p>
<p>
"If we really wanted the whole world to play the game, we could just crank the difficulty down more and more. But that wasn't the right approach," he said. 
</p>
<p>
"Had we taken that approach, I don't think the game would have done what it did, because the sense of achievement that players gain from overcoming these hurdles is such a fundamental part of the experience. Turning down difficulty would strip the game of that joy - which, in my eyes, would break the game itself."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="7 Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree Beginners Tips - A REFRESHER COURSE FOR FORGETFUL TARNISHED" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JblbR93fNDk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>7 Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree Beginners Tips - A REFRESHER COURSE FOR FORGETFUL TARNISHED</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JblbR93fNDk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JblbR93fNDk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>7 Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree Beginners Tips<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JblbR93fNDk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Of course, difficulty is subjective, and Elden Ring's new expansion Shadow of the Erdtree does not add any further accessibility options to the game.
</p>
<p>
However, in an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-creator-hidetaka-miyazaki-on-originating-the-soulslike-genre">interview with Eurogamer</a>, Miyazaki said: "this is not something I'm opposed to in the slightest," adding "we're going to continue to look into it and see how we can do those features in our future titles."

</p>
<p>
Shadow of the Erdtree is released today and, as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-is-fromsoftwares-largest-expansion-ever">Miyazaki previously told Eurogamer</a>, its difficulty is relative to the end of the base game.

</p>
<p>
"We wanted to provide these challenging encounters and these menacing threats, and in order to do that, we wanted to give the player a lot of freedom of approach," he said. "We wanted them to feel free in how they choose and when they choose to approach and tackle these hardships.
</p>
<p>
"So players who look for that sort of challenge in our games will find a challenge on equal footing in the DLC as well."
</p>
<p>
Difficulty was a key point in our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-review">Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree review</a>.

</p>
<p>
"It's true that this distinct type of FromSoft-engineered frustration is an indispensable part of the Souls experience - to hurl yourself repeatedly against a seemingly immovable object until through sheer luck and serendipitous timing, you somehow prevail," it reads.
</p>
<p>
"There is real palpable joy and pride and relief in that - we've all felt it, and with the blessing of hindsight, suddenly all of that failure feels like it was worth it. In other cases they're genuinely instructional, with real lessons learned. This, however, feels like difficulty for difficulty's sake, turned up to eleven, perhaps because with the added expectations of a DLC having something extra-absurd to conquer even though it technically doesn't require finishing the core game."

</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Glittering cyberpunk life sim Nivalis has been delayed until 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/glittering-cyberpunk-life-sim-nivalis-has-been-delayed-until-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/glittering-cyberpunk-life-sim-nivalis-has-been-delayed-until-2025.907575/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/glittering-cyberpunk-life-sim-nivalis-has-been-delayed-until-2025<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>When the makers of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cloudpunk">Cloudpunk</a> revealed their next game would be set in the same cyberpunk city as their sci-fi delivery sim, my ears were pricked. When they showed you'd be running a noodle bar and fishing in the slums instead of flying a hovercar around, I went into full wishlisty mode. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nivalis">Nivalis</a> (named for the cyberpunk city in question) was due to come to PC some time this year. But plans have changed. If, like me, you're intrigued by the promise of a life under a neon canopy, you might have to wait. The release date has been pushed into next year. As compensation, here, the creators have put out another trailer to remind you what's coming.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Nivalis | Official Summer 2024 Trailer [PEGI]" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VYykZ9RBo3w?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Nivalis | Official Summer 2024 Trailer [PEGI]</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VYykZ9RBo3w?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VYykZ9RBo3w?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VYykZ9RBo3w" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"Nivalis will be launching in Spring 2025!" say developers Ion Lands <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1488490/view/4169851371521463458?l=english">in a Steam post</a>. "Our city has taken on a life of its own, growing and evolving in ways we are eager to share with you... Ensuring that Nivalis provides the best possible experience is our priority. Your patience and support are invaluable as we navigate through this creative journey."</p>
<p>Fair dos, I'll hang about. It's still a vague date but at least it's narrowed down to a season. And there are some things in the new trailer we haven't seen before, such as the  pixellated subway map screen, or the little robot fella asking the player if they sell lube (oo-er). But apart from that it seems like another pitch for chill times in a cool <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world</a>. There are no more hints about the serial killer that is supposedly on the loose, as mentioned in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sumptuous-cyberpunk-life-sim-nivalis-will-have-boat-rides-and-serial-killers">previous videos</a>. We'll have to wait and see what's up with that. </p>
<p>All in all it still seems good fodder for folks seeking to resettle in a futuristic city and explore some glowing streets. I got some of that desire out of my system by wandering the sidewalks of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, of course. But something about the noisy voxels of Nivalis makes the city look even more low-life-high-tech. It helps that every car is flying, which essentially pedestrianises the entire city, hopefully making its alleyways and towers more labyrinthine and intricate. Ah, maybe I'm just yearning for that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bernband-gifs">Bernband sequel</a>. Oh well.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PVKK from the Dome Keeper devs is Papers Please but you get a huge planetary defence cannon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pvkk-from-the-dome-keeper-devs-is-papers-please-but-you-get-a-huge-planetary-defence-cannon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pvkk-from-the-dome-keeper-devs-is-papers-please-but-you-get-a-huge-planetary-defence-cannon.907572/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pvkk-from-the-dome-keeper-devs-is-papers-please-but-you-get-a-huge-planetary-defence-cannon<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>And an unlimited supply of tea</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_5VW1EUX.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bippinbits</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
PVKK: Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant - yeah, let's circle back to the title - is described in the first sentence of its Steam bio as a "cozy" game. I entertain suspicions of cozy or cosy games, inasmuch as they are increasingly framed as a kind of antidepressant in the face of a darkening world, but that's OK, because the remaining 17 words in the sentence are: "Operate your planetary defense cannon to fend off an interplanetary invasion from the comfort of your [cozy] bunker." 
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PVKK: Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant - Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DquTRgapsiM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PVKK: Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant - Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DquTRgapsiM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/DquTRgapsiM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DquTRgapsiM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
To offer some quick-and-dirty characterisations, PVKK is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/papers-please">Papers Please</a>, but you get a planetary defence cannon. It is an escape room game, but you get a planetary defence cannon. On reflection, I guess a planetary defence cannon may also serve as a kind of antidepressant in the face of a darkening world - and indeed a means of further darkening it - but well, it seems a bit more cathartic than some pastel-shaded gardening sim, right? A bit more of a release?</p>
<p>You can see the cannon out the reinforced window of your bunker, a brutal Schwerer Gustav-ass weapon menacing the sunset above a rocky valley. Armed with this cannon, an unlimited supply of tea ejected by some kind of dieselpunk Star Trek replicator, and a teleradio's worth of jaunty tunes, you will shoot hostile spaceships out of the sky. Mind you, there's more to PVKK than shooting. Your bunker appears to be haunted, possibly by feelings of displaced guilt at your being the stooge of an autocratic regime, whose propaganda newsletters and broadcasts you can view on the aforesaid teleradio.
</p>
<p>
Now then, that title. Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant, hah. This is the title of a game whose developer gives nary a bean for the affordances of digital media, a developer who cares not for limited Twitter character counts, headline lengths, the demands of SEO or the constraints of touchscreen keyboards. The prefacing abbreviation should be regarded as a gesture of sheer contempt towards people who can't fit the word  Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant into their heads without plugging in some external RAM. 
</p>
<p>
Having digested that title, it's no surprise to discover that the game's interface is an inventively overwhelming MicroProsey warren of analog fixtures. To fire your planetary defence cannon you have to operate a cockpit's worth of wheels and dials and levers and switches and grid displays and light-up buttons with annotations almost too small to read. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mech-engineer">Mech Engineer</a> players will love it to the point of feeling incredibly aroused, I suspect. Perhaps it's worth being the stooge of an autocratic regime if you can be locked away in a dugout with the interface of your wildest dreams and the biggest phallic metaphor your planet's technology can provide. I mean, you seemingly have to oil and repair the dashboard between sessions! Absolute filth! 
</p>
<p>
Those who aren't so keen on MicroProsey stuff should know that you'll spend a fair bit of time exploring the bunker, which harbours secrets about the outside world. "The regime keeps you in the dark, feeding you half-truths and political euphemisms," the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2956040/PVKK_Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant/">Steam page</a> explains. "Look behind these deceptions to understand the real situation and navigate the demands of the different factions in your own best interest." This is where the escape room puzzles come in, of course. You'll also have to make choices during dialogue with your superiors that feed into a spread of endings. Intrigue, there is plenty.
</p>
<p>
PVKK: Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant is the work of Bippinbits, who are, oh goodness, the developers of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dome-keeper">Dome Keeper</a>??? It all makes sense now! It's like they're parodying their own work. I probably should have put that in the intro - I'll put it in the headline instead. The game doesn't have a release date yet.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft Gets Native PS5 Version, Bringing It In-Line With Xbox Series X and S]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-gets-native-ps5-version-bringing-it-in-line-with-xbox-series-x-and-s</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-gets-native-ps5-version-bringing-it-in-line-with-xbox-series-x-and-s.907569/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-gets-native-ps5-version-bringing-it-in-line-with-xbox-series-x-and-s<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/minecraft">Minecraft</a> developer Mojang has released a native PlayStation 5 version in preview form, bringing the game in-line with the Xbox Series X and S version.</p><p>The PS5 version adds native 4K resolution support and higher settings for render distances and anti-aliasing, settings already available in Minecraft on Xbox Series X and S. Unfortunately, there’s no word on the addition of ray tracing to either the Xbox Series X or PS5 versions, despite <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/08/21/minecraft-with-rtx-trailer-shows-block-building-in-a-whole-new-light">Microsoft teasing the tech years ago</a>.</p><p>The first preview of the native PS5 version of Minecraft is available now for testing. If you own the PlayStation 4 version for your PS5, you can test this early version by heading to Settings and then Preview within the game. This preview includes the new Tricky Trials update, but multiplayer is only possible between other players on PlayStation 4 and 5. The exception to this is playing the preview on Realms, which allows you to cross-play with players on other devices. This preview version does not have access to the Minecraft Store.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Explaining the decision to release a native PS5 version in a <a href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/article/minecraft-playstation-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post</a>, Mojang said “we’ll be able to make the game run more effectively on the PS5’s hardware.”</p><p>Minecraft is the best-selling video game of all time with an incredible 300 million copies sold since its early access release in 2009. 15 years later, Microsoft and Mojang have so far resisted the urge to release a sequel, and with good reason — in March last year Xbox boss Phil Spencer said Minecraft had 120 million monthly players.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Studios boss: Tango Gameworks closure was 'forward-thinking' decision]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/xbox-game-studios-boss-tango-gameworks-closure-was-forward-thinking-decision</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-studios-boss-tango-gameworks-closure-was-forward-thinking-decision.907566/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/xbox-game-studios-boss-tango-gameworks-closure-was-forward-thinking-decision<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Xbox Game Studios boss Matt Booty has described the closure of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer as a "forward-thinking" decision.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://variety.com/2024/gaming/news/xbox-studios-matt-booty-podast-game-pass-fallout-studio-closures-1236038120/">Speaking on Variety's Strictly Business podcast</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/ethangach/status/1803887050023739406">as spotted by Kotaku senior reporter Ethan Gach</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">), Booty said </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">"did well" for Microsoft and Xbox, but implied leadership changes within Tango Gameworks were a factor when deciding to shutter the studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"There are a lot of people and processes and oversight to make sure we're making a good decision [to close a studio]," said Booty. "I won't get into the real nitty gritty details of what went into the decision, mostly out of respect for the people there. Just because there was a lot of work that went into delivering </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which was a great game and did well for us.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I think the thing to be considered is that, for us, it's as much a forward-looking situation as much as it is looking back at one certain game. There are a lot of things that go into [delivering] success for a game. What leadership do you have? What creative leadership do you have? Is the team the same team that shipped something successful previously? We have to look at all of those things together and then ask ourselves 'are we set up for success going forward?'"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Although he didn't talk specifics, it's worth remembering that Tango founder and CEO, Shinji Mikami, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/tango-gameworks-founder-shinji-mikami-departing-hi-fi-rush-developer">departed the studio in February 2023</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">–just over a month after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">debuted. Mikami went on to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/shinji-mikami-founds-new-studio-kamuy-inc-">establish a new studio called Kamuy Inc.</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and has previously indicated he might only direct one more title before retiring, having most recently served as an executive producer on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghostwire Tokyo</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> at Tango.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When looking at its studios, Booty said Microsoft had to consider whether some factors that previously led to success may "not all still be in place," and indicated that influenced how it chose to set out its stall moving forward.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He added that doesn't always mean closures, pointing to the decision to allow </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/toys-for-bob-is-splitting-off-from-activsion-blizzard-and-going-indie">former Call of Duty support studio Toys for Bob to go independent</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> following Microsoft's merger with Activision Blizzard.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We've announced we've got a publishing deal with [Toys for Bob] and we'll share more about that when it's important," continued Booty. "I think back to a studio called Twisted Pixel in Texas that we acquired, then we had a change in goals and it wasn't a perfect match anymore. That studio today is still thriving. We wanted to set them up for success, so we absolutely look at what the possible business options are."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Booty was doing the rounds just months after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-microsoft-follows-activision-blizzard-merger-with-1-900-layoffs">Microsoft laid off 1,900 workers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/activision-blizzard-joins-xbox-game-studios-following-microsoft-acquisition">dropping $68.7 billion on Activision Blizzard</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The Xbox maker then </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-closes-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-alpha-dog-studios">closed a number of ZeniMax studios</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> including Arkane Austin, Alpha Dog Games, and Tango Gameworks.&nbsp;</span><br></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring player count has exploded on Steam thanks to the DLC… but it still can’t catch up with Banana]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/elden-ring-player-count-has-exploded-on-steam-thanks-to-the-dlc-but-it-still-cant-catch-up-with-banana/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=elden-ring-player-count-has-exploded-on-steam-thanks-to-the-dlc-but-it-still-cant-catch-up-with-banana</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-player-count-has-exploded-on-steam-thanks-to-the-dlc%E2%80%A6-but-it-still-can%E2%80%99t-catch-up-with-banana.907563/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/elden-ring-player-count-has-exploded-on-steam-thanks-to-the-dlc-but-it-still-cant-catch-up-with-banana/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=elden-ring-player-count-has-exploded-on-steam-thanks-to-the-dlc-but-it-still-cant-catch-up-with-banana<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="360" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">With the launch of the <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shadow of the Erdtree</a></em> expansion, Bandai Namco is hoping it will <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/bandai-namco-expectations-for-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">bring in a lot of new <em>Elden Ring</em> players</a> and bump up the game’s already impressive sales. It’s too early to tell whether it has met the publisher’s expectations but, at the very least, <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> has got more people playing <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-elden-ring/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring</a></em> on Steam.</p> <p data-characters="352" data-current-count="352" data-injectable="false">According to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1245620/charts/#48h" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>, there were just over 240,000 concurrent <em>Elden Ring</em> players at 9 p.m. UTC on June 20, which would’ve been an hour before <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>‘s PC launch in U.S. Once the DLC was available worldwide, that number almost doubled to more than 495,000 players and, at around June 21, 2 a.m. UTC, peaked at 589,948 players.</p> <figure data-current-count="652" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via FromSoftware</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="615" data-current-count="615" data-injectable="true">While nowhere near as high as its all-time peak player count of 953,426 concurrent players, 589,948 is still more than half that number and the best <em>Elden Ring</em> has performed on Steam in two years. There’s unfortunately no way of checking if the player counts on PlayStation and Xbox are similar but, if they are, this looks to be a very strong showing for <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>. What’s more, at the time of writing, <em>Elden Ring</em> has shot up to become <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam’s third most-played game</a> with 467,135 concurrent players. The only two games outperforming it are <em>Counter-Strike 2</em> and <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/i-played-weird-banana-game-blowing-up-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">viral sensation <em>Banana</em></a>.</p>
 <p data-characters="519" data-current-count="519" data-injectable="true">It may seem baffling that a game that only involves clicking a banana over and over is proving more popular than a massive DLC expansion to 2022’s Game of the Year winner, but it does make some sense. For starters, <em>Banana</em> is completely free to play, not to mention much easier than <em>Elden Ring</em>. Last I checked, <em>Banana </em>doesn’t have extremely challenging boss fights. Plus, the bananas you earn from <em>Banana</em> can be sold for real money although this has invited <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/developer-behind-steam-smash-hit-banana-swears-it-isnt-a-scam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">accusations of the game being a scam of some kind</a>.</p>
 <p data-characters="546" data-current-count="546" data-injectable="false">Hopefully, Bandai Namco won’t be too bothered that a basic clicker game has more players than <em>Elden Ring</em> on PC. Although it’s not as if <em>Elden Ring</em> needs to be more successful; even before the DLC launched, it had sold over 25 million copies worldwide according to the <a href="https://x.com/fromsoftware_pr/status/1800891340374642989" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">FromSoftware Twitter account</a>. Despite such sales, <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> is intended to be the only DLC expansion for the game, meaning FromSoftware’s next project will be something else entirely… though I’m sure <em>Elden Ring 2</em> will happen eventually.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero studio uses AI technology to "smoothen" development process]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/zenless-zone-zero-studio-uses-ai-technology-to-smoothen-development-process</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-studio-uses-ai-technology-to-smoothen-development-process.907557/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/zenless-zone-zero-studio-uses-ai-technology-to-smoothen-development-process<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>But draws the line at generating art and voicework.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Zenless-Zone-Zero-ai-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>HoYoverse</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Zenless Zone Zero producer Zhenyu Li revealed in a recent interview with Eurogamer (via an interpreter) that AI generated content is used in the game "program-wise" to "better smoothen the game progress."</p>
<p>No specific programming examples were provided, as Li is "not a tech person," but he did stress that AI "only consists of a small part of the programming [in Zenless Zone Zero], mostly to help the programming team to smoothen the production process, to actually make our work more efficient."</p>
<p>Something we do know is that the game's signature vibrant, urban art style that sets it apart from miHoYo's other titles, Genshin Impact and Honkai: Star Rail, is not something made with AI generation. Li says the team wants to "create something from our own mind" when it comes to art related content, and in a later statement provided to Eurogamer to clarify some comments, it was added that this is "something the whole team believes in."</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Zenless Zone Zero - State of Play Announcement Video.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G4I61egYGdg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In regards to voicework, while miHoYo has used an AI called Anti-Entropy in the past for their Lumi_N0va virtual avatar (and to replace a voice actor for one event in their romance mystery, Tears of Themis, when the they were unavailable), Zenless Zone Zero continues the developer's streak of employing stellar voice actors across multiple languages in their big releases, as we were given a pretty definitive "No" from Li after asking if AI technology was used to generate voices in the game.</p>
<p>Apart from the Anti-Entropy AI, we know that miHoYo also uses Nvidia’s Avatar Cloud Engine (ACE) generative tech, as was revealed at the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in January of this year. ACE is an AI-powered tech that helps with generating facial animations and text-to-speech inputs to assist in the creation of characters.</p>
<p>Although not confirmed, this sounds very similar to the tech Star Rail's development team are using. They <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-honkai-star-rail-is-using-ai-technology-to-supplement-development">revealed to IGN last year</a> they use AI to improve the facial appearance and behavioural patterns of characters in the game, while also mentioning their team "is paying much attention to AI, especially its impact on the gaming industry."</p>
<p>This ACE AI also makes sense as something that might "smoothen the game progress" of Zenless Zone Zero, but without a specific example provided by Li, we don't know for sure if this specific tech was used.</p>
<p>While <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ai-already-used-by-62-of-studios-unity-report-claims">62% of studios reportedly already use AI</a>, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/how-ai-is-changing-video-game-development-forever">AI is changing video game development forever</a>, from Li's comments it sounds like Zenless Zone Zero is continuing miHoYo's trend of only lightly dipping its toes into the controversial tech, for now.</p>




        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Certified PS1 banger Fear Effect is getting a digital Steam release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/certified-ps1-banger-fear-effect-is-getting-a-digital-steam-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/certified-ps1-banger-fear-effect-is-getting-a-digital-steam-release.907554/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/certified-ps1-banger-fear-effect-is-getting-a-digital-steam-release<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Good news for people with good taste</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image_2024-06-21_101651490.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Square Enix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fear-effect">Fear Effect</a>, a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-action-games">action</a> PS1 game from the year 2000 that I have incredibly fond memories of, is getting a Steam release next year, by Limited Run Games in collaboration with Square Enix. The news comes as part of the controversial (more on this in a bit) company’s digital LRG3 event. You can watch the full thing <a href="https://youtu.be/0G3umAZ-nvM">here</a>, and the Fear Effect trailer below.</p>

<figure><a href="https://youtu.be/9rnHe0UASfc">
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9rnHe0UASfc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" height="113" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" title="Fear Effect | LRG3 Reveal Trailer" width="200"></iframe><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</a></figure>
<p>If you’ve not played Fear Effect, you’d be forgiven for assuming from the trailer that it’s a standard fixed-camera action game. But its real beauty lies in influence from both survival horror and cinematic <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-platform-games-on-pc">platform games</a> like<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/another-world"> Another World</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/flashback">Flashback</a>. As you switch between characters in your gang of ne’er-do-wells at set story moments, solving puzzles and combat encounters, new screens offer up insta-death setpieces that need to be carefully considered then perfected. Fail, and you'll often be treated to one of the game's <a href="https://youtu.be/tr_btcSxMP0">dozens of unique death animations.</a></p>
<p>As a consequence of said death scenes and many others, Fear Effect came on four discs. I distinctly remember starting a lending chain with two of my mates where one would complete one disc then lend it on to the next. This was logistically irritating but I did not mind. I simply wished more people to play Fear Effect, altruistic videogame paragon that I am. I cannot take full public responsibility for the game coming to Steam, although I can write *wink wink* and let you decide who the <em>real </em>hero is here (disclosure: I had nothing to do with it.) The closest thing we’ve had to the series on PC for many years now is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fear-effect-sedna">Fear Effect Sedna</a>, which emulates very little of what was good about Fear Effect and its sequel, Retro Helix.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the LRG3 showcase, we got trailers for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/beyond-good-and-evil">Beyond Good &amp; Evil</a> - 20th Anniversary Edition (<a href="https://youtu.be/CaU4tMuvvdc">25th June</a>!), a new edition of <a href="https://youtu.be/PA2GwYOIqCw">Fighting Force</a> (Fighting Force!), and a <a href="https://youtu.be/ixbqTAPCApQ">new trailer</a> for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/clock-tower">Clock Tower: Rewind</a>, alongside several others.</p>
<p>Before you throw any money at Limited Games, though, it’s worth highlighting some recent controversy around the company, who primarily offer special edition re-releases of older or indie games. Earlier this year <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/limited-run-games-apologizes-for-cd-r-discs-after-fan-outcry-says-its-working-on-pressed-disc-solution">they apologised</a> for shipping faulty CD-R’s of the 3DO game D. The company has also been criticised for creating somewhat of a for-profit walled garden, <a href="https://x.com/ellaguro/status/1404540426485485568">antithetical to game preservation through promoting scarcity</a>, alongside various other quality control issues. However, it’s also worth noting that a lot of bad blood against the company has been drummed up by right wingers unhappy with them for <a href="https://x.com/LimitedRunGames/status/1611492929331240961">letting go of a social media manager</a> accused of transphobia last year.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crash Bandicoot N.Sane Trilogy Has Sold Through Over 20 Million Units]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-has-sold-through-over-20-million-units/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-has-sold-through-over-20-million-units.907551/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-has-sold-through-over-20-million-units/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, we learned from the official franchise Twitter/X account that Crash Bandicoot N.Sane Trilogy has now sold through over 20 million units.</p>
<p>Crash Bandicoot N.Sane Trilogy is a collection of remasters of classic platformers, originally released in 2017 for PlayStation 4 and the following year on PC, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch. It was developed by Vicarious Visions (now known as Blizzard Albany following <a href="https://wccftech.com/crash-bandicoot-tony-hawk-vicarious-visions-no-more-blizzard-merger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an internal reorganization</a> within Activision Blizzard).</p>
<p>When the game launched on PS4, Kai Powell <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reviewed</a> the game for Wccftech, awarding it an 8.9/10 score.</p>
<p><em>What else can I say? It looks great, it sounds great and plays great, when you’re not getting ready to throw your controller in frustration from falling off that bridge one last time. All in all, Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy is one of the best remasters I’ve played in a long while and is a must-play for anyone who wants to take a trip back to their childhood. It also <a href="https://wccftech.com/activision-ceo-seeing-real-passion-crash/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">looks like</a>&nbsp;this is just the beginning for Crash...</em></p>
<p>Indeed, Crash Bandicoot received a brand new installment called <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/crash-bandicoot-4-its-about-time-modern-and-retro-crash-together-at-once/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">It's About Time</a> in 2020. Developed by Toys for Bob, it was well-received but did not sell as much as Activision Blizzard hoped, which is why we didn't get a direct sequel. Toys for Bob released the spin-off multiplayer action game <a href="https://wccftech.com/crash-team-rumble-is-all-about-taking-platforming-into-multiplayer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crash Team Rumble</a>, but that didn't make a splash, either.</p>
<p>The developer <a href="https://wccftech.com/toys-for-bobs-first-independent-game-will-still-be-with-microsoft/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has now gone independent</a>, but it made a deal with Microsoft to publish their first game. As such, it could have access to the Crash Bandicoot (or Spyro) IP, if Microsoft wants them to make another entry. Otherwise, it'll likely be a brand new intellectual property.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD fans slam ’embarrassingly low effort’ Fallout crossover skins]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/cod-fans-slam-embarrassingly-low-effort-fallout-crossover-skins/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=cod-fans-slam-embarrassingly-low-effort-fallout-crossover-skins</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-fans-slam-%E2%80%99embarrassingly-low-effort%E2%80%99-fallout-crossover-skins.907548/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/cod-fans-slam-embarrassingly-low-effort-fallout-crossover-skins/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=cod-fans-slam-embarrassingly-low-effort-fallout-crossover-skins<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="274" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Activision has followed the patch of <em>Fortnite</em> in recent years, teaming up with other gaming franchises to bring their skins to <em>Call of Duty</em>. On June 20, <em>Warzone</em> and <em>MW3</em> received a set of four <em>Fallout</em>-themed Operator outfits, which fans have labeled “low effort.”</p> <p data-characters="256" data-current-count="256" data-injectable="false">With Microsoft now the owner of both Bethesda and Activision, it was only a matter of time before we saw links form between the two. That’s come in the form of the four Operator skins, featuring <em>Modern Warfare</em> characters Price, Ghost, Soap, and Gaz. </p> <p data-characters="314" data-current-count="570" data-injectable="true">The cosmetics see the four characters dressed in the classic Vault Dweller outfits, the blue and gold jumpsuit that will be instantly recognizable to anyone who’s played the game or <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/first-fallout-reviews-say-its-one-of-the-best-game-adaptations-ever-made/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">watched the Amazon series</a>. The drop hasn’t gone down well with fans though, who have criticized the lack of creativity. </p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Fans are not impressed. Image via Activision</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="509" data-current-count="809" data-injectable="true">“Talk about low effort. They just copy-pasted the heads of the four main cast onto basically four identical bodies,” wrote punchrockchest on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CODWarzone/comments/1dkgzvt/fallout_bundle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reddit</a>. “First, using the main cast was a bad call. Second, having the heads in their full military appearance and then blue pajamas isn’t a great look. Third, why not have someone from the <em>Fallout</em> show or game? Fourth, why have only the Vault suits? There are tons of iconic suits and characters used rather than four identical outfits.”</p>
 <p data-characters="281" data-current-count="281" data-injectable="false">Kastles1 agreed, stating: “I was going to say the licensing deal probably caused it to be like this and then I thought about it and technically the same company that owns <em>Call of Duty</em> owns <em>Fallout</em>. No reason why we couldn’t get something better than what we got.”</p> <p data-characters="289" data-current-count="570" data-injectable="true">Steampunk22 was particularly frustrated, asking: “How can anyone in good conscience support this game? This is embarrassingly low effort,” while DayDreamerJon called them “terrible and low effort,” asking why there were no Ghoul, Super Mutant, or Power Armor skins.</p>
 <p data-characters="276" data-current-count="276" data-injectable="false">While this set is disappointing to some, there is a chance that this is just the beginning, and we’ll get more <em>Fallout</em>-themed cosmetics further down the road. For now, though, players are not impressed, and I doubt many will be giving up the Nuka Cola Caps for this set.</p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond Good and Evil 20th Anniversary Edition Confirmed to Launch on June 25]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/beyond-good-and-evil-20th-anniversary-edition-confirmed-to-launch-on-june-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beyond-good-and-evil-20th-anniversary-edition-confirmed-to-launch-on-june-25.907539/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/beyond-good-and-evil-20th-anniversary-edition-confirmed-to-launch-on-june-25/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ubisoft has finally confirmed the release date for Beyond Good and Evil 20th Anniversary Edition. First <a href="https://wccftech.com/beyond-good-and-evil-20th-anniversary-remaster-2024-game-leaks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced </a>by Ubisoft in late 2023, the game will debut on June 25 for PlayStation 5 &amp; PlayStation 4, Xbox Series S|X, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, Amazon Luna and PC through the Ubisoft Store, Epic Games Store and Steam. Limited Run Games is also producing a physical edition and a Collector's Edition, with pre-orders set to open on July 12.</p>
<p>The project was developed by Virtuos Games under the supervision of Ubisoft Montpellier, the current franchise steward. While not a full remaster, it will offer several improvements, as detailed in the official overview.</p>
<p><em>Players will be able to (re)discover the pioneering Action-Adventure game by exploring the wonderfully odd maritime world of Hillys in the best way possible with improved performances up to 4k, 60fps and numerous qualities of life improvements including autosave, cutscene-skip, full controller and keyboard &amp; mouse support, and cross-save across all platforms.</em></p>
<p><em>Alongside these updates, Beyond Good &amp; Evil - 20th Anniversary Edition will also introduce a new Speedrun Mode to challenge players, 20+ new achievements and an Anniversary Gallery delving deep into the game’s development history and featuring tons of never-before-seen artworks, videos and so much more.</em></p>
<p><em>Finally, this special edition will feature hunt in which players can discover more about Jade’s past and collect exclusive cosmetic rewards. This exclusive new mission also reveals more about the narrative link to Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2, showing Ubisoft’s enduring commitment to the franchise.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Beyond Good &amp; Evil - 20th Anniversary Edition: Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CaU4tMuvvdc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>That final tidbit is interesting. The release of Beyond Good &amp; Evil 20th Anniversary Edition would indeed look like Ubisoft is investing in the franchise. However, Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 is one of the most delayed games of all time at this point. The prequel was originally announced in 2008, then scrapped, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/beyond-good-and-evil-2-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resurfaced</a> in 2017 before going dark again. In September 2020, creator Michel Ancel <a href="https://wccftech.com/michel-ancel-retires-from-the-industry-wild-and-beyond-good-and-evil-2-development-to-continue/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">retired</a> from the industry, and the project took another hit in July 2023 when creative director Emile More died suddenly at the age of 40.</p>
<p>In August 2022, insider Tom Henderson <a href="https://wccftech.com/beyond-good-evil-2-reportedly-still-years-away-from-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> the game was still several years away from release, and it was once again a no-show at the Ubisoft Forward showcase earlier this month.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Soars to 600,000 Players on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-player-count-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-soars-to-600-000-players-on-steam.907536/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-player-count-steam/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Shadow of the Erdtree is here and it’s already doing bits for Elden Ring’s player count. On Steam, the peak concurrent player count in the last 24 hours sat at a whopping 589,948 users – a week ago, that was 174,000 concurrent users, and a few months back, it sat at around 35,000 players. That’s indicative of the game’s performance across all platforms, as Shadow of the Erdtree has now been released and is already cementing itself as one of the greatest expansions of all time.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-high-numbers">High Numbers</h2>



<p>Elden Ring’s all-time high player count on Steam sits at a staggering 953,426, and that was secured just after the game was released in February 2022. On the popular PC platform, Elden Ring has remained relatively consistent since it dropped, sitting around the top of the table and never falling below a peak concurrent count of 30,000 in a month. That’s huge staying power for any game – and it’s one of the reasons why Elden Ring has 93% positive reviews on Steam.</p>



<p>Shadow of the Erdtree is out today on all platforms, and players are <strong>excited</strong>. It’s a super-sized DLC with a premium price point of $39.99, but it’s worth the investment considering all that the expansion offers. However, some fans have expressed their disappointment in one aspect: Shadow of the Erdtree doesn’t have any new achievements or trophies. It’s a small thing that won’t detract from the overall quality of the expansion, but it seems like an oversight given the size of the DLC.</p>



<p>Are you jumping into Shadow of the Erdtree today? Let us know in the comments.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out what&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-good-asus-rog-ally-one-year-later/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">we think of the Asus ROG Ally one year</a>&nbsp;after launch, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox to attend Gamescom 2024 | News-in-brief]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/xbox-to-attend-gamescom-2024-news-in-brief</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-to-attend-gamescom-2024-news-in-brief.907533/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/xbox-to-attend-gamescom-2024-news-in-brief<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p>The resource for people who make and sell games.</p>

  

  <p>GamesIndustry.biz is owned by Gamer Network Limited.</p>
  <p>© 2024 Gamer Network Limited, 1-6 Grand Parade, Brighton, BN2 9QB, United Kingdom. Registered under company number 03882481.</p>
  <p>All rights reserved. No part of this website or its content may be reproduced without the copyright owner's permission.</p>


  <nav>
    <ul>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://www.facebook.com/gamesindustry" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="facebook" data-type="facebook" aria-label="Check us out on Facebook">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on Facebook"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://twitter.com/GIBiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="x-twitter" data-type="twitter" aria-label="Check us out on X">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on X"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/gamesindustrybiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="linkedin" data-type="linkedin" aria-label="Check us out on LinkedIn">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on LinkedIn"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/feed" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="rss" data-type="rss" aria-label="Subscribe to our RSS feed" type="application/rss+xml">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Subscribe to our RSS feed"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://mastodon.social/@GIbiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="mastodon" data-type="mastodon" aria-label="Check us out on Mastodon">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on Mastodon"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
    </ul>
  </nav>
      </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shadow of the Erdtree Has No New Trophies or Achievements]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-no-trophies-achievements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadow-of-the-erdtree-has-no-new-trophies-or-achievements.907524/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-no-trophies-achievements/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Shadow of the Erdtree, the massive and highly anticipated expansion for Elden Ring, is being released today. However, it has been noted that the super-sized DLC doesn’t have any new trophies or achievements for players to unlock. That’s par for the course with FromSoft games, but it’s still a disappointment to those gamers who seek the extra challenge of ticking those collector-based boxes.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-finally-here">Finally Here</h2>



<p>It has been more than two years since Elden Ring was released to an overwhelmingly positive reception, stunning gamers worldwide. For the longest time, FromSoftware has been cooking on Shadow of the Erdtree, one of the most eagerly anticipated DLCs to emerge in recent years for <strong>any </strong>game. It’s a whopping investment at $39.99, but Elden Ring fans will tell you that it’s more than worth the money.</p>



<p>However, the expansion – which is around 16 GB in size – will feature plenty of content but nothing in the way of new PlayStation Trophies or Xbox Achievements. That’s a hit for those who play games <strong>specifically to unlock </strong>these rewards that many class as outdated or unnecessary. To each his own, right?</p>



<p>Are you particularly bothered by the fact that there are no new achievements or trophies for Shadow of the Erdtree? Let us know in the comments below.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-onlines-bottom-dollar-bounties-update-arrives-on-june-25/">next GTA Online update</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bethesda Files Trademark for New id-Tech Powered IP “Motor”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bethesda-files-trademark-for-new-id-tech-powered-ip-motor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bethesda-files-trademark-for-new-id-tech-powered-ip-%E2%80%9Cmotor%E2%80%9D.907521/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/bethesda-files-trademark-for-new-id-tech-powered-ip-motor/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Zenimax, Bethesda's parent company, has seemingly filed a new trademark application for a new Id-tech powered IP "Motor".</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/bogorad222/status/1803829839259914584" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Spotted</a> by @Bogorad222 on X, the <a href="https://trademarks.justia.com/986/07/motor-powered-by-98607273.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new trademark application</a> was filed some days ago on June 18. As most of you will know, id-Tech is id Software's proprietary game engine with the studio reportedly recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/id-software-id-tech-8/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">having shifted</a> to id-Tech 8. 2020's amazing <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/doom-eternal-review" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Doom Eternal</a> runs on id Sofware's Id-tech 7. No further details about the new "Motor" trademark have been shared just yet, but fans have already been speculating that the trademark might very well be related to a new Rage entry. Of course, it could also be related to a new id-Tech spin-off engine. We've included a screenshot of the trademark application below:</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/motor-bethesda-id-tech-id-software.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Earlier this month, Microsoft and Bethesda officially announced Doom: The Dark Ages, and it will be interesting to learn which version of id Software's engine this new Doom will use.</p>
<p>Doom: The Dark Ages is coming to Xbox, PlayStation 5, and PC sometime next year. We've included the action-packed announcement trailer alongside some additional details about the game below:</p>
<p><iframe title="DOOM: The Dark Ages | Official Trailer 1 | Coming 2025 - Xbox Games Showcase 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CpgAOAOMUnA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Enter the Realm of the Gods, Kings, and the Slayer -&nbsp;</strong>The Doom Slayer stares down the viewer, lit by flames in the background. Wage war as one man matched against Hell’s legions in a dark fantasy setting expanding the Doom universe. Witness the origin of the Slayer’s rage and his rise from a kingdom’s last hope to Hell’s greatest fear in this pulse-pounding, cinematic prequel to Doom (2016) and Doom Eternal.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Face the hordes with Shield Saw and Flail in hand - A</strong>&nbsp;village is besieged by demonic forces as artillery streaks across the night sky. Blast, bludgeon, bisect and break through the enemy ranks using the Slayer’s superhuman strength, lethal arsenal and unmet tenacity. Supplement your trusty Super Shotgun with The Dark Ages’ new weaponry, including the face-shattering Flail and revved-up, throwable Shield Saw. Inspired by the original 1993 Doom, players overcome the odds in The Dark Ages in firmly grounded, heavy-hitting clashes featuring destructible demons, vicious melee strikes and more. With the right combination of ranged bombardment &amp; melee aggression, anyone stepping into the Slayer’s boots will make Hell quiver in theirs.</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Command colossal machines and winged beasts -&nbsp;</strong>The building-sized Atlan mech imposes from above. DOOM: The Dark Ages’ cosmic-scale conflict calls for the heaviest ordnance possible, and the Slayer heeds. Enter the cockpit of your Atlan - a daunting skyscraper-sized mech capable of toppling Hell’s behemoths with titanic metal fists - and reclaim the skies aboard the Slayer’s Mecha Dragon, strapped to the jaws with massive jet engines and overwhelming firepower.</em></li>
</ul>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Another World” From Super Mario Odyssey: A Review]]></title>
            <link>https://vgbees.com/another-world-from-super-mario-odyssey-a-review/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=another-world-from-super-mario-odyssey-a-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%9Canother-world%E2%80%9D-from-super-mario-odyssey-a-review.907503/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://vgbees.com/another-world-from-super-mario-odyssey-a-review/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=another-world-from-super-mario-odyssey-a-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-midnight="dark" data-remove-post-date="0" data-remove-post-author="0" data-remove-post-comment-number="1">

		
		<div>

			<p id="breadcrumbs"><span><span><a href="https://vgbees.com/">Home</a></span> » <span aria-current="page">“Another World” From Super Mario Odyssey: A Review</span></span></p>
			<div role="main">

			
<article id="post-6351">
  
  <div data-padding-pos="all" data-has-bg-color="false" data-bg-color="" data-bg-opacity="1" data-animation="" data-delay="0" id="fws_6675754452185" data-column-margin="default" data-midnight="dark" data-hide-featured-media="0">
				
	<div>
		<p>
			<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NKjx_-Wv1Uw?si=RIV76wimx1GbuQO7" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
		</p>
	</div>
<div> 
<h2>“Another World” From Super Mario Odyssey: A Review</h2>
<p><em>Super Mario Odyssey&nbsp;</em>(Switch, 2017) </p></div><div data-icon-color="default" data-icon-style="border" data-columns="3" data-direction="vertical" data-icon-size="large" data-animate=""><div><h4>Captures the familiar feeling of slipping into the unknown</h4><p>You know, like Brooklyn plumbers do!</p></div><div><h4>Good for exploring an endless void surrounded by clouds past which you cannot perceive</h4><p>Like plumbers like to explore!</p></div><div><h4>Goombas probably here</h4><p>Like plumbers attract!</p></div><div><h4>9.1 / 10</h4><p>Try falling asleep listening to this it'll make you dream stuff you'll be afraid to tell your therapist (complimentary)</p></div></div>
			</div><!--/inner-wrap-->
    
</article>
<!--/author-bio-->

		</div><!--/post-area-->

			
				<!--/sidebar-->

			
		</div><!--/row-->

		<div data-using-post-pagination="false" data-midnight="dark">  <h3>Related Posts</h3><div data-style="material" data-color-scheme="light">
						<div>

								<p><a href="https://vgbees.com/damnds-butt-situation-a-review/"><span></span></a>
								<span><a href="https://vgbees.com/category/stingers/">Stingers</a></span>
								<a href="https://vgbees.com/damnds-butt-situation-a-review/" aria-label="Damnd’s Butt Situation: A Review"></a></p><div>
										<h3>Damnd’s Butt Situation: A Review</h3>
																			</div>

								
							</div>
						
						
						
						<div>

								<p><a href="https://vgbees.com/playing-virtual-boy-in-a-toys-r-us-until-you-feel-like-youre-gonna-throw-up-a-review/"><span></span></a>
								<span><a href="https://vgbees.com/category/stingers/">Stingers</a></span>
								<a href="https://vgbees.com/playing-virtual-boy-in-a-toys-r-us-until-you-feel-like-youre-gonna-throw-up-a-review/" aria-label="Playing Virtual Boy in a Toys R Us Until You Feel Like You’re Gonna Throw Up: A Review"></a></p><div>
										<h3>Playing Virtual Boy in a Toys R Us Until You Feel Like You’re Gonna Throw Up: A Review</h3>
																			</div>

								
							</div>
						</div></div><!--/row-->

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Damnd’s Butt Situation: A Review]]></title>
            <link>https://vgbees.com/damnds-butt-situation-a-review/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=damnds-butt-situation-a-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/damnd%E2%80%99s-butt-situation-a-review.907473/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://vgbees.com/damnds-butt-situation-a-review/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=damnds-butt-situation-a-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-6330">
  
  <div data-hide-featured-media="0">
		<div id="fws_6675754500206" data-column-margin="default" data-midnight="dark"><div data-padding-pos="all" data-has-bg-color="false" data-bg-color="" data-bg-opacity="1" data-animation="" data-delay="0">
				<div> 
<h2>Damd’s Butt Situation: A Review</h2>
<p><em>Street Fighter 6</em> (PC, 2023) </p></div><div data-icon-color="default" data-icon-style="border" data-columns="3" data-direction="vertical" data-icon-size="large" data-animate=""><div><h4>I was unfamiliar with your work</h4><p>1989’s&nbsp;<em>Final Fight</em> didn’t really give us the right angles or fidelity</p></div><div><h4>More like Meatro City, amirite?</h4><p>Mad Gear Gang haha</p></div><div><h4>Attached to a professional kidnapper</h4><p>Too bad</p></div><div><h4>7.8 / 10</h4><p>We appreciate a good butt around here even if they belong to low level crime bosses</p></div></div>
			</div></div>
<div><h4>Tags:</h4><p><a href="https://vgbees.com/tag/final-fight/" rel="tag">Final Fight</a><a href="https://vgbees.com/tag/street-fighter-6/" rel="tag">Street Fighter 6</a></p></div> </div><!--/inner-wrap-->
    
</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>