<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:51:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Enough is Enough!” Ubisoft Worker Unions Call for Strike in Response to Layoffs and Mandatory RTO]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/enough-is-enough-ubisoft-worker-unions-call-for-strike-in-response-to-layoffs-and-mandatory-rto/</link>
            <guid>1418596</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Ubisoft's</strong> recently announced <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-major-reset-cancels-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake/">"<em><strong>major reset</strong></em>"</a> continues to ripple through the video game industry, and now it has led to what was arguably an inevitable point in this story, as French unions representing Ubisoft workers, namely <strong>Syndicat des Travailleurs et Travailleuses du jeu Vidéo (STJV), Solidaires Informatique, la CFE-CGC, CGT</strong>, and <strong>Printemps écologique</strong>, have called for a <strong>strike</strong> in response to the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-more-layoffs-return-to-office-mandate/">recent layoffs, studio closures, and the proposed end to remote work policies under a return-to-office mandate</a>. </p>



<p>The strike called by the French unions will be a three-day event, taking place on <strong>February 10, 11, </strong>and <strong>12,</strong> with the unions calling for all Ubisoft workers worldwide to join them in the demonstration. It's also not the only demonstration planned, as the <strong>CWA Canada</strong> is <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cwacanada1.bsky.social/post/3mdggnk5yos26">set to hold a rally in Halifax this coming <strong>Thursday, January 29, 2026</strong></a><strong>,</strong> in solidarity with the workers <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-shuts-down-ubisoft-halifax-claims-decision-had-nothing-to-do-with-studio-unionizing/">who were laid off when Ubisoft shut down its Halifax studio earlier this month</a>.</p>



<p>"<em>Enough is enough!</em>" begins a collaborative statement from the STJV and the aforementioned French unions. "<em>Faced with the arbitrary decision of the CEO who doesn't even dare talking to employees anymore, unions are calling for a strike on February 10th, 11th, and 12th</em>."</p>







<p>The statement shared goes on to further call out Ubisoft's chief executive officer, <strong>Yves Guillemot</strong>, claiming that he and Ubisoft management are going back on a remote work policy deal that was in place since <strong>September 2025</strong>, and further calls out the company's top brass for not taking responsibility for their actions that have led to this major restructure. A fair point to make, since you might recall that Guillemot and the current Ubisoft leadership led the company to lose <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-lost-nearly-95-of-value-in-eight-years-34-share-price-drop-after-major-reset/">95% of its total value in the last eight years</a>.</strong></p>



<p>"<em>We are told about responsibilities,</em> <em>but those who wield this word so easily do not take any responsibility for the consequences of their catastrophic management, the latest result being the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-launches-voluntary-layoff-program-ubisoft-paris/">elimination of 200 jobs at Ubisoft's headquarters</a></em>."</p>



<p>Prior to this strike call, earlier this week, French union Solidaires Informatique <a href="https://wccftech.com/french-union-claims-ubisoft-ceo-has-no-knowledge-or-understanding-of-his-company-after-major-reset/">directly called out Guillemot for having "<em>no knowledge or understanding of his company</em>."</a></p>



<p>Ubisoft's "<em>major reset</em>" reorganized the company into five Creative Houses, with its various branching studios across the world put into at least one of the five houses, if they survived the restructure. Ubisoft claims the Halifax and Stockholm studio shutdowns were part of this restructure, as were layoffs announced last year at <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-massive-entertainment-layoffs/">Massive Entertainment</a> </strong>and<strong> <a href="https://wccftech.com/trials-rising-developer-ubisoft-redlynx-layoff-60-developers-amidst-shift-to-small-screens/">RedLynx</a></strong>. We also know that the restructure is responsible for pushing out senior veteran talent at Ubisoft, with the company losing its lead on <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/former-assassins-creed-series-boss-didnt-choose-to-leave-ubisoft-asked-me-to-step-aside/">Assassin's Creed</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-tells-the-division-players-dont-worry-series-producer-julian-gerighty-leaves-for-battlefield/">The Division</a></strong>. The former is <a href="https://wccftech.com/former-assassins-creed-boss-marc-alexis-cote-sues-ubisoft-1-3-million/">even suing Ubisoft for "<em>constructive dismissal</em>."</a></p>



<p>The reset also saw six projects get cancelled, including the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/breathtaking-leaked-pre-alpha-images-of-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-are-salt-in-the-wound-for-fans-in-mourning/">Prince of Persia: Sands of Time Remake</a></strong> and seven more delayed, reportedly including the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-ubisoft/">Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag Remake</a></strong>. In all of this mess, however, <a href="https://wccftech.com/beyond-good-and-evil-2-still-in-development-after-ubisoft-major-reset/"><strong>Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2</strong> survived</a>, and is still in production, according to Ubisoft.</p>



<p>It's still early days as to how the dust will settle with this restructure. While French unions put pressure on Ubisoft in the company's home country, the CWA Canada <a href="https://wccftech.com/cwa-canada-files-complaint-ubisoft-halifax-closure-ubisoft-1-billion-tax-subsidies/">continues to apply pressure to the Nova Scotia government and the Canadian public to carefully scrutinize the closure of the Halifax studio,</a> pressure that has already resulted in Ubisoft reconsidering the severance package it would offer workers. The union has also <a href="https://ubisoftworkerscanada.com/">kicked off a letter-writing campaign and published a timeline outlining why it believes the closure to be suspect</a>, as the Nova Scotia Labour Board investigates.</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Wccftech for further reporting on the situation at Ubisoft as it develops.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/enough-is-enough-ubisoft-worker-unions-call-for-strike-in-response-to-layoffs-and-mandatory-rto/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scott Pilgrim EX Release Date Revealed for March, Two New Characters Unveiled]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/scott-pilgrim-ex-release-date-march</link>
            <guid>1418593</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Retro-style brawler <em>Scott Pilgrim EX </em>now has a release date, developer and publisher Tribute Games has announced, and the studio has also revealed two more fighters joining the side-scroller's roster.</p><p>According to a new official trailer, <em>Scott Pilgrim EX </em>will be arriving across PC and consoles on March 3rd, and what's more, two erstwhile foes, Matthew Patel and Robot-01, will be available to play as if you're looking for allies.</p><p>They'll join a roster that also includes playable characters from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/scott-pilgrim-vs-world-game-complete-edition-launches-january-14" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="58de8c13-490f-4d7e-9d00-eb4a7768921a" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Scott Pilgrim vs. the World: The Game</em></a>, like Scott himself and Ramona Flowers, although iconic characters like Knives Chau and Wallace Weldon won't be playable in the game.</p><p>If you're not familiar with <em>Scott Pilgrim EX</em>, it's a brand new side-scrolling beat-'em-up from <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-shredders-revenge" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="0e3ecb91-e301-4ac1-ab70-91478adfdd1a" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Shredder's Revenge</em></a><em> </em>and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-cosmic-invasion-release-date" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3239c132-009d-45e4-bbaa-cf2539d52c49" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</em></a><em> </em>studio Tribute Games.</p><p>Although the name might suggest otherwise, <em>Scott Pilgrim EX </em>isn't an expanded re-release of Ubisoft's rather excellent 2010 side-scroller <em>Scott Pilgrim vs. the World: The Game</em>; instead, it's a completely new title, and it boasts an all-new story penned by series creator Bryan Lee O'Malley.</p><p>Gameplay-wise, as you've probably come to expect from Tribute Games, you can expect chaotic pixel-based side-scrolling action, with screens full of enemies to defeat and retro art to enjoy, plus tons of classic video game references.</p><p>Not only that, but each playthrough allows you to collect and spend coins to upgrade your characters and equip special items, leading to the potential for "a unique build for every playthrough", as Tribute tells it.</p><p>You can check out the new release date trailer for <em>Scott Pilgrim EX</em>, which also shows off Matthew Patel and Robot-01, right here.</p>
<p><em>Scott Pilgrim EX </em>is set to arrive on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2640950/Scott_Pilgrim_EX/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10014026" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/scott-pilgrim-ex/9p8rfn5p0423" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/scott-pilgrim-ex-switch/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Switch</a> on March 3rd. If you're in the mood for some time-traveling, why not check out <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/scott-pilgrim-vs-world-game-complete-edition-review" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="cac4817f-d04b-4322-8eec-0befaf0d8a91" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">our review</a> of <em>Scott Pilgrim vs. the World: The Game - Complete Edition </em>from back in 2021?</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/scott-pilgrim-ex-release-date-march]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Train 2 Sales Reach 500k as First DLC Gears Up for February Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-train-2-sales-500k-first-dlc</link>
            <guid>1418590</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Monster Train 2 </em>is getting its first major DLC expansion next week, publisher Devolver Digital and developer Shiny Shoe have revealed, and the game has passed a major sales milestone as well.</p><p>Per a press release, <em>Monster Train 2 </em>sales have hit 500,000 since <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-train-2-announced-demo-now" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="f1249bf7-838d-4c91-b336-cd737e3f57ed" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">the game</a> launched in May last year, which puts the deckbuilding card battler on par with fellow hits like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/no-im-not-a-human-500k-sales" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="d5684c77-487f-4888-bbf9-847c5d9828ec" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>No, I'm Not a Human</em></a><em> </em>and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/inazuma-eleven-victory-road-sales-500k" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="60aad754-fdd9-4d60-bb74-1251bf703db7" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road</em></a>.</p><p>Alongside celebrating the new sales milestone, Devolver and Shiny Shoe also revealed <em>Destiny of the Railforged</em>, the first major <em>Monster Train 2 </em>expansion. It's set to arrive on February 2nd (that's next Monday at time of writing).</p><p>The DLC will bring a new game mode to <em>Monster Train 2</em>, in which you'll be battling bosses in "any order you wish" and using the souls you gain from those bosses to boost the power of your deck.</p><p>Shiny Shoe and Devolver are promising "a challenge wholly unique from the base game" in the Soul Savior mode, as well as a new cosmic setting that lets you loose on both familiar faces and entirely new monsters.</p><p>A brand new clan, the Railforged, will also be joining the fray, with two new playable characters representing said clan: Herzal, the blacksmith who made your train, and Heph, who built the game's Skullcrusher engine.</p><p>Even if you're not planning to pick up <em>Monster Train 2</em>'s <em>Destiny of the Railforged </em>DLC, you can look forward to a free update that reintroduces the Wurmkin clan from the original <em>Monster Train</em>. All players can enjoy that update without paying a penny.</p>
<p>If you're wondering exactly what <em>Monster Train 2 </em>is, it's the followup to the original <em>Monster Train</em>, and like its predecessor, it's a roguelike deckbuilder in which you'll be doing battle with a variety of infernal foes through card-based combat.</p><p>You can check out <em>Monster Train 2 </em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2742830/Monster_Train_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10012399" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation 5</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/monster-train-2/9NJC29JG70LM" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/monster-train-2-switch/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Switch</a>, and you can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/monster-train-2-review-to-hell-and-back" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3a2bd1e6-1b9d-413f-b649-92b14caafc0f" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">check out our review here</a>.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-train-2-sales-500k-first-dlc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dwarf Legacy turns Tolkien's sturdy miners into bullet hell mountaineers - don't mythril the demo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-legacy-turns-tolkiens-sturdy-miners-into-bullet-hell-mountaineers-dont-mythril-the-demo</link>
            <guid>1418584</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarflegacy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarflegacy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarflegacy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarflegacy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarflegacy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarflegacy.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarflegacy.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarflegacy.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarflegacy.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Wulo Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Remember in The Lord Of The Rings: The Two Towers when Gandalf falls down the big chasm with the Balrog, smacking the sawdust out of it while plummeting towards the waters of the underworld? Well, give Gandalf a gun, play that sequence in reverse, and swap the Balrog for a flock of Space Invaders, and you are playing something like the demo for Dwarf Legacy – a “bullet-hell precision platformer” from Wulo Games about a dwarf clambering up the inside of a mountain. </p>
<p>Oh wait, Gandalf needs to be listening to crunchy dancefloor music to complete the analogy. Also, he needs to stop periodically to buy better guns from a blacksmith. I’m pretty sure this is still within Peter Jackson’s budget.</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dwarf Legacy - Vertical Climb Gameplay" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JOa8XpNFfPI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dwarf Legacy - Vertical Climb Gameplay</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JOa8XpNFfPI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JOa8XpNFfPI?autoplay=1" title="Dwarf Legacy - Vertical Climb Gameplay">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JOa8XpNFfPI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>“Bullet-hell precision platformer” is a verbal fondue calculated to give you palpitations, so it’s alarming that Dwarf Legacy feels very easy, to begin with. Your jump is insanely floaty, and you can stick to walls without worrying about stamina. This isn’t exactly your classic, slow-moving, hard-wearing Dwarven miner. Even Legolas wasn’t this quick on his pins.</p><p>The odds soon steepen, however. The gun, once acquired, can only be shot in fixed directions – vertically, if you’re jumping or standing on the floor, or horizontally, if you’re hanging from a wall. Upgrade the gun to fire an extra bullet per shot, and the additional rounds shoot out parallel or at 45 degree diagonals, as with multishot upgrades in shmups.</p>
<p>Those constraints are all fine and dandy when you’re only fighting a handful of foes, and have room to manoeuvre. But when you’re dogfighting with a crowd in cramped confines, while avoiding spinning blade traps and spikes… yes, this is a test of Dawi mettle indeed. Fortunately, enemies take damage from traps, and have deliberately brainless pathfinding - some gauntlet runs encourage you to lure them to their destruction.</p>
<p>Between clambers, you’ll return to and gradually populate a cave village of upgrade-peddling NPCs. There’s some gently diverting writing, like the botanist who’s ecstatic at the chance to grow vegetables in pitch darkness. Another dweller offers optional challenges to encourage replay of completed areas, on top of the bonuses you'll earn from a higher completion score.</p><p> 

The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2426280/Dwarf_Legacy/">full version of Dwarf Legacy</a> is out later this year, and will offer a few dozen levels across several distinct chunks of mountain strata. Oh, I forgot to mention a couple of Neat things. Firstly, when you grab a surface your character automatically plants a torch, lighting the level in an organic way.
</p><p>Secondly, when you take damage, it dings your helmet off rather than killing you. You can reclaim your helmet to restore that diegetic second chance mechanic. I’d almost beaten the 10th level in the demo, but then some stinkbug bonked my hat off a precipice and I chased it almost all the way to the bottom. Fun! It occurs to me that Gandalf lost his hat during the Balrog descent, and somehow reached the bottom unscathed – truly, he is the, er, Dwarf Legacy of wizards.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-legacy-turns-tolkiens-sturdy-miners-into-bullet-hell-mountaineers-dont-mythril-the-demo]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Razer Wireless Gaming Headsets Are 50% Off on Amazon, the BlackShark V2 Pro Is Officially Licensed for Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/razer-wireless-gaming-headsets-are-50-off-on-amazon-the-blackshark-v2-pro-is-officially-licensed-for-xbox-2000663643</link>
            <guid>1418575</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The Razer BlackShark V2 Pro Wireless Xbox Gaming Headset is an over-the-head headset that keeps your Xbox games sounding as they should and keeps your whole setup cable-free. Memory foam ear cups provide good noise isolation. 50mm drivers have been tuned to produce clear high notes and strong bass, and there is a HyperClear Super Wideband Detachable Microphone for clear communication with your team. The lightweight headband design has been optimized to let you play for many hours, and the headset will remain comfortable on your head with minimal visual bulk.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6921/">You can go to Amazon now to buy the Razer BlackShark V2 Pro Wireless Xbox Gaming Headset for $100, reduced from $200, for a total savings of $100 and 50%.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6921/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A wireless headset perfect for gamers of all skill levels</h2>
<p>The ear cups of the Razer BlackShark V2 Pro Wireless Xbox Gaming Headset feature closed-back designs with memory foam cushions that fit snugly against your ears, reducing ambient noise and distractions. The breathable fabric used to complete the ear cup is designed to keep your skin cool and dry, and the cup itself is styled simply so you can use the headset with either your Xbox or your laptop to watch movies and TV shows.</p>
<p>The audio settings have been adjusted to let you hear every detail of your games with clarity and without excessive volume. Footsteps, character abilities, background noises, and other elements will be able to stand out in the audio mix better than ever before, and voices will always be easy to listen to, whether they come from a character, teammate, or opponent.</p>



<p>The HyperClear Super Wideband Microphone has been designed to capture a wider frequency range of your voice, so it always sounds natural and not muffled when you’re communicating with your team members via party chat or competing in tournaments. Additionally, the microphone is completely removable, making it easy to remove when you don’t need to communicate with others or when you’re just listening to music and podcasts.</p>
<p>Razer HyperSpeed Wireless utilizes a 2.4 GHz wireless connection to ensure that the audio remains synchronized to what you see on the screen, even during fast-paced gameplay. The availability of Bluetooth support provides you with additional wireless connectivity options for phones, tablets, and handheld game consoles, and USB-C charging will make sure that you never run out of power because a full charge can last for up to 70 hours of use on your computer or up to 48 hours of use on your Xbox.</p>
<p>Because the Razer BlackShark V2 Pro Wireless Xbox Gaming Headset is compatible with Xbox, PlayStation, Nintendo Switch 2, PC, and Mac, you can make it your go-to audio device. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6921/">With the current sale price of $100 compared to the usual retail price of $200</a>, you’ll receive long battery life, a comfortable fit due to noise-isolating memory foam ear cups, the flexibility of multiple wireless connectivity options, and a clear, detachable microphone to go along with a great-looking, sleek headset that will fit seamlessly into your gaming setup.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6921/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/razer-wireless-gaming-headsets-are-50-off-on-amazon-the-blackshark-v2-pro-is-officially-licensed-for-xbox-2000663643]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 Director Calls For Civility As Highguard Gets Savaged: ‘Be Nice To The People Creating Stuff’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bg3-swen-vincke-highguard-concord-steam-reviews-metacritic-2000663800</link>
            <guid>1418572</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The launch of <em>Highguard</em> this week has reignited a debate around good manners. Over a hundred people worked for several years on a project they were passionate about. Instead of everyone giving it a fair shake and casually talking about what they did or didn’t like about it, the conversation around the new multiplayer shooter was quickly subsumed by a torrent of knee-jerk negativity. Social media is full of people dunking on the game for clout and Steam reviews are full of users who barely touched it on PC before rushing to grade it almost entirely based on hardware performance.</p> <p>It’s the culmination of an increasingly fractured online ecosystem whose only unifying forces are algorithms that reward rage-bait and endless free content that incentivizes harsh snap judgements in order to sort through it all. If you’re not first, you’re last. If you’re not the best, who cares? The swift, loud, and in many cases overly <a href="https://kotaku.com/geoff-keighley-highguard-game-awards-trailer-hate-2000663574">toxic reaction to <em>Highguard</em></a> has some developers concerned, disgusted, and confused.</p>

 <p>“I don’t like people shitting on things others have created,” <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em> director and Larian Studios CEO Swen Vincke <a href="https://x.com/LarAtLarian/status/2016281728755576974">wrote on X</a> last night. He spent most of his short “soapbox” speech talking about game reviews, which seem completely tangential to what’s going on with <em>Highguard</em> at the moment. He wants them to be less mean and personal; most fans wants them to feel less inflated and overly deferential to the publishers behind the product. But importantly, almost no one has actually <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/highguard/">even reviewed <em>Highguard</em> yet</a>. Maybe we wait for it to get a Metacritic score before we start assigning one to all of its critics, another one of Vincke’s suggestions.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I don’t like people shitting on things others have created. Putting something out into the world makes you vulnerable, and that alone deserves respect, even if you dislike the creation. It’s easy to destroy things, it’s a lot harder to build them. The best critics understand…</p> <p>— Swen Vincke @where? (@LarAtLarian) <a href="https://twitter.com/LarAtLarian/status/2016281728755576974?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 27, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Nevertheless, the veteran RPG maker ended with <a href="https://kotaku.com/divinity-gen-ai-larian-bg3-reddit-ama-2000658429">a call for more civility</a>. “It’s been on my mind for a while and just opening my feed today just pushed it all to the surface,” he wrote. “Think of the time you had to recite something in front of the class and how nervous you were. And how much any negative comment hurt.&nbsp;Be nice to one another, be nice to the people creating stuff to entertain you. Treat them like you would like to be treated if you made something.”</p>

 <p>Vincke wasn’t the only one ruffled. “When did it become trendy to hate on a new game?” <a href="https://x.com/therealcliffyb/status/2016245017073877329">wrote</a> Cliff Bleszinski on X. “Been seeing it more and more in recent years. It’s exhausting.” Epic Games co-founder Mark Reign <a href="https://x.com/markrein/status/2016346300367729008">quoted-tweeted him</a>: “It’s downright horrible. Especially a FREE game from a new studio. Just so sad. This is a hobby for people, they should approach with joy not hatred.”</p>

 <p>Remedy Entertainment Communications Director Thomas Puha was disheartened by how player counts have become weaponized against games in recent years. “Tired of seeing headlines of how many players<em> Highguard</em> has lost,” he <a href="https://x.com/riotrmd/status/2016431155524809143">posted</a>. “Like, sure, you can argue that’s putting facts out there, but I cant escape the feeling there’s just this ‘celebration’ of a game doing badly and just putting out negative headlines for the sake of it. Shouldn’t us game devs even try?”</p> <h2>Another hero shooter meltdown</h2> <p>We could try to psychoanalyze why the online gamer id has latched onto these narratives so zealously rather than just, you know, play the games and enjoy them or move on. Part of it is no doubt an ongoing backlash against the very concept of live-service games. Despite being far and away the most played and profitable genre, there’s a certain type of player that resents the gravity well they’ve created. For one swath of YouTube culture war peddlers, <em>Concord</em>‘s failure was celebrated as a defeat for progressive values in the marketplace. But for others it became symbolic vindication that all of these companies pumping resources into microtransaction casinos were idiots to do so.</p>

 <p>Perhaps they’re simply exhausted with the modern live-service game trying to take over their life and their wallet. Once upon a time, the big scandal was publishers using sticks (single-use multiplayer codes) and carrots (bonus DLC) to get people to stop buying used games. Now the sale of most games is inconsequential. The real bucks are made in the in-game shop and the only way to keep making them is to keep people playing as much as possible. For fans of forever games who love hanging out with their friends in them, no harm done. For someone who doesn’t want their hobby to become like a second job, it’s easy to see where burnout and backlash might ensue.</p> <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:aa23o5w4w2afknay44oqxqz6/app.bsky.feed.post/3mdhctp2krs27" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreido643tuq2buamxesheusn2qdf6afvac2dbcuhe3mcmtoe6zggxoe"> <p lang="en">Try a couple decades of shitty emails ranging from simple insults all the way up to death threats from idiot fanboys who can't handle you giving a game "only" 8/10 and see which one puts more calluses on your soul, dummy. You'd fold in six months or less.</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:aa23o5w4w2afknay44oqxqz6?ref_src=embed">Jeff Gerstmann (@jeffgerstmann.com)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:aa23o5w4w2afknay44oqxqz6/post/3mdhctp2krs27?ref_src=embed">2026-01-28T03:18:56.524Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <p>It does not help that <em>Highguard</em>, despite being inspired by games like <em>Rust</em>, sounds like a knock-off of <em>Overwatch</em> and includes some very generic-looking characters to boot. Made by some of the leads on <em>Apex Legends</em>, the contrast between the launches of those two multiplayer games shows not just a possible increase in live-service fatigue in the intervening years but also the decay of the wider ecosystem where all of those issues get hashed out. “Covid transformed social media into an endless, awful conversation; once you pop, the horrors never stop,” writes <a href="https://aftermath.site/highguard-release-steam-pc-concord-youtube-shadow-drop/">Nathan Grayson at <em>Aftermath</em></a>. He adds, “Recent years have only worsened this dynamic, with short-form video content taking over as the predominant mode of expression and <a href="https://aftermath.site/twitch-twitchcon-2025-security-emiru-assault-irl-streamers/"><u>giving rise to a generation of caustic clip farmers</u></a> who yank at the udder of any perceived drama of the week until it’s chafed and bone dry. Then they move onto the next thing and deploy the same playbook again.”</p> <p>In this milieu of brainrot it’s harder than ever, but also more urgent, to separate bad-faith trolling, drama-farming, and review-bombing campaigns from genuine dislike and revulsion when a game sucks or, more often, just doesn’t have the juice. “Let people fucking hate shit,” <em>Giant Bomb</em> co-founder Jeff Gerstmann <a href="https://youtu.be/CLJErsnsVwc?t=1391">recently joked on his podcast</a>. “Let people be fucking people! Grow up. It’s okay to criticize things that are fucking dumb.” It was in response to someone calling him out for making fun of people with glass-case gaming PCs that let you see inside the rig, but it applies just as much to an ambient strain in gaming discourse that would prefer people with nothing nice to say to say nothing at all.</p>

 <p>The breakdown of the internet has only made criticism more important, not less, and raised the stakes for doing so responsibly and honestly. That requires an open mind, a generous spirit, and an unflinching commitment to saying what you mean and meaning what you say. Also avoiding Twitter and every other irradiated social media platform as much as humanly possible.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bg3-swen-vincke-highguard-concord-steam-reviews-metacritic-2000663800]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scott Pilgrim EX Release Date Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/scott-pilgrim-ex-release-date-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1418569</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Tribute Games has revealed the release date for Scott Pilgrim EX, and it arrives on March 3, 2026, for PC and consoles. </p>



<p>Scott Pilgrim EX was announced back at Summer Game Fest 2025, and Insider Gaming had the chance to preview the title at Gamescom last year. In the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/scott-pilgrim-ex-hands-on-preview-pure-chaos-and-co-op-delight/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hands-on preview</a>, it was described as “a passion project for Tribute Games, and every pixel of the animation radiates that love.” Now, we have a release date for this project. </p>







<h2 id="h-scott-pilgrim-ex-releases-in-march-2026">Scott Pilgrim EX Releases in March 2026</h2>



<p>As revealed in Tribute Games’ latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iV1izGXgJFQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">YouTube video</a>, Scott Pilgrim EX will launch for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X/S, Nintendo Switch, and PC via Steam in March 2026. The latest trailer also provides us with a glimpse of gameplay for two new playable characters, Matthew Patel and Robot-01, bashing enemies left, right, and centre. Interested readers can check out the Scott Pilgrim EX release date trailer below. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Scott Pilgrim EX | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wto_MNMN-Yg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Scott Pilgrim EX takes place in Toronto 20XX, where the city is under the control of three rival gangs, VEGANS, the ROBOTS, and the DEMONS. It features a brand new story, written by series creator Bryan Lee O’Malley, and you get to play as seven characters that can be powered up and customised through coins. The game focuses on creative combos, wacky weapons, and environmental combat, and what’s more, you can bring in 3 more friends through local or online co-op. </p>







<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mlb-the-show-26-release-date-and-cover-athlete-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MLB The Show 26</a>‘s cover athlete and release date have been revealed. Additionally, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-releases-in-march-available-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WWE 2K26</a> is arriving in March 2026 as well, along with a Switch 2 port. Will you be playing Scott Pilgrim EX once it releases in March? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netease-layoffs-montreal-studio-more-possible/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NetEase’s latest round of layoffs, and sources say more could be on the way.</a>&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/scott-pilgrim-ex-release-date-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders and The Finals hit by 'Extensive, Coordinated' DDoS Attacks, Dev Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-and-the-finals-hit-by-extensive-coordinated-ddos-attacks-dev-says</link>
            <guid>1418566</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Embark Studios’ Arc Raiders and The Finals are suffering from what the studio has described as “extensive, coordinated” Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attacks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The attacks were said to be “ongoing” today while the studio battles to mitigate their impact on each game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Arc Raiders players have been complaining of server issues all morning, with some unable to reconnect to or abandon matches. Some affected players are hoping they will see lost loot return once the issues are fixed. “Was just rubber banding and died because it was of course in front of a shredder, and now stuck on the loading screen while trying to join a new lobby,” said one affected player.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Arc Raiders Headwinds Update 'Bird City' Screenshots</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It's unfortunate timing for Arc Raiders in particular, given the DDoS attacks come hot on the heels of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-big-arc-raiders-update-of-2026-adds-solo-vs-squads-matchmaking-bird-city-and-more-tomorrow">Arc Raiders’ Headwinds update</a>, which added a solo vs. squads matchmaking option, a Bird City map condition, and much more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Embark said it’s working on a hotfix that will “solve some of the issues and unintended changes” made by the Headwinds update. That should be out later today.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Arc Raiders is one of the biggest games in the world, having sold an incredible 12.4 million copies in just 10 weeks. The enormously popular extraction shooter has seen impressive staying power, too, setting a new concurrent player peak of 960,000 in January 2026. To put Arc Raiders' success into context, the similarly priced Helldivers 2 set a record for the fastest-selling PlayStation Studios game of all time by selling 12 million in 12 weeks. Arc Raiders, which launched on Xbox as well as PC and PlayStation, hit the 12 million sales mark even faster. It's done so well so quickly, that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-surprise-cameo-on-south-park-shows-just-how-close-to-the-wire-trey-parker-and-matt-stone-make-each-episode"><u>it crossed over into the world of South Park with a surprise appearance that was put together in just a few days</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Headwinds is the first of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-roadmap-promises-a-new-map-more-arcs-and-even-a-little-love-for-scrappy-by-april-2026">a four-phase roadmap</a> that has content scheduled out through April 2026. Next on the docket is the Shrouded Sky update, which adds a new map condition, Arc threat, player project, map update, Raider Deck, and more sometime in February. Flashpoint will then arrive in March with another map condition and Scrappy update, with Riven Tides rounding things out with a new map and a new large Arc in April.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If this has tempted you into giving Arc Raiders a try, check out our guide to the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/arc-raiders/Best_ARC_Raiders_Settings"><u>best settings</u></a>, find out what <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/arc-raiders/Skill_Tree_and_Best_Abilities"><u>skills we recommend unlocking</u></a> first, and see <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/arc-raiders/How_to_Deliver_Field_Depot_Crates"><u>how to earn loot by delivering field depot crates</u></a>… or you can just wait for the inevitable TV show or movie adaptation, although Embark says <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-arc-raiders-movie-and-tv-show-offers-are-already-coming-in-and-the-boss-of-embark-studios-sounds-up-for-it"><u>it hasn't been swayed just yet</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-and-the-finals-hit-by-extensive-coordinated-ddos-attacks-dev-says]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Hero Academia: All’s Justice ‘Full Roster’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/my-hero-academia-alls-justice-full-roster-trailer</link>
            <guid>1418563</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A look at every single playable Hero and Villain.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,829 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Byking [112 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/byking">Byking</a> have released a new trailer for <em><a title="Games > My Hero Academia: All's Justice [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/my-hero-academia-alls-justice">My Hero Academia: All’s Justice</a></em> highlighting the game’s full roster of playable Hero and Villain characters. <span id="more-1021916"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Bandai Namco:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>SMASH through <em>My Hero Academia</em>‘s final story arc and triumph over your foes in spectacular 3v3 battles! Follow Deku and the journeys of other characters in the Final War between Heroes and Villains, and experience the world-shaking, climactic clash between One For All and All For One in <em>My Hero Academia: All’s Justice</em>!</p><p><em>My Hero Academia: All’s Justice</em> is the super-powered 3D arena fighter where your favorite characters from the <em>My Hero Academia</em> franchise appear in their latest and most powerful forms, framed within a Refined Battle System. Furthermore, dive into a variety of game modes, including original scenario based Team-Up Mission where you’ll experience hero life as a U.A. High 1-A student in a Virtual Space!</p><p><strong>Relive the Final War Storyline</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><a title="Companies > Experience [213 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the final battle of <em>My Hero Academia</em> from a new perspective in <em>My Hero Academia: All’s Justice</em>‘s story mode. Re-live Bakugo’s fearless stand against All For One, experience Deku’s heroic struggle to bring justice and redemption to his fated foe, and more in a unique and cinematic take on the climactic clash of <em>My Hero Academia</em>.</p><p><strong>The Largest <em>My Hero Academia</em> Roster</strong></p><p>Heroes and Villains collide in the gigantic roster of <em>My Hero Academia</em> characters! Play your favorite U.A. Students, including all of Class 1-A, Pro Heroes like Mirko and Best Jeanist, and Villains such as All For One, Shigaraki and Dabi from across the full story of <em>My Hero Academia</em>, including their final and full-powered versions!</p><p><strong>Unleash Your Quirks and Potential in Fast-paced Strategic Battles</strong></p><p>Take control of your favorite U.A. Students, Pro Heroes, and Villains, and utilize their unique Quirks to pummel, blast, and trick your foes.</p><p>Unleash each character’s “Quirk” like never before by activating “Rising,” which allows attack power, movement speed, and Quirk <a title="Genres > Action [3,348 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s all enhanced.</p><p>Mix and match your team’s Quirks to find synergies and add depth to your tactics and strategies. Chain combos while switching characters to seize victory!</p><p><strong>A Day in the Life of a Hero</strong></p><p>Step into the shoes of Deku and Class 1-A students in “Team-Up Mission” and tackle training exercise in a Virtual Space! Based on an original game scenario form a team with Class 1-A students as your allies and complete various missions and triumph over Villains in an exclusive map!</p><p>Furthermore, jump into “Archives Battle” which will be unlocked by completing Team-Up Mission to experience iconic battles from across the full story of <em>My Hero Academia</em>.</p></blockquote><p><em>My Hero Academia: All’s Justice</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,274 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,631 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,359 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2362050/MY_HERO_ACADEMIA_Alls_Justice/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on February 6.</p><p>Watch the opening movie below.</p><h2><span>Full Roster Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="MY HERO ACADEMIA: All’s Justice | Full Roster Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H1zLJnKXgHs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/my-hero-academia-alls-justice-full-roster-trailer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders and The Finals hit by "coordinated" DDoS attacks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-and-the-finals-hit-by-coordinated-ddos-attacks</link>
            <guid>1418557</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Servers are now recovering after a period of mass instability.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-hockey.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-hockey.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-hockey.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-hockey.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-hockey.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-hockey.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-hockey.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-hockey.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-hockey.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Embark Studios has confirmed that both <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> and the Finals have been hit by DDoS attacks, claiming they were both "extensive" and "co-ordinated".</p>
<p>These problems first started in the early hours of the morning, with reports of mass instability impacting both games. While initially some stability was brought back to the servers, this soon deteriorated again as the DDos attacks continued.</p>
<p>In an update posted on the official Arc Raiders Discord server a few hours ago, community manager Ossen wrote: "Hey Raiders, both ARC Raiders and THE FINALS have been under extensive, co-ordinated DDoS attacks. The strike team has been working hard on mitigations and solutions to fix the problem, and we are making good progress - but at this point in time the attacks are still ongoing."</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>You can watch Eurogamer's Arc Raiders review here<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oXigyRsVeB0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This effort to resolve the connectivity problems coincided with work on a hotfix targeting unintended changes with the recent major update, which altered the fire rate of some weapons, led to some earned cosmetics going missing, and more.</p>
<p>In the last hour, Ossen updated Arc Raiders players on the DDos issue, stating: "We are noticing that servers are recovering." Whether the DDoS attacks have concluded, or Embark has resolved the issue entirely, remains unclear.</p>
<p>This attack comes only a day following<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/are-you-a-little-too-good-at-arc-raiders-the-new-solo-vs-squad-mode-might-be-for-you"> the release of a new solo vs squad game mode, as well as a Bird City map condition</a>. It's worth noting that even with this ongoing DDoS attack, <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1808500/charts/">SteamDB still tracks well over 100,000 players still in-game</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-and-the-finals-hit-by-coordinated-ddos-attacks]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Still Haven't Played Stardew Valley? It's The Next Free Game Trial For NSO Members (Europe)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/still-havent-played-stardew-valley-its-the-next-free-game-trial-for-nso-members-europe</link>
            <guid>1418527</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>For a limited time only</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="cdc5d2f365bd6"><a title="Stardew Valley" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/cdc5d2f365bd6/stardew-valley.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: ConcernedApe</em></figcaption></figure><p>If, by some chance, you are one of the six remaining people on Earth who haven't played <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/stardew_valley">Stardew Valley</a> <em>and</em> you have a Nintendo Switch Online membership, then boy, do we have good news for you.</p>
<p>Nintendo has <a href="https://x.com/NintendoUK/status/2016442631769686482">announced</a> that ConcernedApe's beloved farming sim is the next title to get the Free Game Trial treatment (in Europe, at least), offering the full game to those with an NSO subscription for a limited time.</p>
<p>From <strong>29th January until 4th February</strong>, members will be able to play Stardew to their heart's content, and yes, that includes all of the multiplayer options too. Those who haven't played it before, be warned, it can prove quite the time sink if it clicks.</p><div><figure data-videoid="r3KMxc-vq0o" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r3KMxc-vq0o?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytr3KMxc-vq0o" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/r3KMxc-vq0o?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r3KMxc-vq0o?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed35e359vpnywx&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Just in case you missed it, the game scored a free Switch 2 Edition update at the end of last year, throwing in a bunch of fun features for the new hardware like mouse mode, Game Share support and new multiplayer options.</p>
<p>"<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/stardew-valley-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Stardew Valley</a> on Switch 2 is almost the best way to play the game (without mods)," we said in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/stardew-valley-nintendo-switch-2-edition">our review</a> of this swanky new version, "just a few bugs, <a href="https://x.com/ConcernedApe/status/2004474989119160737" rel="noopener">which the developer is currently working on</a>, hold it back from perfection."</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:195867 @ 1769612404 -->
<p><em>Will you be checking out this free game trial or have you already played Stardew to death? Plant your thoughts in the comments below.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/still-havent-played-stardew-valley-its-the-next-free-game-trial-for-nso-members-europe]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CAPCOM Shares Soar 10% After Great Sales and Even Better Forecast Powered by Resident Evil Requiem]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/capcom-shares-soar-great-sales-forecast-resident-evil-requiem/</link>
            <guid>1418524</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Japanese developer and publisher <strong>CAPCOM</strong> has enjoyed a strong stock run today, closing <strong>up 9,82%</strong> over yesterday. Investors were pleased with <a href="https://www.capcom.co.jp/ir/english/data/pdf/explanation/2025/3rd/explanation_2025_3rd_01.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the company's third-quarter financial report</a>, which showed a 30% increase in net sales, a 75% increase in operating profit, and a 65% increase in ordinary profit. The current fiscal year's net sales after Q3 are $753 million, with $355 million in operating profit and $338 million in ordinary profit.</p>



<p>The full-year forecast is even better, given the imminent launch of <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/resident-evil-requiem-everything-we-know-about-the-new-game-in-capcoms-beloved-horror-franchise/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resident Evil Requiem</a></strong> (on February 27, 2026) and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-stories-3-twisted-reflection-release-date-march-2026-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection</a></strong> (on March 13, 2026). Both games will be released before the end of CAPCOM's fiscal year, which is scheduled for March 31, 2026. With their help, <strong>the publisher is targeting net sales of $1.2 billion</strong>, operating profit of $477 million, and ordinary profit of $458 million. </p>



<p>That's just the beginning of the publisher's calendar year. For the next fiscal year, CAPCOM already has two potential heavy-hitters: the third-person action/adventure game <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/pragmata-launches-april-24-2026-switch-2-version-added-demo-out-now-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PRAGMATA</a></strong> (an interesting new IP, based on our Gamescom hands-on) and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-gamescom-hands-on-preview-two-heavens-as-one/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Onimusha: Way of the Sword</a></strong>, the long-awaited new installment in the Onimusha franchise. The former is launching on April 24, 2026, while the latter still doesn't have a final release date.</p>



<p>Of course, CAPCOM also continues to bet on the solid performance of its catalog titles. This fiscal year, <strong>Devil May Cry 5</strong> was the top performer, likely due to deep discounts. <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/monster-hunter-wilds-peak-hunting/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monster Hunter Wilds</a></strong> hasn't performed very well, but it still reached <strong>11 million</strong> total units sold since its launch in February 2025. Even with the recent sales slowdown, <strong>it's the studio's fastest-selling game to date</strong>, narrowly beating its predecessor, <strong>Monster Hunter World</strong>, which took a little longer to get to 11 million units sold.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><td><strong>Title</strong></td><td><strong>25/12 (Millions)</strong></td><td><strong>Lifetime (Millions)</strong></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Devil May Cry 5</strong></td><td>2.43</td><td>11.00</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Resident Evil 4</strong></td><td>2.34</td><td>12.26</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Resident Evil Village</strong></td><td>2.28</td><td>13.59</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Street Fighter 6</strong></td><td>1.69</td><td>6.36</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Resident Evil 7 biohazard</strong></td><td>1.68</td><td>16.47</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Resident Evil 2</strong></td><td>1.46</td><td>16.87</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Monster Hunter Rise</strong></td><td>1.10</td><td>18.27</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Resident Evil 3</strong></td><td>1.09</td><td>10.99</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Monster Hunter Rise: Sunbreak</strong></td><td>1.03</td><td>10.91</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Monster Hunter Wilds</strong></td><td>0.99</td><td>11.10</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Perhaps the <a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-patch-significant-performance-improvements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new PC performance patch</a> will reignite interest in Monster Hunter Wilds. Otherwise, it might be difficult to beat Monster Hunter World's total record sales of <strong>over 22 million units</strong> sold to date.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/capcom-shares-soar-great-sales-forecast-resident-evil-requiem/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Drops the Galaxy SmartTag 2 Bluetooth Tracker to Its Lowest Price After New AirTag 2 Arrives]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-drops-the-galaxy-smarttag-2-bluetooth-tracker-to-its-lowest-price-after-new-airtag-2-arrives-2000663636</link>
            <guid>1418515</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Got any big travel plans for 2026? I know when I’m traveling, I become weirdly anxious about all my stuff, afraid I might leave something behind somewhere in a hotel room or backseat of an Uber. That’s why it can be a good idea to slip some Samsung Galaxy SmartTag2 Bluetooth trackers into your bags. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6920/">Right now, Amazon has the trackers 36% off. Normally, priced at $30, they’ve now each dropped by $10 to just $20 per tag</a>. If you need several, a four-pack is now going for just $62, which ends up working out to just shy of $16 per SmartTag2.</p>
<p>This set of four Samsung Galaxy SmartTag2 Bluetooth trackers comes with two black trackers and two white trackers. If you’re just buying one, the white model is $2 cheaper than the black.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6920/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Keep Track of All Your Crap</h2>
<p>Most of us already rely on GPS to locate our phones if they go missing. SmartTag2 extends that same peace of mind to items that don’t have built-in tracking. Paired with a Samsung Galaxy phone or tablet, the tracker lets you see the last known location of your belongings directly on a map. That can save time and frustration when something isn’t where you expected.</p>
<p data-start="882" data-end="1254">Physically, the SmartTag2 is small, lightweight, and designed with a built-in loop, so attaching it is simple. Clip one to your keys, slide one into a backpack, or loop one onto luggage. Some people even attach them to bikes, camera bags, or in gym lockers to keep tabs on where things are. Once you get used to having trackers around, it’s hard not to find new uses for them.</p>
<p data-start="1639" data-end="1997">If an item is nearby but out of sight, the Search Nearby feature comes into play. It pulls up a compass-style interface that guides you toward the tag’s location. For situations where visual clues aren’t enough, you can trigger an audible alert on the SmartTag2, making it easier to track down something buried under clothes or tucked between couch cushions.</p>


<h2 data-start="1639" data-end="1997">Enhanced Battery Life</h2>
<p data-start="1999" data-end="2281">Battery life is another strong point. Each SmartTag2 can last up to 500 days on a single battery, with Power Saving mode extending that lifespan even further, up to 40% longer. With that enabled, you won’t need to think about replacements very often. Might be useful when you’re using them on items you don’t check daily.</p>
<p data-start="2283" data-end="2620" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node="">With an IP67 rating, these trackers can handle dust and water exposure without issue. Optional silicone cases add extra protection, better grip, and a carabiner ring for quicker attachment.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6920/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-drops-the-galaxy-smarttag-2-bluetooth-tracker-to-its-lowest-price-after-new-airtag-2-arrives-2000663636]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mewgenics Release Date Countdown & Exact Start Times]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/mewgenics-release-date-start-time/</link>
            <guid>1418512</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>There is no shortage of games demanding your attention in 2026, with a string of major titles landing onto the scene, and there are also games like Mewgenics that are worth keeping an eye out.</p>



<p>Mewgenics is a new title from Edmund McMillen and Tyler Glaiel, the former of whom is the mastermind behind The Binding of Isaac, and it has already built up a following on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a> ahead of release, with over 20,000 followers.</p>



<p>For all the details on the Mewgenics release date and the exact start time, Insider Gaming has you covered.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-the-mewgenics-release-date">What is The Mewgenics Release Date?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Kitty. Image via Edmund McMillen/Tyler Glaiel</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Mewgenics has an official release date of February 10, 2026, though this date may be impacted based on where you are located in the world.</strong></p>



<p>For the majority of players, Mewgenics will be playable on the above date, but players in some regions will have to wait until the early hours of the following morning.</p>



<p>This is due to Mewgenics having a global release structure, which is standard practice for Steam, and not a staggered release like players usually experience on consoles.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-time-does-mewgenics-release">What Time Does Mewgenics Release?</h2>



<p><strong>Mewgenics</strong> <strong>will be released at 9 AM PT on February 10, with a later release time for other regions in the United States.</strong></p>



<p>Those in Europe will have to wait until later in the day to jump in and enjoy Mewgenics, while those in Asia and Oceania face a late night waiting up until the early hours of the morning for the release. Details of the release time come via SteamDB.</p>



<p>Players on console won’t be able to join the fun, as Mewgenics launches on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PC</a> only, so there are no variations in release time with different platforms.</p>



<p>The table below highlights the release time of Mewgenics in major regions across the world, so you can work out exactly how much longer you need to wait.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Release Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">9 AM – Feb. 10</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">11 AM – Feb. 10</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">12 PM – Feb. 10</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">5 PM – Feb. 10</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (AET)</td><td data-align="center">4 AM – Feb. 11</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<hr>



<p>Are you looking forward to Mewgenics? Share your excitement for the game in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, check out all the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/menace-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date details for MENACE</a>, and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mlb-the-show-26-release-date-and-cover-athlete-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reveal and cover athlete for MLB The Show 26</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/mewgenics-release-date-start-time/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NetEase Holds Layoffs At Montreal Studio With More Possible]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/netease-layoffs-montreal-studio-more-possible/</link>
            <guid>1418509</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>NetEase is cutting jobs again. While not officially announced by the Chinese company, a number of employees have taken to social media in recent days to confirm the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">layoffs</a> at NetEase Montreal.</p>



<p>Right now, the only known employees to be impacted are on the QA staff.</p>







<p><strong>“Last week I was impacted by the layoffs at NetEase and my time with them has come to an end,”</strong> one former QA Project Manager said on LinkedIn. <strong>“It was a great experience and I’m thankful I was able to grow as I did.”&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Said another, <strong>“Unfortunately I have been affected by another round of layoffs, and my time at NetEase Games has come to an end.”&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out multiple times to NetEase for additional context on the scale of the layoffs. As of writing, however, no response has been received.</p>



<h2 id="h-more-netease-cuts-could-be-coming">More NetEase Cuts Could Be Coming</h2>



<p>While the NetEase Montreal layoffs are the ones known to be happening recently, it’s not a guarantee that more aren’t on the way. In recent months, Insider Gaming has been speaking with a number of sources around NetEase that have expressed worry and concern over the future.</p>







<p>NetEase has publicly said they would continue to support studios after a number of layoffs in 2025. However, sources say that the company is continuing to look at divesting from its Western studios. There is an increased desire to invest money domestically due to the recent success of Chinese-developed games like Wuchang: Fallen Feathers and Black Myth: Wukong. </p>



<p>That would see <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-developers-laid-off-as-netease-guts-entire-team/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">studio layoffs</a>, sales, and, potentially, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/another-netease-studio-shutting-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">closures</a>. Insider Gaming has learned of two studios that NetEase is having talks about, including one that is working on a popular IP. Those who spoke on one of the studios said that “everything is on the table” with its overseas studios.</p>



<p>What do you make of the layoffs and concerns at NetEase? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more news, read about members of the United States Congress wanting the Federal Trade Commission <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/us-congress-members-want-ftc-to-review-ea-sale-to-saudi-arabia/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to do a deeper look into the pending sale</a> of Electronic Arts to the Saudi Arabia Public Investment Fund.&nbsp;And for even more Insider Gaming delivered directly to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/netease-layoffs-montreal-studio-more-possible/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Half Sword on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S or Nintendo Switch? All Platforms, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/half-sword-playstation-xbox-nintendo-all-platforms/</link>
            <guid>1418506</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>If you’re looking for a gruesome, gritty, and otherwise grim, yet hilarious, medieval combat game, this is what you need. Half Sword has a big following already, and its platform availability across PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch devices could be a finishing blow.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/half-sword/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Half Sword</a> has more than just swords—full ones too! There’s a wide array of weaponry to slice and dice opponents in this crazy and entertaining physics-based combat title. Its uniqueness and identity should make it a standout indie hit, but let’s see if it’s relegated to just PC, and not other platforms.</p>







<h2 id="h-can-you-play-half-sword-on-ps5">Can You Play Half Sword On PS5?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>En Garde. Credit to Half Sword Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Half Sword will not be making its bow on PlayStation 5 consoles at launch.</strong></p>



<p>If you want to violently spar with your friends, you’ll have to use another physics-based game for now, like Gang Beasts or Stick Fight. It’s been confirmed that PS5 (or PlayStation 4) will not be a launch platform for Half Sword, and this is heartbreaking (and stabbing).</p>







<h2 id="h-can-you-play-half-sword-on-xbox-series-x-s">Can You Play Half Sword On Xbox Series X|S?</h2>



<p><strong>There is no Xbox Series X|S or Xbox One launch for Half Sword.</strong></p>



<p>Microsoft users will feel the pain of PlayStation players. Half Sword made thousands of wishlists and most-wanted lists going into 2026, and its release date, and it might be a wishlist option for you Xbox owners in the future. For now, your sword will have to remain sheathed and your thirst for blood unsatiated.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-half-sword-on-nintendo-switch-or-switch-2">Can You Play Half Sword On Nintendo Switch or Switch 2?</h2>



<p><strong>Whether you own a Nintendo Switch or Nintendo Switch 2, you can’t play Half Sword right away, as it’s not coming to any Nintendo platform on January 30.</strong></p>



<p>Half Sword is a game that looks like a perfect fit for all platforms. Alas, this ye old olde medieval combat is and is PC-only at launch. The Switch is usually a haven for indie titles, but not this time.</p>



<p>However, not all is lost for console owners.</p>



<h2 id="h-half-sword-console-release-date-details">Half Sword Console Release Date Details</h2>



<p><strong>According to the game’s official FAQ, Half Sword is coming to “Consoles later,” meaning a bit of patience is unfortunately required.</strong></p>



<p>The richness of Half Sword’s violence will be coming to consoles later on. Here’s what the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1043854763189600337/1272470349245579396" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">FAQ</a> said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“Intended for PC first. Consoles later. MAC support later if there is enough interest.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s not specified WHICH consoles, though. PS5 and Xbox Series X|S owners are likely going to get the chance to buy it, but the jury is out on PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch (and Switch 2).</p>



<p>Stay tuned for further updates on Half Sword’s console and platform status later on.</p>



<p>Will you patiently wait for a Half Sword console port? Or would it be a case of FOMO for the early-game hype? Share your thoughts on this via the free-to-join <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>, where you can discuss Half Sword, other games, and pretty much anything else in between!</p>



<hr>



<p>Be sure to check out the latest on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-much-will-half-sword-cost-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how much Half Sword will cost</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/half-sword-playstation-xbox-nintendo-all-platforms/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scott Pilgrim EX launches March 3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/scott-pilgrim-ex-launches-march-3</link>
            <guid>1418503</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Retro-style side-scrolling adventure brawler dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Retro-style <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [1,205 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> adventure brawler<em><a title="Games > Scott Pilgrim EX [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/scott-pilgrim-ex">Scott Pilgrim EX</a></em> will launch digitally for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,274 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,631 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,671 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,242 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,359 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2640950/Scott_Pilgrim_EX/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on March 3 for $28.99, developer <a title="Companies > Tribute Games [43 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tribute-games">Tribute Games</a> announced. Physical editions will follow. <span id="more-1021584"></span></p><p>The developer also revealed that Matthew Patel and Robot-01 will be playable characters in the game. Here are their descriptions:</p><blockquote><ul><li><strong>Matthew Patel</strong> brings theatrical flair and mystic chaos to the battlefield. With a style that blends fire and ritualistic showmanship, Patel manipulates the flow of combat like a puppet master – using his summoned demon hipsters to distract enemies, control crowds and lay traps that can tip the scales in his team’s favor. His supernatural abilities allow him to call forth extra arms, launch flame bursts and unleash devastating finishing moves imbued with mythic power.</li><li><strong>Robot-01</strong>, meanwhile, is all precision and punishment – rocketing across the screen with thrusters and transformations, delivering brutal blows at blistering speed. A combat unit built for mayhem, Robot-01 morphs mid-battle, fires long-range blasts and unleashes a powerful stro</li></ul></blockquote><div id="carousel_1021893"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Here is an overview of the game, via Tribute Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Join Scott Pilgrim and Ramona Flowers in a brand-new brawling adventure across space, time, and the streets of Toronto!</p><p>Toronto, 20XX. The city has been taken over by three rival gangs—the VEGANS, the ROBOTS, and the DEMONS. But who’s behind this madness? When Scott Pilgrim’s bandmates are abducted by shadowy forces, a brand-new adventure begins!</p><p><em>Scott Pilgrim EX</em> is an <a title="Genres > Action [3,348 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>–<a title="Genres > Adventure [2,836 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> where players can fight as Scott Pilgrim, Ramona Flowers and more as they battle through the fractured time and space of Toronto. The combat gameplay is driven by instinct and improvisation—a hectic ballet of fists and flair that rewards strategy, spontaneity, and a good bit of brawling chaos. String together stylish combos, experiment with wacky weapons and unleash over-the-top special attacks. Characters can be upgraded with special badges that enhance their stats and grant special bonuses. Players will explore a whole city of interconnected levels to meet old and new faces, complete quests, and discover hidden areas. <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [678 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a> co-op, local or online, lets up to four players join in on the action, making it a fun, dynamic experience.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Seven Playable Characters</strong> – Step into the shoes of seven fan-favorite fighters, each with their own distinct combat style.</li><li><strong>A Brand-New Adventure</strong> – Venture out on epic quests and battle new enemies and bosses across interconnected levels in a new story by series creator Bryan Lee O’Malley that will appeal to longtime fans and newcomers alike.</li><li><strong>Madcap Melee Mayhem</strong> – <a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter creative combos, wield wacky weapons, use your surroundings to your advantage and conquer the chaos!</li><li><strong>Power Up!</strong> – Spend your hard-earned coins to customize your fighter! Equip special items and upgrade your stats to create a unique build for every playthrough!</li><li><strong>New Anamanaguchi Music</strong> – Known for their explosive blend of 8-bit energy and hyper-melodic rock, the band returns to their roots with all new music crafted for this Toronto-hopping adventure.</li><li><strong>Four-Player Cooperative Mayhem</strong> – Join forces with up to three friends, locally or online, with easy drop-in / drop-out <a title="Genres > Co-Op [367 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play. Battle solo or hit the streets together.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/scott-pilgrim-ex/january-28-2026/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Scott Pilgrim EX - Release Date / Matthew Patel and Robot-01 Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dDKOoB-JLWk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/scott-pilgrim-ex-launches-march-3]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Action adventure RPG Emberville launches in Early Access this summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/action-adventure-rpg-emberville-launches-in-early-access-this-summer</link>
            <guid>1418500</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Going beyond the expectations of similar "farm and fight" games.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Action [3,348 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,836 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> <a title="Genres > RPG [17,978 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Emberville [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/emberville">Emberville</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,359 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2295170/Emberville/" target="_blank">Steam</a> this summer, developer <a title="Companies > Cygnus Cross" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cygnus-cross">Cygnus Cross</a> announced. <span id="more-1021783"></span></p><p>The game, which has been in development since 2023, attracted the attention of Twitch streamer CohhCarnage, who has been heavily involved in the co-creation of the game, hand-in-hand with the development team.</p><p>“<em>Emberville</em> is an amalgamation of everything we love, combined with new, fun, and immersive mechanics designed to make it stand out,” CohhCarnage said in a press release. “It’s made by gamers, for gamers. We can’t wait for you to take this journey with us, because it’s been one hell of an adventure over the last few years.”</p><p>Cygnus Cross also announced that Alex Jordan and Doug Cockle are the first of “many” voice actors who will appear as yet unnamed characters in the fully-voiced game.</p><div id="carousel_1021788"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Cygnus Cross:</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Emberville</em> is an action adventure RPG that goes beyond the conventional expectations of similar “farm and fight” games, with a simple-yet-deep combat system, an inherited skill leveling system, and challenging boss fights, and the new gameplay trailer offers players a glimpse of what to expect.</p><p>Customization is key in <em>Emberville</em>. From cross-class combat skills to a full creative building area, players are encouraged to play their way. Building on the two-button combat system, <em>Emberville</em> offers a weapon-bound combo system in addition to class-related skills. Unlock new combos for a variety of weapons and chain different types of attacks to unleash devastating strikes on enemies. Learning skills from leveling multiple classes allows the player to tailor the active combat class for a unique playstyle.</p><p>The creative area gives players a location to place buildings, decorations, farms, crafting equipment, and more, with many items and buildings offering further customization options. To ease inventory <a title="Genres > Management [36 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> between tasks like farming, fishing, building, and combat, <em>Emberville</em> features a dynamic user interface system, which adjusts the HUD seamlessly when approaching areas for each task.</p><p><em>Emberville</em> will offer players an ambitious combination of game systems and mechanics that go far beyond the traditional staples of basic resource gathering and combat that “fight and farm” games are well known for. The leveling system in the game will let players not only swap between different classes, but also allow them to inherit active and passive abilities from that leveled class into a new one, which will allow for flexibility and creativity as each player can find a combination that is unique to their playstyle.</p><p><strong>Exclusive Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Unique Multi-layered Combat Mechanics</strong> – In addition to the traditional two-button combat system, <em>Emberville</em> features a weapon-bound combo system and class-related combat skills.</li><li><strong>Dynamic User Interface</strong> – A User Interface mechanic that changes the HUD in accordance with the player’s needs, making it easier to deal with multiple features without preventing the player from having its own decisions or managing their inventory.</li><li><strong>Inherited Skills</strong> – Combat skills that are inherited from one leveled-up class to another, allowing the player customize the active combat class.</li></ul><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Fast-Paced Combat Mechanics</strong> – The combat is fast-paced and action-oriented, with a big variety of weapons, skills, and abilities.</li><li><strong>Multifaceted Game Progression</strong> – Progression is multifaceted, with players leveling up weapon and armor categories to unlock new classes, leveling up and learning crafting and gathering skills, rescuing NPCs to enhance and rebuild Emberville, and exploring the world to uncover hidden treasures and secrets.</li><li><strong>Farming, Gathering, and <a title="Genres > Crafting [48 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">Crafting</a></strong> – <em>Emberville</em> features farming, gathering, and crafting skills that can be used to grow crops, gather plants, wood, and minerals, and craft items, which can be improved by leveling up, learning skills, blueprints, and recipes.</li><li><strong>Creative Area</strong> – Customizable creative player area, with houses, buildings, and objects that can be custom-placed and be used to improve skills, craft items and as a chill spot.</li><li><strong>Procedural Generation</strong> – The world of <em>Emberville</em> can be explored through a giant procedurally generated world that contains procedurally generated levels with a great variety of events, biomes, enemies, treasures, and so on.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/emberville/january-28-2026/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Emberville - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hPsCEHnjBJc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/action-adventure-rpg-emberville-launches-in-early-access-this-summer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation is encouraging PS4 players to upgrade to PS5 as analyst predicts PS6 won't arrive until after 2028]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ps6-may-not-arrive-in-2028-analyst-predicts</link>
            <guid>1418491</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5_on-blue-background.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5_on-blue-background.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5_on-blue-background.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5_on-blue-background.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5_on-blue-background.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5_on-blue-background.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5_on-blue-background.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5_on-blue-background.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5_on-blue-background.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer/Sony</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The games industry is in a very weird place right now due to both internal and external factors. Perhaps the most pressing one is the <a href="https://za.ign.com/steam-machine/223581/video/how-ram-shortages-are-making-tech-more-expensive-boring-ces-2026">rising cost of key hardware components</a> due to AI and data centre speculation. Therefore, next-gen hardware delays could be on the table as Sony and Microsoft look to maximize PS5 and Xbox Series X/S, respectively, while waiting markets to settle.</p>
<p>Via <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/high-likelihood-ps6-will-launch-after-2028-according-to-new-analyst-forecast-as-sony-focuses-on-extending-ps5-lifecycle">IGN</a>, we're now hearing from David Gibson, senior analyst at MST, who focuses on tech and gaming companies. He published a <a href="https://www.sandstoneinsightsjapan.com/post/sony-group-6758%EF%BC%89%EF%BC%8D%E3%82%B2%E3%83%BC%E3%83%A0%E9%83%A8%E9%96%80%E3%81%AE%E5%A5%BD%E8%AA%BF%E3%81%8C%E7%AC%AC3%E5%9B%9B%E5%8D%8A%E6%9C%9F%E3%82%92%E7%89%BD%E5%BC%95%E3%80%81%E4%BB%8A%E5%BE%8C%E3%81%95%E3%82%89%E3%81%AA%E3%82%8B%E4%B8%8A%E6%98%87%E4%BD%99%E5%9C%B0%E3%81%82%E3%82%8A">report for Sandstone Insights Japan</a> on 16th of this month that commented on Sony's recent financial performance and what might be next for the tech giant.</p>
<p>The good news (for Sony) is that earnings for the third quarter of the fiscal year ending February 2026 are expected to exceed previous forecasts. First- and third-party games continue to drive growth, and it appears PSN subscriptions remain strong, too. Per IGN's report, "Q3 sales are predicted to total around 1.8 trillion yen (approx. $11.6 billion), with operating income at 160 billion yen (approx. $1 billion)."</p>
<p>Good numbers around PS5 hardware and software only makes the case for a delay of PS6 even more convincing. "Sony expects the PS5 lifecycle to be longer than that of previous console generations," Gibson stated, before adding it's likely the PS6's launch won't occur until after 2028. Industry figures <a href="https://www.techradar.com/gaming/gaming-industry/a-ps6-launch-in-2028-feels-right-according-to-former-playstation-boss-citing-increasingly-long-console-generations">had been predicting a 2028 release</a> last year. This would already make the PS5 generation longer than PS4's seven-year exclusive run (though the hardware is still being supported). If a market-induced does occur, PS5 will spend even more time being Sony's top-dog console.</p><p>Recent moves by the company suggest that might indeed be the case, with a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-cheaper-japanese-language-only-ps5-just-for-japan">Japan-only, cheaper PS5 model launching last November</a> and deep discounts happening globally for Black Friday 2025. Via <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2026/01/sonys-sending-messages-to-ps4-players-encouraging-them-to-upgrade-to-ps5">Push Square</a>, we're also seeing reports of PS4 users being targeted by Sony with aimed messages that encourage making the jump to PS5.</p>
<p>Gibson, however, also thinks Sony is now focusing on retaining existing PS5 users over boosting console sales (even if those <a href="https://www.vgchartz.com/article/466830/ps5-best-seller-as-sales-remain-flat-yoy-europe-hardware-estimates-for-december-2025/">remain strong</a>). At the time of writing, price hikes haven't been announced in answer to memory shortage woes, but the analyst admits "Sony might pass future cost increases onto consumers" even if there's no short-term danger. This would line up with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/is-the-switch-2-getting-more-expensive-soon-nintendo-says-theres-no-immediate-impact-but-will-keep-an-eye-on-volatile-memory-market">Nintendo's current stance</a> on the matter. Therefore, solid growth well into 2026 is likely for Sony and Nintendo. On the other hand, <a href="https://www.techradar.com/gaming/in-not-remotely-shocking-news-xbox-has-reportedly-suffered-its-worst-year-on-record-for-console-sales">Xbox sales in 2025 were lackluster</a>, so there are doubts around Microsoft's consoles' performance moving forward.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  




  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/ps6-may-not-arrive-in-2028-analyst-predicts]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ren & Stimpy Are Getting A 7-Game Retro Collection, Courtesy Of Limited Run]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/ren-and-stimpy-are-getting-a-7-game-retro-collection-courtesy-of-limited-run</link>
            <guid>1418473</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Happy, Happy, Joy, Joy</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="7cb5ce2286ff2"><a title="Ren &amp; Stimpy Happy, Happy, Joy, Joy Collection" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/7cb5ce2286ff2/ren-and-stimpy-happy-happy-joy-joy-collection.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Limited Run Games</em></figcaption></figure><p>If the news of the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/nickelodeon_splat_pack">Nickelodeon Splat Pack</a> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/nickelodeon-splat-pack-revives-multiple-snes-titles-in-retro-collection-this-week">release date</a> earlier this week wasn't enough cartoon nostalgia for you, Limited Run Games has <a href="https://limitedrungames.com/products/ren-stimpy-happy-happy-joy-joy-collection-standard-edition-switch-ps5-pc?variant=44905135308853">revealed</a> that it has even more in the pipeline for Switch, in the shape of the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/ren_and_stimpy_happy_happy_joy_joy_collection">Ren &amp; Stimpy Happy, Happy, Joy, Joy Collection</a>.</p>
<p>This is a seven-game compilation title, collecting together a handful of the Nickelodeon duo's SNES and Game Boy adventures. The titles included in this one are <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/ren_and_stimpy_show_space_cadet_adventures">The Ren and Stimpy Show: Space Cadet Adventures</a> (Game Boy), <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/ren_and_stimpy_show_veediots">Veediots!</a> (SNES and Game Boy), <strong>Buckeroo$!</strong> (NES and SNES), <strong>Time Warp</strong> (SNES) and <strong>Fire Dogs</strong> (SNES) — yes, that does mean <strong>Quest for the Shaven Yak</strong> and <strong>Stimpy's Invention</strong> are missing, unfortunately.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067kvipys&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>As we have come to expect from retro compilations like this, the Happy, Happy, Joy, Joy Collection gives you the chance to rewind gameplay and save from anywhere, as well as other additions like a music player and an artwork museum.</p>
<p>It'll come as no surprise to hear that there are a few different purchase options from <a href="https://limitedrungames.com/products/ren-stimpy-happy-happy-joy-joy-collection-standard-edition-switch-ps5-pc?variant=44905135308853">LRG</a> (once pre-orders open on 30th January), including a 'Classic Edition' for <strong>$69.99</strong>, which comes with a retro VHS cover and a steelcase, and a 'Collector's Edition' for <strong>$109.99</strong>, which packs in a bunch of extra merch like a CD, poster, mini cartridge replicas, an acrylic standee and more.</p>
<figure data-uuid="08c0142f50b63"><a title="Ren &amp; Stimpy Happy, Happy, Joy, Joy Collection" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/08c0142f50b63/ren-and-stimpy-happy-happy-joy-joy-collection.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Limited Run Games</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>These pre-orders will only be sticking around until 1st March, so you better get saving your pennies if you want to grab the merch-packed edition. While there's no specific release date just yet, Limited Run estimates that the physical editions should ship sometime between July and September 2026.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:187978 @ 1769613639 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this Ren &amp; Stimpy collection? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://limitedrungames.com/products/ren-stimpy-happy-happy-joy-joy-collection-standard-edition-switch-ps5-pc?variant=44905135308853" rel="noopener" href="https://limitedrungames.com/products/ren-stimpy-happy-happy-joy-joy-collection-standard-edition-switch-ps5-pc?variant=44905135308853">limitedrungames.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/5115cac2b699ec6ed59ce7018f45f988 @ 1769614586 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/ren-and-stimpy-are-getting-a-7-game-retro-collection-courtesy-of-limited-run]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerA’s Alternative to the Nintendo Switch 2 Pro Controller Is a No Brainer at Less Than Half Its Price]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/poweras-alternative-to-the-nintendo-switch-2-pro-controller-is-a-no-brainer-at-less-than-half-its-price-2000663633</link>
            <guid>1418470</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>With the release of the Switch 2 last year, Nintendo simultaneously refreshed it’s Pro Controller to release alongside the new console. The aptly-named Nintendo Switch 2 Pro Controller comes with some big upgrades including a better HD Rumble system, the dedicated C-Button for GameChat, and rear GL/GR buttons that can be mapped to any button you choose. It’s a handy controller to add to your rotation, but it doesn’t come cheap. It’s list price is a whopping $89.</p>
<p>You can get a controller with really everything you actually need for less than half that price. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6919/">The PowerA enhanced wireless controller for both the Nintendo Switch and Nintendo Switch 2 normally goes for $70, but has come down to just $40 after a 43% discount.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6919/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>While the PowerA controller doesn’t have the C-button to launch GameChat directly from your gamepad, I also don’t know many players who would even miss that all too much. What the PowerA controller&nbsp;<em>does</em> have is comfortable ergonomics for long game sessions and wireless connectivity. It’s even got motion controls. What more do you need?</p>
<h2>Advanced Gaming Buttons</h2>
<p>The PowerA controller even has the same two customizable back buttons that Nintendo added to its second generation pro controller. The AGR and AGL buttons can be pulled with your trigger fingers to activate a function of your choice. You can map these buttons to mimic any other button on the controller, making it easy to jump or reload without having to take your thumbs off the sticks. These back buttons can even be programmed on the fly, mid game. No backing out of the game into system settings required.</p>



<h2>Never Stop Playing</h2>
<p>The controller is powered by an internal lithium rechargeable 900mAh battery, so you’re not dealing with double-As like you might with some other third party options. The PowerA controller fully charged could last you up to 30 hours on a single charge. Then when the battery does get low, just plug in the included 10-foot USB-C charging cable so it can recharge while you can keep playing.</p>
<p>The PowerA controller can also be way more fun than the first-party option from Nintendo. Along with the standard black version, PowerA has a wide selection of designs featuring artwork of fan favorite characters. Lots of Mario and friends designs as well as some options from Kirby, Metroid, and Zelda. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6919/">Most of which are currently marked down to the same $40 price tag as the standard version.</a> That’s $49 cheaper than the Nintendo Switch 2 Pro Controller.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6919/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/poweras-alternative-to-the-nintendo-switch-2-pro-controller-is-a-no-brainer-at-less-than-half-its-price-2000663633]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Co-op RC adventure game WheelMates announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/co-op-rc-adventure-game-wheelmates-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>1418467</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in 2026.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Firevolt" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/firevolt">Firevolt</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > WheelMates" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wheelmates">WheelMates</a></em>, a <a title="Genres > Co-Op [367 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,836 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> where two players drive tiny RC cars through the house of an eccentric scientist. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,274 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,631 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,359 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3905450/WheelMates/" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2026. A PC playtest will be held in February. <span id="more-1021860"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Firevolt:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A strange house owned by an even stranger professor lies waiting for someone to discover its secrets…and the whereabouts of its owner. The only way through the building is by piloting a pair of RC cars that must coordinate with each other in order to progress and solve the mystery.</p><p><em>WheelMates</em> focuses on cooperation over competition, with no timers and no pressure to move fast. The experience focuses on shared problem solving at the duo’s own preferred pace, enabling discovery of surprises and secrets, complete with online and split-screen co-op experience.</p><p>These small cars can use powerful experimental equipment to make their way through this household. Jump boosters enable them to reach greater heights and bound over obstacles. Latch onto far away points with grappling hooks. Adhere to metal surfaces with magnet wheels, and manipulate faraway objects with the magnets.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <div id="carousel_1021864"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p>Each room in <em>WheelMates</em> offers a compact playground, filled with hidden paths, mechanical puzzles, and story details waiting to be discovered. From narrow corridors to towering furniture, the house reveals itself gradually. Inspired by <a title="Genres > Metroidvania [253 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/metroidvania">Metroidvania</a>s, backtrack through the mansion, discovering previously inaccessible locales and formerly unsolvable puzzles. </p><p>With roots in classic RC games like Re-Volt and puzzle-<a title="Genres > Platformer [815 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> experiences the team wanted to bring a new type of cooperative adventure with <em>WheelMates</em>, where RC cars become heroes of the game. The movement mechanics of remote-controlled cars, the fun of driving through household environments, all combined with a bunch of power-ups, open up so many possibilities for our fresh take on a genre so many people love.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>RC Adventure</strong> – You drive toy cars through the house, slowly uncovering its owner’s secrets. Remote-controlled cars are the heart of this shared adventure.</li><li><strong>True Cooperative <a title="Companies > Experience [213 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong> – Play together in a genuine cooperative journey where challenges, new locations, and the story can only be unlocked by working as a team.</li><li><strong>Variety of Powers</strong> – Use upgrades like winch rope-swinging, magnetic wheels, and many more to unlock new ways to play.</li><li><strong>Many Paths to Explore</strong> – As you progress, you unlock hidden rooms, opening up new paths in previously discovered areas.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/wheelmates/january-28-2026/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="WheelMates - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/S2GJlxftND0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/co-op-rc-adventure-game-wheelmates-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Side-Scrolling Robo-Shooter Remake 'FZ: Formation Z' Blasts Onto Switch 2 This May]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/side-scrolling-robo-shooter-remake-fz-formation-z-blasts-onto-switch-2-this-may</link>
            <guid>1418449</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>

<p>City Connection and Granzella have announced that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fz-formation-z">FZ: Formation Z</a>, the side-scrolling robot shooter from all the way back in the perm-riddled dark days of 1984 (so long ago this writer had a full head of hair!), is to be resurrected on Switch 2 this very year (thanks, <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2026/01/city-connection-and-granzellas-formation-z-remake-finally-has-a-release-date">Time Extension</a>).</p>
<p>Now, 1984 is a long time ago, yes, and so you may be thinking 'meh' to the idea of resurrecting something so very antiquated. Until you check out the trailer at the top of this article, that is. Also, you may have already played the OG game already on Switch via the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/arcade_archives_formation_z">Arcade Archive re-release</a> and are now just a rabid fan. Welcome, either way!</p>
<p>It does seem as though the devs here have gone to town with this remake of a Jaleco golden oldie, with a full revision of everything from the graphics, gameplay, and sound, whilst "staying true to the classic gameplay and intuitive controls of switching between Robot and Flight forms". They've even brought new weapons to the table. It certainly looks like a good time, judging by the intense and colourful action on show in the gameplay vid, with some very nice <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/r-type_dimensions_ex">R-Type</a>-but-with-big-stonking-robots vibes that this writer is here for all day long.</p>
<p>The remake will release in Japan on 21st May across multiple platforms, and although a Western release hasn't been officially confirmed for Switch at the time of writing, the trailer above does contain the Clear River Games logo, who were attached to publish the game in Europe according to <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2024/11/embracer-group-interim-report-leaks-fz-formation-z-western-release-plans">a release plan leak from Embracer Group</a>. So, fingers crossed, then.</p>
<p>More good news: It'll arrive in both digital and physical forms, and the physical isn't a Game-Key Card, either. Huzzah!</p>
<p>Digital editions will set you back 4400 yen (so roughly £20 or whatever that is where you're located). The physical edition comes in two flavours: a fancy Limited Edition for 14,850 yen (around the £70 mark) which includes a soundtrack, robot-making kit, bonus weapon content and a fancy box for presentation, and a slightly less snazzy standard physical for 5,940 yen (almost 30 British pounds).</p>
<p>Finally, here's some more official details, as per <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2728420/FZ_Formation_Z/">the Steam page</a>, and some screens:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Key Features</p>
<ul>
<li>Transforming Gameplay: Rule the Land or the Air!
<ul>
<li>Your Ixpel can transform in real-time between land and air as long as your energy lasts.</li>
<li>Will you choose the Robot Form to dominate the ground with melee attacks and precision shots, or the Flight form to rip through the battlefield at overwhelming speeds?</li>
<li>Traverse five vast Mission freely and carve out your own path to victory.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Customize Performance in The Factory
<ul>
<li>Use FZ Points earned in missions to unlock new Ixpel and cosmetic items. Enhance your firepower by equipping modules into four available slots.</li>
<li>Whether you build a well-balanced Ixpel with no openings or specialize one trait to its absolute limit is entirely up to you.</li>
<li>With Part swaps, different colours, and stickers, the joy of building your ultimate style is yours to discover.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Challenge Your Limits in Score Attack
<ul>
<li>Once a mission is cleared, Score Attack Mode is unlocked.</li>
<li>You can challenge individual mission to beat your personal best, with high scores recorded for each area.</li>
<li>Use your fully customized machine to rewrite the record books.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Extensive Archives: Record Your Path Through Battle
<ul>
<li>War Record: Tracks total enemies defeated, sortie counts for each Ixpel, and more.</li>
<li>Enemy Data: A detailed encyclopedia of every foe you’ve taken down.</li>
<li>Gallery: Unlock stunning artwork by completing specific in-game conditions.</li>
<li>As you fight, your legacy grows. Keep battling to complete your records!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>

<hr>
<p><em>Does FZ: Formation Z look like your cup of T? Played the OG? Speak words to me! (In the comments.)</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:173308,170014 @ 1769614897 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/fz-formation-z-launches-may-21-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-2-and-pc" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/fz-formation-z-launches-may-21-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-2-and-pc">gematsu.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.timeextension.com/news/2026/01/city-connection-and-granzellas-formation-z-remake-finally-has-a-release-date" rel="noopener" href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2026/01/city-connection-and-granzellas-formation-z-remake-finally-has-a-release-date">timeextension.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/a5d8d3b5b44c48ebc2fd772ed1ad08bf @ 1769612130 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/side-scrolling-robo-shooter-remake-fz-formation-z-blasts-onto-switch-2-this-may]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earth Must Die publishers say an "alien orgy depicted as a gyrating lump on the floor" left the game's Steam launch "unclear"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/earth-must-die-publishers-say-an-alien-orgy-depicted-as-a-gyrating-lump-on-the-floor-left-the-games-steam-launch-unclear</link>
            <guid>1418446</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Valve's bouncers reportedly requested a video so they could double check the context of the gyrating lump orgy</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valve-steam-reviewed-earth-must-sue-alien-orgy-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>No More Robots</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>What Steam operators Valve are and aren't prepared to allow onto their storefront has been a major talking point for the past year or so, especially when it comes to mature or sexually-themed content. Our Edwin's done some <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-payment-networks-control-the-definition-of-acceptable-sex-in-videogames">fine reporting on the topic</a> and how it relates to payment processors, as well as delving into individual cases like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/saturnalia-creators-santa-ragione-will-wind-down-operations-after-valve-ban-horror-game-horses-from-steam">Santa Ragione's Horses</a>.</p>
<p>Now, the developers of point-and-click comedy <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/point-and-click-adventure-game-filled-with-ah-yeah-them-british-actors-earth-must-die-is-out-later-this-month">Earth Must Die</a> say things looked "unclear" for a bit in terms of whether they'd be able to launch on Steam, with the platform then offering a thumbs up after reviewing footage of an "alien orgy".</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Up until a few days ago, it was unclear if we were actually going to be allowed to launch Earth Must Die on Steam, as Valve had told us that they were 'unable to verify' the context of the alien orgy," publishers No More Robots told <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/adventure/valve-needed-to-verify-footage-of-the-alien-orgy-in-earth-must-die-before-it-was-allowed-to-launch-on-steam/#viafoura-comments">Painting Collection Gamer</a>. "We were required to record and send footage of said orgy for their verification."</p>
<p>Thankfully, once that footage was sent over, approval was forthcoming. That said, whether on Valve's orders or by No More Robots' own volition, Earth Must Die's Steam page bears a mature content warning specifying that "there is a puzzle that takes place in an alien adult bookshop, and an alien orgy depicted as a gyrating lump on the floor".</p><p>As much as it's funny to imagine a Valve staffer examining footage of cartoon extraterrestrials going at it, No More Robots' retelling of the events paints what's turned into an amusing anecdote as something that could potentially have thrown a major spanner in the works. If games that dabble in jokey depictions of shagging face that sort of gaze into the void, right up until they're sure Valve are 100% satisfied, one can only imagine the uncertainty more serious explorations of mature themes might encounter.</p>
<p>On one hand, Valve have a right to apply the rules they decide to enforce on their storefront, even if said storefront's domination of the PC space makes such calls far weightier than they might otherwise be. On the other, as Edwin's reported, the matter of credit card companies and payment processors influencing what those rules - and the rules of other storefronts - are when it comes specifically to adult content complicates the matter significantly.</p>
<p>At least in this case, the alien orgy made it through whatever contextual hoops it needed, so that No More Robots' game about British actors and comics quipping their way through a tale about a martian ruler doing quirky stuff could drop as planned this week.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/earth-must-die-publishers-say-an-alien-orgy-depicted-as-a-gyrating-lump-on-the-floor-left-the-games-steam-launch-unclear]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>