<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:46:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Psychological horror Heart of the Forest release date set for February 12th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/08/psychological-horror-heart-of-the-forest-release-date-set-for-february-12th/</link>
            <guid>1400614</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Publisher Wales Interactive and developer Trapped Predator have announced that the interactive psychological horror FMV game Heart of the Forest will be released on February 12th. The confirmed platforms are PC, PS5, PS4, Series X|S, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, iOS and Android. It is a live action story that follows a group of students as they explore Germany’s Black Forest, which is home to an evil spirit.</p>
<p><iframe title="Heart of the Forest - Official Reveal Trailer | Horror Games Award Showcase 2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r-MNjJEcHkE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In Heart of the Forest players will see the world through each character’s point of view, making choices on the information available to steer the story. Each character has their own fears and traumas that are exploited by the forest spirit to scare and hunt the students down. Your choices will determine who lives and who dies. Some of the footage definitely has The Blair Witch Project vibes, which is likely to have been an influence on Heart of the Forest.</p>
<p>In a statement Trapped Predator said, “<em>Heart of the Forest is our modern take on German folklore set in the mysterious Black Forest. In our debut title, we invite you to join our four protagonists on a chilling journey into their darkest nightmares. See you inside the forest!”</em></p>

<p>A price for Heart of the Forest is yet to be confirmed.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/08/psychological-horror-heart-of-the-forest-release-date-set-for-february-12th/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Developer Direct Returns This Month, Will Feature a Look at Fable, Forza Horizon 6, and Game Freak’s New Non-Pokémon Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-developer-direct-2026-fable-forza-horizon-6-game-freak-playground-games/</link>
            <guid>1400611</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Xbox has <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-2026/">announced the return</a> of its <strong>Xbox Developer Direct</strong> event on <strong>January 22, 2026</strong>, which so far looks to be a Playground Games-focused event with a look at both Forza Horizon 6 and Fable, though tagging along and not to be outdone is Pokémon developer <strong>Game Freak</strong>, which will be showcasing its upcoming non-Pokémon game, <a href="https://wccftech.com/beast-of-reincarnation-is-a-game-you-wouldnt-expect-from-pokemon-series-developer-game-freak-launches-in-2026-on-pc-and-consoles/">Beast of Reincarnation</a>.</p>



<p>That's what we know will be there, but there will likely be more shown at the event; every year that Xbox has hosted its Developer Direct to start off the new year, it has led with a few titles that it confirms will be shown ahead of time, and held back one or two surprises to be revealed at the show. </p>



<p><a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/01/09/xbox-developer-direct-2025/">2025's Developer Direct,</a> for example, announced that we'd get a look at <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/south-of-midnight-boring-combat-drags-down-a-beautiful-and-emotional-story/">South of Midnight</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/clair-obscur-expedition-33-dont-fear-the-paintress/">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/doom-the-dark-ages-review/">DOOM: The Dark Ages</a> ahead of the show. The surprise was the reveal of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ninja-gaiden-4-bathed-in-blood/">Ninja Gaiden 4</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ninja-gaiden-2-black-the-edge-of-the-dragon-sword/">Ninja Gaiden 2: Black</a>, to round out the show.</p>



<p>As for what we know Xbox will show at the event, according to the Xbox Wire blog post, we'll get to see gameplay for all three of the aforementioned titles, with the Forza Horizon 6 segment being "<em>a deep-dive</em>" on the coming racer.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>What's more interesting to note, however, is that Xbox Developer Direct events have a history of revealing release dates for the games shown. It's not a surefire thing, of course, but if Xbox keeps that tradition for this year, then we can expect release dates for Fable, Forza Horizon 6, and Beast of Reincarnation.</p>



<p>We could have anticipated a release date for Forza Horizon 6, as we've known that <a href="https://wccftech.com/forza-horizon-6-targeting-h1-2026-launch-window-says-insider/">it is targeting a first-half of 2026 release window</a>. Beast of Reincarnation is a surprise and a bit of a wildcard, since we don't know too much about the upcoming action RPG from Game Freak, who seem to be stepping far outside their comfort zone by making something totally separate from the most well-known franchise in the world.</p>



<p>Fable is the most intriguing of the bunch to get a release date for. The last we heard, <a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-delayed-technical-issues-ps5-2026/">after it was delayed out of 2025 and into 2026</a>, was that <a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-rumored-missing-2026-launch-window/">it might not even hit its proposed 2026 release window</a>. Hopefully, its presence at the Developer Direct means we will get a release date and that the game's development isn't as troubled as it has seemed from the outside looking in. </p>



<p>Beyond that, who knows what will be shown at the event. We could get another look at <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-shooter-games-2026-the-year-of-xbox-studios/">Gears of War: E-Day</a>, or something that's not yet on anyone's radar. This year is Xbox's 25th anniversary year, so we ought to expect Team Green to go all-out right from the beginning. We'll find out when the show premieres on <strong>January 22, 2026, at 10am PT / 1pm ET / 6pm BT</strong>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/xbox-developer-direct-2026-fable-forza-horizon-6-game-freak-playground-games/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The PC market braces for an AI-driven storm]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/858505/pc-market-ram-nand-ssd-gpu-pricing-notepad</link>
            <guid>1400608</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The personal computer has remained surprisingly resilient to change over the past 15 years. Apple promised a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/8/9/9115503/post-pc-is-just-pc">“post-PC” era with the iPad</a> in 2010 and failed to deliver one. Smartphones even overtook laptops as the most popular device to connect to the internet a decade ago, but millions of people still kept buying PCs every year. But this PC resiliency is going to be tested even further this year.</p><p>RAM and NAND / SSD prices have surged in recent months due to shortages created by AI data center demand. Some stores have had to sell memory <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/828337/ram-memory-shortage-crunch-market-prices-central-micro-center">like it’s lobster</a>, prebuilt PC costs <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/831032/cyberpowerpc-maingear-ram-price-increases-pc-gaming">have risen</a>, and some assemblers are even <a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/find-your-own-memory-this-system-builder-now-sells-pcs-without-ram">selling PCs without RAM</a>.</p><p>Now, we’re about to see how the shortage hits regular laptops and PCs from the likes of Lenovo, Dell, HP, Asus, and Acer. <a href="https://www.trendforce.com/presscenter/news/20251211-12831.html">TrendForce predicts</a> that memory prices are projected to “rise sharply again in the first quarter of 2026.” More price rises will only put further pressure on laptop and PC pricing, and we’re seeing early signs that PC makers are adjusting prices at CES this week.</p><p>Asus <a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/asus-officially-announces-price-hikes-from-january-5-right-before-ces-2026">announced</a> to its channel partners this week that it’s implementing price hikes across its products as a result of the memory market conditions. Dell also <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/851047/dell-xps-14-16-13-laptops-brand-return-ces-2026">adjusted the launch pricing</a> of its XPS 14 and XPS 16 just hours before they were announced this week, in a sign that laptop pricing is going to become increasingly fluid. Lenovo has been <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-11-24/lenovo-stockpiling-pc-memory-due-to-unprecedented-ai-squeeze?embedded-checkout=true">stockpiling PC memory</a> to try and weather the storm throughout 2026, and HP has warned it will have to increase prices and offer lower RAM configurations later this year. Like Lenovo, HP also has a stockpile of memory, but it expects the continued rise in costs will begin eating into PC product margins by May.</p><p>There’s no quick fix for PC makers, either. Offering less RAM on laptops will be difficult for manufacturers, particularly below the 8GB threshold. Windows 11 has a minimum RAM requirement of 4GB, but it doesn’t run particularly well in those conditions. While TrendForce predicts some smartphones are likely to return to just 4GB this year, “for budget notebooks, DRAM cannot be reduced quickly due to processor pairing needs and operating system limitations.”</p><p>The timing of this memory shortage couldn’t be any worse for Microsoft and its PC partners. Windows 10 just hit end of life in October, and many businesses are in the process of migrating to Windows 11. That often involves a PC refresh cycle, and there were strong signs throughout 2025 that PC <a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS53855725">shipments were accelerating</a> thanks to a refresh of the existing install base. That momentum could be derailed later this year once RAM stockpiles are depleted.</p><p>Timing isn’t the only problem for the PC market, as the increased prices of RAM and SSDs could be permanent instead of a temporary supply constraint. “This is not just a cyclical shortage driven by a mismatch in supply and demand, but a potentially permanent, strategic reallocation of the world’s silicon wafer capacity,” <a href="https://www.idc.com/resource-center/blog/global-memory-shortage-crisis-market-analysis-and-the-potential-impact-on-the-smartphone-and-pc-markets-in-2026/">warns IDC</a>. “For decades, the production of DRAM and NAND Flash for smartphones and PCs was the primary driver for production. Today, that dynamic has inverted.”</p><p>The demand from hyperscalers like Microsoft, Google, Meta, and Amazon has pushed Samsung, SK Hynix, and Micron to pivot toward building high-bandwidth (HBM) and high-capacity DDR5 memory. “Every wafer allocated to an HBM stack for an Nvidia GPU is a wafer denied to the LPDDR5X module of a mid-range smartphone or the SSD of a consumer laptop,” says IDC.</p><p>This is going to have a big impact on the DIY market and PC gaming, too. “PC gaming is thriving at a time when overall consumer PC shipments have declined by 14 percent in the last five years… annual gaming PC shipments are up 50 percent,” said Henry Lin, director of product management at Nvidia, in a briefing with <em>The Verge</em> last week.</p><p>The popularity of PC gaming has allowed smaller assemblers to offer custom prebuilt systems at competitive prices. These smaller builders can’t stockpile RAM or SSDs, and “will bear the greatest burden of the shortage,” warns IDC. “That in turn represents an opportunity for large OEMs to gain share from smaller assemblers in the gaming space by positioning prebuilt systems as offering higher value.”</p><p>Demand for memory looks set to impact GPU prices too. <a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/board-channels-amd-and-nvidia-gpu-price-hikes-may-reach-aib-cards-in-jan-feb-2026">Rumors have suggested</a> that Nvidia could force GPU partners to adjust pricing to factor in increased memory costs. “The demand for memory in the market is at record levels, and this does mean supply will be tight,” admitted Ben Berraondo, director of global PR for Nvidia GeForce, in a briefing with <em>The Verge</em> last week. “There have been no major changes in how we manage memory with our customers. There are no major supply chain changes to GeForce,” says Berraondo.</p><p>Despite a lack of major memory changes to GeForce, pricing is already starting to increase. <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=44583&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fp%2Fpl%3Fd%3DRTX%2B5090" rel="sponsored">Newegg</a> has started listing a variety of RTX 5090 cards at well above $4,000. It’s becoming increasingly difficult to find an RTX 5090 for under $3,000, after prices were <a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5090-finally-drops-to-1999-in-us-rtx-5080-dips-7-below-msrp">close to</a> the $1,999 retail price in September.</p><p>Berraondo didn’t comment directly on the rumors of $5,000 pricing for the RTX 5090, but he did point to Nvidia’s Founders Edition model still being listed at $1,999 at <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fproduct%2Fnvidia-geforce-rtx-5090-32gb-gddr7-founders-edition-graphics-card-dark-gun-metal%2FJ3GWYHGPCP" rel="sponsored">Best Buy</a>. That’s great, but it’s constantly out of stock so it’s not representative of the true retail pricing of the RTX 5090.</p><p>If the costs of building a gaming PC don’t stabilize in 2026, Microsoft will also feel increased pressure on its next-gen Xbox plans. Microsoft is aggressively pivoting toward PC for the future of Xbox consoles, with the handheld Xbox Ally devices just the beginning of its plans. Component costs could force the price of the next-gen Xbox even higher and also impact Sony’s plans with the PS6 and Valve’s upcoming Steam Machine.</p><p>The memory shortage also threatens to impact Microsoft’s AI PC push. Microsoft set a surprising minimum of 16GB of RAM for its Copilot Plus PCs, in order to handle local small language models. Qualcomm has been pushing to bring Windows on Arm (Copilot Plus PCs) down to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24334870/qualcomm-snapdragon-x-laptops-mini-pcs-ces-2025">$600 price range</a>, but that effort looks set to reverse due to memory costs.</p><p>It increasingly feels like we’re witnessing a battle over the future of the PC, where component prices and AI features are having a big impact on computing. If AI demand wins the battle then more traditional computing tasks will increasingly be performed in the cloud. That could force businesses to increasingly move to virtual machines instead of refreshing laptops and gamers to look at cloud streaming services instead of buying an expensive gaming PC.</p><p>I don’t think this battle means the end of the PC anytime soon. It just feels like another step in Big Tech marching us toward an unproven AI future. I have faith the PC will survive and evolve and prove <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225356/pc-sales-shipments-2020-growth-idc-canalys-remote-work">once again</a> how important it truly is.</p><div><p id="the-pad"><h2>The pad</h2></p></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>Satya Nadella is now blogging about AI slop. </strong>Microsoft CEO <strong>Satya Nadella</strong> created his very own “sn scratchpad” blog over the holidays, generating social media outrage in the process. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/852630/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-scratchpad-blog-ai-slop-comments">Nadella’s first blog entry</a> argues that everyone needs to move “beyond the arguments of [AI] slop vs sophistication.” It’s an argument that has gone viral on social media networks, with “Microslop” trending on X this week. That’s not too surprising, given the backlash to Microsoft’s big AI push. The Microslop moniker is particularly popular among gamers, who aren’t happy with the changes Microsoft has been making to Windows and Xbox.</span></li><li><span><strong>LG forced a Copilot web app onto its TVs, but will let you delete it. </strong>LG is letting users delete a Microsoft Copilot shortcut that it i<a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/847685/lg-copilot-web-app-delete">nstalled on newer TVs</a> after a backlash over the unremovable icon. The icon was simply a shortcut to the web version of Copilot, but the response from Reddit users shows just how unpopular Copilot is among consumers.</span></li><li><span><strong>Microsoft isn’t rewriting Windows in Rust with AI</strong>. Continuing the backlash trend over Microsoft’s AI moves, distinguished engineer <strong>Galen Hunt</strong> announced that Microsoft was <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7407863239289729024/">planning to eliminate</a> “every line of C and C++ from Microsoft by 2030” and use AI to rewrite Microsoft’s largest codebases. The post led to headlines about Microsoft rewriting Windows in Rust with AI and plenty of concern over potential reliability issues for Windows. Hunt was forced to update his original post and clarify that Windows is not being rewritten in Rust with AI.</span></li><li><span><strong>Microsoft “Project Strong ARMed” is all about moving to ARM64. </strong>Over the holidays, Microsoft posted a new <a href="https://careerhub.microsoft.com/careers/job/1970393556627382">job listing</a> that revealed the company has a “Project Strong ARMed” team that’s part of a strategic initiative meant to “transition to ARM64 architecture across the E+D (Experiences &amp; Devices) division.” With Microsoft’s focus on AI features in Windows, its close partnership with Qualcomm, and Intel’s struggles, this all makes sense. Interestingly, part of the job is about driving adoption of Microsoft’s own Cobalt Arm-powered CPUs over traditional Intel and AMD chips.</span></li><li><span><strong>Three big Microsoft employee departures for 2026. </strong>Microsoft is losing veteran employees <strong>Steve Clayton</strong> and <strong>Louis Kahn</strong>. Clayton <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7406380693200715776/">is leaving</a> to become Cisco’s chief communications officer after 28 years at Microsoft, and Kahn is <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/louiskahn_nvidialife-activity-7406707966801952770-TuKZ/">joining Nvidia</a> after 32 years at Microsoft working closely on Xbox engineering. <strong>Manik Gupta</strong>, who was responsible for Microsoft Teams consumer, Skype, and GroupMe at Microsoft, is <a href="https://x.com/manikgupta/status/2008630046945407219">also leaving</a> after nearly five years. Gupta first joined Microsoft in 2021, bringing a wealth of consumer app knowledge that Microsoft desperately needed at the time. It must have been a tough gig trying to turn around Skype and get consumers to care about Microsoft Teams.</span></li><li><span><strong>Dell admits consumers don’t care about AI PCs. </strong>In a surprisingly honest interview, Dell’s head of product, <strong>Kevin Terwilliger</strong>, told <em>PC Gamer</em> that consumers simply aren’t buying PCs for AI features right now and they <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/857723/dell-consumers-ai-pcs-comments">could even be confusing people</a>. “What we’ve learned over the course of this year, especially from a consumer perspective, is they’re not buying based on AI,” said Terwilliger. The biggest benefits of a Qualcomm-powered Copilot Plus PC is the performance and battery life improvements instead of the AI features alone, and Dell is now starting 2026 by moving beyond being “all about” AI PCs.</span></li><li><span><strong>The first Xbox Game Pass drop of 2026 is a good one. </strong>Microsoft is adding <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em> to Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass on January 13th, followed by <em>Resident Evil Village</em> for Ultimate, Premium, and PC Game Pass subscribers a week later on January 20th. Other titles<a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/06/xbox-game-pass-january-2026-wave-1/"> coming to Game Pass this month</a> include <em>Brews &amp; Bastards</em>, <em>Little Nightmares Enhanced Edition</em>, <em>Final Fantasy</em>, <em>My Little Pony: A Zephyr Heights Mystery</em>, and <em>Mio: Memories in Orbit</em>. That’s a good start to the year for Game Pass, after a quiet end to 2025.</span></li><li><span><strong>No, Microsoft didn’t rebrand Office to Microsoft 365 Copilot. </strong>Microsoft has had big parts of the internet confused this week, again. Posts on Reddit, Hacker News, and X have all claimed that Microsoft has rebranded Office to Microsoft 365 Copilot. It’s all down to some confusing text on Microsoft’s <a href="http://office.com/">Office.com</a> website that makes it seem like Microsoft 365 Copilot app is the new name for Office. Microsoft renamed its Microsoft 365 hub app a year ago, but the internet only just found out about this change recently. Either way, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/856149/microsoft-365-office-rebrand-copilot">Microsoft has clarified it hasn’t made any branding changes to Office</a>. I’m hoping Microsoft updates its Office website to make things clearer, but I won’t hold my breath.</span></li><li><span><strong>Xbox Cloud Gaming is coming to Hisense TVs.</strong> Microsoft’s first<a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/05/xbox-bring-cloud-gaming-select-hisense-homeos-powered-smart-tvs/"> Xbox announcement</a> of 2026 is the launch of Xbox Cloud Gaming on select Hisense and V homeOS-powered smart TVs. The Xbox app first launched on Samsung TVs, followed by Amazon Fire TV devices, then select LG TVs, and now Hisense TVs. We don’t have an exact date for when the Xbox app will be available on the Hisense TVs, but Microsoft says it’s coming at some point in 2026.</span></li><li><span><strong>Qualcomm hints at Arm-powered Windows gaming handhelds. </strong>We haven’t seen any Arm-powered handheld gaming PCs at CES this year, but that might change in the coming months. Qualcomm <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/855222/qualcomm-hints-we-might-see-windows-gaming-handhelds-at-gdc-in-march">has hinted to <em>The Verge</em></a> that we should be “keeping an eye” on GDC in March for possible Arm-powered Windows handhelds. That timing lines up with Microsoft’s plans to launch Windows 11 version 26H1 exclusively on Snapdragon X2 devices in the spring and would line up well with some upcoming Xbox PC features. All of this is coming on top of another <a href="https://www.theverge.com/gadgets/850074/2025-windows-arm-laptops-qualcomm-intel-amd-nvidia">great year for Windows on Arm</a>.</span></li><li><span><strong>Microsoft Edge is getting a Copilot-inspired redesign. </strong>Microsoft is preparing to launch a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/854832/microsoft-edge-copilot-redesign-ui-features">major UI refresh of its Edge browser soon</a>. The software maker has started bringing the design language from Copilot to early Canary and Dev test versions of its Microsoft Edge browser. The design changes include a settings section that looks identical to the Copilot app, updated context menus, and an updated new tab page. I don’t actually mind the Copilot UI itself, but I do wonder what this all means for the Fluent design language and whether we’ll see similar changes in Windows itself.</span></li><li><span><strong>Microsoft has removed phone activation from Windows. </strong>Microsoft has started changing the activation experience for perpetual Windows licenses. The traditional telephone-based product activation process was <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/activate-microsoft-perpetual-products-using-the-product-activation-portal-64fdc7f5-ce38-42a9-aea8-393020149983">quietly removed on December 3rd</a>, in favor of a fully online process. “Customers will instead use the Product Activation Portal,” says Katharine Holdsworth, partner group product manager at Microsoft, in a statement to <em>Notepad</em>. “Internet connection is not required for the device being activated; however, customers will require a secondary device, such as smartphone, tablet, or computer with internet connection to access the online portal.”</span></li><li><span><strong>Xbox’s Developer Direct returns on January 22nd. </strong>Microsoft’s annual Xbox Developer Direct event is<a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/858471/xbox-developer-direct-forza-horizon-6-fable-beast-of-reincarnation-stream"> taking place on January 22nd</a> this year. The fourth Developer Direct will provide a closer look at two of Microsoft’s biggest Xbox games this year, <em>Forza Horizon 6</em> and <em>Fable</em>, as well as a first in-depth look at <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em> from Game Freak. I’m hoping we might get a release date for <em>Fable</em>, but Microsoft will likely play it safe with the broad 2026 release window instead.</span></li></ul></div><p>I’m always keen to hear from readers, so please drop a comment here, or you can reach me at <a href="mailto:notepad@theverge.com">notepad@theverge.com</a> if you want to discuss anything else. If you’ve heard about any of Microsoft’s secret projects, you can reach me via email at <a href="mailto:notepad@theverge.com">notepad@theverge.com</a> or speak to me confidentially on the Signal messaging app, where <a href="https://signal.me/#eu/soK8N9/6J1KVh2/ZZblbDEGXHNH1gK0Q+RaxJQ7vUxDDTYvxX8hARqMZfjuz3Egj">I’m tomwarren.01</a>. I’m also tomwarren on Telegram, if you’d prefer to chat there.</p><p>Thanks for subscribing to <em>Notepad</em>.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/858505/pc-market-ram-nand-ssd-gpu-pricing-notepad]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Architect Of Ruin is a beautiful dark fantasy temple builder from former Valve devs and Hooded Horse]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/architect-of-ruin-is-a-beautiful-dark-fantasy-temple-builder-from-former-valve-devs-and-hooded-horse</link>
            <guid>1400602</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Lapsed Dungeon Keepers rejoice</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_Yf5fzOX.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_Yf5fzOX.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_Yf5fzOX.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_Yf5fzOX.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_Yf5fzOX.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_Yf5fzOX.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_Yf5fzOX.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_Yf5fzOX.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_Yf5fzOX.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hooded Horse</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Was your new year resolution to rebuild an evil temple on behalf of a baleful god? I bring wonderful news, then. The former Epic and Valve developers of Dead Money LLC have signed a wicked pact with the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy game</a> illuminati of Hooded Horse to release Architect of Ruin – a “completely hand drawn” fantasy colony simulation game that looks like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dwarf-fortress">Dwarf Fortress</a> twisted by 45 degrees and pumped full of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dungeon-keeper">Dungeon Keeper</a> DNA. I am already in love with the trees, their rich foliage flattening to a core of shadow. Do not turn your back on the trees. Especially when you’re chopping them down to make arcane icons.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
“The old temple lies in ruins, its power dormant, its faithful scattered,” explains <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3778820/Architect_of_Ruin/">the Steam blurb</a>. “As the new master of these broken halls, guide a growing cult against adversity and meddling heroes. Balance resource management, construction, and survival to the glory of dark gods. Untomb forbidden knowledge, perform sinister rituals, and rebuild a long-forgotten sanctuary one blood-soaked stone at a time. Thus does the age of darkness begin.”
</p>



<p>
Here are some things you will build for your creepy lair of skulduggery: turrets, tanning racks, storehouses, bedrooms, chimney stoves, pillars and butcher blocks. And here are some beings you will enlist and/or conjure and bend to your will: “irascible sorcerors”, “unstable zealots”, goblins (I think) and “reanimated thralls”. There are also some deer in the screens but they don’t appear to be especially evil deer, and are probably not recruitable. 
</p><p>
Aside from tending to your horde, you’ll need to chase away angry mobs, rival cultists, and meddling heroes. By the sounds of things, you’re free to repurpose the bodies of any good guys you slaughter. Hey, walking skeletons don’t grow on trees. Not even trees as pungent with menace as these. Unless we’re being metaphorical and talking about dangling gibbets, or whatever.
</p>
<p>
Dead Money LLC number three core members in total. They include co-owner Brandon Reinhart, who has credits on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/half-life-alyx">Half-Life: Alyx</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/counter-strike-global-offensive">Counter-Strike: Global Offensive</a>, Artifact and Dota: Underlords. There’s no release date yet, so you’ll just have to pop along and do blood sacrifices in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/timberborn">Timberborn</a> for the moment, assuming that’s possible. I haven’t played Timberborn.
</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/architect-of-ruin-is-a-beautiful-dark-fantasy-temple-builder-from-former-valve-devs-and-hooded-horse]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Stranger Things Secret ‘Conformity Gate’ Finale Conspiracy Is Dead]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-conformity-gate-secret-netflix-crash-2000658155</link>
            <guid>1400593</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>A subset of </span><i><span>Stranger Things </span></i><span>fans </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-season-5-finale-reaction-byler-acting-2000656424"><span>unsatisfied with the horror series’ finale</span></a><span> have spent the last week </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-season-5-finale-matt-duffer-interview-2000656663"><span>dunking on the creators and actors</span></a><span> and also peddling a conspiracy theory that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-secret-finale-conformity-gate-explained-2000656704"><span>Netflix was holding a secret finale episode</span></a><span> that would explain away things these fans didn’t like about the existing conclusion. According to the “Conformity Gate” theory, the ninth episode of </span><i><span>Stranger Things</span></i><span>’ fifth season was supposed to go live on the streaming service last night, January 7, at 8 p.m. ET. The theory had become so widespread that fans claim Netflix </span><a href="https://ftw.usatoday.com/story/entertainment/pop-culture/2026/01/07/stranger-things-conformity-gate-crashed-netflix/88073821007/"><span>crashed around this time</span></a><span> as fans flocked to the streaming service and overloaded the servers. When they finally managed to get the app to boot up, they found that no such ninth episode had been published.</span></p>   <p><span>While the Conformity Gate theory was an interesting thought experiment, and I’ll admit I watched enough videos about it that I wasn’t quite convinced but was at least willing to see it all play out, this turn of events was hardly surprising, especially after </span><a href="https://variety.com/2026/tv/news/stranger-things-conformity-gate-final-episode-doesnt-exist-1236625074/"><i><span>Variety</span></i></a><span> published a story hours ahead of the supposed launch debunking the theory.</span></p>

 <p><span>What is surprising, however, is just how far reaching Conformity Gate had become before it was inevitably disproven. Some corporate accounts, like the one belonging to the Empire State Building of all things, were posting about </span><i><span>Stranger Things</span></i><span> fans’ collective psychosis, whether in genuine support of the theory or just to take advantage of a trending topic for social media engagement. The Slim Jim account </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@matcrackz/video/7592796861153414413"><span>is in everyone’s comments</span></a><span> like Joyce Byers telling everyone the Conformity Gate theory is canon, to them.</span></p>

   <p><span>Perhaps the interest of brands is understandable, though, in light of what a phenomenon </span><i><span>Stranger Things </span></i><span>was right up through its final episode.. The fifth season has already cracked </span><a href="https://www.netflix.com/tudum/top10/most-popular/tv"><span>Netflix’s top 10 all-time most-streamed series</span></a><span>, and even if some fans online are so unsatisfied with how it all ended that they’re imagining another episode that might fix it all, the series still has enough cultural cache that every social media manager is probably looking at Conformity Gate as a chance to ride the coattails of a trend. Now, however, even people who are actually part of the </span><i><span>Stranger Things </span></i><span>brand are starting to post about it, and sorry to those holding out hope, but the few times that people like actor Brett Gelman have acknowledged the conspiracy, it hasn’t been to confirm it. Here he is addressing Conformity Gate by name while lipsyncing a cover of Prince’s “When Doves Cry,” specifically the line “Maybe you’re just like my mother, she’s never satisfied.”</span></p>

   <p><span>The </span><i><span>Stranger Things</span></i> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@strangerthings"><span>social media accounts</span></a><span> also now have “ALL EPISODES OF STRANGER THINGS ARE NOW PLAYING” </span><a href="https://x.com/Stranger_Things"><span>in their bios</span></a><span>, and it doesn’t get much clearer than that. The X account allegedly responsible for starting the conspiracy, @67gate, has set their profile to private. Now that the dream seems to be truly dead, fans are reacting in a lot of ways. Some are grieving, finally realizing the ending they didn’t like is, in fact, the finale of </span><i><span>Stranger Things</span></i><span>, while others are saying that the theory provided a fun ride for a week, and helped cushion the blow of the finale.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Unfortunately, if you scroll through the comments on videos about there being no ninth episode, you’ll also find people moving the goalpost and saying that a secret finale could still be coming, whether that be after the upcoming </span><i><span>One Last Adventure </span></i><span>documentary about the making of the final season, or at some other date they made up. Maybe they will return to reality in the coming days as more people disperse from the discussion.</span></p>

   <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">i wanna say a huge thank you to <a href="https://twitter.com/67gate?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@67gate</a> for conformitygate this was an incredibly fun adventure and i’ll never forget the mass byler canon spaces &amp; all that. she did us all a massive favor by creating such an amazing theory better than the duffers ever could’ve been capable of</p> <p>— eugène 𖤝 conformity gate .ᐟ (@emagoner) <a href="https://twitter.com/emagoner/status/2008984426328527176?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 7, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">well at least we went crazy together <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/conformitygate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#conformitygate</a> <a href="https://t.co/BXzDd6icnk">pic.twitter.com/BXzDd6icnk</a></p> <p>— emilia (@emlx_23) <a href="https://twitter.com/emlx_23/status/2009068930569261506?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">i still think <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/conformitygate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#conformitygate</a> is one of the coolest things ever and even if it’s not real, these theories were so interesting <a href="https://t.co/DOAxbLgSv8">pic.twitter.com/DOAxbLgSv8</a></p> <p>— kait! (@reidsgarcia_) <a href="https://twitter.com/reidsgarcia_/status/2009069023741542587?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">bothering my niece who believed in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/conformitygate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#conformitygate</a> propaganda <a href="https://t.co/PfK7SI2cWv">pic.twitter.com/PfK7SI2cWv</a></p> <p>— 𝓫𝓮𝓼𝓽𝓲𝓮 👩🏻‍🚀 (@bestiecinema) <a href="https://twitter.com/bestiecinema/status/2009072005589708885?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">this theory was great either way, because now its gonna haunt the duffer brothers knowing their finale was so bad we had to theorise and crash netflix for an alternate ending that didnt exist  <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/conformitygate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#conformitygate</a> <a href="https://t.co/KWdUg33Wqz">pic.twitter.com/KWdUg33Wqz</a></p> <p>— beca☆ (@feefohara) <a href="https://twitter.com/feefohara/status/2009071528525353289?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="qme" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/conformitygate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#conformitygate</a> <a href="https://t.co/OBUIaxvY91">pic.twitter.com/OBUIaxvY91</a></p> <p>— simon (@ssantam01) <a href="https://twitter.com/ssantam01/status/2009068611655397504?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2026</a></p></blockquote>    <p><span>“This whole thing has been the strangest mass delusion I’ve ever seen,” Totheendofsin wrote on </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nottheonion/comments/1q6z2kt/stranger_things_conformity_gate_allegedly_crashed/"><span>Reddit</span></a><span>. That about sums it up, but if you’re tuned into enough fandoms, you’ve probably seen people clowning like this. I lived through the spread of the </span><i><span>Mass Effect 3 </span></i><span>Indoctrination Theory years ago, and I’m sure, despite this idea of a “secret finale which will reveal that the bad ending was just a nightmare we’re all going to wake up from” having never actually proven true, we’ll live through a Conformity Gate moment again in a few years.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Taylor Swift fans are also notorious for </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/taylor-swift-life-of-a-showgirl-announcement-cover-date-2000617177"><span>looking for clues where there are none</span></a><span>, such as when they speculated for months that a re-recorded “Taylor’s Version” of the artist’s </span><i><span>Reputation </span></i><span>album was imminent based on small hints, only for Swift to reveal months later that she’d </span><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250531031134/https://www.taylorswift.com/"><span>barely recorded any of the tracks</span></a><span> for a re-release. Theorycrafting is fun, but when you stake this level of an emotional claim in it, you’re dooming yourself to devastating disappointment. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-conformity-gate-secret-netflix-crash-2000658155]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bose QuietComfort Ultra Earbuds (2nd Gen) Launched Pricier Than AirPods Pro 3, Now Match Their Price After a Drop]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bose-quietcomfort-ultra-earbuds-2nd-gen-launched-pricier-than-airpods-pro-3-now-match-their-price-after-a-drop-2000657843</link>
            <guid>1400590</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If upgrading your audio gear is on your New Year’s checklist, this deal is hard to beat. The Bose QuietComfort Ultra Earbuds are widely praised for their exceptional noise cancellation, immersive sound quality, and all-day comfort, making them a great choice in the premium earbuds category. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6592/">Right now, Amazon is offering them at a $49 discount, dropping the price from their usual $299 down to just $250 for a limited time</a>. Whether you’re tuning out distractions during your daily commute, staying focused while working, traveling, or simply enjoying your favorite playlists at home without the whine of your toddler crying in the other room (they just never stop, don’t they?), these earbuds deliver a noticeably superior listening experience. If you’ve been waiting for the right moment to invest in high-quality audio, this limited-time offer makes now an excellent opportunity to do so for less.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6592/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>World-Class Noise Cancellation</h2>
<p>When paying for a premium audio accessory, you expect solid noise cancellation—and it’s the real deal here. Our sister-site <a href="https://gizmodo.com/bose-quietcomfort-ultra-2-review-the-only-earbuds-you-want-on-an-airplane-2000646784">Gizmodo</a> put it through the ringer, testing the second-gen Bose QuietComfort Ultra earbuds in busy subways and crowded, chatty coffee shops. The results were it could block out&nbsp;<em>everything</em>.</p>
<p>In addition to Quiet Mode, the Bose QuietComfort Ultra earbuds make use of two other modes. Aware Mode is the transparency option where you can pass through the sounds of your surroundings. Wearing in-ear earbuds do a little bit of noise cancelling physically just because of how they’re design. You plug your ear with them after all. This mode will actually play the sounds from your environment that it’s picking up on its and play them through the earbuds. This is good for a range of use cases, particularly if you’re a runner training on the roads while listening to music. Best to be able to hear traffic to avoid any accidents.</p>



<p>The earbuds are also equipped with Immersion Mode which blends together noise-cancelling with 3D audio. This is able to track your head movements so it feels like you are surrounded on all sides by music that you can physically move throughout, even though it’s all just simulated in your ear.</p>
<p>You can choose between five super sleek colorways, though not all have been treated equally by the Amazon discount gods. The humble black model is right now the cheapest, so if you don’t want a pair of earbuds that are too loud (except in the traditional sense, you’re in luck. Offering slightly more pizazz is the desert gold option. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6592/">These are mostly black, but with a gold accent. They’re also priced at the lowest value of $250</a>. Just above that at $268 is a really striking midnight violet model. Then at full price still ($299,) is the white and deep plum versions.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6592/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bose-quietcomfort-ultra-earbuds-2nd-gen-launched-pricier-than-airpods-pro-3-now-match-their-price-after-a-drop-2000657843]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Trigger ‘Nade Nerf, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-trigger-nade-nerf-explained/</link>
            <guid>1400584</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>ARC Raiders has taken the gaming world by storm, and a key reason for its success is its combat. Whether you’re fighting PvP or PvE, there’s a strong variety of weapons and gadgets at your disposal, but one item in particular stands tall above the rest—the Trigger ‘Nade.</p>



<p>This pocket-sized rendition of a C4 packs a serious punch, and whilst it’s fairly effective against the enemy ARC, it’s best utilised against <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-ceo-the-game-isnt-about-shooting-other-players/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fellow raiders</a>. However, the Trigger ‘Nade might be a little bit too good at ending people’s raids, as plenty of fans have been clamouring for a nerf.</p>



<p>Follow along with this guide to see whether Trigger ‘Nades are actually being nerfed in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-tv-show-and-movie-ideas-being-pitched-embark/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a>, and the reason why fans are calling for one. </p>



<h2 id="h-are-trigger-nades-being-nerfed-in-arc-raiders">Are Trigger ‘Nades Being Nerfed In ARC Raiders?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>You’ll want a stash full of them. Image by Embark Studios.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>An ARC Raiders Community Manager has confirmed that the development team is looking into nerfing Trigger ‘Nades. </strong></p>



<p>The news was broken in the <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjJgbCVm_yRAxUaZ0EAHRmqL0gQFnoECAwQAQ&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdiscord.com%2Finvite%2Farcraiders&amp;usg=AOvVaw1Fa-gWhhqWUNZh3rIuGRH-&amp;opi=89978449" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ARC Raiders Discord</a>, where Lily, a Community Manager, was asked whether there were any updates regarding a PVP-focused balancing update. Trigger ‘Nades were specifically mentioned, and Lily promptly responded:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The team’s looking into some nerfs, including trigger nades. Keep an eye on ⁠game-announcements for updates!</p>
</blockquote>



<p>As things stand, that’s all there is to know regarding the Trigger ‘Nade nerf in ARC Raiders. Its existence is confirmed, but to what extent it will present itself in-game, and when you can expect it, you’ll have to wait for further updates from Embark Studios.</p>



<p>One thing Insider Gaming is certain of, though, is that the nerf can’t come soon enough.</p>



<h2 id="h-why-are-trigger-nades-being-nerfed-in-arc-raiders">Why Are Trigger ‘Nades Being Nerfed In ARC Raiders?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>For a small ‘Nade, they pack a mean punch. Image by Embark Studios.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>As things stand, the Trigger ‘Nade in ARC Raiders is incredibly OP, rendering many of the other utility items obsolete. </strong></p>



<p>On paper, the Trigger ‘Nade seems intended for use as a trap; place down the grenade, and remotely detonate it when enemy raiders step within range. However, what has transpired is that raiders use it more like an impact grenade, due to its incredibly quick detonation time and absurd damage potential. </p>



<p>A single well-aimed Trigger ‘Nade can down an entire trio of raiders with ease, thanks to its ludicrous damage output and large radius. To make matters worse, they’re dirt cheap to craft: both Crude Explosives and Processors are immensely simple to acquire. </p>



<p>All of these attributes combined transform the Trigger ‘Nade into what feels like a pocket-sized nuke. Fans have long been <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-november-20-update-full-1-3-0-patch-notes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">desperate for a nerf</a>, and thankfully, it seems like Embark Studios is aware of its unbalanced nature—fingers crossed there isn’t too long a wait.</p>



<hr>



<p>Do you think Trigger ‘Nades need to be nerfed in ARC Raiders? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more ARC Raiders content, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-biggest-arc-raiders-features-we-want-in-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the 7 biggest ARC Raiders features Insider Gaming wants to see in 2026</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-ditched-free-to-play-because-of-helldivers-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how Helldivers 2 influenced the game’s price</a>.</p>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-trigger-nade-nerf-explained/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is ARC Raiders 2026 Roadmap Live Yet? Roadmap Tracker, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-2026-roadmap-live-tracker/</link>
            <guid>1400581</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>ARC Raiders retained its popularity heading into the new year, making 2026 an exciting chapter for Embark Studios and all ARC Raiders players. A 2026 roadmap is what the community is begging for, and this live tracker has the latest details and updates on future changes.</p>



<p>It feels redundant to say, but ARC Raiders is quite good, isn’t it? A record <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-sales-estimate-hits-12-million/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">12 million Peak Player count</a> serves to highlight this more, and ARC Raiders is expected to be a huge presence throughout 2026.</p>



<p>One thing that will keep you all coming back is new content, and this live tracker runs through everything known about the roadmap and future incomings.</p>







<h2 id="h-does-arc-raiders-have-a-2026-roadmap-yet">Does ARC Raiders Have A 2026 Roadmap Yet?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Hang fire for now. Credit to Embark Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>At the time of writing, Embark Studios hasn’t revealed the ARC Raiders 2026 Roadmap yet.</strong></p>



<p>It’s January 8, and Embark Studios is either still feeling the come-down of the holidays (who isn’t?) or reluctant to commit to a 2026 roadmap just yet. There’s always the daunting reality that there might not be a roadmap at all, but it’s unlikely.</p>



<p>Embark has already committed to a 10-year development cycle for ARC. You don’t claim this unless you’re cooking up some serious stuff. Thanks to some digging, a couple of details about the 2026 roadmap content have already been discovered.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming will update this once the roadmap is live, per its tracker status.</p>



<h2 id="h-2026-arc-raiders-roadmap-changes">2026 ARC Raiders Roadmap Changes</h2>



<p><strong>Initial ARC Raiders changes for 2026 include changes to the Trigger Nade, Kettle, and other weapons.</strong></p>



<p>On the ARC Raiders official <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1107589599045361695/1427256238651084895/1458832856120819724" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Discord</a> server, community manager ‘CM | Lily’ had this to say on January 2:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“The team’s looking into some changes to trigger nades.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Then, on January 6, community manager ‘CM | Birdie’ added some more details to the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1107589599045361695/1427256238651084895/1458217158160154704" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Discord</a> about upcoming changes in 2026:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“Hey! The holidays delayed things a bit, but the dev team want you to know that they are looking into balance, for example, the stitcher, kettle, and trigger nade. Rest assured that we hear you and work on delivering a good gaming experience, things are just not immediate.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>These are minor details for now, but they show that the team is already working behind the scenes. A 2026 roadmap likely isn’t far off, and IG will let you know when it’s here.</p>



<p>What are you hoping for with an ARC Raiders 2026 roadmap? Is there a certain feature needed above all else? Let IG know through the free-to-join and always lively <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>While you wait for official roadmap details, be sure to check out fun ARC Raiders content, including the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-biggest-arc-raiders-features-we-want-in-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">7 biggest ARC Raiders features we want in 2026</a>, and why it’s fair to say that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/2025-year-of-the-extraction-shooter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2025 was the year of the Extraction Shooter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-2026-roadmap-live-tracker/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Much is Animal Crossing: New Horizons? Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Prices, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-switch-2-edition-price/</link>
            <guid>1400575</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>2026 is set to be another big year for Nintendo, and the first major content drop of the year on the console is coming to an already-established classic, Animal Crossing: New Horizons, with the Nintendo Switch 2 update, and all the price details you need are here.</p>



<p>Six years after the game was first released, and four years on from the 2.0 update, the Nintendo Switch 2 upgrade for Animal Crossing: New Horizons brings <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-update-new-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">updates to the base game for all players</a>, as well as graphical enhancements for those who purchase the title on the latest console when it <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-switch-2-edition-exact-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">releases on January 15</a>.</p>



<p>If you’re yet to splash out on the latest entry in the Animal Crossing series, or are considering upgrading your edition, Insider Gaming has all the important price details.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-much-is-animal-crossing-new-horizons-on-nintendo-switch-2">How Much is Animal Crossing: New Horizons on Nintendo Switch 2?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Arrival. Image via Nintendo</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Nintendo Switch 2 edition of Animal Crossing: New Horizons is priced at $64.99, $5 more than the original Switch edition of the game.</strong></p>



<p>Purchasing the original Nintendo Switch version of New Horizons will still provide you with the free content coming in the big 3.0 update, though it won’t allow you to take advantage of the Switch 2-exclusive features, which include increasing the maximum amount of players in multiplayer to 12.</p>



<p>Additionally, the Happy Home Paradise DLC is available to purchase for $24.99, but you need to already own the base game to benefit from the additional content.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-much-is-the-animal-crossing-new-horizons-nintendo-switch-2-upgrade">How Much is the Animal Crossing: New Horizons Nintendo Switch 2 Upgrade?</h2>



<p><strong>If you already own Animal Crossing: New Horizons on the original Nintendo Switch, an upgrade pack for the Switch 2 version costs just $5.</strong></p>



<p>There is no need to purchase the game outright again, as Nintendo offers a much cheaper option, but it won’t save you any money if you purchase the base game on the original Switch, then purchase the Switch 2 upgrade. </p>



<p>It remains to be seen whether the Switch 2 edition requires a completely new download, or if it will just update the standard edition of the game, though other Nintendo titles with a Switch 2 upgrade do require a completely new install.</p>







<hr>



<p>What are you most excited for in the Animal Crossing: New Horizons Switch 2 upgrade and 3.0 update? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, check out the<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-nintendo-switch-2-games-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> biggest Nintendo Switch games coming in 2026</a>, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-to-expect-from-pokemon-in-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what to expect from Pokémon in 2026</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-switch-2-edition-price/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Lost In Transmission Quest Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-lost-in-transmission-quest-guide/1100-6537264/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1400569</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537264">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/arc-raiders/" data-ref-id="5000-546105">Arc Raiders</a> occasionally sends you on quests that require you to enter areas that require a key. One of these quests, Lost in Transmission, asks you to head up into Spaceport's Control Tower A6, where you'll need to establish a connection from a terminal there. We're here to guide you through each step of this short but potentially dangerous quest.</p><p>There are two important things to note about this quest:</p><ul><li><strong>You must bring the Spaceport Control Tower Key into the raid</strong>. You will be granted this key upon accepting the quest, and you will not be able to open the necessary door and reach the terminal without it. Place the key in a safe pocket to ensure it's not lost during any potential firefights you encounter. If you didn't bring it or have already lost it, there's a chance someone else will have opened the door, but otherwise you'll need to acquire a new key, which can be found randomly as loot on any map.</li><li>Speaking of firefights, the locked room of Control Tower A6 tends to contain really good loot, so <strong>other raiders will often contest this location</strong>. If you're lucky, your visit to Control Tower A6 may end up quiet. But there's always a chance that you'll need to take someone out, so come prepared.</li></ul><p>When you're ready to tackle Lost in Transmission, follow the steps below.</p><h2 id="Visit_Control_Tower_A6">Visit Control Tower A6</h2><p>Control Tower A6 is located in the lower middle of Spaceport. It's a tall, easily identifiable tower.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632050-share_20260107_0819330.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4632050" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1744" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632050-share_20260107_0819330.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4632050"></a><figcaption>Control Tower A6</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632050-share_20260107_0819330.jpeg"></figure><p>You can enter the building from any angle you prefer, including the opposite side, but we'd recommend entering directly where the tower is located.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632048-share_20260107_0818510-copy.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4632048" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632048-share_20260107_0818510-copy.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4632048"></a><figcaption>Control Tower A6 is easily identifiable due to its being so tall.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632048-share_20260107_0818510-copy.jpeg"></figure><p>Once you reach Control Tower A6, you'll be tasked with reaching the top of the building.</p><h2 id="Reach_the_top_of_Control_Tower_A6">Reach the top of Control Tower A6</h2><p>Inside the lower portion of Control Tower A6, you'll find that there are actually two locked doors. One locked door is in the main room accessed from the front of the building, while the other is in a room filled with red lockers and desks.</p><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632053-share_20260107_0818543.jpeg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632054-share_20260107_0818521.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4632053,1300-4632054" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/679/6794662/4632053-share_20260107_0818543.jpeg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/679/6794662/4632054-share_20260107_0818521.jpeg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632053-share_20260107_0818543.jpeg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632054-share_20260107_0818521.jpeg"></figure><p>Both of these doors lead to the same zipline necessary to reach the top of Control Tower A6, but it's important to check that neither has been opened yet before you use your Spaceport Control Tower Key. If one is open already, then it's likely another raider has taken the zipline up to loot the room you need to access. It's up to you how to handle that situation--be it waiting for them to finish and leave, asking politely to visit for your quest, or simply taking the zipline up unannounced with intentions of slaying them and taking their loot.</p><p>When you reach the top of Control Tower A6, your objective will update once more, now requiring you to establish a connection from a nearby terminal.</p><h2 id="Establish_a_connection_from_the_terminal">Establish a connection from the terminal</h2><p>At the top of Control Tower A6, check the left side of the room for a terminal. Interact with this to establish a connection, which will promptly complete the Lost in Transmission quest.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632055-share_20260107_0818532.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4632055" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632055-share_20260107_0818532.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4632055"></a><figcaption>Interact with the terminal to establish a connection and complete the quest.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4632055-share_20260107_0818532.jpeg"></figure><p>While you're here, it's a good idea to go ahead and loot everything in the room. This key room is one of the game's best for finding good stuff, so there's no reason to let it all go to waste. When you're done, just take the zipline back down and head to the extraction point of your choosing to travel back to Speranza.</p><p>For more on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-arc-raiders-quests-full-mission-list/1100-6535922/" data-ref-id="1100-6535922">Arc Raiders quests</a> and more, check out our comprehensive <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-guides-hub/1100-6536157/" data-ref-id="1100-6536157">guides hub</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-lost-in-transmission-quest-guide/1100-6537264/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders A Balanced Harvest Quest Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-a-balanced-harvest-quest-guide/1100-6537260/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1400566</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537260">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/arc-raiders/" data-ref-id="5000-546105">Arc Raiders</a> quests love sending players to the Research &amp; Administration building on Dam Battlegrounds. One such quest, A Balanced Harvest, tasks you with visiting this hectic location and finding some files on a research project. Getting in and out can be tricky, so we've prepared a guide on how to finish your objectives as quickly as possible.</p><p>You can feel free to bring a free kit into Dam Battlegrounds for this quest, as you won't be required to extract. If you die in the very busy Research &amp; Administration building--which you'll have to visit to complete your objectives--you certainly don't want to lose any good gear. That being said, if you're prone to enjoying PvP, you can always come more prepared for this PvP-centric POI. It's entirely your call, of course.</p><p>When you're ready to wrap up the A Balanced Harvest quest, read on for how to complete each step.</p><h2 id="Go_to_the_Research__amp__Administration_building">Go to the Research &amp; Administration building</h2><p>The first step in this quest is to head to the Research &amp; Administration Building on Dam Battlegrounds.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631864-share_20260107_0637091.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631864" data-ratio="0.5667181865018" data-width="1941" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631864-share_20260107_0637091.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631864"></a><figcaption>Research &amp; Administration</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631864-share_20260107_0637091.jpeg"></figure><p>This is a high-traffic area, primarily due to the fact that it contains some heavily contested key rooms, so it's not uncommon to encounter other raiders here. If your lobbies are particularly aggressive because you PvP frequently, you may find getting in and out of here alive can be a challenge. Prepare accordingly.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631865-share_20260107_0637523.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631865" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631865-share_20260107_0637523.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631865"></a><figcaption>You're welcome to enter the building from any angle, but the reception side is likely best.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631865-share_20260107_0637523.jpeg"></figure><p>You can enter the Research and Administration from any angle, but it's most efficient for this quest to enter from the southwest entrance. This will lead you directly into the reception room. Here, you'll find that your objective updates, and you'll now be required to locate Lab 1 on the upper floor of the building.</p><h2 id="Locate_Lab_1_on_the_upper_floor_above_the_reception">Locate Lab 1 on the upper floor above the reception</h2><p>From the reception room, head up the zipline on the back wall.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631866-share_20260107_0637512.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631866" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631866-share_20260107_0637512.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631866"></a><figcaption>Take this zipline up to the next floor.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631866-share_20260107_0637512.jpeg"></figure><p>When you reach the top, take the path on your right.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631867-share_20260107_0637501.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631867" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631867-share_20260107_0637501.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631867"></a><figcaption>Take the path on the right.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631867-share_20260107_0637501.jpeg"></figure><p>Follow this around to the first door on your left. This is Lab 1.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631874-share_20260107_0729060.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631874" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631874-share_20260107_0729060.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631874"></a><figcaption>Enter this first door on your left.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631874-share_20260107_0729060.jpeg"></figure><p>Your objective will now update and ask you to find traces of the agricultural research project.</p><h2 id="Search_for_any_traces_of_the_agricultural_research_project">Search for any traces of the agricultural research project</h2><p>Once you're inside Lab 1, you're nearly finished. Simply interact with the stack of papers on a desk in the middle of the room to find the trace of the agricultural research project.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631877-share_20260107_0729071.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631877" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631877-share_20260107_0729071.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4631877"></a><figcaption>Interact with these papers to finish the quest.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4631877-share_20260107_0729071.jpeg"></figure><p>With that done, you've completed A Balanced Harvest. You're now free to finish looting up here and extracting--or fighting to the death. That's your call, raider.</p><p>Whatever you decide to do, you can check out more <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-arc-raiders-quests-full-mission-list/1100-6535922/" data-ref-id="1100-6535922">Arc Raiders quests</a> or take a look at our comprehensive <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-guides-hub/1100-6536157/" data-ref-id="1100-6536157">guides hub</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-a-balanced-harvest-quest-guide/1100-6537260/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Sales Were Reportedly Not Amazing Over The Holidays]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-sales-were-reportedly-not-amazing-over-the-holidays/1100-6537274/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1400563</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537274">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Nintendo Switch 2 was indisputably a sales hit after its June 2025 launch, but a new report indicates that the hybrid console's success may not match up to the original Switch's first holiday season.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/nintendo-switch-2-sales-stumble-over" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Game Business</a>, Switch 2 sales in the United States were down by around 35% from November to December compared to Switch 1 sales during the same period in its launch year of 2017. This statistic tracks with an earlier report from Circana revealing that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hardware-sales-in-the-us-just-had-worst-month-in-30-years/1100-6537041/" data-ref-id="1100-6537041">November 2025 was the worst month for hardware sales</a> in the US since 1995.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1064328969" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466611,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;How%20Nintendo%20Won%20The%20Console%20War&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:590,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/how-nintendo-won-the-console-war\/2300-6466611\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466611\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466611\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466611\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466611&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466611,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6537274&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466611},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466611\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1862\/18620770\/4625896-nintendo_won_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/0rOyOiLk.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1767117600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="0rOyOiLk" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> How Nintendo Won The Console War</p>
      </div>
<p>The Switch 2 didn't fare much better in European countries, with UK sales having a reported fall of 16% compared to the Switch 1 in Holiday 2017. In France, Switch 2 unit numbers for its inaugural year are reportedly over 30% lower than what the Switch 1 achieved during its first year.</p><p>The difference is less steep in Japan, where the Switch 2 only had a 5.5% decline from Switch 1 holiday numbers in 2017. Overall, the Switch 2 still had a strong first year, with Switch 2 sales being higher than Switch 1's first-year sales in the UK (by 6%) and Japan (by 11%).</p><p>An unnamed "senior Nintendo employee" speaking to The Game Business attributed the slight decline to the "complicated economic landscape" and "the absence of a major Western game." During the holiday season, Nintendo itself published Kirby Air Riders, which has proven to be popular in Japan, and Metroid Prime 4: Beyond, which received a mixed response from fans.</p><p>Though hardware sales in general are faltering, that isn't to take away from the Switch 2's accomplishments, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-continues-to-be-a-massive-hit-selling-over-10-million-units-in-six-months/1100-6535903/" data-ref-id="1100-6535903">over 10 million units sold in its first four months</a>. Upcoming first-party Switch 2 offerings include an upgrade for Animal Crossing: New Horizons and the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baby-waluigi-cries-waaaah-in-mario-tennis-fever/1100-6537275/" data-ref-id="1100-6537275">Baby Waluigi-starring Mario Tennis Fever</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-sales-were-reportedly-not-amazing-over-the-holidays/1100-6537274/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wccftech’s Most Anticipated Adventure Games of 2026: Against Fire, Air, Water, and Mind]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wccftech-most-anticipated-adventure-games-of-2026-against-fire-air-water-mind/</link>
            <guid>1400551</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>2025 <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-adventure-games-of-2025-weird-and-wondrous-tales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was a great year for adventure games</a>, but this year is <strong>perhaps even more promising when looking at the schedule</strong>. Some of the most talented developers in the genre are returning with innovative games that will offer a staggering amount of variety in gameplay experiences for those who prefer not to engage in action-focused games.</p>



<p>Unsurprisingly, all of them come from independent developers who correctly identified the genre as a niche that most triple-A developers are content to leave alone. There's also a strong presence of French-made titles. Without further ado, here's our shortlist for the <strong>most anticipated adventure games scheduled in 2026</strong>.</p>



<p><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Other Wccftech's Most Anticipated 2026 Games per genre:</em>&nbsp;<em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-role-playing-games-of-2026-legends-and-legacies/">Role-Playing Games</a></strong></em>,&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-indie-games-of-2026/">Indie Games</a></em></strong>,&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-platformers-of-2026-new-adventures-in-familiar-worlds/">Platformers</a></em></strong>,&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-dlc-expansion-of-2026/">DLC/Expansion</a></em></strong>,&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-action-games-of-2026-martial-artists-spies-super-heroes-and-criminals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Action</em></a></strong>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-shooter-games-2026-the-year-of-xbox-studios/"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Shooter</strong></em> <em><strong>Games</strong></em></a>, <em><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-horror-games-of-2026-a-new-era-of-dread/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Horror</a></strong></em>, <strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-sports-racing-games-of-2026-from-japan-to-a-galaxy-far-far-away/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sports/Racing</a></em></strong>, <strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-fighting-games-of-2026-tag-fighters-dominance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fighting</a></em></strong></p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/e3ab0c8181fe01695172b72ef54f893f5fa353678e6da0ec-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-cairn-january-29-2026-pc-playstation-5">Cairn (January 29, 2026 - PC, PlayStation 5)</h2>



<p>French independent developer <strong>The Game Bakers</strong> returns after 2016's bossfight action game <strong>Furi</strong> and 2020's love-themed RPG <strong>Haven</strong>. Both of those were quite unique and garnered acclaim, although they did not achieve the same level of popularity as other indie titles. The upcoming <strong>Cairn</strong> might just pull that off, though, especially on the heels of <strong>Peak</strong> being one of the most successful games of 2025 with <strong>over 10 million units</strong> sold to date. </p>



<p>Suddenly, climbing games look a lot more appealing to many gamers. In this one, professional climber Aava stands at the base of Mount Kami and must reach its peak.​ The gameplay prioritizes realistic climbing simulation over cinematic spectacle. Piton placement, rope management, oxygen depletion, and falling mechanics create genuine survival stakes. There's even a riskier, optional Free Solo mode that cuts safety systems for particularly daring players.</p>



<p>The 15-hour campaign features approximately an hour of cinematic storytelling, voiced by a cast of 10 climbers, each representing psychological archetypes drawn to vertical terrain. Mathieu Bablet, the celebrated comic artist, directs visual language, while the sound design comes from the team behind Limbo, Inside, and Control.​</p>



<p>The Cairn Steam demo received extremely positive feedback, and with <strong>over 700K wishlists</strong> already secured, the game is not only the first title on this adventure games list to launch, it's also among the most likely to be successful.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/0d66ef2024d55bfa49cdd13de1201834fe89a2c3fd74cc68-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-tides-of-tomorrow-february-24-2026-pc-ps5-xss-xsx">Tides of Tomorrow (February 24, 2026 - PC, PS5, XSS, XSX)</h2>



<p><strong>Tides of Tomorrow</strong> is another adventure game that comes from an indie studio based in France, more specifically in Montpellier: <strong>DigixArt</strong>. Founded by the creator of <strong>Valiant Hearts: The Great War</strong>, the studio has since released a rhythm game, <strong>Lost in Harmony</strong>, and three adventure games, <strong>11-11: Memories Retold</strong>, <strong>Road 96</strong>, and <strong>Road 96: Mile 0</strong>. This new game is quite different, to say the least, and incredibly ambitious.</p>



<p>Firstly, it operates in a permanent asynchronous multiplayer narrative-focused mode. Where most online games pursue real-time synchronization, Tides of Tomorrow focuses on the inverse: a cascade of choices where <strong>your decisions reshape another player's story, and theirs reshape yours</strong>. The asynchronous vision system works like this: you select another player to follow—a friend, a streamer, or even a stranger, and begin your journey in locations they previously visited. NPCs retain memories of their actions; they speak about decisions made by the prior player. Ghost echoes of their movements appear as visual guides helping you anticipate environmental hazards. But here's the crux: when you steal from an NPC the previous player befriended, that NPC's attitude shifts permanently for all future players who follow you.</p>



<p>This ties into the environmental narrative, where Plastemia's spread (the conversion of life into plastic) mirrors the ripple effects of player decisions propagating through asynchronous time. <strong>Each player inherits a wounded world shaped by predecessors</strong>; each player wounds it further for successors.​</p>



<p>The developers promise that <strong>the game's branching storylines will respond to the cumulative moral weight</strong>. Story sections can even drastically change based on the prior player's set of choices. Multiple endings, therefore, emerge from whether you preserved or sacrificed NPCs, resources, or your own sanity.  Needless to say, Tides of Tomorrow sounds like a game that will either reinvent the genre or be a total flop. Of course, we're crossing our fingers for the former outcome.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Cthulhu-The-Cosmic-Abyss_2025_03-06-25_006-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-cthulhu-the-cosmic-abyss-april-16-2026-pc-ps5-xss-xsx">Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss (April 16, 2026 - PC, PS5, XSS, XSX)</h2>



<p>The third entry in our adventure games list for 2026 is also the third project that originates from a French developer. They certainly like this genre, don't they? This time, it's <strong>Big Bad Wolf</strong>, the studio behind 2018's episodic mystery adventure game <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-council-episode-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Council</a></strong> and 2022's roleplaying game <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/vampire-the-masquerade-swansong-vampires-make-for-excellent-investigators/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vampire: The Masquerade - Swansong</a></strong>. </p>



<p>After VtM, they're moving to an even creepier setting: <strong>Lovecraft</strong>. In <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/robocop-styx-and-cthulhu-announcements-headline-nacon-connect/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss</a></strong>, <span>however, they're bringing Lovecraft's cosmic horror forward to the year&nbsp;<strong>2053</strong>, when Earth's surface has been nearly strip-mined and desperate corporations tunnel beneath the Pacific in search of</span> rare minerals. When one mining station goes silent, <strong>Noah</strong>, an <strong>Ancile</strong> investigator (an occult division of <strong>Interpol</strong>), descends into <strong>R'lyeh</strong>, the sunken city that the miners unwittingly awakened.</p>



<p>As in classic Lovecraft, <strong>the city's architecture violates Euclidean geometry</strong>, with angles that shouldn't work and paths that loop back on themselves. Corridors will feel simultaneously monumental and claustrophobic, ancient yet pulsating with malevolent consciousness. The city isn't just alien; <strong>it's aware and deeply hostile to Noah's presence</strong>.</p>



<p>There's a perfectly fitting <strong>sanity mechanic</strong>, although in this game, sanity degrades constantly merely by witnessing cosmic wrongness, such as impossible geometry, terrifying audio cues, and distortions that suggest reality itself is warped at R'lyeh's depths. Unlike other horror games where sanity can be restored, <strong>this will be a one-way descent</strong>, and the only choice presented to players is whether to ignore the mysteries to preserve sanity or sacrifice mental stability to uncover the truth. The player's final sanity state at the narrative climax determines which of multiple endings they're going to receive.</p>



<p>NPCs embody the <strong>golden Lovecraftian principle</strong>: true horror resists definition. The player rarely sees the Shoggoth directly. Instead, they'll catch glimpses: shadows, distortions, echoes of something passing nearby, thus increasing the tension already heightened by the first-person view.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/OSS-KeyArt-4K-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-order-of-the-sinking-star-tba-2026-pc">Order of the Sinking Star (TBA 2026 - PC)</h2>



<p><strong>Jonathan Blow</strong>, the acclaimed game designer behind indie gems like <strong>Braid</strong> and <strong>The Witness</strong>, returns ten years after his latest project with <strong>Order of the Sinking Star</strong>. <a href="https://wccftech.com/braid-the-witness-developer-thekla-announce-order-of-the-sinking-star-the-game-awards-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Announced less than a month ago</a> during The Game Awards 2025, this innovative puzzle adventure game is set in a realm filled with magic, monsters, and curious traps. </p>



<p>During this adventure, players will explore <strong>four different worlds</strong>, each with its own rules, characters, secrets, and dangers. Some of the playable characters include <strong>a queen, a thief, a warrior, a wizard, a bard, a druid, and a priestess</strong>, each with their own abilities and skills. For example, the warrior can push blocks forward without restrictions, whereas the thief cannot push anything; objects act as walls to her. On the other hand, pulling is compulsive and automatic for this character. If she moves backwards while adjacent to an object, she must grab it. The wizard's core ability, teleportation, is also involuntary: if a swappable object exists within range in his direction of movement, he must swap positions with it. ​ The Wizard can also generate multiple clones by entering different mirrors, creating simultaneous multi-position puzzle solutions. </p>



<p>It is through the combination of the characters' skills that the player can solve the puzzles featured in this game. And there's going to be a ton of them: Blow revealed there will be <strong>over a thousand handcrafted puzzles</strong>, for an estimated <strong>250-500 hours of gameplay</strong>, depending on your puzzle-solving expertise. If you're into this kind of challenge, Order of the Sinking Star looks like a must-have.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/9163b5_f44c02152b5e4cf1b8fa9bb4fd800af4mv2.jpg"></a></figure>



<h2 id="h-into-the-fire-tba-2026-pc">Into the Fire (TBA 2026 - PC)</h2>



<p>The last pick in our 2026 adventure games shortlist is <strong>Into the Fire</strong>, the next project by Polish developer <strong>Starward Industries</strong>, which made 2023's sci-fi game <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-invincible-exploring-the-unknown/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Invincible</a></strong>, based on a novel by Stanisław Lem. </p>



<p>Into the Fire was actually <a href="https://wccftech.com/dantes-ring-is-a-so-called-anti-combat-action-rpg-from-the-makers-of-the-invincible/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced in late 2024</a> as an <strong>'anti-combat' game</strong> called <strong>Dante's Ring</strong>. Although the title has changed, the setting remains the same. You're a desperate explorer fighting a volcanic apocalypse on <strong>Dante's Archipelago</strong> and must <strong>rescue as many lives as possible</strong>, including yourself, before <strong>extracting from the danger zone</strong>. The game does incorporate some elements from extraction games, although it is single player-only. Whereas in traditional extraction games, you fight off other players and try to extract with new loot, here the main dilemma is: <strong>do you save one more survivor, knowing it risks your extraction</strong>? </p>



<p>You'll be able to discover the stories of those you saved and <strong>help locals by completing their quests</strong>. In the hub, which you'll return to between extraction, you'll get to <strong>craft and upgrade gear, thus customizing the playstyle, and even tend to rescued plants and animals</strong>.</p>



<p>Fire will be both a threat and a tool in this adventure. Expect to have to survive <strong>pyroclastic flows (superheated gas), volcanic bombs (ejecta projectiles), structural collapses, ash storms</strong>, and more. ​Just like in The Invincible, Starward Industries maintains a <strong>retro-aesthetic design</strong>. Here, it's a 1950s-inspired "golden age of scientific ambition" that collides with an apocalyptic reality. </p>



<p>Into the Fire will debut on early access first, though the developer reckons <strong>the full game will still launch in 2026</strong>, making it eligible for this list.</p>



<div id="democracy-1516" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1516,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Most Anticipated Adventure Game of 2026</strong></p></div>



<h2 id="h-honorable-mentions">Honorable Mentions</h2>



<p>Beyond those five adventure games, there's plenty more that should rightfully catch your attention, including the following:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Broken Sword 2: The Smoking Mirror—Reforged</strong></li>



<li><strong>Planet of Lana II: Children of the Leaf</strong></li>



<li><strong>Mixtape</strong></li>



<li><strong>Hela</strong></li>



<li><strong>D-Topia</strong></li>
</ul>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/wccftech-most-anticipated-adventure-games-of-2026-against-fire-air-water-mind/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Tennis Fever Will Feature the Most Playable Characters in Series History, “Most Jam-Packed Mario Tennis Yet”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mario-tennis-fever-overview-trailer-nintendo/</link>
            <guid>1400548</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Nintendo has debuted a new overview trailer for <strong>Mario Tennis Fever</strong>, the upcoming entry in the Mario Tennis series that Nintendo is calling the "<em>most jam-packed Mario Tennis yet</em>," and it's not just saying that. By playable characters alone, Mario Tennis Fever is the biggest game in the series' history as it'll feature a total of <strong>38 characters at launch</strong>.</p>



<p>The overview trailer showcased the new features being introduced in Mario Tennis Fever, chief among them being Fever Rackets. These are different kinds of rackets that you unlock in a match by keeping a rally going, and when you get the chance to use one, you can disadvantage your opponent by making their side of the court a sheet of ice, covering it with flames, electrocutting them; there's a whole swath of elemental damage and obstacles you can place in their path with a well-placed Fever Racket shot.</p>



<p>On top of the 38 playable characters, there are <strong>30 different kinds of Fever Rackets</strong>, each with their own special abilities and methods of changing the style of the match and making it as chaotic as possible.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Mario Tennis Fever – Overview Trailer – Nintendo Switch 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RSyoMsWRL9I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Perhaps more intriguing than the Fever Rackets are all the different game modes. Firstly, there's a much-appreciated classic mode that does away with Fever Rackets and brings the gameplay back to plain old tennis. If you don't want to lose a match because your character was on fire and couldn't return a shot, classic mode puts everything back on a more even playing field.</p>



<p>On the other side of that, there are several modes that make things even more chaotic than they already are with Fever Rackets, and pull inspiration from other Mario games, including a <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/super-mario-bros-wonder/">Super Mario Bros. Wonder</a>-inspired mode that changes the court in surprising ways when you aim for Wonder Flowers.</p>



<p>There's also an adventure mode that will take you through all the basics before you jump into playing multiplayer, either in casual matches online or in ranked matches. You'll also be able to change how you play by taking the Joy-Con 2 controller off the side of your Nintendo Switch 2 and play Mario Tennis Fever like you would if it were a Nintendo Wii game, swinging your controller as the racket.</p>



<p>Mario Tennis Fever will be a Nintendo Switch 2 exclusive title when it launches next month on <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/mario-tennis-fever-launch-february-2026-nintendo-switch-2/">February 12, 2026.</a></strong> It was one of our picks for our <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-sports-racing-games-of-2026-from-japan-to-a-galaxy-far-far-away/">most anticipated sports and racing games of 2026</a>, and today's new overview trailer only validated that choice.  </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/mario-tennis-fever-overview-trailer-nintendo/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox’s Developer Direct returns on January 22nd with Fable and Forza Horizon 6 gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/858471/xbox-developer-direct-forza-horizon-6-fable-beast-of-reincarnation-stream</link>
            <guid>1400545</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Microsoft’s annual Xbox Developer Direct event is <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-2026/">taking place on January 22nd</a> this year. The fourth Developer Direct will provide a closer look at two of Microsoft’s biggest Xbox games this year, <em>Forza Horizon 6</em> and <em>Fable</em>, as well as a first in-depth look at <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em> from Game Freak.</p><p>Playground Games will debut the first gameplay of <em>Forza Horizon 6</em> during the Developer Direct show, after <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/785486/forza-horizon-6-japan-xbox-release-date">first revealing</a> that the next instalment in the <em>Forza Horizon</em> franchise is set in Japan. <em>Forza Horizon 6</em> players will be able to experience the neon lights and buildings of Tokyo City, as well as an open world set in various other parts of Japan.</p><p>We’ve been waiting to hear more about Playground Games’ other big Xbox title, <em>Fable</em>, after <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/619046/microsoft-xbox-fable-game-delay-2026">Microsoft delayed its release</a> to 2026. <em>Fable</em> appears to be on track for a release this year, which also marks 25 years of Xbox. “Devs from the Playground team will unveil the magic and mischief that awaits players in this fresh new beginning for the franchise, including a first look at some stunning new gameplay,” says Joe Skrebels, Xbox Wire editor-in-chief.</p><p>Game Freak, known for its Pokémon RPG games, will also show off parts of its new <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em> action RPG. It’s launching at some point in 2026 on Xbox Series S / X, PS5, and PC, and in the game you’ll play as Emma, who will be accompanied by a canine friend.</p><p>This year’s Xbox Developer Direct will take place at 1PM ET / 10PM PT / 6PM UK on January 22nd and will be streamed live on on <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/xbox">Twitch</a> and <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?xs=1&amp;id=1025X1701640&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fuser%2Fxbox%2Fhub&amp;xcust=__vg0108awT__24102355__________________google.com" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored" target="_blank">YouTube</a>.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/858471/xbox-developer-direct-forza-horizon-6-fable-beast-of-reincarnation-stream]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garmin Offloads Its Rugged GPS Smartwatch at Record Low After Extra Discounts Stack, Grade-A Refurbished Instinct 2X Solar Model]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/garmin-offloads-its-rugged-gps-smartwatch-at-record-low-after-extra-discounts-stack-grade-a-refurbished-instinct-2x-solar-model-2000657278</link>
            <guid>1400533</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Fitness trackers are the perfect way to make sure you stay on track with any weight loss or fitness goals now that it’s 2026. If you plan on spending most of your time outside, on hikes, runs, rides or simply enjoying nature, then the Garmin Instinct 2X Solar is perfect for you. It’s designed to withstand a variety of conditions, including being thrown around, dropped into the mud, water and other harsh elements. It can handle all this while continuing to track your fitness, assist with navigation and perform everyday functions. And it’s on sale right now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6703/">Head to Amazon to get the Garmin Instinct 2X Solar smartwatch right now for $249.99, down from its usual price of $299,99.</a> This represents a savings of $50 or approximately 17% off.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6703/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A rugged smartwatch with a plethora of features</h2>
<p>This smartwatch is super rugged and durable so you can use it as your everyday wearable. In fact, it meets U.S. military standards for thermal, shock and water resistance. Whether you decide to use this watch during trail runs, swims, or in other extreme conditions, you can be confident that it’ll last and last.</p>
<p>It charges via solar power (or by hooking up to a USB-C charger). The ring around the display collects energy from sunlight and extends the battery life significantly. No longer do you have to worry about needing to charge your watch every night before bed with this solar-powered model. You can take it with you on extended camping trips or to training camps knowing that it’ll last as long as you can, no matter what you get up to.</p>



<p>With built-in GPS, heart rate monitoring, and support for multiple sports (running, cycling, hiking, strength training), users will receive detailed data about their workouts. The watch also tracks distance, speed, altitude, and more, giving users a complete picture of their workout. Additionally, the watch provides sleep and recovery data, allowing users to monitor how well they are recovering between workouts.</p>
<p>Another benefit of the Garmin Instinct 2X Solar is its ability to assist with navigation. Users can log their routes using the watch and view breadcrumb trails so they can easily locate themselves while exploring unfamiliar terrain. The ability to create and follow routes without having to constantly access your phone adds an additional level of reassurance to the user experience.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6703/">If you’re looking for a new smartwatch, the Garmin Instinct 2X Solar is a great option. It’s super affordable since it’s on sale right now, too.</a> If you can pick one up, it’s a good investment for anyone looking for a durable, long-lasting smartwatch that provides reliable tracking and navigation. Just make sure you get it while it’s still significantly discounted.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6703/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/garmin-offloads-its-rugged-gps-smartwatch-at-record-low-after-extra-discounts-stack-grade-a-refurbished-instinct-2x-solar-model-2000657278]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 2’s CPU Power Caused Military Concerns, It’s Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-2s-cpu-power-caused-military-concerns-its-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1400530</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The lead on Final Fantasy 9 has revealed that the PlayStation 2’s CPU was so powerful that it raised military concerns. </p>



<p>Talks about the Final Fantasy 9 Remake have completely fizzled out since a reliable insider revealed that the project “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-might-be-on-ice-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">might be on ice</a>“. However, as players wait for official confirmation, the lead has shared an insight from the PlayStation 2 era, revealing that the CPU’s power was no joke back then. </p>







<h2 id="h-playstation-2-s-cpu-was-so-overpowered-that-it-led-to-export-restrictions">PlayStation 2’s CPU Was ‘So Overpowered’ That It Led to Export Restrictions </h2>



<p>During a new interview with <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202512/61817" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Famitsu</a> (translated by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/final-fantasy/final-fantasy-9-lead-says-the-ps2-was-so-so-overpowered-its-cpu-sparked-military-concerns-so-he-struggled-to-get-an-emergency-dev-kit-during-his-stay-in-hawaii-it-was-a-very-difficult-situation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesRadar+</a>), Final Fantasy 9’s Kazuhiko Aoki revealed the difficulties he faced when trying to test the game on the PlayStation 2 due to its CPU. Aoki revealed that, towards the end of his stay in Hawaii, there were discussions about his receiving PlayStation 2 testing equipment to see whether Final Fantasy 9 could run on the console. However, the console’s CPU was “so overpowered” that there was a “possibility that it would be used for military purposes,” so there were restrictions on the console’s export. </p>



<p>But, after taking “quite some time” and the team facing a “very difficult situation,” the console was finally delivered to the Final Fantasy 9 dev team. </p>



<p>In other news, Final Fantasy 7 Remake director wants <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-6-remake-should-be-led-by-someone-else-says-ff7-director/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">someone else to lead the Final Fantasy 6 Remake</a>. Additionally, the director of Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 has stated that the game’s experience is “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-game-experience-is-more-or-less-complete/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more or less complete</a>“. What are your thoughts on PlayStation 2’s CPU being so powerful that it led to military concerns? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-lead-not-sure-why-set-up-for-bad-company-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a former Battlefield lead developer outlining the dream concept for Bad Company 3, which never emerged</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-2s-cpu-power-caused-military-concerns-its-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby Waluigi Cries Waaaah In Mario Tennis Fever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baby-waluigi-cries-waaaah-in-mario-tennis-fever/1100-6537275/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1400527</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537275">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Nintendo has released a new overview trailer for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-tennis-fever-announced-for-nintendo-switch-2/1100-6534693/">Mario Tennis Fever, the upcoming sports game for Switch 2</a>. While the video goes over various modes and special rackets, the most important revelation is Baby Waluigi. He's a real playable character, and he's spectacular.</p><p dir="ltr">Baby Waluigi isn't the only newcomer to Mario Tennis Fever, though. The game will feature Goomba, Nabbit, Piranha Plant, and Baby Wario for the first time as part of the playable cast, consisting of 38 characters overall. The sports title will also serve up 30 Fever Rackets. Nintendo showcased some of the special abilities tied to these frames, such as the Pokey Racket and Golden Dash Racket. The former spawns enemies on your opponent's court, while the latter can make your character super agile.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1544114855" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466626,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Mario%20Tennis%20Fever%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20Gameplay%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:342,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/mario-tennis-fever-official-gameplay-overview-trailer\/2300-6466626\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466626\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466626\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466626\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466626&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466626,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6537275&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;mario-tennis-fever&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;sports,tennis&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;nintendo&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;mario-sports&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;mario&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466626},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466626\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4632491-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/uxJenJQA.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1767882420,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="uxJenJQA" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Mario Tennis Fever – Official Gameplay Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Nintendo also detailed how to counter Fever shots. If players can volley the ball back--meaning not allowing it to bounce off the court--the special effect can be sent back. For instance, the Ice Racket creates a frozen surface on the court. Instead of this slippery area appearing on your side, you can volley the Fever shot back to your opponent.</p><p dir="ltr">Other tidbits from the new Mario Tennis Fever video include the fact that Fever Rackets can be disabled for more straightforward matches. In addition, the Switch 2 title has GameShare capabilities, letting nearby players on Switch 2 and Switch join multiplayer matches locally without a copy of the game.</p><p dir="ltr">Mario Tennis Fever is set to launch February 12, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-tennis-fever-nintendo-switch-2-2026-game-preorder-buying-guide/1100-6534725/">preorders are live</a> for the Switch 2 exclusive. It's the first entry in the Mario spin-off series since Mario Tennis Aces in 2018.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baby-waluigi-cries-waaaah-in-mario-tennis-fever/1100-6537275/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Joy Con 2 Colors Will Launch Alongside Mario Tennis Fever Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/08/new-joy-con-2-colors-will-launch-alongside-mario-tennis-fever-next-month</link>
            <guid>1400524</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>After seven months on the market, the Nintendo Switch 2 is finally getting newly colored Joy Cons. Today, via the Nintendo Today app (<a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/2009253320150425831?s=20">and later on other social media platforms</a>), Nintendo announced that two new Joy Con 2 colors would be hitting shelves on the same day as Mario Tennis Fever, February 12.&nbsp;</p><h2>You can take a look at the new Joy Con 2 colors below:</h2><p>Dubbed "Light Purple" and "Light Green," the new controllers follow the color pattern established by the original Joy Con 2s. Each controller's respective color accents the joystick and connection points, but the shell is still mostly dark gray.&nbsp;</p><p>Until now, the only Joy Con 2 colors available were red and blue: the option included with the console. Even this is fewer options than the original Switch, which launched with a Red/Blue model and a gray model. While it's a minor complaint in the grand scheme of things, if you live in a household with multiple Switch 2s or visit a friend with the console to play some multiplayer, it's hard to tell the handhelds apart. This provides the first official pathway to customization.</p><p>That said, the controllers, <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/nintendo-switch-2-joy-con-2-l-r-light-purple-light-green-127067/?utm_source=HW&amp;utm_campaign=S1001-01&amp;utm_id=S1001-01&amp;utm_content=100009464274542&amp;utm_medium=sofbnoa">which are currently available for pre-order on Nintendo's website</a>, are the same price as red and blue Joy Con 2s – a whopping $99.99. It's a reminder of Nintendo's recently high price tags, though <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/11/04/nintendo-switch-2-sales-surpass-10-million-units">it hasn't stopped the console itself from having a successful launch</a>. However, a recent report also shared last November <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/17/video-game-hardware-and-physical-software-sales-this-year-had-the-worst-november-since">had the lowest number of consoles sold in a long time</a>, so that aforementioned success depends on your perspective.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/08/new-joy-con-2-colors-will-launch-alongside-mario-tennis-fever-next-month]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[January Xbox Developer Direct Will Feature Forza Horizon 6, Fable, And Game Freak's Beast Of Reincarnation]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/08/january-xbox-developer-direct-will-feature-forza-horizon-6-fable-and-game-freaks-beast</link>
            <guid>1400521</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Xbox has announced that it will air a Developer Direct showcase later this month on Thursday, January 22, at 10 a.m. PT/1 p.m. ET. It will feature Playground Games' <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/fable">Fable</a> and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/forza-horizon-6">Forza Horizon 6</a>, both of which are set to launch this year, and Pokémon maker Game Freak's <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/beast-of-reincarnation">Beast of Reincarnation</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>The showcase, stylized as "Developer_Direct," promises new gameplay and insight directly from the developers working on these games. More specifically, it will feature the first extended look at <a href="https://gameinformer.com/xbox-showcase/2024/06/09/playground-games-fable-gets-2025-release-window-in-first-gameplay-trailer">Fable</a> as well as the debut of gameplay for Forza Horizon 6, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/25/forza-horizon-6-takes-players-to-japan-next-year">which is set in Japan</a>, a setting fans of the series have wanted for years. The third game to be featured is <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2023/05/09/pokemon-maker-game-freak-developing-new-action-adventure-ip-codenamed-project-bloom">Game Freak's Beast of Reincarnation</a>, which was <a href="https://gameinformer.com/xbox-games-showcase/2025/06/08/pokemon-developer-game-freak-announces-beast-of-reincarnation-for">revealed at the Xbox Games Showcase last year</a> – the Developer Direct will reveal new details about protagonist Emma's plant manipulation abilities and gameplay with her canine companion Koo.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Here's what Xbox has to say about each game the Developer Direct will feature:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="46b8e594-6cdf-4c28-97ec-fc8f2fcebe37" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="image:responsive_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;responsive_image_style&quot;:&quot;content_body&quot;,&quot;image_loading&quot;:{&quot;attribute&quot;:&quot;lazy&quot;},&quot;image_link&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
          <picture>
                  <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/body_default/public/2026/01/08/b5ee8d40/Developer%20Direct.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 851px)" type="image/webp" width="800" height="450">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2026/01/08/b5ee8d40/Developer%20Direct.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 315px) and (max-width: 450px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2026/01/08/b5ee8d40/Developer%20Direct.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (max-width: 314px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
                  

  </picture>


  
  
  
</article>

<p><strong>Fable</strong><em><strong> </strong>– "</em>Playground Games welcomes players back to the fairytale land of Albion, with the first in-depth look at <em>Fable </em>– one of 2026’s most anticipated titles. Devs from the Playground team will unveil the magic and mischief that awaits players in this fresh new beginning for the franchise, including a first look at some stunning new gameplay. Of course, the core themes of Fable will all be there – choice, consequence, drama, action, British humor and (of course) chickens, all reimagined for existing fans and new players alike."</p><p><strong>Forza Horizon 6</strong><em><strong> </strong>– "</em>The Forza team from Playground Games will share a deep-dive on the much-anticipated <em>Forza Horizon 6 </em>as the open world racer takes players to the beautiful and contrasting landscapes of Japan. The segment will deep-dive into a very first look at gameplay, including reveals of new features – and how Japan comes to life in this stunning new installment."</p><p><strong>Beast of Reincarnation</strong><em><strong> </strong>– "</em>Join us as we delve into Game Freak’s intense one-person, one-dog action RPG. For the first time, Game Freak will reveal details of our protagonist Emma’s innovative plant manipulation actions and gameplay with her canine companion, Koo. In <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em>, a profound and dangerous world unfolds in post-apocalyptic Japan. Discover the development secrets behind its creation in Developer_Direct."</p><hr><p>Though there's no indication of it in the <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-2026/">blog post</a> announcing this Developer Direct, Xbox has used these showcases to surprise viewers with additional reveals and more. Notably, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/xbox-developer-direct/2023/01/25/the-evil-withins-creators-made-a-colorful-rhythm-game-and-its-out">Hi-Fi Rush was shadow-dropped at the 2023 Developer Direct</a>. Nonetheless, Fable, Forza Horizon 6, and Beast of Reincarnation are three hotly anticipated games, so this showcase is likely going to be an exciting one for fans of these developers.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/08/january-xbox-developer-direct-will-feature-forza-horizon-6-fable-and-game-freaks-beast]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox is hosting a Developer Direct later this month, featuring Fable, Forza, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-developer-direct-showcase-january-2026</link>
            <guid>1400518</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Microsoft has announced another Developer Direct, set to take place on the 22nd January. It'll feature Fable, Forza, and Beast of Reincarnation.</p>
<p>As for exact timing, eager spectators can tune in to this Developer Direct at 10am Pacific / 1pm Eastern / 6pm UK on the official Xbox YouTube channel to watch it live.</p>
<p>What exactly will be shown off remains largely a mystery, though <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-2026/">the official Xbox Wire post</a> announcing the show states we'll be seeing the "first in-depth look" <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-developer-game-freak-reveals-beast-of-reincarnation-at-xbox-games-showcase#:~:text=Beast%20of%20Reincarnation%20takes%20place,world's%20corruption%20to%20save%20humanity.">at Beast of Reincarnation since its reveal last June at the Xbox Showcase</a>.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fable Official Trailer | Xbox Games Showcase 2024" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w6TJTHdgmts?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fable Official Trailer | Xbox Games Showcase 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w6TJTHdgmts?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/w6TJTHdgmts?autoplay=1" title="Fable Official Trailer | Xbox Games Showcase 2024">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w6TJTHdgmts" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>There will also be a "deep dive" into <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/forza-horizon-6">Forza Horizon 6</a>, with a focus on gameplay and reveals of new features. It'll also dive into the Japanese setting, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/forza-horizon-6-will-integrate-japanese-culture-into-the-most-full-series-location-so-far#:~:text=The%20game%20will%20be%20coming,our%20coverage%20in%20your%20feeds.">which apparently will be the "Most fulL" integration of a real world setting yet</a>, prior info indicates.</p><p>Fable gameplay will also be present, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsofts-xbox-games-showcase-teased-the-best-line-up-in-years-if-you-can-wait-to-play-it">something desperately sought after since its initial reveal all the way back in 2023</a>. The game made a mostly cinematic appearance in 2024, with a few glimpses of gameplay sprinkled throughout. But a proper lenghty gameplay deep dive, with UI and all the trimmings, has been on the top of people's wants ever since. Those desires will seemingly be met on the 22nd.</p>
<p>Are you going to watch it live? Let us know below!</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  <section>
        


    

      <details>
        <summary>
See 1 more              <span></span>

        </summary>

        
      </details>
  </section>

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-developer-direct-showcase-january-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Developer Direct announced, will feature Fable and Forza Horizon 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-announced-will-feature-fable-and-forza-horizon-6/</link>
            <guid>1400506</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Microsoft has announced that the Xbox Developer Direct will be taking place on January 22nd, and has confirmed Fable, Forza Horizon, and Game Freak’s Beast of Reincarnation will all have gameplay shown. Both Fable and Forza Horizon 6 are pencilled in to launch this year, so we should get release dates for both at Developer Direct, and we may also get a release date for Beast of Reincarnation.</p>
<p><iframe title="Beast of Reincarnation - Reveal Trailer | Xbox Games Showcase 2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L-qZiMPsNz0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In the announcement post, Joe Skrebels, Xbox Wire Editor In Chief, said, <em>“2026 is going to be an incredible year for Xbox players – you might even call it a… fabled year. To celebrate, we’re kicking it off with the fourth installment of our Developer_Direct broadcast on January 22, bringing you news, new gameplay, and insights directly from the incredible teams working on titles coming this year. Presented by the game creators themselves, Developer_Direct will once again give you an inside look at not just the games, but the studios working to bring them to life. Fittingly for Xbox’s 25<sup data-sleek-node-id="Me9CxY">th</sup> anniversary year, that includes the return of some of our most legendary franchises, which rub shoulders with a brand new title from one of Japan’s most beloved studios.”</em></p>
<p>The Xbox Developer Direct will be streaming on January 22nd at 10am Pacific / 1pm Eastern / 6pm UK.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-2026/">Xbox</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-announced-will-feature-fable-and-forza-horizon-6/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: The Legend Of Heroes: Trails Beyond The Horizon (Switch 2) - A Step Up From Daybreak II]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/the-legend-of-heroes-trails-beyond-the-horizon</link>
            <guid>1400503</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon Review - Screenshot 1 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161392/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure><p>The long-running <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-trails-kiseki-games-on-nintendo-switch">Trails</a></strong> series needs little introduction, as Falcom has been chipping away at this JRPG narrative for the better part of two decades across a variety of arcs and perspectives spread over more than a dozen interconnected games. While newcomers have traditionally been discouraged by the mountain of homework necessary to ‘get it’, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_heroes_trails_through_daybreak">Trails Through Daybreak</a> offered a nice on-ramp for the series a couple of years ago, kicking off a fresh arc. After a somewhat disappointing sequel, many hoped Falcom would right the ship with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-heroes-trails-beyond-the-horizon">Trails Beyond the Horizon</a> and start offering some payoffs for the many plot threads it’s set up. Luckily, Falcom <em>has</em> started to get things moving, and this entry overall feels like an improvement over <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_heroes_trails_through_daybreak_ii">Trails Through Daybreak II</a>, though it isn’t without its flaws.</p>
<p>Centred on the initiation of humanity’s first steps into space, this is narratively a continuation of the ‘Calvard arc’ that started with the first Daybreak game, but there’s also a good reason why this wasn’t simply called Trails Through Daybreak 3. While Van is (debatably) the primary character of this release, there are also two parallel story routes starring Kevin and Rean, two protagonists from previously concluded arcs who still have a role to play in the all-encompassing storyline now approaching a grand conclusion that the technological developments of Zemurian space exploration are bringing into focus.</p>
<figure><a title="The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon Review - Screenshot 2 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161388/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>This three-route narrative approach proves to be both a blessing and a curse. On the more positive side, it’s interesting checking in with these older characters to see how they've grown and changed ‘offscreen’ while the focus of the series shifted elsewhere. Plus, bringing some legacy characters into the fold demonstrates how Falcom has begun to unite the previously distinct casts in the run-up to a finale years in the making.</p>
<p>On the other hand, these additional cast members dilute the Calvard characters' story a bit and contribute to turning what is ostensibly a ‘payoff game’ into yet more table-setting for a later resolution. Given the mixed reception to Daybreak II's relatively inconsequential storyline, it feels like a rug-pull in some ways that we have to keep waiting for things to really kick into gear.</p>
<p>Not all players will consider this more indulgent pace a bad thing, but Trails Beyond the Horizon sometimes feels a little too comfortable in keeping the narrative in neutral, coasting towards a finale and making lots of promises that will hopefully be delivered on in the future.</p>
<figure><a title="The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon Review - Screenshot 3 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161399/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Combat continues the hybrid battle system implemented in the last two Daybreak games, mixing simple action combat with a much more in-depth turn-based system. When you first encounter enemies in the field, batting at them with your weapon to chip their health down will also build a gauge for a more powerful stun attack which can combo nicely into the turn-based mode.</p>
<p>This action combat acts as a nice way to clean up trash mobs or to soften up foes before a proper battle starts, but it can fall apart the longer you engage in it and realise how surface-level it tends to be. Falcom has done a good job of making it more interesting over time with the addition of things like reaction attacks and quick arts, but the mechanics here are still relatively sparse, particularly when compared to the significantly more complex turn-based mode.</p>
<p>Once you transition into turn-based combat, things play out more akin to a typical Trails game. When it’s a party member’s turn, you have a variety of attacks and active skills at their disposal, most of which are affected by character positioning. Not only can you freely move characters around within a fixed area before taking an action, but casting arts or crafts usually requires you to ‘aim’ an attack or area of effect to <em>just</em> the right spot to maximise passive buffs and how many enemies get caught in the blast.</p>
<figure><a title="The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon Review - Screenshot 4 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161410/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Amid all this, it’s important to also be cognisant of how your potential actions affect the ongoing battle timeline. Not only are there stat bonuses that you can use (or steal) if you’re careful about how you organise party actions in the turn order, but there are ways you can delay enemy actions to create more openings for your party. Though there’s a learning curve to its management, the timeline adds a fun and dynamic layer to combat proceedings that keeps you engaged not just in <em>what</em> you’re doing, but also <em>when</em> you’re doing it.</p>
<p>This hybrid battle system wasn’t just copy-and-pasted into this entry, however; Falcom has added even more mechanics in the form of ZOC, Awakening, and Shard Commands.</p>
<p>ZOC acts as a way of slowing down time, which either lets you get in a lot more hits on the field or gives you an immediate extra turn in turn-based combat, while Awakening acts as a ‘beast mode’ that can supercharge your damage. The most interesting of these are Shard Commands, which ultimately allow you to burn some boost points in turn-based fights to activate party-wide buffs that can massively turn the tide of battle if you time them properly.</p>
<figure><a title="The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon Review - Screenshot 5 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161384/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The new mechanics don’t feel like revolutionary new ideas and ultimately result in a lot prettier effects and bigger numbers, but it’s nice to see Falcom continuing to iterate on the new combat. Yet when considering all the different features together, it can sometimes feel like there’s a bit too much going on, particularly for the majority of the average encounters you’ll find yourself in. All the same, there’s lots to sink your teeth into with the gameplay here, and the system really shows its potential in the occasional tough boss fight that demands you pull out all the stops.</p>
<p>When it comes to building your team, Trails Beyond the Horizon also borrows the Orbment system from previous games, wherein each character can be equipped with various elemental crystals that grant them new arts, passives, and stat bonuses depending on how you lay things out.</p>
<p>Though there’s no explicit class system here, how you choose to configure a character’s Orbment can significantly affect the sort of role they occupy in your party, and you’re encouraged to really get into the weeds with experimenting with party compositions as the narrative unfolds. It can feel a bit confusing at first, but fooling around with it reveals lots of depth for tailoring your party, and I think it manages to strike an elegant solution to offering deep party customisation without needlessly bogging you down in menus and comparisons.</p>
<figure><a title="The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon Review - Screenshot 6 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161401/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>While the expected mountain of side quests is still present and accounted for, the Marchen Garten makes a return as a significant portion of the optional content. Here, it’s been dubbed the ‘Grim Garten’ and gotten a creepy makeover to reflect a story event that led to its change. The structure largely follows its previous appearance, wherein you put together a party and delve into procedurally generated dungeons in pursuit of fresh rewards and unique story content.</p>
<p>Not only does this provide a convenient way to put together characters who otherwise have little to no interaction with each other in the main story, but it also has an interesting feature where you collect and view 'memories' that fill in some <em>really</em> critical pieces of plot information.</p>
<p>Grim Garten doesn’t necessarily offer much that you can’t find when playing through the rest of the game, but it's a fun side mode that strips away a lot of fat and just lets you get to the meat of the thrilling combat. Plus, it can be a nice distraction from the occasionally glacial pace of the main narrative, where you can kill some time and gather resources to power up your team in the main story quest.</p>
<figure><a title="The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon Review - Screenshot 7 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161387/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>As far as visuals are concerned, this is one of the most beautiful Trails games yet. The new engine that Falcom debuted with Trails into Daybreak really sings on the Switch 2 hardware, holding to a mostly stable 60fps while maintaining an impressively sharp image quality in both docked and handheld modes.</p>
<p>Most notably, the text is <em>actually</em> readable on the Switch 2 screen this time around, clearing up an irksome issue from the last couple of games. Animation quality has also gotten a nice boost this time around, with many of the bigger attacks and arts having a nicely cinematic quality to them that hides some of the ‘Falcom jank’ that gives these games some of their charm.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Trails Beyond the Horizon is another solid new entry in the long-running series and feels like a firm step forward, even if it’s not quite as big a step as some may have hoped. Though the story can be uneven, it’s buoyed by a strong and diverse cast that keeps you invested and reminds you how all the work Falcom has been putting in over the years has ultimately been pushing towards something.</p>
<p>Couple its engaging (if sometimes slow) narrative with polished graphics, deep character customisation, and a dynamic combat system, and you’ve got a great and ambitious JRPG that especially stands out in these relatively early days of the Switch 2 library. I’d give this one a strong recommendation to series fans, as it really does feel like a step up from Daybreak II. Newcomers, though, will want to give this one a pass until they’ve played the previous two Daybreak games, at least.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/the-legend-of-heroes-trails-beyond-the-horizon]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Developer Direct to Bring New Info on Fable, Forza, and More Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-developer-direct-january-22nd-2026</link>
            <guid>1400500</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Xbox has announced a new Developer Direct presentation for later this month, and it will include information on several upcoming games, one of which I'll be particularly interested in learning about.</p><p>As revealed on the official Xbox <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-2026/" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">website</a>, the first Developer Direct of this year will air on January 22nd and will focus on three titles, namely <em>Fable</em>, <em>Forza Horizon 6</em>, and Game Freak's <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em>.</p><p>I'll be watching the progress Playground Games has made on <em>Fable </em>with interest; the game, which was delayed to 2026 <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fable-reboot-delayed-2026" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="48a951d3-c822-4051-88a7-e27a8ee10808" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">back in February last year</a>, is still a bit of an unknown quantity, and Xbox is promising "a first extended look" at it, so we'll hopefully get to learn exactly what it is during the show.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>We'll finally get a first look at <em>Fable </em>later this month.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As well as <em>Fable</em>, the Developer Direct will also be checking in with another Playground Games title in the form of <em>Forza Horizon 6</em>, which will be <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/forza-horizon-6-revealed-ps5" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="7ede297d-3bdf-4de5-b00a-3479b4a33aab" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">launching sometime this year</a> on PC and Xbox (and on PS5 later after that).</p><p>We already know the racer will be moving its open-world simcade action to Japan this time around, but Xbox is promising we'll get to see gameplay during the Developer Direct. I'm willing to bet you'll be racing cars; in fact, I'd put good money on it.</p><p>Finally, the Xbox Developer Direct will be taking a look at <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em>, the action RPG being worked on by <em>Pokemon </em>developer Game Freak that was revealed during Xbox's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-games-showcase-2025-all-news-and-announcements" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="4fbf63a2-36dd-4f58-96b0-c33fd1eb85da" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">summer showcase last year</a>.</p><p><em>Beast of Reincarnation </em>is the only game the show will focus on that isn't being published by Xbox Game Studios, but this isn't exclusively a first-party presentation, after all, so why not, I say.</p>
<p>Xbox hasn't promised any new reveals for the show, so it's possible these will be the only three games we get to see. We'll find out on January 22nd, when the next Xbox Developer Direct airs. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-developer-direct-january-22nd-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DJI Gimbal Stabilizers Go on Clearance as Osmo Mobile 7P With Built-In Extension Rod and Tripod Drops to Its All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dji-gimbal-stabilizers-go-on-clearance-as-osmo-mobile-7p-with-built-in-extension-rod-and-tripod-drops-to-its-all-time-low-2000658108</link>
            <guid>1400494</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Shaky footage is frustrating and, well, headache-inducing, especially when it ends up ruining a perfectly beautiful moment. If you film with your phone and are looking to enjoy stable, steady results, you might want to invest in a gimbal stabilizer.</p>
<p>DJI makes some of the best filming accessories on the market, and <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6702/">we just spotted its Osmo Mobile 7P gimbal stabilizer going at a 20% discount on Amazon.</a> It’s now available for just $103, after the retailer took a sweet $26 off its usual $129 price. Placing your orders today can also help you enjoy free delivery with your purchase, which brings the overall cost down even further. Just be sure to act fast, as the offer is expected to wrap up soon.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6702/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Steady, Hands-Free Footage</h2>
<p>This stabilizer works with both iPhones and Android smartphones. It’s powered by DJI’s seventh-generation stabilization technology to ensure cinema-quality high and low-angle footage at your fingertips, wherever you go. Getting started couldn’t be easier. Unfolding the gimbal turns it on, while the magnetic design makes mounting any paired phone a breeze. Once the phone is up, access the Mimo app with a single click and get to filming right away.</p>
<p>There’s support for native camera features like Apple ProRes and zoom tracking, plus the stabilizer plays nicely with different live streaming apps. Gesture control makes it easy to operate the thing from afar. For instance, the “palm” gesture starts/stops recording, the “Double L” gesture adjusts framing, and making a “V” takes a photo without you having to manually click any buttons. Additionally, you’re getting a built-in fill light which adjusts brightness and color temperature for better, Instagram-worthy results, even in low light conditions.</p>
<p>DJI Mimo offers dual-lens, active tracking. This allows the subject to move freely around while still staying in focus. Play basketball with your little ones, or just show off some dance moves without worrying about the camera focusing on the tree behind. And when there are more than one subjects in the frame, you can effortlessly switch between them by tapping on their selection boxes on your phone. This way, everyone gets to be in the spotlight!</p>



<p>The all-in-one design of the gimbal offers multiple use cases. You can hold it to take selfies or record on the go, as well as set it down as a tripod for solo creation and recording videos. Battery life is another strong selling point. A single charge gets you an operating time of around 10 hours, which is great for extended filming and those long live sessions. Even better, the gimbal is also capable of powering your phone, meaning you won’t have to worry about running out of your smartphone’s battery in the middle of filming an exciting adventure.</p>
<p>Note that you need the DJI Mimo app to get started with using the gimbal. It’s not available on Google Play due to some compatibility issues, but you can install it using the official DJI website.</p>
<p>To wrap it up, this gimbal makes filming a lot more fun, and convenient. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6702/">It typically retails for around $129, but the current discount lets you grab it for $103</a>. There are no delivery charges to worry about, either, so $103 is all you’ve got to pay. Just be sure to get your orders in before the offer expires or the stock runs out.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6702/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dji-gimbal-stabilizers-go-on-clearance-as-osmo-mobile-7p-with-built-in-extension-rod-and-tripod-drops-to-its-all-time-low-2000658108]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Games Confirmed For Xbox Developer Direct]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/first-games-confirmed-for-xbox-developer-direct/</link>
            <guid>1400488</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Xbox Developer Direct is just weeks away, and Xbox has confirmed the first three games that will appear at the annual event.</p>



<p>Airing on January 22 at 1pm ET/10am/6pm UK, the Xbox Developer Direct gives players a look at upcoming first-party games from Xbox Game Studios as well as some third-party titles. Last year featured games liked Ninja Gaiden 4, Doom: The Dark Ages, and Clair Obscur: Expedition 33, among others. And with Xbox celebrating its 25th anniversary this year, Microsoft is promising fans a “incredible year”, starting with the Developer Direct.</p>



<p>On Thursday, <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-2026/?ocid=Event_soc_omc_xbo_tw_Photo_lrn_1.8.1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox announced</a> that Fable, Forza Horizon 6, and Beast of Reincarnation would receive expended looks during the event.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-fans-will-see-at-xbox-s-developer-direct">What Fans Will See At Xbox’s Developer Direct</h2>



<p>For Fable, Playground Games is giving fans the first extended look at the game that’s scheduled to release this year. Forza Horizon 6, also from Playground Games, will receive its gameplay reveal after first being announced at Tokyo Game Show last year. </p>



<p>Lastly, Beast of Reincarnation comes from Pokémon developer Game Freak. The game is an Action RPG featuring “one person, one dog”. During the event, Game Freak will “reveal details of our protagonist Emma’s innovative plant manipulation actions and gameplay with her canine companion, Koo.”</p>



<p><strong>“Presented by the game creators themselves, Developer_Direct will once again give you an inside look at not just the games, but the studios working to bring them to life,”</strong> Joe Skrebels, Xbox Wire editor-in-chief, said. <strong>“Fittingly for Xbox’s 25<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;anniversary year, that includes the return of some of our most legendary franchises, which rub shoulders with a brand new title from one of Japan’s most beloved studios.</strong>“</p>







<p>It’s expected that at least one more game will be shown during the event, though what the game will be is still anyone’s guess. The Xbox Developer Direct takes place on Thursday, January 22. </p>



<p>Insider Gaming will have full coverage of the event as it airs.</p>



<p>What do you think of the lineup announced so far? Leave your thoughts in the comments, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-starcraft-shooter-revealed-blizzcon-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in-development StarCraft shooter</a>&nbsp;and when it could be revealed. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/first-games-confirmed-for-xbox-developer-direct/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 6 Remake Should be Led by Someone Else, Says FF7 Director]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-6-remake-should-be-led-by-someone-else-says-ff7-director/</link>
            <guid>1400485</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The director of Final Fantasy 7 Remake has stated that he would rather see someone else lead the Final Fantasy 6 Remake, with him taking the support role instead. </p>



<p>A lot of new details about Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 have been revealed recently, including that the game’s experience is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-game-experience-is-more-or-less-complete/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more or less complete</a> and that the devs consider it a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-devs-are-considering-a-full-title-after-part-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full title after this instalment</a>. However, a remake has now been mentioned, and it’s none other than 1994’s Final Fantasy 6. </p>



<h2 id="h-final-fantasy-7-remake-director-would-like-to-see-a-new-creator-come-in">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Director Would Like to See a New Creator Come In</h2>



<p>During a new interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jbrBjFZabUE&amp;t=3s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamerBraves</a> (via <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/final-fantasy/while-final-fantasy-6-remake-would-be-a-dream-project-final-fantasy-7-remake-director-thinks-hed-rather-someone-else-lead-it-should-i-be-the-one-to-undertake-remaking-another-series/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesRadar+</a>), FF7 Remake series director Naoki Hamaguchi spoke about someone else leading Final Fantasy 6 Remake. Hamaguchi first spoke about how Final Fantasy 6 has been influential in his journey as a gamer, and that influence often comes through in his work. However, FF7 Remake didn’t include any elements of FF6 as they were following a set script. </p>



<p>Hamaguchi then went on to talk about how many fans have requested a remake of Final Fantasy 6. But, he has been leading the FF7 Remake for close to 10 years and is “now finally seeing basically the end of the tunnel.” He wonders whether he should be the one responsible for taking up another remake series after pouring so much time into remaking this project. </p>



<p>Hamaguchi then states that, rather than him being the lead, he wants to see a “new creator” take the lead position, and he can take a more supportive role, “sort of cheer them on”. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Creative Vision Behind Final Fantasy VII Rebirth | Naoki Hamaguchi Exclusive Interview" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jbrBjFZabUE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, Final Fantasy 7 Remake’s Buster Sword almost had a “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remakes-buster-sword-almost-had-a-more-realistic-version/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more realistic</a>” version. Additionally, FF7 Remake Intergrade will be close to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">100GB on the Switch 2</a>. Do you think someone else should lead the Final Fantasy 6 Remake series, or the FF7 Remake director should take it up? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-3s-rumoured-expansion-could-take-players-to-a-new-region/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Witcher 3’s rumoured expansion, seemingly taking players to a new region</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-6-remake-should-be-led-by-someone-else-says-ff7-director/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Developer_Direct ’26 set for January 22]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/xbox-developer_direct-26-set-for-january-22</link>
            <guid>1400482</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Fable, Forza Horizon 6, and Beast of Reincarnation.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Microsoft will host “<a title="Platforms > Xbox [27,311 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Developer_Direct ’26” on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20260122T1800" target="_blank" rel="noopener">January 22 at 10:00 a.m. PT / 1:00 p.m. ET</a>, the company <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/08/xbox-developer-direct-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>. You will be able to watch it on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@xbox" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YouTube</a> and <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/xbox" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitch</a>. <span id="more-1017728"></span></p><p>The broadcast will feature in-depth looks at the following titles:</p><blockquote><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Fable (2026) [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fable-2026">Fable</a></em></strong> – <a title="Companies > Playground Games [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/xbox-game-studios/playground-games">Playground Games</a> welcomes players back to the fairytale land of Albion, with the first in-depth look at <em>Fable</em>—one of 2026’s most anticipated titles. Developers from the Playground team will unveil the magic and mischief that awaits players in this fresh new beginning for the franchise, including a first look at some stunning new gameplay. Of course, the core themes of Fable will all be there—choice, consequence, drama, <a title="Genres > Action [3,318 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>, British humor and (of course) chickens, all reimagined for existing fans and new players alike.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Forza Horizon 6 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/forza-horizon-6">Forza Horizon 6</a></em></strong> – The <em>Forza</em> team from Playground Games will share a deep-dive on the much-anticipated <em>Forza Horizon 6</em> as the open world racer takes players to the beautiful and contrasting landscapes of Japan. The segment will deep-dive into a very first look at gameplay, including reveals of new features—and how Japan comes to life in this stunning new installment.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Beast of Reincarnation [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/beast-of-reincarnation">Beast of Reincarnation</a></em></strong> – Join us as we delve into <a title="Companies > Game Freak [290 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/game-freak">Game Freak</a>‘s intense one-person, one-dog <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,921 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a>. For the first time, Game Freak will reveal details of our protagonist Emma’s innovative plant manipulation actions and gameplay with her canine companion, Koo. In <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em>, a profound and dangerous world unfolds in post-apocalyptic Japan. Discover the development secrets behind its creation in Developer_Direct.</li></ul></blockquote></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/xbox-developer_direct-26-set-for-january-22]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>