<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 19:29:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda: BOTW & TOTK Are "Transformative" On Switch 2, Says Digital Foundry]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/zelda-botw-and-totk-are-transformative-on-switch-2-says-digital-foundry</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-botw-totk-are-transformative-on-switch-2-says-digital-foundry.1251459/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>

<p>Plenty of people are busy revisiting two of the Switch 1's greatest games — <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Breath of the Wild</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Tears of the Kingdom</a> — on Switch 2. The frame a resolution boost are pretty remarkable in our eyes, and it seems like <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-zelda-upgraded-on-switch-2-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-tested">Digital Foundry agrees</a> with our assessment, calling the upgrades "transformative", especially for the 2023 sequel.</p>
<p>While the upgrades do cost a few pennies to pick up (though they are included in the Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack subscription), Digital Foundry thinks it's "worth it" to see just how remarkable these upgraded titles look on the new console.</p>
<p>First up is dynamic resolution, which is available on Switch 1, but the Switch 2's version has a higher range in both games to support 4K displays.</p>
<figure><a title="DF Zelda" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/12249eada6850/df-zelda.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XtdaeX_fGHI&amp;ab_channel=DigitalFoundry">Digital Foundry</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Where dynamic resolution targeted 1600x900 on Switch 1 while docked, the Switch 2 release boosts that to a maximum of 2560x1440. There are dips in extreme cases, but these are extremely rare.</p>
<p>Digital Foundry did spot a few moments where the frames dipped randomly during cutscenes for no obvious reasons, but quickly corrected itself. And while the resolution boost and improved textures are fantastic across the board, there's a distinct lack (or lack of effectiveness) of anti-aliasing in both games.</p>

<p>Improved load times (some of which are more than halved) and shadow quality are two other highlights the outlet was keen to point out, but we want to focus on the frame rate and performance.</p>
<p>Focusing on Tears of the Kingdom first, Digital Foundry confirms what we all know — the game is running at 60fps for the most part, and stays pretty consistently up in those figures whether you're in battle or using Ultrahand. Testing only the first 6 hours of the game, DF noticed one tiny blip when building vehicles. A huge improvement from our experiences on Switch 1.</p>
<figure><a title="DF Zelda" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/93a8df22abe6f/df-zelda.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XtdaeX_fGHI&amp;ab_channel=DigitalFoundry">Digital Foundry</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Breath of the Wild is even more consistent, with busier areas like Kakariko and Zora's Domain put under the test with exploding barrels. These stay at a rock solid 60fps now.</p>
<p>So, it's an impressive rundown, with a few little caveats. While "rough points" do remain in both games, these two upgrades come with an easy recommendation from the tech specialists.</p>
<p><em>Are you enjoying Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom on Switch 2? Tell us in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183390,183391 @ 1753297204 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/zelda-botw-and-totk-are-transformative-on-switch-2-says-digital-foundry]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Corps of Discovery Board Game Is a Challenging Trek Through the American Wilderness]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-corps-of-discovery-board-game-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-corps-of-discovery-board-game-is-a-challenging-trek-through-the-american-wilderness.1251453/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">“Here be monsters,” says the legend on so many antique maps, firing the imagination with thoughts of kraken, chimeras, or worse. But what if it were true? What if Lewis and Clarke, setting out on their expedition across the American interior, encountered buffalo-headed minotaurs and man-eating plants. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s the premise of the Corps of Discovery comic and now of this board game adaptation. The game comes from the same designers as the superb <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mind-mgmt-board-game-review"><u>Mind MGMT</u></a>, although, save for the comic book connection, this is a very different kind of game.</p><p id="whats-in-the-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="What's in the box">What’s in the Box</h2></p><div catalogid="a6a6c32d-c46f-44a3-834e-97a927e776f1" id="225555"><div id="225555" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Corps of Discovery</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Most box-openings start with a board, and Corps of Discovery is no exception, but the nature of the board itself is rather surprising. Instead of the usual fold-out affair, you get a cardboard sandwich: two layers of card stuck together, with room in between to slip in a sheet of paper. The top layer is punctuated by a regular grid of circular holes, and the box contains an equally unusual supply of thick cardboard sun tokens with wide “pegs” that fit loosely into the grid's holes.</p><p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/pxl-20250628-145130883-1753125741072.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Matt Thrower - (Deluxe edition shown)</figcaption></figure></output></p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are two folders of paper maps that slide into the sandwich, one for each of the two scenarios included in the game. There’s also a second board which is used for tracking the current game state, with spaces for three challenge cards, backpack items and water: this doubles as a handy reminder of the flow of each game day. There are tokens for the various resources that go in your backpack and for your water supply. There are also several card decks, not only the challenge cards that’ll outline the obstacles you must overcome each day, but also characters to play, items for them to use and so on. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As a scenario-based game, there are also additional cards and tokens applicable to particular scenarios. One thing to note is that, as a game based on a comic book series, all the components are furnished with excellent art from the original comics. While it might not be to everyone’s tastes, it does a fantastic job of bringing the game’s dangerous world to life, especially if you’re familiar with the source material.</p></div><p id="rules-and-how-it-plays"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Rules and how it plays">Rules and How It Plays</h2></p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/pxl-20250707-191631962-mp-1753126200486.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Matt Thrower - (Deluxe edition shown)</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Understanding how the game is set up is, unusually, an integral part of understanding how it plays. First, your group chooses one of the two scenarios to play (plus a training mission), and one of the 10 map sheets included for that scenario, covering it with a blank sheet so you can’t see what’s on it. You slip this, cover and all, into the cardboard-sandwich board then cover all the holes with the sun tokens. Then you slip out the blank sheet. The result is a game map that you know nothing about, ripe for exploration and discovery.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-cooperative-board-games"><u>cooperative game</u></a> where you’re working together to map the wilderness and survive. On your individual turn, you simply remove a sun token, revealing an icon underneath, and take a matching resource to add to your collective backpack. There’s no piece to mark where you are on the map. Instead, movement is abstracted away under the presumption that it’s easy to move through already explored territory. The next player just removes a sun token next to any already-revealed space, although there are some mountainous areas on each map that you can’t traverse.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/pxl-20250707-191556654-1753126158243.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Matt Thrower - (Deluxe edition shown)</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Exploration, however, is far from a random walk in the park. Each scenario has a set of rules about where and how the various different icons are laid out. In the Fauna scenario, for example, there’s always one wood icon per row and column, and there will always be a water icon orthogonally adjacent to each wood. Each mud icon will be next to a water and a stone, while forts always form an L-shape series with a water and a skull. There are more rules – and icons – but you get the idea.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This allows you to make predictions and deductions about what you’re going to encounter on the map. Sometimes you can figure it out with complete certainty, but more often it’s a bit of a gamble, where you can narrow down the odds without being sure. Exploration is thus both a fun puzzle where you can aim for specific resources, and an exercise loaded with tension. The rules are complex enough to make it a good group discussion, ensuring there’s a dynamic sense of cooperation, and something you can master with practice. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The rules are complex enough to make it a good group discussion, ensuring there’s a dynamic sense of cooperation, and something you can master with practice.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Each time you remove a sun token from the board you place it on one of three challenge cards dealt at the start of the game day. These cards have a resource requirement that you must spend in order to pass the challenge and a consequence for passing or failing, the latter of which usually means losing even more, different resources. You have to face these consequences once the card accumulates a certain number of suns, often only two or three. Considering many challenges require more than two or three resources to pass, this immediately puts your game under massive pressure to find the right icons on every turn.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/pxl-20250707-190121214-1753125922112.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Matt Thrower - (Deluxe edition shown)</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If you run out of water tokens, you die. If you end the day – timing out the three challenge cards for that die – without any food tokens, you die. Monsters generally don’t kill you outright but sap these precious, precious resource tokens until you die. Even when you’re on top of the resource-mapping system, most games will go down to the wire of you gaining your objective with a few measly drops of water left in your canteen. The last few turns ramp up the tension to crushing levels, until it almost feels like you’re struggling through a real wilderness, desperately following signs of water in the hope of surviving just one more day.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As if this wasn’t enough, on top of surviving you also have a goal to complete. This depends on the scenario. In Fauna, for instance, you’ll meet those buffalo-headed minotaurs who’ll make it harder to traverse rows and columns until you find a fort, learn a recipe for killing one, and sacrifice the necessary resources, all of which you were probably hoping to save to pass a challenge card. These kinds of trade-offs are part of the game’s strategy: identifying times when failing a daily challenge can be a useful step in the wider goal of passing the winning objectives.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/pxl-20250628-145141636-1753125839302.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Matt Thrower - (Deluxe edition shown)</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Other aspects of your decision-making come down to the characters in play and the gear you choose at the outset, all of which offer you special abilities to piece together and increase your chance of survival. You can plan ahead with these since you pick them yourself, look for combos, and build a strategy around them. But there are also destiny cards, random helpful bonuses that you can sometimes replenish by achieving in-game goals, and for these you’ll have to roll with whatever fate gives you, adjusting your tactics accordingly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With practice and luck you will, eventually, manage to beat Fauna and, in time, the game’s second scenario, Flora, which involves a giant carnivorous plant. Corps of Discovery goes out of its way to make these scenarios replayable by offering such a huge range of map sheets – you can also download and print out more – that memorising the layouts is essentially impossible. Variety, however, cannot fully undermine human psychology: there’s an innate tendency to treat a mission as “done” once it’s been won. This is exacerbated by the game’s high difficulty level and lack of narrative detail. Although it does a great job of conjuring up the spectre of starving in the wilderness, the challenge cards feel pretty mechanical, so repeated tries at a scenario can feel a little same-y.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/pxl-20250707-191508329-1753126054718.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Matt Thrower - (Deluxe edition shown)</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This isn’t quite the limiting factor it may sound like as it’ll take you repeated attempts to win both the scenarios, and there are expansions available which further the story and build considerably on the core mechanics – all four are included in the deluxe edition, which we used for the photos accompanying this review. But it still would have felt like a more complete experience if more of these elements had been included in the base game. As it stands, the game’s high toughness is the major motivation for a replay, and it’s almost enough by itself: winning against the odds, in a land where almost everything you encounter is out to kill you, is a hugely satisfying moment.</p><p id="where-to-buy"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Where to buy">Where to Buy</h2></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aBgxA8?object_uuid=efb277a0-a370-437f-878b-a449b5653b6a&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Amazon</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QP8e8O?object_uuid=efb277a0-a370-437f-878b-a449b5653b6a&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Miniature Market</a></li></ul></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 23, 2025 5:36 pm</p></div><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">Corps of Discovery’s core concept of exploring and surviving in unknown, hostile terrain is a strong one, and it’s well executed with some novel mechanical ideas. Each play feels like a gruelling crawl across the wilderness, just as it should, and it feels very rewarding when you manage to eke out a win. As strong as this central pillar is, however, the core of the game lacks much in the way of support from narrative, player interaction, or variety, particularly given the sparse supply of different scenarios to play, so it might not return to your table as often as it should.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-corps-of-discovery-board-game-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Legendary Vehicles To Use As Your MTG Commander After Edge of Eternities]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-legendary-vehicles-to-use-as-your-mtg-commander-after-edge-of-eternities</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-legendary-vehicles-to-use-as-your-mtg-commander-after-edge-of-eternities.1251450/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-edge-of-eternities-preview-everything-announced"><u>Edge of Eternities</u></a> kicks off this week (in prerelease at least), and while it’s yet another <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> set, it’s also shaking things up in the most popular format: Commander.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With the new set, Legendary vehicles (and the Spacecraft within Edge of Eternities) will be able to be used as your Commander, meaning there are almost two dozen Legendary Vehicles you can opt to lead your deck.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here are the ones you should consider, along with some key points to keep in mind.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">The Seriema</h3><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225656"><div id="225656" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering The Seriema</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Wizards revealed <a href="https://zdcs.link/9yD30m?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>The Seriema</u></a> first when showing off Edge of Eternities cards, and it’s perhaps unsurprising as it looks like a pretty potent card for White decks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Seriema can find a legendary creature and put it in your hand each time it arrives, but it can give tapped legendary creatures you control Indestructible. It costs 7 to Station and is a 5/5 in its own right (with Flying).</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Esika’s Chariot</h3></div><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225657"><div id="225657" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Esika’s Chariot</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">One for the cat lovers, <a href="https://zdcs.link/znxlZ4?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Esika’s Chariot</u></a> is a four-cost 4/4 that requires 4 to Crew, but can create tokens when it arrives, and then copy additional tokens.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tie it in with Doubling Season and your go-wide strategy can be, uh, wider than ever, creating four tokens when it enters, and then duplicating more when it attacks. More kitties, more chaos.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Entropic Battlecruiser</h3></div><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225658"><div id="225658" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Entropic Battlecruiser</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Oh boy, where to start? Stick a single creature in the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7dbv?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Entropic Battlecruiser</u></a> and your foes will be pinged for 3 life when discarding, but keep ramping up the Station and you’ll give it a huge health pool, flying, deathtouch, and force discards all around the table.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Will your opponents take it out before it gets there? Potentially, but we reckon it’s worth it for those people who love to mess with their opponents’ hands.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Exploration Broodship</h3></div><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225659"><div id="225659" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Exploration Broodship</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve been looking for a fresh Landfall Commander, this could be it. The <a href="https://zdcs.link/zjprJq?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Exploration Broodship</u></a> costs a single green mana, and it doesn’t take long to Station 3 and allow for bonus land each turn.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can then sacrifice that land to bring back some big, powerful cards from your graveyard. It’s found in the World Shaper Commander Deck, if you’re picking that one up.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">RMS Titanic</h3></div><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225660"><div id="225660" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering RMS Titanic</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">As soon as the rules change was announced, the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxAKZj?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>RMS Titanic</u></a> from the Doctor Who set saw a lot of love, and it’s understandable for what could be a pretty fun (if not entirely functional) Commander.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a 7/1 with a relatively low crew cost, and only costs four mana to bring into play. It’ll also act as a Treasure token engine, has flying and trample. We’d imagine the play here will be buffing it as much as possible to then make a whole host of tokens, which you can then use to bring it back into play with the Commander tax.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">The Last Ride</h3></div><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225661"><div id="225661" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering The Last Ride</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Another one that could be great fun as a literal last-hurrah, this one-mana black Legendary Vehicle from Aetherdrift (that set feels a while ago, right?) could have meme potential.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/z7OvwD?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>The Last Ride</u></a> is strongest the closer you are to death, and being able to roll it out from your Command zone to hit an opponent for big numbers is the kind of chaos we’re here for.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">The Indomitable</h3></div><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225662"><div id="225662" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering The Indomitable</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Fancy building a Pirate deck? Here’s your ideal ghost ship to set sail with. <a href="https://zdcs.link/9wRpPp?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>The Indomitable</u></a> is a 6/6, four-cost Legendary Artifact with Trample and card draw.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It also crews with three, but the real bonus is you can pull it from the graveyard if you have enough pirates attacking. Doing so lets you dodge that Commander tax and bring in those card draw opportunities.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Jackdaw</h3></div><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225663"><div id="225663" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Jackdaw</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">More pirates? Sure, Assassin’s Creed fans, we’ve got you. The <a href="https://zdcs.link/92xdgl?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Jackdaw</u></a> is a 4/4 with Crew 3 and a 3 mana cost, meaning it’s pretty easy to get up and running. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It then gives you <em>the option</em> of discarding your hand and redrawing based on artifact numbers, meaning you can slot it into an Artifact-focused deck and get some obscene card draw.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Weatherlight Compleated</h3></div><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225664"><div id="225664" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Weatherlight Compleated</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re really keen on a colorless deck (you Eldrazi sickos, we see you), then the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QObeYO?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Weatherlight Compleated</u></a> is well worth a look. A 5/5 with flying that costs two colorless is nifty in itself, but it also draws when cards die.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It doesn’t ‘Crew’ in the traditional sense, but if you’re throwing a few tokens at a foe you could power it up (and draw/scry) pretty swiftly.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Lumen-Class Frigate</h3></div><div catalogid="1ccbfd71-cd96-4da9-8e66-a7b565a1edaf" id="225665"><div id="225665" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Lumen-Class Frigate</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">A new Edge of Eternities option, the<a href="https://zdcs.link/z62kLj?object_uuid=75ca9cc3-68af-413b-8e65-01127207d870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u> Lumen-Class Frigate</u></a> has a pair of Station abilities. The first lets you power up your creatures, making it easier to hit the second.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It could be particularly fun with the Tidus deck from the Final Fantasy set as you swap your counters around to get a flying, lifelink spaceship powered up in various ways.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What to Consider When Picking Your Commander</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As with any Commander, picking a Legendary Vehicle that works into your desired playstyle is important, but many of the vehicles available are colorless.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Since you can only pick cards within your Commander’s color identity for your deck, that means you’d be limited to colorless cards if you opted for one of those. That may suit you just fine, but it’s worth mentioning.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Magic: The Gathering’s Spacecraft explained</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Spacecraft make their debut in Edge of Eternities as a new Artifact Subtype. The idea is that your ship uses its ‘Station’ ability to pick up crew. Once you reach the required number of charge counters (calculated from the power of the cards you use to ‘Station’), your ship becomes an Artifact Creature.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Wurmwall Sweeper, for example, needs to be crewed by four or more, so using ‘Station’ to put a couple of 2/2s in there would work nicely.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Wizards puts it best in <a href="https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/feature/edge-of-eternities-mechanics" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>its mechanics blog</u></a>: “If Wurmwall Sweeper has three charge counters on it, it's not a creature and it doesn't have flying. Once it gets its fourth charge counter, it becomes a 2/2 artifact creature with flying.”</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Where to Buy Magic: The Gathering's Edge of Eternities Set</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Ready to head to a whole new galaxy? Be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-edge-of-eternities-preorder-guide">our preorder guide</a> ahead of prerelease weekend which can help you buy packs, Commander decks, bundles, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.
</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 23, 2025 5:00 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-legendary-vehicles-to-use-as-your-mtg-commander-after-edge-of-eternities]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mobile dev Sandsoft is laying off around 65 employees and closing two studios]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mobile-dev-sandsoft-is-laying-off-around-65-employees-and-closing-two-studios</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mobile-dev-sandsoft-is-laying-off-around-65-employees-and-closing-two-studios.1251447/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">July 23, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sandsoft, a mobile developer headquartered in Saudi Arabia, is closing its studios in Riyadh and Barcelona, Spain, while laying off around 65 employees in the process.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">First </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://mobilegamer.biz/sandsoft-is-closing-its-barcelona-and-riyadh-studios-up-to-65-staff-affected/">reported by MobileGamer.Biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> earlier today, the layoffs are affecting around 40 staff members in Barcelona and 25 in Riyadh. The outlet was told that the job cuts are affecting employees working on internally developed games, while those working in publishing are safe. The studio is looking into transitioning some of the affected members into the latter, but there's no confirmation as of yet.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Sandsoft is doubling down on publishing, an area of our business where we’ve already demonstrated significant growth and see significant opportunities for future success," Sandsoft CEO David Fernández told MobileGamer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"As part of this strategic shift, we’ve made the difficult decision to close our internal studios in Barcelona and Riyadh. We deeply appreciate the team’s creativity and dedication, and we’re fully committed to supporting everyone through this transition."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A spokesperson added that the decision "isn't about the quality of work or talent at these studios," and that "it's really about concentrating our resources where we can have the biggest impact and build sustainable growth." As such, the team will now be concentrating solely on publishing.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/igea-launches-game-on-australia-to-assist-and-promote-local-developers" target="_self" data-discover="true">IGEA launches Game On Australia to assist and promote local developers</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Sandsoft still has two offices in Finland and China">Sandsoft still has two offices in Finland and China</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.pocketgamer.biz/sandsoft-plots-hybridcasual-expansion-with-three-new-deals/">reported by PocketGamer.Biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Sandsoft signed three new games as recently as March of this year. Back then, the studio also said it had "several more" games in testing and scheduled to release throughout the year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Riyadh studio is closing merely three years after opening, while the Barcelona studio was opened in 2023. Earlier that same year, Fernández spoke to MobileGamer.Biz about a plan to become a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://mobilegamer.biz/sandsoft-is-closing-its-barcelona-and-riyadh-studios-up-to-65-staff-affected/">mega publisher</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our ambition is to be a leader in the mobile games industry, from our region to the world, in the same way that you have in the U.S. not just mobile, but larger organizations —you have the Activisions, you have the Take-Twos, you have Electronic Arts," Fernández said. "Looking to China, you have Tencent and you have NetEase. We want to be one of those."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mobile-dev-sandsoft-is-laying-off-around-65-employees-and-closing-two-studios]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering's Final Fantasy Set Earned $200 Million In A Single Day]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-mtg-magic-gathering-vivi-stock-1851786817</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magic-the-gatherings-final-fantasy-set-earned-200-million-in-a-single-day.1251423/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>We already knew that the<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/magic-gatheirng-final-fantasy-cloud-sephiroth-pack-set-1851782830&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/magic-gatheirng-final-fantasy-cloud-sephiroth-pack-set-1851782830"><em> Final Fantasy</em> Universes Beyond expansion</a></span> was the fastest-selling set in <em>Magic: The Gathering</em>’s history, but an absurd new stat puts what that actually means in perspective. Hasbro’s CEO recently revealed the massive crossover sporting Cloud, Sephiroth and other Square Enix icons earned $200 million in a single day. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195670" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="184" data-playlist="195670,197550,196055" data-current="195670"><div><p>This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21167.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>“<em>Lord of the Rings </em>took six months to deliver $200 million of revenue, <em>Final Fantasy took</em> one day, and we left demand on the table,” Christian Cocks told analysts during Hasbro’s earnings call on Wednesday (via <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/cecianasta.bsky.social/post/3lunjx2yyh223&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://bsky.app/profile/cecianasta.bsky.social/post/3lunjx2yyh223" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bloomberg</em></a></span>). “So we couldn’t produce enough. I think we increased production runs on it 4x pre-release. It was substantially by many, many very high double-digit percentages ahead of any other production run we’ve ever done, and we left the market wanting more.”</p><p>That might come as a surprise to fans who have struggled to find <em>MTG</em> booster packs and Commander decks for the <em>Final Fantasy</em> set, with stock selling out during advance pre-order periods and then being marked up over MSRP at some locations by the time it hit store shelves. But critics who sometimes claim that Wizards of the Coast artificially limits supply to drive hype and engagement should be happy to know that the company intends to keep selling new <em>Final Fantasy </em>stock for a while yet. </p><p>“Our expectation is there’s going to be a nice long tail of backlist for the product. Likewise, we’re still selling <em>Lord of the Rings</em> product today,” Cocks said. “So even though we hit $200 million in December of ‘22 for<em> Lord of the Rings</em>, we sold a substantial percentage of that in the several years following and we expect <em>Final Fantasy</em> to be no different. It’s partially what’s powering our backlist, which already in, like, five and a half months in the year did more than we’ve ever done in any year prior.” Hasbro chief financial officer Gina Goetter added, “We’re continuing to produce this set. We think the set itself is going to have a huge long tail.” </p><p>While the rarest and most expensive cards in the set were only available in Collector Boosters, the initial print run of which is basically all sold out, regular cards in the set will continue to become available and hopefully drive down prices on some of the more sought-after standard cards. One of those is Vivi Ornitier, a mythic Legendary Creature from<em> Final Fantasy IX</em>. It’s a powerful card that synergizes well with lots of mana-hungry, spell-based decks and has been hovering around $45 for weeks now. Other examples include Knights of the Round and Bahamut summons. Unlike with standard <em>MTG</em> sets, fan interest in the cards for their own sakes, combined with their limited availability, is currently fueling <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/golden-chocobo-mtg-final-fantasy-price-foil-restock-1851784836&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/golden-chocobo-mtg-final-fantasy-price-foil-restock-1851784836">a particularly brutal reseller market for collectors</a></span>. </p><p>One upside is that those who just want to have fun playing with the cards can collect them much more cheaply in<em> Magic The Gathering Arena</em>, the video game adaptation for PC and mobile. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-4-d-d-mtg-arena-commander-g-i-joe-1851703869&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-4-d-d-mtg-arena-commander-g-i-joe-1851703869">It’s due for an update at some point in the future</a></span>, though Cocks also noted that the app only accounts for a small slice of the current fanbase. “Only 15-or-so percent of the player base plays on something like <em>Arena</em>,” he said. <br></p><p>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-mtg-magic-gathering-vivi-stock-1851786817]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Switch-Exclusive Games That Run Better On Switch 2 (Without A Patch)]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-games-run-better-upgrade-bayonetta-hyrule-xeno-1851786809</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/5-switch-exclusive-games-that-run-better-on-switch-2-without-a-patch.1251417/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Nintendo Switch 2 is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-sales-fastest-selling-console-ever-1851784293&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-sales-fastest-selling-console-ever-1851784293">already one of the most successful consoles ever launched</a></span>, and with it came a roster of exclusive launch games that we can only describe as…<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-console-launch-wii-gamecube-nes-snes-1851784781&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-console-launch-wii-gamecube-nes-snes-1851784781">a little lackluster</a></span>. Don’t get me wrong, I am the target audience for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-world-allt-racks-best-character-kart-win-1851785741&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-world-allt-racks-best-character-kart-win-1851785741">a new <em>Mario Kart</em></a></span><em> </em>and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/bravely-default-remaster-flying-fairy-hd-brave-norende-1851785709&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/bravely-default-remaster-flying-fairy-hd-brave-norende-1851785709">a remaster of a throwback 3DS RPG</a></span>. And with <em>Donkey Kong</em> out in the wild, the system is steadily building a healthier library. But after the rock-smashing and Blue Shell-throwing is done, the Switch 2 experience has mostly been about backwards compatibility. Nintendo certainly knows this, which is why <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nintendo.com/us/gaming-systems/switch-2/transfer-guide/games-with-free-updates/?srsltid=AfmBOop0eueemvfF_uaWJRzsD2_vCw7uMpq8lrEW0KO8yMt1pfY2bPsh&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/gaming-systems/switch-2/transfer-guide/games-with-free-updates/?srsltid=AfmBOop0eueemvfF_uaWJRzsD2_vCw7uMpq8lrEW0KO8yMt1pfY2bPsh" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the company selected a handful of titles</a></span> to receive patches that take advantage of the Switch 2 hardware. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195905" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Three Things We Learned From The Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth Demo " data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="121" data-playlist="195905,195519,196646" data-current="195905"><div><p>Three Things We Learned From The Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth Demo </p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195905/195905_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195905/195905_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195905/195905_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195905/195905_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21419.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Classic Switch games that run better than ever after free patches, what more could you ask for? That isn’t a rhetorical question, and the answer is “several additional improved games that never got Switch 2 patches.”</p><p>That’s right, <strong>many original Switch games actually look and run better than they ever did, despite not getting patched for the new system!</strong> It’s not <em>quite </em>the same as revisiting your Steam backlog after getting your new <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/toy-story-gaming-pc-rig-msi-pixar-disney-taiwan-price-1851784996&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/toy-story-gaming-pc-rig-msi-pixar-disney-taiwan-price-1851784996">special edition high-end Toy Story gaming PC</a></span>, as most games are still bound by whatever settings their respective developers hard-coded into them. However, games that had uncapped frame rates or performance hiccups almost always benefit from beefier hardware. For instance, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-batman-arkham-knight-30-fps-boost-performance-1851783702&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-batman-arkham-knight-30-fps-boost-performance-1851783702">the infamously messy OG Switch port of <em>Batman: Arkham Knight</em></a></span> performs much better now, even though it’s still bound to a cap of 30 FPS (Frames Per Second). Conversely, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/trials-of-mana-original-remake-best-version-1851615276&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/trials-of-mana-original-remake-best-version-1851615276">the RPG cult classic <em>Trials of Mana</em></a></span> actually hits 60 FPS on the Switch 2, even though it <em>looked </em>like it ran at 30 FPS on the original Switch.</p><p>That’s all well and good, but performance enthusiasts have likely played these third party games on stronger hardware already. <strong>What about games that were <em>only </em>playable on the original Switch that run noticeably better on the Switch 2?</strong> I’m happy to tell you that you’ve come to the right place, my dear Nintendo fan. If you’re looking for more ways to take advantage of your big new handheld gaming device, give these five unpatched games a shot for some surprising results.</p><h2 id="h555967"><a id=""></a>1: <em>Hyrule Warriors: Definitive Edition</em></h2><figure id="" data-id="c568fae45183219258c847eacf9436f4" data-recommend-id="image://c568fae45183219258c847eacf9436f4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of Hyrule Warriors: Definitive Edition. Impa is shown reaching for her sword on her back." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Hyrule Warriors: Definitive Edition. Impa is shown reaching for her sword on her back." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c568fae45183219258c847eacf9436f4" data-recommend-id="image://c568fae45183219258c847eacf9436f4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of Hyrule Warriors: Definitive Edition. Impa is shown reaching for her sword on her back." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Generally speaking, games in Koei Tecmo’s <em>Warriors </em>series are big beneficiaries of the new hardware. Games like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hyrule-warriors-age-of-calamity-the-kotaku-review-1845702074&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hyrule-warriors-age-of-calamity-the-kotaku-review-1845702074"><em>Hyrule Warriors: Age of Calamity</em></a></span> infamously suffered from bouts of severe slowdown, which is by-and-large fixed when playing on the Switch 2. That said, I want to give a nod to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hyrule-warriors-definitive-edition-the-kotaku-video-r-1826080946&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hyrule-warriors-definitive-edition-the-kotaku-video-r-1826080946"><em>Hyrule Warriors: Definitive Edition</em></a></span> specifically, because it actually does achieve that silky smooth 60 FPS during gameplay, whether you play it in Docked or Handheld mode.</p><p>It certainly doesn’t hurt that <em>Hyrule Warriors: Definitive Edition</em> is both a massive love letter to the <em>Zelda </em>series and one of the best <em>Warriors </em>games ever made. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hyrule-warriors-imprisoning-war-zelda-tokt-switch-2-1851774238&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hyrule-warriors-imprisoning-war-zelda-tokt-switch-2-1851774238">The Switch 2 will get its own <em>Hyrule Warriors </em>game soon</a></span>, but those ready for some good ol’ hacking-and-slashing <em>now </em>can’t go wrong by playing the first entry in this spinoff series.</p><h2 id="h555968"><a id=""></a>2: <em>Pokémon Sword &amp; Shield</em></h2><figure id="" data-id="d51f21d48f170156fa5fe8ac67ae43c4" data-recommend-id="image://d51f21d48f170156fa5fe8ac67ae43c4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of Pokémon Sword. The trainer is on his bike in the wild area." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Pokémon Sword. The trainer is on his bike in the wild area." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Pokemon Company</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d51f21d48f170156fa5fe8ac67ae43c4" data-recommend-id="image://d51f21d48f170156fa5fe8ac67ae43c4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of Pokémon Sword. The trainer is on his bike in the wild area." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-and-violet-review-nintendo-switch-1849843125&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-and-violet-review-nintendo-switch-1849843125"><em>Pokémon Scarlet &amp; Violet</em></a></span> are among the most well-known games to get Switch 2 patches, because…um, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-switch-2-upgrade-shiny-hunting-1851784505&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-switch-2-upgrade-shiny-hunting-1851784505">oh boy did they need it</a></span>. However, that pair of monster-catching adventures were far from the first in the series on the Switch, nor were they the first <em>Pokémon </em>games to run poorly The previous generation of games, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-sword-and-shield-the-kotaku-review-1839812633&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-sword-and-shield-the-kotaku-review-1839812633"><em>Pokémon Sword &amp; Shield</em></a></span><em>,</em> saw performance dips in the open Wild Area, and several effects and battle transitions would play with noticeable slowdown too. These issues seem to be fixed on the Switch 2, even if some of the more infamous graphical imperfections remain the same. Either <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/trees-have-become-the-pokemon-fandoms-ultimate-brain-wo-1847541501&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/trees-have-become-the-pokemon-fandoms-ultimate-brain-wo-1847541501">the tree</a></span> bothers you or it doesn’t.</p><p>While other <em>Pokémon </em>games on the system aren’t as notoriously awful on the performance side (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-arceus-botw-graphics-nintendo-switch-de-1848495479&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-arceus-botw-graphics-nintendo-switch-de-1848495479">despite how often the series’ visual fidelity comes under fire</a></span>), they all generally benefit from the Switch 2 upgrade. Even the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-lets-go-eevee-and-pikachu-the-kotaku-review-1830393778&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-lets-go-eevee-and-pikachu-the-kotaku-review-1830393778"><em>Pokémon Let’s Go</em></a></span> games run a little smoother in places like Veridian Forest. It’d be nice if all the mainline games in Gamefreak’s monster catching franchise received proper Switch 2 upgrades, but in the meantime, it’s not a bad time at all to catch up with any past generations you missed.</p><h2 id="h555969"><a id=""></a>3: <em>Xenoblade Chronicles 2</em></h2><figure id="" data-id="e42e8adb0d9be2870e0fcc4cbce9d8a1" data-recommend-id="image://e42e8adb0d9be2870e0fcc4cbce9d8a1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of a cutscene in Xenoblade Chronicles 2. Pyra and Rex are looking to the right of the screen with their mouths open." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of a cutscene in Xenoblade Chronicles 2. Pyra and Rex are looking to the right of the screen with their mouths open." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Monolith Soft</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e42e8adb0d9be2870e0fcc4cbce9d8a1" data-recommend-id="image://e42e8adb0d9be2870e0fcc4cbce9d8a1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of a cutscene in Xenoblade Chronicles 2. Pyra and Rex are looking to the right of the screen with their mouths open." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This spot honestly belongs to basically every <em>Xenoblade Chronicles </em>game—<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xenoblade-chronicles-2-the-kotaku-review-1820903229&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xenoblade-chronicles-2-the-kotaku-review-1820903229"><em>Xenoblade Chronicles 2</em></a></span> is just what I have on hand to test. Monolith Soft’s flagship RPG series has consistently pushed the limits of Nintendo’s hardware, cramming massive and lush worlds into hardware that’s roughly a generation behind the home console competition. The results are typically impressive, if not a bit compromised. <em>Xenoblade Chronicles 2</em> in particular could suffer from some dips in image quality due to dynamic resolution scaling, and performance wouldn’t necessarily hold at 30 FPS either.</p><p>I’m not 100% sure these issues are <em>totally </em>smoothed over after watching <em>Xenoblade Chronicles 2</em> run on my Switch 2 with my naked eye, but they’re at least greatly minimized. Overall, the experience is just better on the new hardware. The resolution doesn’t appear to dip in the game’s usual trouble spots, and the frame rate didn’t take noticeable hits either. I do hope the <em>Xenoblade</em> series can get proper Switch 2 upgrades, as the game could clearly look way sharper if it wasn’t capped at such a low resolution (especially in handheld mode). That said, this series also contains over 500 hours of content if you intend to 100-percent each game, so I think it’s perfectly okay to get started on it now.</p><h2 id="h555970"><a id=""></a>4: <em>Super Mario RPG</em></h2><figure id="" data-id="dc84c8e9b71cb406f91abd0cdaa3cf44" data-recommend-id="image://dc84c8e9b71cb406f91abd0cdaa3cf44" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of Super Mario RPG for the Nintendo Switch. Mario is jumping after Bowser, who has just kidnapped Princess Peach." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Super Mario RPG for the Nintendo Switch. Mario is jumping after Bowser, who has just kidnapped Princess Peach." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dc84c8e9b71cb406f91abd0cdaa3cf44" data-recommend-id="image://dc84c8e9b71cb406f91abd0cdaa3cf44" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of Super Mario RPG for the Nintendo Switch. Mario is jumping after Bowser, who has just kidnapped Princess Peach." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>To address the pedants right off the bat, <em>technically</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mario-rpg-remake-switch-review-metacritic-1851024152&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mario-rpg-remake-switch-review-metacritic-1851024152"><em>Super Mario RPG</em></a></span> isn’t a Switch-exclusive game since it originally came out on the Super Nintendo. That said, the remake of the game <em>is</em>, and it didn’t always hold at a 60 FPS throughout its runtime on the original Switch. This is most noticeable in the game’s opening, but you can feel the occasional slowdown elsewhere too.</p><p>Fortunately, the Switch 2 smooths over these trouble spots effortlessly. Between the remaster of <em>Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door </em>and the all new <em>Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</em>, the past few years have been great for <em>Mario </em>RPG fans. That latter title benefits from the Switch 2 hardware too! If you’ve never tried these quirky adventures, you’re in for a treat whether you’re a casual gamer or a hardcore RPG nut.</p><h2 id="h555971"><a id=""></a>5: <em>Bayonetta 3</em></h2><figure id="" data-id="bdda8603fb00605e4e0d7511a7755052" data-recommend-id="image://bdda8603fb00605e4e0d7511a7755052" data-format="jpg" data-width="2550" data-height="1434" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A promotional screenshot of Bayonetta 3. The titular Bayonetta is holding a gun and looking towards the camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A promotional screenshot of Bayonetta 3. The titular Bayonetta is holding a gun and looking towards the camera." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Platinum Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bdda8603fb00605e4e0d7511a7755052" data-recommend-id="image://bdda8603fb00605e4e0d7511a7755052" data-format="jpg" data-width="2550" data-height="1434" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A promotional screenshot of Bayonetta 3. The titular Bayonetta is holding a gun and looking towards the camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Up to this point, we’ve talked about performance boosts in games that were mostly okay without them. However, in a fast-paced action game like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/bayonetta-3-review-ending-luka-jeanne-nintendo-switch-1849735230&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/bayonetta-3-review-ending-luka-jeanne-nintendo-switch-1849735230"><em>Bayonetta 3</em></a></span>, you’ll <em>really </em>feel the difference that extra frames can offer. On the original Switch, <em>Bayonetta 3 </em>generally targeted 60 FPS but usually didn’t hit it. Instead, the game would hover in the 50 FPS range and could drop <em>way </em>lower during certain attack animations. It’s not unplayable by any means, but obviously there’s room for improvement.</p><p>Which is <em>exactly </em>what <em>Bayonetta 3</em> on the Switch 2 serves up. Not only do you get those smooth 60-FPS graphics (where it’s possible in the game), but the Switch 2 even fixes some audio desync bugs that could pop up in the original sometimes. Load times are way faster too. If we weren’t limiting this list to Switch-exclusive games, <em>Bayonetta 3</em> would still be one of the most improved games on Nintendo’s next generation hardware.</p><p>As was the case with <em>Xenoblade Chronicles</em>, it would still be nice for <em>Bayonetta 3</em> to get a proper Switch 2 upgrade. If nothing else, the visuals would pop if the resolution was raised, especially in handheld mode. But even if that never comes to pass, there’s no denying that <em>Bayonetta 3</em> is better than it’s ever been before.</p><p>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-games-run-better-upgrade-bayonetta-hyrule-xeno-1851786809]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 details including October release date leak ahead of this week's official reveal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-details-including-an-october-release-date-leak-ahead-of-official-reveal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-details-including-october-release-date-leak-ahead-of-this-weeks-official-reveal.1251411/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Fresh Battlefield 6 details have emerged from a reliable leaker ahead of its big trailer reveal tomorrow, including word the latest instalment of EA's beleaguered shooter series is eyeing up an October release date and an €80 price tag on consoles.
</p>
<p>
That's according to <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/battlefield-6-date-de-sortie-editions-prix-precommande-on-vous-devoile-toutes-nos-infos-inedites-60267">Dealabs' consistently reliable Billbil-kun</a>, whose sources claim Battlefield 6's previously rumoured 10th October release date is accurate, and that the game will launch for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X/S in both Standard and Phantom Edition forms - costing €79.99 and €109.99 respectively on consoles and €10 less on PC.
</p>
<p>
As to what the Phantom Edition actually <em>is</em>, it's supposedly a digital-only special edition featuring unspecified in-game content, which Standard Edition owners can upgrade to at any time via a €29.99 Phantom Pack. It's also claimed there'll be no early access with any version.
</p>
<p>
Battlefield 6 pre-orders will reportedly open next Thursday, 31st July, one week after the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-is-finally-getting-a-reveal-trailer-tomorrow-heres-when-and-where-you-can-watch-it">game's grand trailer unveiling</a>, which is officially scheduled to take place tomorrow, 24th July, at 4PM BST/8AM PST. This, of course, should also be the point we find out if all of the above is true.
</p>
<p>
We already know some of what to expect, of course, thanks to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/new-battlefield-leak-confirms-return-of-fan-favourite-mode">various playtest leaks</a> and EA's early confirmation Battlefield 6 would feature a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-says-next-battlefield-is-modern-day-brings-back-classes-and-more-focused-maps">modern-day setting, classes, and more</a>. It's going to have to be a pretty special, however, if the publisher has any hope of reaching its<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-reportedly-expects-battlefield-6-to-have-100-million-players-three-times-more-than-the-series-best-seller">reported 100m player target</a> across Battlefield 6's main game and a separate free-to-play battle royale - a particularly lofty goal after the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-admits-battlefield-2042-flopped-but-would-have-been-less-than-10-percent-of-annual-revenue-anyway">disastrous Battlefield 2042</a>.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-details-including-an-october-release-date-leak-ahead-of-official-reveal]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another Code Director's Gorgeous Interactive Adventure Comes To Switch 2 Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/another-code-directors-gorgeous-interactive-adventure-comes-to-switch-2-next-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/another-code-directors-gorgeous-interactive-adventure-comes-to-switch-2-next-week.1251402/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Just weeks after being announced</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Dear me, I was..." href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ba8baa243b9f1/dear-me-i-was.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Arc System Works</em></figcaption></figure><p>Arc System Works, the studio most famous for Guilty Gear but who also worked on the recent <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/another_code_recollection">Another Code: Recollection</a> remake, is releasing Switch 2 exclusive <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/dear-me-i-was">Dear me, I was...</a> on 31st July 2025 (thanks <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/dear-me-i-was-launches-july-31">Gematsu</a>!)</p>
<p>The game was spotted on the <a href="https://store-jp.nintendo.com/item/software/D70010000099568">Japanese eShop earlier today</a> and will retail for around 850 yen. That's less than $6 / £5.</p>
<p>Not date has been confirmed for the Western release just yet, but we're sure it'll be the same, as Gematsu states that the game will support multiple language options in addition to English, Japanese and Korean.</p>
<p>Dear me, I was... <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/arc-system-works-announces-new-interactive-adventure-for-switch-2">was only announced a few weeks</a> back with a beautiful teaser trailer, and comes from one of the minds behind <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/trace_memory">Another Code</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/hotel_dusk_room_215">Hotel Dusk</a> — Taisuke Kanasaki — along with the director of Another Code: Recollection, Maho Taguchi.</p>

<p><em>Let us know if you're looking forward to the game in the comments below</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184469 @ 1753297217 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://store-jp.nintendo.com/item/software/D70010000099568" rel="noopener" href="https://store-jp.nintendo.com/item/software/D70010000099568">store-jp.nintendo.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/dear-me-i-was-launches-july-31" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/dear-me-i-was-launches-july-31">gematsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/230a129d2c3b29795d8f0ca7bdb4b929 @ 1753298742 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/another-code-directors-gorgeous-interactive-adventure-comes-to-switch-2-next-week]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sloclap Shoots Off the First Major Patch for Rematch, Includes Button Re-Mapping, Hit Detection Fixes, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/rematch-update-patch-1-notes-sloclap/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sloclap-shoots-off-the-first-major-patch-for-rematch-includes-button-re-mapping-hit-detection-fixes-and-more.1251396/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/rematch-review-an-excellent-football-game-thats-been-tackled-at-the-knees/">Rematch</a>, developer Sloclap's new football game, has just received its <a href="https://www.playrematch.com/post/patch-1-1-200-100">first major patch</a>, a little more than a month after it launched across PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S.</p>



<p>Earlier in the week, Sloclap celebrated Rematch <a href="https://wccftech.com/rematch-surpasses-5-million-players-since-launch-crossplay-support-still-6-9-weeks-away/">surpassing 5 million unique players</a> who've checked it out, either through buying the game directly or checking it out through Xbox Game Pass. Days prior to that, it published a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2138720/view/534356176690741599?l=english">lengthy blog</a> where it acknowledged the feedback players have been giving the team in the last month, and committed to fixing some of the game's key problems, starting with a patch that was due out this week.</p>



<p>That patch is here, with one of the highlights being the fact that players can now re-map the controls on a controller, though Sloclap admits that this first version of button mapping is "<em>quite basic</em>," and that a more advanced version which lets players create combinations of inputs is coming.</p>



<p>Better hit detection is the second highlight of the patch that Sloclap hits, though if you talk to anyone (like me) who has been playing Rematch this past month, hit detection should be the first thing Sloclap mentions in every patch notes release, for as long as it remains an issue. Hit detection, whether that's regarding the ball not being properly handled by goalkeepers or with players not correctly responding to tackles, is the key issue plaguing every game in Rematch. </p>



<p>It's good to see that so many of the fixes in these patch notes are directly related to hit detection issues, and hopefully this patch is the beginning of a turn for the better for the quality of each match.</p>



<p>While this patch has a few key fixes, it still doesn't address one of the major features players have been asking for since the game launched, which is full crossplay support. And players will continue to wait for it until sometime in September, according to Sloclap.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/rematch-update-patch-1-notes-sloclap/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Campaign Teaser Shows NATO Under Attack, and Includes the Return of the Series' Classic Theme]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-campaign-teaser-shows-nato-under-attack-and-includes-the-return-of-the-series-classic-theme</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-campaign-teaser-shows-nato-under-attack-and-includes-the-return-of-the-series-classic-theme.1251393/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Ahead of EA's full <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/untitled-battlefield-game">Battlefield 6</a> reveal tomorrow, a brief teaser for the game's campaign has been posted online, revealing a major conflict. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Set in the near future, Battlefield 6's campaign will see NATO under attack. Its base in Georgia is hit, the British territory of Gibraltar is invaded, and NATO's secretary general is assassinated inside the organisation's Brussels headquarters. The perpetrator? An organisation named Pax Armata. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">A number of countries, including France, are then confirmed to have left NATO to form a new coalition, as in-universe news headlines question whether NATO itself is now a "thing of the past". Hmm...</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The teaser then concludes with Battlefield's trademark theme — you know the one, that 'dun dun dun dun dun' drumbeat — and a reminder that the game's full reveal will take place tomorrow, July 24, at 8am Pacific / 4pm UK time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eagle-eyed viewers will spot the logo for "BF Studios" on the end of the teaser — this is the coalition of developers that EA has pulled together to work on the game, including franchise founder DICE, Los Angeles-based sister studio Ripple Effect, Montreal-based Dead Space Remake developer Motive, and British Need for Speed studio Criterion.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's also the note that "no weapon, military vehicle or gear manufacturer is affiliated with or has sponsored or endorsed this game."</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Battlefield (@Battlefield) <a href="https://twitter.com/Battlefield/status/1948035690836447674?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 23, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">"Pax Armata rises as NATO cracks," a message posted on Battlefield's X / Twitter account reads. "Their motto? 'Our protection, your peace.' But who’s pulling the strings and to what end?" Presumably we'll find out more tomorrow.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In recent months, footage of Battlefield 6 from various closed playtests has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/psa-early-battlefield-6-footage-seems-to-have-leaked-online">started leaking online,</a> showing the game's modern setting, various firefights, destructible environments, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/all-the-improvements-and-features-revealed-by-the-battlefield-6-gameplay-leaks">quality of life improvements</a>, and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-battlefield-leak-reveals-extremely-brief-look-at-the-start-of-a-battle-royale-match-as-ea-issues-takedowns">start of a battle royale match</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Battlefield 6 is currently slated to launch <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-says-next-battlefield-is-expected-fiscal-year-2026">sometime during the current fiscal year</a>, before March 2026. It seems likely we'll see that window narrowed considerably when the game is fully unveiled.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-campaign-teaser-shows-nato-under-attack-and-includes-the-return-of-the-series-classic-theme]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Major Rematch Patch Adds Colorblind Mode And Other Significant Changes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/major-rematch-patch-adds-colorblind-mode-and-other-significant-changes/1100-6533383/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/major-rematch-patch-adds-colorblind-mode-and-other-significant-changes.1251360/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533383">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The popular soccer game Rematch has reached 5 million players, and now the game's newest patch has arrived, ushering in new features and changes--however, the promised cross-play feature remains missing.</p><p>Developer Sloclap said in a <a href="https://www.playrematch.com/post/patch-1-1-200-100" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">blog post</a> that the new Rematch patch "contains many changes in all domains, which should all improve the game in different ways." As for the promised cross-play feature and netcode improvements, Sloclap said these efforts require "the work of specialists in their domain."</p><p>"We can't put all our resources on these topics to make them happen faster," Sloclap said. However, the studio teased that it's making "very good progress" and will have more news to share soon.</p><p>New for Rematch in the update is a colorblind mode that caters to people with deuteranopia, protanopia, or tritanopia by offering a toggle for team colors. Additionally, the player-progression screen has been updated to improve readability. In terms of fixes, the ball indicator should no longer incorrectly follow the ball, while issues with the social panel screen have been addressed.</p><p>There is also a new gamepad-remapping feature in Rematch that is described as "quite basic" for now, but Sloclap said it wanted to start slow here before offering a "more advanced version soon." The new Rematch update also has an improved goal validation system for when the ball is caught on the line. "Decision-making now uses a delay to check for potential deflect/catch and account for network variation before validating the goal," Sloclap said.</p><p>You can see the full patch notes below.</p><p>Sloclap also announced that it's creating Test Servers for the purpose of testing future updates in "separate environments." Sloclap said it needs to spend more time on this before it's ready, however.</p><h2>Matches / Core Gameplay Improvements</h2><h2>Major Changes / Updates</h2><p>Gamepad Remapping</p><ul><li>This first version is quite basic (it doesn’t allow to create combinations of inputs), but we opted to allow players to start tinkering with mapping before offering a more advanced version soon.</li></ul><p>Better Hit Detection</p><ul><li>Fixed an issue where the ball would be deflected instead of being caught by the goalkeeper in certain situations : the ball speed was not correctly evaluated to decide whether to catch or deflect.</li></ul><p>Note: some design to tweaks to catch vs. deflect parameters will also be coming soon.</p><ul><li>Improved goal validation when the ball is caught on the goal line : decision making now uses a delay to check for potential deflect/catch and account for network variation before validating the goal.</li><li>Other general netcode improvements and fixes.</li></ul><h2>Major Fixes</h2><ul><li>Multiple fixes to camera during goal replays, removing jitter</li><li>Fixes to "hindering" (physical contact between players): it should now be more efficient to “body block” opponents</li><li>Fixed end match screens skip function (at last!): scoreboard can now be analyzed without going back to ranking screen automatically</li><li>Fixed pause menu toggle in any stage of match: pause menu should be accessible at all times during matches</li><li>Fixed various crashes happening during post-goal sequence</li></ul><p>Multiple animation improvements and fixes</p><ul><li>New statics tap animations</li><li>Polish on volley shoots animations</li><li>Polish on Dive player animations</li><li>Polish on pushball animations</li><li>Minor animation improvements and fixes</li></ul><h2>Minor / Misc. Fixes</h2><ul><li>Fixed an issue where goalkeepers were not reacting to opponents' collisions: goalkeepers should now react to other player’s physical presence the same way other players do (this does not change the rules of invulnerability against tackles).</li><li>Fixed several issues with the physical &amp; visual state of the ball inside menus &amp; at matches’ kickoff.</li><li>Shots deviated by an outfield player's defense mode now have a wider angle, except against goalkeeper or sweeper shots.</li><li>On mouse and keyboard, when performing a tap, the camera control is given back a bit sooner than before (more news on m&amp;kb tap aiming soon!)</li><li>Fixed an issue with Ball Camera Lock while using mouse and keyboard where the camera would teleport back to the previous position when shooting.</li><li>Fixed an issue where pushball would not keep last direction inputted when going quickly back to neutral</li><li>Increased communication/ball call cooldown from 0.8 to 1s, to slightly decrease comms spam</li><li>Shots now trigger a rumble during the shoot preparation</li><li>Goal Bursts are now stopped correctly after goal replay</li><li>Multiple VFX fixes and improvements during and after goal replay</li><li>Fixed pause menu footer display in match</li><li>Fixed missing move input in spectator mode</li><li>Fixed spectator icon on match livefeed</li><li>Fixed ping icons legibility: switched icon and background colors</li><li>Fixed opponent nametag in match stats screen: color fixes</li><li>Display player number for opponents in scoreboard</li><li>Fixed scoreboard input actions display in footer</li><li>Audio update for the UI SFX of post match screens</li><li>Update on the music integration during the start section of a match</li><li>Various audio update on animations</li><li>Fixed a bug where the music playing during the beginning of a match was not the expected one</li><li>Multiple environment and lighting improvements and fixes</li><li>Multiple minor fixes to tutorials and workshops</li></ul><h2>Menus &amp; Interface</h2><h2>Additions and updates</h2><ul><li>Colorblind mode: when activated, this option will change color selection for teams at match start, according to the three main types of colorblindness (deuteranopia, protanopia, tritanopia). In the next patch, this feature will be pushed further, to apply a filter on the whole screen.</li><li>Visual update of player progression screen - improved readability and UI feedback.</li><li>Added voice channel parameter choice on custom match parameter screen, allowing to chat with all players in the lobby, useful to train with friends on both teams.</li></ul><h2>Additions and updates</h2><ul><li>Fixed ball indicator arrow orientation, was not always following the ball</li><li>Fixed navigation focus and camera in customization menu</li><li>Fixed social panel navigation and display issues</li><li>Fixed ""Some players in lobby are still in a match"" pop-up can not be displayed in same time as reconnect prompt"</li></ul><h2>Misc. Fixes</h2><ul><li>Fixed options footer display</li><li>Fixed matchmaking research panel visibility</li><li>Fixed input action text "Leave lobby" in custom match matchmaking</li><li>Fixed reconnect state being applied to players leaving a server after a ranked game was deemed incomplete</li><li>Fixed mouse navigation in custom match parameter screen</li><li>Fixed purchase popup toggle in customization menu</li><li>Fixed items thumbnail background in store menu</li><li>Fixed focused state lost on clicking spin wheel buttons</li><li>Fixed "Press any key" display in launch screen</li><li>Fixed rank icons in player profile menu</li><li>Fixed custom keyboard mapping preset selection</li><li>Fixed keyboard custom profile input modifier option showing as enabled by default</li><li>Fixed reconnect pop-up overlap</li><li>Fixed missing status when a friend is in a custom match lobby on Xbox</li><li>Fixed warning message overlap</li><li>Fixed victory mood thumbnails display</li><li>Fixed player card customization screen display</li><li>Fixed currencies packs order</li><li>Fixed language options not being properly saved on first launch</li><li>Fixed User Agreement not being translated in languages other than English</li><li>Fixed Xbox version missing rich presence when a friend is currently in a custom match lobby</li><li>Special skin now have an assigned voice</li><li>Various audio fix within the menus</li><li>Audio and voice language options settings are now correctly saved</li><li>Update on SFX for the tutorials and workshops</li><li>Multiple localization fixes and improvements in the options menu</li><li>Multiple UI fixes and improvements</li><li>Multiple fixes in tutorials</li><li>Lighting improvement in Player Profile menus</li></ul><h2>Art / Rendering</h2><h2>Additions and updates</h2><ul><li>Add detail mod for small actors, on levels and VRs.</li><li>Add new Balls to Prologue (ball custo will be coming soon!).</li><li>Add crowd spawn / distribution textures for stadiums.</li></ul><h2>Major Fixes</h2><ul><li>Increase min LOD in low settings for Customization menu.</li><li>Fixed head sections.</li><li>Fixed corrupted crosshair on certain actions.</li><li>Fixed crowd LOD bias.</li><li>Fixed UI material AA.</li><li>UI textures improvement.</li><li>Cast shadow, WPO and VSM optimization on VRs / Stadium.</li><li>Meshes fixes and optimization on levels.</li><li>Optimize minimap &amp; line textures.</li></ul><h2>Minor Fixes</h2><ul><li>Fixed material time period.</li><li>Fixed accessories material on the Ponytail hairstyle.</li><li>Fixed Jelly Tails and Golden Flyaways hairstyle materials.</li><li>Fixed Eyelashes material.</li><li>Fixed Characters textures compression settings.</li><li>Update goal reaction behavior for smokes &amp; flash flares.</li><li>Playable Intro lighting optimization.</li><li>Force LOD on certain sequences in playable intro.</li><li>Cast shadow optimization on VRs.</li><li>Minor material and math optimization.</li><li>Minor update for Eye material.</li><li>Character parts, disable cast shadow on specific parts.</li></ul><h2>Known Issues</h2><ul><li>During kick-off, the ball sometimes emits loud wind sounds until it gets kicked</li><li>Audio is abruptly cut when pressing a button during start screen</li><li>Tackles occurring right after a player control the ball may cause rollbacks for the tackling player</li><li>In some instances a goalkeeper diving into another player controlling the ball will trigger the dive catch feedback without catching the ball</li><li>Consoles : ball position may be desynced for some players after hitting a goalpost</li><li>Achievements unlocking issues are still present on all platforms, we are investigating</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/major-rematch-patch-adds-colorblind-mode-and-other-significant-changes/1100-6533383/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Obituary: Elder Scrolls Daggerfall chief engineer Julian LeFay has passed away]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/obituary-elder-scrolls-daggerfall-chief-engineer-julian-lefay-has-passed-away</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/obituary-elder-scrolls-daggerfall-chief-engineer-julian-lefay-has-passed-away.1251357/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">July 23, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>3 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Picture via GDC 2024 Archive</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Julian LeFay, best known as Bethesda Softworks' chief engineer for pioneer games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Elder Scrolls II: Daggerfall</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, passed away last night at the age of 59.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">OnceLost Games, a studio led by LeFay and former Bethesda Softworks designer and writer Ted Peterson, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/OnceLostGames/status/1947867062216626313">shared the news</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in a statement via X (formerly Twitter). "It is with profound sadness and heavy hearts that we inform our community of the passing of Julian LeFay, our beloved technical director and co-founder of OnceLost Games," the team wrote.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">LeFay and Peterson started the studio back in 2019, with its first project being an open-world RPG called </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Wayward Realms</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> serving as a spiritual successor to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Daggerfall</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The team ran a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/oncelostgames/the-wayward-realms/creator">Kickstarter campaign</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> back in 2024, which was fully funded during its runtime. OnceLost has been working on an Early Access build since.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"At OnceLost Games, Julian was one of the masterminds behind </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Wayward Realms</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, bringing decades of expertise and an unwavering commitment to pushing the boundaries of what RPGs could achieve," the statement continues. "His technical brilliance, creative vision, and dedication to player agency have been the driving forces behind our ambitious project."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Last week, the team </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vwMyPR8Li6k">shared a video</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> announcing that LeFay had been courageously battling cancer for some time now. His doctors informed his colleagues and family that his time with them was limited, and they were preparing to say goodbye to, in their words, "a true legend of the industry." He then stepped away from the studio to live his final moments surrounded by his loved ones.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/how-a-sonic-unleashed-preservation-project-hopes-to-protect-obscure-ports" target="_self" data-discover="true">How a Sonic Unleashed preservation project hopes to protect obscure ports</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="&quot;Without Julian, we would not be here today&quot;">"Without Julian, we would not be here today"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Coloquially referred to as the "Father of the Elder Scrolls," LeFay held the role of chief engineer at Bethesda Softworks throughout the production of not just </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Daggerfall</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but also </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Elder Scrolls: Arena and An Elder Scrolls Legend: Battlespire</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. After quitting Bethesda in 1998, he worked briefly on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as a contractor. LeFay also had a short stint at Sega and lent a hand during the production of the fighting game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Skullgirls</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Outside of games, LeFay </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://licorice.io/articles/julian-lefay-jensen-appointed-as-licorice-cto/">joined Licorice in 2021</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, acting as chief technology officer of the professional services automation company.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bethesda Game Studios also released a statement on LeFay's passing, calling him "the driving force" in the creation of The Elder Scrolls and the foundations of Bethesda Softworks.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Simply put, without Julian, we would not be here today. If you had the opportunity to work with Julian, you were blessed to know a one-of-a-kind force of nature, who pushed everyone to create something special."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/is-generative-ai-really-just-a-tool" target="_self" data-discover="true">Is generative AI really 'just a tool'?</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">LeFay's daughter Shae Jensen also shared a message on behalf of his family </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/oncelostgames/the-wayward-realms/posts/4441522">on the studio's Kickstarter page</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. In it, they describe how much the community's support around </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Wayward Realms</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> meant to him. The message also encourages people who want to show their love for him to continue supporting the team, and if they see fit, to make a donation to any charities supporting the Ukrainian war efforts, which LeFay cared deeply about in his final years. "He would rest well knowing that his passing will contribute to the causes he felt so strongly about," reads the message.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As for OnceLost, the team said that LeFay's vision for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Wayward Realms</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is "deeply embedded in every aspect of our development team," with technical frameworks, design philosophies, and direction being "carefully documented" and shared with colleagues. As such, the team is committed to bringing that vision to fruition.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Ted Peterson, Eric Heberling, and our entire development team remains fully dedicated to this mission," the statement reads. "We will continue to share development updates, maintain our transparency with the community, and ensure that </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Wayward Realms</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> becomes the groundbreaking experience Julian knew it could be."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/25-years-in-havok-unveils-royalty-free-pricing-for-budgets-up-to-20-million" target="_self" data-discover="true">25 years in, Havok unveils royalty-free pricing for budgets up to $20 million</a></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/obituary-elder-scrolls-daggerfall-chief-engineer-julian-lefay-has-passed-away]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grim and joyful deckbuilder The Royal Writ is coming for genre king Balatro next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grim-and-joyful-deckbuilder-the-royal-writ-is-coming-for-genre-king-balatro-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grim-and-joyful-deckbuilder-the-royal-writ-is-coming-for-genre-king-balatro-next-month.1251342/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Sacrifice your cards and trade in their teeth</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Yogscast Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/autobattle-your-past-self-in-fool-king-a-promising-strategy-roguelite-in-which-dice-are-soldiers">Fool King</a> is dead, long live the Deckbuilder King. The Decking, if you will. Publishers Yogscast Games have announced that festive card-based roguelite The Royal Writ will launch on 7th August.</p>
<p>The Royal Writ seems pretty spesh, and yet, we have never covered it before, because we are blundering philistines. Sorry about that. In our defence, this is yet another cousin of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/balatro">Balatro</a> on some level, and there's only so many of those I can process in one year before my thumbs and eyes swell up in protest. But based on a quick snort of the Steam demo, The Royal Writ stands apart thanks to 1) immensely jovial animated storybook visuals 2) an interesting set of card sacrifice mechanics. Here is a trailer.
</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="What is The Royal Writ?" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UxzYphwxLlg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>What is The Royal Writ?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UxzYphwxLlg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UxzYphwxLlg?autoplay=1" title="What is The Royal Writ?">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UxzYphwxLlg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
The Royal Writ might look like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PKYEKhxWy6o">the opening number for Disney's Robin Hood</a>, but it's actually rather grisly. Each lane-based battle is a sort of slaughterhouse line. As the king implied by the title, you place unit cards on the left who advance from turn to turn, column to column towards the enemy outpost on the right, dishing damage as they go. As regards the early battles, at least, columns nearer the enemy give your cards a boost. All fine and dandy, but if those cards actually reach the final column and make contact with the opposing fortifications, they'll be obliterated instantly and vanish from your hand forever. 
</p>
<p>
As such, you'll want to arrange cards so that you build a multiplier and overcome your adversary's health pool before your forces advance too far. Except. Except that sometimes letting your merry minions perforate themselves on the defences is beneficial. For example: there's an affluent Widow card who racks up a fat pile of cash as she advances along her lane. You'll be able to 'inherit' that coin if she dies. So maybe don't win too early, eh? I like the pervasive evilness of The Royal Writ, which elsewhere comes across in resourcing opportunities such as the ability to trade a soldier's teeth for upgrades. 
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3333700/The_Royal_Writ/">Find the Royal Writ demo on Steam</a>. The game is the work of Save Sloth Studios, who are also working on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2876100/Sixth_Sun/">Sixth Sun</a> - an action game set in alternate 1500s Mexico, with similarly luxuriant visuals. Incidentally, if anybody knows of any other upcoming or new-ish games featuring kings (not 9 Kings or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-king-is-watching">The King Is Watching</a>, which we've covered already), please sing out in the comments. I've done three king-themed games today and I need a fourth to finish the poker hand or I won't be able to sleep tonight.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grim-and-joyful-deckbuilder-the-royal-writ-is-coming-for-genre-king-balatro-next-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ironmouse Ignites Vtuber Exodus After Accusing Agency Of Failing To Pay $515,000 Owed To Charity]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ironmouse-vtuber-vshojo-twitch-charity-subathon-1851786808</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ironmouse-ignites-vtuber-exodus-after-accusing-agency-of-failing-to-pay-515-000-owed-to-charity.1251333/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Last fall, popular Twitch streamer Ironmouse broke <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ironmouse-kai-cenat-twitch-vtuber-sub-record-1851661798&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ironmouse-kai-cenat-twitch-vtuber-sub-record-1851661798">Kai Cenat’s subathon record</a></span> with over  314,146 subscribers signing up, and many of the proceeds went to the Immune Deficiency Foundation. But nine months later, the Vtuber says the talent agency that reps her, VShojo, has failed to pay more than half a million dollars to the charity. “This entire situation has broken me,” she said in a new YouTube video posted on Tuesday.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197589" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Ring Psychology: Understanding The 6 Phases Of A Wrestling Match Through Heel Era John Cena" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="659" data-playlist="197589,197586,197585" data-current="197589"><div><p>Ring Psychology: Understanding The 6 Phases Of A Wrestling Match Through Heel Era John Cena</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23110.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Titled “Why I left VShojo,” the video (via <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/twitchs-biggest-vtuber-quits-agency-alleging-missing-charity-funds-of-over-500000/1100-6533329/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/twitchs-biggest-vtuber-quits-agency-alleging-missing-charity-funds-of-over-500000/1100-6533329/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>GameSpot</em></a></span>) details how the Vtuber came to be represented by VShojo and the events since last October that led her to now cut ties with the agency. Signing up in 2020, she said the relationship was ideal since it allowed her to maintain her privacy and focus on streaming as Ironmouse while the agency handled the business side of things. That seemed to go fine until recently, when VShojo allegedly stopped paying out funds it owed to the Vtuber and the charities she had supported. </p><p>“I believe that I am owed a significant amount of funds which I have not been paid,” Ironmouse said. “And most importantly, the Immune Deficiency Foundation is owed over half a million dollars from VShojo. I really wish that I could tell you more, but right now I have been advised to wait for legal proceedings. As of right now, I am an independent VTuber.”</p><p>The Vtuber suffers from an immunodeficiency disorder called CVID (Common Variable Immunodeficiency) and has frequently spoken about the importance of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/twitch-ironmouse-streamer-most-popular-female-vtuber-vs-1848576685&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/twitch-ironmouse-streamer-most-popular-female-vtuber-vs-1848576685">the support provided by the  Immune Deficiency Foundation</a></span>. Ironmouse said she’s helped raise over $4 million for the organization over the years, with last year’s subathon expected to donate an additional $515,000 in money paid directly by fans through Twitch. While that money has allegedly never been paid out, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://tiltify.com/@ironmouse/ironmouse&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://tiltify.com/@ironmouse/ironmouse" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a new Tiltify campaign</a></span> with a goal of $1 million for the foundation has already raised over $850,000. </p><p>VShojo did not immediately respond to a request for comment. </p><p>Ironmouse isn’t the only Vtuber currently speaking out against the agency. “I have been lied to from the company a lot about the situation,” Vtuber Kson <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/cBxw80mZoWI&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/cBxw80mZoWI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recently said</a></span>. “My payments stopped last September. I was asking what’s going on for a long time, multiple times. All they said was, ‘It’s going to be paid,’ and it was never paid, and I think it will never be.”</p><p>Vtuber Kuro also announced she’s leaving VShojo yesterday. “I didn’t want to say anything until its finalized but since people keep making assumptions, no I am not staying here I’ve already submitted a leave contract and had that meeting 11 days ago,” she <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/K9_KURO/status/1947656711524798886&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/K9_KURO/status/1947656711524798886" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote on X</a></span>. “The only reason I still have the VShojo brand logo on here still is because they have to remove it themselves, as an associate u can not remove it yourself (same with everyone other member) in any case I’m just waiting for the contract to be all fulfilled and done but I guess I’m an indie now LOL.” </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.vshojo.com/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.vshojo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Of the 13 Vtubers listed on VShojo’s website</a></span>, the majority have all posted messages announcing they’re taking breaks from streaming or explaining that they are cutting ties with the talent agency. It’s unclear how much of it is a show of solidarity with Ironmouse or is happening because of widespread payment issues. VShojo CEO Justin “TheGunrun” Ignacio gave no indication that anything was amiss in an <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/vtuber-agencies-virtual-idols-global-streaming-superstars-1235387390/#:~:text=Ignacio%E2%80%99s%20background%20in,competition%2C%20Cover%20Corp.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/vtuber-agencies-virtual-idols-global-streaming-superstars-1235387390/#:~:text=Ignacio%E2%80%99s%20background%20in,competition%2C%20Cover%20Corp." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interview with <em>Rolling Stone</em> last week</a></span> about the rise of Vtubers in the U.S.</p><p> “We know what we’re good at, and we know what we want to get better at, and we want to lean into that while making sure our creators, our talents, are able to communicate what success looks like for them and are we aligned to build that out,” he said. Apparently for many of them, success no longer looks like working with VShojo. </p><p>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ironmouse-vtuber-vshojo-twitch-charity-subathon-1851786808]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dear me, I was… launches July 31]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/dear-me-i-was-launches-july-31</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dear-me-i-was%E2%80%A6-launches-july-31.1251330/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New interactive adventure game from Arc System Works dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Interactive <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,412 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Dear me, I was... [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dear-me-i-was">Dear me, I was…</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [253 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> via <a href="https://store-jp.nintendo.com/item/software/D70010000099568" target="_blank">Nintendo eShop</a> on July 31 for 850 yen, <a title="Companies > Arc System Works [1,309 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/arc-system-works">Arc System Works</a> announced. It will support English, French, Italian, German, Spanish, Japanese, Korean, Traditional Chinese, and Simplified Chinese language options. <span id="more-979784"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Arc System Works:</p><blockquote><p><em>Dear me, I was…</em> is an interactive adventure that lets you enjoy a story woven with beautiful visuals, fusing the vibrant watercolor style of Taisuke Kanasaki with rotoscoping technology. The lifelike characters are sure to deeply move your heart.</p><p>In this story, you will relive the life of a certain woman. Experience joy, sorrow, and growth through her ordinary and humble life. Witness the story she weaves in a life interconnected with others.</p></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/dear-me-i-was-launches-july-31]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Teases All-Out War Ahead Of Full Reveal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-teases-all-out-war-ahead-of-full-reveal/1100-6533382/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-teases-all-out-war-ahead-of-full-reveal.1251324/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533382">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>After a lengthy stretch of rumors, reports and leaks, the next major installment in the Battlefield franchise is finally being <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-reveal-trailer-coming-very-soon-see-a-teaser-now/1100-6533340/" data-ref-id="1100-6533340">unveiled on July 24</a>. Before then though, we've received <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6</a>'s first teaser, and things are looking pretty chaotic out there. </p><p>The scattered teaser primarily cuts between several news clips providing a lot of context for the game's inevitable conflict. Of significant note is the trailer's emphasis on the collapse of NATO, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, which is an alliance of existing world militaries. In the broadest sense, this alliance is meant to act as a form of deterrence, both to prevent members from fighting and to prevent outside states from attacking a member.</p><p>Battlefield 6 seems to kick off with an attack on NATO though, with much of the teaser focusing on news reports from all around the world about an attack on a NATO base in Mukhrovani, Georgia. Interspersed between these reports is other alarming news stemming from the fallout of this attack, including the assassination of a secretary general at NATO HQ, a frenzied social media response, and the US president's mobilization of armed forces.</p><p>Throughout, repeated mentions are made to Pax Armata, who appear to be the villainous faction of Battlefield 6 and the perpetrators of the attacks, which can be seen spreading to Belgium and then Gibraltar. The Battlefield X account also makes mention of the organization in the teaser announcement, which reads, "Pax Armata rises as NATO cracks. Their motto? 'Our protection, your peace.' But who’s pulling the strings and to what end?"</p><p>The teaser stresses the modern setting of the latest Battlefield game, which was recently confirmed by leakers and eventually EA. The series has been all over the timeline recently, with Battlefield 2042 taking place in the near future while the game before it, Battlefield V, took place during World War 2.</p><p>It won't be long before we learn more about Battlefield 6's gameplay and setting, seeing as the reveal is set for July 24. Additionally, EA and Battlefield Studios have shared that there will be an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-open-beta-confirmed-will-include-this-key-change/1100-6533303/" data-ref-id="1100-6533303">open beta</a> ahead of the game's release where it is expected to launch on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-teases-all-out-war-ahead-of-full-reveal/1100-6533382/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Julian LeFay, The 'Father Of The Elder Scrolls', Has Passed Away]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/julian-lefay-the-father-of-the-elder-scrolls-has-passed-away</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/julian-lefay-the-father-of-the-elder-scrolls-has-passed-away.1251294/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Former Bethesda dev had battled cancer</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Julian LeFay Passes away" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/203374220c1e6/julian-lefay-passes-away.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: OnceLost</em></figcaption></figure><p>Julian LeFay, the man often referred to as "the father of the <strong>Elder Scrolls</strong>" and co-founder of the indie developer OnceLost Studio, has passed away after a years-long battle with cancer. The announcement was made by his studio earlier today on social media. He was 59 years old.</p>
<p>LeFay was instrumental in the early days of Bethesda's RPG history, back when the likes of <strong>Daggerfall</strong> was laying the foundations for what was to come from the studio in the likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/is-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2">Oblivion</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/elder_scrolls_v_skyrim_anniversary_edition">Skyrim.</a></p>
<p>In the post, OnceLost said that he was "not just a colleague, he was a visionary who fundamentally shaped the gaming industry as we know it today."</p>

<p>LeFay numerous credits include programming lead on <strong>Arena</strong> and <strong>Battlespire</strong>, project lead on <strong>Daggerfall</strong>, as well as having credits on The Elder Scrolls Redguard and Morrowind.</p>
<p>He also worked as a composer and designer on games such as <strong>Wayne Gretzky Hockey</strong> (which came to NES) and music on the DOS <strong>Where's Wally?</strong> game.</p>
<p>LeFay's daughter also <a href="https://x.com/OnceLostGames/status/1948048790986051982">shared a poignant statement</a>, saying "Thank you for supporting his vision and giving him hope and strength until the end".</p>
<p>The studio addressed how this tragedy will affect work on its upcoming RPG, The Wayward Realms, and it's quite emotional reading:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"He touched the lives of millions of players worldwide and inspired countless developers to push creative boundaries. Julian's legacy will live on in every realm, every quest, and every moment of wonder that players will experience in The Wayward Realms."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Our thoughts are with LeFay's friends and family, and he will be missed by many in the industry.</p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://x.com/OnceLostGames/status/1947867062216626313/photo/2" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/OnceLostGames/status/1947867062216626313/photo/2">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1753296292 --></div></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/julian-lefay-the-father-of-the-elder-scrolls-has-passed-away]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloober Team Shows Off More Cronos: The New Dawn Gameplay In 10-Minute Sector A-0 Showcase]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-sector-a-0-gameplay-showcase-bloober-team/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloober-team-shows-off-more-cronos-the-new-dawn-gameplay-in-10-minute-sector-a-0-showcase.1251291/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Cronos: The New Dawn is the next game coming from Silent Hill 2 Remake and Layers of Fear developer Bloober Team, and though we don't have a solid release date for it beyond a <a href="https://wccftech.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-set-to-launch-in-fall-2025/">Fall 2025 release window</a>, we do have a new look at gameplay with a new 10-minute gameplay showcase.</p>



<p>The video shows the protagonist digging through Sector A-0, showing off how you'll manipulate gravity and your environment in order to move towards your objective. It also shows more layers to the horror gameplay that the sci-fi adventure will feature, as you carefully and slowly creep around each corner, finger on the trigger of your weapon, ready to defend yourself against whatever monstrosity awaits.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Cronos: The New Dawn | Sector A-0 Gameplay Showcase" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iW4EcsG_Deg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>First revealed in <a href="https://wccftech.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-is-bloober-teams-next-survival-horror-game/">October 2024</a>, Cronos: The New Dawn looks to be the most confident and the most terrifying work from Bloober Team yet. While the studio's history as a horror game developer began strong with Layers of Fear, it faltered with back-to-back lacklustre releases that <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;opi=89978449&amp;url=https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/bloober-team-claims-its-finished-making-shitty-games/&amp;ved=2ahUKEwityLnytNOOAxVY2MkDHRPGLksQFnoECBUQAw&amp;usg=AOvVaw1q6lWprVE2HpS_CCCQT0qJ">the studio even admitted were poor</a>.</p>



<p>It has since turned things around following its success with the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/silent-hill-2-restless-dreams-town/">Silent Hill 2 Remake</a>, which has led to the studio also taking on a remake of the first <a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-remake-bloober/">Silent Hill</a> game.</p>



<p>We've seen plenty of Cronos: The New Dawn gameplay at this point, with a <a href="https://wccftech.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-dev-diary-outlines-combat-mechanics/">recent deep-dive just weeks ago</a>. The only thing we're really missing from Cronos: The New Dawn, is a release date. Hopefully, we'll hear about one soon. </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-sector-a-0-gameplay-showcase-bloober-team/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wheel World is the feel-good game of the summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games-review/711680/wheel-world-review-ps5-xbox-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wheel-world-is-the-feel-good-game-of-the-summer.1251288/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Momentum is what <em>Wheel World</em> does best. It is the feeling of reaching a downhill section of road, a pristine Sega-blue sea stretching out in the far distance, and letting gravity, the weight of your bicycle, and slope do all the work. Release the right trigger, the button used to peddle, and simply careen down the gently curving asphalt. It’s as if you’re flying — the wind in your hair and shirt fluttering on your back, coasting to wherever the road takes you.</p><p><em>Wheel World</em> is an undeniably feel-good video game. But this wasn’t always the case. It started life with the title “<a href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/the-annapurna-published-cycling-adventure-ghost-bike-is-now-wheel-world-173009766.html">Ghost Bike</a>,” casting you as a deceased cyclist making their way to bicycle Valhalla. One name change later (and probably a lot of behind-the-scenes wrangling), it arrives as a game about the unmitigated joy of riding a bicycle through a Mediterranean island.</p><p>The roads here are lined with cypress trees, the beaches are white and sandy, and you’ll come across many chic cyclists lounging in cafes. The atmosphere is so vividly rendered that I can practically taste the vacation Coca-Cola as I play. Summer itself seems strewn across the screen.</p><p>You play as Kat, a rider chosen by a cycling spirit named Skully to enact an ancient ritual. This is achieved by accruing parts of a so-called legendary bicycle: frame, wheels, chain, and more, which have fallen into the hands of rival cycling gangs. So you race these teams (which have superbly off-beat names like the “Nude Dudes” and “Shimmy Squad”), moving across a mix of dirt and road tracks. You encounter other cycling spirits residing in gigantic sculpted bike bells along the way. Ringing your bell at one of them causes the stonework to crack, thus revealing said spirit. You chat and gain an extra few bars on your boost gauge, before a portion of the map is revealed with tiny little icons indicating where you should pootle to next.</p><p>That’s right: <em>Wheel World</em>, from California-based studio Messhof, maker of the excellent <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/7/22/4547420/nidhogg-indie-fencing-game-coming-out-this-year"><em>Nidhogg</em></a> sword-dueling games, is structured like an open-world behemoth from Ubisoft. But expectations should be kept in check. There isn’t a blockbuster’s worth of content here. Rather, across the roughly seven hours of playtime, you’ll take part in races, duke it out with lone cyclists, and meet cute little dudes with boxes on their heads who point you in the direction of new gear. Oh, and there are strange hovering drones which dole out rewards for classic checklist completion stuff (like finding hidden jumps and lost members of cycling crews).</p><p>You could argue the game is a little slight in its array of things to do. But that’s not quite right. Rather, <em>Wheel World</em> requires you to rethink traditional definitions of content — to move beyond markers on a map. Content, for example, is every highway and path whose varying terrains cause your bicycle to handle differently. It is the shaky, unstable feeling that is channeled from screen to hand to brain via the controller when you veer onto the little slip of gravel next to the road. Content is also watching Kat as she strains to surmount a hill with a gradient that would cause a heart attack in most. Our hero remains stoic: I marvel at her thighs of steel!</p><p><em>Wheel World </em>is filled with many more beautifully animated details. You’re able to hop off your bicycle and push it around on foot. Maneuvering in a tight space, Kat does a kind of swivel trick with her handlebars, essentially spinning the bike frame around in one effortless motion. Another deftly rendered moment: when Kat dismounts, lifting her right leg over the bike, resting it next to her left, and then freewheeling to a gentle stop while standing upright. If you’re a cyclist, this move will likely already be familiar to you: it means every journey ends with nonchalant cool (or so you likely imagine). I’ve never seen it reproduced in a video game before.</p><div><p><cite>Image: Annapurna Interactive</cite></p></div><p>All this serves to make ambling around the island an exquisitely elegant thing. It’s a shame, then, that the racing is a little more chaotic, a little less refined. Showdowns on wide open roads are, for the most part, a joy. Those that take place in tight city streets can be finicky, Kat bouncing awkwardly off AI cyclists, world geometry, and oncoming traffic. The difficulty also feels a touch wonky: races are too easy for much of the game before an unexpected spike arrives in the last hour or so (exacerbated by a chugging frame rate on the PlayStation 5).</p><p>Still, these moments of frustration only made me pine all the more for the relative serenity of the open (world) road. Upon rolling credits, I dived back in to check off remaining objectives while soaking up the picture-postcard vibe again. This, I think, is the true mark of a game like <em>Wheel World</em>: the extent to which the core mechanics might cajole you back.</p><p>Galavanting during my post-credits session, I thought about another notable racing title with light open-world design: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/684518/mario-kart-world-review-nintendo-switch-2"><em>Mario Kart World</em></a>. The latest in Nintendo’s flagship kart racer is a cascading stream of serotonin hits induced by cotton-candy skies, soaring backflips, and delightful <em>wahoos</em>. It is a pure pleasure machine. <em>Wheel World</em>, on the other hand, doles out joy with a little less machine-like efficiency. It is more languid, massaging your eyeballs, ears, and brain with great blocks of warm, cel-shaded color, nostalgia-tinted electropop, and, of course, beautifully tactile cycling.</p><p>What mileage there is in simply ebbing and flowing across the gorgeous sun-kissed land, carried along by both cool breeze and smooth tarmac. Freewheeling, it is practically impossible not to break out in a smile. With every descent, those smiles only widen.</p><p><sub>Wheel World <em>launches July 23rd on PC, PS5, and Xbox.</em></sub></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6NTQzMA=="><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Lewis Gordon</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games-review/711680/wheel-world-review-ps5-xbox-steam]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New PS5 Feature Will Limit Performance In Some Games To Save Power]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps5-feature-power-saver-limit-performance-beta-update-1851786790</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-ps5-feature-will-limit-performance-in-some-games-to-save-power.1251285/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="f1c881a7c8ab26ed14546fb2c465d26e" data-recommend-id="image://f1c881a7c8ab26ed14546fb2c465d26e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f1c881a7c8ab26ed14546fb2c465d26e" data-recommend-id="image://f1c881a7c8ab26ed14546fb2c465d26e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Sony has announced that a new beta firmware update for the PlayStation 5 will begin rolling out to select users starting this week. One noteworthy aspect of this update is that it will include a feature that lets you cut back on your PS5's power consumption while playing games, though doing so will come at a hit to performance. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196230" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="217" data-playlist="196230,197567,195410" data-current="196230"><div><p>This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21779.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.playstation.com/2025/07/23/new-ps5-system-update-beta-previews-dualsense-wireless-controller-pairing-across-multiple-devices/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/07/23/new-ps5-system-update-beta-previews-dualsense-wireless-controller-pairing-across-multiple-devices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On July 23, Sony outlined a new PS5 console update</a></span> that will begin rolling out to a limited number of users tomorrow. Users will be notified of their involvement via email and can opt in or out of the beta. One big feature being added in the update is the ability to have your PS5 controller sync up to multiple devices and switch between them quickly, no resyncing needed. It’s a nifty feature present on current-gen Xbox controllers and will make it easy to use your PS5 gamepad wirelessly on both your PC and console. But the more interesting news is an upcoming PS5 feature Sony is calling “Power Saver.” </p><p>Power Saver won’t be active in the beta, but will go live for everyone in the future. If users turn the optional feature on, the PS5 console will “scale back performance” while playing certain games in order to lower its power consumption. If games don’t support the feature, it won’t kick in. </p><p>Sony doesn’t go into great detail about what “scale back performance” means, but it does mention in some small print text at the bottom of the post that Power Saver won’t support VR games and that some “gameplay features may be limited.” To me, that seems to imply that you won’t be able to run some games at higher framerates when using Power Saver. And because VR demands high framerates to work, that would make Power Saver unusable. I also wonder if we might see some games turn off raytracing or other intense visual options when Power Saver is activated. </p><p>“At [Sony Interactive Entertainment], we are committed to Sony’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/csr/eco/RoadToZero/gm_en.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/csr/eco/RoadToZero/gm_en.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">‘Road to Zero’ environmental plan</a></span>, launched in 2010, which includes achieving net-zero greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions by 2040,” said Sony in the blog post. “We are always exploring how we can contribute to these goals through our products and services.”</p><p>Sony says it will share more details in the near future about Power Saver mode and how it will impact games as we get closer to the option going live. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ps5-feature-power-saver-limit-performance-beta-update-1851786790]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona 5: The Phantom X Holds Stream To Address Player Criticism, Just Makes Everyone Madder]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/persona-5-phantom-x-livestream-marian-review-bomb-gacha-1851786799</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-5-the-phantom-x-holds-stream-to-address-player-criticism-just-makes-everyone-madder.1251279/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/persona-5-the-phantom-x-gacha-rolls-preview-mobile-pc-1851783773&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/persona-5-the-phantom-x-gacha-rolls-preview-mobile-pc-1851783773"><em>Persona 5: The Phantom X</em>’s</a></span> saga of post-launch controversy continues, as Atlus and Black Wings Game Studio’s response to player backlash has only made some members of the game’s community more angry, as they don’t feel like their concerns are being heard.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196055" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="227" data-playlist="196055,196411,196394" data-current="196055"><div><p>6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21584.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>To bring you up to speed, <em>Persona 5: The Phantom X </em>is the new gacha game set in a different timeline from the original RPG. Like most live-service games, it has events, content roadmaps, and microtransactions that bake FOMO into its design. <em>The Phantom X </em>originally launched last year in China, and finally came to the West last month. Atlus and Black Wings announced they would be <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/persona-5-phantom-x-story-content-updates-roadmap-1851785889&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/persona-5-phantom-x-story-content-updates-roadmap-1851785889">speeding up the story content rollout</a></span> in the West to catch everyone up, but when it became clear that the game’s in-game rewards weren’t being improved to compensate for the accelerated pace, fans started <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/persona-5-phantom-x-rewards-china-compare-review-bomb-1851786295&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/persona-5-phantom-x-rewards-china-compare-review-bomb-1851786295">review bombing the game</a></span> for what they called unfair treatment. The team <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/persona-5-phantom-x-atlus-black-wings-statement-rewards-1851786505&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/persona-5-phantom-x-atlus-black-wings-statement-rewards-1851786505">acknowledged the feedback</a></span> and said it would be responding to it, but stopped short of saying it would be making actual changes to address these problems. Now, the studio has held a livestream to talk about the game’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://persona5x.com/news/details/000170xtpbmman.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://persona5x.com/news/details/000170xtpbmman.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1.2 update</a></span> that goes live tomorrow, and players are saying the team hasn’t actually fixed anything, and in some cases, is only making things worse.</p><p>Some changes the patch brings about do acknowledge issues players have complained about; it adds more login rewards and gifts in response to players getting fewer rewards during their play time, for instance. However, while some rewards were rebalanced to be more in-line with the Chinese version, the patch doesn’t do anything on top of that to compensate for the accelerated schedule, nor does it implement higher chances to pull rare characters in the game’s gacha systems. A major point of contention is that characters are not being added to standard banner (basically the baseline pool of characters you can get when rolling for new Phantom Thieves to add to your party) until they have been in the game for six months. According to the stream, this is because the team wants to “act out of consideration for players” who use premium currency to acquire highly sought after characters, which fans have interpreted as the team saying they want to continue to incentivize players to pay up if they want a better chance of getting those characters.</p><p>“Straight up ‘we only care about people who spend money,’” nightoftheghouls <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/personaphantomx/comments/1m78qnk/truly_a_do_you_not_have_phonesor_surprise/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/personaphantomx/comments/1m78qnk/truly_a_do_you_not_have_phonesor_surprise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote on Reddit</a></span>. “You aren’t supposed to say the quiet part out loud guys.”</p><p>What remains to be seen is if this will be standard procedure for the game moving forward, or if it’s just being applied to some characters released in the game’s first month while the devs continue to adjust its monetization and release roadmap. Fans worry this might make the game a bigger money and time investment while the accelerated rollout is still in place, and create a grindier game with less payoff.</p><p>“So now not only do we have an insane release pace of new characters, we will not be able to get any of the ‘Standard’ characters going forward until at least 5 months from now?” N0tZekken <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/personaphantomx/comments/1m783mr/the_12_livestream_didnt_tackle_any_real_problem/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/personaphantomx/comments/1m783mr/the_12_livestream_didnt_tackle_any_real_problem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote in another Reddit thread</a></span>. “Keep in mind that they can actually pull it off for every new character, and they could actually make it worse. What’s preventing them from increasing this to a year if sales are not satisfactory? Wouldn’t be the first time we’ve been lied to in the face by Sega/Atlus.”</p><p>The comments on the live stream VOD are filled with similar disappointment, with several viewers expressing the idea that if the game were to just roll out exactly as it did in China, many of their issues would be fixed. But for now, non-Chinese players are dealing with an accelerated, FOMO-driven game that’s been changed in ways that offer no real benefit. Well, none for players, at least. Atlus stands to gain a lot by forcing players into situations where spending real-world money is the easiest fix. </p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/persona-5-phantom-x-livestream-marian-review-bomb-gacha-1851786799]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 – Rafa gameplay overview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/borderlands-4-rafa-gameplay-overview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-%E2%80%93-rafa-gameplay-overview.1251273/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Get to know Rafa the Exo-Soldier.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > 2K [668 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/take-two-interactive-software/2k">2K</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Gearbox Software [244 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/the-gearbox-entertainment-company/gearbox-software">Gearbox Software</a> have released a Rafa gameplay overview trailer for <em><a title="Games > Borderlands 4 [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a></em>. <span id="more-979774"></span></p><p>Here are the latest details, via 2K:</p><blockquote><p>In the Rafa gameplay overview, you can learn more about how he masterfully wields the cutting-edge weaponry stored in his Deadframe exo-suit. This former Tediore trooper is ready for fights at any distance, whether he’s slicing through enemies at melee range with his twin Arc-Knives, perforating midrange targets with his Peacebreaker Cannons, or blasting holes through multiple enemies with charged-up rounds from his APOPHIS Lance..</p></blockquote><p><em>Borderlands 4</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,940 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,557 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,714 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1285190/Borderlands_4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/borderlands-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> on September 12, followed by <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [253 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> on October 3.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Overview: Rafa</span></h2><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="Borderlands 4 - Official Gameplay Overview - Rafa" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QNxaHZ8HcmU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/borderlands-4-rafa-gameplay-overview]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 has become the fastest selling video game hardware device in US history, usurping the PS4]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-has-become-the-fastest-selling-video-game-hardware-device-in-us-history-usurping-the-ps4</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-has-become-the-fastest-selling-video-game-hardware-device-in-us-history-usurping-the-ps4.1251264/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo/Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nintendo's Switch successor - the aptly named <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-nintendo-switch-2-the-digital-foundry-hardware-review">Switch 2</a> - has become the fastest selling video game hardware device in US history, knocking the PS4 off the top spot.</p>
<p>That's according to the latest data from Circana, with <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lun37i6gok2k">analyst Mat Piscatella</a> revealing 1.6m Switch 2 units were sold in the US during the console's launch month. The previous record holder was Sony's PlayStation 4, with 1.1m units sold during November 2013.</p>
<p>Perhaps unsurprisingly given what I have just told you, the Switch 2 was the best-selling console of the month in terms of both physical unit sales and dollar sales. </p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mario Party Switch 2 May Be Fun, but Is It Just an Overpriced Gimmick?" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X5WAp5xe-QM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mario Party Switch 2 May Be Fun, but Is It Just an Overpriced Gimmick?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X5WAp5xe-QM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/X5WAp5xe-QM?autoplay=1" title="Mario Party Switch 2 May Be Fun, but Is It Just an Overpriced Gimmick?">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Mario Party Switch 2 May Be Fun, but Is It Just an Overpriced Gimmick? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X5WAp5xe-QM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Piscatella said 82 percent of US Switch 2 owners who purchased their console in June also plumped for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-launch-games-everything-you-can-play-on-day-one">launch title Mario Kart World</a>. This was either via a physical new game sale or as part of the Nintendo Switch 2 + <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> Bundle.</p>
<p>These figures come despite the tariff situation in US around the Switch 2's launch. As a reminder, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-delays-us-switch-2-pre-orders-due-to-tariffs">Nintendo delayed pre-orders in the US back in April</a>. It additionally <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-raising-cost-of-switch-2-accessories-in-us-due-to-tariffs-but-console-price-to-remain-same-1">raised the cost of Switch 2 accessories in US due to tariffs</a>. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-us-preorders-reportedly-cancelled-by-major-retailers">some US retailers were reportedly cancelling pre-orders ahead of the console's launch</a>. </p>
<p>All in all, the launch of the Switch 2 boosted the gaming market more generally. Consumer spending in the US - for both hardware and accessories - reached new all-time records. Last month, hardware spending in the US rose by 249 percent compared to this time last year, to $978 million. The previous high for June was $608m, which was recorded in 2008.</p>
<p>June accessories spending in the US, meanwhile, reached $293m. The previous record was $247m, which happened in June 2021.</p>
<p>"What the launch sales of Switch 2 primarily tell us is that they made a lot of Switch 2 to sell at launch," Piscatella said to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-nintendo-switch-2-is-the-fastest-selling-gaming-hardware-in-us-history">IGN</a>, when asked if this record breaking launch means that the Switch 2 is now set to surpass the original Switch's lifetime sales. In February of this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-admits-sales-below-expectations-as-wait-for-switch-2-continues">Nintendo had sold 150.86m Switch consoles</a>.</p>
<p>"Lifetime sales and launch sales of a console often do not correlate, meaning that some consoles with small launches ended up doing incredibly well," Piscatella continued, noting that the PlayStation 2 only sold 400k in its launch month.</p>
<p>"Since launch month demand is rarely satiated by available supply (and it is certainly not a great sign when it is, historically) all we can really get a read on at launch is the confidence of the manufacturer to make so many units available, and the ability of the supply chain to get those units into the market," the analyst closed.</p>
<p>"But having the biggest launch month sales for any new video game hardware platform is a helluva good start."</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo/Digital Foundry</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>On its debut last month, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-is-nintendos-fastest-selling-hardware-ever">Switch 2 became Nintendo's fastest-selling hardware ever</a>, shifting 3.5m units worldwide in its first four days on sale. News of those initial sales came despite <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/is-switch-2-actually-cheaper-than-the-original-console-cost-in-the-uk-and-whats-the-situation-with-switch-2-pricing-globally">criticism of the console's high cost</a>, as well as the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-treehouse-live-viewers-have-very-clear-message-for-nintendo">price of its games and accessories</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-has-become-the-fastest-selling-video-game-hardware-device-in-us-history-usurping-the-ps4]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wheel World Loves Bikes And The People Who Love Them]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/wheel-world-impressions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wheel-world-loves-bikes-and-the-people-who-love-them.1251261/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Wheel World</em> is out today, a ride-your-bike-around game by <em>Nidhogg</em> developer Messhof. Its <a href="https://aftermath.site/wheel-world-demo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">demo</a> back in February covered most of the mechanics I’ve seen so far in the full game, though it did not make clear that there would be <em>cars</em>. I will forgive it for this, because it is <em>mostly</em> bikes and those bikes are very cool and fun to ride, but as is the grand moral duty of every cyclist, and in the allegiance to bikes the game revels in, I reserve the right to huff indignantly.</p><p><em><a href="https://annapurnainteractive.com/en/games/wheel-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wheel World</a></em> takes place in a magical world dominated by bikes, and at its start you’re tasked with helping a burning skull spirit recover their stolen bike parts so they can perform the “Great Shift” and move the “Chain of Life.” (These are bike references, you see.) It’s as good an excuse as any to send you out into the game’s world, where once you cross a bridge off the tutorial island you’re set loose in a lovely landscape that begs to be <a href="https://aftermath.site/bike-road-davis-comic" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">explored</a> by bike. Areas feel different from each other–forested mountains, rolling farmland, <a href="https://aftermath.site/parcel-corps-bike" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">busy cities</a>–and all of it is delightful to discover and speed around on, with changing terrain that constantly brings your attention back to your bike. Everywhere you go you meet cyclists, either alone or in groups, many of whom you can challenge to races. The goal here is to earn enough “Rep,” or reputation points, to take on the riders who stole the bike parts and win them back.</p><p>I’m just at what happens in the game’s narrative after you recover all those bike parts, which you can, like all the parts you find in the game, slap on your bike. Bike parts are scattered around the world, or they can be purchased from shops with tickets you earn from floating corporate drones for doing challenges. The bike parts change how your bike handles, how fast it goes up or downhill, or how tightly you can turn. Charmingly, when you swap a part in, it shows up on your bike itself, letting you build and then admire some kind of Frankenstein’s monster that reminds me of one of my own bikes, a small vintage racing bike I slapped mortifyingly gigantic pedals on because they were the cheapest ones at the shop.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>Messhof</figcaption></figure><p>I appreciate the way this isn’t overly technical, demonstrating a breadth of bike knowledge without requiring you to have that knowledge too. <em>Wheel World</em> is obsessed with bike lingo and subculture; the groups you can race all fit into rider archetypes like gravel riders, gearheads, elite racers, or people just out for a spin to the pub or coffee shop. Being a bike guy, they often gave me a chuckle, but they didn’t require any specialized insight to get the core joke. Similarly, the racing feels just the right amount of technical: beyond managing a boost meter via drafting, or riding closely behind other racers, there isn’t the high-fidelity fiddling or drift control you sometimes see in other racing games, and the gameplay is easy to pick up. (An exception: you can find drive trains around the world with gears you can shift; managing your gearing during a race would present more strategic challenge, but <em>Wheel World </em>makes it clear these parts are optional, and I haven’t spent much time with them.)&nbsp;</p><p>Instead, the races feel about speed and stakes, jockeying for position or trying not to fly off the turns in a velodrome. The courses are clearly marked and easy to follow, something sometimes lacking in other racing games, which lets you enjoy the speed and drama rather than frantically having to scan for the next checkpoint. I appreciated how different courses felt in different areas and even from each other, with some being laps or loops and others an end-to-end sprint. In some races I dominated easily, while in others I was dropped almost instantly or when I careened off a turn, or I lost in the final stretch by not saving enough boost. I’m not the biggest fan of racing games due to the aforementioned technicality featured in many of them, but I really enjoyed <em>Wheel World</em>’s take on them, and especially the sensation of biking around with others in a big, lovely world. Races have various goals that earn you rep, so there’s incentive to replay them with those in mind.</p><p>But then there are the <em>cars</em>. Just look at the bastards.</p><figure><figcaption>Messhof</figcaption></figure><p>Cars are clearly present in the above press screenshot that's been sitting on <em>Wheel World</em>’s Steam page for a while, so I wasn’t hoodwinked here, but the first time I biked over the bridge from the tutorial area to the main world, I gasped with <a href="https://aftermath.site/loser-lane" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cyclist fury</a> when I arrived at a roundabout full of cars. One of the reasons <em>Wheel World</em> changed its name from <em>Ghost Bike </em>is, as the developer explained in a press release last October, that it was originally about being hit by a car and ending up in a cycling afterlife. “<a href="https://www.psreader.com/ghost-bikes-part-1-a-history-of-greif-and-activism/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost bikes</a>” are worldwide memorials to cyclists killed in accidents, and the developer says they were aware of the association but felt that it fit. Such a solemn reference would be out of place in the lighthearted game <em>Wheel World</em> ended up being, so I think it was a good choice to change the name. But the idea of a world of bikes remains in the final game, and this made me shocked to see cars on the road. There aren’t nearly as many of them as there are in my urban bike commutes, and I understand why they’re here: They present challenges that spice up your rides and races, and drafting them or zipping through them refills your boost meter. <em>I get it</em>. But still, their intrusion into my biking paradise made me as furious at them as real-world cars do. A character in one race even agrees, griping about having to share the road with them.</p><p>My reaction, however, does further highlight the vibe of <em>Wheel World</em> inducting you into a special two-wheeled world, one set in opposition to the four-wheeled world of cars, so I’m not going to demand all the virtual cars get off the road the way I used to do in my younger, more confrontational <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Critical_Mass_(cycling)" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Critical Mass</a> days. The fact that the game puts you so firmly into the cycling headspace that this emotion comes up feels like a point in its favor. It’s a game that has a lot of love for bikes and the people who ride them, even when it’s sending some of those people up. It reminds me of what I love about bikes, and it makes me want to get out and ride, though its races are also a <a href="https://aftermath.site/failing-on-a-bike-trip-taught-me-too-much-about-myself" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tragic</a> reminder of how I am the world’s slowest cyclist. At least I can live my hopeless dreams for speed as I keep playing the game.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/ridge-racer-4-zine-magazine"><h3>Riiiiidddgggeeee Raaaaccceerrrr Ziiiinnnneeeee</h3></a><p>'A tribute to Namco's Ridge Racer Type 4, the vibiest racing game of all time'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/vice-waypoint-stories-resignations-editor"><h3>This Was Inevitable</h3></a><p>Waypoint 2.0's ordeal is the story of games media in 2025</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/tyler-the-creator-dont-tap-the-glass-hip-hop-rap-kendrick"><h3>We Should All Outgrow Our Heroes Like Tyler, The Creator</h3></a><p>Turns out all it takes to shake hip-hop’s foundations was “Don’t Tap The Glass” daring its rap listeners to put the keyboard down and dance
</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/waypoint-quit-steam-vice"><h3>Waypoint Writers Quit Over Removal Of Articles Related To New Steam Policy [Update]</h3></a><p>Two articles by writer Ana Valens were removed at the demand of Vice owner Savage Ventures, the latest in multiple deletions at the site</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/wheel-world-impressions]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>