<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:44:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Trek: Prodigy season 2, Tower of God season 2, and more new TV this week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/2024/7/1/24183180/new-tv-netflix-star-trek-prodigy-tower-god-season-2-nfl-anime</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-trek-prodigy-season-2-tower-of-god-season-2-and-more-new-tv-this-week.916422/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/2024/7/1/24183180/new-tv-netflix-star-trek-prodigy-tower-god-season-2-nfl-anime<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="yugZzI">If you’re in the States, then this week is July Fourth. If you’re not in the States, then this week is just July 4 — congrats to all who get to mark the day however they are, wherever they are! No surprise, but: I think we should all celebrate by watching TV. Particularly if you’re in for anime, there’s a <em>lot</em> of premieres this week on Crunchyroll, meaning you can roll right through the long (or regular!) weekend with a blitz of new programs. </p>
<p id="Dkcuag">Here’s the best new TV premieres (and just a <em>few</em> of the anime previews) this week. </p>


<hr id="IF1ehv">
<h2 id="fs6TI9"><strong>New shows on Netflix</strong></h2>
<h3 id="jRZLpn"><strong>Star Trek: Prodigy</strong></h3>
<div id="Wb6nvn"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zXh5TLAeJqw?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="OHuQK7"><strong>Genre: </strong>Star Trek (animated YA adventures edition)<br><strong>Release date: </strong>July 1, with all episodes<br><strong>Showrunner/creator: </strong>Kevin and Dan Hageman<br><strong>Cast: </strong>Brett Gray, Ella Purnell, Jason Mantzoukas, and more</p>
<p id="IlizaR"><em>Prodigy</em> has survived cancellation (read: was in production for season 2 when it got axed by Paramount) and has jumped over to a new network (read: was subsequently picked up by Netflix). That means that if you liked what <em>Prodigy</em> was putting down in season 1, you will probably like it when it makes its way to Netflix. </p>
<h2 id="zr2b1L"><strong>New shows on Max</strong></h2>
<h3 id="46yTmB"><strong>Hard Knocks: Offseason with the New York Giants</strong></h3>
<div id="SPt5ue"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0ccDBPrqmKE?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="SkYi8h"><strong>Genre: </strong>Docuseries, sports drama<br><strong>Release date: </strong>July 2<br><strong>Cast: </strong>The players and staff of the New York Giants</p>
<p id="enGoPW">The New York Giants are entering their 100th season. It’s quite an accomplishment, but they (like all NFL teams) won’t settle for anything less than a Super Bowl slot. Will they get it? Who’s to say — but now we can at least watch what they’re saying during the offseason. </p>
<h2 id="YKj9EM"><strong>New shows on Crunchyroll</strong></h2>
<h3 id="oEPLsj"><strong>Nier: Automata Ver1.1a season 2</strong></h3>
<div id="ITwfSp"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eIMZYgb85xg?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="nsCPWJ"><strong>Genre: </strong>Sci-fi action<br><strong>Release date: </strong>July 5, with one episode<br><strong>Studio: </strong>A-1 Pictures</p>
<p id="ffOrD3">Fans of the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2017/12/12/16754720/nier-automata-best-games-2017"><em>Nier: Automata</em></a>, rejoice: The gorgeous anime adaptation of the hit game is finally making its return this summer with a second season following the first’s protracted and troubled development. Hopefully A-1 Pictures has ironed out all the details for this new season so we won’t be waiting <em>weeks</em> or even <em>months</em> between episodes.</p>
<p id="iNmSxy">The second “cour” (the term for a production block of anime averaging between 10 and 14 episodes) will pick up immediately after the first, with 9S having learned the shocking truth behind Project YoRHa after defeating the alien robots Adam and Eve alongside 2B. We’ll have to wait until July 5 to see just how much <em>Nier: Automata Ver1.1a</em> will diverge from the story of the original game. <em>—Toussaint Egan</em></p>
<h3 id="Ns8Z2k"><strong>Tower of God season 2 </strong></h3>
<div id="8lqkLh"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5H9U6SugSzk?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="8GKeWq"><strong>Genre: </strong>Fantasy action<br><strong>Release date: </strong>July 7, with one episode<br><strong>Studio: </strong>The Answer Studio</p>
<p id="SL7UF5">There’s a (in-universe) six-year gap between seasons here, and while we’ll be following up with Bam, Rachel, and the rest of the season 1 crew — along with their rankings! — season 2 is also bringing in some new protagonists. Meet Wangnan and Jyu, who are a little more advanced in the tower’s levels than we’ve seen so far. Time to find out what new challenges this mysterious tower can bring!</p>
<h3 id="9A6Q7J"><strong>My Deer Friend Nokotan</strong></h3>
<div id="Q3VaJ8"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bf4XTzeUBHo?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="4YATsO"><strong>Genre: </strong>Slice-of-life comedy<br><strong>Release date: </strong>July 7, with one episode<br><strong>Studio: </strong>Wit Studio</p>
<p id="mhc8St">Based on the 2019 manga by Oshioshio, <em>My Deer Friend Nokotan</em> is a comedy that centers on the misadventures of Torako Koshi, a former “yankee” (see: delinquent) girl trying to keep up her appearance as a ideal student at her new high school. That becomes significantly more difficult after she saves Noko Shikanoko, a self-described “deer-girl hybrid” who begins to follow Torako around and get up to all sorts of shenanigans.</p>
<p id="jDdkAQ">The trailer looks ridiculous, with realistic CG depictions of deer juxtaposed with Noko’s chibi-like appearance. There’s even a cute callback to the ending of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/animation-cartoons/2020/5/25/21265521/nausicaa-of-the-valley-of-the-wind-studio-ghibli-movie-watch-meaning-manga">1984’s <em>Nausicaä of the Valley of the Wind</em></a>, with Noko being lifted above a marching herd of deer while surrounded by an aura of light. We’ll see how the actual series holds up when it premieres this weekend. <em>—TE</em></p>
<h3 id="pobboo"><strong>Wistoria: Wand and Sword</strong></h3>
<div id="zY5RHO"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FNiBiXXeyb8?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="IEjowk"><strong>Genre: </strong>Fantasy action<br><strong>Release date: </strong>July 7, with one episode<br><strong>Studio: </strong>Actas, Bandai Namco Pictures</p>
<p id="sCovAx">Based on the fantasy adventure manga by author Fujino Ōmori and illustrator Toshi Aoi, <em>Wistoria: Wand and Sword</em> centers on Will Serfort, a young student who enrolls at a prestigious magic academy with hopes of achieving his dream of becoming one of the most powerful magic users in the world. However, much like <em>My Hero Academia</em>’s Izuku Midoriya or <em>Solo Leveling</em>’s Sung Jin-woo, Will has a critical roadblock: He can’t cast even the simplest of spells to save his own life! </p>
<p id="qm3ivW">That’s not gonna stop him, though, as he descends into the dungeons beneath the school to slay vicious monsters as an alternate way to earn academic credits. He’s like <em>Naruto</em>’s Rock Lee, only instead of being terrifyingly proficient in taijutsu, he’s an absolute beast when it comes to sword fighting.</p>
<p id="HqwaBK">I’m not familiar with the source material myself, but I am intrigued by the fact that Tatsuya Yoshihara, who previously worked as the action director on 2022’s <em>Chainsaw Man</em> and the chief director on the final season of <em>Black Clover</em>, is the director on <em>Wistoria: Wand and Sword</em>. Which means, at the very least, audiences can expect some exquisite action sequences. <em>—TE</em></p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XDefiant Season 1 Patch Notes Released]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-season-1-patch-notes-released/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xdefiant-season-1-patch-notes-released.916419/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-season-1-patch-notes-released/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Ahead of its launch on July 2, <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/xdefiant/news/39Z5ARUSNbU1QcQD0yhthI/y1s10-patch-notes">Ubisoft has released</a> the full patch notes for Season 1 of XDefiant. This new season features a new game mode in Capture the Flag, additional factions, maps, weapons, and more.</p>



<p>There’s a lot going into the first season of the game. You can check out everything for yourself below.</p>



<h6>RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-players-launch/">Ubisoft Confirms XDefiant has had 11 Million Players Since Launch</a></h6>



<h2 id="h-full-xdefiant-season-1-patch-notes">Full XDefiant Season 1 Patch Notes</h2>



<h3>Gameplay</h3>



<ul>
<li>Changed the expiration timing of activated Boosters so their lifespan counts down only during match time, when you’re actually playing, rather than all the time, like when you’re folding laundry or whatever.</li>



<li>Lowered the XP threshold for each Battle Pass tier to give Battle Pass progression a little more pep.</li>



<li>Tuned Match Bonus XP rewards:&nbsp;MVP and Victory went from 2,000 to 1,000 XP.&nbsp;Draw went from 1,000 to 500.&nbsp;Completion doubled from 2,000 to 4,000 to encourage player&nbsp;stick-to-itiveness.</li>



<li>Answered a community ask to add a headshot icon to the Killfeed because it feels good to rub it in.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Factions</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added the GSK faction and their no-nonsense announcer: HQ.
<ul>
<li>These elite Team Rainbow operators from Germany’s Border Protection Command&nbsp;specialize in crowd control and securing territory.&nbsp;They can deploy electrified barbed wire for area denial, counter incoming enemy devices with their Active Defense System, and dazzle multiple foes with flash charges mounted on their G52-Tactical Shield ultra.&nbsp;Call them&nbsp;Grenzschutzkommando because it’s fun and also accurate.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Increased the cooldown of Echelon’s Intel Suit from 30 to 40 seconds.</li>



<li>Tuned the cooldown of the Phantoms’ Mag Barrier from 30 to 40 seconds. Mag Barrier hit points were also reduced from 500 to 400.</li>



<li>The Phantoms’ AEGIS now takes damage from EMP grenades (lob six to put it out of commission).</li>



<li>DedSec Hijack cooldown decreased from 28 seconds (plus the remaining duration of&nbsp; the hacked skill) to 20 seconds (plus the remaining duration of&nbsp; the hacked skill).
<ul>
<li>For example, let’s say a Mag Barrier has 7 seconds left and gets hacked: The cooldown becomes 20 plus 7 seconds. Failed Hijack cooldown, meanwhile, decreases from 8 to 5 seconds.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>DedSec’s Spiderbot cooldown increased from 25 to 40 seconds.</li>



<li>Adjusted Spiderbot behavior so multiple Spiderbots won’t attempt to hug the same face, nor will Spiderbots continue to ignore faces they’ve hugged multiple recent times. Some give and take from the Spiderbot kingdom.</li>



<li>Decreased the cooldown of Libertad’s BioVida Boost from 25 to 20 seconds.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Fixed Libertad’s Medico Supremo so it will no longer disappear after the deploying player respawns as a different faction.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Maps</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added the new Clubhouse map, a two-story hangout popular with international operators. Ideal for firefights in the short- to mid-range. Home to game modes Domination, Occupy, Hot Shot, and the new CTF.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Game Modes</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added Capture the Flag, hereafter referred to as CTF. For the uninitiated: You take the enemy’s flag from their base and bring it back to your own, while protecting your team’s flag. CTF is available on a variety of maps.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Weapons</h3>



<ul>
<li>Improved the hit flinch penalty incurred when being shot with a sniper rifle equipped.<p>These changes are intended to refine the behavior of hit flinch, prevent instances where the camera would move off the target with the first hit and back onto the target with the second, and improve the experience for players sensitive to wild camera movements. Here’s the nitty-gritty:
</p><ul>
<li>The speed of the hit flinch camera transition has been increased by 25 percent.</li>



<li>The camera will now always kick upward rather than up or down at random.</li>



<li>The amount the camera will kick left or right has been increased by 3 times.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Added the L115 sniper rifle, which is not quite as heavy as the TAC-50 and has faster handling, although it deals slightly less damage and is not as effective at penetrating cover.</li>



<li>Added the LVOA-C,&nbsp;a snazzy customized rifle similar to the M4A1. It has a much faster rate of fire than the M4A1, but with that comes more recoil and less range. It also has slightly longer reload and equip times.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Added the Sawed Off secondary weapon.&nbsp;This close-range version of the double-barreled shotgun packs a big boom for its size. Imagine carrying a primary weapon in your secondary slot and that’s this.</li>



<li>Added new Mastery skins: Titanium Violet (unlocked at Weapon Level 300), Titanium Azure (unlocked at 350), and Titanium Prisma (unlocked at 400).&nbsp;</li>



<li>Fixed weapons and optics shake in first-person view while using ADS.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Devices</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added a new and improved visual effect for the flash grenade (replacing the previous effect, which was…intense). The new effect is less retina-searing but still appropriately disorientating.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Removed an exploit where players could respawn with multiple devices after fiddling with the “Copy Loadout” option in the lobby, so nice try.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Social</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added the Creator Code program, which allows players to choose a creator to receive commissions from their XCoin purchases at no additional cost. Choose “Support a Creator” from the store to see a list of eligible creators.</li>



<li>Players were able to create a party with enemy players and voice chat during matches despite being on opposing teams, which seemed shady so that’s fixed.</li>



<li>Disabled whispers in text chat.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Audio</h3>



<ul>
<li>Tweaked the mix of in-game voices and sound effects for volume and clarity.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Miscellaneous</h3>



<ul>
<li>Players who participated in the Closed Beta were supposed to keep Kersey’s Dungaree skin. They didn’t but now they do.</li>



<li>Fixed Challenge-tracking issues with Ubisoft Connect.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Graphical and audio fixes, various.</li>



<li>Additional crash fixes.</li>
</ul>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Warzone And MW3 Might Include A Deadpool & Wolverine Crossover In Season 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-and-mw3-might-include-a-deadpool-wolverine-crossover-in-season-5/1100-6524622/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-warzone-and-mw3-might-include-a-deadpool-wolverine-crossover-in-season-5.916413/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-and-mw3-might-include-a-deadpool-wolverine-crossover-in-season-5/1100-6524622/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524622">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">The Season 4 Reloaded update recently went live in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-iii/" data-ref-id="5000-597446">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone/" data-ref-id="5000-572198">Warzone</a>, and data miners are already looking for clues for Season 5's content. A leak has now surfaced that seems to list a series of potential finishing moves with poses and mannerisms reminiscent of Marvel's Deadpool.</p><p dir="ltr">Data miner "Crashfty" has <a href="https://x.com/crashfty/status/1806747826413539737" rel="nofollow ">shared clips</a> of unreleased finishing moves, which all use quirky execution styles very similar to what you'd see from Ryan Reynolds’ portrayal of Deadpool, with a unique stance, a sarcastic wave, and even the way the operator plops down to lie next to the enemy's body.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="744122348" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464489,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;New%20Playlist%20Modifier%20-%20Bit%20Party%20%7C%20Call%20of%20Duty%20Modern%20Warfare%20III%20Official%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:45,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/new-playlist-modifier-bit-party-call-of-duty-modern-warfare-iii-official-trailer\/2300-6464489\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464489\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464489\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464489\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464489&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4324685-screenshot2024-06-25at10.58.04am.png&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/reT28BL7.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1719339300,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="reT28BL7" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> New Playlist Modifier - Bit Party | Call of Duty Modern Warfare III Official Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">The Season 4 battle pass ends on July 24, meaning that's likely the start of Season 5 and would make for a very well-timed crossover if the leaks are true, as the new Deadpool &amp; Wolverine movie releases in theaters on July 26.</p><p dir="ltr">Call of Duty has introduced several major IP event crossovers in the last few years, including the recent collaborations with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-collab-arrives-in-call-of-duty-mw3-and-warzone-this-week/1100-6524372/">Fallout</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/warzone-modern-warfare-iii-official-gundam-mobile-suit-bundles-gameplay-trailer/2300-6464213/">Gundam</a>, Dune, and The Walking Dead, so another major collaboration wouldn't be surprising.</p><p dir="ltr">We'll likely learn more about upcoming bundles and potential crossover events closer to Season 5's release. Activision is also hosting the Call of Duty: Next event on August 28 to reveal new details and showcase live gameplay of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-release-date-beta-and-more-leak-ahead-of-xbox-showcase/1100-6524072/">Black Ops 6</a> multiplayer.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Xbox Dashboard Seen In Unexpected Place, But It May Never Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-xbox-dashboard-seen-in-unexpected-place-but-it-may-never-release/1100-6524623/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-xbox-dashboard-seen-in-unexpected-place-but-it-may-never-release.916410/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-xbox-dashboard-seen-in-unexpected-place-but-it-may-never-release/1100-6524623/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524623">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>An apparently new Xbox dashboard--located on the screen of a Rimac car--was shown during a segment of the show Top Gear, but it may never see the light of day.</p><p>The Robotaxi <a href="https://x.com/_XboxNews/status/1806429468761760039" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">reveal</a> shows a reimagined Xbox 360-style blades dashboard with The Finals, Fortnite, and Halo Infinite on it. The narrator said that the dashboard is supposed to emulate the same feeling you have when booting up your console in your living room.</p><p>However, Microsoft provided a statement to GameSpot, saying that it had no plans for a dashboard like what was seen in the Rimac card and simply called it a mockup. "We currently have no plans for an Xbox Rimac dashboard," said an Xbox spokesperson. "For more information about this mockup video, please reach out to the Rimac team."</p><p>While Xbox said it has no plans to implement this more streamlined dashboard onto the Rimac, it's possible that it can be placed elsewhere. Microsoft is already in the process of making its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-pushing-ahead-with-plans-for-mobile-game-store-which-isnt-multiple-years-away/1100-6519625/" data-ref-id="1100-6519625">own mobile store for Xbox</a> so that it can compete with Apple and Google in the space. Xbox was working on a streaming-only console, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-streaming-console-patent-unearthed-showing-what-cloud-gaming-could-have-been/1100-6524542/" data-ref-id="1100-6524542">Keystone</a>, which was never released. Microsoft is also reportedly working on an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-is-working-on-xbox-handheld-prototypes-report/1100-6522128/" data-ref-id="1100-6522128">Xbox handheld</a>, similar to something like the Steam Deck and PlayStation Portal.</p><p>This isn't the first time people could play games natively in vehicles. Back in 2019, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cuphead-releasing-for-tesla-cars-this-summer/1100-6467302/" data-ref-id="1100-6467302">Tesla owners could play Cuphead in their cars</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivi Allowed Final Fantasy to Honor its Dying Past]]></title>
            <link>https://vgbees.com/vivi-allowed-final-fantasy-to-honor-its-dying-past/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=vivi-allowed-final-fantasy-to-honor-its-dying-past</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vivi-allowed-final-fantasy-to-honor-its-dying-past.916407/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://vgbees.com/vivi-allowed-final-fantasy-to-honor-its-dying-past/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=vivi-allowed-final-fantasy-to-honor-its-dying-past<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">

			
<article id="post-6497">
  
  <div data-hide-featured-media="0">
<p><em>Editor’s note: this piece contains spoilers for </em>Final Fantasy IX</p>



<p>In 2000, venerated RPG developer Square kicked off the new year with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/more-impressions-from-square-millennium/1100-2460029/">a big announcement:</a> <em>Final Fantasy</em> was going back to its roots. After two games featuring high-tech weaponry, corrupt megacorporations, and sci-fi boarding schools, the beloved franchise was finally returning to the European fairy tale aesthetic of its foundational 8- and 16-bit titles.</p>



<p>And, sure enough, when <em>Final Fantasy IX </em>came out, all the classic elements were there. The game takes place in a steampunk-tinged fantasy world and features a cast of whimsical characters. Elemental crystals, the <em>Final Fantasy</em> series’ recurring McGuffin, were back. So were moogles, dwarves, and — most importantly — black mages.</p>



<figure>
<figcaption><em>captured via <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Lacry">Lacry</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>



<p>Nothing showed Square’s commitment to <em>Final Fantasy IX</em>‘s back-to-basics approach more than Vivi Ornitier. After all, black mages have been part of <em>Final Fantasy</em> since the beginning and still serve as the de facto symbol of the series’ earliest days. In <em>Final Fantasy</em>, <em>Final Fantasy III</em>, and <em>Final Fantasy V</em>, the black mage is one of a few classes (or “jobs”) you can assign to your characters, trading their physical strength for the ability to cast powerful spells. In <em>Final Fantasy II and Final Fantasy IV</em>, black mages live in their own city, Mysidia; during the first few minutes of <em>IV</em>, the protagonist slaughters Mysidia’s robed residents and steals their crystal.</p>



<p>Vivi even looks like the black mages of old, big head and all. The mages’ shadowy faces and glowing eyes might have been <a href="https://na.finalfantasy.com/topics/176">byproducts of the Nintendo Entertainment System’s limited palette</a>, but their design is evocative and instantly memorable. It’s no wonder that they became <em>Final Fantasy</em>‘s first major mascots.</p>



<p>But neither Vivi nor <em>Final Fantasy IX </em>are exactly what they seem. In an unusual move, Square unveiled <em>Final Fantasy IX </em>alongside its two sequels. <em>Final Fantasy X</em>, due out a year later, was the franchise’s first installment on the then-brand-new PlayStation 2, and featured a new combat system, more realistic graphics, and a world inspired by Southeast Asia. <em>Final Fantasy XI </em>was an MMORPG in the vein of <em>Ultima Online </em>and <em>EverQuest</em>, with gameplay to match. The 2001 feature film <em>Final Fantasy: Spirits Within</em> told an alien invasion story.</p>



<p>In other words, <em>Final Fantasy IX</em> wasn’t a revival. It was a eulogy for <em>Final Fantasy</em>‘s classic era, and Vivi was there to help us say goodbye.</p>



<p>Endings — and what comes afterwards — are baked into <em>Final Fantasy IX</em>‘s premise. “Following the death of my mother, I went through some things that made me think about death,” franchise creator and <em>Final Fantasy IX </em>producer Hironobu Sakaguchi said, according to Third Editions’ <em>The Legend of Final Fantasy IX.</em> “In the end, I told myself that this sort of thing is really not so unusual. In spite of the sadness it brings, life goes on.”</p>



<p>It’s probably not an accident that Sakaguchi uses Vivi, <em>Final Fantasy IX</em>‘s most direct link to the franchise’s earlier installments, to express this theme, and the mage’s arc serves as a potent metaphor for the fate of the original Final Fantasy games. Initially, Vivi is clumsy, naïve, and ignorant about his true nature, but he means well and tries hard. As the adventure continues, he learns that he’s actually a <em>product</em>, one of hundreds of black mages produced on an assembly line for use in war. Even worse, Vivi was born with a built-in expiration date. After about a year of puttering around, he discovers, black mages simply stop working.&nbsp;</p>



<figure>
<figcaption><em>captured via <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Lacry">Lacry</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>



<p>Vivi spends the rest of <em>Final Fantasy IX </em>making peace with his impending demise. He succeeds, but time catches up with him anyway. During <em>Final Fantasy IX’s </em>epilogue, Vivi is the only cast member who’s absent. He is not, however, forgotten; a message written by mage before his death plays over the final scenes. “Life doesn’t last forever,” it says. “Even if you say goodbye, you’ll always be in our hearts … Farewell. My memories will be part of the sky.”</p>



<p>Unlike Vivi, <em>Final Fantasy</em> didn’t die after <em>Final Fantasy IX</em>, but it did change radically. Nobuo Uematsu is no longer the series’ sole (or even primary) composer. Sakaguchi is long gone. The Active Time Battle system, which powered <em>Final Fantasy IV </em>through <em>IX</em>‘s turn-based combat, has been retired.</p>



<p>And yet, like Vivi’s memory, those original titles’ influence remains. The first six <em>Final Fantasy</em> games have been remastered, remade, and re-released numerous times. They continue to provide a barometer for <em>Final Fantasy</em>‘s overall vibe, while the creatures, mechanics, and tropes they introduced — including black mages — have been remixed and reinterpreted repeatedly in later installments. Even when a <em>Final Fantasy</em> title tries something radically new, it still feels comfortable, thanks to the foundation those old games established.</p>



<p><em>Final Fantasy IX</em> foresaw this eventuality, of course. While Vivi doesn’t make it to the epilogue, a group of young black mages who claim to be his sons do. The message is clear: Vivi will be missed, but his death isn’t sad, exactly. His time was simply up; now, seeing how his descendants pick up his legacy will be its own, unique source of joy. You can say the exact same thing about classic <em>Final Fantasy</em>.</p>



<figure></figure>
 </div><!--/inner-wrap-->
    
</article>
<!--/author-bio-->

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s Why PS5 Often Runs Games Better Than the Allegedly More Powerful Xbox Series X]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/heres-why-ps5-often-runs-games-better-than-the-allegedly-more-powerful-xbox-series-x/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here%E2%80%99s-why-ps5-often-runs-games-better-than-the-allegedly-more-powerful-xbox-series-x.916404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/heres-why-ps5-often-runs-games-better-than-the-allegedly-more-powerful-xbox-series-x/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>As the ninth console generation approaches its fourth year, one question remained unanswered: how does Sony's PS5 console often outperform Microsoft's Xbox Series X, which is more powerful on paper?&nbsp;A few notable examples include <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-4-demo-performance-ps5-runs-better-xbox-series-x-better-vrr-rt/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Resident Evil 4</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/cod-black-ops-cold-war-performance-mode-ps5-better-ray-tracing-xsx-better/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Call of Duty: Black Ops Cold War</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-v-runs-better-on-ps5-than-xbox-series-x/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grand Theft Auto V</a> following the next-generation update.</p>
<p>As a reminder, both PS5 and Xbox Series X are powered by custom AMD hardware featuring Zen 2 and RDNA 2 CPU/GPU architectures. Microsoft's console has an eight-core CPU clocked at 3.8 GHz (3.6 GHz with simultaneous multithreading enabled), a GPU powered by 52 Compute Units clocked at 1.825 GHz for an estimated 12.16 TeraFLOPS of computing power, and 16GB of GDDR6 SDRAM with a split design (10GB with 320-bit bus and 560 GB/s bandwidth and 6 GB with 192-bit bus and 336 GB/s bandwidth).</p>
<p>On the other hand, PS5 has an eight-core CPU with variable frequency that is capped at 3.5 GHz, a GPU powered by 36 Compute Units with variable frequency up to 2.23 GHz for an estimated TeraFLOPS peak of 10.13, and 16GB of GDDR6 SDRAM with a 256-bit bus and 448 GB/s bandwidth.</p>
<p>Well, today, Digital Foundry <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TQIBknDAj4g" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published a new DF Direct weekly episode</a> in which they attempted to share a more or less final take on the subject. John Linneman mentioned hearing from developers that the shader compiler and the API itself are faster on the PlayStation 5 side.</p>
<p><em>One of the big ones that we've heard referenced multiple times now is the shader compiler on the PS5 side is just extremely fast and optimized. It gets pretty complex, but it makes better use of the actual silicon in a way that allows the PS5 to speedier performance. That seems to be a huge thing. Obviously, Microsoft wouldn't be sleeping on that, they're clearly putting in the work on that, but so is Sony, and developers just seem to prefer Sony's implementation for this. Along those same lines, the PS5's main API also seems to be quite fast, faster than what Microsoft's doing with DirectX.</em></p>
<p>The DirectX topic is interesting, as it is mentioned that Microsoft's choice to provide an API that works fairly seamlessly between PC and Xbox consoles may prove to be a slight penalty in how low-level it is on the console side.</p>
<p>That's not the whole story. According to Alex Battaglia, Unreal Engine 5-powered games generally benefit from the Xbox Series X's higher count of Compute Units. However, other engines may well be more performant on PS5 due to its higher clock rate.</p>
<p>There's more to consider, anyway, as Microsoft's console has the advantage when it comes to variable refresh rate (VRR) implementation. For example, while FromSoftware's Elden Ring runs faster on Sony's console, the Xbox Series X provides a smoother and more stable experience. Ultimately, though, the differences between the two consoles are relatively minor in most games, providing a comparable experience.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Acolyte Episode 5 Review: Stunning Battles, Shallow Characters]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/acolyte-episode-5-review-1851570537</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-acolyte-episode-5-review-stunning-battles-shallow-characters.916398/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/acolyte-episode-5-review-1851570537<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/acolyte-episode-4-review-1851570228&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/acolyte-episode-4-review-1851570228">a slow episode 4</a></span>, <em>The Acolyte</em> turns the volume all the way up on lightsaber battles with an episode that is worth every minute of screen time and then some. Featuring perhaps the best lightsaber choreography in <em>Star Wars</em> history, here the action takes priority over plot and character development.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193897" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="418" data-playlist="193897,194499,194617" data-current="193897"><div><p>10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19360.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Episode 5 (“Night”) picks up right where we left off, seconds before a battle between the Jedi Knights and the acolyte’s mysterious Master, clad in dark armor that’s a mix between that of Darth Vader and Kylo Ren. The battle begins with the Master tearing through several seemingly faceless Jedi, each of whom I’m sure each have their own dense backstories. Even amidst the spectacular all-versus-one action, the lack of intimacy we feel with these unknown Jedi left me feeling like an opportunity had been missed for us to feel more. As each Jedi fell, I would have loved for for their deaths to feel more impactful. All it would’ve taken was a simple meal scene like the goop dinner in the first <em>Matrix</em> movie in which Neo meets the crew of the ship that saved him.<br></p><p>Sprinkled between lightsaber martial arts combos, we have actual story progression. We’re in this fight to see Osha reunite with/arrest her twin sister Mae, both played by Amandla Stenberg. Amidst the battle, the Jedi tell Osha to get to safety, escorted by injured Jedi Knight Yord. Meanwhile, acolyte Mae attempts to evade her former dark Master unsuccessfully, and she sends a psychic distress signal to Osha. Osha tells Yord they have to go back or everyone will die. Osha gets the bright idea to use her pocket-droid’s flashlight to attract a swarm of umbramoths (giant, lethal moths) that surround them in the trees to use against the dark Master, and she and Yord run back to battle.</p><p>Yord lunges at the dark Master and hits his mask, but that doesn’t stop his adversary from slaying the best Jedi fighter, Padawan Jecki Lon (Dafne María Keen Fernández). Finally, we see the face of the Master. No doubt like many fans, up to this point I’d been wondering who the master is. Is it one of Osha and Mae’s mothers? Is it a former Jedi, perhaps the teacher of Master Sol (Lee Jung-jae)? Nope. It’s Qimir (Manny Jacinto). And now the volume on the episode turns down.</p><p>Manny is a great actor who’s performed well in previous episodes, but he feels  miscast in this moment. His reveal underwhelms, and the strength and mystery of the character is now gone. We learn of Qimir’s motivation—to be free—and the authenticity of a villain feels lost. This is not Vader. This is just a bad guy.</p><figure id="" data-id="e0d92967e4fc20101f5ba521fa5ddd6f" data-recommend-id="image://e0d92967e4fc20101f5ba521fa5ddd6f" data-format="jpg" data-width="2857" data-height="1608" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Manny Jacinto in a scene from The Acolyte." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Manny Jacinto in a scene from The Acolyte." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Lucasfilm</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e0d92967e4fc20101f5ba521fa5ddd6f" data-recommend-id="image://e0d92967e4fc20101f5ba521fa5ddd6f" data-format="jpg" data-width="2857" data-height="1608" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Manny Jacinto in a scene from The Acolyte." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Again, we feel the missed opportunities for character development, with the lack of time we’ve had to get to know Qimir up to this point sapping this development of its power. Yes, there are fan theories suggesting that more&nbsp;revelations await, but the narrative we’ve been fed up to this point isn’t potent enough to support this reveal in the here and now. But back to the episode’s highlight: Qimir kills Yord, cementing this scene as having some of the best deaths in any <em>Star Wars</em> battle.<br></p><p>As last Jedi standing Sol fights Qimir, Osha and Mae have gone through their back-and-forth of stun gunning (Osha shot Mae, but she woke up), and Osha sacrifices her droid (that we should care more about, but don’t) by sticking it on Qimir’s back. He’s attacked by the umbramoths and flown into the trees above. Mae awakens to stun-gun Sol, and she has a moment alone with Osha. Mae gives Osha a speech about how the Jedi brainwashed her and how they both need to believe in their sisterly bond. Mae hugs Osha, but Osha puts Mae in an arm lock. Then she delivers some dialogue about doing what she came to do: arrest her sister for murdering Jedi and burning their homeland. </p><p>One of my pet peeves is arm locking and dialogue, followed by reversing an arm lock and delivering more dialogue, which happens in this scene. Another example of the series being riddled with unnecessary tropes that take away from its built-in uniqueness. Mae ends up knocking Osha out cold, then lightsabers her hair and swaps clothing to impersonate her sister. This leads to Mae leaving the planet with the awakened Sol, and Osha being discovered by Qimir, who has defeated the swarm of umbramoths. Hopefully this leads to the truth being revealed behind what the Jedi did to destroy Mae and Osha’s home.</p><p><em>The Acolyte</em>’s fifth episode is the most exciting yet in terms of pacing and action. However, it also highlights how more focus on character development would allow us to understand how these individuals interact with the world and would convey emotional weight when characters die or return, or droid friends are lost. We don’t get enough intimate time with these characters for them to feel real, and I hope this changes with future episodes.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legacy Of Kain: Soul Reaver Is Making A Comeback, But It's Not What You Think It Is]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-is-making-a-comeback-but-its-not-what-you-think-it-is/1100-6524621/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-is-making-a-comeback-but-its-not-what-you-think-it-is.916395/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-is-making-a-comeback-but-its-not-what-you-think-it-is/1100-6524621/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524621">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>There's some good news for Legacy of Kain fans this week, as for the first time in <em>decades</em>, the series is getting some new material. A graphic novel titled Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver - The Dead Shall Rise has been announced, and it'll serve as a prequel to the games starring Raziel. It's not a new game or a remake of the classic titles, but something is better than nothing.</p><p>An official collaboration between Crystal Dynamics and Bit Bot Media, the Soul Reaver graphic novel will reveal more info about Raziel's past, his days as a Sarafan warrior, and how he came to serve under Kain as a vampire. The book will be written by Joshua Viola (True Believer) and Angie Hodapp (Shadow Atlas), with art by Juan Samu (Star Wars), letters by Jeremiah Lambert, and covers by Dave Rapoza and Aaron Lovett.</p><p>"In college, I created a Soul Reaver poster for a class project, never imagining I would one day officially contribute to the franchise," Viola said in a statement (via <a href="https://za.ign.com/legacy-of-kain-defiance/197058/news/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-returns-in-new-prequel-graphic-novel" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN</a>). "Even today, Raziel graces my tattoo sleeve--a testament to my deep connection with this universe. Fans can expect a project infused with that same passion. Working directly with creatives from Crystal Dynamics and reuniting with former collaborators makes this a truly special endeavor."</p><p>The Soul Reaver graphic novel will launch on Kickstarter later this year, and anyone interested can <a href="https://www.backerkit.com/call_to_action/ec6d71d7-3906-45d4-aaab-40fc1a372416/landing?preview_mode=true" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">sign up on BackerKit</a> to be informed when the crowdfunding campaign goes live.</p><p>Beyond this upcoming journey back to Nosgoth, things seem quiet for the Legacy of Kain franchise currently. The IP rights are currently held by Embracer Group, and in October 2022, over 100,000 people completed a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/crystal-dynamics-is-testing-the-waters-for-a-new-legacy-of-kain/1100-6508082/" data-ref-id="1100-6508082">Legacy of Kain survey</a>. According to Crystal Dynamics, fans were heard "loudly and clearly" about their desire to see the franchise return in some form.</p><p>The last true entry in the series, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/legacy-of-kain-defiance/">Defiance</a>, was released 20 years ago in 2003, and Crystal Dynamics is currently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/perfect-dark-gets-first-gameplay-trailer/1100-6524084/" data-ref-id="1100-6524084">co-developing a Perfect Dark reboot</a> with Microsoft studio The Initiative. The studio is also working on a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-next-tomb-raider-game-wont-be-connected-to-prime-videos-tv-series/1100-6524575/" data-ref-id="1100-6524575">new Tomb Raider game</a> that'll be published by Amazon.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons & Dragons Expedition To The Barrier Peaks Preview - Stepping Directly Into Science Fiction]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/previews/dungeons-dragons-expedition-to-barrier-peaks-preview-stepping-directly-into</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-dragons-expedition-to-the-barrier-peaks-preview-stepping-directly-into-science-fiction.916359/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/previews/dungeons-dragons-expedition-to-barrier-peaks-preview-stepping-directly-into<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ahead of the July 16th release of D&amp;D's new anthology book <em>Quests From The Infinite Staircase </em>I was invited along with a number of other <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3579fb91-ffa9-4c99-a750-de9f92ba642f" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons"><em>D&amp;D</em></a> journalists to get an early preview of the level 11 adventure, <em>Expedition To The Barrier Peaks</em> to not only see the otherworldly entities that the adventure has to offer, but also to get hands-on with D&amp;DBeyond's map features.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expedition_to_the_Barrier_Peaks"><em>Expedition To The Barrier Peaks</em></a> is an adventure that was originally written by Gary Gygax himself for <em>Advanced Dungeons &amp; Dragons 1st Edition</em> in 1980. Our quickly thrown together party was DM'd by <a href="https://twitter.com/MakenzieLaneDA">Makenzie De Armas</a>, writer at Wizards of the Coast who recently worked on <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a46e779c-d41c-4fff-b5fb-f04a72837c67" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/deck-of-many-things-review-dd-5e-has-new-best-sourcebook">The Deck of Many Things </a>and <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a8c2ec0c-8e1a-4fc6-a97f-23659c5ab321" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/critical-role-call-of-netherdeep-review"><em>Critical Role: Call of the Netherdeep</em></a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A fun note as we began our game was sentiments shared by other players, including <a href="https://twitter.com/AntonTaleTeller">Anton The Storyteller</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/cozywizrd">Mike Dunn</a>, who had spent time exploring Expedition To The Barrier Peaks in AD&amp;D. It was exciting to be sitting at the table with those about to embark on the journey for the first time, as well as those who had at least a partial idea of what to expect.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Settling in De Armas delivered a quick plot hook, the party had been tasked by a nearby town's mayor to investigate the strange creatures destroying settlements and so we were off to the mountains to investigate. It was explained that each of the adventures in this Anthology Series could be played in a sequential order, using Nafas the Genie who lives in the Infinite Staircase as a plot giver, but that each adventure can also be dropped into existing campaigns.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-classic-and-alt-cover_1.jpg?itok=y_gTHado 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-classic-and-alt-cover_1.jpg?itok=3VQ7Ea-T 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Nafas on both covers of Quests From The Infinite Staircase</figcaption></figure><p>Exploring the mountain the party encountered a cave, newly revealed by a landslide, and as we crossed the threshold the stone under our feet were replaced with cool metal.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.dndbeyond.com/games">De Armas took this moment to direct us towards the maps encounter</a>, which until now had been sitting with the message "Your DM is not currently hosting a game session." The screen came to life as we saw one of the beautiful maps from <em>Quests From The Infinite Staircase</em> appear, mostly obstructed.</p>
<p>Having built our characters as part of a Campaign within D&amp;DBeyond we could find our character tokens, add them to the map (already perfectly sized for the map) and begin combat as a Cloaker descended upon us.</p>
<p>After the quick battle we were met by a Robot who informed us that their leader wanted to speak with us. This wasn't an Auto-gnome, this wasn't an Automaton, Modron, or even a Warforged, but an honest to god Android.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/robots-from-expedition-to-the-barrier-peaks_0.jpg?itok=QNSDxK0b 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/robots-from-expedition-to-the-barrier-peaks_0.jpg?itok=DW7u8Rzc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The top left robot is the one we met and our party named him Frederick</figcaption></figure><p>At this point, we had stepped out of high fantasy and even further past Science Fantasy, we were fully immersed in a Science Fiction world.</p>
<p>The Maps feature of D&amp;DBeyond, while currently in Alpha, is one that I've been using as part of my home games as well as for adventures with other TechRaptor staff, including our recent <a href="https://techraptor.net/podcasts/vecna-eve-of-ruin-session-1-techraptor-podcast-117">four-part <em>Vecna: Eve of Ruin</em> series</a>. Admittedly, this was the first time getting to be on the other end of the map.&nbsp;</p>
<p>As De Armas revealed more of the map, erasing away the fog of war with a square erase tool, I was excited to hear my party mates reacting to the easy reveal of the world, and clicking sounds starting as De Armas let us know that you could move your tokens by selecting them and then using the arrow keys to direct them around the board like a video game. That was a new one for me too!</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/an-effect-overlay-showing-a-breath-weapon-in-dndbeyond-map-tools_0.jpg?itok=2Vs7N3RS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/an-effect-overlay-showing-a-breath-weapon-in-dndbeyond-map-tools_0.jpg?itok=RznnHq7N 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Another new feature I learned about (recreated here with my home game) is that you can create effect lines, circles, and squares and change their color and symbol</figcaption></figure><p>Throughout the rest of the adventure the party got to use tact to negotiate a deal between two warring groups of residents on the spaceship, two families of Vegepygmy, and learn about a number of interesting Tech Weapons available to find. One party member quickly picked up a Laser Pistol, while another got to donn a suit of Powered Armor.</p>
<p>Hearing about all that <em>Expeditions To The Barrier Peak</em> had to offer, including but not limited to malfunctioning combat robots and sections of the lower ship floor flooded with irradiation, De Armas also teased that there was a creature in the depths of the ship.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Asking if we could fast forward to that encounter De Armas was able to quickly show us off the rest of the first floor (of which we'd only managed to see a quarter of in four hours of play), skip through the second floor, and arrive in a central lush garden and lake area on the third floor. Here we faced the Froghemoth Elder.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/a-view-of-the-third-floor-of-the-spaceship_0.jpg?itok=IhcHHyCn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/a-view-of-the-third-floor-of-the-spaceship_0.jpg?itok=A7KButxi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Plenty of space for a Froghemoth Elder to creep out of the water and leap on us...</figcaption></figure><p>Combat in the D&amp;DBeyond map tools against the Froghemoth was quick and easy. As the new map was loaded we were able to pop out each of our tokens, the Froghemoth Elder was already in place on the map where De Armas had put it prior to the session.</p>
<p>In combat we were able to keep an eye on all characters, use rings to indicate what status we might be under (the status options were only color based, I would love to see some text on the rings in the future to better indicate that especially if it could be tied to the status on the character sheet), and when three of our party had been devoured by the Froghemoth I was able to draw a box on the map outside of the battle that indicated tokens inside had been eaten.</p>
<p>Getting invited to this session was a lot of fun, and being led through the world by De Armas and a variety of robotic impersonations was an absolute blast. I can definitely see how while it's part of an anthology book depending on how your party takes their time this could easily be 5+ sessions of time.</p>
<p>It was also a blast getting to see others experience the D&amp;DBeyond map tools for the first time. There is still a lot of roughness around the edges, but if you're running a campaign inside D&amp;DBeyond, with maps and monsters that aren't homebrew it's incredibly easy to hit the ground running. Even if you are importing maps you can scale them so all miniatures match easily, and homebrew creations can be imported just as easily.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring’s creators sure keep talking about an Elden Ring movie]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24189986/elden-ring-movie-tv-show-hidetaka-miyazaki-george-rr-martin</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring%E2%80%99s-creators-sure-keep-talking-about-an-elden-ring-movie.916356/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24189986/elden-ring-movie-tv-show-hidetaka-miyazaki-george-rr-martin<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="rKbUbs"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/22947204/elden-ring-review-from-software"><em>Elden Ring</em></a> creators Hidetaka Miyazaki and George R.R. Martin seem to be hinting that a movie (or TV series) based on the open-world fantasy role-playing game is coming — or at the very least, they’re trying to will one into existence, based on recent comments from the two <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23723957/elden-ring-nebula-award-george-r-r-martin-dlc-expansion">Nebula Award winners</a>.</p>
<p id="Nu0oAY">In a recent interview with <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/article/2024/jun/26/pushing-buttons-meeting-hidetaka-miyazaki">The Guardian</a>, <em>Elden Ring</em> director and FromSoftware president Hidetaka Miyazaki said, “I don’t see any reason to deny another interpretation or adaptation of <em>Elden Ring</em>, a movie for example.” He noted that FromSoftware doesn’t have “the knowledge or ability to produce something in a different medium” and would need to rely on a “very strong partner” to make it happen.</p>
<p id="Q2Cyxb">“We’d have to build a lot of trust and agreement on whatever it is we’re trying to achieve, but there’s interest, for sure,” Miyazaki concluded.</p>
<p id="ctshJF">A few days after that interview was published, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24135223/elden-ring-did-george-r-r-martin-write-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc"><em>Elden Ring</em> lore co-creator</a> George R.R. Martin <a href="https://georgerrmartin.com/notablog/2024/06/29/lose-one-win-one/">cheekily wrote on his blog</a>, “Oh, and about those rumors you may have heard about a feature film or television series based on<strong> </strong><em>Elden Ring</em>...<strong> </strong>I have nothing to say. Not a word, nope, not a thing, I know nothing, you never heard a peep from me, mum mum mum. What rumor?”</p>
<p id="m4rqI3"><em>Elden Ring</em> publisher Bandai Namco has hinted at an expansion of the game’s universe for two years now, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22980899/elden-ring-new-franchise-fromsoftware">hailing the game as the start of a new franchise</a>. When <a href="https://www.fromsoftware.jp/ww/pressrelease_detail.html?tgt=20220316_eldenring_salesdata">FromSoft and Bandai Namco announced</a> in 2022 that <em>Elden Ring</em> had sold 12 million units in its first month, the companies said, “Please look forward to more of Elden Ring as an IP [...]) in hopes of expanding beyond the realm of games.”</p>
<p id="H0vIwr">“Much effort was placed into creating <em>Elden Ring</em> in order to exceed the expectations of our fans worldwide,” said Yasuo Miyakawa, president and CEO of Bandai Namco Entertainment, in that announcement. “With a similar goal, we will continue our efforts in expanding the brand beyond the game itself and into everyone’s daily life.”</p>
<p id="Z5twO1">FromSoftware’s other games, including <em>Dark Souls</em>, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2015/3/27/8209199/bloodborne-review-PS4-playstation-4-exclusive"><em>Bloodborne</em></a>, and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/2019/3/21/18274733/sekiro-review-ps4-xbox-one-pc"><em>Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice</em></a>, have been adapted to other entertainment media, mainly in the form of manga and comic books that expand each title’s story. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elden-Ring-Road-Erdtree-Vol/dp/1975364899?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Elden-Ring-Road-Erdtree-Vol/dp/1975364899?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23954027__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23954027__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><em>Elden Ring</em> has also been adapted to manga form</a>, but as a comedy starring a clueless Tarnished named Aseo who is pathetically struggling to become Elden Lord. Presumably, any bigger-budget adaptation of <em>Elden Ring</em> would take a more serious approach.</p>
<p id="Bbjr5B">While neither FromSoftware nor Bandai Namco have officially announced a film or TV adaptation of <em>Elden Ring</em>, it appears the game’s creators are on board. Such a project would give Martin another opportunity to not complete <a href="https://www.polygon.com/entertainment/23560856/winds-of-winter-release-date-george-r-r-martin-new-york-giants-football"><em>The Winds of Winter</em></a>, and give FromSoftware much bigger exposure outside of games.</p>
<p id="cOoBGA">But what would an adaptation of <em>Elden Ring</em> even look like? Likely not a direct adaptation of the events of the game, but as an expanded version of the lore that leads up to the setting of <em>Elden Ring</em>. Existing prior to the playable portion of this universe is a sprawling medieval fantasy political drama that involves complex familial and romantic relationships, political power struggles, and just a <em>tiny</em> bit of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23344676/house-dragon-episode-4-review-targaryen">incest</a>. Not only is that a proven recipe for Martin, a prequel outlining the lore of <em>Elden Ring</em> would certainly go a long way to helping its more than 25 million players understand <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23020905/elden-ring-lore-story-plot-endings-radahn-ranni">what the hell is going on</a>.</p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XIV: Dawntrail, As Told By Steam Reviews]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-steam-reviews-1851570344</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-xiv-dawntrail-as-told-by-steam-reviews.916350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-steam-reviews-1851570344<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="063d14e6a1fef048a7d5c014496bfd69" data-recommend-id="image://063d14e6a1fef048a7d5c014496bfd69" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="707" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A pictomancer paints with steam reviews floating in the space" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A pictomancer paints with steam reviews floating in the space" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="063d14e6a1fef048a7d5c014496bfd69" data-recommend-id="image://063d14e6a1fef048a7d5c014496bfd69" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="707" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A pictomancer paints with steam reviews floating in the space" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>There’s a lot of pressure on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-community-preview-1851521989&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-community-preview-1851521989"><em>Dawntrail</em></a></span>, the newest expansion for Square Enix’s critically acclaimed MMO <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-endwalker-dawntrail-ps5-controller-1851385139&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-endwalker-dawntrail-ps5-controller-1851385139"><em>Final Fantasy XIV</em></a></span>. As the first expansion after the game finished off a decades-long story with world-ending stakes in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-endwalker-goodbye-dawntrail-1851561996&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-endwalker-goodbye-dawntrail-1851561996"><em>Endwalker</em></a></span>,<em> Dawntrail</em>’s adventure in the tropical locale of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-turalism-site-rhys-darby-1851564573&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-turalism-site-rhys-darby-1851564573">Tural</a></span> is a new start and also a much-needed summer vacation for the Warrior of Light. But can it be a relaxing expansion while also setting up the stakes for the MMO’s next decade? Steam reviews seem mixed on how well <em>Dawntrail</em> pulls it all off.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195519" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="I Didn’t Play Final Fantasy XVI ‘Right,’ And That’s OK" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="148" data-playlist="195519,195905,196805" data-current="195519"><div><p>I Didn’t Play Final Fantasy XVI ‘Right,’ And That’s OK</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21013.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Many are praising <em>Dawntrail</em>, with some even calling it the best expansion the game has ever received (which is incredibly high praise considering how good <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-shadowbringers-the-kotaku-review-1838105413&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-shadowbringers-the-kotaku-review-1838105413"><em>Shadowbringers</em></a></span> was). Generally, positive reviews highlight the new world of Tural and its diverse cast of characters, including everyone’s favorite Hrothgar, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-wuk-lamat-npc-love-1851569954&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-wuk-lamat-npc-love-1851569954">Wuk Lamat</a></span>. It’s no surprise that a lower-stakes adventure for the Warrior of Light and their best buddies through a tropical wonderland is hitting perfectly for a lot of long-time players. But it isn’t just the relaxing vibes and beautiful setting getting high praise, <em>Dawntrail</em> also brought with it quality-of-life features like a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-7-0-patch-visual-upgrade-1851559585&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-7-0-patch-visual-upgrade-1851559585">graphical update</a></span> which has made the game shine like new. The overall takeaway from positive Steam reviews is that <em>Dawntrail</em> is a breath of fresh air for the aging MMO in almost every way.</p><p>Shocking nobody, however, the fanbase is hardly unanimous on the matter. <em>Dawntrail</em> haters have two major problems. The first is Wuk Lamat. Yes, some of these people just hate Wuk Lamat! I cannot understand it but a lot of negative reviews are criticizing the character many other players adore. Specifically, the critique is that Wuk Lamat is so central to the overarching <em>Dawntrail</em> story that she effectively becomes the main character over the Warrior of Light. Second, some feel that the relaxing vibes of the expansion, rather than making it work as a vacation-like adventure, diminish it instead, making it too low-stakes with a boring nothing-burger of a plot. Some reviews go so far as to say that <em>Dawntrail</em> is as bad (if not worse) than <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-stormblood-the-kotaku-review-1796771052&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-stormblood-the-kotaku-review-1796771052"><em>Stormblood</em></a></span>, the second and most-derided expansion to <em>Final Fantasy 14</em>. </p><p>Some of the criticism of <em>Dawntrail</em> is probably a result of how different its goals are from those of past expansions. From the release of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-a-realm-reborn-the-kotaku-review-1440536417&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-a-realm-reborn-the-kotaku-review-1440536417"><em>A Realm Reborn</em></a></span> until the conclusion of <em>Endwalker</em>, each expansion raised the stakes of the story and led to a climactic finale to a decades-long story. <em>Dawntrail</em> couldn’t have raised the stakes from <em>Endwalker</em>, and it’s meant as a de-escalation. Inherently that may be less exciting, but it is intentional. To tell a new exciting story you have to start from square one.</p><p>At the end of the day, Steam reviews have given me a sense of what to expect in <em>Dawntrail</em> when I finally get around to it. Most importantly, I now know that I will encounter sentient corn at some point, so I have more motivation than ever to get to Tural. Check out what else players are saying.</p><figure id="" data-id="08e5fb27432ab968864a6f16061bb9df" data-recommend-id="image://08e5fb27432ab968864a6f16061bb9df" data-format="jpg" data-width="620" data-height="264" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Game is pretty good if you skip the entire story&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Game is pretty good if you skip the entire story&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="08e5fb27432ab968864a6f16061bb9df" data-recommend-id="image://08e5fb27432ab968864a6f16061bb9df" data-format="jpg" data-width="620" data-height="264" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Game is pretty good if you skip the entire story&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="b331b87eb2043a7c784db5c33f87a538" data-recommend-id="image://b331b87eb2043a7c784db5c33f87a538" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="308" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I personally think that every time Wuk Lamat isn't on screen a character should ask &quot;Wheres Wuk Lamat?&quot;  (Edit - This actually happens.)&quot;&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I personally think that every time Wuk Lamat isn't on screen a character should ask &quot;Wheres Wuk Lamat?&quot;  (Edit - This actually happens.)&quot;&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b331b87eb2043a7c784db5c33f87a538" data-recommend-id="image://b331b87eb2043a7c784db5c33f87a538" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="308" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I personally think that every time Wuk Lamat isn't on screen a character should ask &quot;Wheres Wuk Lamat?&quot;  (Edit - This actually happens.)&quot;&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="b1903241c492f3e0659783a8ca293838" data-recommend-id="image://b1903241c492f3e0659783a8ca293838" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="497" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Follow the adventures of Brave Hero Wuk Lamat (OC DO NOT STEAL) as she learns the meaning of friendship along with her friends such as, no prior accomplishments you can do it person (This NPC is customizable!), Krile and guy with a backpack! Learn fun lessons like no crime is unforgivable if you become a friend! Who needs leadership to lead? Is that boat a boat? and last but not least lets get sad then do a 180 after literally one sentence of encouragement! SE has pulled out all the stop on this expansion by somehow out doing the award winning writer of the famed Jailer (from WoW!) with the subversion of well known tropes as story structure, character growth and having fun!  Graphics Update: 10/10 Dungeons: 10/10 New Lore: 8/10 Main City Music: Donkey Kong Story: 2/10  Overall Rating: Wuk Lamat/Wuk Lamat&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Follow the adventures of Brave Hero Wuk Lamat (OC DO NOT STEAL) as she learns the meaning of friendship along with her friends such as, no prior accomplishments you can do it person (This NPC is customizable!), Krile and guy with a backpack! Learn fun lessons like no crime is unforgivable if you become a friend! Who needs leadership to lead? Is that boat a boat? and last but not least lets get sad then do a 180 after literally one sentence of encouragement! SE has pulled out all the stop on this expansion by somehow out doing the award winning writer of the famed Jailer (from WoW!) with the subversion of well known tropes as story structure, character growth and having fun!  Graphics Update: 10/10 Dungeons: 10/10 New Lore: 8/10 Main City Music: Donkey Kong Story: 2/10  Overall Rating: Wuk Lamat/Wuk Lamat&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b1903241c492f3e0659783a8ca293838" data-recommend-id="image://b1903241c492f3e0659783a8ca293838" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="497" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Follow the adventures of Brave Hero Wuk Lamat (OC DO NOT STEAL) as she learns the meaning of friendship along with her friends such as, no prior accomplishments you can do it person (This NPC is customizable!), Krile and guy with a backpack! Learn fun lessons like no crime is unforgivable if you become a friend! Who needs leadership to lead? Is that boat a boat? and last but not least lets get sad then do a 180 after literally one sentence of encouragement! SE has pulled out all the stop on this expansion by somehow out doing the award winning writer of the famed Jailer (from WoW!) with the subversion of well known tropes as story structure, character growth and having fun!  Graphics Update: 10/10 Dungeons: 10/10 New Lore: 8/10 Main City Music: Donkey Kong Story: 2/10  Overall Rating: Wuk Lamat/Wuk Lamat&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="02257e7f4a9f477bdb2d469ef0a9e538" data-recommend-id="image://02257e7f4a9f477bdb2d469ef0a9e538" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="264" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Baby sitting Wuk Lamat&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Baby sitting Wuk Lamat&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="02257e7f4a9f477bdb2d469ef0a9e538" data-recommend-id="image://02257e7f4a9f477bdb2d469ef0a9e538" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="264" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Baby sitting Wuk Lamat&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="8259007fd2bb845b74f8c3c04467351e" data-recommend-id="image://8259007fd2bb845b74f8c3c04467351e" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="281" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I don't know what everyone is complaining about. I've skipped every cutscene since ARR and I think Wuk Lamat is a cool dude.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I don't know what everyone is complaining about. I've skipped every cutscene since ARR and I think Wuk Lamat is a cool dude.&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8259007fd2bb845b74f8c3c04467351e" data-recommend-id="image://8259007fd2bb845b74f8c3c04467351e" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="281" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I don't know what everyone is complaining about. I've skipped every cutscene since ARR and I think Wuk Lamat is a cool dude.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="7c54a06e13ba0137c28b6585f5987c80" data-recommend-id="image://7c54a06e13ba0137c28b6585f5987c80" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="260" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I am a camera man&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I am a camera man&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7c54a06e13ba0137c28b6585f5987c80" data-recommend-id="image://7c54a06e13ba0137c28b6585f5987c80" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="260" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I am a camera man&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="d7a2f5a37f1e22382796d87533f2ac1c" data-recommend-id="image://d7a2f5a37f1e22382796d87533f2ac1c" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="309" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I think dawntrail would be better if instead of speaking to wuk lamat we got to speak to wuk larat and instead of a big cat she was a big rat and instead of the battle for the big throne it was the battle for the big cheese and-&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I think dawntrail would be better if instead of speaking to wuk lamat we got to speak to wuk larat and instead of a big cat she was a big rat and instead of the battle for the big throne it was the battle for the big cheese and-&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d7a2f5a37f1e22382796d87533f2ac1c" data-recommend-id="image://d7a2f5a37f1e22382796d87533f2ac1c" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="309" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I think dawntrail would be better if instead of speaking to wuk lamat we got to speak to wuk larat and instead of a big cat she was a big rat and instead of the battle for the big throne it was the battle for the big cheese and-&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="f520f48ae679b793d6d8329db36ef530" data-recommend-id="image://f520f48ae679b793d6d8329db36ef530" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="272" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I can't believe they made a MSQ worse than Stormblood. Impressive, really.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I can't believe they made a MSQ worse than Stormblood. Impressive, really.&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f520f48ae679b793d6d8329db36ef530" data-recommend-id="image://f520f48ae679b793d6d8329db36ef530" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="272" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;I can't believe they made a MSQ worse than Stormblood. Impressive, really.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="e4c6157fde715f868c2f421c2f037fe7" data-recommend-id="image://e4c6157fde715f868c2f421c2f037fe7" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="319" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Big fat tacos, oh, big fat tacos, Oh, big fat tacos, So big!&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Big fat tacos, oh, big fat tacos, Oh, big fat tacos, So big!&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e4c6157fde715f868c2f421c2f037fe7" data-recommend-id="image://e4c6157fde715f868c2f421c2f037fe7" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="319" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Big fat tacos, oh, big fat tacos, Oh, big fat tacos, So big!&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="ff07ad96d46a240ea87bc12acc859507" data-recommend-id="image://ff07ad96d46a240ea87bc12acc859507" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="286" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;&quot;The story is fine, ya'll were just spoiled by the last two expansions. Critique shit that actually matters&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;&quot;The story is fine, ya'll were just spoiled by the last two expansions. Critique shit that actually matters&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ff07ad96d46a240ea87bc12acc859507" data-recommend-id="image://ff07ad96d46a240ea87bc12acc859507" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="286" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;&quot;The story is fine, ya'll were just spoiled by the last two expansions. Critique shit that actually matters&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="d2b1e54ed477494702dbade2df544f61" data-recommend-id="image://d2b1e54ed477494702dbade2df544f61" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="208" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;They added the Sanghelli from Halo to FFXIV&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;They added the Sanghelli from Halo to FFXIV&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d2b1e54ed477494702dbade2df544f61" data-recommend-id="image://d2b1e54ed477494702dbade2df544f61" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="208" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;They added the Sanghelli from Halo to FFXIV&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="eef179356f61d4d83828d829feb57255" data-recommend-id="image://eef179356f61d4d83828d829feb57255" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="261" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;They ruined AST and not even the alpacas can save this&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;They ruined AST and not even the alpacas can save this&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="eef179356f61d4d83828d829feb57255" data-recommend-id="image://eef179356f61d4d83828d829feb57255" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="261" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;They ruined AST and not even the alpacas can save this&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="01cde1d9ec107c2002fbac0d86a31f64" data-recommend-id="image://01cde1d9ec107c2002fbac0d86a31f64" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="261" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Yawntrail&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Yawntrail&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="01cde1d9ec107c2002fbac0d86a31f64" data-recommend-id="image://01cde1d9ec107c2002fbac0d86a31f64" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="261" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Yawntrail&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="1943666fca39d81451df7344dcef2516" data-recommend-id="image://1943666fca39d81451df7344dcef2516" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="261" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Wuk Lamat I love you&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Wuk Lamat I love you&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1943666fca39d81451df7344dcef2516" data-recommend-id="image://1943666fca39d81451df7344dcef2516" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="261" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Wuk Lamat I love you&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="31e3a7574323c70291d8902530f7eea5" data-recommend-id="image://31e3a7574323c70291d8902530f7eea5" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="300" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;&quot;I've only had Wuk Lamat for a day and a half, but if anything happened to her, I would kill everyone in this room and then myself.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;&quot;I've only had Wuk Lamat for a day and a half, but if anything happened to her, I would kill everyone in this room and then myself.&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="31e3a7574323c70291d8902530f7eea5" data-recommend-id="image://31e3a7574323c70291d8902530f7eea5" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="300" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;&quot;I've only had Wuk Lamat for a day and a half, but if anything happened to her, I would kill everyone in this room and then myself.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="216438076208f6da229af7a3d6d45c75" data-recommend-id="image://216438076208f6da229af7a3d6d45c75" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="232" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Has a sentient corn quest. 10/10. Game of the Year&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Has a sentient corn quest. 10/10. Game of the Year&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="216438076208f6da229af7a3d6d45c75" data-recommend-id="image://216438076208f6da229af7a3d6d45c75" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="232" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;Has a sentient corn quest. 10/10. Game of the Year&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="bfff81e402b42bfa0d7de87098f49b99" data-recommend-id="image://bfff81e402b42bfa0d7de87098f49b99" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="246" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;It is so calm and relaxed. NO pressure at all. I needed this vacation&quot;&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;It is so calm and relaxed. NO pressure at all. I needed this vacation&quot;&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bfff81e402b42bfa0d7de87098f49b99" data-recommend-id="image://bfff81e402b42bfa0d7de87098f49b99" data-format="jpg" data-width="617" data-height="246" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Steam review that reads &quot;It is so calm and relaxed. NO pressure at all. I needed this vacation&quot;&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 14 Director Apologizes for Dawntrail Early Access Issues]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-director-apologizes-for-dawntrail-early-access-issues</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-14-director-apologizes-for-dawntrail-early-access-issues.916347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-director-apologizes-for-dawntrail-early-access-issues<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"I would like to offer my sincere apologies."</h2></div><section><p>Final Fantasy 14 director Naoki Yoshida has apologized for the issues present in <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy-xiv-online-dawntrail">Dawntrail</a>, the latest expansion currently available in early access.</p><p>In a <a href="https://eu.finalfantasyxiv.com/lodestone/topics/detail/09598d1b4efffdc7cdc3360d32bf2086026761b6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post</a>, Yoshida apoligized to fans who preordered the game and thus unlocked the early access version, and explained what has caused certain issues and how the development team at Square Enix plans to address them. He also suggested a hotfix would arrive sometime "this week" alongside a brief server maintenance period.</p><p>"Firstly, I would like to thank everyone who has been playing Dawntrail since the start of early access," Yoshida said. "However, I would like to offer my sincere apologies regarding the issues that we have identified."</p><p>Xbox version issues have perhaps been most prominent, as the game client can become completely unresponsive when moving between locations. "Our preliminary investigation suggests that this issue is likely due to a phenomenon known as memory fragmentation," Yoshida said.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I would like to offer my sincere apologies regarding the issues that we have identified.</p></div><p>Square Enix is looking into a fix for the problem but it will be "several days" before one is released, Yoshida said. This is because a patch must go through myriad checks by the quality assurance team.</p><p>"We are working to expedite the release of this patch at the earliest possible opportunity," he said. "However, we regret to say that this process will require some time. We sincerely apologize for the inconvenience this causes and appreciate your patience and understanding as we work to address the issue."</p><p>Players, in the meantime, may encounter the issue less if they play on worlds with low populations. "Until we have resolved the issue, we kindly suggest you consider playing on either the Dynamis, Shadow, or Oceania data centers," Yoshida said.</p><p>An incoming patch will also address freezing abilities not functioning properly and an issue with the display and animations of cerain characters.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>FINAL FANTASY XIV: Dawntrail Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>"The aforementioned issues are being classified as a high priority," Yoshida said. "They are under investigation on our development server and are being addressed in a systematic manner. We are considering the release of a hot fix, which is likely to occur sometime this week, which would be accompanied by a brief maintenance period."</p><p>It's therefore likely all of these issues will still be in Dawntrail upon its full launch tomorrow, July 2, 2024. The accompanying <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-version-70-patch-notes-reveal-every-change-coming-alongside-dawntrail">Version 7.0 patch hade made plenty of positive changes</a> to the game too, such as new areas, quests, quality-of-life improvement, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-getting-a-major-graphics-update-with-new-requirements-for-dawntrail-expansion">a huge graphical upgrade</a>, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-trailer-pictomancer-job-female-hrothgar-and-more-revealed-at-tokyo-fan-fest">the Viper and Pictomancer jobs</a>, but seemingly not without a few frustrating bugs.</p><p>Dawntrail's Steam page is also full of middling reviews, as while Final Fantasy 14 expansions are usually widely praised by fans and critics, Dawntrail has dropped to a "mixed" rating. Despite "review bombing" being a common tactic for players looking to express frustration, Dawntrail's current Steam user review rating appears to be the result of genuine grievances and not bugs.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom Celebrates Dino Crisis’ 25th Birthday With a Picture of a Bloody Dinosaur Foot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-celebrates-dino-crisis-25th-birthday-with-a-picture-of-a-bloody-dinosaur-foot</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-celebrates-dino-crisis%E2%80%99-25th-birthday-with-a-picture-of-a-bloody-dinosaur-foot.916344/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-celebrates-dino-crisis-25th-birthday-with-a-picture-of-a-bloody-dinosaur-foot<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/dino-crisis">Dino Crisis</a> is now 25 years old, with the first game in the series launching on PlayStation on July 1, 1999.</p><p>Capcom’s much-loved dinosaur survival horror game has seen three games so far, the first of which remains the best-selling with 2.4 million sold. Dino Crisis 2, which followed a year later in 2000, sold 1.2 million copies. Dino Crisis 3 launched as an original Xbox exclusive in 2003 and fans have yet to see a new game since.</p><p>Despite the occasional groundswell of opinion that Dino Crisis should return from hardcore fans, Capcom seems uninterested in reviving the franchise. Indeed Capcom's 2022 announcement of <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/exoprimal">Exoprimal</a>, a multiplayer-focused action game featuring dinosaurs, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dino-crisis-exoprimal-producer">was seen as the final nail in the coffin for Dino Crisis</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>But today, July 1, to celebrate Dino Crisis’ birthday, Capcom tweeted a picture of a bloody dinosaur foot, which some hopeful fans were taking as a positive sign.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">7月1日は『ディノクライシス』(1999年/PS)の発売日です！ <a href="https://t.co/s6vdi8ukQM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/s6vdi8ukQM</a></p>— CAPCOM公式 (@capcom_official) <a href="https://twitter.com/capcom_official/status/1807685651867082915?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 1, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Capcom, though, has plenty to be getting on with right now. It’s got <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> due out at some point in 2025, as well as multiple Resident Evil remakes and a brand new Resident Evil game. Then there’s the upcoming <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-announced">Dead Rising remake</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvel-vs-capcom-fighting-collection-arcade-classics">Marvel vs. Capcom Fighting Collection: Arcade Classics</a>. Is there a place for Dino Crisis in Capcom's lineup? Only time will tell.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s Not That Difficult To Talk About FromSoftware Games]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-hard-difficulty</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it%E2%80%99s-not-that-difficult-to-talk-about-fromsoftware-games.916332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-hard-difficulty<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>There is an albatross hanging around the neck of the latest FromSoftware release, the same as every FromSoftware release: difficulty. The problem is that talking about difficulty in the abstract like it’s a set value is boring, reactionary, and not particularly productive, It obfuscates the real trade-offs that From often makes with their games, and <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> is very much a game of trade-offs. And the worst thing about it is that talking about these games critically with nuance is simply not that difficult.</p><h2>Mixed Blessings</h2><figure><figcaption>If you've gotten to this point you know exactly what this game's deal was, or at least you did a year or two ago. Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Shadow of the Erdtree </em>is the DLC expansion to <em>Elden Ring</em> and from the jump, it is not an easy bit of DLC to unlock, requiring that you have beaten Mogh, an optional boss hidden in a fairly out of the way place. The placement, aside from its lore implications, is a significant choice and establishes who the DLC was always meant for: everyone who has beaten the extreme ends of <em>Elden Ring</em> into the ground, have hit the ends of the base game and gotten to around level 150. By touching the The Cocoon of the Empyrean, you are transported to The Land of Shadow, a reality with its own special rules.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Warning: Minor location, weapon, and boss spoilers ahead, although I have attempted to avoid discussing major plot elements whenever possible.</strong> </p><p>The second you go into the Land of Shadow, you quickly notice that everything in it hits you like a fucking fire truck. To balance the fact that people are probably overleveled going into this expansion, <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> introduces a new mechanic, centred around items called Scadutree Fragments. By collecting these fragments, you are able to power up both the damage you deal and the damage you take. This is where nuance is important, because while the rationale for this system is smart and addresses a very real problem, it’s implemented quite badly.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>You will find Scadutree fragments around here, sometimes, mostly. Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment.</figcaption></figure><p>It is clear that FromSoftware, who have created a gargantuan world, would like you to explore all of it instead of just boss rushing the whole thing, (To reduce this release to simple DLC would be underselling it, although I disagree that this is basically a sequel.) But they both clumsily tell you about the Scadutree Fragment system while never really stressing how significant a difference it makes in the basic playability of the DLC. The scaling, at least at launch, was gargantuan. What's more, by hiding leveling in a Korok-ass collectible, progression becomes a fetch quest.&nbsp;</p><p>This would be fine if there was some kind of cohesion about where shards appear, but there’s only a vague rhyme or reason behind their placement. Initially it seems like they mostly stay around crucifixes, but sometimes guys who have jars have them, and sometimes they are near statues, but also sometimes big hippos carry them, and once I saw one in a coffin under a waterfall. You could argue that this is no different than hiding Golden Seed flask upgrades, but I feel like those are fundamentally different mechanics. There’s a better way they could have done this, and I feel slightly vindicated here given the fact that they aggressively patched the scaling of the system as I was writing this blog, making the initial Scadutree Fragments more significant, and the later ones more gradual.&nbsp;</p><h2>Lands Between&nbsp;</h2><figure><figcaption>The verticality in these games is breathtaking, the map is somewhat annoying. Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment</figcaption></figure><p>Forcing the player to explore the world is a valid choice, because <em>Shadow of the Erdtree </em>has some of the most gorgeous landscapes I have ever seen in a game. But many of those vistas are also a little empty, even by <em>Elden Ring </em>standards. It’s not uncommon to see beautiful, striking biome in the distance, get there, and then find like two things to do in them.&nbsp;</p><p>I do admit there’s a kind of beauty to a huge, empty space. The Abyssal Woods are terrifying, so much so that your mount will not let you summon it, forcing you to take this space on foot. And some of these locations serve important storytelling purposes just by dint of being there, like the Finger Ruins. And yet I can’t shake the feeling that the entire thing was either scaled back at one point, or that the game itself is simply masquerading as a much larger experience, like a bag of potato chips as my colleague Ash Parrish observed on Aftermath Hours. This was always a fundamental compromise of the base game, particularly near the end, but in <em>Erdtree </em>it is felt much more aggressively. I don’t even know that I want more things to do in those places; the expansion is the perfect length to me, but I can’t help but feel a sense of disappointment, or that these areas feel unfinished, a sensation that <em>Elden Ring</em> delivered much less frequently.&nbsp; Like the base game, <em>Erdtree </em>has a very showy beginning and middle, but loses cohesion in the extremities and the back section. That said, there are real highlights to the end, especially in the way the structure of the final area looks like an impossible Rodin sculpture.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>Some of the most breathtaking environments in any video game. I wish they were not so hollow. Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment</figcaption></figure><p>One of the most striking things about the map is its verticality. Much of the Shadow Realm consists of massive cliffs and valleys, and there is something breathtaking about seeing locations far in the distance and wondering “how the hell am I going to get there?” This is a valid question, and one you may ask yourself repeatedly, because the routes to get to those places are inorganic and uneven in a way that I don’t personally find enjoyable. Artistically, there is validity to making huge parts of your map aggressively convoluted to find, but I always found that to be both the most elusive part and greatest weakness of Miquella's Haligtree in the original game. But unlike the Haligtree, there’s no <em>there</em> when you get there in <em>Erdtree</em>, and the tease of having these spaces that are distant and gorgeous but ultimately hollow half the time left me cold.&nbsp;</p><h2>Who’s the Boss?</h2><figure><figcaption>This game features some of the best and most confusingly tuned boss fights From has ever done. Rellana is a standout. Credit: Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment</figcaption></figure><p>There is also the issue of bosses in this game, and in my fair assessment as a From player, there’s simply a lot of bullshit here. This is not unusual for a From game, and I love a lot of bullshit Souls bosses.&nbsp;</p><p>Many of the bosses themselves are the logical conclusion trying to one up <em>Elden Ring</em>, and to account for players already having a medium sized arsenal of disgustingly broken gear. Some of the bosses, like the Golden Hippo or the Shadow Sunflower, are just straight up bad, the big sloppy monster type that is often in line with From’s weakest offerings. A few of the bosses are among their most creative and beautiful designs, featuring gorgeous cutscenes. Rellana and Messmer are standouts here. A huge portion of them have either some tremendously cheesy thermonuclear bomb up their sleeve, some flowing combo similar to Malenia’s Waterfowl Dance, or both. A handful are tuned very bizarrely, and favor certain playstyles and builds overly aggressively. The final boss is particularly guilty of this.</p><figure><figcaption>Everyone hates this hippo. Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment</figcaption></figure><p>Many of the choices make sense, as <em>Elden Ring’s </em>design was originally about offering the player some unreasonable challenges coupled with almost too many options than could be playtested at launch, and seeing how the player base could break the game. This flexibility gave it a mass market appeal that previous games did not. In terms of design, <em>Erdtree</em> is no different. I see a lot of people complain that these encounters are too “hard,” but a more accurate word is “unsatisfying.” Are these encounters balanced well, and what audience are they balanced for? Is that the same audience of 25 million that bought the game, or diehards who solo Malenia naked wearing a big fungus helmet? Is the friction rewarding and meaningful and does eking out a win feel good? There are some shining standouts, but a lot of times the answer for me is no.&nbsp;</p><h2>The Shadow of the Erdtree</h2><figure><figcaption>I will say, I like these guys. Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment</figcaption></figure><p>Sometimes I wonder what lessons From took away from the meme-like popularity of Malenia, the optional ultra hard boss hidden deep in an easily missable section of the original game, because I feel her presence, the tradeoffs in her design and location, a lot in this game. But aside from the decisions that are outright bad, I don’t know how much I can fault the developers for how <em>Erdtree </em>is shaped, because many of the things I personally dislike are simply the logical conclusion to conceptual tradeoffs FromSoftware made to make a game as gargantuan as <em>Elden Ring</em>.&nbsp;</p><p>Reskinning bosses and locations from other games and encounters has long been one of From’s favorite bits, and oftentimes they are good at recontextualizing assets in a way that either adds a new spin to them, contributes to the lore, or is very funny. Sometimes in <em>Elden Ring </em>this was implemented poorly or contributed to fluff: for example, there’s no reason for me to fight Astel twice, when even as an optional fight this choice made the first fight less special. This also rears its head aggressively in the DLC, where many lesser bosses are reskins of enemies that I have already fought, in a way that is <em>not </em>additive. Many of the dragons you find in the fields will feel familiar. One dragon in particular is very annoyingly balanced in a way that feels both cheap and disrespectful to the original encounter. To From’s credit, however, Bayle The Dread is very much worth fighting.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>You can fight these guys a whole lot if you'd like. Credit: Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment</figcaption></figure><p>I would be remiss if I did not praise the new gear and spells here. I got through much of the DLC with a weapon called Milady and using an ash called Wing Stance to bleed enemies to death. The hand-to-hand combat weapons are enjoyable, although they feel conservatively balanced to be initially underwhelming. Giant katanas are a welcome touch, as are perfume bottles, which are currently busted the same way Hoarfrost Stomp was at launch. <a href="https://youtu.be/v20jFYM0nLI?si=xPoHbd3f_UzozQMZ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">YouTuber Syrobe discovered that Rolling Sparks ash</a>, when aimed at the ground and with a specific loadout, will decimate any boss in less than 20 seconds. Probably the best addition is the Deflecting Hardtear, a flask upgrade that temporarily buffs timed blocks to behave closer to <em>Sekiro</em>. Considering that <em>Sekiro </em>is From’s best game, and people have <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/3471" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">extensively modded</a> the base game to add <em>Sekiro-</em>style combat, that was a good choice.</p><figure><figcaption>I would be shocked if they don't nerf this Ash of War. Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment</figcaption></figure><p>From games aren’t for everyone of course, but they’re also not for every From fan. They don’t have to be, which is an important part of this. I think <em>Bloodborne </em>and <em>Sekiro </em>are their most finely tuned games, in part because they are scoped much tighter. <em>Shadow of the Erdtree </em>needs to account for so many variables because it’s an extension of <em>Elden Ring</em>, itself extended from the <em>Souls </em>games. There’s a million ways to beat every boss; it is an action RPG<em> </em>after all. Chasing that meta is itself a system to engage with, one that I find fun in the abstract but that has never got me to the same place of pure, placid flow as the Genichiro fight from <em>Sekiro </em>or even many of the fights in <em>Armored Core </em>VI.</p><p>I should stress that I do very much like <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>. There is a lot to praise about it, particularly when it comes to visual design, music and how it adds to the lore, which rank among FromSoftware’s best work. But it is following up on <em>Elden Ring</em>, a once-in-a-decade game that was a singular, impossible achievement when the industry itself seemed devastated by covid. Even if things had gone perfectly, it would be hard to recapture that same sense of grandeur, because the reality is you can’t enter the same Siofra River twice.&nbsp;</p><h2>“Hit them where they’re weakest”</h2><figure><figcaption>Why tell me this? Who do you think I am? Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment</figcaption></figure><p>There is one series of choices in <em>Erdtree </em>that may seem very minor but make me mad every time I think about them. Occasionally in the expansion, you will see messages infrequently left on the ground not by players but by the developers. Alexis Ong noted this in their (quite good)<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-review" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Eurogamer review of the game</a>, but I was not prepared for how inelegant these messages are. One group of them pertain to the behaviors of a very specific group of enemies. I will try to avoid spoiling the area or the enemies themselves, but they behave atypically. “Hide yourself,” “Await your chance,” “crouch in the undergrowth,” “combat is not an option.” Aside from sounding like tips in an Ubisoft open world game, that last bit of advice is categorically wrong in ways that are actively misleading, and not in a playful FromSoft way (several player notes around them advise the correct way to deal with the enemies.). There are other examples, like a lumbering golem with high defense and a huge obvious weak spot on its back. The game politely tells me “Hit them where they’re weakest,” as though I would never figure that out under my own steam. The worst offender I saw was a message that just said “I’ll be damned if there isn’t a way past the wall,” which seemed to nudge me to look for a small hole in the back of the building. I would understand this if it was in a mission critical area, but it’s just some side building with some stuff inside it.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>Who is the audience for this information? Credit: Bandai Namco Entertainment</figcaption></figure><p>These choices, which I am guessing are the result of playtesting, are baffling to me because it goes against so much of From’s design philosophy. Do they not have faith that the notes laid by players are enough? Are they not confident in their design choices, and if not, why resort to a note instead of addressing those choices? And who do they think is reading these notes, hidden in optional content, down labyrinthine paths, in an aggressively challenging 40 dollar expansion that is, itself, hidden inside an optional end game dungeon? Again, it’s a very minor complaint in the grand scheme of things, but it made me severely doubt that From totally knows what they are doing, which I don’t do that often.</p><h2>Sound and Fury</h2><p>The worst part about all of this is the sheer amount of noise adjacent to any criticism of From games. Many people can be normal. But when it does manifest it’s either wildly reductive to the work or, more often, a childish accusation that the critic does not understand or is bad at the game. (I saw this happen in real time about the aforementioned EuroGamer review.) The latter is some Reddit six years ago shit, so much so that it feels quaint. This is annoying because I know firsthand that if you willingly sign up for FromSoft duty at a publication you’re very probably qualified to do it. I know this because I have been on hand for these pre-release. It can be gruelling and I am glad that I have never had to put a number next to any of them. The largest issue is that these games are designed for and react to the ecosystem they are released in, and so going into one of them half blind and under a hard deadline before that equilibrium is established is fundamentally more difficult and limited than the average player will face. This goes doubly so for people who do guides work; they are saints and angels who hold up half of the world.&nbsp;</p><p>But even in ideal conditions, my favorite conversations about these games happen well after their release. I have talked to friends who rank this expansion among their favorite things FromSoftware has ever done, and others who really hated it in the second half. Aside from being living texts, people’s relationships to these games are deeply personal, and I feel better having taken my time with <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>, to have digested it like a big meal, and to think about how it sat with me. I am glad that I can write this without SEO optimization or deadlines. I think these games deserve nuance, but what do I know? I liked <em>Dark Souls 2</em>.</p><p>See? That wasn’t that&nbsp;difficult.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond Good & Evil's new anniversary edition content demands BG&E2 is made]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/beyond-good-evils-new-anniversary-edition-content-demands-bge2-is-made</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beyond-good-evils-new-anniversary-edition-content-demands-bg-e2-is-made.916326/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/beyond-good-evils-new-anniversary-edition-content-demands-bge2-is-made<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>New cutscenes include big reveal.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/NEW-Beyond-Good-%26-Evil-Lore!-!!SPOILERS!!-(20th-Anniversary-Edition)-17-34-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
When will Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 be released? More than two decades on from the launch of Ubisoft's original game, we still don't know - but Beyond Good &amp; Evil's 20th Anniversary Edition now demands that its succesor does arrive, and sooner rather than later. 
</p>
<p>
As well as technical upgrades and a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rayman-originally-featured-in-beyond-good-evil-and-other-development-secrets">deep, fascinating behind-the-scenes developer archive</a>, Ubisoft's new version of Beyond Good &amp; Evil includes fresh story and new cutscenes which directly tie into the publisher's long-held plans for the game's successor. 
</p>
<p>
Characters from Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 (which is set to be a prequel) appear in video diaries showing them interacting with Jade as a young girl. There's also a brand-new cutscene featuring a specific character - and a big reveal regarding their relationship to Jade.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FQg2NCp1bQU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Progress far enough through Beyond Good &amp; Evil's 20th Anniversary Edition and Jade will acquire objects passed down to her from characters seen in some of the trailers for Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 thus far. (You can also acquire some alternate cosmetic options for characters, including the outfit Uncle Pey'j is seen wearing in a previous BG&amp;E2 trailer.) 
</p>
<p>
As a reminder, BG&amp;E2 is set a generation before the original game, with Pey'j and a fresh group of human and animal hybrids living as space pirates aboard the starship Gada. 
</p>
<p>
Crew members such as Knox the Monkey are among those who have left items for Jade, which she can then learn more about via newly-added M-disc collectables. These are narrated by Dakini, the Gada's captain. Most offer brief looks at how each character interacted with the young Jade, though there's confirmation here that chief engineer Callum is not Jade's father (as some fans had speculated).
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="NEW Beyond Good &amp; Evil Lore! !!SPOILERS!! (20th Anniversary Edition)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tw5O5PBIGRs?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>NEW Beyond Good &amp; Evil Lore! !!SPOILERS!! (20th Anniversary Edition)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tw5O5PBIGRs?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tw5O5PBIGRs?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>A compilation of new Beyond Good &amp; Evil story additions, compiled by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tw5O5PBIGRs">Handsum German</a>.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tw5O5PBIGRs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
That said, a further full cutscene can be unlocked featuring Dakini which does offer a big reveal - that she is Jade's mother. For players, this is a sizable moment, though it is revealed through a scene where Jade sees a hologram of her absent parent - and it is not played as a surprise to her. The implication appears to be that Dakini and the rest of the Gada crew are simply elsewhere, and Jade has been left with her uncle for her own safety.
</p>
<p>
So, when will we see these plot threads be picked up on? In January 2023, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/beyond-good-evil-2-remains-vapourware-it-seems">Ubisoft told Eurogamer</a> that "Beyond Good and Evil 2's development is under way and the team is hard at work to deliver on its ambitious promise." Just this month, Ubisoft reconfirmed this statement to Eurogamer, and said the project remained on its schedule.
</p>
<p>Last week, Christian Donlan wrote how he <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/beyond-good-evils-just-got-a-new-edition-and-the-games-always-been-different-every-time-ive-played-it-anyway">viewed Beyond Good &amp; Evil as something of its own sequel</a>, as it remained rewarding to play multiple times. </p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Remembers Team Fortress 2 Exists, But In The Worst Way Possible]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/funko-fusion-pops-figures-tf2-team-fortress-2-dlc-valve-1851570190</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-remembers-team-fortress-2-exists-but-in-the-worst-way-possible.916320/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/funko-fusion-pops-figures-tf2-team-fortress-2-dlc-valve-1851570190<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It’s been over 6 years since<em> Team Fortress 2</em> received a major update. But don’t worry, Valve hasn’t forgotten about its popular class-based FPS franchise. In fact, the <em>Half-Life </em>creators have approved a new <em>TF2 </em>DLC for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/funko-fusion&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/funko-fusion"><em>Funko Fusion</em></a></span><em> </em>aka that Funko Pop-themed video game coming out later this year. Yay...?</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196049" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="134" data-playlist="196049,196653,196909" data-current="196049"><div><p>This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21580.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/funko-fusion-pop-new-game-chucky-jurassic-park-landfill-1850375748&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/funko-fusion-pop-new-game-chucky-jurassic-park-landfill-1850375748"><em>Funko Fusion </em>was announced in April 2023</a></span>. It’s a third-person action-adventure game that plays a bit like the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.1010games.com/news/funko-fusion-arrives-on-consoles-and-pc-september-13th#:~:text=Funko%20Fusion%20is%20the%20debut%20title%20from%2010%3A10%20Games%2C%20a%20studio%20co%2Dfounded%20by%20five%2Dtime%20BAFTA%20award%20winner%20and%20TT%20Games%20founder%20Jon%20Burton%20with%20a%20team%20of%20experienced%20developers%20known%20for%20their%20work%20on%20brick%2Dbased%20games.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.1010games.com/news/funko-fusion-arrives-on-consoles-and-pc-september-13th#:~:text=Funko%20Fusion%20is%20the%20debut%20title%20from%2010%3A10%20Games%2C%20a%20studio%20co%2Dfounded%20by%20five%2Dtime%20BAFTA%20award%20winner%20and%20TT%20Games%20founder%20Jon%20Burton%20with%20a%20team%20of%20experienced%20developers%20known%20for%20their%20work%20on%20brick%2Dbased%20games." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recent Lego games</a></span> but replaces all the cute Lego minifigs with ugly, big-headed Funk Pop figures. Funko Fusion will feature characters and worlds from various movies, TV shows, and games, including <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/funko-fusion-trailer-mummy-nope-jurassic-release-date-1851447102&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/funko-fusion-trailer-mummy-nope-jurassic-release-date-1851447102"><em>Nope, Jurassic Park, Megan, The Thing, Hot Fuzz, The Mummy</em>,</a></span> and more. And now, we know that the beloved characters from<em> Team Fortress 2 </em>will also be playable in this pop-culture fever dream. </p><p>On July 1, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Wario64/status/1807794194511249868&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1807794194511249868" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">as spotted by Wario 64 on Twitter</a></span>, a new<em> Team Fortress 2</em> character DLC pack for <em>Funko Fusion</em> went live on Steam. The new DLC is free for all Steam users and contains playable Funko Pop versions of Heavy, Scout, Medic, and Engineer. Here’s the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/3037360/Funko_Fusion__Team_Fortress_2_Pack/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3037360/Funko_Fusion__Team_Fortress_2_Pack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DLC’s store page description</a></span>: </p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>Packing more punch than the sandvich, this all-action add on is kind of a big deal! Relive some of your favourite Team Fortress 2 moments in Funko Fusion with these characters.</p></blockquote><p>You might be wondering: “Hey, where are all the other characters from <em>TF2</em>?” Or maybe you are asking: “Oh god, why does any of this exist?”</p><p>I can’t answer that last question, but as for your first, it seems Valve and Funko never got around to making figures based on the other characters, like Pyro or Sniper. Weirdly, I don’t think there was ever an official Engineer figure from Funko, but apparently, the devs wanted to include him anyway. Maybe that means the other TF2 characters could eventually arrive in <em>Funko Fusion</em> via a second DLC pack? I know I’ll be waiting intently for that day.</p><p>I don’t think many people would mind Valve approving a <em>TF2 </em>DLC for <em>Funko Fusion</em> if the studio still supported the game in a meaningful way.  However, that isn’t the case—the last major content for <em>Team Fortress 2</em> happened all the way back in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://wiki.teamfortress.com/wiki/Jungle_Inferno_Update&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://wiki.teamfortress.com/wiki/Jungle_Inferno_Update" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 2017</a></span>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/DaysTf2/status/1803545052766990620&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/DaysTf2/status/1803545052766990620" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over 2400 days ago</a></span>. <em>TF2 </em>also has a bot problem, with the annoying bastards constantly ruining matches, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tf2-team-fortress-bots-valve-fan-petition-fix-pc-fixtf2-1851519583&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tf2-team-fortress-bots-valve-fan-petition-fix-pc-fixtf2-1851519583">forcing players to run fan campaigns to get Valve’s attention</a></span>. </p><p>So yeah, for many players, watching <em>TF2 </em>continue to slowly die from a thousand cuts as Valve does little to help or grow the shooter has been a frustrating experience. And then <em>Funko Fusion</em> announces a <em>TF2</em>-themed DLC. It probably feels like rubbing salt in an open wound at this point. </p><p>  <em>Funko Fusion</em> will released on September 13 on PS4, PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and Nintendo Switch. Yes, it seems like it’s also <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-marvel-vs-capcom-mvc2-collection-arcade-switch-ps5-1851546799&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-marvel-vs-capcom-mvc2-collection-arcade-switch-ps5-1851546799">skipping Xbox One</a></span>.</p><p>&nbsp;.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Crazy Taxi Game Takes The Open-World Route With MMO Elements]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-crazy-taxi-game-takes-the-open-world-route-with-mmo-elements/1100-6524616/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-crazy-taxi-game-takes-the-open-world-route-with-mmo-elements.916317/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-crazy-taxi-game-takes-the-open-world-route-with-mmo-elements/1100-6524616/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524616">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sega has confirmed that the new upcoming Crazy Taxi game will feature an open world and contains multiplayer elements.</p><p>In a new <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/new-crazy-taxi-title-will-be-an-open-world-massively-multiplayer-aaa-game-according-to-sega/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">developer interview</a> (translated by Automaton Media), Sega said it is currently working on testing the game's multiplayer compatibility, including MMO elements. The goal here is to experiment with new mechanics for the game while keeping Crazy Taxi's chaotic feel. It boasts photorealistic visuals, and its setting and motifs are inspired by what looks to be California and the west coast. The developers explain that the bright yellow taxis with vibrant blue skies help create an energetic and exciting world. The open-world structure is also inspired by theme parks.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uLQsitFYpg8" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/uLQsitFYpg8" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>While not much new footage was shown in the developer interview, it shows a player driving a police-style taxi while chasing down others in regular taxis, which gives a hint of what multiplayer concepts the team is working with, such as a tag or search-and-destroy kind of mode.</p><p>The new Crazy Taxi game was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sega-announces-new-jet-set-radio-crazy-taxi-and-more-long-awaited-sequels/1100-6519798/" data-ref-id="1100-6519798">announced at The Game Awards 2023</a>, along with new entries in four classic Sega franchises: Jet Set Radio, Shinobi, Streets of Rage, and Golden Axe. So far, platforms and release windows were not revealed.</p><p>The last Crazy Taxi game was 2017's Crazy Taxi Tycoon, a spin-off game on iOS and Android. The last mainline entry was 2002's Crazy Taxi 3: High Roller.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything You Need To Know About Quests From The Infinite Staircase, A D&D Adventure Anthology Blast From The Past]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/everything-you-need-to-know-about-quests-from-infinite-staircase-dd-adventure</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-you-need-to-know-about-quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-a-d-d-adventure-anthology-blast-from-the-past.916308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/everything-you-need-to-know-about-quests-from-infinite-staircase-dd-adventure<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>While we've already heard about the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dungeons-dragons-2024-core-rulebook-pre-order-bonuses-sub-classes-and-dm-assistance">2024 Core Rulebook, including a new <em>Player Handbook, Dungeon Master Guide, and Monster Manual</em></a> as part of the <em>D&amp;D</em> 50th Anniversary celebration next month will also mark the release of a new anthology adventure book; <em>Quests From The Infinite Staircase</em>.</p>
<p>Last week we got to sit down and hear from Justice Arman, Senior Game Designer, about what to expect when you get your hands on this new adventure book.</p>
<p><em>Quests From The Infinte Staircase</em> will be releasing on July 16th with an Early Access release of July 9th. While Early Access has traditionally been two weeks Wizards of the Coast wanted to make sure that players had time to spend with their families over the 4th of July holiday.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/red-dragon-attack_olivier-bernard.jpg?itok=MGmT3UOk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/red-dragon-attack_olivier-bernard.jpg?itok=0gRyQdfg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A dragon attack from the Level 4 adventure in Quests From The Infinite Staircase,&nbsp;Artwork by Olivier Bernard</figcaption></figure><p>"I always try to approach projects with reverence" Arman began "especially if it's an instance where we're taking something that has been and taking it forward to be explored by new players." Arman referenced his work with Planescape as another time that they've been&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"I like to think of it as the first adventure for the 2024 rules"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So much of the work as adventures were created was keeping an eye to the future rule changes.</p>
<h2>Covers and Artwork</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-classic-and-alt-cover.jpg?itok=G9MLeihW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-classic-and-alt-cover.jpg?itok=5K_9kMp4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Quests From The Infinite Staircase Regular cover art by Syd Mills and Alternate art by Patrick Ganas</figcaption></figure><p>On the standard cover you can see Nafas, like Durnan to the Yawning Portal, Nafas is a noble genie and quest giver related to the stories within <em>Quests From The Infinite Staircase</em>. Across the cover you'll see all kinds of elements related to the different adventures within.</p>
<p>Nafas is also shown on the alternate cover art but with a more etherial look. "You can see the texture on his clothing, the whispyness or air" This artist does a lot with wind and because Nafas is an Air Genie they let him run wild letting him sell the idea of him being an "embodiement of etherial winds."</p>

<p>The Infinite Staircase was first introduced in <em>2nd edition Planescape</em> but it was mentioned more recently in the <em>2014 DMG</em>. The book opens with a chapter on what the Infinite Staircase is. The staircase is a unique way to travel the multiverse because there's doorways across this that could lead to anywhere. You just need to happen upon the right doorward to stumble upon the Infinite Staircase</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"They could be adventuring in a dungeon, open a doorway, and are greeted by the [Infinite Staircase]"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The chapter on the staircase itself will go over the features of it like how gravity works, or what happens if you fall off it. There are also examples of what doors might look like and where could they lead. Nafas is also introduced in this chapter.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/nafas-the-air-genie-resident-of-the-infinite-staircase.jpg?itok=mzEOEha5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/nafas-the-air-genie-resident-of-the-infinite-staircase.jpg?itok=rXl8cu4T 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Artwork showing off the air genie qualities of Nafas from within the Senser of Dreams</figcaption></figure><p>The Senser of Dreams is the palace of Nafas where he lives on the Infinite Staircase. He was created when winds from each of the different doors came together spawning him as a noble genie. He's able to hear the many wishes from across the multiverse and tries to make that a reality. Nafas gets his name from the Persian word for Breath, this leans into his Air Genie qualities but also because he is the "Breath of the Multiverse."</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There is a stat block for Nafas, a CR 23 elemental, and can be used for a Pact of the Noble Genie Warlock or he can be used to gain favor for a Wish spell.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The adventures within this anthology will have the characters meeting Nafas who hears wishes, and you'll be asked to complete them. Nafas himself can't leave the Staircase but can ask you to assist, maybe for a reward? Like other anthology adventures you can also use them as stand alone adventures and not use Nafas as a quest giver.</p>
<p>Unlike previous anthology books like <em>Tales From The Yawning Portal, <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c69efd7c-c5a7-4b44-a82c-59be6e59f819" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-and-dragons-candlekeep-mysteries-review">Candlekeep Mysteries</a>, or <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="fd0050cc-2541-4de8-858f-46e54f556d11" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/keys-from-golden-vault">Keys From The Golden Vault</a> </em>the adventures found in <em>Quests From The Infinite Staircase</em> are multi-level adventures that should take a few sessions to get through.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>The First Adventure: <em>The Lost City</em> (1-4)</h3>
<p>The adventure was originally written by Tom Moldvay for the <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="8427f65d-d957-42a6-862a-cedb580b6ba0" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/making-of-original-dungeons-dragons-review-not-history-book-but-museum">Original Dungeons &amp; Dragons</a></em>. Where the players meet a strange faction who is trying to restore their former glory, each with their own masks. The three factions that the players meet allow the players to join.</p>
<p>An update for this adventure is that joining these factions is easier, and not something denoted by gender. Players might get tattoos or masks upon joining. Each faction also has multiple stat blocks.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mage-of-usamigaras_jaqueline-florencio.jpg?itok=XZ8KNwnf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mage-of-usamigaras_jaqueline-florencio.jpg?itok=EgxbrQWW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Artwork of the Mages of Usamigaras by Jaqueline Florencio</figcaption></figure><p>Another update is providing additional guidance for the encounters. Many of them have been rebalanced, because of the differences in CR from then to now, as well as reviewing treasure rewards and including new monsters.</p>
<p>When recreating these encounters there was a lot more thought given to the description of places, characters' motivations, and interaction opportunities with people or places.</p>
<p>The ultimate hook of this adventure is that the party will be trapped in this place and need to work with the different factions to get out, whether that be by working with or against these different cults is up to them.</p>
<h3>The Second Adventure: <em>When A Star Falls</em> - Level 4-6</h3>
<p>This is the first adventure in the book that came from the UK TSR team.</p>
<p>The players here are going to retrieve a fallen star to protect the power of prophecy from evil sages. The original kicked off with an encounter with a Memory Web, when it's slain the memories get released. It's a neat way of delivering a quest to players even if they just want to kill everything.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/derro-lair_yuliya-litvinova.jpg?itok=O7nC1QK2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/derro-lair_yuliya-litvinova.jpg?itok=7VPoxY_D 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Artwork of the Derro and their reanimated corpses performing tasks of manual labor by Yuliya Litvinova</figcaption></figure><p>Players will encounter the Derro, a race that is stealing and reanimating corpses, to have them work for them. The adventure will also have the players meet a clan of deep gnomes.</p>
<p>For players who like having the 'D' in <em>D&amp;D</em> players will encounter a Dragon at the end of the adventure.</p>
<h3>The Third Adventure: <em>Beyond the Crystal Cave</em> - 6-7</h3>
<p>Inspired by William Shakespeare the characters are searching for two paramores who didn't approve of their relationship, very similar to the story of <em>Romeo &amp; Juliet</em>. Back in the 80s it was ahead of its time because you can complete parts of this adventure without any combat.</p>
<p>In the original game the players visit a 'magical garden' prior to the invention of the feywild, this has now been updated. Leprechaun's have been added as denizens of the fey that players will meet. They've been updated to be more akin to mushroom people in red clothing.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-beyond-the-crystal-cave-door-and-unicorns.jpg?itok=LvM0h-ir 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-beyond-the-crystal-cave-door-and-unicorns.jpg?itok=3cudVxRO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Reach 'Beyond the Crystal Cave' through a garden door (Artwork by Axel Defois) and meet philosophical unicorns (Artwork by Katerina Ladon)</figcaption></figure><p>Other fey creatures highlighted include Unicorns. What's interesting is that these are philosophical unicorns that like to ponder, one even has a pipe.</p>
<p>No combat is very much the approach with this adventure and because of that the DM are given a lot of tools for the kinds of conversations.</p>
<h3>The Fourth Adventure: <em>Pharoh </em>- Level 7-9</h3>
<p>In this adventure the characters are reached out to by the ghost of a pharoh. They've been asked to help break a curse on the Pharoh themselves as well as on the land. The party needs to recover two items. The dungeon here is more deadly. New diagrams have been included to help interpret the pyramid in 3D as well as artwork of the different levels.</p>
<p>For the inclusion review pass WOTC reached out to a historical expert in Ancient Egypt to make sure that while the adventure is in tact some aspects of it have been updated. Along the adventure the party will meet other adventurers, as well as a group who is also looking to see the land return to a more prosperous state.</p>

<p>A piece of art shown by Titus Lunter, done physically, is of the Pharoh's boat floating high in the sky.</p>
<h3>The Fifth Adventure: <em>The Lost Caverns of Tsojcanth</em>&nbsp;- Level 9-11</h3>
<p>There is a wilderness exploration that will become before the dungeon, then there's the portion that was included in the tournament version that was released, and then the Greater Caverns.&nbsp;This adventure is tied to a witch who created the Demonomicon. What kinds of weird demons and devils that can be down here</p>
<p>One important encounter is with the daughter of Iggwilv (who D&amp;D fans might be more familiar with calling Tasha), Drelzna There will be over 50 rooms in this adventure, and at level 9 that will take some time…</p>
<h3>The Sixth Adventure: <em>Expedition To The Barrier Peaks</em> - Level 11-13</h3>
<p>Arman's favorite adventure tied with From a Star is the final adventure<em>, Expedition To The Barrier Peaks</em>. The design team wanted to make sure to have an interesting location. With <em>Tomb of Horrors</em> taken the second choice was the strange tech adventure.</p>
<p>Characters reach a crashed space ship where they'll see strange denizens like androids who are training in battle. There is a boxing, martial art, and fencing unit among many others that you'll be meeting.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/training-androids_kevin-glint.jpg?itok=Ug7kTOkX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/training-androids_kevin-glint.jpg?itok=mxmtI17b 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Different androids from Expedition To The Barrier Peaks by Kevin Glint</figcaption></figure><p>In creating these robot designs they intentionally went for a more retro aesthetic with rolling around on treads. It's an awesome adventure "but it's also kind of silly at times".</p>
<p>Players will get to find a variety of tech weapons and items. They could be small spaceship trinkets or charge based tech devices. Arman didn't want to tease too much so didn't delve further. These charged items will use the energy cell.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In terms of weapons there will be laser pistols, needler rifles, and new granades. "If you were scared about giving them to your players you can always decrease the number of energy cells they find as a finite resource."</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/334802.jpg?itok=XzK8Tx7N 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/334802.jpg?itok=_bnR8B-1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Different technological weapons that players will have access to in the Expedition To The Barrier Peaks adventure in D&amp;D</figcaption></figure><p>The maps have been updated to be a little bit smaller, some of the encounters have been moved around to make more memorable encounters in places along players paths, new encounters have also been created for some of the interesting locations.</p>
<p>The original adventure structure was pretty… unstructured, but now there is more of a throughline to help the players have a sense of direction.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"I think this one tilts past Spelljammer into full sci-fi" - Arman</p>
</blockquote>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox "mobile style" dashboard may have been leaked by Top Gear]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-mobile-style-dashboard-may-have-been-leaked-by-top-gear</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-mobile-style-dashboard-may-have-been-leaked-by-top-gear.916305/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-mobile-style-dashboard-may-have-been-leaked-by-top-gear<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-07-01-at-16.41.55.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Top Gear / XboxCore</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><strong>Update, 6.18pm:</strong> In a statement to Eurogamer, Xbox denied it had plans for "a Rimac dashboard", and called the new streamlined dash a "mockup".</p>
<p>"We currently have no plans for an Xbox Rimac dashboard," an Xbox spokesperson said. "For more information about this mockup video, please reach out to the Rimac team."</p>
<p>Original story follows.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Original story, 5pm:</strong>: A Top Gear segment about vehicle manufacturer Rimac may have unwittingly leaked a new mobile Xbox dashboard.</p>
<p>As spotted and uploaded to social media by XboxCore, the reveal came in a recent Top Gear segment about the Robotaxi.</p>
<p>It features a dash that is considerably different to the current iteration most Xbox fans would recognise, its signature "blades" reimagined to better suit a handheld device.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FQg2NCp1bQU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>It's only quick - five seconds, in fact - but here's a quick glimpse of it, as captured by XboxCore:</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>𝗣𝗼𝘀𝘀𝗶𝗯𝗹𝗲 𝗟𝗲𝗮𝗸: Rimac may have leaked a new mobile style 𝗫𝗯𝗼𝘅 𝗗𝗮𝘀𝗵𝗯𝗼𝗮𝗿𝗱 during the Robotaxi reveal on Topgear.</p><p>Would look good on an 𝗫𝗯𝗼𝘅 𝗛𝗮𝗻𝗱𝗵𝗲𝗹𝗱, is all I'm saying! <a href="https://t.co/JJN5UYzLPk">pic.twitter.com/JJN5UYzLPk</a></p></div>— XboxCore (@_XboxNews) <a href="https://twitter.com/_XboxNews/status/1806429468761760039?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 27, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Games like Fortnite, Halo Infinite, and The Finals feature on the front page, although it's unclear what modes and features would be available for those gaming on the go.</p>
<p>The demonstrator says the Xbox functionality in the Robotaxi has been designed "to emulate the feeling that you have in your own living room".</p>
<p>We've reached out to Xbox for comment and will update you just as soon as we know more.</p>
<p>Remember Microsoft's Xbox cloud gaming device, codenamed Keystone? The one that got announced in 2021, was cancelled in its original form a year later, then showed up on Phil Spencer's shelf after that, bamboozling everyone?</p>
<p>Well, if you've ever wondered what it could have looked like in more detail, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-what-xboxs-ill-fated-cloud-gaming-console-might-have-looked-like-according-to-newly-surfaced-patent">a newly surfaced patent might have some answers</a>.</p>
<p>A side-by-side comparison with the "old prototype" version of Keystone that appeared on Phil Spencer's desk in October 2022 also supports that claim, with both the patent and prototype version featuring the same front panel.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[D&D’s Quests from the Infinite Staircase will be backward-compatible, here’s how]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24187596/dnd-quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-backward-compatible-onednd-6th-edition</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/d-d%E2%80%99s-quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-will-be-backward-compatible-here%E2%80%99s-how.916302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24187596/dnd-quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-backward-compatible-onednd-6th-edition<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="nLr6PR">If there’s one thing that <a href="https://www.polygon.com/dnd-dungeons-dragons">Dungeons &amp; Dragons</a> has gotten right in the last decade, it’s anthologies: meaty volumes filled with disparate adventures loosely connected by a common theme. Titles like <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/22315969/dungeons-dragons-candlekeep-mysteries-review"><em>Candlekeep Mysteries</em></a>, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2017/4/4/15107222/dnds-tomb-of-horrors-tips-for-dms-5th-edition-yawning-portal"><em>Tales from the Yawning Portal</em></a>, and the Nebula Award-nominated <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23269854/dnd-journeys-through-the-radiant-citadel-review"><em>Journeys through the Radiant Citadel</em></a> are among this generation’s best official materials. At the dawn of a highly publicized <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24180523/dnd-dungeons-dragons-2024-phb-dmg-core-rulebooks-revealed">revision of the 5th edition ruleset</a>, publisher Wizards of the Coast is making one last stab at greatness. Its final anthology for the current ruleset, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24122063/dnd-dungeons-dragons-quests-infinite-staircase-historians"><em>Quests from the Infinite Staircase</em></a>, is landing at retail on July 16.</p>
<p id="ep2gKc">But as managing game designer Justice Ramin Arman said during a recent press briefing, <em>Infinite Staircase</em> is more than just the last book published for the original 5th edition. It’s also among the first to be published for the game’s <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24177102/dungeons-and-dragons-dnd-core-rulebook-revised-2024-preorder">2024 rules revision</a>. That makes it the exemplar for how the legendary tabletop role-playing game plans to handle the issue of backward compatibility.</p>
<p id="Gwns0U">Historically, every new edition of D&amp;D has pretty much been a clean break, with little but lore connecting one to the next. The result has been a fragmentation of the game’s community on generational fault lines. The most recent example came in 2008, when Wizards launched the 4th edition. Some folks — myself included — liked the 4th edition just fine, and dove headlong into the game and all of its tactical, miniatures-friendly glory. Other folks, not so much. They either moved on to other hobbies or games entirely, or glommed on to Paizo’s <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2016/8/1/12317888/the-story-of-pathfinder-dungeons-and-dragons-most-popular-offspring"><em>Pathfinder</em></a>, which, at its inception at least, hewed very close to the 3rd edition.</p>
<p id="x9rWbi">Wizards, and its corporate owner <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23998290/hasbro-layoffs-before-christmas">Hasbro</a>, would very much like for that not to happen again. Over the last 10 years, it’s managed to catapult the seminal TTRPG back into the public consciousness, growing its player base to what it claims to be new heights. Having only recently weathered the painful fiasco that was <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23587624/non-dnd-dungeons-dragons-ogl-controversy-indie-sales-numbers">the OGL debacle</a>, Wizards would like to change the narrative with this newly revised ruleset. </p>
<p id="Z2bGDN">Arman said that <em>Infinite Staircase</em>’s adventures are “truly playable regardless of whether you’re using” the <em>Player’s Handbook </em>(2014) or the soon-to-be-released <em>Player’s Handbook </em>(2024), and the same goes for the <em>Monster Manual</em> (2014) and the <em>Monster Manual</em> (2025). So how was that accomplished?</p>
<p id="iKcJFa">One of the ways is by changing how adventures give good guidance to Dungeon Masters.</p>
<p id="FfUr4i">“Something I find in older books of ours [is] sometimes when a monster appears, it might have a tactical suggestion or mention a specific monster ability,” Arman said. “A lot of the time that’s great, but if something happens in our [2025] <em>Monster Manual</em> that changes the name of an ability, we don’t want to confuse a DM who [only has access to] the updated version of that text.”</p>
<p id="ZIxeJ7">To be more frank, Arman said that <em>Infinite Staircase</em> won’t call out specific spells or abilities for a particular monster to use in a given encounter. Instead, Wizards will give DMs more broad advice for what they should do instead.</p>
<p id="QIlMRY">“When you see that there’s a Cloaker in this room, the text won’t say, ‘The Cloaker uses Phantasmal Illusions to create three illusory duplicates of itself,’” Arman said. “It might just specify what the Cloaker does without referencing that one-to-one text. What that does is almost give more general guidance in some places that’s more intuitive [than it previously might have been], rather than making it feel like you need to go cross-reference a specific ability or trait [in a book that you don’t have]. Which honestly, I think, makes the adventures more user-friendly, anyway. Because if you’re a new DM picking this text up, you don’t need to know what the abilities of a Cloaker [were in 2014]. You just need to know that it’s hiding, and it attacks.”</p>

<p id="VVcRXD">Is that guidance going to jibe for harried DMs on the go? Hard to say until we’ve seen all of the updated rules — something that won’t be possible until the revised <em>Monster Manual</em>, the last of the three core rulebooks currently in the production pipeline, is finally published in early 2025. But Arman says the team at Wizards is good for it.</p>
<p id="QqBgCh">“Look, I was D&amp;D fan [...] for a long time [before I came to work at Wizards of the Coast], and I recognize there might be a certain subset of people who are holding out [on the revised core rulebooks],” Arman said. “<em>Is it really backwards compatible? Let’s wait until it comes out, and let’s see.</em> But, you know, I encourage you to do that if that’s what you want to do. And if not, you can trust us. Look at the book when it comes out. You can see it on [D&amp;D Beyond], and see for yourself with the previews we’ve already had for the new <em>PHB </em>[on YouTube]. It’s still just as compatible with the new stuff as it is 2014 stuff.”</p>
<p id="Y5L1I8"><em>Quests from the Infinite Staircase</em> will be available at retail on July 16, including a version with a special alternate art cover made available only at local game stores. Those who pre-order the physical and digital bundle directly from Wizards of the Coast will receive their materials two weeks early on July 9. More information on the <em>Player’s Handbook </em>(2024) is rolling out right now on Wizards’ YouTube channel.</p>
<hr id="gsZ02M">


  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Should You Buy The Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance Digital Deluxe Edition?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/shin-megami-tensei-v-deluxe-edition-worth-it-1851570189</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/should-you-buy-the-shin-megami-tensei-v-vengeance-digital-deluxe-edition.916296/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/shin-megami-tensei-v-deluxe-edition-worth-it-1851570189<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In the tradition of many modern games, <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance</em> offers two different versions of the game to purchase: The base game, which costs $59.99 USD, contains the additional demon subquest DLC packs that were made available for the original 2021 release of <em>Shin Megami Tensei V</em> and the Digital Deluxe Edition costs $69.99 USD and includes two new demon subquests alongside three DLC packs that can increase the appearance rate of rare Mitama enemies. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>If you’re totally new to <em>Shin Megami Tensei V</em>, you might be wondering what literally any of that means and whether or not the Digital Deluxe Version is worth it.</p><p>Long story short: The <strong>Digital Deluxe Edition of <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance</em> adds very little in terms of raw gameplay</strong>. The added subquests won’t take you longer than 30 minutes to finish combined even if you go slow and challenge them at really low levels. The Mitama packs don’t add any actual gameplay either. All told, the <strong>Digital Deluxe upgrade mostly exists to make the game easier, even though <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance </em>has several difficulty options to do that already</strong>.</p><h2 id="h5960"><a id="subquests"></a>What do you get in <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance’s </em>DLC subquests?</h2><figure id="" data-id="3dd6896a0832a5f63ff053d6eea8a6a7" data-recommend-id="image://3dd6896a0832a5f63ff053d6eea8a6a7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A bestial-looking character stands with their arms crossed against a gradient background." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A bestial-looking character stands with their arms crossed against a gradient background." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->ATLUS / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3dd6896a0832a5f63ff053d6eea8a6a7" data-recommend-id="image://3dd6896a0832a5f63ff053d6eea8a6a7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A bestial-looking character stands with their arms crossed against a gradient background." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The two new subquests included in the Digital Deluxe edition of <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance </em>are “Sakura Cinders of the East” and “Holy Will and Profane Dissent.” Both of these can be unlocked relatively early in the game, but you’ll likely need to level up a bit to actually complete both of them. “Sakura Cinders of the East” recommends you reach level 47 first, whereas “Holy Will and Profane Dissent” recommends level 75. </p><p>That said, you can absolutely complete these quests at a lower level than what’s recommended if you know how to prepare for them. For more information, check out our dedicated guides for “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/shin-megami-tensei-5-sakura-cinders-of-the-east-1851561744&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/shin-megami-tensei-5-sakura-cinders-of-the-east-1851561744">Sakura Cinders of the East</a></span>” and “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/shin-megami-tensei-5-holy-will-profane-dissent-dlc-1851561953&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/shin-megami-tensei-5-holy-will-profane-dissent-dlc-1851561953">Holy Will and Profane Dissent</a></span>.”</p><p><br><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/shin-megami-tensei-5-sakura-cinders-of-the-east-1851561744&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/shin-megami-tensei-5-sakura-cinders-of-the-east-1851561744">Everything You Need To Know About <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance’s</em> Sakura Cinders Of The East DLC</a></span></p><p>While these quests have a few structural differences, each of their focal points remain the same. “Sakura Cinders of the East” features a new boss battle against Konohana Sakura (Yukiko’s Persona in <em>Persona 4</em>), and “Holy Will and Profane Dissent” makes you face off against Dagda (best known from <em>Shin Megami Tensei IV: Apocalypse</em>). After defeating these foes, they’ll join your party for free, regardless of your current level.</p><p>Konohana Sakura is primarily a healer with an overpowered, unique healing spell called <strong>Sakuya Sakura</strong>. This spell restores the party’s HP, MP, <em>and </em>boosts all stats by one stage. Meanwhile, Dagda is a brutal physical attacker, with the unique attack <strong>Lost Hit </strong>that deals severe damage on top of potentially insta-killing common foes. He won’t necessarily replace all your other damage dealers, but he packs a serious punch.</p><p>Both of these bosses feature unique battle themes, and you’ll have the option to replay each battle by visiting the Virtual Trainer in-game.</p><h2 id="h5961"><a id="mitama"></a>What do the Mitama DLC packs do in <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance</em></h2><figure id="" data-id="866641c36163cd18fd370d3f4b9aad00" data-recommend-id="image://866641c36163cd18fd370d3f4b9aad00" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot shows a combat sequence in Shin Megami Tensei." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows a combat sequence in Shin Megami Tensei." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->ATLUS / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="866641c36163cd18fd370d3f4b9aad00" data-recommend-id="image://866641c36163cd18fd370d3f4b9aad00" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot shows a combat sequence in Shin Megami Tensei." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Also included in the Digital Deluxe version of <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance </em>are three Mitama-related packs. <strong>These include </strong>Mitama Dance of Wealth<strong>, </strong>Mitama Dance of Miracles<strong>, and </strong>Mitama Dance of EXP<strong>.</strong></p><p>For those new to <em>Shin Megami Tensei V</em>, Mitama are rare enemies that drop valuable loot when you defeat them. Rewards include EXP, money, and Glory (the game’s equivalent of skill points). With the Mitama DLC packs turned on, the appearance rates of these enemies goes way up. Within minutes of taking these packs for a spin, I would spot groups of two or three Mitama in the game’s open world within <em>seconds</em>. They appeared so frequently that I quickly started ignoring them; something that I’d never do when they appeared at normal rates.</p><p><strong>Fortunately, you can toggle these three DLC packs off from the in-game main menu</strong>.</p><p>In short, <strong>these picks make grinding much faster in <em>Shin Megami Tensei V</em></strong>. <strong>However, that isn’t necessarily a good thing</strong>. The game’s difficulty curve is a bit lopsided.In the early game, it can be hard to defeat enemies while your roster of demons and spells is so limited. However, once you progress into the midgame and really develop your active party, you can completely overpower even major story bosses. The game only starts to get really tough again once you get into endgame and postgame content, where optional superbosses will push your skills to their limits.</p><p>All of this is to say that the Mitama DLC packs can help smooth over some of the game’s more challenging parts, <strong>but they otherwise really skew the game’s balance towards being way too easy</strong>. I’d say <strong>they’re most valuable to players deep into <em>Shin Megami Tensei</em>’s postgame who want to build absolutely perfect teams</strong>. Otherwise, it’s very obvious that <em>Shin Megami Tensei V</em> was not balanced with this DLC in mind.</p><h2 id="h5962"><a id="worthit"></a>So is the Digital Deluxe version worth the extra 10 bucks?</h2><figure id="" data-id="0a8acd006121acc28dd2703ff9848731" data-recommend-id="image://0a8acd006121acc28dd2703ff9848731" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Two female characters engage in a conversation in the middle of nature." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Two female characters engage in a conversation in the middle of nature." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->ATLUS / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0a8acd006121acc28dd2703ff9848731" data-recommend-id="image://0a8acd006121acc28dd2703ff9848731" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Two female characters engage in a conversation in the middle of nature." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>On one hand, <strong>if you’re absolutely, 100% certain that you want all the DLC in <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance</em>, then it’s technically better to get the Digital Deluxe version</strong>. The two subquest DLCs will run you $5 each, and the Mitama packs are $3 each. That’s $19 all together, or you can get an All-In-One bundle after purchasing for $15. Either approach will run you more money than getting the Digital Deluxe version for $10 more.</p><p><strong>Otherwise, I frankly don’t think the Digital Deluxe version is worth the money</strong>. These DLC packs primarily exist to make the game easier, which players can already do via the in-game difficulty settings. As it is, the DLC demons from the game’s original release are here, and they <em>already </em>offer huge power boosts to your team when you recruit them. The Mitama packs in particular hurt the overall experience more than they help, since they let you level up <em>way </em>too fast. This in turn minimizes the excitement you’d otherwise feel from spotting rare enemies in the wild.</p><p>Granted, the two new demons on offer here <em>do </em>have some sentimental value to <em>Shin Megami Tensei </em>fans. I’m not here to judge anyone who purchases things that make them happy. I’m personally of the mind that two characters shouldn’t have been paywalled to begin with, but maybe that’s just the cost of business in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/game-industry-layoffs-how-many-2024-unity-twitch-1851155818&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/game-industry-layoffs-how-many-2024-unity-twitch-1851155818">an extremely hostile industry</a></span>.</p><p>Don’t get me wrong, <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance </em>is a <em>fantastic </em>game. The entertainment it has provided me has easily surpassed several games I’ve spent $70 on. If you’d just like to show Atlus the extra support and enjoy a couple extra demons as fanservice, I won’t stop you. Just make sure to tune up the difficulty higher than you normally would. After fighting your fifth Mitama in just a couple of minutes, you’ll be <em>begging </em>for some semblance of challenge again.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Acolyte Episode 3 Review: Star Wars Finds Religion In A Whole New Way]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/acolyte-episode-3-review-force-1851570042</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-acolyte-episode-3-review-star-wars-finds-religion-in-a-whole-new-way.916293/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/acolyte-episode-3-review-force-1851570042<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Just because you can grab an audience with a name like <em>Star Wars</em> doesn’t mean you can keep their attention. With its third episode, <em>The Acolyte</em> introduces a theme so big and so important—religion—that if the show doesn’t take it seriously in the coming episodes, it may lose mine.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194617" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Fortnite Introduces Force Abilities In Latest Star Wars Collab" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="194617,193897,194499" data-current="194617"><div><p>Fortnite Introduces Force Abilities In Latest Star Wars Collab</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20078.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Episode 3 spends most of its time giving us the backstory of Brendok, the homeworld of twin sisters Mae and Osha. Here, we get to see a society of women—the equivalent of witches—who are experts on the Force. Mae and Osha are the only children in their tribe, and when Jedi Masters Indara (Carrie-Anne Moss), Sol (Lee Jung-jae), Torbin (Dean-Charles Chapman), and Kelnacca (Joonas Suotamo) arrive to test the kids for potential Jedi knighthood, we learn that they have no father. They were conceived through some secret use of the Force, and their mothers don’t want the Jedi to find out the details.<br></p><p>This secret is a <em>massive</em> development for the show, and not simply because <em>Star Wars</em> fans will connect this birth and Mae &amp; Osha’s psychokinetic link to Rey and Kylo Ren’s coupling decades later, referred to as a “Dyad” in the Force by Emperor Palpatine. No, fandom-centric speculation is not what matters to me. I’m the fan that’s looking at where George Lucas found his inspiration for the Force itself, and why this challenges the real-world ancient philosophies upon which the entirety of <em>Star Wars</em> is based. <br></p><figure id="" data-id="93e82253662388dd9b036dfca6890c68" data-recommend-id="image://93e82253662388dd9b036dfca6890c68" data-format="jpg" data-width="2857" data-height="1608" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jodie Turner-Smith as Mother Aniseya in The Acolyte." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Jodie Turner-Smith as Mother Aniseya in The Acolyte." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Lucasfilm</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="93e82253662388dd9b036dfca6890c68" data-recommend-id="image://93e82253662388dd9b036dfca6890c68" data-format="jpg" data-width="2857" data-height="1608" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jodie Turner-Smith as Mother Aniseya in The Acolyte." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>See, the Force was inspired specifically by Mo Pai Nei Kung, an ancient energy manipulation method that involves balancing the Yin and Yang (“soft” and “hard,” aka Light and Dark) energies within the practitioner’s body to influence the external world. A man named John Chang was well known to create different kinesis effects, such as burning paper by hovering his hand over it (see <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/0AZU8S9F0yI?si=pBbYyx8gBy2RCtwL&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/0AZU8S9F0yI?si=pBbYyx8gBy2RCtwL" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the VHS videos uploaded to YouTube</a></span>).<br></p><p>It doesn’t matter if you train Nei Kung (I teach it), it doesn’t matter if you believe in “chi” (aka “qi”). If you’re invested in <em>Star Wars</em>, you’re invested in a narrative universe that references real-world philosophies and modalities, especially Eastern ones, that are senior to and related to many ideas in Western fables, fairy tales and religious parables. It doesn’t take an academic to see how <em>Star Wars</em> previously referenced the Immaculate Conception for Anakin Skywalker’s birth without a father in <em>Attack of the Clones</em>. Now, <em>The Acolyte</em> is connecting the chi-inspired Force to Mae and Osha’s unique birth, and further frames the method of achieving a “miracle” as what can be perceived as witchcraft.<br></p><p>As someone who has a profound amount of interest in and respect for all religious paths, I find this creative choice incredibly compelling. Science fiction (we shouldn’t forget that that’s what <em>Star Wars</em> is) is <em>the genre</em> to challenge old ideas and catalyze us to look at things from a new perspective. Whether it’s framing ancient energy manipulation practices as the Force, or the concept of spontaneous birth that is found in several religions from Christianity to Hinduism, <em>The Acolyte</em> is raising its profile by using fiction to re-examine these beliefs.<br></p><p>I truly hope future episodes can handle the weight of these subjects with increasing grace and maturity. My fear is that the wisdom required to do so is quite rare, and that the series may chicken out of bold conclusions in favor of the easy way out for <em>Star Wars</em> writing: either lightsaber battles or a space chase. Although, neither of those would be too bad…&nbsp;</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon II adds Xbox Series, Xbox One versions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/darkest-dungeon-ii-adds-xbox-series-xbox-one-versions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/darkest-dungeon-ii-adds-xbox-series-xbox-one-versions.916290/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/darkest-dungeon-ii-adds-xbox-series-xbox-one-versions<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out alongside PlayStation and Switch versions on July 15.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Turn-based roguelike <a title="Genres > RPG [16,390 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Darkest Dungeon II [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/darkest-dungeon-ii">Darkest Dungeon II</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,640 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,303 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> alongside its <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/04/darkest-dungeon-ii-coming-to-ps5-ps4-on-july-15">previously</a> <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/darkest-dungeon-ii-adds-switch-version">announced</a> PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and Switch versions on July 15 for $39.99, developer <a title="Companies > Red Hook Studios [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/red-hook-studios">Red Hook Studios</a> announced. Pre-orders are available now via <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/darkest-dungeon-ii/9n0q3tgwhg1f" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>. <span id="more-896120"></span></p><p><em>Darkest Dungeon II</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1940340/Darkest_Dungeon_II/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/product/darkest-dungeon-2/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> on October 26, 2021, followed by a full release on May 8, 2023.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Red Hook Studios:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Darkest Dungeon II</em> is a turn-based roguelike road trip of the damned. Form a party, equip your stagecoach, and set off across the decaying landscape on a last gasp quest to avert the apocalypse. The greatest dangers you face, however, may come from within…</p><p><a title="Genres > Roguelike [227 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">Roguelike</a> Runs, Each With Its Own Emerging Story: Each expedition lasts from 30 minutes to several hours. Even an untimely end will arm you with resources that can be spent to improve your next journey.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Unforgettable Heroes</strong> – Uncover and experience the tragic origin stories of each hero. Unlock their full potential via new skills, paths, items, and more.</li><li><strong>The Altar of Hope</strong> – Engage with a massive system of upgrades and boons that opens up new strategies for each expedition. Choose what’s important to you as you formulate your assaults on the Mountain.</li><li><strong>The Affinity System</strong> – As travels progress, heroes bond with each other or develop animosity, leading to desperately needed combat synergies or journey-ending dysfunction. <a title="Series > Mana [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge their stress and interaction to keep the team together until the bitter end.</li><li><strong>Nightmarish Environs</strong> – From the burning Sprawl to the diseased Foetor, the long road to the Mountain will challenge your strategies and your endurance. Explore five distinct regions, each with their own unique creatures and challenges.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,348 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Darkest Dungeon II - Xbox Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HFp_tFFqbQY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manor Lords Publisher's RTS Cataclismo Delays Release, Adopts Early Access]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cataclismo-delayed-early-access</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/manor-lords-publishers-rts-cataclismo-delays-release-adopts-early-access.916269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cataclismo-delayed-early-access<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Cataclismo</em>, an upcoming RTS from&nbsp;<em>Manor Lords&nbsp;</em>publisher Hooded Horse, has been delayed by a few days, and the decision has also been made to release the game in Early Access.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1422440/view/4222769301380727215" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam news post announcing the changes</a>, Hooded Horse and developer Digital Sun say that the delay, which will see the game launching on July 22nd, is intended to "get everything in place for a successful [Early Access] launch".</p>
<p>The devs also say that Early Access was chosen to "polish the game alongside our community", calling this model "the perfect tool" to ensure that the finished product is as good as it can be, a position with which I'm sure&nbsp;<em>No Rest for the Wicked</em>'s <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/no-rest-for-wicked-ceo-early-access-comments">Thomas Mahler would agree</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cataclismo-delayed-early-access-siege.jpg?itok=qT4QjPuY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cataclismo-delayed-early-access-siege.jpg?itok=Ma4PNYYT 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Siege RTS&nbsp;<em>Cataclismo&nbsp;</em>is being pushed back a few days.</figcaption></figure><p>Although it's not explicitly mentioned, it's not hard to imagine that Hooded Horse and Digital Sun have chosen to launch&nbsp;<em>Cataclismo&nbsp;</em>into Early Access partially as a result of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/manor-lords-sales-two-million">success of the publisher's city-builder&nbsp;<em>Manor Lords</em></a>.</p>
<p>The two studios say that the Early Access period for&nbsp;<em>Cataclismo&nbsp;</em>will be "short", and it sounds like the game will have plenty of stuff to do.</p>
<p>At launch,&nbsp;<em>Cataclismo&nbsp;</em>will feature a campaign complete with a tutorial and eleven levels, with more coming before the 1.0 launch. It'll also offer a skirmish mode across "two different levels and biomes", as well as an endless play mode and a level editor.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Cataclismo</em>, it's a hybrid real-time strategy and tower defense game created by the folks behind roguelike shop management sim&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter</em>.</p>
<p>During the day, you'll build up your defenses and gather resources with "Lego-inspired mechanics", and by night, you'll use the traps, fortifications, and troops you've amassed to defend your stronghold from encroaching horrors.</p>
<p><em>Cataclismo&nbsp;</em>will boast a realistic physics model that allows you to crush enemies beneath falling bricks, and when the full release arrives, it'll also offer a full 30-hour campaign "with VA and cutscenes".</p>
<p>You'll be able to check out&nbsp;<em>Cataclismo&nbsp;</em>when it launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1422440/Cataclismo/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC via Steam Early Access</a> on July 22nd. Stay tuned for more on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>