<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 17:18:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Developer League of Geeks goes into hibernation due to economic situation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/12/developer-league-of-geeks-goes-into-hibernation-due-to-economic-situation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/developer-league-of-geeks-goes-into-hibernation-due-to-economic-situation.899490/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/12/developer-league-of-geeks-goes-into-hibernation-due-to-economic-situation/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The game developer League of Geeks, known for creating titles such as Armello, Solium Infernum, and Jumplight Odyssey, has announced an indefinite hibernation. This move is a response to the economic uncertainties within the industry and comes after the company reduced its staff by 50% at the end of 2023.</p>
<p><iframe title="Solium Infernum - Gameplay Reveal" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IvQA1P3Akrk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The complete statement from Co-founders and Directors Trent, Blake &amp; Ty can be read below.</p>
<p><em>“With over 13 years under our belt as an entirely independent studio, and the economic situation in games being what it is right now, we have made the decision to put LoG into hibernation for the foreseeable future and take some extended time off. The vast majority of our team have moved on to exciting new endeavours and those who remain are going to take a well deserved break over the next few months.</em></p>
<p><em>We’re not sure when (or if) we will resurrect this great beast, but we’re incredibly proud of all we’ve achieved, both in the experiences we’ve crafted together, the great developers who made LoG a world-class development environment, the peers we inspired along the way, and of course, those community members who believed in what we made, how we made it, and supported us fiercely in those convictions. Now it’s time for rest, some play, and other opportunities. As for our games… They will remain online and will be supported during this period.</em></p>

<p><em><strong>Solium Infernum</strong> remains in Open Critic’s Top 10 games of 2024 (#20 on Metacritic!), and we are incredibly proud of where the game is now. Unfortunately, its sales revenue cannot fund further active development or DLC. However, we do love our Hellish strategy game and have a couple of treats up our sleeve still, some bug fixes and minor content. So I’m sure we’ll find an opportunity to get a lil update or two out.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Jumplight Odyssey</strong> has, as of this point, not found workable and timely investment that would reinstate development on the title. We would love nothing more than to see this project finished, but unfortunately, development will remain on hiatus. We are aiming to bring it out of Early Access at some point in the next 12 months. This is unlikely to be the fully realised v1.0 release we had originally planned, though we will try to find some way to tuck the game in with our limited, remaining resources. In brighter news, we will be releasing the Jumplight Odyssey OST for FREE, complete with expanded and remastered tracks, on Steam (and other platforms) in the next week or so!</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Armello</strong> will continue to cruise along as it has for the past few years, rotating seasonal content and providing a hit of heroism for our furry adventurers. The Armello Board Game won’t be affected in any way by this. That’s in the caring hands (paws?) of King of the Castle Games and we’re around for anything they need. Though admittedly, they’re all over it! You can find posts with more information relevant to each game in their respective Steam communities.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://leagueofgeeks.com/blog#gone-fishin">League of Geeks</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metallica headlines Fortnite, as it introduces a new music-themed battle mode and fresh concert]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/metallica-headlines-fortnite-as-it-introduces-a-new-music-themed-battle-mode-and-fresh-concert</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metallica-headlines-fortnite-as-it-introduces-a-new-music-themed-battle-mode-and-fresh-concert.899487/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/metallica-headlines-fortnite-as-it-introduces-a-new-music-themed-battle-mode-and-fresh-concert<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
The next musical stars to join Fortnite are Metallica, via an all-encompassing arrival set to land across the game's various modes. 
</p>
<p>
Most obviously, Metallica will headline the game's next Fortnite Festival season - the Rock Band-esque mode made by Harmonix. Not only will Metallica's four members be unlockable as skins in the mode's next Festival Pass, but tomorrow's game update notably adds a new competitive way to play Festival: Battle Stage. 
</p>
<p>
Here, 16 players face off against each other via a song chosen at random, with your Overdrive operating as an attack power to take other players down a peg. Or, you can team up with a four-person party of friends and pick specific tunes to fight over.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fortnite Festival - Battle Stage Trailer (feat. Metallica)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JmVDgkr1WIM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fortnite Festival - Battle Stage Trailer (feat. Metallica)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JmVDgkr1WIM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JmVDgkr1WIM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Metallica joins Fortnite, as the game's new Battle Stage music mode arrives.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JmVDgkr1WIM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Metallica will also feature in what sounds like an old-school Fortnite music concert - it's been a while! - set to be made available at a range of times over the weekend of 22nd and 23rd June. 
</p>
<p>
This means if you're busy, or if you want to replay the event, you can log in at 7pm or 10pm UK time on Saturday 22nd, or 4am, 3pm, 7pm or 10pm UK time on Sunday 23rd to watch. 
</p>
<p>
In battle royale, mythic guitar items will be added which look to be a traversal item. "Use one to create a lightning arc in the sky that your squadmates can ride," Epic Games says. "One your descent, come crashing down to bring the beginning of an enemy's end." Each match's lategame Loot Island will also now rift in with a Metallica look, inspired by the band's stage on the M72 World Tour. 
</p>
<p>
And finally, there's a new Rocket Racing track, appropriately themed with volcanic lava. New quests will also offer a Metallica-themed car.
</p>
<p>
As you'd expect, plenty of Metallica music is coming to the game to buy as Jam Tracks, playable in most modes. As of tomorrow's update, Jam Tracks can also finally become playable as lobby tunes - which is music to my ears.
</p>




        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS Plus Extra/Premium Adds Monster Hunter Rise, Crusader Kings III, and More in June]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ps-plus-extra-premium-june-2024-monster-hunter-rise-crusader-kings/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps-plus-extra-premium-adds-monster-hunter-rise-crusader-kings-iii-and-more-in-june.899484/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ps-plus-extra-premium-june-2024-monster-hunter-rise-crusader-kings/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In early June, Sony offered <a href="https://wccftech.com/ps-plus-essential-june-2024-spongebob-extra-premium-bonus-titles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some “bonus” titles</a> for <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/ps-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS Plus Extra and Premium subscribers</a>, but we’re also getting a regular mid-month update as well. Extra subscribers can look forward to Monster Hunter Rise, Crusader Kings III, Football Manager 2024, Far Cry 4, and more. Meanwhile, Premium subscribers can jump into Daxter, Lego Star Wars II, and more.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/WCCFpsplus26.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Here are your <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/12/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-june-monster-hunter-rise-football-manager-2024-crusader-kings-iii-after-us-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS Plus Extra headliners for June</a>…</p>
<p><em><strong>Monster Hunter Rise</strong> (PS4, PS5)</em></p>
<p><em>From Wccftech’s review – “Once players get past the poor onboarding experience, Monster Hunter Rise might offer the series' best entry for first time players while series veterans will fly over the competition with the new Wirebug mechanics. The ways that Capcom has streamlined the onboarding and pre-hunt experiences to give players more time to focus on the actual hunt itself show that Capcom wants to respect the player's time, especially when they're trying to get three friends together for an afternoon of hunting.”</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Crusader Kings III</strong> (PS5)</em></p>
<p><em>From Wccftech’s review – “Crusader Kings III pulls off a difficult dual victory, bringing a new level of depth, charm, and polish to the franchise, while also making it far more approachable than it’s been before. Some aspects of Crusader Kings III still aren’t as user-friendly as they could be, but overall, this is a worthy heir to the throne.”</em></p>
<p>Here are the other games available to PS Plus Extra subscribers this month:</p>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>After Us</strong> (PS5)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Anno 1800</strong> (PS5)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Far Cry 4</strong> (PS4)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Football Manager 2024</strong> (PS5)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Lego The Hobbit</strong> (PS4)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Lego The Incredibles</strong> (PS4)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Monster Energy Supercross – The Official Videogame 6</strong> (PS4, PS5)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Police Simulator: Patrol Officers</strong> (PS4, PS5)</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Meanwhile, here are your PS Plus Premium Classics and a bonus PS VR2 game:</p>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Kayak VR: Mirage</strong> (PS VR2)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Lego Star Wars II: The Original Trilogy</strong> (PS4, PS5)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Ghosthunter</strong> (PS4, PS5)</em></li>
<li><em><strong>Daxter</strong> (PS4, PS5)</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Sony now offers three tiers of PS Plus – Essential, Extra, and Premium.&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/ps-plus-prices-increasing-all-tiers-september-2023-ps-plus-essential-saints-row/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The price for all three tiers have gone up</a>&nbsp;for those subscribing for a year, but the monthly cost hasn’t changed. You can&nbsp;<a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-ca/ps-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">explore the games available via each tier and sign up here</a>.</p>
<p>The new PS Plus Extra/Premium games get added to the collection on June 18. What PS Plus games are you planning to play this month?</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metallica Is Taking Over Fortnite In Next Update]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fortnite-metallica-content-music-festival-pass-battle-1851535494</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metallica-is-taking-over-fortnite-in-next-update.899481/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/fortnite-metallica-content-music-festival-pass-battle-1851535494<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fortnite-festival-season-3-guitar-controller-support-pc-1851429714&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-festival-season-3-guitar-controller-support-pc-1851429714"><em>Fortnite</em></a></span>’s next few updates are going to be adding a lot of Metallica to Epic’s online F2P battle royale, including the band members themselves, some of the group’s best songs, and even a new mode all about battling other players using music. </p><div data-video-id="196395" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="80" data-playlist="196395,191683,194440" data-current="196395"><div><p>The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21945.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>The first part of this <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/news/metallica-lights-up-fortnite-with-a-new-music-experience-festival-season-and-more&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/metallica-lights-up-fortnite-with-a-new-music-experience-festival-season-and-more" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">big Metallica x <em>Fortnite </em>event</a></span> begins on June 13 with <em>Fortnite Festival </em>- Season 4. This new season of the rhythm game adds six new Metallica songs to buy and play, including “Enter Sandman,” “Fuel,” and “Ride The Lighting.” Epic says more songs from the band will be added over the course of the season, too. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-festival-season-4-prepare-for-battle-with-metallica&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-festival-season-4-prepare-for-battle-with-metallica" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As part of this new <em>Festival </em>season</a></span>, players will gain access to a new Festival Pass. The premium track features all four Metallica band members as unlockable and playable skins. Finally, James Hetfield can fight Goku and Darth Vader. The premium track also includes access to a new Jam Track, Metallica’s “One.”</p><p>As part of this Metallica-themed <em>Festival </em>season, Epic has added a new mode: The Battle Stage. In this new mode, 16 players all play through the same four musical tracks in a big battle concert. Play better to unlock attacks that you can shoot at other musicians to throw them off their game. Play well enough and you can outlast everyone and win. The new mode sounds like a lot of fun and Epic says it will stick around even after Metallica has left once this <em>Festival</em> season ends in August. </p><p><em>Fortnite</em>’s new <em>Festival </em>update has also unlocked the ability for players to use <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fortnite-lobby-music-video-song-epic-games-lyrics-1851443904&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-lobby-music-video-song-epic-games-lyrics-1851443904">Jam Tracks they own as lobby music</a></span> which is a small thing, sure, but something I’m happy about. Now I can have the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fortnite-star-wars-may-4th-update-lando-chewbacca-lego-1851449880&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-star-wars-may-4th-update-lando-chewbacca-lego-1851449880">Cantina song from<em> Star Wars</em></a></span> as my lobby music. </p><h2 id="h20656"><a id=""></a>There’s <em>even more </em>Metallica stuff coming to <em>Fortnite</em></h2><p>Also coming in the June 13 update: Metallica is getting a <em>Rocket Racing-</em>themed track, car, and Lego versions of each band member, too. I told you in the headline that Metallica is taking over <em>Fortnite</em>. I wasn’t lying! </p><p>But wait, there’s more! You’ll be able to find Metallica on the <em>Fortnite </em>battle royale map and watch holographic versions of the band rock out as you get sniped by a 14-year-old hiding in a bush. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/news/metallica-lights-up-fortnite-with-a-new-music-experience-festival-season-and-more#:~:text=SATURDAY%2C%20JUNE%2022%2C%202024&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/metallica-lights-up-fortnite-with-a-new-music-experience-festival-season-and-more#:~:text=SATURDAY%2C%20JUNE%2022%2C%202024" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">And on June 22 and June 23</a></span>, <em>Fortnite </em>will be hosting a Metallica concert inside the game. We’ve seen this kind of thing before and it appears that, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/RiM0moNk74o&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/RiM0moNk74o" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">like those past concerts</a></span>, the Metallica one will happen a few times throughout the two-day event. </p><p>I think that’s all the Metallica content coming to <em>Fortnite</em>. Boy, I really hope you like the band or at least don’t mind them. If not, well...most of this stuff is leaving on August 16. So it won’t be around forever at least.</p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astro Bot First Hands-On Preview: Worlds of Fun]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/astro-bot-first-hands-on-preview-worlds-of-fun</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/astro-bot-first-hands-on-preview-worlds-of-fun.899478/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/astro-bot-first-hands-on-preview-worlds-of-fun<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Did you like Astro’s Playroom? I sure did. In fact, the meanest thing I can say about it is that there wasn’t enough of it – I finished its five levels and final boss battle within a single evening. But as if in response to my hunger for more of PlayStation’s newest mascot, developer Team Asobi has opened the floodgates in Astro Bot, a game that looks to be everything I loved about the Playroom, but galaxies more of it.</p><p>I played a 45-minute demo of Astro Bot at Summer Game Fest Play Days over the weekend, and what a blast it was! What Astro’s Playroom got right, and what Astro Bot continues to absolutely nail, is making it wildly fun to just run around and be Astro. Everything is tuned precisely to feel just right: his movement speed, his jumping height and distance, the exact way he smashes little crates and zaps enemies with feet lasers, the density of obstacles in my path and the exact way each stage follows a linear path but branches and loops back on itself to allow room for secrets. Running through a single level in Astro Bot clicks my brain cells into a flow state where I am constantly moving and always have an objective in mind, but don’t feel overwhelmed by my options. I love smashing stuff; I love jumping over stuff; I love bouncing off stuff.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Where Astro’s Playroom had five major levels themed loosely around PlayStation 5 components, Astro Bot sends our little hero cruising through space atop a giant DualSense controller, hopping from planet to planet in search of his lost bot buddies. I’m told Astro Bot has around 80 levels to visit, all bursting with hidden bots, puzzle pieces, boss battles, goofy power-ups, coins, and little challenges leading to delightful secrets.</p><p>I saw five levels in my playthrough. One, a lush area with clear pools, pink flamingos, and rolling green hills in the distance, was full of water-based mechanics. I swam through little reefs of colorful fish, slid down a giant water slide, and unzipped giant water bubbles to unleash the flood inside. There, Astro could inflate like a little robot bubble to drift quickly up to higher areas, a skill especially useful underwater. In another level themed around a construction zone, Astro flung paint around to uncover hidden platforms, sucked up metal items with giant magnets, and equipped some kind of dog jetpack to zoom across long distances his usual hover wouldn’t normally clear. </p><p>Another level centered around a boss fight with a giant octopus wearing boxing gloves. To compensate, I got ahold of a pair of my own frog-themed gloves that let Astro punch enemies at a distance and swing like a monkey from certain overhangs. Another (wildly minor) criticism I had of Astro’s Playroom was that some of its power-up/vehicle sections frustrated me due to cumbersome movement mechanics as they tried to showcase the PS5’s unique features. Freed from that obligation, Astro Bot is better able to focus on giving me new toys that are just pure fun to use. Quick, solid, alternating punches using R1 and R2 made me feel like I was Goku-fighting the octopus, and I sent him packing.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Astro Bot Official Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>The final two stages I tried were special challenge levels designed to test my platforming abilities. One of them tested my ability to dodge rapidly spinning enemies on crumbling platforms, while another forced me to execute sections of tricky jumps in limited periods of time. I managed to finish both in the demo time allotted, though not without some struggle on the first one. It’s hard to gauge just from these two stages how high the difficulty of Astro Bot’s platforming will eventually scale. But what pleased me the most about them was how the fast respawn time and overall brevity of the stages made trying again and again and again so easy and enjoyable. I found myself thinking, “Just one more try,” more than once, only to try two, three, ten more times. There was a moment toward the end of the demo where I stopped, looked around, and realized everyone else had left the room already. Just one more try…and I nailed it.</p><p>And yes, Astro Bot looks to be a nostalgia-fest. Sure, when compared to Playroom, I think Astro Bot seems a bit more focused on being an excellent platformer rather than reveling in PlayStation history. But that’s to its benefit - levels like the watery/flamingo one don’t need to have references to Bloodborne every two feet to keep me happy. Rather, Astro Bot’s PlayStation celebration largely resides with the bots I’m rescuing through each level, some of whom are dressed up like favorites such as Ratchet, Rivet, PaRappa, and more. And I have reason to suspect fans of PlayStation’s biggest franchises might be well-rewarded for finishing certain levels. When I beat the octopus, for instance, I rescued a bot pair clad as Kratos and Atreus, who then flew off to an icy-looking planet I couldn’t access in the demo. If my reading is right, we might be in for a full-blown God of War-themed level in the full game, and perhaps more besides.</p><p>When Team Asobi first started making the Astro games, it was easy for me to mentally make a shorthand comparison of their work to Nintendo’s long history of platformers. Both have similar throughlines, especially with how the two make games that feel like touchable, experimental toys and how both emphasize playfulness, joy, and surprise. But I’m pretty well convinced Team Asobi is beyond chasing Nintendo’s pedigree. Built on the foundation of Astro’s Playroom, Astro Bot seemed poised to elevate the Astro games into a league all their own, if they weren’t there already. You’re telling me they’ve got 80 levels of what I just played? Sign me up to fly with Astro and crew.</p><p><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astro Bot Will Get Free Post-Launch DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/astro-bot-will-get-free-post-launch-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/astro-bot-will-get-free-post-launch-dlc.899472/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/astro-bot-will-get-free-post-launch-dlc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Mostly challenge levels, but maybe some surprises too.</h2></div><section><p>PlayStation’s upcoming platforming celebration, Astro Bot, is already launching with roughly 80 levels. But there will be even more on the way later, via free DLC.</p><p>Speaking to IGN, Team Asobi studio head Nicolas Doucet told us there were plans for eventual free DLC for Astro Bot, coming “soon” after launch. He says it will be based around adding more challenge levels to the game – shorter levels focused on specific platforming challenges – but that won’t be the only component.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Doucet didn’t share more details about what else might be coming in these DLC additions, but we can throw some guesses out there. For one, both of the challenge levels we played in the preview were centered around rescuing a bot in a PlayStation character costume, so it only seems logical that more DLC means more character cameos that won’t appear in the base game. Given that there are apparently around 150 PlayStation character cameos already, it will be interesting to see how deep the cuts go here.</p><p>Beyond that, we can hope that we’ll also see more large, character-themed levels both in the base game and the DLC. While playing Astro Bot in our hands-on preview, we rescued a Kratos and Atreus bot via a boss battle, which led to them flying off to an ice-covered world. For this reason, we suspect there will be at least one God of War-themed level in Astro Bot, and perhaps even more character-themed levels beyond that.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Astro Bot Official Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>“The hammer and the two Odin's Ravens kind of give it away, but what happens inside that world is TBD,” Doucet said. “Please play it when it comes out.”</p><p>Doucet told us that PlayStation “completely opened the doors” to whatever characters Team Asobi wanted to include in the game, and internal studios even sent requests pouring in for their characters to be featured. In our demo, we saw Ratchet and Rivet, PaRappa, Kratos, Atreus, Jak, and the Traveler from Journey. I’m told PaRappa’s pal Lammy also made an appearance, but we missed her.</p><p>Astro Bot getting free DLC makes sense, as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/astros-playroom-gets-surprise-update-ahead-of-astro-bots-release"><u>Astro’s Playroom also got a little love recently</u></a> in celebration of the Astro Bot announcement. If you open up Astro’s Playroom now, a number of new objectives have cropped up throughout its PlayStation-themed worlds, all leading up to a countdown to Astro Bot’s September 6 release date.</p><p>You can catch up on the rest of our interview with Doucet from Summer Game Fest <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-astro-bots-developers-are-still-pushing-the-limits-of-ps5-tech">right here</a>, as well as our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/astro-bot-first-hands-on-preview-worlds-of-fun">full hands-on preview of Astro Bot</a>.</p><p><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds: The First Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-the-first-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-the-first-preview.899466/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-the-first-preview<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>If Monster Hunter World was the first huge, noticeable evolution of the long-running series, Wilds is shaping up to be a clear, exciting progression that takes many of World’s surprising change-ups a step further. Where World disposed of individual zones in each region, Wilds removes loading screens between each region and its home-base town, now located right on the map itself; where World allowed you to eat and change equipment at camp, Wilds additionally lets you pop up a portable tent; and where World introduced voiceovers to its human companions, Wilds gives voices to the Felyne Palicos. I learned all of this and more in a closed-door, hands-off demo and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-monster-hunter-wilds-devs-answer-all-of-our-questions-sgf-2024">interview with the Monster Hunter Wilds developers</a> at Summer Game Fest. </p><p>As is tradition, the hunt I watched started off in town, where you can eat, manage your inventory, and craft weapons and armor with the encouraging <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-fans-love-gemma-the-smithy-so-much-that-its-now-tagged-as-a-dating-sim-on-steam">new smithy, Gemma</a>. However, this village was established <em>within</em> the Windswept Plains hunting locale with no loading screens separating it from the action. In fact, the entire 30-minute demo, from preparing in town to taking down a monster and exploring, was completely seamless. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>While still in town, the hunter mounted their Seikret – a new small bird wyvern type mount that the presenter mentioned is especially useful because the maps in Wilds are two times the size compared to previous games. Considering how vast the <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/monster-hunter-world/Locations">locales in World</a> felt, this sounds massive to me. <br>The hunter then headed off to another small settlement in the Plains. The people here specialized in cultivating cheese and raising herbivores for livestock, and among them was a cheesemonger. After purchasing some of her wares, the NPC said “This will see <em>gouda</em> use.” Personally, I’m happy to see classic Monster Hunter puns still in the dialogue rotation, though I understand some may find it a bit cheesy. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>...maps in Wilds are two times the size compared to previous games.</p></div><p>Ingredients in hand, next up was to find the monster to hunt. The map in the menu now shows the area's elevation in a sort-of 3D render rather than the flat illustrated maps we’re used to, and while looking through it, our hunter chose a target for their Seikret to find and follow by way of scent. This is a more automatic approach and didn’t seem to require much action on the hunter’s part. The Seikret can even avoid monster herds on its own as it travels.  </p><p>During those travels, the hunter showed off a new portable tent. The temporary structure allows you to change your equipment and eat just like in the regular tents dotted scarcely on the map. He also cooked a custom meal in the field, using the cheese purchased earlier along with some meat. Ready for a hunt, he continued on his way. </p><p>The hunter targeted an Alpha Doshaguma within a herd of the beasts. The Alpha’s larger size and redder fur differentiated it from the rest, and the hunter donned a Ghillie Mantle to approach unnoticed and initiate battle with a sneak attack. (So, <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/monster-hunter-world/Mantles_and_Boosters">mantles</a> are back – at least this one!) Striking the monster a few times automatically triggered the start of a quest to defeat it.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/12/doshagumabackground-1718170480430.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>A Doshaguma, a fanged beast that occasionally roams the Windward Plains in packs. </figcaption></figure></output><p>Trying to fight one large monster amongst a herd looked a little chaotic but also cool, and the Seikret made it possible for the hunter to lure the crowd to a nearby narrow ravine. There, a Bahalara’s quicksand trap quickly took care of the filler Doshagumas, sucking them down into a presumably sandy grave. Unpredictably, once the clashing hunter and Doshaguma were back out in the open, a new monster appeared to shake things up. This was the “Apex” of the plains – the new wyvern shown in the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-crossplay-confirmed-alongside-new-trailer">most recent trailer at Summer Game Fest</a>. Usually, this lightning-wielding Flying Wyvern (presumably)  shows up <em>with </em>a storm, but the presenter said this time it appeared a little early. To attack, this yet-to-be-named wyvern braces itself on the ground and “closes” its plate-like horns into a pointed formation to aim a beam of electricity. It’s an attack that requires some build-up and looks especially impressive, and though it didn’t happen in my demo, I heard it had the ability to one-shot an unsuspecting (or careless) hunter. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/12/mysterious-monster-1718171048402.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>The mysterious, unnamed Apex of the Plains.</figcaption></figure></output><p>The thunderstorm that followed impressed me — the visuals of lightning crashing down onto the sands and flashing in the background were mesmerizing. At one moment, the hunter called back to a tent on a cliff and looked off into the distance, where the storm rumbled amongst a peculiar environmental structure. </p><p>Eventually, the hunter was able to escape the new threat and tackle the alpha Doshaguma with the help of some NPCs called upon by an SOS Flare, a mechanic that allows you to “summon” other hunters seamlessly at will into your current hunt. When online, these would be other players, of course. <br>Though the Monster Hunter series played with getting more cinematic with World and even Rise, Wilds really takes advantage of the effect the field of view the camera can have to create additional drama and tension to battles. Upon a Power Clash, where the hunter fought off the Doshaguma with a Great Sword rammed in its mouth, the camera zoomed in so that the hunter and monster’s ferocious jaws encompassed most of the screen, adding stress to the moment. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Executive director and art director Kaname Fujioka said while they’re not trying to make Monster Hunter Wilds like a movie, they are working on utilizing the camera work to “service what we want players to focus on visually and to increase their immersion.” </p><p>Here are some more key moments and details from the demo: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Director Yuya Tokuda said the Palico now having a voice helps the player understand what’s happening, as there are a lot of “environmental changes” and “things happening in real time.” For example, the Palico spoke and said, “Shock trap’s down and ready for you” in the demo. I can definitely see the audio cues being helpful when it’s difficult to read text in the middle of the action, but Tokuda-san assured me you can change the voice back to the familiar meows of cat-speak if you choose.</li><li>You can now pick up and reposition barrel bombs.</li><li>Wounds will appear on the monster as you fight it. This is a system related to Focus Mode, which allows you to specifically target attacks and guards where you aim the cursor. When you enter Focus Mode, Scoutflies will highlight the wounded areas in red. Attacking those wounds specifically, either in or outside Focus Mode, will eventually destroy them and couse damage. There are even special moves for each weapon designed to destroy wounds more quickly. </li><li>A red line from a monster to you notes when a monster will chase you. </li><li>Each biome in these “Forbidden Lands” have different environmental phases, and different materials will only be available during certain times. For example, the Windward Plains has dry and abundant phases, punctuated by sandstorm weather events that have severe lightning strikes.. Great Thunderbugs only appear in the plains during those thunderstorms. </li><li>If you’re patient, you can watch the endemic life live out their lifecycles. For example, a bird building a nest, hatching eggs, and feeding its young. Fujioka said their goal with the Monster Hunter series has always been to make players feel immersed in a living ecosystem, just like a real natural environment, and intend to deepen that concept in Wilds. </li><li>The Hunting Horn is returning to its style from World, but with some additional changes.</li><li>The Light Bowgun and Heavy Bowgun have “received some of the most kind of broad action changes” of all the weapon types, Tokuda said.</li><li>Tokuda said they’ve made playing through the story in multiplayer a lot more convenient in Wilds than in World, but you won’t be able to play perfectly together in sync throughout the story as there are some story elements you’ll have to witness solo before matching back up. “We’ve introduced new features in the game so that in the background, you’re always connected,” Tokuda explained. “...so as soon as you’re able to go into a quest, it matches you up quickly and you can seamlessly go back into multiplayer gameplay.” </li></ul><p>Overall, Monster Hunter Wilds looks especially promising at this key first glance. It’s beautiful on current hardware and appears to be taking full advantage of the technical capabilities by introducing concepts like herds of large monsters and dynamic, changing environments. Of course, I’m excited to see more, and am especially eager to learn more about the finer tweaks and additions to the gameplay that will make Wilds fresh and unique. As the start of the loved Monster Hunter series’ sixth generation, it has big expectations to meet! </p><p><em>Casey DeFreitas is IGN's Deputy Editor, Guides. You can catch her chatting about monsters on Twitter </em><a href="https://x.com/shinycaseyd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@ShinyCaseyD</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Physical Edition of Alan Wake 2 Is Up For Preorder, Out October 22]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/alan-wake-2-physical-edition-preorder</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-physical-edition-of-alan-wake-2-is-up-for-preorder-out-october-22.899460/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/alan-wake-2-physical-edition-preorder<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Show me the Champion of Light!</h2></div><div><section><p>It's official: Alan Wake 2 is getting a physical release. If you've been itching to get your hands on it, you can preorder the Alan Wake 2 Deluxe Edition for <a href="https://zdcs.link/DdVWR" target="_blank">PS5</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/ZRdbD" target="_blank">Xbox Series X</a> right now at a variety of retailers. It's set to release on October 22 and will set you back $79.99.</p><p>Alongside the main game, it also comes bundled with the Night Springs and Lake House expansions, the Digital Edition of Alan Wake Remastered, and a variety of cosmetics, including the Nordic Shotgun Skin for Saga, the Crimson Windbreaker for Saga, the Celebrity Suit for Alan, the Parliament Shotgun Skin for Alan, and Lantern Charm for Saga. Check it out at the links below to preorder your copy today.</p><h2>Alan Wake 2 Deluxe Edition is Up for Preorder - Out October 22</h2><div><div id="201947"><p><h3>Alan Wake 2 Deluxe Edition - Xbox</h3></p></div><div id="201948"><p><h3>Alan Wake 2 Deluxe Edition - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div></div><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/kn7yn" target="_blank">Also at Best Buy</a> - PS5 - $79.99</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/vdxyx" target="_blank">Also at Best Buy</a> - Xbox Series X - $79.99</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/8BbG7" target="_blank">Also at GameStop</a> - PS5 - $79.99</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/JdVDN" target="_blank">Also at GameStop</a> - Xbox Series X - $79.99</li></ul><h2>Alan Wake 2 Collector's Edition</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/12/alanwakeii-mockup-market-banner-ce-v1717847812697-1718199898165.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>There's also a Collector's Edition of Alan Wake 2 that's exclusive to Limited Run games. This is available for both Xbox Series X and PlayStation 5 and can be purchased for $199.99. For that price tag, you'll get the Alan Wake 2 Deluxe Edition game listed above (complete with the expansions, cosmetics, and the Digital Edition of Alan Wake Remastered), alongside a light-up Angel Lamp, 160-page hardcover art book, enamel pin set, an Oceanview Hotel keychain, and an embossed Collector’s Edition slip-cover. </p><p>Get it while you can, as <strong>preorders close on Sunday, July 21, 2024 at 11:59PM ET.</strong></p><div><div id="201945"><p><h3>Alan Wake 2 Collector's Edition (PS5)</h3></p><div><p>Estimated ship date Dec 1 – 31</p></div></div><div id="201946"><p><h3>Alan Wake 2 Collector's Edition (Xbox Series X)</h3></p><div><p>Estimated ship date Dec 1 – 31</p></div></div></div><h2>Alan Wake 2 Trailer</h2><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>What is Alan Wake 2?</h2><p>Alan Wake 2 is the celebrated sequel to Alan Wake. Since its release last October it has garnered numerous accolades and earned its place on many a end-of-year list for 2023 (even coming in as a runner-up on our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-video-games-2023">Game of the Year list for 2023</a>). In our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/alan-wake-ii-review">Alan Wake 2 review</a> we gave the game a 9/10, stating that it "delivers one of the boldest and most brain-bending survival-horror storylines this side of Silent Hill 2, presents it with uniformly immaculate art direction and audio design, and reinvigorates the series’ signature light-based shooting as though it’s been locked and loaded with a fresh pack of Energizers."</p><p>The recently-released first DLC expansion also received high praise from us. In our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/alan-wake-ii-night-springs-dlc-review">Alan Wake II: Night Springs DLC review</a>, we called the expansion "a compact collection of standalone stories that veer from entertainingly violent shootouts, to tense stretches of survival horror, before settling on and reveling in the utterly batshit craziness that makes Remedy’s multiverse of madness so keenly absorbing to explore."</p><h2>More Preorder Guides</h2><p>Looking for even more games to preorder? There's plenty to check out, especially after so many exciting showcases to kick off Summertime. Check them out at the links below.</p><div><ul><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-physical-edition-of-alan-wake-2-is-officially-up-for-preorder-out-october-22">Alan Wake 2 (Physical) Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadow-release-date-collectors-edition">Assassin's Creed Shadows Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/astro-bot-heres-what-comes-in-each-edition">Astro Bot Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-release-date-editions">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-release-date-editions">College Football 25 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/concord-ps5-pc-release-date-preorder-bonus">Concord Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-collectors-edition-preorder">Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/luigis-mansion-2-hd-preorder">Luigi's Mansion 2 HD Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/madden-nfl-25-release-date-special-editions">Madden NFL 25 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/master-detective-archives-rain-code-plus-is-up-for-preorder">Master Detective Archives: Rain Code Plus Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-heres-what-comes-in-each-edition">Metal Gear Solid Delta Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metaphor-refantazio-release-date-collectors-edition">Metaphor: ReFantazio Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-release-date-deluxe-edition">Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-stories-collection-preorder">Monster Hunter Stories Collection Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-shadow-generations-preorder-guide">Sonic X Shadow Generations Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-release-date-special-editions">Star Wars Outlaws Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-release-date-collectors-edition">Super Monkey Ball: Banana Rumble Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li></ul></div><p><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelance writer who works with the Guides and Commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jun 12, 2024 2:49 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Exciting Updates Coming to Fallout 76]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/6-exciting-updates-coming-to-fallout-76</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/6-exciting-updates-coming-to-fallout-76.899457/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/6-exciting-updates-coming-to-fallout-76<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>We’re fast approaching the sixth year of Fallout 76 and although the popular action RPG has received dozens of additions so far, it could be argued that the upcoming Skyline Valley update will be the most impactful of them all, at least from what I’ve seen of it so far. </p><p>From the first-of-its-kind map expansion to the ability to finally play as a Ghoul in 2025, here’s six exciting updates coming soon for all you vault dwellers to enjoy. </p><h2><strong>Appalachia is Getting Bigger</strong></h2><p>Fallout 76 has previously expanded its scope with new locations like 2022’s The Pitt Expedition and last year’s trip to Atlantic City. But unlike Expeditions, which take you to entirely different locations, Skyline Valley’s more seamless map extension approach means this is the very first time in six years that the core region is being expanded, spreading south into the Shenandoah region.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/06/map-exnading-1717688634706.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>“We [knew] that there was a skirt around the whole map of unused space,” says Fallout 76’s Creative Director, Jon Rush. “And we wanted to do a region expansion for a while. We wanted to make it impactful and really tie it into the story, so [Skyline Valley] just felt like the right time and place.”</p><p>Previous Expeditions have been very isolated experiences, lacking maps or any real exploration opportunities outside of their specific questlines. Skyline Valley gives wastlanders the first chance to continue their 76 experience in new locations that are part of the main world map.</p><p>“There are very pointed reasons for going on the Expeditions [with] specific things you're trying to get,” says Rush. “So we wanted an in-world place where [players] could adventure and explore. Camp builders can make new camps [here] and people can come up with their own new stories.”</p><h2><strong>20 New Points of Interest</strong></h2><p>Skyline Valley isn’t just a side quest. With the map expansion comes 20 new points of interest for players to explore, with some such as Mary’s Rock Tunnel, Rapidan Camp, and Skyline Drive being based on real-world Shenandoah locations.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/06/locations-1717688660807.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>There are also new factions, quests, and activities coming to the expansion, including a new event called ‘Dangerous Pastimes’ that tasks you as a storm chaser trying to power up a giant lightning rod and hopefully kick off an electrical light show.</p><h2><strong>A Brand New Vault to Explore</strong></h2><p>Hardcore Fallout 76 fans will be no stranger to Vault 63, a bunker that has remained mysteriously closed since launch. Skyline Valley will finally open its giant mechanical door for the first time and let players discover what’s hidden inside.</p><p>“Why [has] that Vault 63 door been closed for so long?” asks Rush, hinting that the answers are soon to be discovered. “It has drawn so much intrigue and mystery [with fans], ‘What's going on back there? There's something.’”</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/06/hugo-1717688686724.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>A lot of the true nature of Vault 63 is still a mystery, but what we do know is that Skyline Valley will trigger an incident that finally exposes Vault 63 to the wasteland, catapulting its once-sealed door across Appalachia. As for what’s inside, we know Vault 63 wasn’t completed before the bombs dropped, and so all of its residents were soaked in radiation and turned into (albeit quite content) ghouls. Their leader, Hugo Stolz, looks slightly different, though. Hugo is (at least cosmetically) one of the brand-new enemy types coming with the Skyline Valley update called The Lost.</p><h2><strong>The Lost</strong></h2><p>The Lost are former denizens of Vault 63 who now live out their days as electrified, almost feral ghouls. </p><p>“The Lost dwell in their own skewed reality,” explains Rush. “[They’re] unable to communicate outside to others and will defend themselves against all outsiders.”</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/06/the-lost-1717688710246.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Why they’re electrified and why Hugo’s mind hasn’t deteriorated like the rest of his kin is still yet to be explained. But what we do know is that The Lost will regularly roam the Skyline Valley region once Vault 63 is exposed, and are very much the main fodder you’ll have to deal with. They act almost feral-like, with a focused impulsion to hunt you down and swing their melee weapons in your direction. </p><p>The Lost aren’t the only new enemy types coming to Skyline Valley, though.</p><h2><strong>Storm Goliaths</strong></h2><p>We’ve only seen some short glimpses so far, but the Storm Goliaths are three giant, raging robots that appear to harness bad weather and weaponise it directly into your face. </p><p>“[Storm Goliaths are] a trio of super-sized robo-brains built by the great minds of Vault 63,” shares Rush, letting on that Vault 63 contains a bevy of bad ideas that have now been unleashed into Appalachia. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/06/storm-1717688770630.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>But it’s not just technical monstrosities you’ll have to tangle with. Skyline Valley continues the tradition of irradiated mutations, with a particular new highlight being the Thrasher; a weird, cow-sized mutant turkey hybrid that now roams the hills of Shenandoah.</p><p>In a later update coming in 2025, though, you won’t just be fighting radiated nightmares, you’ll become one.</p><h2><strong>Play as a Ghoul</strong></h2><p>For the first time ever, Fallout 76 will give level 50+ players the chance to don the leathery, noseless skin of a ghoul. According to Rush, this is significantly more than a cosmetic appearance.</p><p>“If you're a ghoul, you're obviously not too concerned about radiation,” he says. “Radiation can actually heal you as a ghoul. It will also be positioned to have other very striking benefits as well, punctuated a bit more by dozens of ghoul-specific perk cards that we're going to be adding.”</p><p>Rush explains that the key to ensuring playing as a ghoul was far more than a cosmetic experience was realising how it could alter the gameplay for experienced players.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/06/ghoul-1717688789664.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>“Most players wear power armour to get away from radiation. As a ghoul, you wouldn't want to wear power armour, because [you want the radiation], right? ” explains Rush. “So that encourages a playstyle that doesn't [need] power armour and frees up a ton of perk points that can be used in a bunch of different other ways.”</p><p>Playing as a ghoul will disrupt the meta for Fallout 76, changing the way players optimise their character and encouraging further, unprecedented experimentation. It’s clearly something that the team at Bethesda have had in their minds for a while, but It feels like no coincidence that this is arriving hot on the heels of Walton Goggins’ The Ghoul in the extremely successful Amazon Prime Video show. With the popularity around ghouls never being higher, it makes sense that fans of the show would want to live out their irradiated fantasies in Fallout 76. </p><p>Rush also all but confirmed a gameplay mechanic is directly inspired by the show. Fallout on Prime established rules for how a ghoul maintains lucidity, via copious amounts of the drug-like remedy that prevents a downward spiral into the zombie-like, feral status. When asked if regularly drinking the mysterious concoction would be used as a gameplay survival feature he simply replied “Possibly” while maintaining a smile that would make a Vault Boy proud. </p><p><em>For more from the Appalachian wasteland, why not check out </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/the-weird-and-wonderful-fans-still-playing-fallout-76">our documentary</a><em> about the weird and wonderful community that still plays Fallout 76, including roleplaying cannibals, a Shakespeare troupe and a full-time courier service. </em></p><output data-cy="article-video"></output></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Visions of Mana Release Date Set for August]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-release-date-set-for-august</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/visions-of-mana-release-date-set-for-august.899451/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-release-date-set-for-august<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A summer of magic awaits. </h2></div><section><p>Square Enix has announced that Visions of Mana, the latest in the long-running Mana series, will be released later this summer. </p><p>Revealed as part of a new trailer, Visions of Mana will arrive on PlayStation 4 and 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC on August 29. Its launch will mark the first new Mana game in over 15 years, as well as the first time the Mana series will have appeared on an Xbox platform in its 30-year-plus history. (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-isnt-coming-to-xbox-game-pass-after-all">Just don't expect it on Game Pass</a>, sorry.) </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Visions of Mana was first announced at The Game Awards in 2023 and then shown at Xbox's Developer Direct, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-will-let-you-ride-a-big-cute-dog-around-in-summer-of-2024-xbox-direct-2024">where we got a look at the Pikul</a>; a big, fluffy dog that you can ride around the world on. And in our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-the-first-hands-on-preview">hands-on preview</a>, we said that it "paints an image of how exciting it has the potential to be. While it may seem like a scary change, the action-focused combat and the introduction of gameplay elements such as Elemental Vessels might be what the series needs to bring it back into the modern-day limelight."</p><p>If classically styled Japanese RPGs are what you're looking for in 2024, then you may also be interested in <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/metaphor-refantazio-official-awaken-trailer">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a>, the new game from the Persona 5 team. We recently <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/metaphor-refantazio-hands-on-with-the-wild-new-rpg-from-the-persona-5-team-ign-live-2024">went hands-on</a> with it and admired its wild approach to dungeons, world design, and story. </p><p><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Senior Features Editor. </em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Super Mario RPG Gets Another Big Limited Time Discount Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-rpg-best-deal-switch-2024-updated</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/super-mario-rpg-gets-another-big-limited-time-discount-amazon.899445/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-rpg-best-deal-switch-2024-updated<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Don't miss out on this deal again.</h2></div><div><section><p>Have you been looking for a reason to play Super Mario RPG on Nintendo Switch? In one of the best game deals this year, Amazon practically puts golden coins in your pocket. Originally priced at $59.99, the turn-based RPG remake is now available for just <a href="https://zdcs.link/kn7x3?_ga=1195960001.1647009307" target="_blank">$39.95—that's 33% off!</a> Last time this deal was available, it quickly went out of stock, so it's worth snapping up ASAP to avoid disappointment.</p><div id="201943"><p><h3>Super Mario RPG (Nintendo Switch)</h3></p></div><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-mario-rpg">Super Mario RPG</a> is one of Mario's most unique adventures. Developed by Square (now Square Enix) around three decades ago, the game has been remade for a new generation while maintaining the charm and quirkiness that made it a standout hit. The 2023 remake delivers an incredibly faithful recreation of the original, complete with updated graphics and smart combat updates that breathe new life into the classic.</p><p>Mario's journey begins unusually in this RPG, with him rushing to Bowser's keep and quickly rescuing Princess Peach. However, their celebration is cut short when a giant sword crashes through the castle, sending Mario and his friends on a quest to collect seven Star Pieces and save the Mushroom Kingdom. This engaging story is filled with humor and off-the-wall moments, making it a fan favorite and serving as the springboard to the Paper Mario series.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The game's turn-based combat system remains straightforward yet addictive, incorporating timing-based button prompts for attacks and defenses. This system, which has influenced numerous games over the years, includes updates that enhance the experience. Precise button presses bring home the mushrooms in style while introducing new powerful Triple Moves, adding a strategic layer to battles.</p><p>Super Mario RPG's varied environments and creative enemies keep players entertained in one of the most unique takes on the Italian plumber over the years. Each area is a new adventure, from battling living weapons to exploring ghost-filled pirate ships. The remake's updated 3D graphics are more than just a lick of fresh paint; this is a great RPG experience for all ages, with mechanics holding up over the last 30 years. Still on the fence about Super Mario RPG? <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-rpg-review">Here's our review</a> to help make your mind up. We're always on the lookout for epic gaming deals here at IGN.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Super Mario RPG Gameplay Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>In general, now's a great time to purchase games at a discount as there are so many sales going on to kick off Summer. Right now, you can save on a few <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/select-switch-games-are-discounted-right-now-at-best-buy-to-3999">excellent Switch titles at Best Buy</a> as well, including several that are down to just $39.99 like <a href="https://zdcs.link/XDdVY" target="_blank">Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/yLwG2" target="_blank">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a>, and <a href="https://zdcs.link/b1nMr" target="_blank">Splatoon 3</a>. These are some of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-deals">best Nintendo deals</a> going right now.</p><p>If you're wondering what Xbox has going on at the moment following an exciting <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-games-showcase-and-black-ops-6-direct-june-2024-everything-announced">Xbox showcase</a>, we have plenty of offers in our roundup of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals">best Xbox deals</a>. You can score a Series X at a discount right now and there are quite a few Xbox controllers on sale that are worth checking out. </p><p>Christian Wait is a UK-based freelancer for IGN, you can follow him @ChrisReggieWait on Twitter/X.</p></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jun 12, 2024 12:14 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doom: The Dark Ages’ Saw Shield Has Already Been Modded Into the Original Doom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/doom-the-dark-ages-saw-shield-has-already-been-modded-into-the-original-doom</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages%E2%80%99-saw-shield-has-already-been-modded-into-the-original-doom.899442/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/doom-the-dark-ages-saw-shield-has-already-been-modded-into-the-original-doom<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">No need to wait to protect and tear. </h2></div><section><p>Within hours of Xbox revealing Doom: The Dark Ages, a modder had added the upcoming game's seriously metal saw-toothed shield to the original Doom.</p><blockquote data-media-max-width="560" data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">aight I kinda ended up trying to make actual decorate for it... it works, will upload in a bit. <a href="https://t.co/OORmCydVL0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/OORmCydVL0</a></p>— Craneo (@CreeperOfSteam) <a href="https://twitter.com/CreeperOfSteam/status/1800033013881004087?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 10, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Posting to <a href="https://x.com/CreeperOfSteam/status/1800033013881004087" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a>, modder Craneo showcased a retro version of The Dark Ages' saw shield being used in the opening level of Doom 2 on PC. The mod replaces the original game's chainsaw with the new shieldsaw, but this isn't just a re-skin. In an effort to truly replicate what we saw in The Dark Ages' trailer, Craneo's modded saw not only cuts through enemies, but can also be thrown into distant foes and used to defend against damage. </p><p>This work arrived in quicker than quick time: Craneo posted the video of the mod to X/Twitter barely 12 hours after the trailer for Doom: The Dark Ages had debuted as part of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-games-showcase-and-black-ops-6-direct-june-2024-everything-announced">Xbox Games Showcase</a>. Minutes later the <a href="https://x.com/CreeperOfSteam/status/1800033699867820402" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">.wad file for the mod</a> was also posted. </p><p>While developed quickly, the mod seems built on smart logic. The defend ability likely triggers a temporary use of Doom's godmode cheat to negate incoming damage - a skill the game's original chainsaw certainly doesn't have. As for the throw, it requires a <a href="https://x.com/CreeperOfSteam/status/1800323020332077478" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">little tinkering in the sourceport options</a>, but it's an effective weapon in the OG Doom's confined corridors, especially because it can ricochet. This version of the shield sadly can't boomerang back to you, though, so you'll need to stay alive long enough to pick it back up. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>As for id Software's actual saw shield, we'll need to wait until 2025. However, despite being a Bethesda game, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/phil-spencer-briefly-explains-the-decision-to-bring-doom-the-dark-ages-to-playstation-5-ign-live-2024">Microsoft has decided to bring Doom: The Dark Ages to PlayStation 5</a> as well as the expected Xbox and PC platforms. That's a good thing, too, as it looks like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/doom-the-dark-ages-could-be-the-series-boldest-reinvention-yet">Doom: The Dark Ages could be the series' boldest bet yet</a>. </p><p><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Senior Features Editor. </em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steve Carell and Illumination troll Marvel Cinematic Universe with a parody Despicable Me 4 trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/steve-carell-and-illumination-troll-marvel-cinematic-universe-with-a-parody-despicable-me-4-trailer/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=steve-carell-and-illumination-troll-marvel-cinematic-universe-with-a-parody-despicable-me-4-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steve-carell-and-illumination-troll-marvel-cinematic-universe-with-a-parody-despicable-me-4-trailer.899436/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/steve-carell-and-illumination-troll-marvel-cinematic-universe-with-a-parody-despicable-me-4-trailer/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=steve-carell-and-illumination-troll-marvel-cinematic-universe-with-a-parody-despicable-me-4-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="536" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Steve Carell, the voice of Gru in the <em>Despicable Me</em> movies, has unveiled the “Megaverse”. The newly released <em>Despicable Me 4</em> trailer features Carell introducing the Mega Minions in a planned universe where many movies and shows will expand the lore around the Mega Minions. Through the trailer, Illumination and Carell took a cheeky dig at the superhero franchise model from <em>Marvel Cinematic Universe</em>, which features loads of movies and shows that are interconnected and part of a main storyline that goes on for many years.</p> <p data-characters="344" data-current-count="344" data-injectable="false">Illumination took the joke a step further by revealing an <a href="https://www.despicable.me/megaverse/">official website</a> where the planned timeline of movie releases and an official synopsis are listed. While the joke began with superhero movies and Marvel in particular, the quips expand to other movies as well, with clever nods to <em>Star Wars</em>,<em> Jerry Maguire</em>,<em> James Bond</em>,<em> Mad Max</em>, and more.</p> <figure data-current-count="644" data-injectable="true"><p> <iframe title="Despicable Me 4 - Enter the Megaverse" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sCwAOm7fCSg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure>
 <p data-characters="206" data-current-count="206" data-injectable="false">The official movie titles include <em>Mega Minions Legacy</em>, where the movie’s plot states that the heroes must return “after the Anti-Villain League’s quarterly earnings dramatically miss estimates.”</p> <p data-characters="216" data-current-count="422" data-injectable="true">Another hilarious movie is simply slated as an <em>Untitled Mega Minion Spin-off</em> and its outlined plot suggests that the story will be “determined based on rigorous market testing and ad hoc decision-making.”</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Despicable Me 4 - Official Clip (2024) Steve Carell, Kristen Wiig, Will Ferrell | IGN Live 2024" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0r4CjzDjqqY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="152" data-current-count="452" data-injectable="true">The movie names and the Megaverse announcement are clearly a parody, but it would be interesting to see some of these many movie ideas come to fruition.</p>
 <p data-characters="121" data-current-count="121" data-injectable="false"><em>Despicable Me 4</em> will have the super-powered Mega Minions at least, and the movie is slated for a release on July 3, 2024.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 will not be 300GB in size, Activision clarifies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-will-not-be-300gb-in-size-activision-clarifies/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=call-of-duty-black-ops-6-will-not-be-300gb-in-size-activision-clarifies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-will-not-be-300gb-in-size-activision-clarifies.899433/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-will-not-be-300gb-in-size-activision-clarifies/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=call-of-duty-black-ops-6-will-not-be-300gb-in-size-activision-clarifies<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="246" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Good news: you may not have to clear off your <em>entire </em>hard drive to make room for the next <em>Call of Duty</em>. <em>Black Ops 6</em> seemed to have a total install size of 309.85GB as per the pre-order page, but Activision has now clarified this is not the case. </p> <p data-characters="199" data-current-count="199" data-injectable="false">The publisher took to social media and said that the current estimated file size shown on the <em>Black Ops 6</em> pre-order pages “does not represent the download size or disk footprint for <em>Black Ops 6.</em>”</p> <p data-characters="224" data-current-count="423" data-injectable="true">Activision explained that the 300GB download size includes the full installations of <em>Call of Duty Modern Warfare 2</em>, <em>Modern Warfare 3</em>, <em>Warzone</em>, and “all relevant content packs, including all localized languages combined.”</p>
 <p data-characters="320" data-current-count="320" data-injectable="false">The publisher has further clarified that players will be able to download <em>Black Ops 6</em> at launch without any requirements to download any other <em>Call of Duty</em> game or any need to download all language packs. Activision said that the “actual estimation” for <em>Black Ops 6</em> file size will be revealed “closer to launch.”</p> <figure data-current-count="620" data-injectable="true"><div> <blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>📢 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackOps6?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BlackOps6</a></p><p>Correction: The estimated file size currently displayed on the Black Ops 6 pre-order pages does not represent the download size or disk footprint for Black Ops 6.</p><p>The sizes as shown include the full installations of Modern Warfare II, Modern Warfare III, Warzone…</p></div>— Call of Duty Updates (@CODUpdates) <a href="https://twitter.com/CODUpdates/status/1800273804389941699?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 10, 2024</a></blockquote> </div></figure>
 <p data-characters="496" data-current-count="496" data-injectable="true"><em>Call of Duty Black Ops 6</em> was recently revealed at the Xbox Games Showcase, and there was an immediate showcase following the show, focusing solely on the title. Lead developer Treyarch Studios talked the viewers through the development of the game’s campaign, Zombies mode, and the new ‘omnimovement’ which allows players to dive in <em>Max Payne</em> fashion and roll around when they’re prone. There is a lot more to look forward to, as the game inches closer to the October 25 release date.</p>
 <p data-characters="248" data-current-count="248" data-injectable="false"><em>Call of Duty Black Ops 6</em> will also be the first <em>CoD </em>game to launch on Game Pass since the acquisition of Activision Blizzard by Microsoft. It’ll be interesting to see what that means for <em>Black Ops 6</em>‘s concurrent player counts at launch.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anime Defenders Value List for all Units and Items]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/anime-defenders-value-list-for-all-units-and-items/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=anime-defenders-value-list-for-all-units-and-items</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anime-defenders-value-list-for-all-units-and-items.899427/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/anime-defenders-value-list-for-all-units-and-items/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=anime-defenders-value-list-for-all-units-and-items<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="387" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">One of the more interesting aspects of <em>Anime Defenders</em> is the ability to trade your units and items freely with other players. This has created somewhat of a dynamic market, with the prices and values of everything fluctuating constantly based on player demand, recent balance changes, and new updates. Here is a current and up-to-date <em>Anime Defenders</em> Value List for all Units and Items.</p> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure> <h2 id="h-anime-defenders-value-list-raids-update" data-injectable="false">Anime Defenders Value List (Raids Update)</h2> <p data-characters="350" data-current-count="650" data-injectable="true">Typically speaking, Mythic units are more valuable than Legendary and Epic units, simply because they are stronger in general and much more rare to acquire. However, some units with unique specialties or purposes may hold their value over others. Here is our Value List for Units and Items in <em>Anime Defenders</em> as of the recently released Raids Update:</p>
 <h3 id="h-epic-units" data-injectable="false">Epic Units</h3> <figure data-found-rows="2" data-current-count="380" data-injectable="false"><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Unit</strong></td><td data-align="center"><strong>Standard Value</strong></td><td data-align="center"><strong>Shiny Value</strong></td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bloomer</td><td data-align="center">25</td><td data-align="center">400</td></tr></tbody></table></figure> <p data-characters="119" data-current-count="499" data-injectable="true">Bloomer is the only Epic unit at the moment with true value due to her utility, though this may change at a later date.</p>
 <h3 id="h-legendary-units" data-injectable="false">Legendary Units</h3> <figure data-found-rows="4" data-current-count="460" data-injectable="true"><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Unit</strong></td><td data-align="center"><strong>Standard Value</strong></td><td data-align="center"><strong>Shiny Value</strong></td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Admiral of Light</td><td data-align="center">100</td><td data-align="center">1000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Cursed Fighter</td><td data-align="center">100</td><td data-align="center">1000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Pink Rockstar</td><td data-align="center">250</td><td data-align="center">2500</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
 <h3 id="h-mythic-units" data-injectable="false">Mythic Units</h3> <figure data-found-rows="13" data-current-count="820" data-injectable="true"><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Unit</strong></td><td data-align="center"><strong>Standard Value</strong></td><td data-align="center"><strong>Shiny Value</strong></td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ant King</td><td data-align="center">2000</td><td data-align="center">30000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bear King</td><td data-align="center">250000</td><td data-align="center">700000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Carp</td><td data-align="center">2500</td><td data-align="center">30000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Curse Prince</td><td data-align="center">1200</td><td data-align="center">27000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Donut Warrior</td><td data-align="center">2400</td><td data-align="center">28000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Elf Wizardess</td><td data-align="center">2000</td><td data-align="center">25000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Esper</td><td data-align="center">600</td><td data-align="center">18000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Flame Dragon King</td><td data-align="center">4000</td><td data-align="center">38000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Sharpshooter</td><td data-align="center">1200</td><td data-align="center">26000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Skull Warrior</td><td data-align="center">1500</td><td data-align="center">30000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Thunder Shinobi</td><td data-align="center">700</td><td data-align="center">19000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Warrior Princess</td><td data-align="center">3500</td><td data-align="center">55000</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
 <h3 id="h-secret-units" data-injectable="false">Secret Units</h3> <figure data-found-rows="4" data-current-count="460" data-injectable="true"><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Unit</strong></td><td data-align="center"><strong>Standard Value</strong></td><td data-align="center"><strong>Shiny Value</strong></td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Chance Taker</td><td data-align="center">200000</td><td data-align="center">550000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Cursed Knight</td><td data-align="center">250000</td><td data-align="center">820000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Gamer</td><td data-align="center">270000</td><td data-align="center">850000</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
 <h3 id="h-items" data-injectable="false">Items</h3> <figure data-found-rows="6" data-current-count="540" data-injectable="true"><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Unit</strong></td><td data-align="center"><strong>Standard Value</strong></td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Frost Bind</td><td data-align="center">200</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Risky Dice</td><td data-align="center">300</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Star Rift (All Basic Colors)</td><td data-align="center">100</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Star Rift (Rainbow Color)</td><td data-align="center">600</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Trait Crystal</td><td data-align="center">150</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
 <p data-characters="298" data-current-count="298" data-injectable="false">Every unit and item can bounce around between certain values, but for the most part it stays around these current prices until there is a new update or big changes to balance. As long as you stay within a small range of this <em>Anime Defenders</em> value list, you should be getting the best value you can.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sumo Group closes Timbre Games amid plans to cut 15% of staff]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/12/sumo-group-closes-timbre-games-amid-plans-to-cut-15-of-staff/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sumo-group-closes-timbre-games-amid-plans-to-cut-15-of-staff.899397/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/12/sumo-group-closes-timbre-games-amid-plans-to-cut-15-of-staff/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sumo Group has announced it is reducing its global workforce by 15%, which equates to 250 people, and the first studio that has been impacted is Timbre Games. Staff of Timbre Games took to social media to confirm they had been told the studio would be closed, with Sumo Group confirming the news to <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/report-sumo-group-closing-timbre-games">GameIndustry.biz</a>.</p>
<p>In a statement yesterday, Sumo Group confirmed the plans to layoff staff across its operations. The statement said, <em>“Every day the incredibly talented people across Sumo studios are dedicated to creating great games and bringing ground-breaking experiences to players worldwide. That work and dedication over the past 21 years has helped to put Sumo on the map and build a family of studios that are second to none, and we are incredibly proud of what Sumo has become.</em></p>


<p><em>Whilst Sumo has been able to manage through many of the recent difficulties the games industry has faced, we have not been immune and reshaping operations across the business to better navigate the upcoming challenges expected in the coming months is a path we must now take to ensure the security of the business going forward.</em></p>
<p><em>The difficult decision to reduce our costs across the business in a number of ways is a direct result of these challenges, and unfortunately will include a reduction in the number of people the business can support. Every alternate route to limit the impact to our people is being considered but sadly this process of transformation will affect up to 15% of our people across the Group in Canada, UK, Poland, Czech Republic and India.</em></p>
<p><em>This is an incredibly challenging process to go through for everyone at Sumo and our focus is now on supporting our people and working with our partners on their games as we move forward to ensure we emerge from this difficult time, ready for the future.”</em></p>

<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/07/19/british-developer-sumo-digital-acquired-by-tencent-1-3-billion/">Sumo Group was acquired by Tencent for a sum of $1.3 billion</a>.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/sumo-group-to-reduce-staff-by-up-to-15">GamesIndustry.biz</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[June's PlayStation Plus Premium and Extra games include Monster Hunter Rise, Football Manager 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/junes-playstation-plus-premium-and-extra-games-include-monster-hunter-rise-football-manager-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/junes-playstation-plus-premium-and-extra-games-include-monster-hunter-rise-football-manager-2024.899394/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/junes-playstation-plus-premium-and-extra-games-include-monster-hunter-rise-football-manager-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Plus Crusader Kings 3, Anno 1800, and more.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GNI5OvDXUAMWxbA.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Capcom</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
June's additions to the PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium games catalogue have <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/12/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-june-monster-hunter-rise-football-manager-2024-crusader-kings-iii-after-us-and-more/?sf273529707=1">been revealed</a>, and it's a pretty strong line-up, introducing the likes of Monster Hunter Rise, Crusader Kings 3, Anno 1800, and Football Manager 2024.
</p>
<p>
In total, June adds ten titles that'll be accessible to both PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium subscribers, and all are available to download starting next Tuesday, 18th June:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Monster Hunter Rise (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Football Manager 2024 (PS5)</li>
<li>Crusader Kings III (PS5)</li>
<li>Anno 1800 (PS5)</li>
<li>Lego The Hobbit (PS4)</li>
<li>Lego The Incredibles (PS4)</li>
<li>After Us (PS5)</li>
<li>Monster Energy Supercross 6 (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Police Simulator: Patrol Officers (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Far Cry 4 (PS4)</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PlayStation upsets VR fans as it kicks off this year's not-E3 hype cycle" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ev55ao9pf4M?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PlayStation upsets VR fans as it kicks off this year's not-E3 hype cycle</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ev55ao9pf4M?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ev55ao9pf4M?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: PlayStation upsets VR fans as it kicks off this year's not-E3 hype cycle.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ev55ao9pf4M" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
There's some good stuff coming in June, then - Monster Hunter Rise being an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-rise-review-the-switchs-best-game-since-breath-of-the-wild">absolute treat</a> for action fans, while Crusader Kings 3 and Anno 1800 both serve up some superb historical strategy, even if they both approach it from completely different directions. Chuck in those perennial Lego favourites, some enjoyable (if <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/after-us-is-a-vast-vibrant-platformer-with-a-muddled-heart">rather muddled</a>) ecological platforming in After Us, and the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/football-manager-2024-review">quietly revolutionary</a> Football Manager 2024, and there's a lot to love.
</p>
<p>
As for Premium subscribers specifically, June adds one new PSVR 2 title to the catalogue alongside three Classics:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Kayak VR: Mirage (PSVR2)</li>
<li>LEGO Star Wars 2: The Original Trilogy (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Ghosthunter (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Daxter (PS4, PS5)</li>
</ul>
<p>
All the above join PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium on 18th June - but while one hand is busy offering welcoming handshakes to the newcomers, the other will be waving fond farewells to Sony's latest list of catalogue departures, which this time are as follows:
</p>
<ul>
<li>GTA 5 (PS5, PS4)</li>
<li>MotoGP 23 (PS5, PS4)</li>
<li>SpongeBob SquarePants: Battle for Bikini Bottom Rehydrated (PS4)</li>
<li>Monster Jam Steel Titans (PS4)</li>
<li>Unturned (PS4)</li>
<li>Brothers:A Tale of Two Sons (PS4)</li>
<li>DC League of Super-Pets: The Adventures of Krypto and Ace (PS5, PS4)</li>
<li>Dodgeball Academia (PS4)</li>
<li>The Talos Principle (PS4)</li>
<li>Baja: Edge of Control (PS4)</li>
<li>The Wild at Heart (PS4)</li>
<li>Indivisible (PS4	)</li>
<li>Slime Rancher (PS4)</li>
</ul>




        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Games database leak hints at a trove of unannounced games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/12/24176964/epic-games-database-leak-unannounced-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-games-database-leak-hints-at-a-trove-of-unannounced-games.899391/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/12/24176964/epic-games-database-leak-unannounced-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>An unofficial site tracking titles in the Epic Games library may have just leaked a ton of upcoming games, as reported earlier <a href="https://wccftech.com/major-epic-leak-hints-at-unannounced-games-coming-to-epic-games-store/">by <em>Wccftech</em></a>. The site, called EpicDB, was taken offline shortly after it posted information scraped from the Epic Games Store catalog on Monday, but that didn’t stop people from scanning the list and posting their findings.</p><p>You can see the list of games from publishers like Bethesda, Sega, Sony, Square Enix, and others in a series of screenshots posted by a <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-lot-of-unannounced-games-are-leaking-via-epicdb.898755/">user on a <em>ResetEra</em> forum</a>. While some, like <em>Turok</em>, are easy to spot, others are listed under previously rumored codenames, such as <a href="https://kotaku.com/sources-the-new-bioshock-has-been-in-the-works-for-yea-1840314561">“Parkside<em>” </em>or <em>BioShock 4</em></a>. </p><p>There are still other titles under codenames we haven’t heard about. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1ddua4x/epicdb_several_publisher_games_are_being_leaked/?share_id=6m1QV-LYimeoJ1TcX40o5&amp;utm_content=1&amp;utm_medium=android_app&amp;utm_name=androidcss&amp;utm_source=share&amp;utm_term=1">Some users speculate</a> that “Momo” could point to a <em>Final Fantasy 9</em> remake, while “Selma” may be the PC port of <em>Red Dead Redemption 1</em>. The codename “Utah” could also hint at the PC version of<em> The Last of Us Part 2</em>, which is rumored to <a href="https://www.techradar.com/gaming/consoles-pc/the-last-of-us-part-2-is-reportedly-ready-to-launch-on-pc">be almost ready to launch</a>.</p><p>Epic Games has since pushed an update preventing sites like EpicDB from scraping its list of unpublished games. “We released an update tonight so third-party tools can’t surface any new unpublished product titles from the Epic Games Store catalog,”&nbsp;Epic Games said in a statement provided to <em>Wccftech. The Verge</em> reached out to Epic Games with a request for comment but didn’t immediately hear back.</p><p>But with so many other titles listed under unknown codenames, like CurlyWurly from Sega and Brownie from Bethesda, internet sleuths still have plenty of mysteries to figure out.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Still Wakes the Deep, Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun and Deathsprint 66 makers to lay off hundreds of staff]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/still-wakes-the-deep-warhammer-40000-boltgun-and-deathsprint-66-makers-to-lay-off-hundreds-off-staff</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/still-wakes-the-deep-warhammer-40-000-boltgun-and-deathsprint-66-makers-to-lay-off-hundreds-of-staff.899388/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/still-wakes-the-deep-warhammer-40000-boltgun-and-deathsprint-66-makers-to-lay-off-hundreds-off-staff<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Sumo Group studios have also co-developed games including Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League and Hogwarts Legacy</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/warhammer-40000-boltgun-a.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Focus Entertainment</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Sumo Group, the British video game collective which owns developers Sumo Digital, publishers Secret Mode and more - including <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/everybodys-gone-to-the-rapture">Everybody's Gone to the Rapture</a> devs The Chinese Room - is laying off hundreds of staff, cutting 15% of their workforce “to better navigate the upcoming challenges expected in the coming months”.</p>
<!--more-->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<p>The news came just a couple of days after Secret Mode showed off upcoming PC releases Critter Café, freerunning Mario Kart-but-deadly-a-like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/deathsprint-66">Deathsprint 66</a> and The Chinese Room’s next moody title <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/still-wakes-the-deep">Still Wakes the Deep</a> during Summer Games Fest over the weekend, with Sumo Digital chirpily celebrating the “busy weekend” <a href="https://www.sumogroupltd.com/news/2024/secret-mode-makes-a-splash-at-summer-game-fest/">on Monday</a>. The very next day, Sumo Group - which owns the various Sumo Digital studios - released <a href="https://www.sumogroupltd.com/news/2024/sumo-group-update/">a separate announcement</a> of layoffs, stating that they would be “reshaping operations” to “to ensure the security of the business going forward”.</p>
<p>The layoffs will hit up to 15% of the entire group’s workforce across its 19 UK, Canadian, Polish, Czech and Indian offices - meaning up to 270 people may be affected, going by the latest headcount of 1,790 on <a href="https://www.sumogroupltd.com/">the company’s website</a>.</p>
 <p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>As well as leading development on games such as multiplayer horror game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-texas-chain-saw-massacre">The Texas Chain Saw Massacre</a>, LittleBigPlanet spin-off <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sackboy-a-big-adventure">Sackboy: A Big Adventure</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/crackdown-3">Crackdown 3</a>, Sumo are known for their work as co-developers of games including <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league">Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hogwarts-legacy">Hogwarts Legacy</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/forza-horizon-5">Forza Horizon 5</a>. In 2021, the group was acquired by Chinese megacorp Tencent, with its own acquisitions including the likes of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warhammer-40000-boltgun">Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun</a> devs Auroch Digital and, most recently, mobile studio Midoki.</p>
<p>“This is an incredibly challenging process to go through for everyone at Sumo and our focus is now on supporting our people and working with our partners on their games as we move forward to ensure we emerge from this difficult time, ready for the future,” Sumo wrote. Good luck to all those affected.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Lets You Stick with One Protagonist for Most of the Game; Exploration Loop Is Sherlock-Like]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-lets-you-stick-with-one-protagonist-for-most-of-the-game-exploration-loop-is-sherlock-like/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-lets-you-stick-with-one-protagonist-for-most-of-the-game-exploration-loop-is-sherlock-like.899385/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-lets-you-stick-with-one-protagonist-for-most-of-the-game-exploration-loop-is-sherlock-like/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows will be the first new entry since 2020's Valhalla. In that game, players had to choose at the start whether to play with a female or male main character (Eivor Varinsdottir), but in the new installment, there will be two separate protagonists: the shinobi Naoe and the samurai Yasuke.</p>
<p>In case you were wondering to which extent Assassin's Creed Shadows will dictate who you're playing with, associate director Simon Lemay-Comtois <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/assassin-s-creed/assassins-creed-shadows-preview-june-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told GamesRadar</a> that players would be able to stick with their favorite protagonist for most of the game if they wish.</p>
<p><em>If you want to be only one character, you can for most of the game. So we're not really strong-arming anyone to switch back and forth. There are setups that are definitely better with Naoe, such as, if there's a bunch of bandits in a cavern that is very, very dark, sure you can go with Yasuke, but if you go with Naoe, it'll be quicker because it's in the dark. So there are some hints like this, but other than story missions that are particularly tailor made for one or the other, we don't specify who needs to be played at this moment, it's up to the players.</em></p>
<p>This is a similar approach to Marvel's Spider-Man 2, another game with dual protagonists in which you could play as either Miles Morales or Peter Parker during most of the open-world missions.</p>
<p>In case you're interested in the differences between Naoe and Yasuke, our <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-forward-presentation-and-impressions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">freshly posted</a> Assassin's Creed Shadows preview from Summer Game Fest outlines them very clearly:</p>
<p><em>A massive studded club was Yasuke’s primary weapon in the Assassin’s Creed Shadows demos, which would be swung around like a baseball bat and squish ashigaru skulls like overripe tomatoes. For enemies that take more than a single strike to down, Yasuke’s mighty swings rip through the air and smash into their armor to strip their breastplates off in the streets. Charged attacks and a trio of special skills each operated on cooldowns mix up his brutish swings all the while having the fortitude to shrug off intense blows.</em></p>
<p><em>On the other hand, Naoe hearkens back to the more refined assassination styles. In addition to the single hidden blade, this plucky shinobi wields a shorter katana and a chain-and-sickle weapon called a kusarigama. With the latter, Naoe can swing a massive chain around for crowd control but also stun enemies with the weighted end before closing the distance and stabbing the foe with the sickle end (sometimes taking more than one stab to finish them out in brutal fashion). As a much smaller and more nimble combatant, Naoe does more with her agile frame to dodge and jump around the battlefield to sidestep enemy attacks that glow red (blue-highlighted attacks, on the other hand, can be blocked and parried)</em></p>
<p>In the aforementioned Gamesradar interview, Simon Lemay-Comtois also talked about introducing a more enticing exploration loop that rewards gathering information in a Sherlock Holmes-like fashion.</p>
<p><em>Early on, we decided to break the rules as much as we could on the conception of Assassin's Creed Shadows. So we tried to go and change the formula as much as we could. That's one of the places where we've heard the criticism, we ourselves wanted to push the exploration to be more engaging to the player, to want to discover things rather than just sinking into something and being fed information. So it's something new that we try to work into the game. And since it's working, we kind of built it throughout all the quests and the missions that you can do in the game. Now, I will say there is still a guided mode that players can opt into, which is more classic. It will tell you where to go and stuff like that, but the basic mode, our new exploration loop, is more about playing Sherlock Holmes a little bit and having to work for the reward at the end.</em></p>
<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows is set to launch on November 15 for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, Mac, and iPad.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Is Addressing One Of The Big Criticisms Of DAII’s Romances]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-romance-pansexual-playersexual-1851535412</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-is-addressing-one-of-the-big-criticisms-of-daii%E2%80%99s-romances.899382/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-romance-pansexual-playersexual-1851535412<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>BioWare’s upcoming RPG <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard </em>seems heavily influenced by 2011’s <em>Dragon Age II</em>. It’s evocative of the second game’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-gameplay-trailer-dreadwolf-rook-1851532144&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-gameplay-trailer-dreadwolf-rook-1851532144">action-driven combat</a></span>, goes back to its three-path tone-driven dialogue, and its letting you <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-4-veilguard-romance-options-dreadwolf-1851524102&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-4-veilguard-romance-options-dreadwolf-1851524102">romance any character you want</a></span>. However, it does seem BioWare learned some lessons in the 13 years since <em>Dragon Age 2</em>, as it will be circumventing one of the criticisms of the second game’s approach to romance and identity.<br></p><div data-video-id="196742" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="254" data-playlist="196742,196452,196790" data-current="196742"><div><p>What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22297.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>In 2011, <em>Dragon Age 2 </em>was an early example of what would colloquially go on to be called <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/video-game-romance-playersexual-baldurs-gate-dragon-age-1851253394&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/video-game-romance-playersexual-baldurs-gate-dragon-age-1851253394">“playersexual” romance</a></span>. This refers to when players can romance any paramour regardless of their character’s gender. Games like this are often criticized for making characters feel like they are molded by the player’s presence, rather than people with their own individual identities. <em>Dragon Age 2’s</em> four main romanceable characters are all bisexual, but the game has a storyline involving party member Anders, whose past relationship with a man is only brought up if protagonist Hawke is a man. <em>DA2</em> writer David Gaider told <em>Kotaku </em>in February this was meant to distinguish Anders’ relationship with male or female versions of Hawke, but recognizes this comes off like the mage’s identity was a switch to be flipped in hindsight.</p><p>“Unfortunately, we just didn’t have enough time to get enough feedback and iterate on those situations,” he said. “We would hit a particular interaction, we would make a judgment call either as a group or the writer on their own, and that was it. There was no time for anything more than one gut-check, which is probably not the way to go.”</p><p><em>The Veilguard</em>, meanwhile, seems to be going out of its way to make it clear each of its party members are pansexual, regardless of who Rook is or if they’re <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-dreadwolf-emmrich-volkarin-romance-1851535012&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-dreadwolf-emmrich-volkarin-romance-1851535012">initiating a relationship with them</a></span>. In an interview with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-confirmed-to-let-you-romance-any-companion-you-want-will-include-nudity-it-gets-pretty-spicy?&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-confirmed-to-let-you-romance-any-companion-you-want-will-include-nudity-it-gets-pretty-spicy?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>IGN</em></a></span>, <em>Veilguard </em>director Corinne Busche said the team was cognizant of how these player-facing relationships can be “off-putting,” and wants to make it clear that each of these characters’ identities are independent of the player. This can be through their other previous romantic histories, or future love stories that have yet to unfold.</p><p>“Their past experiences or partners, they’ll reference them and indeed who they’ll become romantic with,” Busche tells<em> IGN</em>. “For instance, we saw Harding. I might be playing a straight male character flirting with her, but I choose not to pursue a romance. She might get together with Taash. So my perception, my identity has no bearing on their identities and that comes through really strongly.”</p><p>That <em>The Veilguard</em>’s companions can end up in relationships with each other if you pursue them is exciting, and something <em>Dragon Age </em>has done in previous games. If you’re going to have a cast of pansexual misfits, some of them might as well start smooching. It’s also one of the surefire ways to demonstrate a character’s identity without it having anything to do with the player. Anders’ story may have run into this clarity issue in <em>Dragon Age II</em>, but party members Fenris and Isabela enter a relationship with each other if the player doesn’t pursue either. This helped alleviate the feeling that their identities were tied to Hawke, so at the very least, it seems BioWare is aware of criticisms that follow the free-for-all romance approach and is trying to circumvent them.</p><p><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard </em>is coming to PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X/S this fall.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Game Catalog Gets 14 Games In June 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-14-games-in-june-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-14-games-in-june-2024.899379/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-14-games-in-june-2024/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Sony <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/12/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-june-monster-hunter-rise-football-manager-2024-crusader-kings-iii-after-us-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has announced that 14 new games</a> are joining the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog in June 2024. All of the games will be available starting June 18.</p>



<p>Of the 14 games, 10 are available for PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium members. The remaining four are for Premium subscribers only. There’s also even a game for PS VR2 in this month’s list of games and one game returning after being previously removed.</p>



<h2 id="h-playstation-plus-game-catalog-games-june-2024">PlayStation Plus Game Catalog Games June 2024</h2>



<h3>PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium</h3>



<ul>
<li>Monster Hunter Rise – PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Football Manager 2024 – PS5</li>



<li>Crusader Kings 3 – PS5</li>



<li>Monster Energy Supercross – The Official Videogame 6 – PS4, PS5</li>



<li>After Us – PS5</li>



<li>Anno 1800 – PS5</li>



<li>Police Simulator: Patrol Officers – PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Far Cry 4 – PS4 (returning to PS Game Catalog)</li>



<li>LEGO The Hobbit – PS4</li>



<li>LEGO The Incredibles –  PS4</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-playstation-plus-premium-ps-vr2-amp-classic-games">PlayStation Plus Premium | PS VR2 &amp; Classic Games</h3>



<ul>
<li>Kayak VR: Mirage – PS VR2**</li>



<li>LEGO Star Wars II: The Original Trilogy – PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Ghosthunter – PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Daxter – PS4, PS5</li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the games coming to the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog in June 2024? For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-outlaws-complete-30-hours/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how long it will take to complete Star Wars Outlaws</a> when it launches in August, and  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lifeless Moon coming to PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, and Xbox One on July 9]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/lifeless-moon-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-july-9</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lifeless-moon-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-july-9.899376/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/lifeless-moon-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-july-9<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Lifeless Planet successor currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>Lifeless Planet</em> spiritual successor <em><a title="Games > Lifeless Moon [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lifeless-moon">Lifeless Moon</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,287 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,573 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,815 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,257 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> on July 9, publisher <a title="Companies > Serenity Forge [52 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/serenity-forge">Serenity Forge</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Stage 2 Studios [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/stage-2-studios">Stage 2 Studios</a> announced. <span id="more-891889"></span></p><p><em>Lifeless Moon</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1147330/Lifeless_Moon/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on August 10, 2023. The PC version will launch via <a title="Companies > Epic Games [339 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store alongside the console versions on July 9.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Serenity Forge:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Lifeless Moon</em>, the spiritual successor to the popular 2014 indie title <em>Lifeless Planet</em>, is a 3D <a title="Genres > Platformer [462 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> that puts you in the center of a mysterious Moon expedition. This new <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,565 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>, inspired by classic science fiction, plays as an Apollo-era astronaut who finds themself in the aftermath of an old 1970s experiment: an oddly familiar desert town… on the <a title="Games > moon [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/moon">moon</a>.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Explore Anomalies</strong> – Secrets in the desolate moon city soon unlock mysteries on a much grander scale… Equipped with a jetpack and your sense of <a title="Genres > Survival [290 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>, search for the truth through landscapes one could hardly fathom.</li><li><strong>Collect Documents</strong> – You’ll need perseverance and wit to uncover this mystery. Record your thoughts and find clues from the past to unravel the dark secrets residing on this celestial body.</li><li><strong>Utilize the Technology</strong> – If you want to understand the forces at hand, you’ll need to use them to your advantage. Solve puzzles and work with strange technology to create a path forward.</li><li><strong>Unearth the Mystery</strong> – In a land where objects materialize from nothing and time flows unexpectedly, relive the experiences and traumas of the scientists that came before you. After all, following their footsteps might be the only way to return home.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Consoles Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Lifeless Moon - Console Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/a9oasgQ92MI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astro Bot Marks A "New Beginning" For PlayStation's Burgeoning Mascot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/astro-bot-marks-a-new-beginning-for-playstations-burgeoning-mascot/1100-6524178/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/astro-bot-marks-a-new-beginning-for-playstations-burgeoning-mascot.899373/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/astro-bot-marks-a-new-beginning-for-playstations-burgeoning-mascot/1100-6524178/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524178">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">In the music industry, a band often uses a self-titled album years into its career to denote a reinvention. "<em>This</em> is who we are now" is the intended and unspoken message. PlayStation's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/astro-bot/" data-ref-id="5000-630892">Astro Bot</a> uses the same naming convention to signal a similarly fresh start. Following a 2018 VR exclusive with obviously limited reach and a 2020 game that Team Asobi's studio head and creative director Nicolas Doucet considers a "tech demo," 2024's simply titled Astro Bot feels like it's ready to launch the cutesy robot to the top of the crowded PlayStation pantheon.</p><p dir="ltr">"Astro's Playroom is actually called [that] so it wouldn't be mistaken for an Astro Bot-sized game," Doucet told me following a demo in which I beat several levels, rescued many PlayStation characters reimagined as robots, and beat a boss in the form of a boxing cephalopod. "A lot of people actually don't know the Astro universe outside of Astro's Playroom, so starting [here] with the name Astro Bot made a lot of sense as a new beginning."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="375777567" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464379,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Astro%20Bot%20Finally%20Unleashes%20A%20Full-Scale%20Game&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:517,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/astro-bot-finally-unleashes-a-full-scale-game\/2300-6464379\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464379\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464379\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464379\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464379&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464379,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6524178&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;astro-bot&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,platformer&quot;,&quot;collection&quot;:&quot;summer-game-fest-2024&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;sony-interactive-entertainment&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;the-playroom-astro&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;the-playroom-astro&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464379},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464379\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4316709-astrobot_v1_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/O8Rnh48k.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1718208000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="O8Rnh48k" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Astro Bot Finally Unleashes A Full-Scale Game</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Doucet said that the VR game's success convinced the team to revisit the Astro Bot world with the PS5 pack-in that followed it, and they thought if a wider audience was <em>still </em>falling in love with the mascot and their world at that point, then they could go biggest of all with something else. Astro Bot is that something else.</p><p dir="ltr">From what I played, the differences between Astro Bot and its predecessors are obvious in some ways and subtle in others. The diverse levels I experienced took me across beaches like those in Astro's Playroom and a construction yard hung high above the clouds just like in Rescue Mission, but these familiar landscapes were clearly denser too, and the overworld seemed more like something from LittleBigPlanet, in which I could pilot a jet-propelled DualSense from planet to planet as I unlocked levels, bonus challenges, and more.</p><p dir="ltr">My favorite part of the game is its ability to feel almost clairvoyant. Every time I'd experiment with the environment by smashing up certain parts of it, climbing way up high, or tucking away into a corner expecting a secret, I would find one. The levels have a masterful way of guiding me down their correct paths, but also signaling where I may be rewarded for dashing down the B or C or even D paths. I'd find coins to spend or more bots dressed like Ratchet, Rivet, Kratos, and more of the game's 150+ cameos, which is a number Doucet revealed to me.</p><p dir="ltr">This perpetual cycle of exploration and reward pairs very well with the game's mechanics, which remain as tight as before and bring a few new DualSense toys with them. I don't just want to turn over every stone for the secrets I may find; I also just want to keep playing the game because it <em>feels</em> so good to play.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317367-astrobotannouncescreenshot06.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317367" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317367-astrobotannouncescreenshot06.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317367"></a><figcaption>With more than 150 cameos in the game, virtually every beloved PlayStation character can be discovered.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317367-astrobotannouncescreenshot06.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">"We've doubled down on the use of DualSense," Doucet said, adding that the game adds about 15 new power-ups in total, with only "three or four" shown in the debut trailer. One of those is the ability for Astro Bot to turn into a sponge, which uses adaptive triggers as you wring the robot dry to give you a feeling of becoming lighter. In my demo, I also equipped a rocket-boosted dog in a backpack, which shot me horizontally across some of the larger gaps or allowed me to smash through some obstacles. In my hands, the triggers kicked back forcefully to imitate the thrusters.</p><p dir="ltr">But the most clever use-case I learned of--though I didn't experience it in my demo--is a trick with the texture of some objects. Walls can hide hollow points with secrets on the other side, and as Astro grazes against these borders, reaching out and touching them like Nathan Drake passing through a doorframe, the feedback on the controller may indicate these secrets. For completionists, I suspect these will prove to be the trickiest, but perhaps most fulfilling, collectibles in the game. "We don't use it, like, tons and tons," added Doucet. "We use this feature just a bit, but enough to create that magic moment."</p><p dir="ltr">After two games that were beloved but constrained in different ways, 2024's Astro Bot seems destined to be full of magic moments. It launches September 6, exclusively on PS5.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Horizon Adventures Isn't Your Typical Lego Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-horizon-adventures-isnt-your-typical-lego-game/1100-6524180/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-horizon-adventures-isnt-your-typical-lego-game.899370/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-horizon-adventures-isnt-your-typical-lego-game/1100-6524180/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524180">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">The foundational elements of a Lego game have remained largely unchanged for 20+ years: Smash everything into bricks and studs, collect characters by the dozens, then use those characters to jump back into levels to solve puzzles that were previously gated off. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/lego-horizon-adventures/" data-ref-id="5000-631814">Lego Horizon Adventures</a> has a little bit of that DNA, and moving back to a fixed camera like the pre-Skywalker Saga games makes it look like a classic Lego game of yesteryear, but after playing 30 minutes in single-player and co-op, I came away thinking of it as the most cinematic Lego game to date. Rather than intensely focus on smashing and collecting things, it's putting the focus on Guerrilla's story--and putting that story through a kid-friendly filter.</p><p dir="ltr">"We were determined to make a Lego game unlike any other Lego game," James Windeler, narrative director at Guerrilla, told me after my hands-on session. "From a visual perspective, we wanted to make a statement in the sense that we wanted to create a playable Lego movie in terms of the visual quality. But one of the things that's really unique about it and very different from other games is that everything you see is made from individual bricks. Every asset could, in theory, be made from physical material, Lego pieces."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317370-lha_screen_cinematic_thunderjaw_toy_logo.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317370" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317370-lha_screen_cinematic_thunderjaw_toy_logo.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317370"></a><figcaption>Lego Horizon Adventures stands out from other Lego games in several ways, with the visuals being an immediately obvious example.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317370-lha_screen_cinematic_thunderjaw_toy_logo.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">He's right, of course. Traditionally, Lego games involve bricks in the playable area and backgrounds made to look more like traditional video game environments, and that difference here, paired with the gorgeous visuals, really makes Lego Horizon Adventures stand out instantly when you see it.</p><p dir="ltr">But playing it feels a bit different than classic Lego games, too. Sure, you can smash up some of the environment to collect studs, but not nearly as much as in other Lego games, and there seemed to be no stud counter demanding you unlock some status such as "True Adventurer." That's because this isn't really a collect-a-thon like Lego Batman or Lego Star Wars. It is, as Winderler says, like playing a Lego movie starring Aloy, Rost, and other stars of Horizon Zero Dawn.</p><p dir="ltr">And I do mean Zero Dawn specifically. Lego Horizon Adventures reshapes the 2017 game in key ways to be more appealing and appropriate for kids, but without totally reimagining its story. "It's not a faithful retelling, and neither is it a parody," explained Windeler, who said the game will take players about 7-8 hours to complete, though there are elements of replayability to be revealed later. "We wanted to poke fun at the IP; we wanted to use all the self-referential humor that's characteristic of Lego properties.</p><p dir="ltr">"We also very much wanted to make sure that the game had a very broad appeal [...] We didn't make the whole open-world game and put it in here. We told a story that we felt captured some of the spirit of the original, some of the themes [...] It's more of an inspiration."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317371-lha_ps5_screen_cauldron_logo.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317371" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317371-lha_ps5_screen_cauldron_logo.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317371"></a><figcaption>Lego Horizon Adventures can be played alone, but it's designed for co-op between family members or friends, either locally or online.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317371-lha_ps5_screen_cauldron_logo.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Given how those themes originally included things like climate change and corporations' habit of commandeering a dilemma to present a solution before making matters worse, I wondered how much of the game would go into those beats specifically. "We definitely pushed some of the more complicated and truly dark themes very much into the background. Those ideas are in the game, but they're very subtle," he said. "You know, the story takes place more in the present and is very much focused around the more emotional story of a girl looking for her mother who gets drawn into an adventure with existential stakes."</p><p dir="ltr">Just as it translates the story and world into bricks and minifigs, one of the coolest parts of my demo was how it transforms the series' weak-spot targeting system into a simpler version that less experienced players can grapple with more easily, specifically on the Nintendo Switch's small controllers. "A lot of thinking went into that," Windeler revealed.</p><p dir="ltr">"But we also wanted to make sure that we maintained the kind of level of tactical thinking and combat that the fans of the franchise might be used to, too. So even though the control schemes are quite simple, you will recognize mechanics, like [focusing] on the weak spot, but also, there's like a complexity; there's a difficulty slider, and if you slide it up, there's a requirement to really kind of engage on a tactical level."</p><p dir="ltr">In practice, this involves holding the aim button at a machine's parts as they glow a vibrant yellow, just like in the traditional Horizon games, then releasing it to hit the robotic beast in that spot. Players can also sneak around in the tall grass and even kick off wildfires that propagate across the brick-filled landscape, causing chaos and even sometimes solving environmental puzzles.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317372-lha_ps5_screen_mothers_heart_logo.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317372" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317372-lha_ps5_screen_mothers_heart_logo.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317372"></a><figcaption>Mother's Heart is a customizable hub you'll return to, perhaps to build things like hot dog carts or roller coasters.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4317372-lha_ps5_screen_mothers_heart_logo.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">And of course, in two-player co-op, all of these elements can be doubled, creating a kid-friendly combat system that is still more like an action-adventure game rather than a traditional Lego game, which tends to a button-mashy brawler. In a word, Winderler called Lego Horizon Adventures' combat systems "frantic."</p><p dir="ltr">With Lego Horizon Adventures reimagining the story, whether it's for a visual gag or just to make it a better family gaming experience, I asked if Guerrilla ever flinches at the task of taking a character like Aloy, whom the studio has always spoken so highly of, and turning her almost into a caricature of herself. But Windeler doesn't see a conflict there.</p><p dir="ltr">"We do have the single-player games, you know," he said. "We're still very protective of the characters in that canon, [but] everyone who was involved in this wanted to have fun with it. There are still some heart-wrenching moments in the story. And like, we're not completely skipping out on the emotion of the original story. But it's definitely meant to bring joy to people."</p><p dir="ltr">Lego Horizon Adventures arrives on PS5, PC, and--yes--Nintendo Switch this holiday season.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox June Update Out Now, Here's What It Does]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-june-update-out-now-heres-what-it-does/1100-6524208/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-june-update-out-now-heres-what-it-does.899364/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-june-update-out-now-heres-what-it-does/1100-6524208/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524208">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The latest Xbox firmware update has arrived, ushering in a set of changes and improvements. Microsoft ran through the changes in a <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/06/12/xbox-june-update/?ocid=Platform_soc_omc_xbo_tw_Link_lrn_6.12.1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">blog post</a>, and we are highlighting the key takeaways below.</p><p>First off, the update gives players more personalization options for their backgrounds. Players previously had to choose if they wanted a dynamic background or game art when hovering over a title. But with this new update, users have both options available at the same time. You can find this new option by navigating this way: Settings &gt; General &gt; Personalization &gt; My Background &gt; Show selected game art. Additionally, a new setting allows players to change the color of their dynamic background without changing their default profile color.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4317830-screenshot2024-06-12at12.05.16pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317830" data-ratio="0.56716417910448" data-width="1005" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4317830-screenshot2024-06-12at12.05.16pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4317830"></a><figcaption>The latest Xbox update is out now</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4317830-screenshot2024-06-12at12.05.16pm.png"></figure><p>The June update also makes changes to wireless settings with the aim of making it easier to switch between Wi-fi networks if you need to do that, like in the event you bring your Xbox on a trip. Your Xbox can now remember up to 10 networks, and you can now connect to them without inputting a password again.</p><p>Additionally, this new update allows users to manage their subscriptions directly from the Xbox instead of outside the console platform. Microsoft also noted that users might see experimental features in June, including different Game Pass page layout styles, more information in search card results, and the ability to find specific people using search.</p><p>Beyond the console updates, Xbox wireless controllers are getting a new firmware update this June. Specifically, the Xbox Adaptive controller now has support for additional USB accessories, with each port now supporting up to 12 buttons, along with a second stick, and a hat switch.</p><p>For the Xbox App on PC, the June update introduces a new Game Pass "sub navigation" menu that makes it easier to browse through the catalog. In terms of cloud gaming changes, players can now self-manage game data and cloud saves to help out in situations like troubleshooting corrupted save data or resetting a game to its original state for anyone who wants to start a game over. Finally, mouse and keyboard support for cloud gaming is now available for all players following a testing period.</p><p>Many of these features were made available first to members of the Xbox Insider program, which is <a href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/account-profile/manage-account/xbox-insider-program" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">free to join and open for everyone.</a></p><p>In other Xbox news, Microsoft announced three new Xbox consoles during the Xbox Games Showcase, including a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-announces-new-all-digital-xbox-series-x/1100-6524077/" data-ref-id="1100-6524077">$600 Xbox Series X with a 2 TB hard drive.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix games boss Mike Verdu moving on to new role]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflix-games-boss-mike-verdu-moving-on-to-new-role</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix-games-boss-mike-verdu-moving-on-to-new-role.899361/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflix-games-boss-mike-verdu-moving-on-to-new-role<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Former EA and Facebook exec will remain leader of Netflix's games efforts until replacement is found</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Netflix's VP of Games Mike Verdu is taking on a new role as the company ramps up its ambitions in the video games space.</p>
<p>A former Facebook and EA exec, Verdu first <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflix-hires-new-vp-of-game-development">joined Netflix in 2021</a> ahead of the streaming firm announcing its push into mobile games.</p>
<p>The details of his new position are unclear at this time, but <em>GamesIndustry.biz</em> understands it involves 'innovation in game development.'</p>
<p>He will continue to lead Netflix's video games business until a replacement is found.</p>
<p>"I am so proud of what we’ve accomplished, and excited to start a new team at Netflix on the cutting edge of game innovation," said Verdu. "New technologies have always been key to creativity in games development and, as an entrepreneur at heart, this initiative is right in my happy place."</p>
<p>Since Verdu joined Netflix, the company has launched 100 titles for its subscribers, including internally developed games based on some of the firm's most popular shows such as Too Hot to Handle, Virgin River and Money Heist.</p>
<p>Netflix has also acquired multiple studios, including <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflix-acquires-oxenfree-developer-night-school-studio-0">Night School</a>, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflix-continues-games-push-with-boss-fight-entertainment-acquisition">Boss Fight</a>, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflix-to-acquire-next-games">Next Games</a> and <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflix-acquires-spry-fox-as-sixth-internal-studio">Spry Fox</a>, and opened two more in <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflix-opening-fifth-studio-and-seriously-exploring-cloud-gaming">California</a> and <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflix-launches-new-studio-in-finland">Helsinki</a>, all of which are focused on creating new games for the service.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring tops 25 million in players and sales ahead of expansion launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/elden-ring-tops-25-million-in-players-and-sales-ahead-of-expansion-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-tops-25-million-in-players-and-sales-ahead-of-expansion-launch.899358/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/elden-ring-tops-25-million-in-players-and-sales-ahead-of-expansion-launch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via FromSoftware/Bandai Namco.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/fromsoftware_pr/status/1800891340374642989">FromSoftware</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has revealed that Elden Ring has crossed a new sales milestone of over 25 million copies. Just a few months ago, in February, on the day of its two-year anniversary, it had sold 23 million units.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The fantasy RPG has been a consistently strong seller since its launch in 2022. But the new number takes on extra significance due to the launch of its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Shadow of the Erdtree </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">expansion on June 21.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Similarly, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">player count has now reached </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1800890964925366476">25 million players</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> across all systems. To this, FromSoftware thanked players "for your passion and support. We have come a long way together."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Erdtree </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">will be the game's one and only expansion, and its release will likely grow its already larger player base and sales. But in February, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.fromsoftware.jp/ww/pressrelease_detail.html?tgt=20230222_eldenring_salesdata">FromSoftware</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> said it'd keep making "various ways for players to enjoy the world of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in the future."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astro Bot makes the tech demo mascot into leading bot material]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/astro-bot-s-next-solo-title-takes-him-from-tech-demo-mascot-to-lead-material</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/astro-bot-makes-the-tech-demo-mascot-into-leading-bot-material.899355/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/astro-bot-s-next-solo-title-takes-him-from-tech-demo-mascot-to-lead-material<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via Team Asobi/PlayStation</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">PlayStation has found its very own cute platformer mascot in the modern age with Astro, the hero of the Astro Bot series from developer Team Asobi. He burst onto the scene in 2018 with the critically acclaimed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot: Rescue Mission</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for PS4 and PlayStation VR. His follow-up adventure, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro’s Playroom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, was released in 2020 and came pre-installed with every PS5 console.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Those two games both debuted as demonstrations of major technology rollouts for the company. In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Rescue Mission</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Asobi used Astro Bot to show off the capabilities of PSVR, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro's Playroom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> introduced the computing power capabilities of the PS5—capabilities that many developers have yet to fully take advantage of.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If other developers aren't using that processing power—well then the little bot will just do it himself. Earlier this month Sony announced that Astro’s journey would continue in the upcoming PS5 game, titled </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://youtu.be/wHMNQzLG_Jg?si=Q57_ZiQidXmWeeRk">Astro Bot</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer spent some time playing Astro Bot at Summer Game Fest and spoke with director Nicolas Doucet about what it’s like to make a game with a character previously known for showing off tech demos and expanding even more on the haptic feedback features of the DualSense controller.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Astro Bot"><span>Astro Bot</span> shows off more power from the PS5</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Doucet said that Team Asobi went with the simple name </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in order to distinguish that it’s a big story for Astro and a new beginning. The studio’s first two games were released in 2016 called </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Playroom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Playroom VR</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which could be described as tech demos to show off the capabilities of PS4’s DualShock 4 controller and the PSVR headset.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That naming convention transferred over to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro’s Playroom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. “So we use that word on purpose to really establish that this is a toy, just a tech demo,” Doucet explained. “Now the name is free so we can make something big and really start from there.”</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Team Asobi learned from developing </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Rescue Mission</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro’s Playroom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that the gameplay has to continually keep the experience fresh, which is why the team created 15 new powers for Astro to utilize when going traversing through levels. With </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, a big focus was creating many different kinds of planets and worlds filled with unique gameplay mechanics.</span></p><p>Image via Team Asobi/PlayStation</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Three of Astro’s new powers were playable during the hands-on segment. These included Astro puffing himself up like a balloon to reach new heights, a backpack that lets him charge at enemies, and a pair of spring arms to hit enemies from afar.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">“It's more about what’s going to be the next surprise that the game throws at you. In order to keep that going, we have to be really inventive and creative,” said Doucet.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There were several different ways that Team Asobi prototyped new DualSense features. In one independent demo separate from the game, the developers had this idea of turning Astro into a sponge. The adaptive triggers would feel heavy, like how a sponge would be filled with water. But when pressed down, water would squeeze out and then the triggers would feel light.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Doucet also revealed another DualSense haptic feedback feature that wasn’t shown off in the demo. There are moments in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> where players can stroke their hand and run Astro against the wall. And according to a change of texture, you can feel when you’ve stumbled across a secret passage.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">“That's something that could be done with normal vibration, but it would’ve been very primitive,” Doucet said. “With the DualSense, it has so much finesse that you can actually feel the difference in expression.”</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">’s level design and layout have changed from previous games too. In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro’s Playroom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the levels were laid out with some platforming, then some mini-games, then back to platforming. Doucet noted that the big difference in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is that every power up and ability supports the game’s basic platformer mechanics.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The overworld has been structured similar to something like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Super Mario Galaxy</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Astro can fly around in his ship to decide on which world to tackle next. There are six galaxies and 80 levels in total, which include the main campaign, side levels, and secret ones. This approach was made to provide players more freedom in the order they want to tackle levels as they unlock.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In these levels, Astro can find his missing bot crewmates hidden as collectibles. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will also feature over 150 VIP bots, which are cameos from other PlayStation franchises.</span></p><p>Image via Team Asobi/PlayStation.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The demo included bot versions of Kratos and Atreus from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>God of War</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Once found, this caused their own unique level to appear in the galaxy, although it remained locked in the demo. While Doucet wouldn’t reveal what made those levels distinguishable from normal ones just yet, he explained that the team didn’t want the cameo characters to just be simple background decorations.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Why doesn't ">Why doesn't <span>Astro Bot</span> support PSVR2?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Despite PlayStation showing support to its franchises in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> through these cameos, including seemingly forgotten ones such as Parappa the Rappa, Ape Escape, and LocoRoco, the game doesn’t seem to support PlayStation’s latest venture, PSVR 2.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot: Rescue Mission</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was exclusive to PSVR and couldn’t be played without a headset on PS4, while </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> doesn’t require a PSVR 2 setup at all. When asked if Team Asobi would be open to bringing Astro Bot back to the world of VR on Sony’s next-generation headset, Doucet said, “We’ve only been thinking about PS5 at the moment. That's been our main focus.”</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monopoly GO: All Grease And Glory rewards and milestones]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/monopoly-go-all-grease-and-glory-rewards-and-milestones/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=monopoly-go-all-grease-and-glory-rewards-and-milestones</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monopoly-go-all-grease-and-glory-rewards-and-milestones.899352/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/monopoly-go-all-grease-and-glory-rewards-and-milestones/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=monopoly-go-all-grease-and-glory-rewards-and-milestones<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="390" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">It’s time to get your cars ready as you advance through several racing-themed events in <em>Monopoly GO</em>, from the debut of the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/monopoly-go-tycoon-racers-guide-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tycoon Racers event</a> to today’s Grease and Glory tournament. You can get a few thousand dice from milestone and leaderboard ranking prizes and thousands of Tycoon Racers flags for a chance to win a wild sticker. Let’s check out the full rewards list.</p> <h2 id="h-all-monopoly-go-grease-and-glory-tournament-rewards-and-milestones" data-injectable="false">All Monopoly GO Grease And Glory tournament rewards and milestones</h2> <p data-characters="253" data-current-count="253" data-injectable="false"><em>Monopoly GO’s</em> Grease and Glory tournament has 30 rewards up for grabs until June 13, 2024. Alongside 4,140 dice and several sticker packs, you can get 2,320 <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/monopoly-go-how-to-get-free-tycoon-racers-flags/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tycoon Racers flags</a> for additional prizes. Below is Grease and Glory’s rewards list.</p> <figure data-found-rows="30" data-items-injection="true" data-current-count="1753" data-injectable="true"><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Tournament Level</th><th data-align="center">Point Required</th><th data-align="center">Rewards</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr data-index="0"><td data-align="center">1</td><td data-align="center">50</td><td data-align="center">60 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr data-index="1"><td data-align="center">2</td><td data-align="center">40</td><td data-align="center">45 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="2"><td data-align="center">3</td><td data-align="center">80</td><td data-align="center">100 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr data-index="3"><td data-align="center">4</td><td data-align="center">120</td><td data-align="center">One-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="4"><td data-align="center">5</td><td data-align="center">140</td><td data-align="center">160 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr data-index="5"><td data-align="center">6</td><td data-align="center">150</td><td data-align="center">120 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="6"><td data-align="center">7</td><td data-align="center">130</td><td data-align="center">160 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr data-index="7"><td data-align="center">8</td><td data-align="center">160</td><td data-align="center">Five minutes of High Roller</td></tr><tr data-index="8"><td data-align="center">9</td><td data-align="center">180</td><td data-align="center">180 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr data-index="9" data-injectable="true"><td data-align="center">10</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">150 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3">
</td></tr><tr data-index="10"><td data-align="center">11</td><td data-align="center">250</td><td data-align="center">Two-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="11"><td data-align="center">12</td><td data-align="center">225</td><td data-align="center">175 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="12"><td data-align="center">13</td><td data-align="center">300</td><td data-align="center">300 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr data-index="13"><td data-align="center">14</td><td data-align="center">320</td><td data-align="center">Three-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="14"><td data-align="center">15</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="15"><td data-align="center">16</td><td data-align="center">375</td><td data-align="center">300 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="16"><td data-align="center">17</td><td data-align="center">425</td><td data-align="center">320 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr data-index="17"><td data-align="center">18</td><td data-align="center">500</td><td data-align="center">Four-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="18"><td data-align="center">19</td><td data-align="center">600</td><td data-align="center">400 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="19" data-injectable="true"><td data-align="center">20</td><td data-align="center">650</td><td data-align="center">320 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3">
</td></tr><tr data-index="20"><td data-align="center">21</td><td data-align="center">550</td><td data-align="center">Four-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="21"><td data-align="center">22</td><td data-align="center">700</td><td data-align="center">20 minutes of Mega Heist</td></tr><tr data-index="22"><td data-align="center">23</td><td data-align="center">900</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="23"><td data-align="center">24</td><td data-align="center">1,100</td><td data-align="center">700 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="24"><td data-align="center">25</td><td data-align="center">1,000</td><td data-align="center">340 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr data-index="25"><td data-align="center">26</td><td data-align="center">1,300</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="26"><td data-align="center">27</td><td data-align="center">1,500</td><td data-align="center">850 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="27"><td data-align="center">28</td><td data-align="center">1,700</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="28"><td data-align="center">29</td><td data-align="center">2,000</td><td data-align="center">380 Tycoon Racers flags</td></tr><tr data-index="29"><td data-align="center">30</td><td data-align="center">2,200</td><td data-align="center">1,400 Dice Rolls</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
 <p data-characters="344" data-current-count="344" data-injectable="false">In particular, the flags are the highlight of this tournament, as they allow you to progress further in the ongoing Tycoon Racers event. Considering this has a chance to grant you a wild sticker, it’s worth trying to progress as far as you can, as this can make a huge difference when completing your card album by the season’s end.</p> <h2 id="h-how-to-score-points-in-the-monopoly-go-grease-and-glory-tournament" data-injectable="false">How to score points in the Monopoly GO Grease and Glory tournament</h2> <p data-characters="239" data-current-count="583" data-injectable="true">Scoring points during <em>Monopoly GO’s</em> Grease and Glory tournament requires landing on railroad spaces. Each railroad space leads to either a Landmark Shutdown or Bank Heist minigame, with the following outcomes determining your points:</p>
 <ul data-found-items="5" data-current-count="200" data-injectable="false"> <li>Shutdown – Blocked: Two points</li> <li>Shutdown – Success: Four points</li> <li>Bank Heist – Small: Four points</li> <li>Bank Heist – Large: Six points</li> <li>Bank Heist – Bankrupt: Eight points</li> </ul> <p data-characters="412" data-current-count="612" data-injectable="false">These points increase depending on your current dice multiplier, allowing you to gain more points per tile if you’re willing to use extra dice. However, this also means your supply will drain much faster, so watch your total dice count, just in case. Outside of this, you can use rewards from banner events like <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/monopoly-go-all-fast-and-luxurious-rewards-and-milestones/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fast and Luxurious</a> or the Tycoon Racers event to gain additional prizes, including extra dice.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here Are Some Cool Steam Demos I’ve Played]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/steam-next-fest-demos-summer-game-fest</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here-are-some-cool-steam-demos-i%E2%80%99ve-played.899349/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/steam-next-fest-demos-summer-game-fest<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>There’s another <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/nextfest" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam Next Fest</a> on, which means my hard drive is <a href="https://aftermath.site/tag/steam-next-fest" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">once again</a> full of tiny slices of games I wish I could play all of, but I can’t. The writer in me wants to find some kind of narrative cohesion to put all the ones I’ve checked out into the same blog, but their main connecting thread is that I liked them! Maybe you will like them too.</p><h2>Wax Heads</h2><div><figure><p><iframe title="Wax Heads Announcement Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pQLJKugCxJM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2769240/Wax_Heads/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Wax Heads</em></a> was announced earlier this year. In real life, I’m not a big fan of collecting things, including records, but I do love a video game where you have to do chores. In the demo, you play as a new record store employee who has to fill a steady stream of customer requests, searching the store for their desired record based on what customers tell you. Some are pretty straightforward: a brand new record, or one that’s on sale. Others are more complicated: do you recommend the newest album from a risque band to a young teen requesting it, or offer them a tamer, earlier release? Which album will satisfy this guy with a lot of opinions about a band’s membership over the years? What is this dude in a mascot head actually asking for?&nbsp;</p><p>It could feel like a hidden object game with music fandom slapped over it, but the world-building of the shop elevates the game into more than just hunting through rooms until you spot the right item. Albums have history and connection, the shop is full of rich little details, and there’s a plot percolating about the shop owner’s history and the shop’s future. Each album has a thoughtful track list and cover art, creating a real sense of a fictional music scene. Combined with side tasks like a flyer to make and an arcade game to play, even though the demo is just one day in the shop,<em> Wax Heads</em> feels full and engaging.</p><h2>Reka</h2><div><figure><p><iframe title="REKA - Official Gameplay Reveal Trailer | Future of Play Direct 2023" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hhZiJ1AFfyw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1737870/REKA/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Reka</em></a> was announced last year, and comes to Early Access in August. In the demo, you play as a girl who wanders into helping a witch, Baba Jaga, with a ritual to rebuild her home. That home is a customizable hut on giant chicken legs, in which you’ll travel the game’s world in the full release, but in the demo are confined to just stomping around dramatically at the end.&nbsp;</p><p>Most of what you do in the demo is fetching things the witch tells you to and helping her with a ritual, but rather than feeling simple, this paints the witch as a standoffish, mysterious character with secrets to impart that immediately made me want to know more about her. I’m a sucker for any game with woods, and the <em>Reka</em> demo has a beautiful slice of landscape to explore, full of items to loot for spells and little quests to do for the superstitious townspeople. The demo prevents you from stomping the town to pieces in the chicken hut, but lumbering over the treetops felt cool as hell, and I’m excited to see how the hut plays into the full game.</p><h2>One Btn Bosses</h2><div><figure><p><iframe title="One Btn Bosses - Official Reveal Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WldHLxkAW5g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>I’m not a big fan of boss battle games–or maybe, I want to be, but I suck at them. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1910600/ONE_BTN_BOSSES/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>One Btn Bosses</em></a> joins games like <em>Titan Souls </em>in bringing limited mechanics to boss battles–here, that you only press one button, which in the demo changes the direction of your geometric character along a track. There’s a bit of <em>Vampire Survivors</em> in the auto-shooting bullet hell vibe, but rather than increasing the number of enemies as that game does, each level in the demo brings a new attack to look out for. The levels are short and chaotic, asking you to manage your speed (moving in the same direction increases your damage output) and avoid the boss’ varied attacks. Your character can only take a few hits, and things get tough fast, but basically all you’re doing is dodging, which is mostly what I do in boss fights anyway.&nbsp;</p><h2>Grunn</h2><div><figure><p><iframe title="Grunn - Official Demo Trailer" width="710" height="533" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7vcX8m2_0Z0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2720950/Grunn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Grunn</em></a> is by Tom van den Boogaart, who you might remember from indie “walk around a weird space station” game <em>Bernband</em>. In <em>Grunn</em>, you’re walking around a dilapidated garden, with a list of chores to complete over a weekend. The game’s trailer makes it very clear all is not as it seems, but I was still taken by surprise when things got weird. (Be aware there’s jumpscares, which are objectively not scary but scared the heck out of me because I’m a horror wuss.) The demo has multiple endings to see, and I’m curious about what’s really going on despite how loudly I yelled “No!” at the faintest whiff of creepiness. At the very least, it’s satisfyingly inefficient to cut the entire estate’s grass with hedge clippers.</p><h2>Fruitbus</h2><div><figure><p><iframe title="Fruitbus - Official Announcement Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SxE6pwfrH0k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2484130/Fruitbus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Fruitbus</em></a> is by <em>Among the Sleep</em> studio Krillbite, but it has the opposite vibes of that game’s horror: you drive a food truck around a brightly colored world, serving little animal characters fruit salad. There’s a lot of buttons to press (my <a href="https://aftermath.site/pacific-drive-star-trucker-buttons-steam" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">favorite</a>) to turn the bus on and off, open the counter, and buy items at shops. While it seems you can buy a backpack to carry more stuff, I was incredibly charmed by how you can only hold two things in your hands at once, which led to me ferrying fruits I found back and forth, making multiple trips for change at shops, or fumbling with knives, bowls, and apples while characters waited for their food. There’s a plot about convincing people to come to your grandmother’s funeral, but I mostly careened around the game’s island in my bus, honking my horn and angering the locals.</p><h2>Morse</h2><div><figure><p><iframe title="MORSE Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q82n8ALqHxg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>I’m not sure if <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1976860/MORSE/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Morse</em></a> is part of Next Fest or Next Fest just led me to realize it has a demo, but it’s a game that’s been on my radar for a while now. You play as a Morse code operator in World War 1, fending off enemy soldiers, ships and planes by attacking squares using Morse code. At first, I struggled to get my head around it, frantically glancing between the dots and dashes of the various letters and the battle. But once it clicked, I started to feel accomplished in both strategy and Morse code, confidently tapping out letters and bouncing between rows. I’m really into the minimalist art style, and I love the whole idea of the game, so it was cool to play some of it. I don’t have a Playdate console, but there will be a version of it on there with a <a href="https://x.com/alexvscoding/status/1772966301813641495" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">custom physical controller </a>that looks deeply cool.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve and Steam Sued for Over $840m Over Claims of "Rigging the Market"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/valve-and-steam-sued-rigging-market</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-and-steam-sued-for-over-840m-over-claims-of-rigging-the-market.899322/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/valve-and-steam-sued-rigging-market<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Valve is being sued by a UK law firm to the tune of £656m (around $840m) over claims that the Steam service is ripping off consumers owing to unfair price parity obligations.</p>
<p>Per <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cpwwyj6v24xo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">the BBC</a>, UK law firm Milberg London LLP, which also brought a case making similar claims against Sony <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/sony-playstation-being-sued-for-5-billion-amid-claims-it-ripped-off-nine-million-consumers-12678949" rel="noopener" target="_blank">back in 2022</a>, is claiming that Valve uses its dominance over the digital PC gaming market to impose unfair charges on 14 million UK consumers.</p>
<p>Digital rights campaigner Vicki Shotbolt is leading the case, and she's alleging that Valve is "rigging the market" thanks to price parity obligations, which, according to Milberg London's claim, publishers on Steam are "force[d]" to sign up to.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/steam-valve-sued-storefront.jpg?itok=twNPsnqY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/steam-valve-sued-storefront.jpg?itok=iWz7ZaO0 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Valve is "rigging the market" with unfair price parity obligations, a new lawsuit claims.</figcaption></figure><p>According to Shotbolt and the claim, Valve makes publishers who want their games on Steam sign up to promise that they won't charge less for their games on other platforms.</p>
<p>This leads to Valve being able to charge what Shotbolt calls "an excessive commission of up to 30%" on its games, which in turn drives prices up and forces consumers to pay more than they should.</p>
<p>The claim alleges that Valve has been engaging in this practice for at least six years, and that a victory would "stop this unlawful conduct" and help consumers "get back what they are owed".</p>
<p>Given that the Epic Games Store <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-epic-games-store-will-take-just-12-revenue-share">takes just 12%</a> compared to Valve's cut, but that games are rarely (if ever) cheaper on Epic's store, this claim seems like a slightly strange one, although given past form, it may only be a matter of time before those companies find themselves in Milberg London's sights as well.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/epic-games-store-storefront.jpg?itok=pZOVFcaq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/epic-games-store-storefront.jpg?itok=I0Xmz19P 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Other storefronts, like Epic, don't appear to be in Milberg London's crosshairs.</figcaption></figure><p>This also isn't the first time Valve has found itself in legal trouble over supposedly unfair price parity agreements.</p>
<p>Back in 2021, Valve was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/wolfire-games-accuses-valve-of-controlling-non-steam-game-prices">sued by Humble Bundle creator Wolfire Games</a>, which alleged that the Steam provider forced publishers to sign up for price parity agreements or risk having their games removed from Steam.</p>
<p>It seems like this is a legal argument that isn't going to go away for Valve, and given that Milberg London's case against Sony appears to still be ongoing, it may be one that comes back to haunt the Washington-based gaming giant. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>