<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 03:29:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Shadow Syndicate mixes a bit of LA Noire, a touch of Max Payne, and furries to make a game you should keep your eye on]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-shadow-syndicate-mixes-a-bit-of-la-noire-a-touch-of-max-payne-and-furries-to-make-a-game-you-should-keep-your-eye-on</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-shadow-syndicate-mixes-a-bit-of-la-noire-a-touch-of-max-payne-and-furries-to-make-a-game-you-should-keep-your-eye-on.1180575/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-shadow-syndicate-mixes-a-bit-of-la-noire-a-touch-of-max-payne-and-furries-to-make-a-game-you-should-keep-your-eye-on<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>A wolf in human's clothing</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>KillaSoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Do you ever think to yourself, "gee, I wish that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/l-a-noire">LA Noire</a> actually looked like a noir film and also everyone is a furry"? Then boy howdy do I have the game for you: The Shadow Syndicate. It just got announced yesterday at the Gamescom Latam showcase, and I should say it's not exactly like LA Noire in that you don't have to try and read the faces of motion capture actors overperforming their hearts out. What it does have is some detective work, gunplay, and even some <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/max-payne">Max Payneish</a> bullet-time. How can you not be into that mixture?
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
The game is set in an early 1930s Brooklyn, and you play as private detective Sam Marlowe. According to a press release, Sam's mentor has gone missing, and alongside that there's a weird secret group getting up to no good. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Shadow Syndicate - Official World Premiere Reveal Trailer - FGS Live From gamescom latam" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zcxW7qOesd8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Shadow Syndicate - Official World Premiere Reveal Trailer - FGS Live From gamescom latam</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zcxW7qOesd8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zcxW7qOesd8?autoplay=1" title="The Shadow Syndicate - Official World Premiere Reveal Trailer - FGS Live From gamescom latam">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zcxW7qOesd8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
I would like to point out there is also essentially zero mention of the fact that everyone is an anthropomorphic animal anywhere in said press release, the only mention it gets is "evocative character designs", which they certainly are. I'm into it though, this is a hard-boildish Noir we're talking about, everyone being a dog or a chicken is just the way of the world, don't think about it too hard.
</p>
<p>
There's two parts to the gameplay, one being the aforementioned <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-action-games">action</a> gunplay, which does seem to borrow from Max Payne's iconic mechanic. The other is talking to citizens to collect clues, as well as interacting with the city at large, all of which gets jotted down in Sam's journal to help open up new dialogue options and story paths.
</p>
<p>
Unfortunately, The Shadow Syndicate doesn't have an exact release date just yet. It's due out some time in 2026 at the very least, and in the meantime, you can always <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3668300/The_Shadow_Syndicate/">wishlist it on Steam</a>.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There's a new Honkai game on the way with characters from Star Rail and Impact 3rd, and it sure does look like a Pokemon clone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/theres-a-new-honkai-game-on-the-way-with-characters-from-star-rail-and-impact-3rd-and-it-sure-does-look-like-a-pokemon-clone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/theres-a-new-honkai-game-on-the-way-with-characters-from-star-rail-and-impact-3rd-and-it-sure-does-look-like-a-pokemon-clone.1180569/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/theres-a-new-honkai-game-on-the-way-with-characters-from-star-rail-and-impact-3rd-and-it-sure-does-look-like-a-pokemon-clone<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Just don't expect much from the trailer</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>HoYoVerse</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I'm not sure how they have time for it, but as part of a livestream held earlier today, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/hoyoverse">HoYoVerse</a> revealed yet another new game. This one isn't a completely new world, it's actually another Honkai game, though right now it doesn't have a name. A very short teaser was shared for it which literally just called it a "brand new Honkai game", but there were a couple of signs that it was one anyway. Namely, the presence of a couple of characters, Kiana and Blade.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Kiana isn't from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/honkai-star-rail">Star Rail</a>, she's from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/honkai-impact">Impact 3rd</a>, one of the main characters in fact, and Blade is a playable character in Star Rail, so it seems like there's a bit of a crossover going on here. The teaser doesn't have a lick of gameplay, it's just a pre-rendered cutscene, but I think it's a safe bet on being some kind of Pokemon clone. 
</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="547"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HonkaiStarRail/comments/1kdsy74/new_honkai_game_announced/">New Honkai Game announced</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Vegetable-Feedback11/">u/Vegetable-Feedback11</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HonkaiStarRail/">HonkaiStarRail</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>
When Kiana rocks up she's accompanied by the most gelatinous looking dog creature you've ever seen in your life. Blade also has a dog thing with him, though his one's a bit cooler, and the two dogs are shown charging towards each other for a fight. You can see a couple of other characters that also have their own critters with them, so, this really does come across as HoYoVerse starting to stake their claim on Pokemon's cash cow.
</p>
<p>
There's as strong possibility of the game being named Honkai: Nexus Anima as the fan-run account <a href="https://x.com/StarRailVerse1/status/1915725508639179139">Star Rail Universe</a> found that a bunch of Twitter accounts have been registered with that name. I guess we'll have to wait and see on that one.
</p>
<p>
Pokemon doesn't seem like the only game that HoYoVerse is going after, as there's been leaks and other social media accounts spotted to do with a <a href="https://www.vg247.com/hoyoverse-stardew-valley-style-game-astaweave-haven-wechat-account-potential-announcement-soon">game that might be in the vein of Stardew Valley</a>. This is what I mean about them being so busy! Guess they really just want to have a game for every genre.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: Monster Hunter Wilds, 11th Gen iPad, Xbox Series X, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-may-3-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-monster-hunter-wilds-11th-gen-ipad-xbox-series-x-and-more.1180554/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-may-3-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Hunting for great deals.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The weekend is officially here, and we've rounded up the best deals you can find! Discover the best deals for May 3 below:</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Monster Hunter Wilds for $54.99</h2><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220084"><div id="220084" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Monster Hunter Wilds - Standard Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter Wilds is still one of the biggest games of 2025, and you can save $15 off the PS5 version for a limited time at Woot. This is by far the most beginner-friendly Monster Hunter to date, with new features like Focus Mode that allow you to approach fights in new ways. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, "Monster Hunter Wilds continues to smooth off the rougher corners of the series in smart ways, making for some extremely fun fights but also lacking any real challenge."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">11th Gen iPad for $299</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219548"><div id="219548" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>New Apple iPad 11-inch: A16 chip, 11-inch Model - 128GB</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">First up, you can save $50 off the newest iPad. Powered by the A16, the newest <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/apple-ipad-11th-generation">11th-generation iPad</a> is an exceptional addition to any workspace. You can use this device with both <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ipad-accessories">Apple Pencil and Magic Keyboard Folio</a> to make the most out of it without having to go for the iPad Air or iPad Pro. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pre-Order Ghost of Yotei Now</h2></div><div catalogid="e3234859-17ec-4093-81f2-be710ac1b038" id="220005"><div id="220005" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Ghost of Yotei (PS5)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Ghost of Yotei is finally up for pre-order at Amazon. Set in the Hokkaido region in 1603, you'll play as Atsu to gain revenge on those who killed your family. While not much has been revealed for this game yet, we can expect Yotei to play very similarly to its predecessor, Ghost of Tsushima. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Visions of Mana for $34.99</h2></div><div id="219546" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Visions of Mana - Amazon Exclusive Edition (PS5)</h3></p></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219547"><div id="219547" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Visions of Mana - Amazon Exclusive Edition (XSX)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Visions of Mana released at the end of August, and it's available on sale for the first time this weekend. This is the first new Mana game in almost two decades, starring a cast of characters on a quest to save the world. In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-review">our 8/10 review</a>, we stated, "Visions of Mana finally brings the long-dormant classic RPG series into the modern age, looking great and playing even better thanks to multi-layered class and skill systems that interact in clever ways."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Xbox Series X for $479.99</h2></div><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220085"><div id="220085" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xbox Series X 1TB SSD Console</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Xbox announced this week <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-raises-the-price-of-all-xbox-series-consoles-xbox-games-confirmed-to-hit-80-this-holiday">that the Xbox Series X will increase in price by $100 in the United States</a>. This puts the almost five-year-old console at $599.99, but you can still score an Xbox Series X for under its previous MSRP at Amazon right now. At $479.99, you're saving $120 off the new price of Xbox Series X, and there's no telling when or if we will see it this low again soon.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga for $10</h2></div><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220086"><div id="220086" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga - Standard Edition - PlayStation 4</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga is by far the biggest LEGO game available, with hundreds of characters to collect across numerous planets. You can pick up the game for just $10 at Amazon right now for PS4, making this a deal you won't want to pass on. All nine films are included in this game, with characters from newer Disney+ Star Wars series as well.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Super Mario Party Jamboree for $44.99</h2></div><div catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9" id="218600"><div id="218600" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">With the recent reveal of Nintendo Switch 2 Edition games, it's no question that you are going to want to save anywhere you can. The Nintendo Switch 2 Edition of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-party-jamboree-review">Super Mario Party Jamboree</a> is set to cost $79.99, but you can upgrade from a Nintendo Switch copy for presumably $20. This weekend, save your cash and pick up a copy of Super Mario Party Jamboree from Woot for only $44.99.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>May 3, 2025 6:04 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No, sorry, put the party poppers away, Chrono Trigger isn't getting a remake, as far as anyone knows anyway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-sorry-put-the-party-poppers-away-chrono-trigger-isnt-getting-a-remake-as-far-as-anyone-knows-anyway</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-sorry-put-the-party-poppers-away-chrono-trigger-isnt-getting-a-remake-as-far-as-anyone-knows-anyway.1180521/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-sorry-put-the-party-poppers-away-chrono-trigger-isnt-getting-a-remake-as-far-as-anyone-knows-anyway<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Time travel won't fix this goof</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Square Enix</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Well, this is all a bit awkward. Yesterday, you might have seen claims that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/chrono-trigger">Chrono Trigger</a> writer Yuji Horii accidentally confirmed that a remake of the beloved <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-japanese-games-to-play-on-pc">JRPG</a> is in the works. It all read a bit suspicious right off the bat, because it initially just came from a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/chronotrigger/comments/1kd1gij/yuji_horii_confirms_chrono_trigger_remake_at/?sort=new">Reddit post</a> from someone who attended a panel Horii was speaking at during Napoli Comicon without any video evidence. Then some other posts started cropping up, alongside commenters saying they were also there and that this was true. Except, it isn't true, because it was all a translation miscommunication.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Later on in the day, a <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2448211166?t=18941s">Twitch VOD</a> was shared of the event, where <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/gematsu.com/post/3lo7v4b6jdc23">Gematsu</a> was able to confirm that Horii didn't actually mention anything about a remake of Chrono Trigger at all. It seems that somehow the interpreter interpreted something Horii said as confirmation of a remake. I can't tell you how that happened though, as I neither speak Japanese nor Italian. Go figure!
</p>
<p>
It's not exactly a surprise that such a story got people so excited so quickly. After all, on the game's 30th anniversary back in March, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> noted that they <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-celebrating-chrono-trigger-anniversary-with-new-projects-sparking-re-release-hopes">plan to share word of various projects</a> that "go beyond the world of the game" later this year. I can't exactly blame someone for thinking that that's code for "a remake is coming", and for all I know one still is happening. It just hasn't been accidentally revealed by one of its lead writers, that's all.
</p>
<p>
Personally, I don't even think it needs a remake. I'd imagine it would be an HD-2D one in the style of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-quest">Dragon Quest</a> 3 and Live A Live, which while pretty, just feels pretty unnecessary. Of course, none of you can hold this against me if one does get announced and I think it looks cool, actually, ok? Cheers.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign is no Bloodborne 2, but you can dress up as a hunter at the very least]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-is-no-bloodborne-2-but-you-can-dress-up-as-a-hunter-at-the-very-least</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-is-no-bloodborne-2-but-you-can-dress-up-as-a-hunter-at-the-very-least.1180515/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-is-no-bloodborne-2-but-you-can-dress-up-as-a-hunter-at-the-very-least<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>A hoonter, in search of the Elden Ring you say?</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>FromSoftware</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
We're not too far off <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a> now, with the spinoff game due out right at the end of the month. Some of you might have even played some of it already, unlike James, who struggled to play any of it at all when the test was held <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ten-pc-games-i-could-have-played-in-full-during-the-time-i-spent-failing-to-connect-to-elden-ring-nightreign-on-ps5">back in February</a>. Considering how few of us have actually spent any time on it overall though, quite conveniently <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/fromsoftware">FromSoftware</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> shared a little overview trailer yesterday that dove into what you'll be doing in the Fortniteish Souls game.
</p>
<p>
When you first drop into Limveld, you'll be doing so pretty weak as a level one character. From there, you can fight just regular old enemies, loot some treasure chests, the typical kind of thing you'd do in the original <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a>. One thing that differs is that you can also sneak into different bases to try to get some info from some maps about the land. And, of course, there's also some big blighters that'll knock you down pretty easily if you're not careful you can try to take a whack at if you're feeling brave enough for some bigger rewards.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN | Overview Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p2uYT8BQefA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN | Overview Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p2uYT8BQefA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/p2uYT8BQefA?autoplay=1" title="ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN | Overview Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p2uYT8BQefA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Another big difference is random events that can take place. As you might already know, from session to session the maps change shape, sometimes much more dramatically than others. Sometimes there'll be a volcanic area that erupts, or you'll have to trek through some woods full of rot. That guy that calls you a foul tarnished might rock up too! There honestly looks to be quite a lot of variation.
</p>
<p>
The Fortnite constantly dwindling circle storm aspect of the game isn't just a case of it slowly killing you while you're outside it. By the time nightfall comes, you'll be forced into a very tiny circle, having to fend off some much tougher enemies.
</p>
<p>
You'll also find that this game's version of the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-how-to-get-to-roundtable-hold">Roundtable Hold</a> looks a bit different. It's here where you'll equip relics that have different effects. Just your usual stat buffs and improved skills kind of things from the looks of it, but it wasn't a particularly comprehensive look. 
</p>
<p>
There's an in-game currency called murk that lets you buy different outfits for the preset characters, so there'll be some amount of customisation at the very least. And yes, there is a Solaire of Astora costume, amongst references to other characters too. My favourite's the hunter outfit from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/bloodborne">Bloodborne</a>, which won't be a surprise to anyone that knows me.
</p>
<p>
On top of all that, despite not being able to make your own character, you can find something called fragments which unlock bits of the respective Nightfarers' backstory. And, of course, there's proper boss fights if you make it to the third day in a session. Wouldn't be a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-soulslike-games">Soulslike</a> without boss fights!
</p>
<p>
I'm still not entirely convinced by Nightreign as a concept, it's a smart way to reuse assets that's for sure. I just prefer my FromSoft games to be a little bit more handcrafted. Still, I'll keep my mouth shut until May 30th, when the game launches.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Talos Principle: Reawakened – In the Beginning – Castle Puzzle Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/the-talos-principle-reawakened-in-the-beginning-castle-puzzle-guide/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-talos-principle-reawakened-%E2%80%93-in-the-beginning-%E2%80%93-castle-puzzle-guide.1180497/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/the-talos-principle-reawakened-in-the-beginning-castle-puzzle-guide/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-talos-principle-reawakened-i-know-im-a-person-but-not-a-genius/">The Talos Principle: Reawakened</a> was a strong remaster, not just because it was a great Unreal Engine 5 upgrade for a decade-old game, but because it included a whole new expansion called In the Beginning.</p>
<p>In the Beginning includes 18 new puzzles for fans to solve, with <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=31026X886738&amp;isjs=1&amp;jv=15.7.1&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwccftech.com%2Fhow-to%2Fthe-talos-principle-reawakened-in-the-beginning-subway-escape-puzzle-guide%2F&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fnews%2Fapp%2F2806640%2Fview%2F519709875052217858%3Fl%3Denglish&amp;xs=1&amp;xtz=240&amp;xuuid=49867ab213c4ee089d653e284f7a2968&amp;xjsf=other_click__auxclick%20%5B2%5D">16 of those puzzles</a> being made by fans who collaborated with Croteam on the expansion. So it's no surprise that these are some of the most difficult puzzles to solve in The Talos Principle: Reawakened.</p>
<p>This guide will take you through how to solve the Castle puzzle in the expansion, one of the more complicated puzzles. If you don't want the whole solution, and just want a hint, then the best hint I can give is that you need to make lasers fly.</p>
<p>If you want the full solution, keep reading.</p>
<h2>The Talos Principle: Reawakened - In the Beginning - Castle Puzzle Guide</h2>
<h3>Phase One - Gather all the pieces</h3>
<p>When you enter the Castle puzzle area, you'll notice that the tetromino is on an elevated platform that you can only reach by a fan directly underneath it, and that you'll need to get both a red and blue laser to the nodes on either side of this elevated platform to reach the tetromino.</p>
<p>To do that, you first need all the pieces you'll need. Basically, this puzzle is one part gather the pieces, the other part execution.</p>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Start by grabbing the fan off the vent below where you fly up to the tetromino, and place the fan on the pressure switch directly in front of you.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>&nbsp;With the fan on the pressure switch, you'll be able to reach the first connector (C1). Connect it to the red node and red laser generator that you can see through the window, and the red node on the wall behind you.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Pick up the fan from the pressure switch, and use the fan that's activated to fly yourself (with the first fan in hand) over the gate and into the walled-off area with a deactivated fan vent and a second connector (C2).</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Place the fan on the vent to activate it, grab the connector and use it to get back across to the other room, without having to pass through the purple forcefield between them.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Bring C2 into the main puzzle area, and grab the fan you used to fly yourself over the gate the first time, and place it on the first pressure switch you activated. Now you're free to grab C1 and carry it to the center puzzle area, so that you have two connectors and a fan at your disposal.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Pick up the fan, and place it on the pressure switch on the left side of the center puzzle area.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab C1 and connect it to the red laser generator that's on the left side of the puzzle area, and place it down on the pressure switch on the right side of the puzzle area. Connect it to the red node in the room on the right side of the puzzle area to clear the path to a box.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Pick up the box and bring it to the center puzzle area.&nbsp;Place the box on the pressure switch on the left side of the puzzle area (removing the fan first) and using C1, connect it to the blue laser generator on the right side of the puzzle area and the blue node on the left side of the puzzle area. Place C1 on top of the box.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab C2 and connect it to the red laser generator, and the red node that's hidden behind the shield you're deactivating with the blue lasers to release the third connector (C3). Bring the third connector into the center puzzle area.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now you nearly have all the components you need. All that's left is the box stuck behind a shield on the right side of the center puzzle area, with a red and blue node on either side to deactivate it.</p>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Take the box off the pressure switch, and replace it with C1. Connect C1 to the red laser generator.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab C2 and connect it to the blue laser generator, and the blue node in the center puzzle area on the right side.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab C3 and connect it to C1 and the red node on the other side of the shield. Place C3 on top of the box, making sure the box is somewhere that you can angle C3 to hit C1 and the red node.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>If you've done it correctly, your laser layout will look something like this.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab the second box and bring it to the center puzzle area. You should now have two boxes, three connectors, and a fan at your disposal.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Phase Two - Make the lasers fly</h3>
<p>Now you have all the components, you're ready to make the lasers fly.</p>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab one box, head up the stairs on the right side of the center puzzle area and place it in front of the fan underneath the blue node. Do the same with the other box on the left side of the puzzle area.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab C1, and connect it to the blue laser generator, the blue node above the box, and the blue node that deactivates the shield blocking the way to the tetromino. Place it on top of the box under the blue node when you're done.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab the fan, and place it on the pressure switch on the right side of the room. Grab C3 and connect it to C1 and the blue laser generator. Make sure the angles are set, and when you place C3 down, you should see the box and C1 on top of it flying back and forth.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Grab C2 and connect it to the red laser generator, the red node above the box, and the red node that deactivates the shield blocking the way to the tetromino. Place it on the box when you're done.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Pick the fan back up, and place it on the pressure switch on the left side of the puzzle area. Grab C3 and connect it to C2 and the red laser generator. Again, ensuring the angels are right, when you place C3 down, the box and C2 should be flying back and forth.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Now you can pick up the fan, and place it down on the vent just below the elevated platform where the tetromino is.</li>
</ul>

<figure></figure>

<ul>
<li>Fly up to where the tetromino is, and the shield will be deactivated, letting you grab the tetromino to solve the puzzle.</li>
</ul>
<p>And that's how you solve the Castle puzzle in The Talos Principle: Reawakened's new In the Beginning expansion. A few of the steps can be done differently, but it all leads to the same final shape. At least, I think it does. Let me know if you figured out a different solution.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everyone's gutted about the GTA 6 delay except this guy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/everyones-gutted-about-the-gta-6-delay-except-this-guy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everyones-gutted-about-the-gta-6-delay-except-this-guy.1180488/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/everyones-gutted-about-the-gta-6-delay-except-this-guy<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Luke Dale / Rockstar / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>As fans come to terms with the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-everything-we-know-so-far-9357">GTA 6</a> delay - from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GTA6/comments/1kd7oq8/i_built_a_gta_6_countdown_website_because_therapy/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">creating countdowns "that are cheaper than therapy"</a> to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GTA6/comments/1kdp5pp/i_think_we_need_to_calm_ourselves_about_the_delay/">pleas to "calm ourselves"</a> - at least one person is delighted by the news: Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 actor, Luke Dale.</p>
<p>Dale, who portrayed Hans Capon in the game, took a glass-half view on the delay, writing on X/Twitter: "WE'RE IN WITH A SHOT! GOTY!", appending the hashtag #KCD2.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Review" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zAljLcUMomM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Review</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zAljLcUMomM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zAljLcUMomM?autoplay=1" title="Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Review">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's Eurogamer's Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 review.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zAljLcUMomM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>You see, while players have been salivating for the next instalment of the universally-acclaimed series - so much so that <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/take-two-interactive">Take-Two Interactive</a> boss Strauss Zelnick acknowledged the fervor for GTA 6 is "<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6s-release-date-is-still-secret-because-take-two-boss-wants-to-maintain-the-anticipation-and-excitement">the greatest anticipation [he's] ever seen for an entertainment property</a>" - developers and publishers of other games targeting a similar release window were understandably worried about accidentally butting up against GTA 6's launch. Even Gearbox's Randy Pitchford was forced to strenuously <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-not-the-reason-for-borderlands-4-release-date-change-randy-pitchford-insists">deny that bringing Borderlands 4's release date forward</a> had anything to do with GTA 6 (which turned out to be true).</p>
<p>And of course, Luke Dale is <em>not</em> the only person in the games industry to have puffed out a sigh of relief yesterday - he just chose to do so publicly. The silver lining now is that games that have already released in 2025 - and those that had been holding back on solidifying release dates until  GTA 6'a launch was confirmed - can feel more confident about securing an accolade or two in award ceremonies or best games of 2025 lists (thanks, <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/action-rpg/with-gta-6-delayed-to-2026-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-star-celebrates-were-in-with-a-shot-to-win-game-of-the-year-2025/">GamesRadar+</a>).</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>We gave <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-review">Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 three out of five stars</a>, writing: "This gorgeous medieval RPG continues to be just as divisive, prickly and abrasive as its predecessor."</p>
<p>Following a hugely successful launch that saw <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-hits-1m-sales-in-just-one-day">over 1m people snapping up Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 in just 24 hours</a>, developer Warhorse Studios continues to plug away at its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/kingdom-come-deliverance-2s-post-launch-roadmap-bringing-barbers-horse-riding-and-more">post-release roadmap</a>, mostly recently adding <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-gets-mod-support-a-barber-shop-and-over-a-thousand-fixes-and-improvements">mod support, a barber shop, and "over a thousand" fixes and improvements</a>.</p>
<p>Yesterday, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-delayed-to-2026">Rockstar announced it was delaying the launch of GTA 6 to 2026</a>. The highly-anticipated sequel will now arrive for PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S on 26th May 2026. Rockstar's confirmation of a delay follows months of speculation over whether the game would still make its 2025 launch window, despite assurances from Take-Two that the game was still on track.</p>
<p>No other information was announced by Rockstar at the time. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-first-trailer-released-early">Rockstar released GTA 6's first - and so far only - look at the game back in December 2023</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sandfall have no plans for more Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 just yet, but "chances are good" anyway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sandfall-have-no-plans-for-more-clair-obscur-expedition-33-just-yet-but-chances-are-good-anyway</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sandfall-have-no-plans-for-more-clair-obscur-expedition-33-just-yet-but-chances-are-good-anyway.1180476/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sandfall-have-no-plans-for-more-clair-obscur-expedition-33-just-yet-but-chances-are-good-anyway<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"We're honestly still just trying to process everything that's happening."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Kepler Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It seems like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> is doing quite alright for itself, 'ey? The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">J'RPG</a> was awarded Rock Paper Shotgun's coveted Bestest Bests badge by our own Nic in his <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review">review</a>, and by all accounts it's been received well by most everyone else too. Not that sales matter much in terms of a game's quality, but the fact that it's done well there as well at minimum means the lights are staying on at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/sandfall-interactive">Sandfall Interactive</a>. In fact it seems things are going better than just keeping the lights on, as it sounds like the developer is considering more of it, whatever that might be.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Earlier this week, screenshots of a conversation with the game's lead writer Jennifer Svedberg-Yen on Instagram were shared on <a href="https://www.neogaf.com/threads/chances-for-clair-obscure-expedition-33-dlc-are-good.1683512/">NeoGAF</a>, where she was asked if there's plans for any Clair Obscur DLC (cheers, <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/clair-obscur-expedition-33-dlc-has-a-good-chance-of-happening-according-to-games-lead-writer/">Vice</a>). Unsurprisingly, Svedberg-Yen said that as of now, there's "nothing concrete that I can say at the moment, we're honestly still just trying to process everything that's happening. It's been a lot to take in!"
</p>
<p>
The interesting bit followed that though, as Svedberg-Yen continued, "we've always said if there is a strong desire from the players that we would love to do something more, and based on the responses so far, I'd say chances are good." Now, that's obviously not a confirmation of any kind. It's not even the writer saying that there'll be DLC necessarily, just that there's hopes to do more, so it's still probably best to temper your expectations.
</p>
<p>
Still, it's nice to see an underdog do so well, especially in such a busy week for RPGs. Personally I'd love to see some DLC where they pop across the border to Germany, if only to have someone put a JRPG there.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘A Brand New Honkai Game’ teased at Honkai: Star Rail Concert 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/a-brand-new-honkai-game-teased-at-honkai-star-rail-concert-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98a-brand-new-honkai-game%E2%80%99-teased-at-honkai-star-rail-concert-2025.1180470/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/a-brand-new-honkai-game-teased-at-honkai-star-rail-concert-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > miHoYo [194 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mihoyo">miHoYo</a> teased “a brand new <em>Honkai</em> game” at its <em><a title="Games > Honkai: Star Rail [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/honkai-star-rail">Honkai: Star Rail</a></em> Concert 2025 in Shanghai today. <span id="more-962780"></span></p><p>The teaser trailer shows two creature trainers preparing to engage in a battle.</p><p>miHoyo recently filed trademarks for “<em>Honkai: Nexus Anima</em>” in the <a href="https://tsdr.uspto.gov/#caseNumber=99147879&amp;caseSearchType=US_APPLICATION&amp;caseType=DEFAULT&amp;searchType=statusSearch" target="_blank" rel="noopener">United States</a>, <a href="https://euipo.europa.eu/eSearch/#details/trademarks/019175494" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Europe</a>, <a href="https://www.kipris.or.kr/khome/search/searchResult.do" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Korea</a> (search “넥서스 아니마”), and so on. A <a href="https://honkai-nexus-anima.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">potential website</a> and Twitter accounts were also registered, including <a href="https://x.com/honkaina" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HonkaiNA</a>, <a href="https://x.com/honkaina_id" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HonkaiNA_ID</a>, <a href="https://x.com/honkaina_th" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HonkaiNA_TH</a>, <a href="https://x.com/honkaina_vn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HonkaiNA_VN</a>, <a href="https://x.com/honkaina_ru" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HonkaiNA_RU</a>, <a href="https://x.com/honkaina_de" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HonkaiNA_DE</a>, and <a href="https://x.com/honkaina_fr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HonkaiNA_FR</a>. While not yet confirmed, this could be the title of the new game.</p><p>Watch the teaser trailer below.</p><p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]--><br><video id="video-962780-1" width="640" height="360" poster="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Brand-New-Honkai-Tease_05-03-25_Video-Thumb.jpg" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://files.catbox.moe/kfuahi.mp4?_=1"><a href="https://files.catbox.moe/kfuahi.mp4">https://files.catbox.moe/kfuahi.mp4</a></video></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Thanks, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gachagaming/comments/1kdt0t0/teaser_for_a_brand_new_honkai_game/" target="_blank">r/GachaGaming</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honkai: Star Rail x Fate/stay night [Unlimited Blade Works] collaboration launches July 11]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/honkai-star-rail-x-fate-stay-night-unlimited-blade-works-collaboration-launches-july-11</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/honkai-star-rail-x-fate-stay-night-unlimited-blade-works-collaboration-launches-july-11.1180440/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/honkai-star-rail-x-fate-stay-night-unlimited-blade-works-collaboration-launches-july-11<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Saber and Archer join the fray.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/honkai-star-rail-version-2-4-update-finest-duel-under-the-pristine-blue-launches-july-31">July 2024-announced</a> <em><a title="Series > Fate [66 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a>/stay night [Unlimited Blade Works]</em> collaboration for <em><a title="Games > Honkai: Star Rail [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/honkai-star-rail">Honkai: Star Rail</a></em> will launch on July 11 as part of the version 3.6 update, <a title="Companies > miHoYo [194 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mihoyo">miHoYo</a> <a href="https://www.hoyolab.com/article/38584657" target="_blank">announced</a> (<a href="https://www.hoyolab.com/article/38584449" target="_blank">2</a>, <a href="https://www.hoyolab.com/article/38584566" target="_blank">3</a>). <span id="more-962773"></span></p><p>Here are the first details:</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ Special Collaboration Warp</strong></p><p>“Sweet Dreams and the Holy Grail: <em>Honkai: Star Rail</em> × <em>Fate/stay night [Unlimited Blade Works]</em> Collaboration” will officially launch on July 11.</p><p>Starting from July 11 at 12:00 (server time), Trailblazers can use Star Rail Special Passes to participate in the collaboration event and obtain the limited 5-star collaboration characters Saber (Destruction: Wind) and Archer (The Hunt: Quantum)!</p><p>This collaboration warp will be available over a long period of time.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>*The cumulative warp count for this collaboration warp is calculated independently of other warp types (e.g. “Character Event Warp”). Please stay tuned for future official announcements for more details about the warp details and warp event rules.</em></p><p><strong>Saber</strong></p><p><em>“Are you my master? My sword is yours to command. I will give it my all to bring you victory.”</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Honkai-Star-Rail-Fate_05-03-25_001.jpg"></a></figure><p>The solitary Heroic Spirit traverses the long night of fate. The banner of the round table remains unfurled in a dream. Alas, the knight-king of Camelot has yet to reach that ever distant utopia.</p><p>Though still a young maiden, she has heeded the call for this most unique iteration of the Holy Grail War. With the Sword in the Stone offering its choice once more, how shall she shatter the illusions of the past?</p><p>“The wishes I did not fulfil will end here.”</p><p><strong>Archer</strong></p><p><em>“First meeting, huh? Just call me Archer. Lucky for us, we’re not here to kill each other, so let’s keep things civil—if we can.”</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Honkai-Star-Rail-Fate_05-03-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>Despair plays in cycles from past and future. Countless grand ideals were incinerated before that red and sacred cloth. Yet, do not let this smear of ashes fool you…</p><p>Should someone create a phantasmal sweet dream under the guise of false ideals, then he will burn again, facing down the hypocrites of the world till the very end.</p><p>No matter where he is, he always remains justice’s steadfast companion.</p><p><strong>■ Log In to Claim Archer</strong></p><p>After July 11 at 12:00 (server time) and until Version 3.6 ends, Trailblazers can log in to the game to claim the limited 5-star collaboration character, Archer (The Hunt: Quantum), for free!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Honkai-Star-Rail-Fate_05-03-25_003.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>*Please refer to the follow-up announcements for detailed event rules.</em></p><p><strong>■ <em>Fate/stay night</em> Event</strong></p><p>In the planet of dreams, compete to gain the Holy Grail, which can realize all dreams, and summon historical celebrities as Servants – the first Penaconian Holy Grail War is about to begin! And the Trailblazer will be… Player?</p><p>From 12:00, July 11 (server time), the “Fate/stay night” event begins. Summon Heroic Spirits, use Command Seals, wield Noble Phantasms, and try different classes to win strategic battles!</p><p><em>*Please refer to the follow-up announcements for detailed event rules.</em></p></blockquote><p><em>Honkai: Star Rail</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,400 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [23,062 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://hsr.hoyoverse.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">client download</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/honkai-star-rail" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/honkai-star-rail/id1599719154" target="_blank" rel="noopener">App Store</a>, and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.HoYoverse.hkrpgoversea&amp;hl=en_US&amp;gl=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kiana and Blade star in "brand new" Honkai game announcement teaser]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/kiana-and-blade-star-in-brand-new-honkai-game-announcement-teaser</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kiana-and-blade-star-in-brand-new-honkai-game-announcement-teaser.1180437/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/kiana-and-blade-star-in-brand-new-honkai-game-announcement-teaser<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"What is going on lmao, Kiana and Blade with some funky Pokémon, this looks hilarious."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>MiHoYo</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>MiHoYo has just dropped a new teaser giving us our first peek at the "brand new" Honkai game on the way.</p>
<p>Developer MiHoYo announced the news in a livestream, and while it didn't get very much away at all - not even a name at this point - the developer urged players to "stay tuned" in a 20-second teaser showing the familiar faces of Kiana, Blade, and what looks like, but is not confirmed to be, Pokémon-esque or monster collecting gameplay.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Honkai: Star Rail Concert 2025: &quot;Hope Is the Thing With Feathers&quot;" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sH5GErffgWA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Honkai: Star Rail Concert 2025: "Hope Is the Thing With Feathers"</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sH5GErffgWA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/sH5GErffgWA?autoplay=1" title="Honkai: Star Rail Concert 2025: &quot;Hope Is the Thing With Feathers&quot;">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Honkai: Star Rail Concert 2025: "Hope Is the Thing With Feathers".<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sH5GErffgWA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Bro what?" said <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HonkaiStarRail/comments/1kdsy74/comment/mqdao5q/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">commenter</a> on the official subreddit. "What is going on lmao, Kiana and Blade with some funky Pokémon, this looks hilarious."</p>
<p>"Yup, this was shown a while ago in Mihoyo recruitment posters," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HonkaiStarRail/comments/1kdsy74/comment/mqdaz1y/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">opined</a> another. "I think it’s called Honkai: Nexus Anima. In an investor briefing, they recently showed that GGZ, HI3, HSR are all under the Honkai IP, separate from Genshin/ZZZ/ToT which are their own IPs. So we can expect characters from at least GGZ/HI3/HSR to appear in HNA.</p>
<p>"There is another called Petit Planet coming soon, which is like Animal Crossing/Stardew Valley."</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="547"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HonkaiStarRail/comments/1kdsy74/new_honkai_game_announced/">New Honkai Game announced</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Vegetable-Feedback11/">u/Vegetable-Feedback11</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HonkaiStarRail/">HonkaiStarRail</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>Fans are having fun speculating who they do - and do not - <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HonkaiStarRail/comments/1kdsy74/comment/mqdetl5/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">see in the silhouettes at the end of the teaser trailer</a>, with some suggesting Ifa or Aventurine could be hiding in the shadows.</p>
<p>If you're a fan of both <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/genshin-impact">Genshin Impact</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/honkai-star-rail">Honkai: Star Rail</a> and don't want to wait for this mysterious new game, don't forget, you can now play <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zenless-zone-zero-tier-list-best-characters">Zenless Zone Zero</a>.</p>
<p>"There's something missing from Zenless Zone Zero. Armed with a deep combat system, new urban setting, and roster of characters easy to love, it seemed like developer miHoYo was teed up for another win after recent successes Genshin Impact and Honkai: Star Rail... and yet after playing its second beta, I'm left more confused than anything else," Jessica wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zenless-zone-zero-would-be-brilliant-if-it-didnt-keep-wasting-your-time">Eurogamer's Zenless Zone Zero preview feature</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Shouldn't Be Surprised GTA 6 Was Delayed, Rockstar Has a Long History of Doing Just That]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/we-shouldnt-be-surprised-gta-6-grand-theft-auto-delayed-rockstar-history</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we-shouldnt-be-surprised-gta-6-was-delayed-rockstar-has-a-long-history-of-doing-just-that.1180422/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/we-shouldnt-be-surprised-gta-6-grand-theft-auto-delayed-rockstar-history<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Take a deep breath and remember: Delays are good.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">OK, that statement isn’t <em>always</em> true, but it usually is. Delayed projects sometimes result in bad games (looking at you, Duke Nukem 3D), but much more often taking more time produces good stuff. Spending meticulous weeks to get something just right matters in art, as does finding the bravery to throw out ideas that seemed wise in concept but never panned out. Think about how many half-finished games you’ve ever bought and played and then wished the publisher had just delayed until it was right and ready. Got that thought in your head? OK, hold onto it. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi"><u>GTA 6</u></a> is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-delayed-to-may-2026"><u>delayed</u></a>, and that’s good, because it will probably be better for the delay. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar has a long history of delaying games to make sure they’re ready for market, a strikingly consistent bit of discipline that places them alongside Nintendo in an elite fraternity of studios that wait until the casserole is fully cooked before serving. And boy, is it always delicious. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ve been playing GTA games as long as they’ve been around, starting with four-player PC GTA LAN parties. I’ve played the most obscure (London 1969), the best (GTA V), and the true best (Chinatown Wars for DS). I’ve ransacked and crashed and shot my way through these goofy, wonderful worlds for decades. And thankfully, these games are practically always late... and not coincidentally, always great. Here’s every delay in GTA history (and some Red Dead too). </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Grand Theft Auto III </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar’s New York offices were located only a few blocks from the World Trade Center, and Take Two didn’t waste any time briefly delaying GTA III following the September 11 attacks. . Marketing VP Terry Donovan <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2001/09/19/take-two-examines-changes-fall-games"><u>announced the delay</u></a> only days after the tragedy: </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Our decision is based on two factors, firstly it has been a little difficult to get work done in downtown Manhattan in the last week since basic communications infrastructure has been intermittent at best, and secondly we felt that a full content review of all our titles and the marketing materials we use to represent them was absolutely necessary for us in light of the horrifying event we all witnessed in the United States last week.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He continued: "As for Grand Theft Auto, since the game is so huge the review is no short process. So far we have come across certain small contextual references that we were no longer comfortable with, as well as a couple of very rare gameplay instances that no longer felt appropriate to us. We apologize to you and all the people waiting for this game to ship for the delays that have now ensued, but I'm sure you can understand our reasoning. Rest assured the game will be phenomenal...and you can expect it to hit shelves in late October.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even with only minimal content changes, the delay was a wise decision for Rockstar and players alike. Blasting cops and ambulances in Liberty City so soon after the violent deaths of thousands wouldn’t have been appealing to anybody.  </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Grand Theft Auto: Vice City and Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The co-prize for shortest delay is shared between Vice City and San Andreas. Back in the olden days before downloadable game stores and day-one patches, manufacturers guessed ahead of time just how much of a physical product they’d need to produce for a given shelf date, and sometimes they guessed wrong. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-vice-city-delayed/1100-2879482/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Rockstar delayed Vice City</u></a> by seven days to give them time to manufacture more discs (and thus meet the tremendous day-one demand for a GTA III follow-up). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">San Andreas for PS2 also hit streets a week later than planned, a<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/news100904sanandreas" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u> strategic decision designed to give the dev team a few extra days to polish their two-year project.</u></a> </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every Celebrity in GTA: San Andreas</h3></div></output><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Stories and Grand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Okay, so real talk: The GTA handheld games go hard... hard enough that it’s worth dusting off your ancient PlayStation Portable or DS to try them. GTA’s excellent forays onto portables usually arrive on time, but Vice City Stories for PSP <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20071011211856/https://www.gtaportable.com/news/6228/vice-city-stories-delayed-globally" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>was delayed for two weeks</u></a> in North America, and longer in parts of Europe. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The best GTA of them all (fight me!) didn’t arrive precisely on time. The incredibly creative and intricate DS gamechit shelves <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rockstar-delays-gta-chinatown-wars" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>two months later</u></a> than expected. When it did finally arrive, it blew the socks off of critics, and it’s one of gaming’s great tragedies that nobody bought it... we might be playing Chinatown Wars 3 on our new Switch 2s right now if they had.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Grand Theft Auto IV </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">After GTA III changed the landscape of video games, anticipation for GTA IV was palpable. With clunky RenderWare left behind and a brand new console generation to work with, Rockstar Leeds was aiming for the stratosphere. Bringing their vision to reality ultimately demanded <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2007/08/02/grand-theft-auto-iv-delayed"><u>several months of delay</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As Rockstar’s Sam Hause explained, “The new consoles [PS3 and 360] are allowing us to create the Grand Theft Auto game we always dreamed about. Every aspect of the game and its design has been completely transformed. The game is huge and is pushing the hardware platforms to their absolute limits. The top engineers from Sony and Microsoft are working closely with the team in Edinburgh right now, helping us to fully leverage the power of both platforms. As always, our goal is to surpass even the wildest expectations of the game's fans, and to create the ultimate high definition video game experience."</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Grand Theft Auto V</strong></h2><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The biggest console game of all time was a long time coming. GTA V finally landed in September 2013, but was originally anticipated to arrive in the spring of that same year. But in late January 2013, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2013/01/31/grand-theft-auto-v-gets-a-september-release-date"><u>Rockstar released the following</u></a> message:  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We know this is about four months later than originally planned and we know that this short delay will come as a disappointment to many of you, but, trust us, it will be worth the extra time. GTAV is a massively ambitious and complex game and it simply needs a little more polish to be of the standard we and, more importantly, you require. ‘To all Grand Theft Auto fans, please accept our apologies for the delay, and our promise that the entire team here is working very hard to make the game all it can be. We are doing all we can to help ensure it will meet if not exceed your expectations come September – we thank you for your support and patience.’"</p><p data-cy="paragraph">They weren't wrong. GTA V went on to become the most successful console game of all time, and alongside RDR2, it’s a true jewel in Rockstar’s crown.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Red Dead Redemption 2</strong></h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/05/reddeadredemption-performancereview-blogroll-2-1730827905085.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of RDR2... it’s not a part of the GTA series, but it is Rockstar’s best game and I love talking about it. In keeping with the tradition of Rockstar quality-based delays, we’re adding a bit of an appendix by mentioning Red Dead Redemption 2, which was delayed twice, <a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/25o24118133518/Red-Dead-Redemption-2-Is-Now-Coming-Spring-2018?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_term=newswire&amp;utm_content=rdr2-05222017" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>first in spring 2017</u></a> for quality assurance purposes. The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/02/01/red-dead-redemption-2-delayed-to-october"><u>second delay</u></a> came in February 2018, pushing RDR2 to late October. The statement from Rockstar explained that, again, this was a quality issue. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We are excited to announce that Red Dead Redemption 2 will be released on October 26th 2018. We apologize to everyone disappointed by this delay. While we had hoped to have the game out sooner, we require a little extra time for polish.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We sincerely thank you for your patience and hope that when you get to play the game, you will agree the wait will have been worth it. In the meantime, please check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/02/01/red-dead-redemption-2-delayed-to-october"><u>these screenshots</u></a> from the game. We look forward to sharing a lot more information with you in the coming weeks."  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That delay, like all the others here, worked out swimmingly, delivering a true work of art still unparalleled in adventure gaming.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So friends, don’t despair. GTA 6 will come, and when it comes, it will almost certainly be very, very good. See you in Vice City.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Jared Petty is a former IGN editor who likes writing about how wonderful and silly video games are. You can find him at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/pettycommajared.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><em>Bluesky as pettycommajared</em></u></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA confirms it is "reducing roles" at Codemasters, and "redeploying as many as possible"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-confirms-it-is-reducing-roles-at-codemasters-and-redeploying-as-many-as-possible</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-confirms-it-is-reducing-roles-at-codemasters-and-redeploying-as-many-as-possible.1180419/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-confirms-it-is-reducing-roles-at-codemasters-and-redeploying-as-many-as-possible<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>“As a business, we are constantly evolving to meet the growing needs of our players."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA/Codemasters</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-says-its-pausing-development-on-future-rally-games-as-wrc-partnership-ends">Days after announcing it was "pausing development" on all future games in its World Rally Championship</a>, EA has confirmed it has "reduced some roles" at Codemasters.</p>
<p>EA announced the end of its partnership with the World Rally Championship earlier this week. At the time, it was not clear if - or how many - members of the Codemasters team had been impacted.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="EA SPORTS WRC - Official Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JFy_cWefBtQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>EA SPORTS WRC - Official Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JFy_cWefBtQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JFy_cWefBtQ?autoplay=1" title="EA SPORTS WRC - Official Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>EA Sports WRC launched in November 2023.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JFy_cWefBtQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In a statement to <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/codemasters-confirms-layoffs-as-ea-owned-studio-shifts-focus-away-from-beloved-rally-games/">VGC</a>, EA again did not confirm the number of its colleagues affected, but did acknowledge: “As a business, we are constantly evolving to meet the growing needs of our players and driving greater focus across our portfolio.</p>
<p>"This has led us to look at reducing some roles, while we redeploy as many as possible against our strategic priorities," the statement concluded.</p>
<p>EA's decision to end its WRC partnership follows its announcement last year - made as it laid off 670 employees - that it would be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-announces-further-lay-offs-this-time-likely-to-affect-around-670-employees">moving away from "future licensed IP"</a> toward its "owned IP, sports, and massive online communities".</p>
<p>The WRC news <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-reportedly-lays-off-over-300-employees-cancels-new-titanfall-game">followed yet more layoffs at EA</a>, reportedly affecting "between 300 and 400" employees who also lost their jobs earlier this week. That means around <a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/vg-layoffs/Archive/2025">2200 developers</a> have lost their jobs in the first four months of 2025 alone.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Following Apple victory, Epic Games Store drops revenue share for games up to first $1m profit, adds out-of-app webshops]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/following-apple-victory-epic-games-store-drops-revenue-share-for-games-up-to-first-1m-profit-adds-out-of-app-webshops</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/following-apple-victory-epic-games-store-drops-revenue-share-for-games-up-to-first-1m-profit-adds-out-of-app-webshops.1180401/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/following-apple-victory-epic-games-store-drops-revenue-share-for-games-up-to-first-1m-profit-adds-out-of-app-webshops<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Webshops will be a "more cost-effective" to "Apple, Google, and others' exorbitant fees".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Epic Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Epic Games has "exciting updates" for game makers, confirming the storefront will no longer take a share of revenue up to the first $1,000,000 profit a game makes.</p>
<p>Starting in June 2025, Epic confirmed developers will pay zero percent "revenue share on their first $1,000,000 in revenue per app per year", followed by its usual 88/12 percent revenue cut - with Epic taking the latter - on revenue earned beyond that.</p>
<p>This means games that don't meet the million dollar threshold will never have to share its profits with Epic Games.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Oblivion Tips for New Players - How To Make Money in Oblivion Fast and More!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JBiRsqE9xC8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Oblivion Tips for New Players - How To Make Money in Oblivion Fast and More!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JBiRsqE9xC8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JBiRsqE9xC8?autoplay=1" title="Oblivion Tips for New Players - How To Make Money in Oblivion Fast and More!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's our Zoe with some Oblivion tips for new players.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JBiRsqE9xC8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In comparison, competitor Steam - much like other digital stores like the Nintendo eShop - takes around 30 percent, although Valve's store revised its Steam Distribution Agreement and revenue share tiers back in 2018 <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/steam-revises-revenue-share-policy-to-let-big-game-developers-keep-more-of-their-profits">so developers can keep more of the profits of their most successful games</a>, taking 30 percent on the first $10 million of revenues earned, 25 percent from $10 million onwards, and 20 percent on any revenue over $50 million.</p>
<p>But that's not the only seismic change, either.</p>
<p>"We’re making some exciting updates to the Epic Games Store to provide an even better deal for developers, starting in June," Epic announced in a <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/news/new-epic-games-store-webshops-and-revenue-share-update">brief statement</a>.</p>
<p>"In June 2025, we are releasing a new feature enabling developers to launch their own webshops hosted by the Epic Games Store. These webshops can offer players out-of-app purchases, as a more cost-effective alternative to in-app purchases, where Apple, Google, and others charge exorbitant fees.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Epic Games Store will take 0% on the first $1,000,000 of payments we process per game per year (vs 15% for Apple), and 12% after that (vs 30% for Apple).</p><p>Next month, we launch EGS Webshops for out-of-app purchases, as an alternative to in-app purchases.<a href="https://t.co/yTufyZbiqR">https://t.co/yTufyZbiqR</a></p></div>— Tim Sweeney (@TimSweeneyEpic) <a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1917973199309987970?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 1, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>"With new legal rulings in place, developers will be able to send players from games to make digital purchases from webshops on any platform that allows it, including iOS in the European Union and United States."</p>
<p>To sweeten the deal, player spend accrued in Epic "Webshops" will also receive five percent Epic Rewards on their purchases.</p>
<p>The changes come after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/apple-updates-app-store-guidelines-in-wake-of-seismic-judgement-paving-way-for-fortnites-return">Apple formally updated its App Store guidelines to reflect the dramatic decision</a> laid down by a US judge around alternative app store payments. In a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-offers-peace-proposal-to-apple-after-court-decision-tears-into-iphone-maker-accuses-execs-of-lying-under-oath">fiery injunction passed this week</a>, Apple was told it could no longer dissuade app makers from offering other payment methods by applying a 27 percent commission on their proceeds. The move allows apps and games to offer direct - and potentially cheaper - options for in-app purchases, at least in the US.</p>
<p>In February, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-games-store-has-more-pc-players-than-ever-295-million-in-fact">Epic revealed 295 million PC players had used Epic Games Store in the last year,</a> up 25 million from 2023, and 898 million are using Epic cross-platform accounts - that's up 94m. Together, we've run up 7.72bn hours of playtime.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gigabyte Aorus Master 16 review: powerful graphics, LOUD FANS]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/reviews/658137/gigabyte-aorus-master-16-gaming-laptop-rtx-5080-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gigabyte-aorus-master-16-review-powerful-graphics-loud-fans.1180392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/reviews/658137/gigabyte-aorus-master-16-gaming-laptop-rtx-5080-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The Gigabyte Aorus Master 16 is a gaming laptop, and it sure looks like one. It’s an inch thick, weighs 5.5 pounds, and is awash in RGB lighting, stylized text, and curved plastic. </p><p>This Aorus Master offers powerful hardware and a lovely high-res, high-refresh OLED display. It’s the first of several laptops we’re reviewing with the GeForce RTX 5080, Nvidia’s second-fastest laptop graphics card of this generation. At $3,100, it’s actually a few hundred dollars less than similarly powerful models from Razer, Lenovo, and Asus, and over a thousand dollars less than laptops with the RTX 5090, Nvidia’s fastest GPU.</p><p>But in exchange for being a little cheaper than <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24336394/asus-rog-strix-scar-16-18-specs-price-ces-2025">its direct competitors</a>, the Aorus Master <em>feels</em> a little cheap, and its built-in software includes a useless AI chatbot but no custom fan controls. And those fans get <em>loud</em>.</p><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->3100</span></p><div><div><h4>The Good</h4><ul><li>Very good game performance from the RTX 5080 GPU</li><li>Lovely 2.5K 240Hz OLED display</li><li>Slightly less expensive than other 5080 competitors</li><li>Solid port selection</li><li>User-replaceable RAM and SSDs</li></ul></div><div><h4>The Bad</h4><ul><li>Fans can get distractingly loud</li><li>Meager battery life</li><li>Plasticky build</li><li>Included 1TB SSD storage is a little slow</li><li>GiMate software is clunky and bad, and its AI chatbot is even worse</li></ul></div></div></div><p>Like the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/649577/razer-blade-16-2025-rtx-5090-review">Razer Blade 16</a>, the Aorus Master 16 comes with a 16-inch 2560 x 1600 OLED display. The Aorus’s panel isn’t quite as accurate as the Blade’s — with <em>slightly </em>lower color reproduction — but it’s just as bright and about as pleasing to the eye in regular use. It’s got punchy colors that aren’t oversaturated, and its 2.5K resolution and maximum 240Hz refresh rate enable games, websites, and videos to look sharp and smooth.</p><div><div><p id="component-report-card"><h2><strong>Component report card:</strong></h2></p></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>Screen:</strong> A</span></li><li><span><strong>Webcam:</strong> C</span></li><li><span><strong>Mic: </strong>C</span></li><li><span><strong>Keyboard:</strong> B</span></li><li><span><strong>Touchpad:</strong> B</span></li><li><span><strong>Port selection:</strong> B</span></li><li><span><strong>Speakers:</strong> C</span></li><li><span><strong>Number of ugly stickers to remove:</strong> 2</span></li></ul></div></div><p>By contrast, the plastic screen bezel is a bit ugly, and the Aorus Master as a whole isn’t much of a looker. Its plasticky build feels dated and a little low-rentcheap compared to the more grown-up-looking Lenovo Legion Pro 7i or the all-out RGB bombast of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24336394/asus-rog-strix-scar-16-18-specs-price-ces-2025">Asus’ ROG Strix Scar</a>, with its wraparound light bar and animated LED matrix on the lid. The lid of the Aorus opens easily with one hand, but the screen can wobble. And the diagonal-line designs in its vents and branding across its trackpad look cheesy. It has “Team up. Fight on” written on the lid for some reason, and it even projects the Aorus wordmark below the rear exhaust fans, which is as gauche here as it is on the <a href="https://www.jalopnik.com/the-ten-most-ridiculous-car-design-details-1743426644/#:~:text=2.)%20Door%20Projector%20Puddle%20Lights">doors of luxury cars</a>.</p><p>While I’ll poke fun at the Aorus’ tryhard design, Gigabyte gets credit for focusing on what counts: the screen, GPU, CPU, ports, and even user-upgradeable RAM and storage. The keyboard and trackpad are solid, with good tactile feedback. The keyboard has a 1.7mm key travel and the trackpad, while a little loud, easily clicks even near its top hinge. </p><div id=":R29dlhr96:"><div><p><figcaption><em>The right side ports include USB-A, USB-C, headphone jack, and microSD slot.</em></figcaption></p></div><div><p><figcaption><em>On the left are power (barrel plug), ethernet, HDMI, USB-A, and Thunderbolt 5</em>.</figcaption></p></div></div><p>The 1080p webcam, built-in mics, and speakers aren’t anything special, but you’ll get through video calls looking and sounding fine in most lighting. The speakers sound decently full for music, but dialog is flat. It can be slightly difficult to clearly hear spoken lines in games against loud music and sound effects, especially since you’ll also be competing with the Aorus’ fans.</p><p>Fan noise is my biggest hangup with the laptop. In graphically intensive games like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/617587/monster-hunter-wilds-review-ps5-xbox-steam"><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em></a> or <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F1749860%2FLushfoil_Photography_Sim%2F" rel="sponsored"><em>Lushfoil Photography Sim</em></a> it’s loud and irritating enough that you find yourself cranking the game volume or reaching for a pair of headphones.</p><div><p><figcaption><em>The keyboard only has three-zone RGB lighting instead of per-key customization, but the see-though WASD and adjacent keys are fun.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>My wife is used to hearing the fans of gaming laptops in our shared home office, but at one point the Aorus made her turn to me and say, “What the hell is going on over there?”</p><p>I was playing <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/649795/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-release-date"><em>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</em></a> on a 4K external monitor, and the fans were audible even in the next room, especially during initial shader compiling. At peak rpm, they sound like someone running a small vacuum cleaner across the room. The fans on the Razer Blade 16 and ROG Strix Scar 16 are noticeably quieter and less annoying.</p><div id=":R3pdlhr96:"><div><div><p><figcaption><em>Always be teaming. Always be fighting.</em></figcaption></p></div><div><p><figcaption><em>The holographic nameplate is one of three Aorus brandings on the keyboard deck and screen bezel.</em></figcaption></p></div></div><div><p><figcaption><em>The front-facing light bar has three-zone RGB and the rear-facing has two zones of color.</em></figcaption></p></div></div><p>And unlike Razer Synapse or Asus Armoury Crate, Gigabyte’s GiMate software doesn’t let you tweak the fan curves, only choose between four presets. Switching the laptop from game mode to balanced, and the fans from performance to normal can cut the noise a bit with minimal sacrifice to framerates. Though, even in this mode, the fans can still go loud when necessary. And turbo mode is solely for masochists; it pegs the fans at 100 percent the whole time.</p><div><table><thead><tr><th><h3>System</h3></th><th><h3>Gigabyte Aorus Master 16 / RTX 5080 / Core Ultra 9 275HX / 32GB / 1TB</h3></th><th><h3>Asus ROG Strix Scar 16 / RTX 5080 / Core Ultra 9 275HX / 32GB / 2TB</h3></th><th><h3>Razer Blade 16 (2025) / RTX 5090 / Ryzen AI 9 HX 370 / 32GB / 2TB</h3></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Geekbench 6 CPU Single</td><td>3051</td><td>3113</td><td>2968</td></tr><tr><td>Geekbench 6 CPU Multi</td><td>19334</td><td>19709</td><td>15922</td></tr><tr><td>Geekbench 6 GPU (OpenCL)</td><td>197539</td><td>200189</td><td>213016</td></tr><tr><td>Cinebench 2024 Single</td><td>136</td><td>137</td><td>119</td></tr><tr><td>Cinebench 2024 Multi</td><td>1955</td><td>1965</td><td>1287</td></tr><tr><td>PugetBench for Premiere Pro</td><td>13416</td><td>13409</td><td>12593</td></tr><tr><td>PugetBench for Photoshop</td><td>8648</td><td>8482</td><td>8679</td></tr><tr><td>Sustained SSD reads (MB/s)</td><td>4802.21</td><td>6832.06</td><td>6726.25</td></tr><tr><td>Sustained SSD writes (MB/s)</td><td>3893.34</td><td>6550.21</td><td>4931.41</td></tr><tr><td>3DMark Time Spy</td><td>20520</td><td>20977</td><td>22498</td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>GiMate’s other features are sparse, limited in scope, and worse than native solutions within Windows 11 and Nvidia’s GPU settings. Its operating modes are just shortcuts to Windows power settings. In some cases, GiMate simply opens Microsoft Copilot or Nvidia’s Control Panel and Broadcast App. But its interactions with other apps get even weirder when you unplug the charger and GiMate prompts you to switch to integrated graphics and kill apps it says are using the discrete GPU. This MUX switch functionality is already handled by Nvidia’s <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fnews%2Frtx-laptops-advanced-optimus%2F" rel="sponsored">Advanced Optimus</a>, so I’m not sure why Gigabyte brute forces it this way.</p><p>The GiMate AI chatbot, another misfire, allegedly helps you optimize your laptop. I asked it to tell me the difference between Game Mode and Balanced, and it just enabled Game Mode. You can ask it to do basics like toggle Wi-Fi on or off, but it takes much longer than doing it yourself. That could be useful for someone unfamiliar with computers, but this is a gaming machine.</p><p>Bad software and noisy fans aside, the Aorus Master 16 is mostly a good performer. Its 24-core Intel Core Ultra 9 275HX CPU, RTX 5080 GPU, and 32GB of RAM easily handle multitasking across various productivity apps, though it can’t last more than six hours on charge, even using power saving mode. It did okay with some hefty photo editing, but on two occasions on battery power Lightroom Classic slowed to the point where I had to close and restart it — not ideal when you need to edit quickly.</p><p>In gaming performance, the Aorus Master is right in line with an Asus ROG Strix Scar 16 using the same CPU and GPU for $200 more. The Aorus Master is usually on par or a frame or two better in 4K and 2.5K benchmark tests of <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> and <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>. And like the Asus, that puts the Gigabyte within reach of the flagship RTX 5090 in the $4,500 Razer Blade 16. In our tests, the 5090 bested it by an average of just 3.5 fps without frame generation, and by up to 10 fps with frame generation. Those are pretty minimal differences, making the mobile 5080 a much better value — at least, compared to the Blade 16’s power-limited 5090. We haven’t yet tested a laptop with an uncapped 5090. </p><p>I averaged 143 fps in <em>Oblivion Remastered</em> on a 4K display with high settings and frame generation turned on in the game’s prologue. Turning off frame gen dropped it to an average of 99 fps. When I switched to ultra settings in the open world I saw an average of 50 fps without frame gen and 77 with. The one thing I couldn’t turn off was the incessant fan noise.</p><section tabindex="-1" aria-label="carousel"><p><strong>1<!-- -->/<!-- -->6</strong><span><figcaption><em>The lid has a striped pattern across it that’s most visible when it catches the light.</em></figcaption></span></p></section><p>If you always play with headphones on, you can mitigate the Gigabyte’s biggest issue. But while the Aorus Master 16 is one of the cheapest 5080 laptops, there are plenty of interesting competitors for just a little more. The <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fshop.asus.com%2Fus%2F90nr0ld1-m005n0-rog-strix-scar-16-2025.html" rel="sponsored">Asus ROG Strix Scar 16</a>, for example, looks cooler and has quieter fans; the <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://www.hp.com/us-en/shop/pdp/omen-max-gaming-laptop-16-ah0097nr" rel="sponsored">HP Omen Max</a> and<a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1875949-REG%2Flenovo_83f50052us_16_legion_pro_7.html" rel="sponsored"> Lenovo Legion Pro 7i</a> both have OLED screens like the Gigabyte. I think I still prefer the Gigabyte’s OLED to the Asus’ Mini LED, but I need to spend more time with the Asus before making that call. I’ll also be testing the Lenovo and HP; their OLED screens could make them closer competitors to the Gigabyte.</p><p>There’s a lot to like in the Aorus Master 16, but it’s not as easy to love. Its powerful hardware and brilliant OLED display are a treat to game on, but the lackluster GiMate software, basic build quality, and at times maddening fan noise feels like someone knocking the ice cream cone from your hand right after you get it.</p><div><div><p id="2025-gigabyte-aorus-master-16-specs-as-reviewed"><h2>2025 Gigabyte Aorus Master 16 specs (as reviewed)</h2></p></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>Display: </strong>16-inch (2560 x 1600) 240Hz OLED</span></li><li><span><strong>CPU:</strong> Intel Core Ultra 9 275HX</span></li><li><span><strong>GPU:</strong> Nvidia RTX 5080</span></li><li><span><strong>RAM:</strong> 32GB DDR5 5600MHz (user-replaceable)</span></li><li><span><strong>Storage:</strong> 1TB M.2 PCIe Gen 5 NVMe (with one extra Gen 4 slot)</span></li><li><span><strong>Webcam:</strong> 1080p, Windows Hello</span></li><li><span><strong>Connectivity:</strong> Wi-Fi 7, Bluetooth 5.4</span></li><li><span><strong>Ports:</strong> 2x USB-A 3.2 Gen 2, 1x Thunderbolt 5 USB-C (left side), 1x Thunderbolt 4 USB-C (right side), HDMI 2.1, RJ-45 ethernet, microSD slot (UHS-II), 3.5mm combo audio jack, DC power</span></li><li><span><strong>Weight:</strong> 5.5 pounds</span></li><li><span><strong>Dimensions:</strong> 14.01 x 10 x 0.91 — 1.18 inches</span></li><li><span><strong>Battery:</strong> 99Wh</span></li><li><span><strong>Price:</strong> $3,099.99</span></li></ul></div></div><p><em>Photography by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Polygon’s new owner says it will ‘do what’s right for Polygon’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/660635/polygon-valnet-vox-media-new-owner-interview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/polygon%E2%80%99s-new-owner-says-it-will-%E2%80%98do-what%E2%80%99s-right-for-polygon%E2%80%99.1180380/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/660635/polygon-valnet-vox-media-new-owner-interview<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Polygon</em>, <em>The Verge’s</em> former sister site dedicated to covering gaming and entertainment, is now owned by Valnet, a company that owns more than 27 different brands covering gaming, entertainment, sports, travel, and more. The transition is, let’s say, <em>ongoing: </em>a day after the acquisition, the site still said it was a Vox Media property, and the site’s coverage continued more or less uninterrupted. </p><p>But Valnet has indeed acquired <em>Polygon</em>, so to learn more about the deal, why the company acquired it, and the future of the site, I got on the phone with Valnet’s head of mergers and acquisitions, Rony Arzoumanian.</p><p>Polygon is a “triple-A gaming brand” that Valnet has been of “high interest” for “some time,” Arzoumanian said. Valnet’s gaming portfolio also includes <em>GameRant</em>, <em>TheGamer</em>, <em>Fextralife</em>, <em>DualShockers</em>, <em>Hardcore Gamer</em>, and <em>OpenCritic</em>. Arzoumanian said the company is “bullish” on gaming coverage. </p><div><p>“We think Polygon has a lot of potential and could be much more.”</p></div><p>Valnet initiated the <em>Polygon</em> deal, and Arzoumanian said the conversations started a “few months ago.” He declined to share the terms of the deal. </p><p>Going forward, Valnet wants to ensure that <em>Polygon</em> has the “deepest” coverage of the gaming space, Arzoumanian said. He declined to share specific coverage expectations, but said Valnet will “do what’s right for <em>Polygon</em>” and that “we think <em>Polygon</em> has a lot of potential and could be much more.” </p><p>Around 10 existing <em>Polygon</em> staffers are moving over to the site’s new owner, Arzoumanian said. Matt Patches, who was previously <em>Polygon’s</em> executive editor, is heading things up for now. Valnet is also “rebuilding” the team, investing in its operations, and making sure it builds <em>Polygon</em> “for the next five to ten years,” according to Arzoumanian.</p><p>Valnet wants to recruit “triple-A” writers and editors for <em>Polygon</em>, Arzoumanian said. When I asked about what the balance might be of full-time hires and contractors, Arzoumanian deferred on specifics, but said “we will do it right.” Arzoumanian also deferred on whether <em>Polygon</em> would hire another editor-in-chief, saying that right now, the focus is on ensuring continuity following the close of the deal.</p><p>The sale resulted in most of <em>Polygon’s</em> staff leaving or being laid off, including <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/plante.bsky.social/post/3lo4mn4noqc26">former editor-in-chief Chris Plante</a>. Chris Grant, Vox Media’s group publisher of <em>The Verge</em> and formerly <em>Polygon</em>, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/charstring.com/post/3lo56isadnc2g">said that</a> “Valnet literally refused to meet with me or answer a single question of mine throughout this process.” (It all added to what turned into a brutal day for gaming journalism, which also included the news of <a href="https://kotaku.com/giant-bomb-fandom-dan-ryckert-jeff-grubb-gerstmann-1851778728">Fandom’s changes for <em>Giant Bomb</em></a>.)</p><p>I asked Arzoumanian about Grant’s post, reading him the part of the sentence I quoted above and asking if it was true. Arzoumanian said that Valnet “predominantly dealt” with Jim Bankoff, Vox Media’s CEO, and that “I’m not in a position to answer that, unfortunately.”</p><p>Valnet plans to keep <em>Polygon’s</em> archives available, Arzoumanian said, meaning we won’t see a repeat of GameStop’s Thanos-snap disappearance <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/3/24212291/game-informer-video-game-industry-mourns">of <em>Game Informer’s</em> archives</a>. (<em>Game Informer</em>, fortunately, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/subscribe">is back now</a>.) When I asked if Valnet plans to introduce AI-generated stories onto <em>Polygon</em>, which has been a disconcerting trend <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/16/24158531/gannett-ai-generated-overviews-usa-today-memo">at other publications</a>, Arzoumanian said, “not at all.”</p><p>I also asked if Valnet more broadly is making changes in response to a recent report about Valnet <a href="https://www.thewrap.com/valnet-labor-lawsuit-hassan-youssef-digital-media-sweat-shop/">from <em>TheWrap</em></a>, which included an allegation from one former contributor about “almost sweatshop-level” working conditions at a Valnet publication. Arzoumanian pointed me to Valnet’s press release about <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250425504752/en/Valnet-Inc.-and-its-CEO-File-Lawsuit-Against-The-Wrap-News-Inc.-for-Defamation-Unfair-Competition-and-Other-Illegal-Actions">its recent defamation lawsuit</a> filed against <em>TheWrap.</em></p><p>A year from now, Arzoumanian said he doesn’t expect things to be that different. Valnet wants to maintain course and keep investing in the brand. He deferred to the operations side of Valnet on whether the company wants <em>Polygon</em> to switch to <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/2018/9/4/17689100/polygon-reviews-no-scores">scored reviews.</a></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Consoles And Games Get A Price Hike, Borderlands 4 Gets A Showcase, And More Of The Week's Top Stories]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/polygon-sold-giant-bomb-xbox-price-borderlands-4-1851778862</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-consoles-and-games-get-a-price-hike-borderlands-4-gets-a-showcase-and-more-of-the-weeks-top-stories.1180377/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/polygon-sold-giant-bomb-xbox-price-borderlands-4-1851778862<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="efa978d036416fb996cf7b532431ed6d" data-recommend-id="image://efa978d036416fb996cf7b532431ed6d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="in-house-art" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Vox Media<!-- -->, <!-- -->Giant Bomb / Fandom<!-- -->, <!-- -->Halo Studios<!-- -->, <!-- -->Microsoft / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Nintendo<!-- -->, <!-- -->Gearbox / 2K / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Lucasfilm / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="efa978d036416fb996cf7b532431ed6d" data-recommend-id="image://efa978d036416fb996cf7b532431ed6d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>This week saw gaming website <em>Polygon </em>sold to Valnet, the company that owns <em>Screen Rant</em> and <em>Game Rant </em>among other sites, and many of its staffers laid off. Meanwhile publication at another gaming site, <em>Giant Bomb</em>,  is currently on hold as owner Fandom engages in what it calls a “strategic reset and realignment of our media brands” and some staffers suggest the company has interfered with the site’s content and its famously irreverent tone. </p><p>Elsewhere, Microsoft announced that Xbox consoles were going up in price, effective immediately, and that by this holiday season, we can expect higher prices on Xbox games as well. And we got a closer look at <em>Borderlands 4</em>&nbsp;via a new PlayStation State of Play presentation. Read on for all the details on these stories and more.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="7b7e3de78102ad34be1539f5539bfefe" data-recommend-id="image://7b7e3de78102ad34be1539f5539bfefe" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A logo shows the word polygon. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A logo shows the word polygon. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Vox Media</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7b7e3de78102ad34be1539f5539bfefe" data-recommend-id="image://7b7e3de78102ad34be1539f5539bfefe" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A logo shows the word polygon. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The video game website <em>Polygon</em> has been sold to click-farm powerhouse Valnet and much of its masthead has been laid off, <em>Kotaku</em> has learned. The sale was subsequently <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250501630767/en/Valnet-Acquires-Premium-Gaming-Publication-Polygon-from-Vox-Media&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250501630767/en/Valnet-Acquires-Premium-Gaming-Publication-Polygon-from-Vox-Media" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announced in a press release</a></span>. Multiple staff members have posted online about losing their jobs or about colleagues now being out of work.  - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/polygon-sold-vox-media-valnet-layoffs-digital-gaming-1851778655?_gl=1*5t6jdo*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjE4MjQ5NC42My4xLjE3NDYyMDYyNDkuMzEuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/polygon-sold-vox-media-valnet-layoffs-digital-gaming-1851778655?_gl=1*5t6jdo*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjE4MjQ5NC42My4xLjE3NDYyMDYyNDkuMzEuMC4w">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="26f9d5bf5170d56963c36415887ef4b6" data-recommend-id="image://26f9d5bf5170d56963c36415887ef4b6" data-format="png" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A logo reads &quot;Giant Bomb.&quot; " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A logo reads &quot;Giant Bomb.&quot; " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Giant Bomb / Fandom</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="26f9d5bf5170d56963c36415887ef4b6" data-recommend-id="image://26f9d5bf5170d56963c36415887ef4b6" data-format="png" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A logo reads &quot;Giant Bomb.&quot; " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Giant Bomb</em>’s future is uncertain following a showdown with parent company Fandom, which also owns <em>GameSpot</em>, over editorial interference. Creative director Dan Ryckert announced on a recent livestream that he would no longer be appearing on the Giant Bombcast and co-host Jeff Grubb confirmed on social media on Thursday that he’s no longer with the company.<em> Giant Bomb</em> content is currently on hold while Fandom engages in a “strategic reset and realignment of our media brands,” it confirmed to <em>Kotaku</em>.  - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/giant-bomb-fandom-dan-ryckert-jeff-grubb-gerstmann-1851778728?_gl=1*1vgsdej*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjE4MjQ5NC42My4xLjE3NDYyMDYyNDkuMzEuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/giant-bomb-fandom-dan-ryckert-jeff-grubb-gerstmann-1851778728?_gl=1*1vgsdej*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjE4MjQ5NC42My4xLjE3NDYyMDYyNDkuMzEuMC4w">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="65d1d650b2bd64ccdfca87212957b046" data-recommend-id="image://65d1d650b2bd64ccdfca87212957b046" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Xboxes with red pointy up arrows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Xboxes with red pointy up arrows." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Microsoft / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="65d1d650b2bd64ccdfca87212957b046" data-recommend-id="image://65d1d650b2bd64ccdfca87212957b046" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Xboxes with red pointy up arrows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/hardware-network/console/may-2025-pricing-updates&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/hardware-network/console/may-2025-pricing-updates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft has announced</a></span> it will be raising the prices of all Xbox consoles, accessories, and games, and the increases are <em>huge</em>. Console and peripheral prices will go up today, May 1, by an enormous amount, while new first-party game prices will all hit $80 by the holidays. - John Walker <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/microsoft-xbox-series-x-s-price-increase-may-2025-1851778615&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-xbox-series-x-s-price-increase-may-2025-1851778615">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1f5b5deecb76f5a078127083871f6872" data-recommend-id="image://1f5b5deecb76f5a078127083871f6872" data-format="png" data-width="1024" data-height="574" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Nintendo Switch hangs in the air. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Nintendo Switch hangs in the air. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1f5b5deecb76f5a078127083871f6872" data-recommend-id="image://1f5b5deecb76f5a078127083871f6872" data-format="png" data-width="1024" data-height="574" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Nintendo Switch hangs in the air. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p> The Nintendo Switch received a major firmware update today that paves the way for its integration with the Switch 2 and institutes a less than stellar new regime of virtual game sharing. But firmware version 20.0.0 also made some other equally notable but less advertised changes, including a major shift to how Nintendo ranks best-selling games in the eShop. The result could have big ramifications for how games are discovered on one of the biggest console install-bases in history, and could help alleviate <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248">some of the platform’s “slop” problem</a></span>.  - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/slop-nintendo-switch-eshop-best-seller-firmware-update-1851778523&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/slop-nintendo-switch-eshop-best-seller-firmware-update-1851778523">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="2797b124069af2d1edbf35fee5ca0fc2" data-recommend-id="image://2797b124069af2d1edbf35fee5ca0fc2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Gearbox / 2K / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2797b124069af2d1edbf35fee5ca0fc2" data-recommend-id="image://2797b124069af2d1edbf35fee5ca0fc2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Today, we learned a lot more about <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-release-date-state-play-gta-6-fall-2025-1851762044&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-release-date-state-play-gta-6-fall-2025-1851762044"><em>Borderlands 4</em></a></span> during a roughly 20-minute PlayStation State of Play dedicated exclusively to Gearbox and 2K’s upcoming sci-fi looter shooter sequel. - Zack Zwiezen <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-state-of-play-gearbox-round-up-trailer-1851778578&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-state-of-play-gearbox-round-up-trailer-1851778578">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="4f00681faf5577f2403cb4bf972ee737" data-recommend-id="image://4f00681faf5577f2403cb4bf972ee737" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Lucasfilm / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="4f00681faf5577f2403cb4bf972ee737" data-recommend-id="image://4f00681faf5577f2403cb4bf972ee737" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>A greatest hits collection of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-best-games-ranked-jedi-knight-dark-forces-lis-1848893189?_gl=1*1iw9k22*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NTg1MTc4Ni4zMzYuMS4xNzQ1ODUzNzQ0LjkuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-best-games-ranked-jedi-knight-dark-forces-lis-1848893189?_gl=1*1iw9k22*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NTg1MTc4Ni4zMzYuMS4xNzQ1ODUzNzQ0LjkuMC4w"><em>Star Wars</em> PC games</a></span> are currently on sale right now on GOG, just a few days ahead of May the 4th. And some are now part of an awesome <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gog-games-preservation-program-drm-1851696363&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gog-games-preservation-program-drm-1851696363">preservation program</a></span> that will help keep them playable for years to come.  - Zack Zwiezen <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-games-may-4th-sale-gog-preservation-pc-deals-1851778109&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-games-may-4th-sale-gog-preservation-pc-deals-1851778109">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="33836f5190052218946100376b8d7678" data-recommend-id="image://33836f5190052218946100376b8d7678" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Miis prepare to share games on their Switches. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Miis prepare to share games on their Switches. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="33836f5190052218946100376b8d7678" data-recommend-id="image://33836f5190052218946100376b8d7678" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Miis prepare to share games on their Switches. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-direct-march-27-2025-metroid-pokemon-dragon-qu-1851772682&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-direct-march-27-2025-metroid-pokemon-dragon-qu-1851772682">Nintendo Switch</a></span> just got a major update to prepare for the arrival of Switch 2 in June. Ver. 20.0.0, released overnight, adds system transfers to Switch 2 as well as support for the new console’s GameShare feature and the sharing of virtual game cards. Players have quickly discovered a major caveat for that last part: when using virtual game cards, you can’t simultaneously play a game online across two separate Switches. It’s a confusing hang-up with significant consequences.  - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-share-virtual-game-card-firmware-20-0-1851778447&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-share-virtual-game-card-firmware-20-0-1851778447">Read More</a></span></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 Assassin’s Creed Games Are Reportedly in Development]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/9-assassins-creed-games-are-reportedly-in-development/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/9-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-games-are-reportedly-in-development.1180353/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/9-assassins-creed-games-are-reportedly-in-development/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ubisoft has nine Assassin's Creed games currently in development, according to a new report published by Tom Henderson <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-further-details-on-the-assassins-creed-roadmap-and-what-games-to-expect/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on Insider Gaming</a>.</p>
<p>We have been aware of at least four for a while.&nbsp;<span><a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-jade-mobile-gameplay-leaked-on-reddit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jade</a>, the mobile game set in Ancient China, is one of only two officially announced</span>. There hasn't been any news on this title for at least two years, but Henderson says it'll be the next franchise entry to make its debut.</p>
<p>Then there's Invictus, the Fall Guys-style multiplayer spin-off. Last month, the same insider <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-invictus-an-arcade-multiplayer-game-rumored-to-launch-this-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> this game would launch in 2025. Today, he added that Ubisoft is prepared to support it for at least five years post-launch, provided it sells according to internal estimates.</p>
<p>The highly anticipated <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-is-reportedly-closer-than-we-thought/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag Remake</a> (codenamed Obsidian) should launch around the same time, so we could be playing it in late 2025 or early 2026 at the latest.</p>
<p>Assassin's Creed Hexe is the other game on this list that Ubisoft has confirmed. As you might recall, a brief tease was <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-project-red-japan-project-hexe-witchcraft-infinity-hub-detail/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dropped</a> during a Ubisoft Forward presentation in September 2022. This project is in development at Ubisoft Montréal and is led by Clint Hocking, a Ubisoft veteran who was the Creative Director of Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory, Far Cry 2, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/watch-dogs-legion-bold-gameplay-mild-story/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Watch Dogs: Legion</a>. It was officially described as a 'very different' franchise experience, and it does sound like it will be the next Mirage-like game. The current plan, says Henderson, is to launch it when Assassin's Creed Shadows ends its post-release support. This should happen in around two years, so Hexe could drop in 2027, with one year of planned post-launch support of its own.</p>
<p>The next big open-world Assassin's Creed RPG, codenamed Scarlet, has already entered production. Henderson speculates it might be Assassin's Creed Nebula, a game that should take place in three different settings: the Aztec Empire, India, and the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>The roadmap gets increasingly hazy from now on. Stardust is the codename of another remake, but there's no info on which game would be remade. Then there's Emerald, reportedly another multiplayer game with a five-year support plan. Emerald is expected to be released close to Stardust.</p>
<p>'RPG 3' is completely unknown at this point, except that it should launch after the usual two years of live support for Scarlet. Similarly, the report could not add anything about 'Remake 3' other than the fact that it will release around one year after RPG 3.</p>
<p>That will be many years from now. Meanwhile, Ubisoft has officially <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-shares-year-one-roadmap-and-theres-no-mention-of-multiplayer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unveiled</a> the year one roadmap for Assassin's Creed Shadows.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Something for the Weekend – 03/05/25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/03/something-for-the-weekend-03-05-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/something-for-the-weekend-%E2%80%93-03-05-25.1180344/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/03/something-for-the-weekend-03-05-25/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>We might be coming to the end of this heatwave, but there’s still a little time to try and enjoy the last of this good weather through this bank holiday. Given that there’s the extra day (once again) to the weekend, there’s still plenty of time for gaming, and I’ve got a big long list of games big and small that I’ll be sinking time into.</p>
<h2>In the News This Week</h2>
<p>It was a busy old week for video games news, and while we had the gameplay deep dive for Borderlands 4, it was the GTA 6 delay that was the biggest story of the week. Thankfully, there’s still tons of big games for 2025, so it’s not like we won’t have plenty to look forward to through the rest of this year.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/02/gta-6-gets-a-release-date-but-its-been-delayed-to-2026/">GTA 6 gets a release date, but it’s been delayed to 2026</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/01/xbox-series-xs-console-prices-are-jumping-up-around-the-world-games-to-hit-80-this-winter/">Xbox Series X|S console prices are jumping up around the world – games to hit $80 this winter</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/report-ea-lays-off-more-than-300-staff-and-cancels-rumoured-titanfall-spin-off/">Report: EA lays off more than 300 staff and cancels rumoured Titanfall spin-off</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/29/borderlands-4-gameplay-state-of-play-is-airing-tomorrow-30th-april-release-date-moved-forward/">Borderlands 4 release date moved forward by a fortnight</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/assassins-creed-shadows-year-one-roadmap-detailed/">Assassin’s Creed Shadows year one roadmap detailed</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/ea-sports-wrc-will-get-no-more-content-future-rally-game-development-paused/">EA Sports WRC will get no more content, future rally game development paused</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/02/paradox-interactive-will-announce-grand-strategy-game-project-caesar-on-8th-may/">Paradox Interactive will announce grand strategy game Project Caesar on 8th May</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/nintendo-switch-system-update-20-0-0-is-here-virtual-game-cards-gameshare-new-icons-and-more-switch-2-prep/">Nintendo Switch system update 20.0.0 is here – Virtual Game Cards, GameShare, new icons, and more Switch 2 prep</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/evil-dead-the-game-is-getting-delisted/">Evil Dead: The Game is getting delisted</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/02/the-shadow-syndicate-revealed-for-xbox-series-xs-ps5-switch-2-and-pc/">The Shadow Syndicate revealed for Xbox Series XS, PS5, Switch 2 and PC</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/28/devolver-reveals-co-op-fungi-shooter-mycopunk-steam-demo-out-now/">Devolver reveals co-op fungi shooter Mycopunk – Steam demo out now</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/may-2025s-ps-plus-monthly-games-features-balatro-boomer-shooting-dinos/">May 2025’s PS Plus Monthly Games features Balatro, boomer shooting &amp; dinos</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>Games in Review &amp; Featured Articles</h2>
<p>Just the one scored game review this week, where we ask, what if a loose cannon police man decided to go arrest Satan?</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/01/shotgun-cop-man-review/"><b>Shotgun Cop Man</b></a> – NSW, <b>PC </b>– 7/10</li>
</ul>
<p>But what will you be sitting on while arresting Satan? Why not a great big lovely bean bag?</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/29/big-bertha-ultra-lux-gaming-bean-bag-review/">Big Bertha Original Ultra Lux Gaming Bean Bag</a></strong> – 9/10</li>
</ul>
<p>Away from this, we had a good batch of previews. I went hands on with Devolver’s freshly announced co-op shooter <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/28/mycopunk-preview-a-co-op-shooter-for-all-you-fun-guys-out-there/"><strong>Mycopunk</strong></a>, shared some impressions of the “First Person Booter” <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/01/glum-is-a-first-person-booter-that-promises-a-swift-kick-up-the-arse/">GLUM</a></strong>. For a change of pace from that, I also went hands on with the real time tactical wargaming action of <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/29/broken-arrow-preview-would-you-like-to-play-a-wargame/">Broken Arrow</a></strong>, while Dom broke all the music laws while previewing <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/28/unbeatable-is-a-rhythm-action-narrative-adventure-thats-creating-its-own-genre/">Unbeatable</a></strong>.</p>

<p>Finishing up for the week, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/02/what-we-played-mycopunk-oblivion-and-clair-obscur-expedition-33/"><strong>What We Played</strong></a> featured Oblivion Remastered, Clair Obscur &amp; Mycopunk.</p>
<h2>Trailer Park</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/check-out-the-borderlands-4-gameplay-reveal-everything-we-now-know/">Check out the Borderlands 4 gameplay reveal – everything we now know</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe title="Borderlands 4 - State of Play Deep Dive | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0KlRBwf3sjY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/02/get-a-10-minute-look-at-elden-ring-nightreigns-systems/">Get a 10 minute look at Elden Ring Nightreign’s systems</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe title="ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN | Overview Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p2uYT8BQefA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/01/starrupture-gets-10-minutes-of-showcase-footage-showing-gameplay/">StarRupture gets 10 minutes of showcase footage showing gameplay</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="StarRupture: The World of Arcadia-7 Showcase" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/srtUwMGwCuE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/02/sea-of-stars-free-throes-of-the-watchmaker-dlc-ticks-to-release-in-may/">Sea of Stars free Throes of the Watchmaker DLC ticks to release in May</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Sea of Stars: Throes of the Watchmaker DLC | Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tgFi2jXwzVI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>Your Achievements</h2>
<p>What have you been playing this week?</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>TSBonyman&nbsp;</strong>has made a good start on Oblivion Remastered, he just needs to stop breaking so many lockpicks…</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s the round up for this week. Hope you have a great weekend ahead and we’ll see you back here next week!</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naughty Dog Reportedly Canceled a Single Player Game This Year, But Another Unannounced Game Is Still in the Works]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/naughty-dog-reportedly-canceled-a-single-player-game-this-year-but-another-unannounced-game-is-still-in-the-works/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/naughty-dog-reportedly-canceled-a-single-player-game-this-year-but-another-unannounced-game-is-still-in-the-works.1180317/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/naughty-dog-reportedly-canceled-a-single-player-game-this-year-but-another-unannounced-game-is-still-in-the-works/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to insider Daniel Ritchman (as reported <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/naughty-dog-125394539?utm_medium=clipboard_copy&amp;utm_source=copyLink&amp;utm_campaign=postshare_fan&amp;utm_content=web_share" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on his paywalled Patreon page</a>), Santa Monica-based developer Naughty Dog quietly canceled an unannounced single-player game earlier this year. The project had been in development for over a year following the cancellation of The Last of Us Online, the ambitious multiplayer game that was ultimately <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-last-of-us-multiplayer-canceled-naughty-dog-live-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">canceled</a> because Naughty Dog did not want to turn into a live-service games studio (after Bungie explained to them what it would mean).</p>
<p>As you might remember, towards the latter end of its development, The Last of Us Online was being directed by Vinit Agarwal, who previously worked as Game Designer on Uncharted 4: A Thief's End, Uncharted: The Lost Legacy, and The Last of Us Part II. He then moved on to this unannounced project, which was still in its infancy when it was canceled. Agarwal subsequently left Naughty Dog.</p>
<p>Again, according to Richtman, another unannounced single-player title is in the works at the studio. This one is further along in development, having started around three years ago. Its director is Shaun Escayg, who returned to Naughty Dog in April 2021 after a brief stint at Crystal Dynamics as the Director of the ill-fated Marvel's Avengers. Escayg was previously credited as the Lead Cinematic Animator on The Last of Us and Uncharted 4: A Thief's End, and later directed Uncharted: The Lost Legacy.</p>
<p>There's no further information on this game, but we might learn something more concrete in the next couple of years, at least based on the usual development timeframe of a triple-A game. Of course, the main project at Naughty Dog remains Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, a brand new sci-fi intellectual property <a href="https://wccftech.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-naughty-dog-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> at The Game Awards 2024. This action/adventure game is directed by Neil Druckmann, the company's president and the renowned creator of The Last of Us (and current executive producer on the HBO show). Druckmann recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-is-a-game-about-faith-and-religion-where-players-will-feel-lonely-says-druckmann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> it'll be a game where players will feel lonely, unlike most Naughty Dog titles, where the protagonist is accompanied by friends and teammates. Religion will be a central theme.</p>
<p>The game has no release date yet, but Bloomberg's Jason Schreier <a href="https://wccftech.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-wont-launch-before-2027-says-schreier/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reckons</a> it won't launch before 2027. It will launch on PlayStation 5 and, presumably, on PC after a while.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blue Prince Interactive Map is Now Available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/blue-prince-interactive-map</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blue-prince-interactive-map-is-now-available.1180251/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/blue-prince-interactive-map<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Includes locations for Clues, Special Keys, Terminals, and more!</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN's Blue Prince map is here! Our interactive map tracks essential locations across Mount Holly, including Clues and Puzzles, so you always know where to go next.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/maps/blue-prince/mount-holly">Blue Prince Interactive Map</a></h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/03/blue-prince-interactive-map-1746236685784.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Click on the image above to go to our Blue Prince interactive map!</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The available map filters for our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/maps/blue-prince/mount-holly"><strong>Blue Prince interactive map</strong></a> include:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Locations</strong>, including Safes, Terminals, Floorplans, and Permanent Unlocks, such as the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/How_to_Unlock_the_West_Gate"><strong>West Gate Path</strong></a>.</li><li><strong>Exploration</strong>, such as Clues, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/Find_the_8_Red_Letters_Walkthrough"><strong>Red Letters</strong></a>, Puzzles, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/List_of_Special_Items_and_Keys"><strong>Special Keys</strong></a>.</li><li>Other miscellaneous map markers, including Upgrade Disks and Allowance Tokens.</li></ul><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/07/blue-prince-blogroll-1744067433486.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">Blue Prince Guides</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are many puzzles in Blue Prince, and it's more than likely you'll find yourself getting stuck more than once. IGN's Blue Prince Game Help is here to assist, with guides for complicated puzzles, how to find certain items, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Our Blue Prince coverage includes:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/Essential_Tips_and_Tricks"><strong>Essential Tips and Tricks</strong></a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/Walkthrough"><strong>Walkthrough</strong></a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/Puzzle_Guides"><strong>Puzzle Guides</strong></a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/Room_Directory_Guide"><strong>Room Directory Guide</strong></a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/How_to_Get_More_Coins"><strong>How to Get More Coins</strong></a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/How_to_Get_More_Gems"><strong>How to Get More Gems</strong></a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/List_of_Special_Items_and_Keys"><strong>List of Special Items and Keys</strong></a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince/All_Workshop_Item_Contraption_Recipes"><strong>All Workshop Item Contraption Recipes</strong></a></li><li>...And more!</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Head to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/blue-prince"><strong>our Blue Prince wiki</strong></a> for more Game Help.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Meg Koepp is a Guides Editor on the IGN Guides team, with a focus on trends. When she's not working, you can find her playing an RPG or spending time with her corgi.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Andor Is Only Getting Better As Its Second Season Continues]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-andor-season-2-review-vg-chat-cinta-ghorman-1851778986</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/andor-is-only-getting-better-as-its-second-season-continues.1180188/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/star-wars-andor-season-2-review-vg-chat-cinta-ghorman-1851778986<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Another Tuesday, another drop of three new <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/what-we-liked-and-loved-about-rogue-one-a-star-wars-st-1790258571&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/what-we-liked-and-loved-about-rogue-one-a-star-wars-st-1790258571"><em>Star Wars: Andor</em></a></span><em> </em>episodes. This time in the <em>Rogue One </em>prequel series, Bix and Cassian dealt with the struggles of being rebels while we learned more about Ghorman and its own fight against the Empire. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197551" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Minecraft Movie Song Sets Record as Shortest Track Ever on Billboard Hot 100" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="121" data-playlist="197551,197550,197547" data-current="197551"><div><p>Minecraft Movie Song Sets Record as Shortest Track Ever on Billboard Hot 100</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197551/197551_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197551/197551_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197551/197551_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23075.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>These new episodes, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-andor-season-2-review-discussion-so-good-1851777959?_gl=1*k9keq4*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDYyMTY4OTIkbzM0OSRnMSR0MTc0NjIyNDc0MSRqMzkkbDAkaDA.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-andor-season-2-review-discussion-so-good-1851777959?_gl=1*k9keq4*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDYyMTY4OTIkbzM0OSRnMSR0MTc0NjIyNDc0MSRqMzkkbDAkaDA.">like last week’s first three</a></span>, were fantastic. And once again, not everyone made it out alive this week. Turns out rebellions are dangerous. Here’s our conversation about <em>Andor </em>episodes 4-6.</p><figure id="" data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><strong>Carolyn Petit</strong>: Last week I said that I really hoped Cassian would get to play a more active, central role in this chunk of episodes, and he certainly did, but I’m gonna kick things off by sidelining him anyway because I want to start with our boy Syril. </p><p>I have to admit, the first 15 minutes or so of episode 4 really had me going. I thought we might see that petty fascist fuck undergo a profound awakening, that maybe his experiences on Ghorman had opened his eyes to the evils of the Empire and provoked a moral crisis within him. They got me good with him telling his mother that she’s been watching too much “Imperial news”—I love the idea of the Empire having its own propagandistic media arm, it totally makes sense that it would, and I know so many folks who have seen their own parents be brain-poisoned by exposure to Fox News so his concern rang true for me—only for this to be revealed as part of the long, elaborate con he’s running with Dedra. </p><p>Did y’all think there might be some good somewhere deep in Syril, or was I the only one naive enough to fall for it?</p><p><strong>Zack Zwiezen</strong>: I also bought it for a bit. And I have some thoughts on that which I’ll mention later, but yeah, I was like “Okay, maybe he’s better!” Nope.</p><p>I loved the one resistance guy who was listening in on his call, remarking on how terrifying his mother sounded. Made me chuckle hard.</p><p>Ethan, did Syril trick you like us? Or did you see through it.</p><p><strong>Ethan Gach</strong>: I was totally hoodwinked, just like the naïve bourgeoisie turned budding rebels Ghormans Cassian chides later on. </p><p>I did appreciate the time spent showing us his new art deco office. Parts of the brief-case carrying Mise-en-scène are very reminiscent of Mad Men. Ghorman is quiet beautiful, and the romanticism of its underground freedom fighter movement cuts an interesting contrast with Bix and Cassian’s claustrophobic safe house on Coruscant.</p><p><strong>ZZ: </strong>I think it was really smart of Gilroy and co to make Ghorman basically space France and show the rebels as the French Resistance. It immediately conveyed what was happening here without having to spend too much time explaining the details.</p><p><strong>CP:</strong> Yes! The show is very deft with its kind of revolutionary politics shorthand, cluing us in to the ways it draws on historical events and famous thinkers while still being believably rooted in <em>Star Wars.</em>&nbsp;</p><p>And to Ethan’s point, one thing I really appreciated across all three of these episodes was <em>Andor’s </em>use of physical space and real sets. Having that plaza on Ghorman with its hotel and café and twillery showroom helped make everything there feel more concrete, from the bellhop’s story about remembering the Tarkin Massacre to the action of that tragic covert op at the end. </p><p>And while Ghorman was often sunny and open, Bix and Cassian’s safehouse was, as you say Ethan, claustrophobic, the lighting there often reminding me of what we see in Deckard’s apartment in<em> Blade Runner</em>, very urban and gray. The show is a visual treat in addition to everything else, and for me it makes such a difference that it doesn’t rely too heavily on the kinds of (admittedly pretty effective) techniques that <em>The Mandalorian </em>often employed.</p><p><strong>ZZ: </strong>I really loved that Ghorman was a big set. I didn’t realize how much I miss <em>Star Wars </em>having big sets filled with aliens and people in the background. By the end of the three episodes I felt like I understood that part of the planet/city and could probably walk around it and not get lost.</p><p><strong>EG:</strong> Yea you got a lot of your silly aliens this week Zack. However, Mon Mothma is no Nancy Pelosi when it comes to whipping votes.</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> I was so happy to see all those alien senators and weirdos. That’s<em> Star Wars,</em> baby. And yeah, poor Mon Mothma. The reveal that the person she’s talking to and trying to get a vote from is Ghorman’s own senator. Damn.</p><p><strong>CP:</strong> Those Ghormans are in a tight spot, no doubt about it.</p><p><strong>ZZ: </strong>At least they live in a very walkable city with lots of nice cafes Though, based on how easily Bix and Andor get around in the dreary depths of Coruscant, I think that giant city is walkable, too. I was also excited to see what, I think, is our first on-screen bodega in <em>Star Wars.</em></p><p><strong>EG: </strong>I kept wondering how anyone picks what bar to go to on a single-city planet.</p><p><strong>CP:</strong> Yes! In fact that’s one of the things I love about <em>Andor </em>in general. By being focused so much on the lives of relatively “ordinary” people—sure, people who get swept up in revolutionary struggle but not Jedi or bounty hunters or what have you—it’s informing our understanding so much of what life is like for ordinary people in the galaxy. Oh look, they have bad daytime TV shows! Oh look, they watch sports (podracing) when they should be doing their jobs!</p><p>That to me is way more interesting territory to explore about that “galaxy far, far away” than, I don’t know, more details about the life of Boba Fett.</p><p><strong>ZZ: </strong>Yes, the moment where Bix woke up to a  crappy morning talk show was very relatable.</p><p><strong>EG:</strong> Saw Gerrera, on the other hand, feels like he needs his own animated spin-off. Forest Whitaker creating a more compelling <em>Star Wars</em> in less than 15 minutes than most of the new trilogy.</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> Ethan, let me introduce you to <em>Star Wars Rebels</em> and <em>Star Wars Clone Wars. </em>But yes, Saw was great in these three episodes. It was also nice to finally find out why he was so fucked up in <em>Rogue On</em>e. We had theories and half answers. Turns out: Dude was huffing space jet fuel and getting wicked high. That’s fun. Good for him.</p><p><strong>CP:</strong> Forest Whitaker is such an incredible actor, and I was so glad to see him finally get to bring the full force of his talent to this role. </p><p>I admit I only know Saw from <em>Rogue One </em>and now <em>Andor </em>(not counting his little appearance in <em>Jedi: Fallen Order</em>), and I’ve always wanted to understand what drove him better, and have a better handle on his politics and on what he brings to the struggle. Part of me felt that his presence in<em> Rogue One </em>could be interpreted as kind of a warning, that little neoliberal tsk-tsk of “sure everyone, fighting fascist oppression is good but you don’t want to go too far with it.” </p><p>But in <em>Andor</em>, because it can take the time to flesh out characters like Luthen, Saw, Kleya, Mon Mothma, and others, all of whom have their own ethics and perspectives, it’s not as big of a deal to me if Saw is a little out there at times.</p><p><strong>EG</strong>: I could use one or two more VFX shots to better establish scope of his insurgency. Show me the battalion pieces on a chess board.</p><figure id="" data-id="8d03a859854f3a9ab32966e1364b43b4" data-recommend-id="image://8d03a859854f3a9ab32966e1364b43b4" data-format="jpg" data-width="835" data-height="467" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Benthic Two Tubes stands against a rocky background." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Benthic Two Tubes stands against a rocky background." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Two Tubes!</figcaption><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Lucasfilm</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8d03a859854f3a9ab32966e1364b43b4" data-recommend-id="image://8d03a859854f3a9ab32966e1364b43b4" data-format="jpg" data-width="835" data-height="467" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Benthic Two Tubes stands against a rocky background." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><strong>CP: </strong>Also, what a great little ragtag band of freedom fighters he’s got with him. Give it up for Two Tubes!</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> Two Tubes!</p><p>Once again, I think this chunk of episodes really did a fantastic job of showing us that the rebellion isn’t this unified thing that we see eventually in the OG movies.</p><p>It’s still messy, spread out, disorganized, and sometimes directly at odds with each other and their methods. And I hope by the end of the series we see them coming together just in time for the Rebels’ first big victory against the Empire as seen in <em>Rogue One.</em></p><p>Also, can we talk about how great Kleya is?! She’s been one of the best parts of the show since season 1, but I feel like these three episodes, in particular the party sequence, gave us more Kleya and I’m happy about that.</p><p><strong>CP:</strong> Yes. I’ve always sort of gotten the feeling that she’s doing more to drive things forward for the Rebellion than the show has let on, but here we finally really saw the steel and determination in her, both in her holding her own against Luthen in arguments and in her actions at the party.</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> The scene where she is squeezing the hidden mic so hard that her hand starts to bleed was one of the best moments in show. That whole sequence was so tense, too.</p><p><strong>EG:</strong> And then Luthen saying how much is face hurt from smiling.</p><p><strong>CP: </strong>It was tense, the show building to climactic points on multiple fronts and then playing them against each other. I’m fully on board with the three-episode release structure at this point, because it really does seem like each of these clusters has its own internal conflicts that pay off in the third episode while also contributing to the season in bigger ways.</p><p><strong>ZZ: </strong>Agreed! Speaking of that moment with Luthen and Kleya, I wanted to shout out the “We should have killed Krennic” comment.</p><p>It was nice to see them both laugh and joke together. But it also felt like Luthen might be a bit of a hypocritic, with his stance against relationships in the rebellion. I wonder if by the end of this season he’s going to have to reckon with how much he cares about Kleya.</p><p>I can almost imagine a scenario where Kleya sacrifices herself to some Imperial asshole to save Luthen from getting caught, taking the fall and in the process scarifying her life and freedom for the cause.</p><p><strong>EG: </strong>I assume the link up with Rogue One means Luthen is not going to make it. Speaking of people who don’t make it...</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> I think Luthen can make it. Just because he’s not there doesn’t me he’s dead. And are you are talking about Bix?</p><p><strong>EG:</strong> Cinta!</p><p><strong>CP:</strong> Okay, yeah, let’s talk about Cinta.</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> Ohhh right right. I guess she isn’t making after being shot dead. </p><p>I was so happy to see her back in this episode. And to have her go out like that was heartbreaking. But I don’t agree with some who say her death was handled poorly. I think like Brasso, her death was an example that nobody is safe in a rebellion and death can come quickly. Heroes don’t always get big moments. Sometimes they just die quietly because of a dumb kid or a single trooper. </p><p><strong>EG:</strong> She’s always been the most laser focused on the cause, and puts it above even her relationship with Vel. Her loss seemed fittingly chaotic and self-inflicted, but I think she also knew that was a possibility and made the choice anyway, unlike some of the rebels who still have only one foot in that world.</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> I do wonder how she’ll react when she finds out (if she does) that Andor said no to helping which put her and Cinta into this spot.</p><p><strong>CP: </strong>I saw the critique raised that her death was a textbook example of the “Bury Your Gays” trope, but while I think being aware of such tropes can be useful for perceiving larger patterns that repeat—sometimes innocuously, sometimes harmfully—across popular media, I personally don’t care to criticize Andor specifically for having Cinta die. </p><p>She was a character we cared deeply about, she’s one of many characters who have died (and no doubt more will yet), and I feel the show earned that moment, which, as you suggest Zack, may have repercussions in the episodes to come.</p><p><strong>ZZ: </strong>Totally. And look, its not like<em> Star Wars </em>has a good track record (in live-action at least) for representing LGBTQ+ characters. So I do have empathy for people who finally saw themselves in<em> Star Wars </em>in a way that is so rare in this franchise, only to have one of them killed like that.</p><p><strong>CP: </strong>Absolutely.</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> But I also agree that the death had meaning, will likely be one of many to come, and might factor into future events. So I’m not sure it is a negative example of the trope. </p><p>Something we also don’t see much in <em>Star Wars</em>: Sex. Or well... the moments before sex. Syril and Dedra’s moment in her apartment. “Turn off the lights.”</p><p><strong>CP:</strong> Hahaha, when we finally do get a prelude to sex it’s the most awkward prelude imaginable between the most awkward people imaginable.</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> I really wonder what... <em>that </em>looks like.</p><p><strong>CP: </strong>It’s interesting in a way to contrast their relationship with the one between Cassian and Bix.</p><p>Both are brought together to some degree by common cause but Cassian and Bix’s connection feels so much more warm and human, even though there’s tension and conflict there sometimes. </p><p>Thematically, this week’s episodes reminded me a lot of one of my all-time favorite shows, <em>The Americans.</em> On that show, the central couple—Russian spies posing as an American couple—always had to put on phony identities and disguises and engage in deception and performance on multiple levels. And on this week’s <em>Andor </em>episodes, we had Cassian take on a totally fake identity and deal with complications in his relationship, while Dedra and Syril are also engaged in these layers of deception for their operation. </p><p>And in that dynamic, Dedra seems to be operating at one level of deception beyond Syril; to him, they’re partners of a sort, but I feel like to her, maybe he’s just a pawn.</p><p><strong>ZZ: </strong>Speaking of Syril, I do want to call out that the actor who plays him mentioned in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/3ihBfycg8Wg&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/3ihBfycg8Wg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a recent behind the scenes video</a></span> that Syril doesn’t really know what’s going on. This is something that the show also mentions. And the actor suggests that if Syril was to learn the trurh about Ghroman and being used like that, he might not like it. I wonder if that’s a hint that perhaps Syril will turn before the show ends. </p><p><strong>CP:</strong> I’m not sure if I hope you’re right or wrong there, Zack. Part of me wants to see him redeem himself in some way, and part of me just loves to hate him for the sniveling fascist that he is.</p><p>Before we wrap up, I also want to mention Cassian and Bix’s little excursion. It’s funny to find an execution like that romantic but in a way I did. Cassian is devoted to Bix, and will gladly blow up a motherfucker for her. It was one more thing that made the dynamic between the two of them such a wonderful contrast with the kind of clammy, off-putting energy that pulls Dedra and Syril together.</p><p><strong>ZZ: </strong>Yes! I loved that ending. I also appreciated how the show trusted us to connect to dots on how they found him, etc. And that moment where she sits the evil space-Nazi doctor in his torture chair and gets her revenge was great. </p><p>I especially like that last minute reveal of Andor. At first I was like, wait is she going rogue? But no, they are a great couple, he trusts her, and they get shit done. It goes against what Luthen worries about. It turns out having someone on your side, someone you love and trust, can be a strength in a rebellion. </p><p><strong>CP: </strong>That’s exactly right. And in a way I think this ties into the larger arcs of <em>Star Wars</em> as well, such as the Jedi focus on a lack of attachment or love as seemingly a state to be pursued. We’ve seen the toll that can take. </p><p>Ultimately, what are all these characters fighting for, from Luke Skywalker to Cassian Andor to Saw Gerrera and Luthen and on and on? Not for themselves. Many of them know they probably won’t make it. You fight for each other, and loving other people should, it seems to me, be at the core of that. I think you’re right that even Luthen will come to realize this to some degree before all is said and done.</p><p><strong>ZZ:</strong> Stellan Skarsgård mentioned in that same behind the scenes video I mentioned earlier, that Luthen checking on Bix is an example of him having empathy. And he points out that Luthen has to have empathy because that’s the entire point of a rebellion. You care about others so much you are willing to die for them to save them. That’s empathy. Luthen is cold at times. But he does care. </p><p>And I’m excited to see more of him and the rest of the gang next week!</p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's The Emperor From Star Wars Holding An Assault Rifle In Fortnite]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-fortnite-emperor-gun-rifle-fortnite-palpatine-1851778966</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-the-emperor-from-star-wars-holding-an-assault-rifle-in-fortnite.1180164/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/star-wars-fortnite-emperor-gun-rifle-fortnite-palpatine-1851778966<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="52e5606092fa58fbf9146248b71c279e" data-recommend-id="image://52e5606092fa58fbf9146248b71c279e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="52e5606092fa58fbf9146248b71c279e" data-recommend-id="image://52e5606092fa58fbf9146248b71c279e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>I wanted to share this with you. The image above is a real screenshot of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/how-parents-can-get-started-in-fortnite-1851688072&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/how-parents-can-get-started-in-fortnite-1851688072"><em>Fortnite</em></a></span><em> </em>featuring Darth Sidious aka the Emperor aka Sheev Palpatine from <em>Star Wars</em> holding an assault rifle. I thought you would want to see this, so I’m sharing it with you.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194617" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Fortnite Introduces Force Abilities In Latest Star Wars Collab" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="194617,196029,196115" data-current="194617"><div><p>Fortnite Introduces Force Abilities In Latest Star Wars Collab</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20078.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>I don’t have that much more to add, really. I guess I should provide some context. On Friday, <em>Fortnite </em>launched its newest in-game season. As the above image of Palpatine holding an assault rifle might indicate,<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-fortnite-darth-jar-jar-galactic-battle-skins-1851777078?_gl=1*h1mno4*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjIxNjg5Mi4zNDkuMS4xNzQ2MjIxODgyLjE4LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-fortnite-darth-jar-jar-galactic-battle-skins-1851777078?_gl=1*h1mno4*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjIxNjg5Mi4zNDkuMS4xNzQ2MjIxODgyLjE4LjAuMA.."> the new season is <em>Star Wars</em>-themed</a></span>. And our ol’ pal the Emperor has been added to the game’s ever-growing roster of characters. That means the Emperor can land in <em>Fortnite</em> and kill Goku with a shotgun. We live in a weird world, huh? <br></p><p>To unlock Emperor Palpatine in <em>Fortnite </em>you’ll need to reach page seven of the new <em>Star Wars</em> battle pass. He’s the final big reward. You can also unlock a Lego version of him. That one can’t hold a gun, but he can hold swords, blasters, and bows. That’s fun. You can also unlock a red version of the Emperor as seen in<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-best-and-worst-parts-of-every-star-wars-movie-1850406311&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-best-and-worst-parts-of-every-star-wars-movie-1850406311"> <em>Star Wars Episode III: Revenge of the Sith</em></a></span>. I prefer his old black robes, but to each their own. </p><p>I guess while I have you here, I should mention that all <em>Star Wars </em>characters that get added to <em>Fortnite </em>can also hold assault rifles. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/FortniteLeaks/comments/1k51jci/c3po_skin_coming_to_fortnite_next_season_via_hypex/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortniteLeaks/comments/1k51jci/c3po_skin_coming_to_fortnite_next_season_via_hypex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">There’s a rumor that C-3PO might be added to the game soon</a></span>. If so, he, too, will be able to load up and shoot some guns. That’s wild. </p><p>If that happens I’ll try to remember to update this blog and include an image of that. Until then, please enjoy that image of the Emperor from <em>Star Wars</em> holding an assault rifle in <em>Fortnite</em>. </p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;  .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Polygon And Giant Bomb Are Being Sacrificed At The Altar Of Slop]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-giant-bomb-polygon-layoffs-valnet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/polygon-and-giant-bomb-are-being-sacrificed-at-the-altar-of-slop.1180161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-giant-bomb-polygon-layoffs-valnet<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>We live in a time when it’s not exactly uncommon to have your routine shattered by the sudden, resounding death knell of a publication that taught you your whole worldview, but two in one day? Come on. That’s exactly what happened this week when both <a href="https://aftermath.site/polygon-layoffs-sale" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Polygon</a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/giant-bomb-fandom-dan-ryckert-jeff-grubb-gerstmann-1851778728" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Giant Bomb</a>, beloved games media institutions, got gutted within hours of one another. The internet is descending into a sea of slop, and this is how it happens: one sacrifice to the almighty Line at a time. On this week’s <a href="https://aftermath.site/tag/aftermath-hours" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Aftermath Hours</a>, we mourn what was.</p><p>None of this was, strictly speaking, necessary, with Polygon an unqualified success in terms of traffic while Giant Bomb boasted a dedicated audience drawn to its unique mix of personalities. But of course, parasitic execs decided to suck the marrow from the bones of both, and now we’re left wondering what comes next. Independent, worker-owned sites like ours hope to pave a path toward a better future, but that will take a lot of time, and many excellent writers are out of work right now. In the short term, nobody benefits from this. Even influencers who claim to dislike journalists rely on them for content, and due to vastly different incentive structures, content creation is doing a poor job of taking journalism’s place.&nbsp;</p><p>Then, in less soul-crushing news, we discuss this year’s latest surprise hit, <a href="https://aftermath.site/clair-obscur-nathan-tips" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">extremely French J’RPG <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a>, which we do our best to celebrate despite the dour mood. Finally, we wrap up with the longest mailbag in the show’s history, so get comfortable.</p><p>You can find this week's episode below and on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/7qtlX6MNeEoyNuHBU0chUJ?si=a2f12b75911f43cb" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spotify</a>, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/aftermath-hours/id1727407094" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Apple</a>, or wherever else you prefer to listen to podcasts. If you like what you hear, make sure to leave a review so that we can someday afford to hire everybody who’s been laid off and let them do whatever their hearts desire. In other words, absolute freak shit.</p><p>Here’s an excerpt from our conversation (edited for length and clarity):</p><p><strong>Nathan:</strong> You definitely have a lot of executives who obviously don’t understand media in general. That’s <a href="https://www.megangreenwell.com/the-adults-in-the-room" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the “Adults In The Room” post</a>, talking about people who on one hand ostensibly are the leaders of these websites, but on the other hand do not trust the people who are writing things – who are creating what basically is the appeal of the website – to understand what would be best for the website.</p><p>But then there’s another layer to it with games in that execs don’t even have a frame of reference for the subject matter. Like if you’re an exec at G/O Media back in the day with Deadspin, you’re like “Well, I know sports vaguely. I grew up with sports. They’re all around me. I know how to play some of them because I went to school.” Whereas a lot of these executives with video games are like “Well yeah, I’ve heard of <em>Mario </em>and <em>Fruit Ninja</em>” – or something else incredibly basic that’s not really indicative at all of the breadth and scope of video games in the year 2025.&nbsp;</p><p>So from this very narrow point of view, they imagine that people who read about games just want reviews and guides. There’s probably nothing else happening in the games industry; it’s not like it’s bigger than Hollywood or anything. Because their imagination is so limited and their understanding is so incurious, this is where you end up. They’re like “Oh yeah, I’m sure you can just get rid of all these people who are intrinsic to the site’s identity and slap the same label on some different guides.” Because it’s all interchangeable to them. It’s all the same slop.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Luke: </strong>This is every industry, though, right? Enough generations of business leaders have had their brains so commodified by business school “number go up” [rationale] that numbers going up is the only thing that matters. The fact that those numbers are actually representative of the actions and the work of people was lost a long time ago.&nbsp;</p><p>And so, they will look at the numbers and think the guides are this, they’re worth this much money, or they’re going to be worth this much money. Valnet look at Polygon’s guides and think they’re worth X amount of money, and they will now have that money. And it’s like, well, no you won’t, because the people who wrote those guides, which made them good, which provided those numbers are gone, you fucking idiots. You’re not getting what you paid for, because you’re only looking at numbers. You’re not looking at people.</p><p><strong>Chris:</strong> The thing that’s so frustrating about today is that you have two tragedies stacked on top of each other, and it makes the more recent one – the bigger one, honestly – take priority, but it is the same dynamic with Giant Bomb. In that case, it’s like, brand safety? They got mad at them for brand safety. They’re Giant Bomb! Why would you buy them if you don’t like them cursing and shit?</p><p><strong>Nathan:</strong> While we’ve been recording this, Giant Bomb, the brand, put out a statement – a very short one that basically elucidates nothing. They <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/giantbomb.bsky.social/post/3lo55ow25dc2a" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>, “We understand your frustration and appreciate your patience — we're actively exploring creative directions for the future of GB and look forward to sharing more with you soon.” After a week of internal upheaval and clear unrest, that’s the best they could come up with.</p><p><strong>Chris:</strong> That sounds just like their voice, too. When I think of Giant Bomb, I think of shit like that. And replies have been disabled.</p><p><strong>Nathan: </strong>The whole thing is especially weird to me in Giant Bomb’s case, because it points to this tension between a wider shift in the media landscape and what the owners of these sites seem to want. Media has moved, for better and for worse, in a very personality driven direction, which is why so many people get their news from influencers in video games and outside of video games. Meanwhile, a lot of people who are buying up these sites are like “No, we’ve gotta strip away as much personality as possible,” whether it’s this brand safety thing for Giant Bomb, or Kotaku, for example, not letting writers do personal game-of-the-year lists anymore. Because that gives them too much of a face and a name, I guess.</p><p>One of these things is proven to work, which is personalities; that’s what people are into now. But personalities are hard to control, and they can become bigger than the site in question and gain more power. The people in charge are so afraid of individuals gaining power that they’re like “I will shoot myself in the foot just to make sure that you can’t carve out a space for yourself.” It is deranged and again goes back to this idea that these people do not know what they’re doing and are not even good at running a business. Because the thing that would help them is clear as day, but they’re too afraid to do it, because they’re too afraid of losing power. It’s all about power.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/soccer-mommy-stardew-valley"><h3>Soccer Mommy’s Guide To Stardew Valley, The Coziest Video Game Ever</h3></a><p>The open-hearted indie rocker plays the farming game for the romance</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/polygon-layoffs-sale"><h3>Polygon Sold To Valnet</h3></a><p>Multiple staff laid off</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GAMA Expo Will Be Moving To Baltimore in the Future]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/gama-expo-will-be-moving-to-baltimore-in-future</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gama-expo-will-be-moving-to-baltimore-in-the-future.1180143/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/gama-expo-will-be-moving-to-baltimore-in-future<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Game Manufacturers Association has chosen a new home for the GAMA Expo. Due to rising attendance, this tabletop convention, one of the largest in North America, will come to Baltimore in the future.</p>

<h2>The GAMA Expo Location Change</h2>

<p>In a report by <a href="https://boardgamewire.com/index.php/2025/05/01/gama-picks-baltimore-as-new-home-for-annual-gama-expo-after-trade-event-quickly-outgrows-new-louisville-home/" rel="nofollow">Board Game Wire</a>, GAMA's site selection committee chose Baltimore out of 30 potential cities as the future venue for the GAMA Expo. According to a representative, the expo had doubled in size since 2023. The last year held at its original venue in Reno, Nevada, resulted in over 2,000 attendants.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gama-expo-show-floor-banner.jpg?itok=tav0D7OG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gama-expo-show-floor-banner.jpg?itok=AsNXSmQL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As a result of this growth, the GAMA Expo was moved to Louisville, Kentucky for their 2024 and 2025 conventions. While this choice was made based on historical data, attendance blew past the organization's original projections. The attendance of this year's expo rose to 3,420.</p>

<p>This venue change will not happen immediately. GAMA signed a three-year contract in Louisville for 2024 to 2026. An extension was made to 2027 as part of the city recognizing the organization had outgrown the footprint available across the original dates. That means that, for the time being, the GAMA Expo will be in Louisville until that contract expires.</p>

<p>The Game Manufacturers Association is one of the largest tabletop organizations in the US. They are a vocally progressive organization, suspending known alt-right grifter <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/jon-del-arroz-suspended-from-gama" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Jon Del Arroz</a> from their ranks and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/game-manufacturers-association-opposes-new-trade-tariffs" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">expressly opposing</a> the disastrous US trade tariffs on Chinese imports.</p>

<p>The fact the GAMA Expo continues to see growth in attendance and talent is a welcome one in the tabletop industry. It is one contrasted with the harsh realities of publishers <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/cmon-reduces-staff-and-pauses-board-game-development-amid-us-trade-tariffs" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">shutting down</a> or <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/stonemaier-games-suing-us-president-over-tariffs" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">filing lawsuits</a> amind a volatile present and uncertain future. However, this does show that there is still a passionate community willing to give more creative talents a voice and platform.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>