<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:17:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ratatan Early Access Review – Rhythm-action warfare is the best kind of warfare]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/10/ratatan-early-access-review-rhythm-action-warfare-is-the-best-kind-of-warfare/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ratatan-early-access-review-%E2%80%93-rhythm-action-warfare-is-the-best-kind-of-warfare.1321600/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<hr>
<p>Few sounds are as deeply ingrained in our household as the merry chant of the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/patapon">Patapon</a>. A PSP favourite, and with three games in the bag, Sony then seemed to forget about the little one-eyed weirdos, occasionally <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/10/patapon-12-replay-review-rhythm-action-repeat/">dusting the first two games off for remasters</a>. The team at TVT and Ratata Arts haven’t forgotten, though. Made up of various team members from the original games, they’ve set sail on an all new, rhythm-action extravaganza in the shape of Ratatan. For all the changes and modernity that they’ve brought, it’s still of game of tiny weirdos, impressive footwork and merry chants. I wouldn’t want it any other way.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ratatan Animation: Welcome to Rataport" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ANtXCPQ7eD0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Expansive. That’s the word that you’ll associate with Ratatan if you’ve played previous Patapon games. There’s simply more here, and that starts with choosing your Ratatan. There’s eight incredibly cool, but equally cute, leading characters to choose from, all of whom have different abilities and weapon selections.</p>


<p>Mashuma is clad in a mushroom – or maybe is a mushroom? – and plays a toadstool bagpipe. That’s very cool. Pyokorappa looks like a cyberpunk rabbit, plays a trombone, and sounds suspiciously like a Patapon. That’s all very cool too. Frogs, owls, ninja cats, whichever of the lovingly created characters you go for, you’ll find you now have direct control over them, functioning as lead instrumentalist and general, so not only do you have to command your diminuitive single-eyed army, you have to think about where you’re standing too. At first, this feels like more than the tiny human mind can cope with, but you soon start to understand how it all works.</p>


<p>Ratata looks stunning. The artwork here is beautiful, taking the stripped back visual design of Patapon and laying on a massive palette of colour, detail and vibrancy. Everything feels alive, and that sense of life carries through from the characters and different enemies you come across, all the way to the hub world that you visit in-between each run.</p>
<p>Each run sees you taking your army of Ratatan, which are one eyed fish people as opposed to one eyed… actually, what were Patapon? Presumably, they’re the same species as Mike Wazowski? Some sort of cyclops? Anyway, you set out int the overworld with your army, fighting your way through small skirmishes until you meet the huge boss at the end. That starts out with a huge dinosaur-esque badnik, before moving things onto giant armoured crabs and shark/bull hybrids.</p>
<p>Whatever awesome-looking form they take, you’ll need to be prepared, and you do that through repeated runs. Patapon was fundamentally always roguelite adjacent, rewarding repeated runs through the same areas, building your armoury and levelling up your army. That’s just more obvious here, and as you beat all those evil little one eyed armies with your good one eyed army, you’ll pick up weaponry and materials that you’ll need to advance further.</p>

<p>Besides that, there’s a run of Ratakurata cards that you collect, enhancing your attacks with different effects. The two main card types add an elemental attack to either your standard move or your special, while others may prolong certain effects or give you higher damage or better defense. Each run can be completely different, between choosing alternate lead characters, who then use different Cubon types, with access to alternate weaponry, and then the random factor and decisions of selecting your Ratakurata cards. It really helps to avoid some of the grind, when everything can be changed up run by run as you seek out your favourite setup. It throws a lot at you, but manages to maintain a distinct sense of self and direction in the process</p>
<p>It all comes down to the music though. Rhythm-action games live and die by their soundtrack, and Ratatan serves up bop after bop. I don’t remember a rhythm action game in recent memory that has had me bopping along as consistently as Ratatan does, with each world shifting through clearer genres and musical composition than Patapon ever did. It will make you smile, and it will make you happy, and that kind of unburdened joy is in short supply these days.</p>

<p>As you progress, your hub town swells to include various different townspeople and merchants, all of whom want to help you out, or charge you a suspiciously high amount of materials in exchange for something else. Levelling up and crafting weapons for your army is a highlight, and some of the designs for the special weaponry is Monster Hunter-level good. They definitely need to make more of these, because what’s better than a one-eyed army setting off into battle with an array of sick weaponry?</p>
<p>Ratatan is exactly what I wanted it to be. In Early Access this is a fresh, modern take on Patapon’s iconic action with an invigorating visual design and awesome soundtrack. All I want now from the journey to 1.0 is even more of this.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/10/ratatan-early-access-review-rhythm-action-warfare-is-the-best-kind-of-warfare/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Little Nightmares III Review – Fresh Storyteller, Stale Scares]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/little-nightmares-iii/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/little-nightmares-iii-review-%E2%80%93-fresh-storyteller-stale-scares.1321597/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Little Nightmares III</h5><p><span>October 10, 2025</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch, Nintendo Switch 2</span>
						</p></div><div>
							<h5>Developer</h5><p><span>Supermassive Games</span>
						</p></div></div></div>			
			<p>The Little Nightmares franchise has been a bit of a surprise hit, moving over 20 million units to date, so it’s <em>not </em>surprising that publisher Bandai Namco has opted to continue on with a third entry even though series creators Tarsier Studios has decided to move on. <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/little-nightmares-iii/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares III</a> instead comes to us from the horror specialists at <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/supermassive-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Supermassive Games</a>, who have made a clear effort to recreate the look and feel of previous entries in the series. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Is Little Nightmares III a successful continuation of the franchise? Or is it time to wake from this recurring dream? Rub that sleep from your eyes and read on to find out...</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>While the Little Nightmares series has always taken a wordless enigmatic approach to storytelling, the first two games offered more character development and hinted-at lore than you might expect. Supermassive at least partially resets the universe in Little Nightmares III, introducing two new mysterious protagonists, "Low" and "Alone," and some changes to the series' narrative structure that turns the "Little Nightmares" title into more of a literal statement. Overall, our new protagonists are likable enough, but some of the sense of intrigue and mystery that surrounded the first two Little Nightmares games is missing here.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In terms of gameplay, Supermassive doesn’t stray far from Tarsier’s blueprint. Little Nightmares III is a 2.5D platformer, with players having a relatively limited moveset, including the ability to jump, grab onto ledges and items, run, and crouch to sneak and fit through tight spaces. New to this game, each playable character now has a specific tool they carry with them at all times — Low has a bow that they can use to shoot things from afar, and Alone wields a wrench they can use to smash stuff and turn some cranks.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>For the most part, Supermassive have very accurately replicated the feel of past Little Nightmares games, for better and worse. Character movement is very deliberate, which isn't a bad thing in a horror game, but platforming in particular can feel very inconsistent and "canned." There are times when the game's fixed camera angles and perspectives make it very difficult to properly judge jumps, with certain trouble spots causing me to die dozens of times (and I’ve been playing difficult platformers since the '80s). Thankfully, Supermassive<em> has </em>addressed Little Nightmares II's excruciatingly bad combat. It's still not <em>great </em>here, but both Low and Alone having their own dedicated weapons greatly reduces frustration.</p>



<p>Speaking of our dual protagonists, the other big thing Supermassive has added to Little Nightmares III is online co-op. Little Nightmares II took a The-Last-of-Us-like approach, with players relying on an AI-controlled partner to get past some obstacles, and you can still play that way in Little Nightmares III, but you can also now team up with an actual human. Due to the new co-op focus, Supermassive have included some puzzles and challenges that require some slightly more involved teamwork. Nothing too crazy — this isn't a Hazelight game — but you will need some coordination when playing with another person, which can be fun.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Unfortunately, these moments aren’t as satisfying when playing solo. Players pick Low or Alone at the beginning of a singleplayer run, and there’s no ability to switch back and forth between them. During some of the more complex team tasks, you simply do your side of the challenge and the AI will automatically do their side. Strictly speaking, this works, but it almost feels like cheating as your AI partner flawlessly completes their half of a puzzle. When your AI companion isn’t being overly competent, they’re often the opposite, getting lost behind or failing to zero in and do a simple thing you need to proceed. The AI always came around in the end for me, but not before some moments of irritation and wasted time.</p>



<p>Supermassive could also have done more to make co-op accessible to more people. Little Nightmares III can only be played online with folks on your friends list; there is no couch co-op, and your ability to communicate with your partner is very limited. That said, Little Nightmares III does include a Hazelight-style Friend Pass, allowing you to play with an online pal even if they don't own a copy of the game, so kudos for that.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Beyond the addition of co-op, Little Nightmares III feels very much like its predecessors, with its various sequences and set pieces sometimes feeling almost copy-pasted. Platform over rickety structures, crawl through various vents and tunnels, find skittery hiding nomes, tote around batteries to power devices, observe and sneak by various shambling monstrosities, run from those monstrosities in tense chase scenes, etc. If you’ve played past Little Nightmares games, you’ve done all this before. Little Nightmares III only summons up a couple of genuinely original sequences, which are saved for the game's final chapter. This finale hints at what Little Nightmares III <em>could </em>have been, but for most of the game's runtime, the game is merely fine. Arguably more fun and refined than the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/little-nightmares-ii/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">often-frustrating Little Nightmares II</a>, but rarely surprising.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The game is also rarely all that scary. Earlier Little Nightmares titles were far from perfect, but they had a special <em>something</em>. The leathery Muppet-ey freaks that populated Tarsier's Little Nightmares games were uniquely off-putting, and while Supermassive tries their best to dream up their own atrocities, their creations don't quite measure up with many treading too close to generic creepy doll territory. Visually, Little Nightmares III also lacks some of the ambiance of the first two games, and even on PS5, it doesn't run quite as well as I'd like.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Little Nightmares III - 'Alone' Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qj7mv95LbFU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Don’t get me wrong, despite the relatively negative tone of this review, Little Nightmares III does have its moments and can be fun with another human player. The game just doesn’t stand out in any particular way and with a relatively brief 4-hour runtime, this will likely be one of those dreams that fades from your mind not long after you wake up.</p>



<p><em>This review was based on a PS5 copy of Little Nightmares III provided by publisher Bandai Namco.</em></p>

						<p>You can find <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-we-test-video-games/">additional information about our standard review process and ethics policy here.</a></p>
			
				

						<div>
					
					<div>
						<p><span>6</span></p><h5>WCCFTECH RATING</h5>
					</div>
					<h2>Little Nightmares III</h2>
				</div>
			
						<section>
				<p>Little Nightmares III does a solid job of emulating the gameplay of earlier entries in the series, sometimes to a fault, but it doesn’t bring a whole lot else to the table and new developer Supermassive Games can’t quite pin down the eerie tone and creeping tension that made these games popular. While the ability to play online with others will appeal to some, it’s hard to escape the feeling that this series has officially gone from sleeper hit to just plain sleepy.</p>
				<div>
												<ul>
							<h6>Pros</h6>
							<li>Familiar gameplay still mostly works
</li><li>Some memorable late-game moments
</li><li>Online co-op is a welcome addition
</li><li>Effectively icky sound effects</li>						</ul>
																		<ul>
							<h6>Cons</h6>
							<li>Truly original ideas thin on the ground
</li><li>Not as uniquely creepy as the Tarsier games
</li><li>Lack of local co-op and other options
</li><li>A very quick playthrough</li>						</ul>
										</div>
				<a rel="sponsored nofollow noskim" href="https://amzn.to/4ocBs5i">Buy for $39.88 from Amazon</a>
				<span>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may
					earn from qualifying purchases.</span>
			</section>
			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/review/little-nightmares-iii/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 director warns next patch will target overpowered builds relying on "unintended interactions"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-director-warns-next-patch-will-target-overpowered-builds-relying-on-unintended-interactions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-director-warns-next-patch-will-target-overpowered-builds-relying-on-unintended-interactions.1321594/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>As the latest one focuses on gear tweaks</p>

    </div>


  <p>


  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-4-patch-gear-balancing-more-performance-fixes-soon-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Gearbox</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>This week's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> patch has arrived, firing some gear balancing tweaks into the looter <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooter</a>'s innards, then probably dropping a cringey catchphrase. Developers Gearbox have also revealed some of what's in store for the larger patch that's set to arrive next week, with performance fixes back on the menu alongside some more in-depth balancing that'll touch "those unintended interactions" folks have been relying on for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/psst-borderlands-4-has-a-pretty-broken-infinite-damage-build-and-it-may-soon-go-the-way-of-the-dodo">overpowered builds</a>.</p>
<p>It's all in the line with the nice rhythm the studio have settled into following an initial flurry of activity in response to the game running not goodly on PC out of the gate. Last week brought <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4s-first-major-balancing-patch-is-out-now-delivering-beefy-vault-hunter-buffage-across-the-board">a big patch featuring the first round of vault hunter balancing tweaks</a>, so this week sees a chaser precede the next shot.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"We’re continuing to monitor feedback to the vault hunter changes and identifying areas to make further improvements," Gearbox wrote in <a href="https://borderlands.2k.com/borderlands-4/update-notes/">the notes for this chaser patch</a>, before listily outlining the following gear adjustage:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ruby's Grasp damage increased by 50%</li>
<li>Ruby's Grasp fire rate increased by 25%</li>
<li>Bully drone damage increased by 50%</li>
<li>Bully base damage increased by 50%</li>
<li>Rangefinder base damage increase by 30%</li>
<li>Queen's Rest spawn chance increased from 30% to 50%</li>
<li>Queen's Rest fire rate increased by 50%</li>
<li>Seventh Sense orb damage increased by 250%</li>
<li>Hellwalker base damage increase 30%</li>
<li>Convergence base damage increase by 25%</li>
</ul>
<p>There are a couple of other tweaks. The legendary tediore shotgun anarchy will now properly award stacks of mutualism when auto-reloading or netting kills, every single pet now gets the appropriate chance of a critical hit from passives and gear, and Vex's bleed now counts as status effect damage. That last one sounds like it could be bad news for those exploity Vex knife builds, but even if it isn't, overpowered Vexers likely won't sleep well for the next seven days.</p><p>I say that because Gearbox have made clear next week's patch will "address unintended interactions in certain vault hunter skills, and make adjustments to overperforming gear", with Borderlands 4 director Graeme Timmins going as far as to phrase <a href="https://x.com/ProdigyXL/status/1976321473041322127">a tweet about it</a> as a warning to those with overpowered builds. He's gotten some pushback from anti-nerfage campaigners, and responded by writing: "We have future content like the upcoming Invincible that we want players to find challenge/accomplishment in. If we balanced that content around bad gear, it would remove build diversity, forcing players into specific builds using said gear."</p>
<p>Also teased for next week's patch were "another round of adjustments that will focus on class mods, repkits, shields, and firmware being tuned to provide greater viability for melee builds, and account for deficiencies in other specific vault hunter builds", and more stabs at improving the game's performance. In the meantime, maybe pen a poetic eulogy for Vex's boss-destroying knifeage, lest the heady days of its max bleeding be forgotten.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-director-warns-next-patch-will-target-overpowered-builds-relying-on-unintended-interactions]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 has brought back a community-favourite dog tag for all the high fliers out there]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-has-brought-back-a-community-favourite-dog-tag-for-all-the-high-fliers-out-there</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-has-brought-back-a-community-favourite-dog-tag-for-all-the-high-fliers-out-there.1321591/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>


  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Battlefield-6-Official-Campaign-Trailer-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a> players have discovered that a fan-favourite aerial manoeuvre has been given its own dedicated dog tag, for those willing to leap from the safety of their aerial vehicle.</p>
<p>The Rendezook dog tag is awarded to players who manage to leap from the pilot seat of their jet, shoot down an enemy jet with a bazooka, then climb back into the safety of their own jet. The term is a blend of the words rendezvous and bazooka, describing the safe return of a player after using their bazooka for some daring rocket-to-plane action.</p>
<p>The Rendezook is a feat cemented in Battlefield history by its community, specifically by a player called Stun_Gravy, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FOaGhE_sejI">who posted a Battlefield 3 video</a> in which he performs the now-legendary Rendezook. That video went viral, and as such the challenge for other Battlefield players to reenact the move was established.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Battlefield 6 Review (Spoiler Free)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N5TCS-pDmqk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Battlefield 6 Review (Spoiler Free)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N5TCS-pDmqk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/N5TCS-pDmqk?autoplay=1" title="Battlefield 6 Review (Spoiler Free)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Battlefield 6 Review - The Best Entry In Ages...When It's Being Battlefield<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N5TCS-pDmqk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>For those unaware, Dog Tags in Battlefield games are unlockable cosmetics, all of which require some pre-requisite achievement or challenge to be completed before you can wear them. You can steal another player's dog tags by taking them down in melee, but you can't wear these stolen tags. That means for the Rendezook dog tag - as well as all other prestigious tags - you'll have to do it yourself.</p><p>It means in your multiplayer games you could very well see some bozo try and fail over and over again to pull off a Rendezook in a public lobby, which hey, is part of the Battlefield charm. Seeing someone grab and waste a jet is about as classic a Battlefield moment as seeing a helicopter full of soldiers swan dive into the floor.</p>
<p>Speaking of Battlefield 6, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-review">Eurogamer's Battlefield 6 review went live this week</a>. Reviewer Rick Lane wrote: "Battlefield 6 delivers a thrilling multiplayer reset and a decent, if derivative single-player. But it still displays nagging doubts about what makes Battlefield special."</p>



        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-has-brought-back-a-community-favourite-dog-tag-for-all-the-high-fliers-out-there]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Minecraft Movie gets inevitable sequel after grossing almost $1bn, putting lava chicken back on the menu]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-gets-inevitable-sequel-after-grossing-almost-1bn-putting-lava-chicken-back-on-the-menu</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-minecraft-movie-gets-inevitable-sequel-after-grossing-almost-1bn-putting-lava-chicken-back-on-the-menu.1321588/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>


  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-Minecraft-Movie-_-Official-Trailer-0-24-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Warner Bros.</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A Minecraft Movie is getting a sequel and it's due out on 23rd July 2027.</p>
<p>The news was shared on the official Minecraft social media account with an image of two pickaxes. "Building terrain," the post teased.</p>
<p>News of a sequel is no surprise, in part due to the reveal in April a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-sequel-discussions-are-already-happening">follow-up film was already in discussion</a>. The film's director Jared Hess teased where the film series could go next, pointing to a post-credits scene for clues.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="A Minecraft Movie | Official Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wJO_vIDZn-I?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>A Minecraft Movie | Official Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wJO_vIDZn-I?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wJO_vIDZn-I?autoplay=1" title="A Minecraft Movie | Official Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>A Minecraft Movie | Official Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wJO_vIDZn-I" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Hess is also due to return to the director's chair for the sequel, <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/10/minecraft-2-release-date-1236574896/">Deadline</a> reported.</p>
<p>But more so, A Minecraft Movie has been a phenomenal hit, even if <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-review">critics weren't particularly impressed</a>.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>As we reported after its release, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-opens-with-biggest-us-domestic-opening-weekend-ever-for-a-video-game-adaptation">A Minecraft Movie had the biggest domestic debut of any video game film adaptation ever in the US</a>, with an opening weekend of $157m (£121.5m). Worldwide it made $301m (£233m) in that weekend.</p>
<p>Now, Deadline has reported the film has grossed almost $1bn since its release. A sequel, then, was inevitable.</p>
<p>The film became well-known for disruptive screenings thanks to its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movies-viral-chicken-jockey-moment-is-causing-chaos-in-cinemas">Chicken Jockey trend</a> of throwing popcorn all over cinemas. While <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-director-defends-popcorn-throwing-chicken-jockey-chaos-says-viewers-just-having-a-true-party">Hess called it "a total blast"</a>, a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-now-shows-warning-following-disruptive-chicken-jockey-trend">warning was retrospectively added</a> to the start of the film, along with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-is-leaning-into-the-memes-with-sing-along-screenings">specific sing-along screenings</a>.</p>
<p>Where else could the film series go? Perhaps to The Far Lands, as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-far-lands-over-14-years-later-the-edge-of-a-minecraft-world-has-been-reached">one Minecraft player has spent the past 14 years walking to</a>.</p>



        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-gets-inevitable-sequel-after-grossing-almost-1bn-putting-lava-chicken-back-on-the-menu]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost MMO by Fantastic Pixel Castle Is in Danger After NetEase Pulls the Plug]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ghost-mmo-fantastic-pixel-castle-is-in-danger-netease-pulls-plug/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-mmo-by-fantastic-pixel-castle-is-in-danger-after-netease-pulls-the-plug.1321582/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A few hours ago, Fantastic Pixel Castle Studio Head and Game Director Greg Street <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7382143103379587072/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed via LinkedIn</a> that the company's debut game, <a href="https://wccftech.com/ex-wow-designer-founds-new-netease-studio-making-an-aaa-fantasy-mmo-codenamed-ghost/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the fantasy MMORPG codenamed Ghost</a>, is in serious danger. That's because NetEase, which had provided the initial funding, has decided to pull the plug. Both NetEase and Fantastic Pixel Castle have been looking for another publisher, but with the current market conditions, it's a very challenging proposition.</p>



<p>That's why Greg Street admitted that team members are already being encouraged to 'explore future opportunities' (that means looking at new jobs):</p>



<p><em>If we're unable to find a publisher soon, the reality is that the studio would likely close, and the entire team, leadership included, would be affected. We want to thank the Ghost community, our playtesters, and the literally hundreds of people who have given us advice on how to find funding in this absurdly challenging time for our industry. I hope you all will have a chance to play Ghost. I also want to thank the FPC team who has made a game that we all should be proud of. I know it's cliche to say this, but demonstrably this is the best team I have ever worked with. </em></p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-mmorpg-qa-ex-wow-designer-opens-up-on-every-aspect-of-the-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">We interviewed Greg Street</a> (previously, the Lead Systems Designer of World of Warcraft between 2008 and 2013) a couple of years ago, and the designer opened up on the upcoming MMO. The main twist of Ghost was supposed to be that players could hop between public 'Red' Shards, more akin to regular MMOs, and private 'Blue' Shards, which at first were supposed to offer survival elements but were then redesigned to support roguelike elements. </p>



<p>Fantastic Pixel Castle is not the only developer to suffer from NetEase pulling the plug; <a href="https://wccftech.com/t-minus-zero-entertainment-is-a-new-netease-studio-founded-by-bioware-bethesda-mmo-vets/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it already happened with T-Minus Zero</a>, a studio formed by former BioWare and Bethesda veterans, as well as <a href="https://wccftech.com/netease-ceo-reportedly-cutting-funding-for-a-dozen-games-wont-support-marketing-for-nagoshis-and-other-japanese-made-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">other projects canceled earlier this year</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ghost-mmo-fantastic-pixel-castle-is-in-danger-netease-pulls-plug/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo Studios 17-Year Veteran Leaves Company With Mysterious Warning]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/halo-studios-veteran-leaves-company-with-warning/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo-studios-17-year-veteran-leaves-company-with-mysterious-warning.1321579/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Glenn Israel, a veteran of Halo Studios (previously 343 Industries) with more than 17 years under his belt in the universe, has departed the company and shared an ominous message on LinkedIn. In the message, he warns others in the industry about ‘staying strong and taking evidence’.</p>



<p>He also mentioned that he’s not able to talk about circumstances beyond a minor post, but said that next year, when it’s ‘absolutely safe to do so’, he’ll expand on his ‘story’.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-state-of-our-industry-seems-dire">‘The State of Our Industry Seems Dire’</h2>



<p>In a post on LinkedIn, Glenn Israel, former Art Director at 343 Industries (Halo Studios) wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>As of today and after seventeen long years, I am officially no longer contributing to the Halo universe. There is litle more I can say for the moment, though I intend to share this particular story in its entirety when it is absolutely safe to do so next year. In the meantime, I have a message for anyone and everyone who needs to hear it.</p>



<p>I know that the state of our industry seems dire, but never forget that you are *free to choose*. No illusion of security nor promise of wealth or fame or power is worth trading away your health, your dignity, your ethics or values – and no one can force you to. Stay strong, take evidence when necessary, and find where you belong.</p>



<p>As always, I’ll be here if you need to talk.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s most likely that Israel finds himself under an NDA after leaving Halo Studios, which is common practice to ensure that, for a time, developers aren’t discussing what they were working on or why they were let go from (or left) a company.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/glenn-israel-19696485_as-of-today-and-after-seventeen-long-years-activity-7379767940897959936-btQc?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAACr_MyIB0LsPQAIci9zs45L99nTb3k_h6f8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">post was published</a> over a week ago at the time of writing, but recently found its way into social circulations.</p>



<p>Recently, in the Halo space, it was claimed that a Halo: Combat Evolved <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-ce-remake-virtuos-studio-claim/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">remake was in co-development</a> by a Virtuos studio and is potentially set to be revealed during a Halo showcase at the Halo World Championship later this month.</p>



<p>Let me know what you want to see from the next Halo game on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-maps-remade-in-battlefield-6/">Call of Duty maps are in Battlefield 6</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/halo-studios-veteran-leaves-company-with-warning/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Took Mere Hours for Call of Duty Maps to Be Remade in Battlefield 6]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-maps-remade-in-battlefield-6/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-took-mere-hours-for-call-of-duty-maps-to-be-remade-in-battlefield-6.1321567/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlefield 6’s new Portal mode is a UGC dream, featuring a full-fledged toolkit that tech-savvy individuals can use to make all manner of things from maps to immersive experiences. In a recent post on social media, it was revealed that one keen creator has rebuilt one of Call of Duty’s most iconic multiplayer maps <strong>in Battlefield 6</strong>.</p>



<p>The addition of this map to Portal means that anyone can find it and play on it, and from what has been shown, it’s a like-for-like replication of Shipment, a Call of Duty map first introduced in 2007’s Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare.</p>



<h2 id="h-shipment-is-in-battlefield-6-and-people-love-it">Shipment is in Battlefield 6, and People Love It</h2>



<p>The first thing folks did when responding to Matavatar’s post on social media was <strong>request</strong> <strong>more Call of Duty maps </strong>for Battlefield 6’s Portal platform.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>From the clips and shots above, you can see that Matavatar has painstakingly recreated Shipment in Battlefield 6, adding everything down to the minute details, and has promised that the map should be playable from day one of Battlefield 6 dropping, <strong>which is today</strong>.</p>



<p>In the comments under the post, Matavatar listed the other Call of Duty and retro Battlefield maps he intends to rebuild in Battlefield 6, all of which are pretty obvious:</p>



<ul>
<li>Nuketown</li>



<li>Ziba</li>



<li>Metro</li>



<li>Bazaar</li>



<li>Noshahr</li>



<li>Firing Range</li>
</ul>



<p>If nothing else, Matavatar’s creation is a perfect representation of how fluid and accessible the UGC platform is on Portal in Battlefield 6. He assembled this map in mere hours of the function going live, and it’ll be open to all Battlefield 6 players accessing Portal.</p>



<p>Do you think you’d like to play Battlefield 6 across a range of Call of Duty maps? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-6-launch-patch-notes-movement-nerfs-weapon-handling-rebalanced/">the latest Battlefield 6 patch notes</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-maps-remade-in-battlefield-6/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Outer Worlds 2 Preload Guide & File Size Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-outer-worlds-2-preload-and-file-size-explained/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-outer-worlds-2-preload-guide-file-size-explained.1321558/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Outer Worlds 2 will be released worldwide on October 29th, coming to Xbox Series, PC, and PlayStation 5 platforms. It’s the next iteration of the series started by Obsidian in 2019, which dropped and was dubbed ‘New Vegas in space’ by many.</p>



<p>In this ever-digital world, it’s always key to know when you can preload games, and the situation with The Outer Worlds 2 is no different. In this snapshot guide, I’ve got the information you need, including the data regarding The Outer Worlds 2’s file size on all platforms.</p>



<p>Read on to learn everything you need to know.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-can-you-preload-the-outer-worlds-2">When Can You Preload The Outer Worlds 2?</h2>



<p><strong>Preloads for The Outer Worlds 2 are available now on Xbox Series S, Xbox Series X, and Xbox on PC. </strong>I’m working to verify if preloads are available on PlayStation and PC via other platforms.</p>



<p>In a post published by <a href="https://xboxera.com/2025/10/10/the-outer-worlds-2-preload-is-up-on-xbox-its-a-chonky-boi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">XboxEra</a>, the preload window was confirmed, as were the file sizes for The Outer Worlds 2. Be warned, this is a very hefty game, which might come as a surprise to some.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-outer-worlds-2-file-size-explained">The Outer Worlds 2 File Size Explained</h2>



<p><strong>The preload file size for The Outer Worlds 2 is 79.49 GB on Xbox Series S and Xbox Series X and 77.30 GB on Xbox on PC.</strong> It hasn’t been confirmed how much space the game will occupy on PlayStation 5, but it’s safe to assume it’s around the same mark.</p>



<p>We’ll update this guide once we’ve got that information.</p>



<p>The Outer Worlds 2 is a single-player title with open-world elements and plenty of RPG mechanics, but it still comes as a surprise that it’s almost 80 GB on some platforms. That’s a huge installation in any world, especially for a game expected to have a 30 – 40 hour range.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-preload-the-outer-worlds-2">How to Preload The Outer Worlds 2</h2>



<p><strong>If you want to preload The Outer Worlds 2, you can do so by heading to the Xbox Store on console or PC and clicking to preload the game. </strong>While we haven’t verified this yet, it’ll be the same process on PlayStation and other PC platforms like Steam.</p>



<p>If you don’t have Game Pass, you’ll need to purchase the game first. Those with Game Pass Ultimate can preload The Outer Worlds 2 <strong>right now</strong>.</p>



<p>Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord</a> server if you’re excited to play The Outer Worlds 2.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/youtube-dropped-to-low-point-in-years/">YouTube is suffering against rising competition</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-outer-worlds-2-preload-and-file-size-explained/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YouTube Has Dropped To a Low Point For The First Time ‘In Years’ as Competition Rises]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/youtube-dropped-to-low-point-in-years/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/youtube-has-dropped-to-a-low-point-for-the-first-time-%E2%80%98in-years%E2%80%99-as-competition-rises.1321555/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In recent data, it was revealed that YouTube Live is suffering a comedown amid rising competition across the streaming space. In recent years, the likes of Kick.com and TikTok have come for the crowns claimed by YouTube and Twitch, and the video-based titans are starting to feel that pinch.</p>



<p>Steamscharts recently published a report for the Q3 2025 ‘Global Livestreaming Landscape’, and it revealed that quarter-over-quarter, YouTube Live saw a drop of more than 10% in hours watched, falling below the 50% market cap spot ‘for the first time in years’.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-streaming-space-is-becoming-saturated">The Streaming Space is Becoming Saturated</h2>



<p><a href="https://streamscharts.com/news/q3-2025-global-livestreaming-landscape" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Streamscharts’ report</a> included coverage of every major and growing minor streaming platform around the world:</p>



<ul>
<li>YouTube</li>



<li>TikTok</li>



<li>Twitch</li>



<li>Kick</li>



<li>SOOP Korea</li>



<li>CHZZK</li>



<li>Rumble</li>



<li>NimoTV</li>
</ul>



<p>The numbers represent a considerable drop in foothold for YouTube Live, which is crumbling under the competition represented by TikTok Live. In recent years, TikTok has become a powerhouse platform for streamers looking to make a buck, with intense monetization features that are just too lucrative for anyone to ignore.</p>



<p>That’s why TikTok Live now makes up 31.4% of the livestreaming market, 4.4% of which is dedicated to gaming, fast becoming one of the cornerstones of the platform that was once made up of teenagers dancing to popular music.</p>



<p>YouTube Live still has a 45% claim over the market, but as Streamscharts wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong>YouTube Live remains the top platform but</strong>&nbsp;saw a 10.6% drop in Hours Watched (13.25B) and its share fell below 50% for the first time in years.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Kick continues to grow, despite constant controversies being raised on the platform. It’s still a site under intense scrutiny, but that hasn’t stopped streamers from flocking to the site as another option for their broadcasts.</p>



<p>Are you surprised that YouTube Live has seen a drop this year? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that a former Assassin’s Creed actor <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-civil-war-former-actor-reacts/">has reacted to the canceled game</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/youtube-dropped-to-low-point-in-years/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trails In The Sky 1st Chapter Update Adding "Image Quality / Performance Settings" On Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-update-adding-image-quality-performance-settings-on-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-update-adding-image-quality-performance-settings-on-switch-2.1321549/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>A first-person perspective, too</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="755c73bc78548"><a title="Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/755c73bc78548/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter.large.jpg"></a></figure><p>Following last month's release, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</a> is now getting updated to Version 1.05 on the Switch and Switch 2.</p>
<p>Perhaps, most notably, the Switch 2 update will add "image quality and performance settings". Additionally, there is also a first-person perspective mode. Here's the translation from the official Falcom website (via Gematsu):</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Added “Image Quality / Performance Settings” to the Nintendo Switch 2 Edition.</em></li>
<li><em>Added options to adjust text speed and text auto-advance speed.</em></li>
<li><em>Added one-key shortcuts for actions that normally require two key presses on keyboard.</em></li>
<li><em>Added a first-person mode.</em></li>
<li><em>Added the option to hide in-game user interface.</em></li>
<li><em>Corrected various text errors.</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed other miscellaneous bugs.</em></li>
</ul><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067osgtiv&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>836k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p><em>*Updates for Nintendo Switch™ 2/Switch will be released at a later date.</em></p>
<p>To activate this first-person mode on the Switch 2 and Switch, you'll need to press R + ZL. And to hide the user interface, you'll need to press R + ZR.</p>
<p>And in case you missed it, here are the updates for Version 1.04:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Added camera distance setting to options</em></li>
<li><em>Adjusted the Brave Attack input acceptance time in High Speed ​​Mode</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed an issue where some battles could become unprogressible.</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed a crash that could occur when jumping between maps.</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed a crash that could occur when operating the Orbment menu.</em></li>
<li><em>Corrected typos and omissions</em></li>
<li><em>Fixed other bugs</em></li>
</ul>
<p>In our review here on Nintendo Life, we mentioned how there were some "slight performance issues" in the Switch 2 version. Here's part of what we had to say about this particular version of the game:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The journey of our sibling Bracers is most impressive on Switch 2, which targets 60fps...Undocked is notably the best mode and runs with what feels like flawless stability in combat and wandering the open world. Docked is also strong, but there is the odd frame hiccup in population centres and during visually busy battles. The game isn’t a visual powerhouse by any means, but it’s nice to see the characters adventure through lovingly designed environments without any compromises on the newer console."</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:188335 @ 1760086661 -->
<p>Have you tried out this game on the Switch or Switch 2 yet? How have you found the experience so far? <em>Let us know.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.falcom.co.jp/sora/product/support.html" rel="noopener" href="https://www.falcom.co.jp/sora/product/support.html">falcom.co.jp</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-version-1-05-update-now-available-adds-first-person-mode#google_vignette" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-version-1-05-update-now-available-adds-first-person-mode#google_vignette">gematsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/a4ccdefe9c814d166c019a438fa557e3 @ 1760086661 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-update-adding-image-quality-performance-settings-on-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft Realm ‘Vernearth’ Opened by Slipknot Member as ‘a Surrealist Experience’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-realm-verneath-opened-by-slipknot/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-realm-%E2%80%98vernearth%E2%80%99-opened-by-slipknot-member-as-%E2%80%98a-surrealist-experience%E2%80%99.1321543/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>At the end of October, Vernearth will go live, bringing a Realm to Minecraft players everywhere that bends the rules of time and reality. It is composed of more than 100 million blocks and offers ‘endless opportunities for creation, combat, and exploration,’ allowing users to build, battle or ‘just lose themselves in the atmosphere.’</p>



<p>Oh, and it has been created by M. Shawn ‘Clown’ Crahan, a founding member of Slipknot and lover of Minecraft. It has been stressed that Crahan will be playing alongside fans when the Realm goes live at the end of October.</p>



<h2 id="h-enter-vernearth-powered-by-slipknot">Enter Vernearth, Powered by Slipknot</h2>



<p>In a release, Vernearth is described as something almost otherworldly:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>What is Vernearth? For Clown, Vernearth isn’t just a game world, it’s an extension of his creativity outside Slipknot, suitable for players of all ages. This isn’t just Minecraft. It’s Vernearth. Vernearth is a surrealist experience. Think of it as a place where time and reality don’t play by the rules. </p>



<p>Over 100 million blocks make up this ever-changing landscape, home to mysterious beings called Mind Stewards and endless opportunities for creation, combat, and exploration. Whether you want to build, battle, or just lose yourself in the atmosphere, Vernearth is designed to pull you in and never let go.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the imagery provided, Vernearth resembles a gothic underworld of sorts, teeming with dark architecture that you’d probably be comfortable linking to a brand like Slipknot.</p>



<p>If you’re not familiar, Minecraft Realms is a subscription service that allows players to set up, manage, and explore private servers that have unique rules, modifications, and shared server facilities.</p>



<p>From what we can see in the image provided by the team, Vernearth will feature some kind of daily reward system, awarding chests to players who log in every day.</p>



<p>Do you think you’d want to explore Vernearth? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/a-minecraft-movie-sequel-confirmed-2027/">a Minecraft Movie 2 is coming</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-realm-verneath-opened-by-slipknot/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter version 1.05 update now available, adds first-person mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-version-1-05-update-now-available-adds-first-person-mode</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-version-1-05-update-now-available-adds-first-person-mode.1321537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Plus the option to hide the user interface.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Nihon Falcom [758 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nihon-falcom">Falcom</a> has <a href="https://twitter.com/nihonfalcom/status/1976481932897857966" target="_blank">released</a> the version 1.05 update for <em><a title="Games > Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter [25 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter">Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</a></em> on <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,501 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, which adds a first-person view mode and an option to hide the user interface, among other updates. The <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [546 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> and Switch versions will follow at a later date. <span id="more-999141"></span></p><p>Here are the patch notes:</p><blockquote><ul><li>Added “Image Quality / Performance Settings” to the <em><a title="Platforms > Switch [17,816 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> 2 Edition</em>.</li><li>Added options to adjust text speed and text auto-advance speed.</li><li>Added one-key shortcuts for <a title="Genres > Action [3,121 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s that normally require two key presses on keyboard.</li><li>Added a first-person mode.</li><li>Added the option to hide in-game user interface.</li></ul><table><thead><!-- AD: content -->
        <tr><th></th><th>First-Person Mode</th><th>Hide User Interface</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><th>Switch 2 / Switch</th><td>R + ZL</td><td>R + ZR</td></tr><tr><th>PlayStation 5</th><td>R1 + L2</td><td>R1 + R2</td></tr><tr><th>Steam Gamepad</th><td>RB + LT</td><td>RB + RT</td></tr><tr><th>Steam Keyboard</th><td>Insert</td><td>X</td></tr></tbody></table><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter-Update_10-09-25_001.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter-Update_10-09-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter-Update_10-09-25_003.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter-Update_10-09-25_004.jpg"></a></figure><ul><li>Corrected various text errors.</li><li>Fixed other miscellaneous bugs.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</em> is available now for PlayStation 5, Switch 2, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3375780/Trails_in_the_Sky_1st_Chapter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-version-1-05-update-now-available-adds-first-person-mode]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 Launch Title Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD Remaster Updated (Version 1.0.2), Here Are The Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/switch-2-launch-title-bravely-default-flying-fairy-hd-remaster-updated-version-1-0-2-here-are-the-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-launch-title-bravely-default-flying-fairy-hd-remaster-updated-version-1-0-2-here-are-the-patch-notes.1321534/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Improvements, adjustments, bug fixes and more</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="8ea27b5ef4126"><a title="Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/8ea27b5ef4126/bravely-default-flying-fairy-hd.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure><p>The Switch 2 had all sorts of third-party support at launch, and one of these titles happened to be the Square Enix role-playing game <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/bravely-default-flying-fairy-hd-remaster">Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD Remaster</a>.</p>
<p>This remaster comes loaded with not only the main adventure but also brand new <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/video-bravely-default-flying-fairy-hd-remaster-shows-off-switch-2-mouse-minigames">minigames utilising the Joy-Con 2 mouse mode</a>. Now, Square Enix has released the <strong>Version 1.0.2</strong> update.</p>
<p>You can manually perform this update by clicking on the game's Switch 2 home menu icon. Here are the full patch notes courtesy of Square Enix's support page. It comes loaded with various improvements, adjustments, tutorial improvements and also addresses some bugs.</p>
<h3>Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD - Version 1.0.2 (October 10, 2025)</h3>
<p>Version 1.0.2</p>
<p>This update is scheduled to become available at midnight on October 10, 2025 (JST). Update Contents ■ Improvements regarding connecting to the internet:</p>
<ul>
<li>An issue that caused the software to disconnect from the internet when loading or waking from sleep has been resolved.</li>
<li>A “Communication in process” dialog will display and the software will wait to connect when changing maps after waking from sleep.</li>
<li>A “Communication in process” dialog will now also display when a connection is not yet completed after loading, and the software will wait to connect and check the status of friends and guests.</li>
<li>Friends and guests will now be restored when possible without waiting for a change of maps.</li>
<li>The behavior for automatically disabling internet connections after a communication error has been changed, and error details will now be displayed.</li>
<li>An Internet Connection Test option has been added to the Config menu, and the current connection status may be checked.</li>
</ul>
<p>■ Adjustments to the Exchange Shop:</p>
<ul>
<li>The number of tokens needed to exchange for all prizes has been lowered.</li>
</ul>
<p>■ Achievement corrections:</p>
<ul>
<li>An issue wherein dealing 9,999 damage or more to Orthros would not award the “9,999” achievement has been resolved</li>
</ul>
<p>■ Tutorial improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>A “Press and hold” explanation now accompanies the button icon with initial job tutorials.</li>
<li>A tutorial now accompanies notes appearing for the first time when playing Luxencheer Rhythm Catch in the game corner.</li>
</ul>
<p>■ Miscellaneous:</p>
<ul>
<li>Other minor bugs have been addressed</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>If you haven't tried out this remaster on the Switch just yet, we called it a solid refresh for the 3DS gem. Here's our full review:</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183379 @ 1760085950 -->

<p>Have you tried out this game on the Switch 2 yet? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://support.square-enix-games.com/s/article/000001850?game=bdflyingfairyhdremaster&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="noopener" href="https://support.square-enix-games.com/s/article/000001850?game=bdflyingfairyhdremaster&amp;language=en_US">support.square-enix-games.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/10ef9322a54dd5c359d60f615e116cca @ 1760084357 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/switch-2-launch-title-bravely-default-flying-fairy-hd-remaster-updated-version-1-0-2-here-are-the-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo's "Mysterious" Switch Online Playtest Program Gets Another Patent]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/nintendos-mysterious-switch-online-playtest-program-gets-another-patent</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendos-mysterious-switch-online-playtest-program-gets-another-patent.1321531/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The playtest was extended to Switch 2 in July</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="54d885022693f"><a title="Switch Online Playtest" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/54d885022693f/switch-online-playtest.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life / Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Another patent has been published for the Switch Online Playtest Program, which was <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/nintendos-switch-online-playtest-program-returns-includes-switch-2-support">extended to Switch 2 users</a> in July.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ninpatentswatch.bsky.social/post/3m2rzkc4lx22b">Nintendo Patents Watch on Bluesky</a>, the patent was originally filed in Japan in April last year and in the US in April 2025. The latest one was published in the US this week and reportedly describes a system in which the player can "intuitively select multiple objects in a virtual space by walking around them".</p>
<p>Here's the official abstract:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"A player character is caused to move in a three-dimensional virtual space according to a first operation input. In the three-dimensional virtual space, a first object that connects a reference point set at a position according to a second operation input, and the player character is generated. A shape of the first object is changed based on movement of the player character. Whena second object is surrounded by the first object in the three-dimensional virtual space, the second object is designated for further game processing."</p></blockquote><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067osgtiv&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>836k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div><blockquote>
</blockquote>

<p>As highlighted by the same source, Nintendo president Shuntaro Furukawa <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2025/250205e.pdf">mentioned earlier this year</a> how the playtest was "related to a new feature for the Nintendo Switch Online service", but did not elaborate on this.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"We plan to leverage results and other learnings gained from this intiative in future Nintendo Switch Online services, but we have not announced any details".</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Although details and footage about the first playtest were leaked online, Nintendo kept the same requests in place for the second playtest - asking participants to not "discuss or disclose content" about the program with others.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185371,185375,187768 @ 1760086881 -->
<p>Did you participate in this playtest on Switch or Switch 2? What are your thoughts about the latest patents? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://image-ppubs.uspto.gov/dirsearch-public/print/downloadPdf/20250312694" rel="noopener" href="https://image-ppubs.uspto.gov/dirsearch-public/print/downloadPdf/20250312694">image-ppubs.uspto.gov</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.gonintendo.com/contents/53757-nintendo-files-another-patent-related-to-the-nso-playtest-program" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gonintendo.com/contents/53757-nintendo-files-another-patent-related-to-the-nso-playtest-program">gonintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/ec09d9efd7023972978bfbf0111b438b @ 1760084250 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/nintendos-mysterious-switch-online-playtest-program-gets-another-patent]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Candy Factory Chapter 2 Dolls in Little Nightmares 3—Every Chapter 2 Doll Location, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/all-candy-factory-chapter-2-dolls-little-nightmares-3-locations/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-candy-factory-chapter-2-dolls-in-little-nightmares-3%E2%80%94every-chapter-2-doll-location-explained.1321507/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Chapter 2’s Candy Factory takes a sinister right turn in Little Nightmares 3. It’s where the game starts to become unhinged and reveal its true colors. While exploring the mysteries of the facility, you need to find Dolls in Little Nightmares 3. Our Candy Factory guide is the perfect walkthrough to do this.</p>



<p>It’s hard to keep your eyes on the ball in Candy Factory. A nasty spider-bug lady is chasing you, and the whole building is a gargantuan cesspool of unnerving sights and sounds. Hidden amongst its many rooms, corridors, and hidey-holes are Doll collectibles.</p>



<p>If you’re after <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-review-a-familiar-dream-but-one-you-shouldnt-sleep-on/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3</a>‘s collection of secret Dolls—especially for the game’s trophy list—you need this guide (and some prayers after).</p>



<h2 id="h-how-many-dolls-in-candy-factory-chapter-2-in-little-nightmares-3">How Many Dolls in Candy Factory Chapter 2 in Little Nightmares 3?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Another five to go. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You must find five Dolls throughout Candy Factory in Little Nightmares 3 if you want to own every doll in the level.</strong></p>



<p>A tiny spoiler alert: Not every <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/little-nightmares/little-nightmares-iii" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Little Nightmares 3</a> chapter has five Dolls. That’s why it’s important to address this question in each Doll guide. Candy Factor does have five, so let’s get into the level!</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-2-candy-factory-doll-1-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 2 Candy Factory Doll 1 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Just out of your vision. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>The compulsory path to completing Candy Factory takes you into a large room filled with filing cabinets, folders, and the chapter’s main antagonist. Sneak across the room to the other side and climb up the shelves. <strong>Reach the beams at the top</strong>, and when you start walking toward the screen, turn left at the end, and the first Doll is at the end of the beam.</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-2-candy-factory-doll-2-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 2 Candy Factory Doll 2 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It’s there, we promise you. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>Make your way through Candy Factory until you reach a room where you pull down a lever, making the bugs in the room flee, allowing Low and Alone to jump up and down on the platform in the middle of the room. After falling into the next room, climb up the ladder to the right, go through the vent, and move on until you climb up through the grate that puts you in front of a <strong>powered-down elevator</strong>. Take a left through the hole in the wall, and in the room with stacked tubs, <strong>use our screenshot above</strong> to find the second Doll.</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-2-candy-factory-doll-3-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 2 Candy Factory Doll 3 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>One of the more hidden Dolls in the game. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>Once you’ve restored full power to the elevator, ride it up. Open the window shutter, taking you outside, and instead of running toward you (the player) to carry on, from the window, <strong>run down the long pipe in the opposite direction</strong>—left of the hot air balloon in the background. Climb through the window at the end, and claim Doll number three.</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-2-candy-factory-doll-4-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 2 Candy Factory Doll 4 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It pays to explore. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>You’ll find Doll four not long after the third one. Once you return to the beaten path, you naturally encounter <strong>a room filled with static TVs, the chapter’s boss enemy again, and a wooden plank you need to walk across</strong>. Do this, wait for the boss to leave, and descend to the bottom of the room. Instead of opening up the two-person vent, go to the opposite side of the room to find the Doll sitting small and cute in the open room.</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-2-candy-factory-doll-5-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 2 Candy Factory Doll 5 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The end is nigh. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>A final chase sequence with the Candy Factory’s boss</strong> results in them being squished in a hydraulic press (lovely, I know), and the door in the press room unlocks once they’re defeated. Go down the long corridor and into the room on the left. The Doll is on the table next to a machine.</p>



<hr>



<p>Fingers crossed this guide was more of a treat for you than the horrors of the Candy Factory! Little Nightmares 3 sure does have some creative levels, and we might be brave enough to attempt to clean up the game’s remaining Dolls. Keep checking back with Insider Gaming for more content, and head to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">IG forum</a> for the latest gaming gossip.</p>



<p>Do check out our guides on Little Nightmares 3’s game length, as well as the lowdown on all chapters and upcoming DLC for extra free content.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/all-candy-factory-chapter-2-dolls-little-nightmares-3-locations/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Necropolis Chapter 1 Dolls in Little Nightmares 3—Every Chapter 1 Doll Location, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/chapter-1-dolls-little-nightmares-3-necropolis-doll-locations/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-necropolis-chapter-1-dolls-in-little-nightmares-3%E2%80%94every-chapter-1-doll-location-explained.1321504/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Necorpolis is where Low and Alone’s journey begins in Little Nightmares 3. The game starts brighter and sandier than you might expect, but just because it’s light doesn’t mean you’ll have an easy time tracking down every Chapter 1 Doll in Little Nightmares 3’s Necropolis level.</p>



<p>It depends on which side of the fence you reside where collectibles are concerned. Some people love them, and some hate them. While <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-review-a-familiar-dream-but-one-you-shouldnt-sleep-on/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3</a> does have collectibles across its various chapters, there aren’t many—but each one can be an endeavor to track down (and a nightmare).</p>



<p>If you’re having trouble with so much as one collectible Doll in Chapter 1’s Necropolis, we’re here to help.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-many-dolls-in-necropolis-chapter-1-in-little-nightmares-3">How Many Dolls in Necropolis Chapter 1 in Little Nightmares 3?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>We did it, and so can you. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>There are five collectible Dolls to find in Little Nightmare 3’s first chapter—Necropolis.</strong></p>



<p>It’s a fairly easy start to Doll collecting in the game. A couple are handed to you on a silver platter, but the others are very missable if you don’t know where to look in <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/little-nightmares/little-nightmares-iii" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Little Nightmares 3</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-1-necropolis-doll-1-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 1 Necropolis Doll 1 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The first Doll. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>Doll number one is <em>unmissable</em>. Proceed through Necropolis and travel through the long, dusty desert. Eventually, you climb a huge ladder that takes a long time to climb. Once you reach the top, crawl through the tunnel, break through the wall, and the Doll is there out in the open in the middle of the floor.</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-1-necropolis-doll-2-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 1 Necropolis Doll 2 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Second Doll. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>The next Doll requires you to carry on as normal until you reach the point where Low and Alone fall into a giant room—behind a helter skelter-like pillar—and the giant baby monster appears and leers into the room. Move between the statues; both of you need to trigger the floor switch, and an elevator takes you all the way down. Instead of going right through the hole in the door, <strong>use Alone’s wrench to break down the wall to the left</strong>. The Doll is in the middle of this secret room.</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-1-necropolis-doll-3-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 1 Necropolis Doll 3 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Can’t miss the third Doll. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>After a section where you <strong>climb up a large wall of broken wooden planks, shimmying from side to side</strong> occasionally, you reach a market area at the top. Go right, and instead of using your umbrella to ride the vertical breeze to the platform, instead, go up the exposed staircase. The third Doll is at the top, next to a wicker basket.</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-1-necropolis-doll-4-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 1 Necropolis Doll 4 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The fourth Doll in a dark room. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>Doll number four is available after we go through <strong>Low’s cutscene, where they’re in a prison-like room, unmasked, and hiding under the bed</strong>. When Low and Alone come to, go left, crouch through the hole in the broken door, and the fourth Doll is in the room—this one is easily missable because you’d think to go right as the game hints at.</p>



<h2 id="h-chapter-1-necropolis-doll-5-location-in-little-nightmares-3">Chapter 1 Necropolis Doll 5 Location in Little Nightmares 3</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The sneaky fifth Doll. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>Our fifth and final Doll is toward the end of the level. <strong>You must complete a sequence in a bell tower where you smash the head of a statue, and use the bow to cut the rope and ring the bell</strong>—summoning the baby monster. Hide in the box, and once it grabs the bell and leaves, exit through the window to the right. Now, complete the mini umbrella and ladder puzzle, and proceed. You will reach a section where you use the umbrellas to ride across a gap and then pull the plank off the bottom of a door. Climb through and into the alley. Head up the path, and instead of turning right into the opening, carry on going forward, and the final Doll is sneakily hidden away at the end of the passage on the left.</p>



<hr>



<p>We hope this guide was a big help in helping you find the Dolls in Necropolis. We have more Doll guides coming, so stay tuned. If you want any specific Little Nightmares 3 guides, you can let us know through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p>For more on Little Nightmares 3, check out the game’s length, as well as information on all its chapters and upcoming DLC.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/chapter-1-dolls-little-nightmares-3-necropolis-doll-locations/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Complete Little Nightmares 3 Trophy List—How To Get All Achievements And Trophies]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-trophy-list-all-achievements-and-trophies/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/complete-little-nightmares-3-trophy-list%E2%80%94how-to-get-all-achievements-and-trophies.1321501/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Little Nightmares 3 trophy and achievement list has as much aura and mystery as the whole game. Supermassive Games has whipped up a truly confusing trophy and achievement list that will have you thinking more than twice about each one. Let’s check out how many there are and their descriptions.</p>



<p>It’s apt that a horror game like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-release-date-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3</a>—shrouded in mystery and shadows—clouds its own trophy and achievement list with unclear descriptions. You’ll be scratching your head over the majority of the trophies in this fairly extensive list.</p>



<p>The Little Nightmares 3 trophies and achievements list is a curious one.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-little-nightmares-3-achievements-amp-trophies">All Little Nightmares 3 Achievements &amp; Trophies</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Hang in there. Credit to Bandai Namco</figcaption></figure>



<p>Usually, we give you a quick rundown of what you need to do for a trophy list. The <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/little-nightmares/little-nightmares-iii" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Little Nightmares 3</a> list doesn’t specifically mention completing chapters or activities. However, we’ve earned a lot for ourselves—because <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-review-a-familiar-dream-but-one-you-shouldnt-sleep-on/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming was able to review the game</a> fully before launch—and can tell you some will be earned without you realizing.</p>



<p>So, let’s cut the chatter and get straight into the Little Nightmares 3 trophies and achievements list.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Trophy &amp; Achievement Name</th><th data-align="center">Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Mastery of The Spiral</td><td data-align="center">Keep on turning</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Child’s Play</td><td data-align="center">You’re not rattled that easily</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Unsupervised&nbsp;</td><td data-align="center">Survived the most pressing of situations</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Showstoppers</td><td data-align="center">The show cannot go on</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Spiral Out</td><td data-align="center">A twisted mind unraveled</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Low-Spirited</td><td data-align="center">The real memories are the friend you made along the way</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">From Nowhere, With Love</td><td data-align="center">…But to be is to have been</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Special Connection</td><td data-align="center">There is no bond as strong as this</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Toybox</td><td data-align="center">Playtime’s over now</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Candy Shop</td><td data-align="center">Sweets for my sweet</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Token Gestures</td><td data-align="center">You hit the jackpot</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Filed Away</td><td data-align="center">Nothing left in the medicine cabinet</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Loose Threads</td><td data-align="center">Little shapes of big things to come</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Hello?</td><td data-align="center">You can always call on me</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Guiding Hands</td><td data-align="center">We’re connected, you and I</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Spanner in the Works</td><td data-align="center">I can be quite handy when I want to be</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bullseye</td><td data-align="center">You gotta aim high</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Peekaboo</td><td data-align="center">There’s a twinkle in that eye</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Windy City</td><td data-align="center">Just don’t open it indoors</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Birdbrained</td><td data-align="center">Always ruffling feathers</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Capital Punishment</td><td data-align="center">You’re heading for a shock</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Home Sweet Home</td><td data-align="center">Ready or not, here I come</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stay Tuned</td><td data-align="center">Are you taking notes?</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Light or Flight</td><td data-align="center">Look on the bright side</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Another One in the Bag</td><td data-align="center">Nothung but net(profits)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Unsavory Delicacies</td><td data-align="center">Rotting from the inside, delicious on the outside.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Omnipresence</td><td data-align="center">Far or near, she can make us fear</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Delivery Feed</td><td data-align="center">From store to (cage) door</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Aim Low (and Alone)</td><td data-align="center">Win a prize every time</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Illuminating Experiences</td><td data-align="center">The gift of second sight</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Institutionalized</td><td data-align="center">The Kids Aren’t Alright</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Hand-Eye Coordination</td><td data-align="center">You’ve stayed at arm’s length</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-how-many-achievements-and-trophies-are-in-little-nightmares-3">How Many Achievements And Trophies Are In Little Nightmares 3?</h2>



<p><strong>Little Nightmares 3 has 32 PlayStation Trophies, which means it has 31 Xbox Achievements—with the PlayStation Platinum Trophy proving to be the difference between the two as standard.</strong></p>



<p>The trophy list is divided into the following quantities and rarities: 1 Platinum Trophy,&nbsp;4 Gold Trophies,&nbsp;16 Silver Trophies, and 11 Bronze Trophies. It’s a healthy distribution with plenty of firepower to add to your overall trophy player level!</p>



<hr>



<p>It’s not the biggest trophy list in the world, but it might be one of the most confusing. You might need a helping hand along the way, but the Little Nightmares 3 trophy list will be a satisfying Platinum Trophy or full bundle of Gamerscore. Flex on everyone via the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a> once you finally achieve this.</p>



<p>For more on Little Nightmares 3 content, check out the latest on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-little-nightmares-3-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crossplay</a>, its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-game-size-pre-load-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game size</a>, and if it’s available on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Game Pass</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-trophy-list-all-achievements-and-trophies/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Long to Beat Little Nightmares 3? Game Length Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-to-beat-little-nightmares-3-game-length/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-long-to-beat-little-nightmares-3-game-length-explained.1321495/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Supermassive Games has gotten its hands on the Little Nightmares franchise. The studio brings a wealth of experience to one of the most niche yet beloved indie horror franchises. That said, we’re giving you information on how long the game is based on our experience.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-release-date-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmare 3</a> is finally out. The transition from Tarsier Studios to Supermassive Games may have caused the game to take longer than thought. However, the new developer isn’t actually new, and has built up a reputation in the horror genre—highlighting titles like Until Dawn and The Dark Pictures Anthology as fine examples.</p>



<p>The third game oozes quality—which we can testify to, thanks to our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-review-a-familiar-dream-but-one-you-shouldnt-sleep-on/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3 review</a>—so let’s see how much there is to enjoy.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-many-hours-to-beat-little-nightmares-3">How Many Hours to Beat Little Nightmares 3?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A solid ride. Credit to Supermassive Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>By the time we rolled the Little Nightmares 3 credits, the PlayStation home screen indicated that we had spent at least 7 hours playing the game, but it might be closer to 8 hours, to be safe.</strong></p>



<p>If you’re a PS5 owner, you’ll know that when you highlight a game on the home menu screen, there are two indicators on the screen: One indicating playtime and one showing main story progress. When we wrapped up our first playthrough, the home menu was showing 7 hours.</p>



<p>However, this figure doesn’t always seem 100% accurate, based on previous games we’ve played. <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/little-nightmares/little-nightmares-iii" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3</a> doesn’t show your playtime in any of the save file slots.</p>



<p>Bandai Namco’s PR did tell us: “We’d expect a playthrough to come in at under 10 hours!”</p>



<h2 id="h-how-long-is-a-little-nightmares-3-full-completionist-run">How Long is a Little Nightmares 3 Full Completionist Run?</h2>



<p><strong>To get every collectible and even get all of the Little Nightmares 3 trophies, you’re probably looking at anywhere between 10-15 hours—depending on how you approach the game.</strong></p>



<p>Little Nightmares 3 has an obscure and lengthy trophy and achievement list. If you go into this without a trophy guide at the ready, you could spend a while figuring everything out. Furthermore, each of the four main chapters has a set amount of collectibles. Again, without guidance, it’s going to eat up your time replaying chapters.</p>



<p>Depending on your approach, we’d say that if you use guides to assist you, 10-15 hours sounds about right. If you insist on doing everything yourself and figuring out trophies on your own, you could be looking at even greater game length numbers!</p>



<hr>



<p>Is this your first Little Nightmares experience? If not, what is it about the previous two games that has you coming back for more in Little Nightmares 3? As always, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a> is a great environment to discuss your gaming thoughts.</p>



<p>For more on LN3, check out its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-game-size-pre-load-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game size</a> and whether it’s on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game Pass</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-to-beat-little-nightmares-3-game-length/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Auction demo now available for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/dark-auction-demo-now-available-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-auction-demo-now-available-for-pc.1321492/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Try out the mystery adventure game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>A demo for “authentic mystery <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,624 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>” game <em><a title="Games > Dark Auction [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dark-auction">Dark Auction</a></em> is now available for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,501 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2363180/Dark_Auction_Hitlers_Estate/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, publisher <a title="Companies > Good Smile Company [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/good-smile-company">Good Smile Company</a>, and publisher and developer <a title="Companies > IzanagiGames [105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/izanagigames">IzanagiGames</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2363180/old_view/518601098272964998" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-999178"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2363180/Dark_Auction_Hitlers_Estate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A deep, compelling mystery adventure with a script and scenario written by Rika Suzuki, known for her brilliant work on <em>Another Code</em> and <em>Hotel Dusk: Room 215</em>. Also featuring character design by Kohske, the author / illustrator of <em>GANGSTA.</em>, and music by <em><a title="Series > Monster Hunter [41 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/monster-hunter">Monster Hunter</a></em> composer Yuko Komiyama.</p><ul><li>Search freely within an ancient castle across a 3D map</li><li>Apply reason and analyze the possibilities using keywords found in word clouds</li><li>Join an auction where the truth is revealed about the past</li></ul><p>West Germany, 1981.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Eighteen-year-old Noah is haunted by the memory of his mother abandoning him at a very young age. He lives together with just his father Leonardo, a failed writer and eccentric obsessed with Hitler research. Although Noah wishes his father would put aside such a strange pursuit, Leonardo has no intention of giving it up, despite the various money problems that they endure.</p><p>One day, an invitation arrives for an auction selling items connected to Hitler. Leonardo brushes aside Noah’s objections and soon departs for the ancient castle where the auction will be held. He promises to tell Noah all about it upon his return.</p><p>But Leonardo never comes home on the appointed day. Having lost all contact with his father, Noah sets off for the castle himself. There, he witnesses a most shocking sight.</p><p>Noah soon finds himself trapped inside the castle together with other auction participants. Upon the invitation of the auctioneer, he too takes part in the mysterious event.</p><p><strong>Staff</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Original Story / Scenario:</strong> Rika Suzuki (Another Code and Hotel Dusk: Room 215)</li><li><strong>Character Design:</strong> Kohske (<em>GANGSTA.</em>)</li><li><strong>Soundtrack:</strong> Yuko Komiyama (<em>Monster Hunter</em> series)</li></ul><p>*This game tells the tale of a group of young people who resolve to strive for a peaceful future after learning of the past. While historical war-related recollections appear as motifs at times during the story, this game does not, in any way, seek to glorify or promote the crimes of war.</p></blockquote><p><em>Dark Auction</em> is due out for PlayStation 5, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2363180/Dark_Auction_Hitlers_Estate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on January 29, 2026.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/dark-auction-demo-now-available-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's Official, Minecraft Is Getting A Second Live-Action Movie]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/its-official-minecraft-is-getting-a-second-live-action-movie</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/its-official-minecraft-is-getting-a-second-live-action-movie.1321480/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>See you in theatres in 2027</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="924c3a102738a"><a title="Minecraft Movie" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/924c3a102738a/minecraft-movie.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Warner Bros. Pictures</em></figcaption></figure><p>It's official, the live-action <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/minecraft">Minecraft</a> Movie is getting a second film, and it's scheduled to arrive in cinemas on <strong>23rd July 2027</strong>.</p>
<p>If you saw the post-credits scene in the original movie, this probably shouldn't come as a surprise. The first movie starred Jack Black as Steve, who was joined by Jason Momoa and a crew of misfits, tasked with saving the Overworld from the Piglin invasion.</p>
<p>A promotional shot has also been shared alongside this announcement, which shows two pickaxe with a purple glow. This has already led to speculation about <a href="https://minecraft.wiki/w/The_End_(biome)">The End biome</a>, and everything related to it. Jason Hess is also <a href="https://www.empireonline.com/movies/news/minecraft-2-movie-officially-in-the-works-set-for-summer-2027-release/">confirmed to be heading back</a> to the mines to direct.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067osgtiv&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>836k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>

<p>When the first film made its debut in cinemas earlier this year, it was positively received and ended up becoming a <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/04/minecraft-movie-box-office-success-1236362729/">major box office success</a>. While it's admittedly no cinematic masterpiece, this comedic live-action fantasy adventure does a great job <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/09/video-minecraft-movie-exclusive-insight-shows-off-the-live-action-crafting-table">recreating the world of Minecraft</a> with all sorts of lore and references to the hugely popular crafting and survival video game.</p>
<p>Mojang even released some free DLC and as well as an in-game event inspired by various "iconic scenes" from the movie.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:180349 @ 1760085785 -->
<p>Are you excited for the second Minecraft Movie? Have you seen the first one yet? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/its-official-minecraft-is-getting-a-second-live-action-movie]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII / VIII Remastered Twin Pack And IX Physical Releases Confirmed For North America]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/final-fantasy-vii-viii-remastered-twin-pack-and-ix-physical-releases-confirmed-for-north-america</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-viii-remastered-twin-pack-and-ix-physical-releases-confirmed-for-north-america.1321474/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Arriving this December</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="49b3fdfb05de1"><a title="Final Fantasy" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/49b3fdfb05de1/final-fantasy.large.png"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>When the Switch generation was in full swing, Square Enix released physical versions of <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/final_fantasy_vii">Final Fantasy VII</a></strong> &amp; <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/final_fantasy_viii_remastered">Final Fantasy VIII Remastered</a></strong> Twin Pack and <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/final_fantasy_ix">Final Fantasy IX</a></strong> in certain regions.</p>
<p>In an update today, the company has confirmed these physical releases will be officially coming to North America on 9th December 2025. They'll be $39.99 each, and pre-orders are now available on the Square Enix website.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Play three classic adventures anytime, anywhere: Final Fantasy VII, VIII, and IX are launching physically on Nintendo Switch in North America from December 9th, 2025!"</p></blockquote><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067osgtiv&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>836k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div><blockquote>
</blockquote>

<p>As also noted in the description on the official Square Enix website, the Twin Pack comes on a single cartridge and no download is required.</p>
<p>Square Enix will also be releasing <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</a> on the Switch 2 early next year. It also recently launched <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:106157,106263,192377 @ 1760086793 -->
<p>Will you be adding these games to your collection? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/final-fantasy-vii-viii-remastered-twin-pack-and-ix-physical-releases-confirmed-for-north-america]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameZone, A Website Dating Back To 1994, Has Had Its Archives Wiped]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/gamezone-video-game-journalism-reviews-archives</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamezone-a-website-dating-back-to-1994-has-had-its-archives-wiped.1321456/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Old heads or students of games media might remember a site called GameZone, which while never a titan in the industry had managed to survive in one way or another since 1994, enjoying various periods of success throughout, which is an <em>incredible</em> achievement in such a volatile field. Sadly in recent months it appears to have been all but killed off by its owners, with archives spanning decades wiped in favour of front page content that doesn’t feel like it was written by or for human beings.&nbsp;</p><p>Despite appearing long dormant--its featured content for most of 2025, like a PS5 review, was years out of date, its<a href="https://www.facebook.com/gamezone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Facebook page hasn't posted since January 2024</a> and its<a href="https://www.youtube.com/GAMEZONE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> YouTube channel hadn't been updated since 2019</a>--in the early months of this year users could still visit GameZone and access decades of older features and reviews. One of the oldest articles I could find a link for via the Wayback Machine was a review for <em>Tiberian Sun</em>, which came out in 1999!</p><figure><figcaption>A snapshot of what GameZone looked like in 2005</figcaption></figure><p>This continuity wasn't just a legacy archive for a long-running site and for games media in general, but was also a way for games writers and those who have since moved to other positions in the media and games industries to link back to their old work. If you go searching through the footnotes of Wikipedia, especially for articles on older games, you'll often find GameZone mentioned, whether it's<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Def_Jam:_Fight_for_NY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> <em>Def Jam: Fight for NY</em></a> or<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Simpsons:_Hit_%26_Run" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> <em>The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run</em></a>.</p><p>Luckily those Wikipedia links point to archived copies of those articles, because GameZone's own backlinks are now dead. With the site having been redesigned in the last few months, GameZone has removed the ability to search the site, and its archives now only contain 12 stories, some of which feature AI-generated imagery (like the example below), and many of which are bylined by Javier Lassus, who is a "Solutions Engineer" and web developer at a company called Playwire. Other posts have Louis Barbati's byline, who is also a "Solutions Engineer" at Playwire, and another whose resume has a lot of customer service and web development on it. If someone told me all their posts--with their bullet points, generic text and rambling on about unrelated topics--had also been written by AI, I would not raise either of my eyebrows.</p><p>(I contacted Playwire for comment on this but at time of publishing have not heard back.)</p><div><figure><div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Gabe brought to my attention that GameZone, the website I wrote at for five years and became Editor-in-Chief of, has seemingly erased every article ever written for the site.</p><p>This includes thousands of news articles, reviews, rare interviews, and features I wrote. <a href="https://t.co/JFqPDt1vtK">https://t.co/JFqPDt1vtK</a></p></div>— Cade Onder (@Cade_Onder) <a href="https://twitter.com/Cade_Onder/status/1972424612974903752?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure></div><p>I spoke to Gabe Reisinger, a former writer for GameZone, and Cade Onder, its last functional EIC who departed in late 2020, and neither of them say they were given even a courtesy heads-up that years of their work was going to be deleted by the site's owners.</p><p>Playwire,<a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/new-coo-for-playwire-media" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> the company that has owned GameZone for years</a>, isn't really a traditional media publisher; they're an ad company, and recently<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7255204402938966017/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> celebrated inking a sales deal with the Gamurs network</a>, a<a href="https://aftermath.site/gamurs-escapist-siliconera-destructoid-layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> group of websites we have covered a few times before</a>. Having left the site (Facebook page aside) long dormant, it’s unclear why Playwire decided to reboot it now, at a time when<a href="https://aftermath.site/polygon-layoffs-sale" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> the prospects for games media websites are as dire as they've ever been</a>, even if the plan is to juice stuff via things like SEO.</p><figure><figcaption>A snapshot of what GameZone looks like in October 2025</figcaption></figure><p>The redesigned site still boasts of its 1994 heritage at the foot of the front page, saying:</p><blockquote><p>Founded in 1994, GameZone has been working to bring gamers everything there is to know about the games industry, from reviews on the latest game releases to breaking news and rumors. In addition to gaming, we bring relevant culture and entertainment news.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>But when I contacted the email tips line right next to that text to ask about the redesign and its content, the email bounced back with an "Address not found" error.</p><p>Look, GameZone wasn't a relevant games media resource in 2025. It hadn't been meaningfully updated in years, and seemed to exist solely to juice some social media accounts with large legacy followings and as an archive for 30 years’ worth of video game journalism. But that last point was important! This is history, of the industry and the medium and of all the work everyone who wrote for GameZone since 1994 had put in, and to have it all just deleted like that without notice doesn't just suck, it should--<a href="https://aftermath.site/game-informer-archives-closed-illegal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">as I've said before</a>--be something that has some consequences.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/100-meters-gkids-anime-movie-review"><h3>100 Meters Is A Soulful Gem About The Poetry Of Running</h3></a><p>Studio Rock’N Roll Mountain’s rotoscope take on Uoto’s track manga unearths raw truths and soulful cadence with every thunderous footfall</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/baby-steps-manbreaker-did-not-break-me-challange"><h3>Baby Steps’ Manbreaker Did Not Break Me</h3></a><p>Baby Steps' Manbreaker is an optional, brutal challenge that is as much a test of your humility as it is your skill.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/skin-deep-patch-notes-impaled-swordfishes"><h3>Good Patch Notes</h3></a><p>"The trash chute now ignores impaled swordfishes"</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/gamezone-video-game-journalism-reviews-archives]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Minecraft movie is getting a sequel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/798064/a-minecraft-movie-sequel-2-release-date-2027</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-minecraft-movie-is-getting-a-sequel.1321444/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><div><article><div><div><p>The new film hits theaters on July 23rd, 2027.</p></div><div><div><p>The new film hits theaters on July 23rd, 2027.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2025-10-09T23:36:00+00:00">Oct 9, 2025, 11:36 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Image: Warner Bros. Discovery</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>A Minecraft Movie</em> is getting a sequel, and according to a post on X, the new film will debut <a href="https://x.com/AMinecraftMovie/status/1976341544266498142">in theaters on July 23rd, 2027</a>. Jared Hess, who directed the first film, is returning for the second, <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/10/minecraft-2-release-date-1236574896/"><em>Deadline</em> reports</a>, but Warner Bros. Discovery hasn’t yet said who from the first film’s cast might return.</p><p>The first movie was a huge hit, having <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/644344/a-minecraft-movie">the biggest box office opening weekend ever</a> for a video game film in the US. It’s also the second highest grossing movie this year, earning nearly $1 billion, <em>Deadline</em> says. So it’s perhaps not a huge surprise that Warner Bros. Discovery has already started work on a sequel, though will it have <a href="https://www.theverge.com/film/647922/minecraft-chicken-jockey-warnings">another viral Chicken Jockey moment</a>?</p><div><p>Nintendo is also gearing up to release a sequel to its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/1/23695720/nintendo-mario-movie-billion-box-office">big video game box office hit</a>: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/777071/super-mario-bros-movie-sequel-nintendo-direct-september-2025"><em>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</em></a> is coming to theaters on April 3rd, 2026.</p></div><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></div></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/798064/a-minecraft-movie-sequel-2-release-date-2027]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kamla coming to PS5, Switch on October 30]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/kamla-coming-to-ps5-switch-on-october-30</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kamla-coming-to-ps5-switch-on-october-30.1321438/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PC, iOS, and Android.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Soft Source Publishing [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/soft-source-publishing">Soft Source Publishing</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Mad Mantra" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mad-mantra">Mad Mantra</a> will release <a title="Genres > Horror [725 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > Kamla [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kamla">Kamla</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,816 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on October 30, the companies announced. <span id="more-999119"></span></p><p><em>Kamla</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2585270/KAMLA/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 7, 2024, followed by iOS and Android on February 8, 2025.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Soft Source Publishing:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Find a way out of an old mansion as a priest, you have been tasked to exorcise a woman who has been possessed. Solve puzzles and complete objectives to cure her demonic possession in this experience.</p><p>Set in 1980’s India, Kamla was recently married into a rich family with a mansion full of mysteries to uncover and stories to unfold.<br><!-- AD: content -->
        </p>Just a year later she has lost her sanity and killed people in the family and is now waiting for help.<p><strong>Kamla</strong></p><p>After losing her sanity because of the demonic possession, Kamla has already killed few people and now haunts the mansion walking around, you must find her and help her.</p><p><strong>The Ritual</strong></p><p>You are an Indian priest with prowess in black magic, also known as a “Tantrik.” You must find objects required in your recipe to exorcise Kamla near the holy fire, These recipe items have unique values and are scattered around the house in different ways. some easy to get and some hidden behind obstacles and puzzles.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Solve puzzles to clear obstacles and unlock items.</li><li>Evade Kamla when she is angry, find places to hide and dont lose collected items!</li><li>Collect these items in the holy fire and say the final prayer to finish the exorcism.</li></ul><p><em>Kamla</em> provides a tense atmophospheric thrill for the ones who love a little scare, we hope you get in there and fix Kamla as soon as possible!</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PlayStation 5 and Switch Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Kamla | Coming to Nintendo Switch and PlayStation 5!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/agJjwqMdM-8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/kamla-coming-to-ps5-switch-on-october-30]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7, 8, and 9 Physical Editions for Switch Are Up for Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-8-and-9-physical-editions-for-switch-are-up-for-preorder-where-to-buy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-7-8-and-9-physical-editions-for-switch-are-up-for-preorder.1321414/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Play them again, for the first time.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest versions of the PS1-era Final Fantasy games are getting physical editions for Nintendo Switch on December 9. Final Fantasy VII and Final Fantasy VIII Remastered are being released together in a “twin-pack” box, while Final Fantasy IX will have a box all its own. All of the games feature some modern conveniences that weren’t available in their initial release. They cost $39.99 each and are now available for preorder at various retailers.</p><p id="final-fantasy-9-switch"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Final Fantasy 9 (Switch)">Final Fantasy IX</h2></p><p id="final-fantasy-7-8-remastered"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Final Fantasy 7 &amp; 8 Remastered ">Final Fantasy VII &amp; VIII Remastered Twin Pack</h2></p><div catalogid="0493e958-f62a-434f-b66f-21a8c2137182" id="229385"><div id="229385" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Final Fantasy 7 &amp; 8 Remastered Twin Pack</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QWEd16?object_uuid=7c2b4a9f-e2be-439b-802d-47e3217b418d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0FVGBTNHF" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Amazon</a> - $39.99</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aN8DpB?object_uuid=7c2b4a9f-e2be-439b-802d-47e3217b418d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at SE Store</a> - $39.99</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">All of these games are <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/all-final-fantasy-games-on-nintendo-switch-in-order">already available on Switch</a> (and other platforms) in digital form. But this is the first time they’ll be available in the US in physical form. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Final Fantasy VII was a major release in 1997, and was the first time the series debuted on a non-Nintendo platform. It follows former SOLDIER Cloud Strife as he and a team of freedom fighters battle against the evil Shinra corporation. This version of the game features 3x speed mode, the ability to turn off random encounters, and “battle enhancement mode.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Final Fantasy VIII Remastered is an enhanced version of a game that hit the PS1 in 1999. It follows Squall and the rest of the members of SeeD as they fight back against the sorceress Edea, who’s causing quite the global ruckus. This version of the game has various battle assist options, a 3x speed boost, and the ability to turn off random encounters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At the time of its initial release in 2000, Final Fantasy IX was something of a throwback to the medieval-settings settings of the first six entries in the series. This game follows Zidane and a troupe of actors, who “kidnap” Princess Garnet, who secretly wanted to be kidnapped to get away from her deranged mother, the queen. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The visuals have been gently revamped to look better on modern displays. It has other new features as well, including auto-save and seven game boosters, including high speed and no-encounter modes.</p></div><p id="more-preorder-guides"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="More preorder guides">Other Preorder Guides</h2></p><div><ul><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/007-first-light-heres-what-comes-in-each-edition">007 First Light Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-heres-what-comes-in-each-edition">Battlefield 6 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-heres-what-comes-in-each-edition">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-preorder-clair-obscur-expedition-33-mirror-edition-ps5-xbox-amazon-exclusive">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Mirror Edition Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-dragon-quest-1-2-hd-2d-remake">Dragon Quest I and II HD-2D Remake Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-heres-what-comes-in-each-edition">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-physical-deluxe-edition-where-to-buy">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered Physical Deluxe Edition Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-nintendo-switch-2-xbox-where-to-buy">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade (Switch, Xbox) Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-8-and-9-physical-editions-for-switch-are-up-for-preorder-where-to-buy">Final Fantasy 7, 8, and 9 (Switch) Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hades-2-where-to-buy">Hades 2 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-switch-2-where-to-buy">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-nintendo-switch-2-preorders">Kirby Air Riders Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-tennis-fever-nintendo-switch-2-where-to-buy">Mario Tennis Fever Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-4-beyond-where-to-buy">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nioh-3-where-to-buy">Nioh 3 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-preorder-octopath-traveler-0">Octopath Traveler 0 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-preorder-pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch">Pokemon Legends Z-A Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-preorder-trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-switch-ps5-pc">Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li></ul></div>
<p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Chris Reed is a commerce editor and deals expert for IGN. He also runs IGN's board game and LEGO coverage. You can follow him on </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/chrislreed.com" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 9, 2025 10:01 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-8-and-9-physical-editions-for-switch-are-up-for-preorder-where-to-buy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[100 Meters Is A Soulful Gem About The Poetry Of Running]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/100-meters-gkids-anime-movie-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/100-meters-is-a-soulful-gem-about-the-poetry-of-running.1321411/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>For decades, anime has routinely spun athleticism into artistic spectacle, be it ping pong duels, basketball games, or wacky, high-octane races that blur the line between vehicular sport and myth. <em>100 Meters</em>, the latest theatrical release from GKids and Studio <a href="https://aftermath.site/100-meters-gkids-anime-movie-kenji-iwaisawa-director-interview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rock’N Roll Mountain</a>, doesn’t chase flash. Adapted from Uoto’s manga <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/100_Meters_(manga)" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Hyakuemo</em></a>, this rotoscoped-driven gem trades bombast for breadth, offering a quietly powerful and inspiring view of an athlete's ambition fighting underneath the pitfalls of competition, burnout, and career-threatening injury.&nbsp;</p><p>At its core are Togashi, a prodigy whose speed and natural-born athleticism feel God-sent, and Komiya, a scrappy underdog fueled by grit alone. Their friendship-turned-rivalry unfolds across years, framed not by medals or podium envy but by a single refrained question: Why do you run? While the film explicitly answers this question, it never feels like it needs to. It's evident in the way the characters’ bodies move—whether they’re leading the pack, trailing behind chasing glory, or simply chasing each other.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="劇場アニメ『ひゃくえむ。』本編冒頭映像６分特別公開！【大ヒット上映中】" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ObspfdX4jGA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Like <a href="https://aftermath.site/look-back-gkids-tatsuki-fujimoto" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Look Back</em></a>, <em>100 Meters</em> scratches the itch of watching two people from wildly different walks of life wrestle with maintaining their passion. But where Tatsuki Fujimoto’s work spirals into grief and artistic obsession, <em>100 Meters</em> stays grounded in the purity of the 100-meter dash, a brutally simple sport where runners have just ten seconds to prove they’re the fastest and etch their name into history. If someone’s a hair quicker, or your body fails you, you’re forgotten in the blink of an eye.&nbsp;</p><p>Although <em>100 Meters</em> flirts with the ephemeral glory of being the best in a sport predicated on “who’s on top right now” over who once was, it never wallows in the futility of the Sisyphean pursuit of greatness. Even in its most agonizing defeats and major setbacks, it refuses to become grim. Instead, it finds beauty in the act of picking yourself back up and starting again—to compete not for legacy, but for love. For the joy of movement, and to run shoulder to shoulder with the like-minded people beside you.&nbsp;</p><p>What makes <em>100 Meters</em> truly magnificent is how, despite being about track and field, it refuses to embellish or exaggerate its modest place in sports. The stands aren’t packed; races aren’t roared over outside of the confines of its niche fandom. The sport isn’t the celestial body around which the universe revolves. It’s just something that <em>100 Meters</em>’ characters collectively chose.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Rock'N Roll Mountain/GKids</span></figcaption></figure><p>Visually, <em>100 Meters’</em> rotoscope animation—arguably the biggest selling point— is sublime. With herculean production feats like a three-minute and 40-second one-shot long take totaling <a href="https://x.com/ROCKNROLL_MT/status/1970718588081189235" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">approximately 9,830 animation cels</a> across foreground and background layers, Rock’N Roll’s craftsmanship is undeniable. But its rotoscoping truly sings in the film’s quieter moments. Subtle gestures, flickers of emotion, and the rhythmic ebb and flow of movement—both in anguish and elation—are illustrated with painterly grace.&nbsp;</p><p>Complementing this is the film’s soft watercolor background art, where every brushstroke and stain evokes the cozy tactility of a Little Golden Book, tying its visual poetry together with warmth and texture. A texture that erupts from the frame with rapturous adrenaline as its ensemble hits its eighth gear, diving headlong into their runner’s high to finish out strong with primal ferocity.&nbsp;</p><p><em>100 Meters</em> doesn’t grandstand. It just runs. And in doing so, it discovers something achingly beautiful and universal in the blur of its poetry.</p><hr><p><em>100 Meters hits</em> select theaters on October 10 and will be available nationwide from October 12 to October 14.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/baby-steps-manbreaker-did-not-break-me-challange"><h3>Baby Steps’ Manbreaker Did Not Break Me</h3></a><p>Baby Steps' Manbreaker is an optional, brutal challenge that is as much a test of your humility as it is your skill.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/skin-deep-patch-notes-impaled-swordfishes"><h3>Good Patch Notes</h3></a><p>"The trash chute now ignores impaled swordfishes"</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/100-meters-gkids-anime-movie-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>