<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:54:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gearbox Debuts the First New Vault Hunter Coming to Borderlands 4 in Paid DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/gearbox-debuts-first-new-vault-hunter-borderlands-4-paid-story-dlc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gearbox-debuts-the-first-new-vault-hunter-coming-to-borderlands-4-in-paid-dlc.1311556/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Over this past weekend, during Tokyo Game Show 2025, Gearbox and 2K unveiled the first of two new vault hunters that'll be joining Borderlands 4 as part of the game's first paid story DLC set to release sometime during Q1 2026.</p>



<p>The new hunter's name is C4SH, a former casino bot turned vault hunter whose skills and abilities will be "<em>distinctly unpredictable, as they all involve an element of chance</em>," <a href="https://borderlands.2k.com/borderlands-4/news/c4sh-vault-hunter-teaser/">according to Gearbox in a blog post</a> on the Borderlands 4 website.</p>



<figure><figcaption>C4SH's kit in Borderlands 4. Image credit: Gearbox</figcaption></figure>



<p>We don't exactly know what that means for now, but Gearbox has said that we'll learn more about who C4SH is and his abilities as we get closer to the release of the first story DLC pack, Mad Ellie and the Vault of the Damned. A short teaser trailer released alongside the reveal of C4SH gives us a visual of the character and his kit, but doesn't go into detail on them.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Borderlands 4 - Vault Hunter Teaser: C4SH" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b1XYW_fOS3k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>If you purchased the Super Deluxe Edition of Borderlands 4 or the Vault Hunter Pack for the game, then you won't have to make an additional purchase when C4SH and the Mad Ellie and the Vault of the Damned story pack go live. If you just bought the base game, then you'll have to grab this paid DLC separately.</p>



<p>It's all well and good to see what Gearbox is working on bringing to Borderlands 4, particularly for players who've already blown through the game's main story campaign in the last two weeks since it was released and are looking for more to do. But it would be easier to be more excited about it if it weren't for the fact that players are still experiencing major technical issues with the game.</p>



<p>Gearbox is updating the game as quickly as it can, <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-update-adds-fov-slider-consoles-stability-improvements-more/">adding technical fixes and (in some cases) adding features that really should have been in the game at launch</a>, but it'll likely be a while before all of its major issues have been mopped up.</p>



<p>It can also only be seen as humorous that the teaser trailer for C4SH includes a mention of the Nintendo Switch 2 version, which, on top of Borderlands 4's other issues, <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-nintendo-switch-2-delayed-pre-orders-cancelled/">was indefinitely delayed last week</a> after initially scheduled to release on October 3.</p>



<p>A new Vault Hunter on the scene is nice. A game without major frame rate issues that didn't crash all the time would be better.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/gearbox-debuts-first-new-vault-hunter-borderlands-4-paid-story-dlc/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameSir’s clip-on controller turns smartphones into Game Boys]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/787200/gamesir-controller-smartphone-nintendo-game-boy-tokyo-game-show</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamesir%E2%80%99s-clip-on-controller-turns-smartphones-into-game-boys.1311553/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2006, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Over the past weekend at the Tokyo Game Show, GameSir demonstrated a new controller that turns your smartphone into a Game Boy. Unlike the company’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/24/24187539/gamesir-g8-bluetooth-mobile-controller-ios-android-nintendo-switch-pc">GameSir G8 Plus</a> that offers similar functionality by clamping on to the top and bottom of a phone turned sideways recreating the ergonomics of the Nintendo Switch, this new controller is much smaller and keeps the phone vertical. GameSir didn’t make any formal announcements of what the accessory is called, what it will cost, compatibility, or when it will be released.</p><p>Although the accessory is visible in the background of a <a href="https://x.com/mygamesir/status/1971130648166564029">photo GameSir shared of its TGS booth on X</a>, better photos were shared by the <a href="https://x.com/yoshivesmovie">X account, @Yoshivesmovie</a>, after getting the chance to go hands-on with the controller. The C-shaped accessory slides on to the bottom of a smartphone and features a D-pad, Start and Select buttons, and four action buttons that are all styled after the Game Boy’s. There’s also a pair of additional face buttons plus shoulder buttons on the back ensuring it can be used to play more than just <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24150467/delta-emulator-apple-app-voice-notes-ai-vergecast">emulated Game Boy titles</a>.</p><p>It’s not known how the controller will connect to a smartphone, but the photos seem to show a cutout on the bottom that may keep a phone’s charging port accessible. If the accessory isn’t relying on a USB-C connection, it will probably use Bluetooth which also means it will have its own rechargeable battery. Having yet another accessory to remember to charge isn’t ideal, but the ergonomics look much better than the recently announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/785720/xiaomi-retro-handheld-phone-case-17-pro-gaming">Retro Handheld Console Case for the Xiaomi 17 series smartphones</a> that only works with the camera bump screen on the back of the phone.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/787200/gamesir-controller-smartphone-nintendo-game-boy-tokyo-game-show]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill f Has One Of The Best And Creepiest Puzzles Of The Year]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/silent-hill-f-scarecrow-puzzle-field-hinako-2000629866</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-f-has-one-of-the-best-and-creepiest-puzzles-of-the-year.1311550/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Early on in <a href="https://kotaku.com/silent-hill-f-review-horror-konami-hinako-ryukishi07-2000627505"><i>Silent Hill f</i></a>, as Hinako and friends try to regroup after the fog and its monsters roll into town, our girl finds herself stranded in the middle of a field, surrounded by scarecrows dressed like schoolchildren wielding sickles. Like many moments in <i>f</i>, the way through this challenge involves some puzzle solving and a couple of scuffles. What really makes this moment sing, however, is how it combines the separate elements of <i>Silent Hill f</i> into one: Puzzle solving, paranoid dread, and combat that will punish you for sloppy mistakes.</p> <p><strong>Read More:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://kotaku.com/silent-hill-f-review-horror-konami-hinako-ryukishi07-2000627505"><em>Silent Hill f</em>: The&nbsp;<em>Kotaku</em> Review</a></p> <p>The scarecrows are, of course, no ordinary scarecrows, and can definitely turn those sickles on you. They don’t attack immediately, however; instead, they remain frozen, waiting for you to pick the right one based on a cryptic riddle, after which the correct scarecrow will point you in the direction of the next challenge and eventually out of the fog. Choose the wrong scarecrow and you’ll get attacked, with few replacement weapons in sight. Oh, and you’ll regularly hear footsteps behind you as you try to figure out which scarecrow is the correct one. Yes, they are following you, but only when you’re not looking. The number of scarecrows and the speed with which they freeze when you turn to look at them is enough to make you question whether or not you’re hearing things, and even those footsteps don’t guarantee an attack every time you hear them. Early on, I wondered if the game was just playing the sound effect to screw with me. Nope! I was eventually attacked by one of these freaks.</p> <p>The horror of this whole scene isn’t one of blood dripping red in your face, but instead comes from the pressure to figure out the puzzle, which is virtually immune to brute force solutions, in a timely manner. The sheer tension of this situation, sustained in the perpetual gray fog of this endless field, makes it one of <i>f</i>’s best moments.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000629872" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000629872"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000629872">© Screenshot: NeoBards Entertainment / Claire Jackson / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Most of <i>Silent Hill f</i>’s puzzles resist brute-force solutions due to their sheer number of variables. Many of them are technically solvable by just trying out every possible combination, but it’s all too easy to end up spinning your wheels in frustration for far longer than is necessary instead (ask me how I know). What makes the field puzzle so uniquely resistant to brute force is that it punishes you rather harshly for just trying to spam your way through it.</p>

 <p>Each scarecrow segment starts with a riddle like:</p> <blockquote><p>Can you even imagine how I feel?<br> I’ll put on my polite smile for now.</p></blockquote> <p>You’ll then need to choose the one that best fits the description from among around half-a-dozen scarecrows. It’s not easy; you’ll have to determine which scarecrow seems to give a “polite smile,” or in another instance, which scarecrow looks like it’s betraying another.</p>

 <p>Against your better judgment, you’ll have to get up close and personal with many of the scarecrows, with footsteps playing behind you sporadically, and the chance that one of these freaks is actually ready to jump you at any moment.</p> <p>During my first playthrough, I screwed up the final puzzle of this whole sequence and had about five or six scarecrows stalking me around the feels as I frantically tore at the remaining ones to find the correct solution.</p> <p>The puzzle also deals with <i>f</i>’s consistent themes about love, longing, betrayal, and harm; so, not only is the game asking you to survive the dread of the endless gray fog and murderous scarecrows, but you’ll also be trying to figure out how this sequence fits in with <i>f</i>’s cryptic narrative. It’s a nice mixture of traditional survival horror puzzle solving,&nbsp; the threat of the game’s punishing combat, and its looming sense of dread, all without feeling like it’s a bunch of abstract symbol-matching or number crunching.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/silent-hill-f-scarecrow-puzzle-field-hinako-2000629866]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Peacemaker Dance Pulled Over Nazi Concerns Following Latest Episode’s Big Reveal]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/peacemaker-fortnite-nazi-emote-season-2-spoilers-2000629842</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-peacemaker-dance-pulled-over-nazi-concerns-following-latest-episode%E2%80%99s-big-reveal.1311544/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>“Peaceful Hips” is an&nbsp;emote that was added to <em>Fortnite</em> earlier this month. Part of the “DC Series,” it cost 400 V-Bucks and referenced HBO’s show <em>Peacemaker</em> HBO, specifically a dance move the character does in the season 2 intro that has him flapping his arms and swerving his hips around. That was all fine and good until the comic book series’ big season 2 reveal last week cast it in a different light. Epic Games has now pulled the cosmetic over concerns about its “creative intentions.” In plain English, Epic is worried it might be intended to look like a Nazi Swastika.</p> <p>“We’re disabling the Peaceful Hips Emote in <em>Fortnite</em> as we inquire into our partner’s creative intentions in this collab emote,” the battle roayle’s <a href="https://x.com/FortniteStatus/status/1972168326551138447">official account</a> announced over the weekend. “Assuming it’s not coming back, we’ll issue refunds in the next few days. Sorry folks.” All of this weirdness stems from the following dance which players were previously able to buy separately or as part of the Peacemaker bundle:</p> <figure id="attachment_2000629848" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000629848"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000629848">Epic Games / DiscussingFilm / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>It wasn’t until <em>Peacemaker</em> season 2 episode 6 that some people started seeing it in a different light. Full <strong>spoiler warning</strong> ahead if you haven’t watched yet and don’t want to know what happens.</p> <p>Chris Smith, AKA Peacemaker, doesn’t want to leave the alternate dimension where things seem “perfect” despite that menacing suspicion that something is very, very off.&nbsp; It turns out that this Earth-2 the mercenary’s been hanging out in is actually Earth-X, our planet in an alternate timeline where the United States lost to Hitler’s Germany in WWII. In case the lack of any non-white people didn’t give it away already, the big reveal comes when Chris realizes there’s a Swastika on the American flag. It now seems like that Nazi theme may have made it into the <em>Fortnite</em> emote. <em>Forbes</em> notes its similarity to a&nbsp; dance Donald Duck performs in the&nbsp; Disney short “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I7vb89c6pQY">Der Fuehrer’s Face</a>” when he’s trained to become a Nazi.</p> <p>The headscratching part is how Epic Games didn’t know about this twist coming ahead of time, or who at Warner Bros. or HBO would have tried to keep its “creative intentions” hidden. The show is written and directed by James Gunn, the creative force fueling <em>Superman</em> and the rest of the rebooted DC universe right now. Epic would have seemingly developed the emote in-house, suggesting that it didn’t initially raise any suspicions internally. Live by the branded cosmetic, fail by the branded cosmetic, I suppose.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/peacemaker-fortnite-nazi-emote-season-2-spoilers-2000629842]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brotato post-launch development moved to Evil Empire]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/brotato-post-launch-development-moved-to-evil-empire</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/brotato-post-launch-development-moved-to-evil-empire.1311541/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em><a title="Games > The Rogue Prince of Persia [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-rogue-prince-of-persia">The Rogue Prince of Persia</a></em> developer <a title="Companies > Evil Empire [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/evil-empire">Evil Empire</a> has taken over the post-launch development of&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Brotato [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/brotato">Brotato</a></em>, the <a title="Companies > Blobfish [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/blobfish">Blobfish</a>-developed, multi-million-selling roguelike <a title="Genres > Action [3,094 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,280 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a>, the company announced. <span id="more-997209"></span></p><p>Evil Empire is known for its long and steady years of support for&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Dead Cells [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dead-cells">Dead Cells</a></em> from <a title="Companies > Motion Twin [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/motion-twin">Motion Twin</a>, which ended with the downloadable content “Return to Castlevania.” The Evil Empire team, founded by ex-Motion Twin developers, was originally created for this specific type of development—supporting and working with game communities to bring new content to beloved games.</p><p>“I’m excited to see how the game evolves under the direction of such a talented team and what fresh perspectives they’ll bring to the table,” said Blobfish CEO Thomas Gervraud in a press release. “Above all, though, I’m just eager to dive back in and have fun playing <em>Brotato</em> again.”</p><p>Here is a sneak peek at what players can expect when&nbsp;<em>Brotato</em> gets its first fill update in October—a new mob called “The Gobbler”:</p><p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]--><br><video id="video-997209-1" width="640" height="360" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://i.imgur.com/LyUCc4g.mp4?_=1"><a href="https://i.imgur.com/LyUCc4g.mp4">https://i.imgur.com/LyUCc4g.mp4</a></video></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Here is a brief overview of the game, via Evil Empire:</p><blockquote><p><em>Brotato</em> launched in 2023 and since then the top-down arena shooting roguelike has spawned more than 10 million-plus players around the world across <a title="Platforms > PC [24,420 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, console, and mobile platforms. Already a robust title for solo or <a title="Genres > Co-Op [335 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> players, Evil Empire is joining in to keep baking <em>Brotato</em>, adding the ever-necessary topping of fire updates packed with new content and even more roguelike goodness. <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a>d shepherds of <a title="Genres > Roguelike [372 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelikes</a> that they are, Evil Empire’s additions to <em>Brotato</em> won’t be thrown on willy-nilly (much like tuna on a baked potato, because who even does that).</p></blockquote><p><em>Brotato</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,514 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,399 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,226 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,771 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1942280/Brotato/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, iOS, and Android.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/brotato-post-launch-development-moved-to-evil-empire]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fornite Disables John Cena Emote After Major Peacemaker S2 Twist]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fornite-disables-john-cena-emote-after-major-peacemaker-s2-twist/1100-6535083/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fornite-disables-john-cena-emote-after-major-peacemaker-s2-twist.1311538/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535083">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2025-09-29T07:41:38-0800">September 29, 2025 at 7:41AM PDT</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Epic Games has announced that a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a> emote associated with retiring WWE superstar and current movie mega-star John Cena has been disabled, maybe indefinitely, because of its possible Nazi connection.</p><p>Peaceful Hips, <a href="https://x.com/DiscussingFilm/status/1972176095580754324" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">an emote in the popular battle royale shooter</a>, was created in collaboration between James Gunn's DC show Peacemaker and Epic Games. The emote sees your character goofily rotate their hips before making alternating "L" shapes with their arms. If you've watched Peacemaker, then you're familiar with the dance; it's what Cena performs in the second season's opening montage. It's awkward and stiff, which is what's supposed to make it a lighthearted gaff, particularly given the character's often violent personality. However, with the show's latest episode, the quirky dance--and Fortnite emote--have taken on a whole new meaning.</p><h4>Light Spoilers for Peacemaker S2, E6</h4><p>Titled "Ignorance Is Chris," the September 25 episode sees Peacemaker discover that the alternate dimension he's so fond of is actually Nazi America. This version of the US shows a true Anglo state, where there are only white people, and the stars of the American flag have been replaced with swastikas. It's this fact that unlocks the new meaning behind Peacemaker's dance in the opening of Season 2; those alternating "L" shapes he's making with his arms are stand-ins for the swastika.</p><p>With some <a href="https://x.com/JonesyFrotting/status/1971989740489789894" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">fans pointing this</a> out on <a href="https://x.com/CTropes/status/1971797634576011500" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">X/Twitter</a>, Epic Games has pulled the emote offline, possibly indefinitely, as it investigates its partner's "creative intentions."</p><p>"We're disabling the Peaceful Hips Emote in Fortnite as we inquire into our partner's creative intentions in this collab emote," Epic Games <a href="https://x.com/FortniteStatus/status/1972168326551138447" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said on X/Twitter</a> on September 28. "Assuming it's not coming back, we'll issue refunds in the next few days. Sorry folks."</p><p>Peacemaker showrunner James Gunn hasn't publicly commented on the situation. As noted by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/battle-royale/fortnite-quickly-pulls-peacemaker-emote-while-it-figures-out-our-partners-creative-intentions-after-the-shows-huge-twist-gives-it-a-whole-new-meaning/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC Gamer</a>, however, Gunn <a href="https://x.com/JamesGunn/status/1967015798939283554" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">promoted the collab on X/Twitter</a> on September 13. Considering how frequently he posts on the social media site, there's a possibility he'll say something about Epic Games' decision.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fornite-disables-john-cena-emote-after-major-peacemaker-s2-twist/1100-6535083/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hades 2 Passes 110,000 Concurrent Players On Steam, Doubling All-Time Peak For Original]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hades-2-passes-110000-concurrent-players-on-steam-doubling-all-time-peak-for-original/1100-6535081/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hades-2-passes-110-000-concurrent-players-on-steam-doubling-all-time-peak-for-original.1311535/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535081">

            
            
  


    


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container" data-in-content-placements="[{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-incontent-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:1,&quot;minElements&quot;:2},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:4,&quot;minElements&quot;:5}]},{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-banner-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:7,&quot;minElements&quot;:8},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:10,&quot;minElements&quot;:11},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:13,&quot;minElements&quot;:14}]}]">
                <p dir="ltr">The full release for Hades 2 has led to a new all-time high of concurrent players on Steam for the sequel. The roguelite game topped out at 112,947 people over the weekend, according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1145350/charts/#max" rel="nofollow ">SteamDB</a>. That breaks the sequel's record from its Steam Early Access debut in May 2024 with just over 103,000 players. In addition, Hades 2 has already doubled the peak of Hades, which hit 54,240 concurrent players in May 2024, too, per <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1145360/charts/#max" rel="nofollow ">SteamDB</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Developer Supergiant <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hades-2-hits-1-0-release-patch-notes-reveal-big-changes/1100-6535023/">delivered Hades 2 version 1.0</a> a few days ago on September 25. The full launch also included the true ending for the game, along with 50 different achievements and new artwork. So far, Hades 2 is only available on PC, Switch, and Switch 2.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="83330020" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466378,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Hades%202%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:888,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/hades-2-review\/2300-6466378\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466378\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466378\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466378\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;phone&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:true,&quot;allowMutedAutoplay&quot;:true,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466378&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/mobile_web\/gamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466378,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;ssai&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6535081&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;hades-ii&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,macintosh,nintendo-switch-2,nintendo-switch&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;supergiant-games&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;hades&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;hades&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web\/gamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466378},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466378\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4573809-hades2_review_site_only.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/92zeqptV.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1758726000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="92zeqptV" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Hades 2 Review</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Hades 2 is the first sequel that Supergiant has ever created. The studio formed in 2009 and previously made Bastion, Transistor, Pyre, and the original Hades. GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/hades-2-review-witching-hours/1900-6418231/">Hades 2 review</a> rewarded the follow-up with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-gamespot-10-10-review-score/2900-153/#16">a prestigious 10/10</a>--the second title to earn that score this year (Split Fiction being the other).</p><p>Looking ahead, Supergiant hasn't teased <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hades-2-dev-on-how-it-will-choose-next-game-and-major-industry-issues/1100-6535044/">what could be next from the developer</a>. However, it's expected that Hades 2 will come to PlayStation and Xbox platforms in the future, similarly to the original. For more, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hades-2-guides-hub/1100-6523315/">Hades 2 guides hub</a>.</p>
  
                        
        
    
    
                                  </div>


          
  
        <div data-merchant-service-api-link="https://www.gamespot.com/merchantapi/offer/?gameid=577618"><div><p>
      There are currently no available deals
    </p></div><p>GameSpot may get a commission from retail offers.</p></div>  
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hades-2-passes-110000-concurrent-players-on-steam-doubling-all-time-peak-for-original/1100-6535081/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Internet Reacts To EA’s $55 Billion Sale To Some Of The Worst People Around]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/electronic-arts-acquisition-saudi-arabia-jared-kushner-2000629849</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-internet-reacts-to-ea%E2%80%99s-55-billion-sale-to-some-of-the-worst-people-around.1311520/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>After </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/report-saudi-arabia-and-other-investors-nearing-50-billion-deal-to-buy-ea-2000629291"><span>reports sprouted up last week</span></a><span> that Electronic Arts, the publisher behind </span><i><span>The Sims</span></i><span>, BioWare’s catalog, and most of your favorite sports games, was being acquired for over $50 billion in a joint venture between Saudi Arabia’s Private Investor Fund, Silver Lake, and the Jared Kushner-owned Affinity Partners, the company has </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ea-sale-saudi-arabia-madden-pif-jared-kushner-2000629829"><span>officially confirmed the deal</span></a><span>. If approved, the acquisition would be one of the most expensive in the history of the video game industry and would make Electronic Arts a privately held company. Given the questionable ownership, the internet is not taking the news well.</span></p> <p><span>The Saudi Arabian government’s attempts at sportswashing away the stink of its dire human rights laws, as evidenced by its </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/evo-saudi-arabia-street-fighter-6-sony-esports-2000622367"><span>investments in various facets of the video game industry</span></a><span>, are well-documented at this point. Its money runs so deep that it has investments and ownerships in things like fighting game tournament EVO, the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/apex-legends-lgbtqia-characters-tournament-saudi-arabia-1851411189"><span>Esports World Cup</span></a><span>, and even </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-go-scopely-niantic-saudi-arabia-monster-hunter-1851769360"><i><span>Pokémon Go</span></i></a><span>. Now it has a lot of money in one of the biggest video game publishers on the planet, and the internet is worried about what it means not just for the games themselves, but for the people working under EA’s umbrella.</span></p>            <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp/app.bsky.feed.post/3lzy2ieztws2w" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreicf45ugrviqm6nkgxwn2nvt5sn65fy7mwenduemxb7uhu56sgtvri"> <p lang="en">A lot of people are (understandably) focused on the Saudi Arabia and Kushner part of this, but the far bigger immediate impact will come from the new private EA being on the hook for $20 billion in debt. That could mean mass layoffs, more aggressive monetization, and other big cost-cutting measures</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp?ref_src=embed">Jason Schreier (@jasonschreier.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp/post/3lzy2ieztws2w?ref_src=embed">2025-09-29T12:52:46.256Z</a></p></blockquote></div>   <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:7qaydotyzl5tbnyolgootvvz/app.bsky.feed.post/3lzy4qqgbs22d" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreidgtijljy42vzp4peyz2h6nkkh4uy4l3cgyvzi24whcuenuuxit6e"> <p lang="en">EA owns BioWare (Dragon Age, Mass Effect), Respawn (Titanfall, Apex Legends), System Shock, Dead Space, Need for Speed, classics like Ultima and Wing Commander, and The Sims, on top of so, SO many more games and franchises which will now be subject to the control of the Saudi Royal family.</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:7qaydotyzl5tbnyolgootvvz?ref_src=embed">TBSkyen (@tbskyen.com)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:7qaydotyzl5tbnyolgootvvz/post/3lzy4qqgbs22d?ref_src=embed">2025-09-29T13:33:14.178Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:6hit5rjdbmlnscmuk4bbtmuc/app.bsky.feed.post/3lzxzsz2bls24" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreifze6geb442rnkbu56vaxldoqb4qc4frr476kexc4gyrfcjsursxq"> <p lang="en">this business model should be flatly illegal</p> <p>taking on a bunch of debt to buy a company and then burning the company to the ground to service that debt while paying yourselves huge fees is a purely destructive practice that has never once had a positive outcome</p> <p>ban it completely</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:6hit5rjdbmlnscmuk4bbtmuc?ref_src=embed">Micah (@rincewind.run)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:6hit5rjdbmlnscmuk4bbtmuc/post/3lzxzsz2bls24?ref_src=embed">2025-09-29T12:40:49.043Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <p><span>Given Saudi Arabia’s treatment of queer people, a fair bit of concern has been extended specifically to </span><i><span>The Sims </span></i><span>and to BioWare, the developer of </span><i><span>Mass Effect </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Dragon Age</span></i><span>, all of which have been trailblazers for queer representation in video games. EA CEO Andrew Wilson has stated in an email statement to staff that the company’s “values and [its] commitment to players and fans around the world remain unchanged,” but considering that both the Saudi Arabian government and Jared Kushner, the owner of Affinity Partners and Donald Trump’s son-in-law, now own the publisher, that’s not exactly convincing.</span></p>     <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:2znkikj4whfsfygetsubw2xr/app.bsky.feed.post/3lzraqcz3ts26" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreicvrdef5o37ujsyzhnm3nid5ip6rxrm3wrub6rdpwgdxahkn4337i"> <p lang="en">Buyers: So your games… guns and football, yes?</p> <p>EA: Mmhmm, mmhmm, mostly guns and football, yep.</p> <p>Buyers: No gay stuff? No politics we're not going to like?</p> <p>EA: Haha, definitely not! Hey, could you give me one sec? I just need to shut down a studio real quick.</p> <p>kotaku.com/report-saudi…</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2znkikj4whfsfygetsubw2xr?ref_src=embed">Trick Weekes (@trickweekes.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2znkikj4whfsfygetsubw2xr/post/3lzraqcz3ts26?ref_src=embed">2025-09-26T19:55:56.852Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">BioWare… u gotta escape… you gotta leave now… someone please buy BioWare before EA hands it over</p> <p>— jas | comms open? | 🏳️‍🌈 (@jxsmin_twts) <a href="https://twitter.com/jxsmin_twts/status/1971835290454274417?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 27, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>The Saudi government’s influence on the games it has money in has thus far resulted in some bizarre shit, such as soccer player Cristiano Ronaldo </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/cristiano-ronaldo-fatal-fury-city-wolves-saudi-arabia-1851772758"><span>showing up in the latest </span><i><span>Fatal Fury</span></i></a><span>, though developer SNK </span><a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/snk-lead-insists-saudi-arabia-sale-will-have-no-effect-on-the-games-we-make/"><span>has insisted</span></a><span> the company’s sale to PIF would not affect its games. Beyond that, the Saudi Arabian government has been hosting events with industry figureheads like Hideo Kojima. The nation’s monetary investment in video games has been extensive, but buying one of the biggest companies in the space, whose games are played by millions every year, is almost certainly the farthest-reaching move it’s made thus far. We don’t know what impact this will have on EA, its studios, and its IP in the future, but in this moment, things look bleak.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/electronic-arts-acquisition-saudi-arabia-jared-kushner-2000629849]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASUS ROG Xbox Ally Up for Pre-order Is Live, Skip the Sell-Out FOMO and Secure Yours Before October 16 Release]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/asus-rog-xbox-ally-up-for-pre-order-is-live-skip-the-sell-out-fomo-and-secure-yours-before-october-16-release-2000629343</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/asus-rog-xbox-ally-up-for-pre-order-is-live-skip-the-sell-out-fomo-and-secure-yours-before-october-16-release.1311517/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>We may not be getting a handheld Xbox anytime soon, but this will be the next closest thing. Asus has partnered with Microsoft to create an update to the ROG Ally with official-branding for Xbox. The Asus ROG Xbox Ally enters the market as a new competitor to the Steam Deck and Nintendo Switch 2 to be your go-to gaming handheld. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4361/">It’s set to arrive on October 16 and the pre-order window has just opened up.</a> Head on over to Amazon and reserve yours today for $600.</p>
<p>Let’s talk about the core improvements on this model over the existing Asus ROG Ally. This new model is now powered by an AMD Ryzen Z2 A processor and puts to use an all-new streamlined Windows OS. Both will lead to a smoother user experience both in and out of your games.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4361/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Your Gaming Library, Anywhere</h2>
<p>Access your full library of PC games and boot up directly into the new Xbox App UI. Stream Xbox games from either your console or from Microsoft’s cloud streaming service. The Xbox Game bar can be accessed quickly via the Xbox button on the left side of the handheld. The Asus ROG Xbox Ally also has support for Steam, Epic Games Store and other game stores so you won’t just be locked into the Xbox architecture.</p>
<p>The gaming handheld comes with 16GB of dual channel RAM along with a 512GB PCle Gen4 M.2 2280 SSD. Storage is upgradable if you wish to download more games than the default capacity allows.</p>



<p>The screen measures in at seven inches across, same as the Steam Deck, and weighs just under 1.5 lbs. — almost exactly the same as the Steam Deck on that front too. The display is capable of 1080p HD along with a refresh rate of 120Hz. The redesigned chassis is pulls inspiration from the model Xbox wireless core controllers, employing new contoured grips for better comfort gaming all day long. Choose to play either handheld or hooked up to your TV via the dual USB-C ports.</p>
<p>The Asus ROG Xbox Ally has a 60Wh battery to your game time running long and can recharge fairly quickly. Just have it plugged in for a half hour will get it back up from zero to 50% battery life.</p>
<p>Alongside this model is the upgraded Asus ROG Xbox Ally X which features a more powerful processor, more RAM and a full 1TB SSD, doubling the base model’s storage capacity. It also comes with an 80Wh battery. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4361/">Unfortunately, most storefronts appear to be sold out on the X model, but you can still pre-order the Asus ROG Xbox Ally for $600 over at Amazon.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4361/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/asus-rog-xbox-ally-up-for-pre-order-is-live-skip-the-sell-out-fomo-and-secure-yours-before-october-16-release-2000629343]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s official: EA is selling to private equity in $55 billion deal]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/its-official-ea-is-selling-to-private-equity-in-55-billion-deal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it%E2%80%99s-official-ea-is-selling-to-private-equity-in-55-billion-deal.1311511/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<p>The Saudi Arabia PIF also has significant investments in gaming giants such as Nintendo, Take Two, Activision Blizzard Capcom, Nexon, and Koei Tecmo managed through the Savvy Games Group. In 2023, the PIF <a href="https://www.axios.com/2023/08/14/saudi-arabia-savvy-games-embracer-group">backed out of a mulled $2 billion deal</a> for gaming acquisition firm Embracer Group.</p>
<figure>
    <div id="caption-1179385"><p>
              Ivanka Trump and Jared Kushner on the South Lawn of the White House.
                              </p>
                          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Ivanka Trump and Jared Kushner on the South Lawn of the White House.

              <span>
          Credit:

                      <a href="http://www.gettyimages.com/search/2/image?artist=win%20mcnamee&amp;amp;excludenudity=true&amp;amp;family=editorial&amp;amp;sort=mostpopular" target="_blank">
          
          Win McNamee/Getty Images

                      </a>
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Silver Lake was part of the consortium involved in <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/09/china-keeps-the-algorithm-critics-attack-trumps-tiktok-deal/">this month's controversial deal</a> to bring Tiktok under the control of US-based companies. Back in 2013, the private investment firm also <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/09/michael-dell-wins-buyout-bid-after-icahn-takes-ball-goes-home/">helped take computer-maker Dell private in a $25 billion deal</a>.</p>
<p>Affinity Partners CEO Jared Kushner, the son-in-law of President Trump, said in a statement that he has "admired [EA's] ability to create iconic, lasting experiences, and as someone who grew up playing their games – and now enjoys them with his kids – I couldn’t be more excited about what’s ahead."</p>
<p>EA first went public with an IPO on the NASDAQ stock exchange in 1990, and by 1996 its market cap had risen to $1.61 billion. Last week, the company's valuation was hovering around $43 billion.</p>
<p>EA brought in $7.5 billion in revenue in the 2025 fiscal year (ending March 31) on the strength of franchises including <em>Madden NFL</em>, <em>EA Sports FC</em>, <em>Battlefield</em>, <em>The Sims</em>, <em>Dragon Age</em>, and <em>Plants vs. Zombies</em>.</p>


          
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/its-official-ea-is-selling-to-private-equity-in-55-billion-deal/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Release Times Seemingly Revealed, And There Is No Early Access]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-times-seemingly-revealed-and-there-is-no-early-access/1100-6535079/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-release-times-seemingly-revealed-and-there-is-no-early-access.1311505/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535079">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6</a>'s launch on October 10 is coming up very soon. If you're wondering precisely when you can start playing, the release times for the military shooter have now been posted online.</p><p>As confirmed previously, there is no early access for Battlefield 6, so the game will launch at the same time for everyone on October 10. The global rollout begins at 8 AM PT on October 10, which works out to 11 AM ET and 4 PM BST. You can see more global launch times below, as <a href="https://x.com/BFBulletin/status/1972167971788210539" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">posted by Battlefield Bulletin.</a> GameSpot has contacted EA in an attempt to confirm these times and get more information.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EunkRPRzECg" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EunkRPRzECg" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Preloading times have been revealed as well, and they begin a week before launch.</p><p>Battlefield 6 will be EA's first major new release following the announcement that the company <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-goes-private-in-55-billion-deal-from-saudi-arabia-jared-kushners-company-and-others/1100-6535078/" data-ref-id="1100-6535078">revealed plans to sell itself</a> to Saudi Arabia's PIF, Jared Kushner's Affinity Partners, and private equity company Silver Lake for $55 billion.</p><p>Battlefield 6 is the first entry in the series since 2021's Battlefield 2042, a game that was a disappointment for many fans. Early signs look more positive for Battlefield 6, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-looks-great-but-it-wont-beat-call-of-duty-this-year/1100-6534282/" data-ref-id="1100-6534282">experts do not believe the game has enough juice to beat Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 this year.</a> In any event, EA is having some playful fun with the competition, recently releasing a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-live-action-trailer-pokes-fun-at-call-of-duty/1100-6535075/" data-ref-id="1100-6535075">live-action trailer for Battlefield 6 that roasts Call of Duty. </a></p><h2><strong>Battlefield 6 global launch times</strong></h2><p><strong>October 10</strong></p><ul><li>8 AM PT</li><li>11 AM ET</li><li>9 AM CST</li><li>12 PM BRT</li><li>4 PM BST</li><li>5 PM CEST</li><li>6 PM EEST</li></ul><p><strong>October 11</strong></p><ul><li>12 AM JST</li><li>1 AM AEST</li></ul><h2>Battlefield 6 preload times</h2><p><strong>October 3</strong></p><ul><li>8 AM PT</li><li>11 AM ET</li><li>9 AM CST</li><li>12 PM BRT</li><li>4 PM BST</li><li>5 PM CEST</li><li>6 PM EEST</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-times-seemingly-revealed-and-there-is-no-early-access/1100-6535079/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyper Light Drifter studio's next game is a cyberpunk metroidvania with Smash Bros-inspired combat, out next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/hyper-light-drifter-studios-next-game-is-a-cyberpunk-metroidvania-with-smash-bros-inspired-combat-out-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyper-light-drifter-studios-next-game-is-a-cyberpunk-metroidvania-with-smash-bros-inspired-combat-out-next-month.1311499/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Will it be possessing your time?</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/POSSESSOR(S)-Gameplay-Overview-_-PS5-and-PC-on-November-11-2-48-screenshot-(1).png?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Heart Machine</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Heart Machine, the studio behind sci-fi Zelda-like Hyper Light Drifter, has a new metroidvania out next month called Possessor(s).</p>
<p>Publisher Devolver released a new gameplay overview trailer over the weekend revealing its PS5 and PC release date of 11th November.</p>
<p>Possessor(s) is a metroidvania (or "search action" game, as the developers are describing it) set in a quarantined cyberpunk city, with players taking the role of high school student Luca who's struck a deal with a demon.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="POSSESSOR(S) Gameplay Overview | PS5 and PC on November 11" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6la77h-t7rU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>POSSESSOR(S) Gameplay Overview | PS5 and PC on November 11</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6la77h-t7rU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6la77h-t7rU?autoplay=1" title="POSSESSOR(S) Gameplay Overview | PS5 and PC on November 11">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>POSSESSOR(S) Gameplay Overview | PS5 and PC on November 11<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6la77h-t7rU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>As with Hyper Light Drifter, the game is visually arresting, here a clean animated aesthetic as Luca explores a cityscape controlled by a corrupt energy megacorporation.</p>
<p>Combat, meanwhile, is inspired by Nintendo's Smash Bros. fighting series. Luca will be able to juggle enemies with aerial attacks, with makeshift weapons ranging from a computer mouse, to a guitar and a pair of sunglasses.</p>
<p>It's looking great, especially if it can live up to the exceptional quality of Hyper Light Drifter, though there's stiff genre competition from <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> at the moment.</p>
<p>Still, Heart Machine in January released a surprising miss with its roguelike Hyper Light Breaker that remains in early access, but has a Mixed rating on Steam. It's still being regularly updated, though, with the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hyper-light-breaker-receives-community-suggested-fixes-as-studio-acknowledges-risk-of-early-access">studio acknowledging the "risk" of early access</a>.</p>


        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/hyper-light-drifter-studios-next-game-is-a-cyberpunk-metroidvania-with-smash-bros-inspired-combat-out-next-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Goes Private After $55 Billion Acquisition By Saudi Arabia's PIF, Silver Lake & Affinity Partners]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/ea-goes-private-after-usd55-billion-acquisition-by-saudi-arabias-pif-silver-lake-and-affinity-partners</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-goes-private-after-55-billion-acquisition-by-saudi-arabias-pif-silver-lake-affinity-partners.1311478/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>"We will continue to push the boundaries of entertainment, sports, and technology"</p>
</section><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="28e11746d6d6d"><a title="Electronic Arts" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/28e11746d6d6d/electronic-arts.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: EA</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/EA-Announces-Agreement-to-be-Acquired-by-PIF-Silver-Lake-and-Affinity-Partners-for-55-Billion/default.aspx">Electronic Arts has announced</a> that it has entered an agreement to be purchased by the PIF (Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund), Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners for a staggering USD $55 billion.</p>
<p>The deal, which is expected to close in Q1 FY 2027, was confirmed earlier today, following a report last week from <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/deals/ea-private-deal-buyout-video-game-maker-808aefec?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAjGI4bh2ChypG-9gaU4qrQZFignKjZm8EjJFqEKJbszfMv0Uyk0spCKAkIGRcw%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68d6e0aa&amp;gaa_sig=Zf9usHKAPLc-xSauIbct6cEJae6QEXZDp84TM7SJsSlbIQtorAg_Hxy8OCUW_MYx6L4o8fLt5FyADejiqmwsQA%3D%3D">Bloomberg's Jason Schreier</a>. The company is most famous for its series of sports titles, <strong>The Sims</strong>, <strong>Battlefield</strong>, and for publishing BioWare's <strong>Dragon Age</strong> and <strong>Mass Effect</strong> series.</p>
<p>Notably, the deal is made up of an equity investment of $36 billion dollars, with a $20 billion dollar debt in EA's name. This, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3lzy2ieztws2w">as Schreier puts it</a>, could lead to layoffs, more monetisation, and cost-cutting measures.</p><div><figure data-videoid="zEeK-8I84eI" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zEeK-8I84eI?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zEeK-8I84eI?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zEeK-8I84eI?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed61cb68kjgyhv&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>835k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>Andrew Wilson, Chairman &amp; CEO of Electronic Arts has shared this statement on the deal:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Our creative and passionate teams at EA have delivered extraordinary experiences for hundreds of millions of fans, built some of the world’s most iconic IP, and created significant value for our business. This moment is a powerful recognition of their remarkable work.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, we will continue to push the boundaries of entertainment, sports, and technology, unlocking new opportunities. Together with our partners, we will create transformative experiences to inspire generations to come. I am more energized than ever about the future we are building.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The PIF previously owned 9.9% of the company and was already the third-largest institutional owner of EA. As a reminder, the PIF owns stakes in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/11/saudi-arabias-pif-further-reduces-its-stake-in-nintendo">Nintendo</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/02/5percent-of-capcom-acquired-by-saudi-arabias-public-investment-fund">Capcom</a>, Embracer Group, and Take-Two Interactive.</p>
<p>Turqi Alnowaiser, the PIF's Deputy Governor and Head of International Investments, says that “PIF has demonstrated a strong commitment to [global gaming and esports] sectors, and this partnership will help further drive EA’s long-term growth, while fueling innovation within the industry on a global scale.”</p>
<p>In terms of the other acquirers, Silver Lake is one of the companies potentially involved with TikTok's US spin-off, while Affinity Partners is the investment firm founded by the current US President's son-in-law, Jared Kushner.</p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/EA-Announces-Agreement-to-be-Acquired-by-PIF-Silver-Lake-and-Affinity-Partners-for-55-Billion/default.aspx" rel="noopener" href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/EA-Announces-Agreement-to-be-Acquired-by-PIF-Silver-Lake-and-Affinity-Partners-for-55-Billion/default.aspx">ir.ea.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/41fa949f597311f3bd601825857a1a29 @ 1759156607 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/ea-goes-private-after-usd55-billion-acquisition-by-saudi-arabias-pif-silver-lake-and-affinity-partners]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill f Reaches 1 Million Copies Sold Faster Than the Silent Hill 2 Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-f-reaches-1-million-copies-sold-faster-than-silent-hill-2-remake-konami/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-f-reaches-1-million-copies-sold-faster-than-the-silent-hill-2-remake.1311475/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Silent Hill f officially arrived on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S this past September 25, 2026, <a href="https://www.konami.com/games/corporate/ja/news/topics/20250929/">and according to Konami, by Sept. 26, 2025</a>, the latest entry in the Silent Hill franchise and the first one to make several big changes such as setting the game in Japan and not in the US for the first time, hit one million copies sold.</p>



<p>One million copies sold in one day is a huge milestone for what is the first new Silent Hill game in years and a continuation of the momentum that Konami was able to kickstart with the help of Bloober Team delivering above and beyond what players expected in the Silent Hill 2 Remake.</p>



<p>It took the Silent Hill 2 Remake <a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-2-remake-becomes-million-seller/">a week to hit one million copies sold</a>. Konami could have had no better endorsement in the return of its beloved horror series than to see the first brand-new entry hit the same sales milestones as a nostalgia-charged remake six days faster.</p>



<p>"<em>The remake of Silent Hill 2 released last year, surpassed one million units shipped worldwide within a week of its release, but Silent Hill f is growing in shipments at an even faster pace in each</em> <em>region, including Japan</em>," Konami writes in its announcement of the sales milestone.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>It's good to see one of the videogame industry's most influential series make such a strong return with its last two entries, but more particularly with Silent Hill f simply because it's the first brand-new game because of how many big swings and risks it takes to change things up.</p>



<p>In our review of Silent Hill f, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/silent-hill-f-review-a-beautiful-nightmare/">Wccftech's Francesco De Meo wrote</a>, "<em>With an engaging story full of haunting, disturbing sequences, a finely tuned balance of everything that makes survival horror great, and combat deeply rooted in resource management, Silent Hill f is a triumphant return for the series after its long hiatus. Its short length and minor PC performance issues may disappoint some, but no fan of the franchise, or the genre, should miss one of the best survival horror releases in years.</em>"</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-f-reaches-1-million-copies-sold-faster-than-silent-hill-2-remake-konami/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero Version 2.3 Brings Spooky Delights Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-23-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-version-2-3-brings-spooky-delights-next-month.1311472/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HoYoverse has announced the release date for the next major&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>update, and since it'll arrive not long before the spookiest day of the year, you can expect lots of creepy treats to enjoy.</p>

<p>Per a press release, Version 2.3, which will, naturally, follow on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-22-release-date" rel="nofollow">September's Version 2.2</a>, will be arriving on October 15th, bringing three brand new Agents for your team, a new map to explore, and more.</p>

<p>First and foremost, you'll be exploring the brand new Timesworn Hills area, which, as HoYoverse says, is a place where "ghost stories echo through abandoned ruins". You'll be investigating the disappearance of miners in the region, which will lead to the discovery of "unsettling truths".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-2.3-release-date-spook-shack.jpg?itok=fgIjtAP4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-2.3-release-date-spook-shack.jpg?itok=R4R73ypu 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>Version 2.3 will have you investigating miners' disappearances alongside the Spook Shack faction.</figcaption></figure><p>Naturally, you'll also be recruiting new Agents to your cause, starting with Lucia, an S-rank Ether Support Agent who can boost her allies' HP and damage, making her a valuable asset as you explore the Timesworn Hills.</p>

<p>She's joined by Yidhari, an S-Rank Ice Rupture Agent whose damage is boosted as her HP falls. You'll need to strike a balance between risk and safety if you want to maximize her damage potential.</p>

<p>Your final new Agent in&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>Version 2.3 is Komano Manato, an A-Rank Fire Rupture Agent who gains damage as his HP scales. S-Rank Agents Vivian and Ju Fufu will also be available during this update as rerun banners.</p>

<p>You can also expect a new powered-up version of Soldier 0 - Anby, who first debuted during&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-16-march" rel="nofollow">Version 1.6</a>, as well as a new turn-based combat challenge and the return of the Snap! Shining Strike photography event.</p>




<p>News of this latest&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>update comes shortly after HoYoverse announced two brand new free-to-play games being added to its lineup, namely <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hoyoverse-honkai-nexus-anima" rel="nofollow">autochess creature-collector&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hoyoverse-honkai-nexus-anima" rel="nofollow">Honkai: Nexus Anima</a>&nbsp;</em>and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hoyoverse-petit-planet-cozy-life-sim" rel="nofollow">cozy life sim&nbsp;<em>Petit Planet</em></a>.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em><a href="https://zenless.hoyoverse.com/en-us/main" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">for free right now</a> on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S, as well as mobile devices. Version 2.3 launches on October 15th across all platforms.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-23-october]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Didn’t Wait for Prime Big Deal Days, Fire TV Stick HD Is Already Down to Almost Free]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-didnt-wait-for-prime-big-deal-days-fire-tv-stick-hd-is-already-down-to-almost-free-2000629372</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-didn%E2%80%99t-wait-for-prime-big-deal-days-fire-tv-stick-hd-is-already-down-to-almost-free.1311460/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Lots of awesome movies that hit theaters over the summer have finally released to streaming. So if you missed them on the big screen, now’s your chance to see them on the small-to-medium screen. James Gunn’s take on<em> Superman&nbsp;</em>starring David Corenswet as the titular super-powered man arrived on HBO Max. There you can also check out Tim Robinson and Paul Rudd’s painfully awkward, intense, and hilarious <em>Friendship</em>. And Zach Cregger’s invigorating horror flick <em>Weapons&nbsp;</em>can now be rented from most places that offer digital on-demand. But in order to watch any of these, you’re gonna need something to stream to —something like Amazon’s Fire TV Stick. Right now, you can get one for dirt cheap. These things normally aren’t too pricey to begin with, starting at $35. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4359/">For a limited time, however, you can snag one for about half price at just $18.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4359/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>Amazon has upgraded its line of Fire TV Sticks over the years and this is the latest model, albeit, the first in the lineup. It doesn’t support 4K, and it’s still stuck back on Wi-Fi 5. While it does only stream in Full HD 1080p, most streaming service charge extra for 4K streaming to a point where they’re not even worth it. Netflix’s premium plan is now up to $25 per month. That’s more than you’re paying for the Amazon Fire TV Stick and that’s just for a single month. You’ll likely be streaming most content in regular HD anyway, so in practice, you may not even notice the difference between getting this one or shelling out for the Fire TV Stick 4K.</p>



<h2>Xbox Games Right to Your TV</h2>
<p>One big bonus of the Fire TV Stick is it now supports Xbox Game Pass Ultimate. You no longer need an Xbox console to play Xbox games. Stream games from the cloud like&nbsp;<em>Black Myth Wukong</em>, <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>, or even the newly released <em>Borderlands 4</em>. The first two are just part of Game Pass, but the latter does require you to purchase a copy.</p>
<p>If you are intrigued by the prospect of playing Xbox titles directly off the Fire TV Stick, you can consider picking up the unit bundled with a Luna Controller. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4360/">That normally goes for $105, but has also been marked down halfway to just $53</a>. You can also choose to pair a different Bluetooth controller such as the official Xbox core wireless controller. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4359/">Otherwise, just go with the standard Fire TV Stick HD, now only $18.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4359/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-didnt-wait-for-prime-big-deal-days-fire-tv-stick-hd-is-already-down-to-almost-free-2000629372]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia is taking EA private alongside other investors]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-is-taking-ea-private-alongside-other-investors</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/saudi-arabia-is-taking-ea-private-alongside-other-investors.1311451/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">September 29, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>3 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Logo via EA / Background image via PIF</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">An investor consortium that includes Saudi Arabia's state-backed Public Investment Fund (PIF) has agreed to acquire Battlefield, Apex Legends, and EA Sports FC maker Electronic Arts for $55 billion.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rumors of deal began circulating last week and have now been </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/EA-Announces-Agreement-to-be-Acquired-by-PIF-Silver-Lake-and-Affinity-Partners-for-55-Billion/default.aspx">confirmed by EA</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The U.S. publisher—which owns a number of development studios such as BioWare, DICE, Maxis, Motive, Respawn, and Criterion—has entered into a definitive agreement to be acquired by a consortium of investors that includes PIF, Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The deal will take the form of an all-cash transaction that values EA at around $55 billion. EA said the move will enable it to "accelerate innovation and growth to build the future of entertainment" while delivering "compelling value" to all stockholders.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Under the terms of the agreement, the Consortium will acquire 100 percent of EA, with PIF rolling over its existing 9.9 percent stake in the Company. EA stockholders will receive $210 per share in cash," said EA in a note to investors.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The per share purchase price represents a 25 percent premium to EA’s unaffected share price of $168.32 at market close on September 25, 2025, the last fully unaffected trading day, and a premium to EA’s unaffected all-time high of $179.01 at market close on August 14, 2025."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/silent-hill-f-has-sold-1-million-copies-worldwide" target="_self" data-discover="true">Silent Hill f has sold 1 million copies worldwide</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The transaction is expected to complete in Q1 FY27 and remains subject to regulatory and stockholder approval. If the deal closes, EA will remain headquartered in Redwood City, California, and will continue to be led by CEO Andrew Wilson.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Commenting on the deal, Wilson said the transaction—which represents the largest all-cash sponsor take-private investment in history—is a "powerful recognition" of the remarkable work of EA employees, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-allegedly-lays-off-hundreds-of-workers-after-canceling-more-games-at-respawn-entertainment">many of whom have been laid off in recent years</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our creative and passionate teams at EA have delivered extraordinary experiences for hundreds of millions of fans, built some of the world’s most iconic IP, and created significant value for our business," said Wilson.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This moment is a powerful recognition of their remarkable work. Looking ahead, we will continue to push the boundaries of entertainment, sports, and technology, unlocking new opportunities."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Human Rights Watch claims PIF has &quot;facilitated and benefited from human rights abuses&quot;">Human Rights Watch claims PIF has "facilitated and benefited from human rights abuses"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's unclear how much control PIF will have over EA post-completion, but a spokesperson for the investment fund certainly indicated it will be heavily involved moving forward.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"PIF is uniquely positioned in the global gaming and esports sectors, building and supporting ecosystems that connect fans, developers, and IP creators," said Turqi Alnowaiser, deputy governor and head of international investments at PIF.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-ea-nearing-50-billion-leveraged-buyout-deal-would-be-partly-owned-by-saudi-pif" target="_self" data-discover="true">Report: EA nearing $50 billion leveraged buyout deal, would be partly owned by Saudi PIF</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"PIF has demonstrated a strong commitment to these sectors, and this partnership will help further drive EA’s long-term growth, while fueling innovation within the industry on a global scale."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">PIF already held a 9.9 percent stake in EA, which will now be rolled over as a result of the transaction.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The sovereign wealth fund, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.pif.gov.sa/en/who-we-are/">which bills itself as a "catalyst of change" on its website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, is chaired by Saudi Arabia's de-facto ruler and crown prince Mohammed bin Salman.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-45812399">As noted by The BBC</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Mohammed bin Salman was linked to the murder of Washington Post journalist Jamal Khashoggi, who frequently criticized his policies and leadership.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Advocacy groups such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amnesty.org.uk/saudi-arabia-human-rights-raif-badawi-king-salman">Amnesty International</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hrw.org/world-report/2025/country-chapters/saudi-arabia">Human Rights Watch</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have spoken out against Mohammed bin Salman and Saudi Arabia for (among other things) attempting to control the media, restricting free speech, legally prohibiting LGBTQ+ relationships and gender expression, outlawing protests and demonstrations, and discriminating against women.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2024/11/20/saudi-arabia-public-investment-fund-linked-abuses">Human Rights Watch specifically claims PIF</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> "has facilitated and benefited directly from serious human rights abuses linked to Crown Prince Mohammed," and is being used as a tool to whitewash the country's "abysmal" human rights record.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-s-high-end-xbox-handheld-will-cost-999-in-the-united-states" target="_self" data-discover="true">Microsoft's high-end Xbox handheld will cost $999 in the United States</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">PIF has heavily invested in the video game industry directly or through subsidiaries such as Savvy Games Group. Earlier this year, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/pokemon-go-and-niantic-s-game-business-is-being-sold-to-the-saudi-state">Savvy-owned publisher Scopely</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> purchased Niantic's video game business and key franchises such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Pokemon Go</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The wealth fund also owns stakes in Nintendo, Koei Tecmo, Capcom, Nexon, and Take-Two.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-is-taking-ea-private-alongside-other-investors]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There Are No Ghosts at the Grand Preview - Fixer Upper]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/there-are-no-ghosts-at-grand-preview-fixer-upper</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-fixer-upper.1311430/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>was revealed during this year's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-games-showcase-2025-all-news-and-announcements" rel="nofollow">Xbox summer showcase</a>, and it was an instant highlight of the show for me. It's a mixture of reggae musical, renovation sim, and spooky mystery adventure game, and what's more, it's tiny UK studio Friday Sundae's first title.</p>

<p>I got a chance to sit down with a demo of the game, which showcases a slice of gameplay during which I (partially) renovated a hotel, sojourned down to a creepy abandoned island, and fought off monstrous chair-spider ghosts.</p>

<p>All of that might sound like tremendous fun, and I have faith that with a little extra time, it could be. Unfortunately, the demo I played is in serious need of some extra work before it's ready to open its doors to the public.</p>

<h2><em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>Is Ambitious as Heck</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-renovation.jpg?itok=9gMkHCD2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-renovation.jpg?itok=-kGJaHGy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand</em>'s renovation mechanics are simple, but satisfying.</figcaption></figure><p>During my time with&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand</em>'s demo, which lasts around 30 minutes, I got to experience a tasting platter showing off all three of its core pillars. It's a pretty brief demo, and I don't think it necessarily does the full scope of&nbsp;<em>No Ghosts&nbsp;</em>justice.</p>

<p>The renovation mechanics on offer here are...fine. If you're expecting the depth of something like <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/house-flipper" rel="nofollow">House Flipper</a>&nbsp;</em>or <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/powerwash-simulator" rel="nofollow"><em>PowerWash Simulator</em></a>, you're likely going to be disappointed; the systems are fairly surface-level, and they don't amount to much more than "point the right gun at the thing".</p>

<p>Still, the feelings of hoovering up loose debris or popping broken pieces of a boat back onto its hull are satisfying, and I can imagine that the areas you'll be expected to renovate will increase in complexity as you progress through the full game.</p>

<p>There's a fun little twist on the renovation mechanics whereby you need to use your house-flippin' tools to right the scenes of memories so they can progress, but again, they're not too much more than just following on-screen instructions.</p>

<p>During this demo, I didn't get much of a chance to explore <i>No Ghosts</i>' gorgeous English seaside setting, but I'm hoping that the full game will offer more incentive to wander the environs of the Grand and uncover hidden secrets. It's hard to say how well exploration and narrative will stack up since the demo is so short.</p>

<p>It's impressive that Friday Sundae is attempting to cram a reggae musical into&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>as well, but I have to say I'm a little worried about how that element is going to pan out.</p>

<p>This demo offers one brief musical sequence, which admittedly isn't anywhere near enough to express a full opinion, but the character animation feels a little too stilted for singers to express the full range of the songs' emotions.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen whether Friday Sundae's game can capitalize fully on the immense potential of incorporating musical sequences into its exploration-renovation loop, but on the strength of the song snippet presented during this demo, I'm skeptical.</p>


<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-memory.jpg?itok=s3PC3PDZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-memory.jpg?itok=UgQfltwr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I had to restart this section multiple times because of bugs.</figcaption></figure><p>Let's get one thing out of the way first: this is a demo, and it's an early one at that.&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>is not due to launch until 2026, so Friday Sundae has plenty of time to rid itself of some of the more bothersome bedbugs in its hotel's rooms.</p>

<p>That's a good thing, too, because I encountered no shortage of bugs during my time with this demo. I had to restart chapters multiple times due to game-breaking (demo-breaking?) progress bugs, and the starting position for one chapter restart in particular is halfway through the floor.</p>

<p>Performance-wise, my rig struggled with&nbsp;<em>No Ghosts&nbsp;</em>as well. This is perhaps an even more subjective criticism than any other I've offered so far, but I'm running an RX 9070 XT and a Ryzen 7 9700X (plus 64GB of RAM), which is way above the game's minimum specs.</p>

<p>Despite that, performance was iffy, with lots of slowdown and chugging in scenes that weren't even particularly busy. Not only that, but some sections stuttered and froze up for several seconds, and while they always righted themselves in the end, I constantly worried each hitch would be the point at which the demo crashed.</p>

<p>I couldn't find a way to change the graphical options beyond resolution upscaling, and changing those options didn't seem to alter performance for me at all. Again, though, I should stress that there's every chance you won't experience these issues. We all know how mercurial PC gaming can be.</p>

<p>At the end of the demo, Friday Sundae sets up an exciting escape sequence, and my support character yelled at me that there was no way I could take all of the things chasing me, so I should just "leg it", in his words (a colloquialism I appreciated seeing as a Brit).</p>

<p>However, when I then dispatched every enemy chasing me with relative ease,&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>didn't seem to know what to do, so it just kind of didn't do anything for a while before a title drop anticlimactically brought the demo to a close.</p>

<p>It was a funny moment, sure, but it also made me worried about <i>No Ghosts</i>' future. Yes, there's still lots of time for Friday Sundae to fix it, but I'm not sure this demo was ready for release, at least not in my eyes. This one's going to need a lot more time in the oven.</p>

<h2><em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand&nbsp;</em>Preview | Final Thoughts</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-petting.jpg?itok=PQaRA2Oy 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/there-are-no-ghosts-at-the-grand-preview-petting.jpg?itok=--oLLint 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The cat is very, very cute.</figcaption></figure><p>I'm really rooting for Friday Sundae and&nbsp;<em>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand</em>. The genre mixture on offer here is so unique and so mad that I want nothing more than for this game to launch and blow me away.</p>

<p>Sadly, on the strength of this demo, I think it's got a very long way to go before it can achieve that. It's messy, janky, and glitchy, so it's safe to say that a lot of renovation is needed before this hotel is ready to admit guests, even for the demo itself.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>There Are No Ghosts at the Grand</strong>&nbsp;was previewed on a PC using a demo build provided by the developers. All screenshots were taken during the preview process.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/there-are-no-ghosts-at-grand-preview-fixer-upper]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill f Sales Top 1m, Outpacing Silent Hill 2 Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-f-sales-1m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-f-sales-top-1m-outpacing-silent-hill-2-remake.1311427/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Konami has announced that&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>, the latest entry in the long-running&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill&nbsp;</em>survival horror franchise, has managed to hit a major sales milestone, and it's outpacing the last big release in the series as well.</p>

<p>Per a <a href="https://www.konami.com/games/corporate/ja/news/topics/20250929/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">press release</a> (for which we're using machine translation),&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f&nbsp;</em>sales topped one million within a single day of the game's launch. Naturally, that figure includes both physical sales and digital shipments.</p>

<p>As Konami says in the press release,&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>managed to rack up a million sales <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-sales-1m" rel="nofollow">in its first week</a>, which means that&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>&nbsp;reached the same milestone significantly faster than its predecessor. Konami will doubtless take this as an encouraging sign for the franchise as a whole.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/silent-hill-f-sales-1m-kneeling.jpg?itok=KJEVVgw- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/silent-hill-f-sales-1m-kneeling.jpg?itok=uklUoOrg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The latest&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill&nbsp;</em>game,&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>, has reached a million sales already.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>went on to pass the two million sales mark <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-sales-2m" rel="nofollow">in January this year</a>, and if&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f&nbsp;</em>continues at its current pace, then it won't take the latest title in the series too long to pass its predecessor on that milestone as well.</p>

<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>, it's the latest entry in the&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill&nbsp;</em>series, although it's technically a spinoff of the main games that doesn't require any prior knowledge to enjoy.</p>

<p>Developed by Hong Kong-based studio NeoBards, the game revolves around Hinako Shimizu, a high school student who must get to the bottom of why her sleepy town of Ebisugaoka has suddenly become wreathed in fog and populated by dangerous monsters.</p>

<p>Konami's goal with&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f&nbsp;</em>was to return the franchise to its Japanese roots, hence the setting being a Japanese town rather than the more Westernized locales of prior titles.</p>




<p>News of&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f</em>'s strong sales performance will likely come as a relief to Konami; the studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/konami-bloober-team-new-silent-hill" rel="nofollow">revealed back in June</a> that it's working on a remake of the original&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill&nbsp;</em>alongside&nbsp;<em>SH2&nbsp;</em>remake developer Bloober Team.</p>

<p>While we wait for more on that, you can check out&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2947440/SILENT_HILL_f/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/silent-hill-f/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/silent-hill-f/9n5nfrqv2hqq" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-f-sales-1m]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[$55 billion EA buyout hands Madden over to investors including Saudi Arabia and Jared Kushner]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/787112/electronic-arts-55-billion-privacte-acquisition-pif-silver-lake-affinity-partners</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/55-billion-ea-buyout-hands-madden-over-to-investors-including-saudi-arabia-and-jared-kushner.1311424/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>Silver Lake, PIF, and Affinity Partners will take the gaming giant private.</p></div><div><div><p>Silver Lake, PIF, and Affinity Partners will take the gaming giant private.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2025-09-29T12:51:27+00:00">Sep 29, 2025, 12:51 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Image: Alex Castro / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTE2"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Emma Roth</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a news writer who covers the streaming wars, consumer tech, crypto, social media, and much more. Previously, she was a writer and editor at MUO.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Electronic Arts has announced it is <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250929186526/en/EA-Announces-Agreement-to-be-Acquired-by-PIF-Silver-Lake-and-Affinity-Partners-for-%2455-Billion">being acquired</a><a href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/EA-Announces-Agreement-to-be-Acquired-by-PIF-Silver-Lake-and-Affinity-Partners-for-55-Billion/default.aspx"> </a><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250929186526/en/EA-Announces-Agreement-to-be-Acquired-by-PIF-Silver-Lake-and-Affinity-Partners-for-%2455-Billion">and taken private</a> in a $55 billion deal involving Silver Lake, Saudi Arabia’s Public Investment Fund, and Affinity Partners, which is founded and led by Donald Trump’s son-in-law, Jared Kushner.</p><p>The deal is expected to close in the first fiscal quarter of 2027 and is still subject to approval by regulators and EA stockholders. If approved, it will mark one of the biggest buyouts of a publicly traded company.</p><div><blockquote><p>The transaction was approved by EA’s Board of Directors, is expected to close in Q1 FY27 and is subject to customary closing conditions, including receipt of required regulatory approvals and approval by EA stockholders. Following the close of the transaction, EA’s common stock will no longer be listed on any public market.</p><p>The transaction will be funded by a combination of cash from each of PIF, Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners as well as roll-over of PIF’s existing stake in EA, constituting an equity investment of approximately $36 billion, and $20 billion of debt financing fully and solely committed by JPMorgan Chase Bank, N.A., $18 billion of which is expected to be funded at close. Each of PIF, Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners plan to fund the equity component of the financing entirely from capital under their respective control.</p></blockquote></div><div><blockquote><p>Upon completion of the transaction, EA will remain headquartered in Redwood City, California and continue to be led by Andrew Wilson as CEO.</p></blockquote></div><p>PIF, which already holds a nearly 10 percent stake in EA and has also <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/10/us/jared-kushner-saudi-investment-fund.html">poured money</a> into Affinity Partners, also <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/1/23948992/saudi-arabia-gaming-investment">invests in other gaming giants</a> like Nintendo, Take-Two Interactive, and Capcom. The companies announced the agreement just days before EA plans to launch <em>Battlefield 6</em> on October 10th.</p><p>Like other game publishers, EA’s business has experienced some turbulence in recent months, with the company laying off staff and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/658468/ea-layoffs-respawn-entertainment-titanfall-canceled">canceling upcoming <em>Titanfall</em></a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/675923/black-panther-cancelled-cliffhanger-studios-shut-down-ea"><em>Black Panther</em> titles</a>. EA also <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/22/24349886/dragon-age-the-veilguard-didnt-meet-eas-expectations">said in January</a> that <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em> “underperformed” expectations.</p><p>“Our creative and passionate teams at EA have delivered extraordinary experiences for hundreds of millions of fans, built some of the world’s most iconic IP, and created significant value for our business. This moment is a powerful recognition of their remarkable work,” said EA CEO Andrew Wilson.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTE2"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Emma Roth</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/787112/electronic-arts-55-billion-privacte-acquisition-pif-silver-lake-affinity-partners]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Goes Private in $55 Billion Deal With PIF, Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners, Andrew Wilson to Remain as CEO]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-goes-private-in-55-billion-deal-with-pif-silver-lake-and-affinity-partners-andrew-wilson-to-remain-as-ceo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-goes-private-in-55-billion-deal-with-pif-silver-lake-and-affinity-partners-andrew-wilson-to-remain-as-ceo.1311415/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"I am more energized than ever about the future we are building."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA has confirmed it has agreed to be acquired by an investor group composed of PIF, Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners in a transaction valued at approximately $55 billion. It's the largest all-cash sponsor take-private investment in history.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Under the terms of the agreement, the group will acquire 100% of EA, with Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund (PIF) rolling over its existing 9.9% stake in the company. EA stockholders will receive $210 per share in cash. The per share purchase price represents a 25% premium to EA’s unaffected share price of $168.32 at market close on September 25, 2025, and a premium to EA’s unaffected all-time high of $179.01 at market close on August 14, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Following the close of the transaction, EA’s common stock will no longer be listed on any public market.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/09/29/gettyimages-970613584-1759148343537.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">EA boss Andrew Wilson will remain in charge of the company. Photo by Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Andrew Wilson, EA Chairman and CEO, commented: </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Our creative and passionate teams at EA have delivered extraordinary experiences for hundreds of millions of fans, built some of the world’s most iconic IP, and created significant value for our business. This moment is a powerful recognition of their remarkable work.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Looking ahead, we will continue to push the boundaries of entertainment, sports, and technology, unlocking new opportunities. Together with our partners, we will create transformative experiences to inspire generations to come. I am more energized than ever about the future we are building.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA will continue to be led by Wilson and will remain headquartered in Redwood City, California. The transaction is expected to close in Q1 FY27, subject to regulatory and stockholder approvals.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The transaction will be funded by a combination of cash from each of PIF, Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners, the latter of which is an American investment firm based in Miami, Florida, and formed in 2021 by Jared Kushner, Donald Trump's son-in-law.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Combined, the deal is for an equity investment of approximately $36 billion, and $20 billion of debt financing fully and solely committed by JPMorgan Chase Bank, N.A., $18 billion of which is expected to be funded at close. Each of PIF, Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners plan to fund the equity component of the financing entirely from capital under their respective control, the companies said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The enormous sale comes just days before EA releases Battlefield 6, a crucial launch for the company, and hot on the heels of FC 26 and Skate. EA games in development include Mass Effect at BioWare, Star Wars Jedi 3 at Respawn, and Iron Man at Motive.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg via Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-goes-private-in-55-billion-deal-with-pif-silver-lake-and-affinity-partners-andrew-wilson-to-remain-as-ceo]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>