<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 13:06:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["The Most Impressive Switch 2 Port To Date" - Digital Foundry Examines Star Wars Outlaws]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-most-impressive-switch-2-port-to-date-digital-foundry-examines-star-wars-outlaws</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-most-impressive-switch-2-port-to-date-digital-foundry-examines-star-wars-outlaws.1291437/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Gotta trace those rays</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a> is out now on the Switch 2 (a fact you might have missed thanks to last week's furore around <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>) and now the tech experts over at Digital Foundry have provided their analysis of the game's performance on Nintendo's new hardware.</p>
<p>Despite some concerns pre-launch, Outlaws is kind of a technical marvel, with Digital Foundry calling it "the most impressive Switch 2 port to date", noting that despite the console being weaker than its console siblings – including the Xbox Series S – advancements within the architecture mean that Outlaws is able to punch well above its weight.</p>
<p>Looking at image quality, DLSS allows Outlaws to output at 1440p when docked, with comparisons to the Series S more favourable than Digital Foundry has initially expected. Similarly, frame rate remains pretty consistent at 30fps throughout, though some menus actually push this up to 60fps. Cutscenes and pre-rendered videos sometimes drop a few frames here and there, but the gameplay is where it counts, and this is solid.</p>
<p>Digital Foundry also highlights some solid use of ray-tracing, while also noting that volumetric lighting and fog has been decreased slightly when compared to other consoles.</p>
<p>In a rather curious comparison doing the rounds from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@FactorofGames">Factor of Games</a> on YouTube, gameplay from the Switch 2 goes head-to-head with the Steam Deck. Context around exact performance parameters on the Steam Deck is missing, but otherwise the video demonstrates an obvious advantage for the Switch 2.</p>

<p>Overall then, it seems Outlaws is a pretty solid benchmark for what can be achieved on the Switch 2, and it seems to be an even more impressive port than launch title <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition</a>. It's a good indication of what might be achieved in the future, should developers and publishers strive to put in the work and not cut corners. Fingers crossed.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187348,187400,187479 @ 1757335503 -->
<p><em>Have you been playing Star Wars Outlaws on Switch 2? What do you make of it so far? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XlKCBGzrB1I" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XlKCBGzrB1I">youtube.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/c0958a6b8f7e4d85c307d5687f1e1f50 @ 1757336388 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-most-impressive-switch-2-port-to-date-digital-foundry-examines-star-wars-outlaws]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Legends: Z-A Preview – Another Reason to Get a Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/pokemon-legends-z-preview-another-reason-to-get-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-legends-z-a-preview-%E2%80%93-another-reason-to-get-a-switch-2.1291434/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I remember being fairly interested in what Game Freak was doing with its first stab at <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/pokemon-legends-arceus" rel="nofollow"><em>Pokemon Legends: Arceus</em></a>. It was a whole new way to play with Pocket Monsters, but dodgy frame rates and a repetitive rhythm lulled me away from really enjoying it.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, it had a certain quality that a lot of first tries have in this industry: it fell a little flat for me, but there was lots of potential for a sequel to really knock it out of the park. So I knew I had to try <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A </em>while at PAX West.</p>

<p>The show floor demo was played on a Nintendo Switch 2, and it showcased two parts of the game: Battle Zones and a story encounter against a Mega Absol. After about 20 minutes with the game, I walked away from that demo excited for <em>Pokemon</em> like I was a kid waiting for <em>Pokemon Diamond </em>and <em>Pearl</em>&nbsp;again.</p>



<h2>Battle Zones Put the Focus on Trainers</h2>

<p>The first 10 minutes in the Battle Zone reminded me of a huge factor that I felt was missing from <em>Arceus</em>: trainer battles. Most of my memories with <em>Arceus </em>were roaming around wide open spaces, throwing balls at wild Pokemon with the occasional battle punctuated throughout.</p>

<p>In a Battle Zone, it's all about fighting opposing trainers. You can sneak up on their Pokemon by sending yours out from behind, giving you an advantage in the ensuing fight.</p>



<p lang="EN-US" paraeid="{773212e2-ce74-4f72-bc73-72ccdcf9ce45}{111}" paraid="115263152" xml:lang="EN-US">This time around, too, the old-school turn-based battles are no more. Everything is in real time now. You aim at an enemy while holding down a shoulder button, and all the face buttons are mapped to your Pokemon's abilities.</p>

<p>There were no agile or strong mode inputs from what I could see. Instead, each individual ability was on a cooldown, and as you'd expect, weaker attacks tend to cool down faster than others. I found myself settling into a rhythm of which attacks to rotate through, trying to minimize downtime as much as possible.</p>

<p>If you're in a poor matchup, you can quickly swap to another Pokemon by using the D-pad. It all felt seamless thanks to not having to pause the game, and the real-time menuing felt snappy and convenient.</p>



<h2>Living It Up in Lumiose City</h2>

<p><em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em> is set entirely in Lumiose City, the large city from <em>Pokemon X</em> and <em>Y</em>. When I first learned that, my immediate worry was performance. The Switch, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/2017-was-magical-year-for-nintendo" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">as amazing as that system is</a>, was starting to feel its age in recent years.</p>

<p>Luckily, the demos for <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A </em>ran on the Switch 2, and all my fears disappeared. Running around the Battle Zone was smooth as butter, and it looked pretty good to boot.</p>

<p>As a city boy, I always love when a game brings an entire urban landscape to life, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/marvels-spider-man-2-review-2-spider-man-1-furious" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">like the&nbsp;<em>Spider-Man </em>games</a>. So I'm excited to see Pokemon's take on it, especially with the power of the Switch 2.</p>



<p>The final leg of the demo involved a boss fight with a rogue Mega Absol, which was provided a bit of story context. It seems there's some mysterious reason these random Mega Evolutions are happening, and in true Pokemon fashion, you're randomly roped into stopping them.</p>

<p>In the demo I played, the protagonist didn't have a Mega Ring at first, so this Mega Absol could be one of the early ones we'll run into in the full game.</p>



<p>The fight itself felt a bit like the bosses in <em>Arceus</em>, where the trainer themself has to dodge a bunch of attacks. However, this time around, instead of throwing weird items at them, you're ordering your Pokemon to do attacks.</p>

<p>An extra layer of strategy I enjoyed is that my Lucario had Protect mapped as one of its abilities. Using it at just the right time so it didn't take damage from a large area-of-effect attack felt so satisfying, in a way I wouldn't expect from a Pokemon game.</p>

<p>Overall, the boss fight wasn't difficult, but there were just enough plates spinning that it remained engaging throughout, which is more than I can say for my experience with some games in the franchise's past. Hopefully that momentum remains in the full release.</p>



<h2><em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em> Preview – Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Pokemon is a franchise I've learned to temper my expectations with. The level of fun I had with it as a kid probably won't match whatever I'm looking for as an adult. However, <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em> could be the game that makes me second guess that lesson.</p>

<p>I had so much fun with the little time I spent with it, and it instantly became something I'm looking forward to playing on my Switch 2. I hope the story remains interesting the long-term, but even if not, roaming around Lumiose City holds a lot of promise for me.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Pokemon Legends: Z-A </strong>was previewed on a Nintendo Switch 2 at PAX West.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Robert Scarpinito is the Features Editor of TechRaptor. With a Bachelor of Arts in Journalism from the Ohio State University, sharing compelling stories is… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/robert-scarpinito">More about Robert</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/pokemon-legends-z-preview-another-reason-to-get-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battle of Hoth Review - Ice Cold Fun]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/battle-of-hoth-review-ice-cold-fun</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battle-of-hoth-review-ice-cold-fun.1291431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>AT-AT's stomp on the hard-packed ice of Hoth, shaking the ground and rattling the hidden bunkers underneath. Meanwhile, hordes of brave Rebel soldiers burst from the snow, sending torrents of well-aimed blaster fire. Does the fate of the galaxy hinge on this pivotal battle? It does when you and your friends pick up a copy of&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth</em>, a new strategic board game from Days of Wonder. Asmodee USA sent me a copy to check out, so let's fire up our snow-speeders and jump right in.</p>

<h2>What Is&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth</em>?</h2>

<p><em>Battle of Hoth</em>&nbsp;is a strategic skirmish board game for two players (with a team-mode to allow for three to four players), with one player taking on the role of the Rebel Alliance and the other taking on the Imperial army. The objective of the game is (usually, though there are many different scenarios to play through) being the first to claim a set amount of victory medals by meeting a specific scenario's victory conditions.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-board.jpg?itok=Q6-GASz3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-board.jpg?itok=byl1tAD0 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>To do so, you'll assign orders to your forces around the board, roll dice to attack, and attempt to out-pace and out-think your opponent in this quick strategic game. Each scenario instructs players on how to set up the board, placing their units onto the battlefield as well as terrain hexes that alter the environment.</p>

<h2>Activating Activations</h2>

<p>I really like the way activating units is handled in this game. Instead of issuing order tokens, or secretly selecting units from your battlefield, you'll play a Command card from a hidden hand you draw. And the command cards (except for special leader cards) break up the battlefield into thirds.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-command-card.jpg?itok=IsloiLGK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-command-card.jpg?itok=vruOD9mj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>In this example, the Rebel player has played the command card seen on the board, meaning they can activate two units in the left shaded quadrant.</figcaption></figure><p>Your Command card may say you can activate two units in the middle of the board, or one on each of the left and ride sides of the board, or some other combination. I find this approach to the game extremely engaging, as I have to both work with what I've got on the board&nbsp;<em>and</em>&nbsp;decide which of my Command cards to use, and which to save.</p>

<h2>A Fast-Paced Blast</h2>

<p>One of the first things that caught my attention with&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth</em>&nbsp;is how little time it takes to actually set up the game and get rolling. Before I even opened the box, I admit I was expecting some hulking behemoth full of cards, rulebooks, miniatures, and tokens galore. But that's not the case with&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth</em>, with only a slim rulebook, a straight-to-the-action scenario book, 19 double-sided terrain hexes, 6 attack die, and miniatures for each side (the Rebels get 35 minis, and the Imperials get 39).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-rebel-minis.jpg?itok=Vaf846dt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-rebel-minis.jpg?itok=rzpKtTWr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The three types of Rebel miniatures included in the game.</figcaption></figure><p>Playing the game, I was equally surprised at how nicely it moved along. You move your units, roll dice to attack, and before you know it you're scoring hits, removing enemy units, and getting closer and closer to your goal of four victory points (or more or less, depending on scenario).</p>

<p>You achieve these victory medals by completely eliminating an enemy unit (though some scenarios may offer extra or different ways to achieve victory medals).</p>

<p>So what this creates is a truly feeling of chaotic warfare on the battlefield, with snow-speeders zooming around, AT-AT's lumbering through the battlefield, and hordes of little dudes running around trying to pick each other off. Aside from some of the more complicated scenarios, you'll be done a standard scenario within 35-45 minutes. That's fast for a strategy wargame!</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-imperial-minis.jpg?itok=RRq71tI7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-imperial-minis.jpg?itok=n_QD63Cz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The three types of Imperial Miniatures available in the game.</figcaption></figure><h2>Deeper Than It Seems</h2>

<p>I'm doing a lot of praising the game's speed and simplicity, but it certainly is deeper than it seems. As I mentioned above, the Command card activations are a fun and engaging way to mobilize troops. Add to that the ability to slightly customize your deck by choosing a commander, and it's almost like a mini-game within the game.</p>

<p>The dice-resolution is great fun on this too, with custom symbols on the dice representing a soldier silhouette, a mechanical gear, and a starburst. To hit your opponent's unit, you have to get the proper symbols. Starbursts hit everything, but the other two symbols matter: you can only hit troops with a soldier silhouette and snow speeders and AT-AT's with the gear (probe droids and rebel artillery can&nbsp;<em>only</em>&nbsp;be hit with the starbursts).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-dice-roll.jpg?itok=TnM6ZC7a 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-dice-roll.jpg?itok=xB5nQv1U 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>In this scenario, the Rebel player has rolled their three dice to attack the Imperial Unit. The blue symbol and the yellow starburst are both hits, so two Imperial minis would be removed from this unit.</figcaption></figure><p>And then there's the Scenario Book, which contains 18 different scenarios to play through - from a first assault on an Imperial Scouting mission to defending the shield generators, medevac'ing important officers out of the field, and a final mass showdown called "Assault on Hoth," there's just so much game in here.</p>

<h2><em>Battle of Hoth -&nbsp;</em>Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>You don't have to be a&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em>&nbsp;fan to find a lot to love in&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth -&nbsp;</em>though I assume many <em>will</em>&nbsp;with its focus on the classic&nbsp;<em>Empire</em>&nbsp;set piece. With its fast-paced gameplay and pick-up-and-play rules, this might be one of the cleanest introductions to strategy wargaming I've ever played. Using simple, intuitive dice-roll mechanics, easy unit movement rules, and few other "Yes... but!" clauses that can clog up the gameplay, what we get is a clean, well-oiled machine of a strategy skirmish game that prioritizes player fun over fussiness.</p>

<p>Highly, highly recommended - get out there and give it a try for yourself!</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of&nbsp;</em>Battle of Hoth<em>&nbsp;used in the creation of this review was provided for us by Asmodee USA.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Giaco Furino joined the TechRaptor team as a Staff Writer in 2019 after searching for a dedicated place to write and talk about Tabletop Games. In 2020, he… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/giaco-furino">More about Giaco</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/battle-of-hoth-review-ice-cold-fun]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roku Clears Out Its Streaming Stick Plus 2025 at Nearly Free, While Amazon Fire TV Stick Stays Full Price]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/roku-clears-out-its-streaming-stick-plus-2025-at-nearly-free-while-amazon-fire-tv-stick-stays-full-price-2000623465</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roku-clears-out-its-streaming-stick-plus-2025-at-nearly-free-while-amazon-fire-tv-stick-stays-full-price.1291422/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>How old is the TV in your living room? Is it absent of any smart features and streaming apps? Or maybe it is a smart TV, but you’re just not a fan of that particular manufacturer’s user interface (I’m looking at you LG with your wannabe Wiimote motion controls). You don’t need to be locked down to whatever your TV was capable of just out of the box. Pick up a Roku streaming stick for basically nothing and now you’ve got an intuitive, reliable way to stream content and navigate the apps. Usually, you can find<strong> the 2025 Roku Streaming Stick Plus with 4K and HDR support</strong> for $40. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/">However, right now Amazon is running a limited time deal that’s bringing its price down by 27% to just $29.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Jump Right In</h2>
<p>With a Roku streaming stick, you’ll have access to tons of different apps like Netflix, Hulu, and HBO Max (or whatever they’re deciding to call it this week). Customize the home screen to your preferences, putting the apps you use most frequently front and center. You’ll even be able to watch a good handful of Roku originals at absolutely no added cost. The service has shows like <em>Dinner Budget Showdown</em>,&nbsp;<em>Celebrity Family Food Battle</em>,&nbsp;<em>Martha Cooks</em>,&nbsp;<em>Emeril Cooks</em><em>,&nbsp;</em>and I’m sure a bunch of other stuff that aren’t cooking shows.</p>



<p>This streaming stick from Roku is capable of streaming content in 4K resolution and in HDR, so you won’t be sacrificing any image quality by making the jump from your 4K HDR TV’s interface to the more user-friendly Roku Plus. The streaming stick can even by synced up with your TV so it automatically turns on and off with one press. You can even control volume and navigate your Roku all with just the one remote. It even has a voice buttons which makes searching for your favorite TV shows or movies even easier. Just hold the button, say, “<em>My Cousin Vinny</em>,” and the next thing you know, you’ll be watching Marisa Tomei bang her foot on the ground as her biological clock ticks <em>like this</em>.</p>
<p>The Roku Streaming Stick Plus is designed to be unobtrusive. It’s compact form factor doesn’t block any other neighboring HDMI inputs. It’s powered by USB-A so you can just plug that end of it right back into your TV to run it. The whole thing will stay out of sight and you’ll avoid and extra cable running out, adding to the clutter.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/">Right now, you can grab the Roku Streaming Stick Plus for nearly 30% off for a limited time.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/roku-clears-out-its-streaming-stick-plus-2025-at-nearly-free-while-amazon-fire-tv-stick-stays-full-price-2000623465]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Day 1 Patch 'Does a Lot,' Randy Pitchford Says, but Don't Expect Miracles From Older PC Hardware]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-day-1-patch-does-a-lot-randy-pitchford-says-but-dont-expect-miracles-from-older-pc-hardware</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-day-1-patch-does-a-lot-randy-pitchford-says-but-dont-expect-miracles-from-older-pc-hardware.1291410/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Gearbox development chief Randy Pitchford has said the inbound Borderlands 4 Day 1 patch “does a lot,” amid concern about the performance of the looter shooter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pitchford responded to concern about Borderlands 4’s pre-release performance on PC from some users on <a href="https://x.com/DuvalMagic/status/1964424122861064640" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X / Twitter</a>, confirming not only that there’s a Day 1 patch on the way, but that it sounds pretty much essential to play the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Borderlands 4 has an official release date of September 12 across PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, and PC via Steam and the Epic Games Store, with the Nintendo Switch 2 launch following shortly after. Fans will be keen to jump in as soon as possible, making the Day 1 patch an early hoop to jump through.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite the Day 1 patch, playing Borderlands 4 on older hardware won't miraculously unlock "buttery smooth performance," Pitchford added. It should be expected that Borderlands 4 is “unplayable” if you’re trying to use a PC below min-spec, he said, and, generally, playing new AAA games on older hardware won't achieve impressive results.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the comment in full:</p><blockquote>The Day 1 patch does a lot! That said, the expectation for using a below min-spec machine should be that the game is unplayable. That the game runs at all on your system is a miracle. That you can get 55 - 60 fps out of heavy combat is actually incredible given how the engine and what's going on under the hood. Your specification doesn't indicate if you're on SDD or HDD, but that could also explain some of the hitching. It's a big, bold, new, seamless world and I'm sorry to say that older hardware may not provide buttery smooth performance for the latest gen AAA games, as has always been the case since the dawn of PC gaming.</blockquote><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Borderlands 4 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">A significant portion of the PC gaming audience play on low-end hardware. Indeed, just last month the developers of Battlefield 6 told <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-dev-says-a-significant-number-of-users-played-the-game-below-the-minimum-recommended-specs-as-ea-points-to-the-importance-of-weaker-hardware" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eurogamer</a> they saw a "substantial number" of open beta players on or around the minimum recommended specs, with a number of users even playing below the minimum spec.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While you wait for Borderlands 4 to launch, be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/on-borderlands-3-in-our-worst-hours-it-sometimes-felt-like-parody-gearbox-explains-borderlands-4s-more-grounded-story">IGN’s recent interview</a> with narrative director Sam Winkler, lead writer Taylor Clark, and managing director of narrative properties Lin Joyce to learn more about why the team decided to create a more grounded story this time around.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-day-1-patch-does-a-lot-randy-pitchford-says-but-dont-expect-miracles-from-older-pc-hardware]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Edge of Memories Gamescom Hands-On Preview – Not Visions of Mana, But in a Good Way]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/edge-of-memories-gamescom-hands-on-preview-not-visions-of-mana-but-in-a-good-way/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/edge-of-memories-gamescom-hands-on-preview-%E2%80%93-not-visions-of-mana-but-in-a-good-way.1291392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Although the excellent Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 was the first taste of a JRPG not developed by a Japanese studio for many, the game developed by Sandfall Interactive is hardly the first JRPG developed by a French team. Years ago, Midgar Studio released <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/edge-of-eternity/">Edge of Eternity</a>, a solid open-world JRPG inspired by series like Final Fantasy and Xenogears, combining a vast world with a strategic turn-based combat system that made the experience rather remarkable, even with some of its issues. Years after work on the game has been completed, Midgar Studio is set to continue their franchise with <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/edge-of-memories/">Edge of Memories</a>, a very different game than its predecessor but one that fans of certain types of action role-playing games will want to keep their eyes on.</p>



<p>During this year's <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/gamescom-2025/">Gamescom</a>, I had the chance to briefly try out the game while speaking with Jérémy Zeler-Maury, Midgar Studio founder and CEO, who showed the same passion he did when I met him back in 2016 for an early look at Edge of Eternity. As soon as I picked up the controller to explore a world ravaged by a mysterious plague known as the Corrosion in the role of the Soul Whisperer Eline, I couldn't help but notice the extreme similarities the game developed by Midgar Studio has with last year's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/visions-of-mana-ps5/">Visions of Mana</a>. According to the Midgar Studio CEO, I wasn't the only one to do so, as, when Square Enix revealed the new entry in the Mana series, many told him they thought it was Edge of Memories that had been revealed. While these similarities are inevitably going to impact the game's reception, and wrongly, as Edge of Memories has been in development long before Visions of Mana got announced, the uncertain future of the Square Enix series could definitely benefit the game, as, aside from a similar, colorful art direction, the Midgar Studio title definitely seems more involving, especially in combat.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>Edge of Memories looks a lot like Visions of Mana, but don't let appearances deceive you.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>While my time with Edge of Memories was short, the demo did an excellent job highlighting some exploration and traversal mechanics, which require players to use the proper elemental powers to open up the way, and some light platforming segments that often take advantage of these mechanics. What was really striking besides the implementation of these mechanics was the nice sense of scale the world, and the fact that I was able to get to any location which looked interesting enough from a distance, although, given the short time and the focused demo, this may not be a thing in the final release.</p>



<p>It's in the combat mechanics, however, that Edge of Memories sets itself apart more from Visions of Mana. Fighting enemies in the Midgar Studio game is considerably more involving, with multiple combo strings, skills sets that can be switched on the fly, and a general more action-oriented feel which aims to recreate the feel of NieR Automata, as Jeremy pointed out as I was trying to take down a boss with multiple targets launching area of effect attacks whose range was highlighted by red circles on the ground, in the vein of modern Mana series games. Not having had a lot of time to delve into these systems, I cannot say if Edge of Memories will feature the same combo freedom as the PlatinumGames-developed title, but controlling Eline felt smooth enough to make combat enjoyable even with minimal knowledge of the game's intricacies.</p>



<p>With Nacon publishing the game after acquiring Midgar Studio in 2022, Edge of Memories won't have to go through an Early Access period when it launches sometime next year on PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S. I hope the game will launch sooner rather than later, as I am excited to see what else it will have to offer, and if it will be as good as the short Gamescom demo suggested.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/edge-of-memories-gamescom-hands-on-preview-not-visions-of-mana-but-in-a-good-way/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guy Who Tried To Fight Nintendo Piracy Lawsuit Without A Lawyer Will Now Pay $2 Million]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-lawsuit-modding-switch-2-ryan-daly-2000623984</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/guy-who-tried-to-fight-nintendo-piracy-lawsuit-without-a-lawyer-will-now-pay-2-million.1291389/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Mario as a lawyer.</span> © Nintendo / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Nintendo’s war against modders and ROM distributors has seen some brutal takedowns over the years, <a href="https://kotaku.com/bowser-agrees-to-pay-nintendo-10-million-in-hacking-la-1848172917">dishing out extraordinary punishments</a> against those who make it possible for people to pirate Nintendo games. The latest to fall afoul of the Japanese behemoth is Ryan Daly, who for the longest time looked like he was attempting an incredibly optimistic and clearly naive attempt to fight back. That’s over now as the MIG switch modder has settled for $2 million and an agreement to never touch a mod again in his life.</p> <p>Ryan “Homebrew Homie” Daly had run Modded Hardware, a site that sold modded Switches able to install homebrew or pirated versions of Switch games, and sold the tools with which others could do the same. Nintendo also claimed the site would return Switches with pirated games pre-installed. Back in March 2024, Nintendo threatened to sue Daly over the site, and the two parties agreed that Daly would stop his naughty behavior and the whole thing would go away. Daly said he would, then absolutely didn’t. So in June, Nintendo went to court.</p> <p>Daly continued to make surprising choices. Rather than rush to settle, the entrepreneur instead opted to respond to the complaint denying all wrongdoing, and even more wildly, did this without the advice of any lawyers. He even denied being responsible for the Modded Hardware business.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000623987" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000623987"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000623987">© Modded Hardware / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/modded-hardware-defendant-denies-nintendos-copyright-claims-in-court-241006/">As reported by&nbsp;<em>TorrentFreak</em></a>, Daly’s <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/images/daly-response.pdf">response</a> wasn’t exactly stunning legal work. He essentially quoted the accusations and wrote “ANSWER: Denied” underneath them. However, despite all the denials of having done the things, Daly added “affirmative defenses” of the very things he was saying he didn’t do, defenses which included fair use and even accusing Nintendo of a “lack of unclean hands,” a legal doctrine that suggests Nintendo had acted unethically or dishonestly.</p> <p>Well, surprisingly enough this didn’t work out so well. This weekend the Seattle District Court <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.wawd.336725/gov.uscourts.wawd.336725.30.0.pdf">released the details of a settlement</a>, in which Daly agrees to pay Nintendo $2 million, as well as hand over the URL of his site, and even agrees to the seizure of all his technology that might contain the means to infringe the agreement. It also comes with the most astonishingly strict list of requirements based on what Daly is and isn’t allowed to do for the rest of his life, which goes on for pages and pretty much amounts to never touching another MIG switch or modding tool so long as he lives.</p> <p>Whether Daly can afford to pay the $2 million is largely irrelevant to Nintendo. The company <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-gary-bowser-hacking-case-legal-jail-xecuter-1850346297">gleefully bankrupted Gary Bowser</a> over his association with a ROM-selling site in 2021, with a $10 million ruling the man will never be able to pay off, along with a gruesome 40-month prison sentence.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-lawsuit-modding-switch-2-ryan-daly-2000623984]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Airline-Friendly 10,000mAh Power Bank Is Priced Like Peanuts, and It Has 83,000 Five-Star Ratings]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-airline-friendly-10000mah-power-bank-is-priced-like-peanuts-and-it-has-83000-five-star-ratings-2000623986</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-airline-friendly-10-000mah-power-bank-is-priced-like-peanuts-and-it-has-83-000-five-star-ratings.1291386/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It’s always frustrating when your phone dies in the middle of the day when you need it. From trying to order a ride to checking emails or just browsing something to pass the time, running low on battery can spoil it all. If you’d rather never have to go through that again, the solution is simple: grab a decent power bank.</p>
<p>But hold up — not all of these are worth your money. Some charge like they’re trying to break records, some suck their batteries dry too fast, and most are just too bulky to lug around. That’s where Anker enters the scene with a 10,000mAh model that’s our absolute favorite: And <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3966/">now that Amazon sells it for just $19, reduced from its original price of $26, there’s never been a better time to grab one and add it to your day kit</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3966/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Our Fav Power Bank</h2>
<p><strong>Anker PowerCore 10K has a 10,000mAh capacity</strong> which is more than enough to charge <strong>most smartphones two or three times from one recharge</strong>. That’s to say you can go out all day without needing to worry about keeping your phone charged. It also works with tablets such as an iPad, so it’s not just on your phone. As <strong>airplane-friendly as well</strong>, you can even leave it in your carry-on bag without worrying about restrictions.</p>
<p>With Anker’s PowerIQ and VoltageBoost technology, <strong>it charges up to 5V/3A</strong>&nbsp;so you’re not waiting around for hours just to have your phone return to a decent battery level. That means charging for the briefest moment can provide you with a genuine boost, something that’s handy if you’re in transit with not much stopping time to refuel. And with<strong> both USB-C in and out and a traditional USB-A port</strong>, it supports both newer and older cables and gives you flexibility regardless of the daily device you’re working with.</p>



<p>With a size about the width of a smartphone, it easily fits into a pocket, small purse or backpack without adding bulk. You won’t wince lugging it around like with some of those other larger battery packs that are brick-like. It still packs enough juice in it to keep you powered up without sacrificing size, which is the reason so many swear by it for daily use and travel.</p>
<p><span>This deal feels like one of those no-brainers that should be grabbed before it disappears: You’re essentially getting travel-ready security for your phone or tablet at a price lower than most cases, and it’s backed by one of the most trusted names in charging.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3966/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-airline-friendly-10000mah-power-bank-is-priced-like-peanuts-and-it-has-83000-five-star-ratings-2000623986]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Candy Rangers launches October 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/candy-rangers-launches-october-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/candy-rangers-launches-october-2.1291374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>On-rails <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,248 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Candy Rangers [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/candy-rangers">Candy Rangers</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,320 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,859 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,321 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,167 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,629 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,174 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2787680/Candy_Rangers/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on October 2, publisher <a title="Companies > JanduSoft [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/jandusoft">JanduSoft</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Mechano [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mechano">Mechano</a> announced. <span id="more-990394"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2787680/Candy_Rangers/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Race against time in this brand new on-rails shooter where you control four characters at once!</p><p>Meet Candy, Mint, Lemon, and Plum, quadruplets that live together and work as rangers to fight creatures that come in to ruin the natural environments of the city.</p><p>In this game, enemies will come in waves in different formations and arrangements, luckily for you, each character’s has its own special gun with its own shooting pattern to help you take them out as efficiently as possible!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Candy</strong> – Candy can shoot bullets sideways.</li><li><strong>Mint</strong> – Mint can shoot them vertically.</li><li><strong>Plum</strong> – Plum shoots them back and forth.</li><li><strong>Lemon</strong> – Lemon’s bullets can clear diagonal patterns.</li></ul><p>Make good use of each one of them to clear levels as efficiently as possible!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Four playable worlds and two extra.</li><li>Four playable characters.</li><li>Over five languages supported.</li><li>Single-player.</li><li>Multiple items to collect that will let you unlock new paths.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Candy Rangers - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4A7fveAQ_qY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/candy-rangers-launches-october-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpongeBob SquarePants: Titans of the Tide Preview – Spectral starfish and sponge]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/08/spongebob-squarepants-titans-of-the-tide-preview-spectral-starfish-and-sponge/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spongebob-squarepants-titans-of-the-tide-preview-%E2%80%93-spectral-starfish-and-sponge.1291356/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>There’s always a fondness for the games and the franchises that we grew up with, and while the SpongeBob SquarePants games of the early 2000s weren’t exactly gaming haute couture, the underwater denizens of Bikini Bottom have enjoyed a resurgence of popularity in recent times, helped along by internet memes and new seasons of the show. After the<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/07/03/spongebob-squarepants-battle-for-bikini-bottom-rehydrated-review/"> Battle for Bikini Bottom –&nbsp;Rehydrated</a> remake in 2020, and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/01/30/spongebob-squarepants-the-cosmic-shake-review/">The Cosmic Shake</a> in 2023, we now have SpongeBob SquarePants: Titans of the Tide coming in a few months time.</p>
<p><iframe title="SpongeBob SquarePants: Titans of the Tide | Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B_DRlBipcHY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>A Paddy Shack tussle between King Neptune and the Flying Dutchman goes awry, with SpongeBob and Patrick caught in the crossfire and… well, they get totally deadified, just as ghosts are unleashed across the realms. Still, it’s up to them to save Bikini Bottom, and as they journey across the sea’s many regions and try to get these two grumpy old men to make up. Luckily, there’s just enough life between them to have one of Patrick or SpongeBob kept in corporeal form at a time, with the strength of their friendship and their BFF rings allowing them to swap back and forth in a flash.</p>


<p>That’s right, Patrick is a playable character in this game and is now pretty much an equal to SpongeBob. They both have their own specific abilities, with Patrick able to use a grapple to grab enemies or objects and then throw them, as well as to dive under the ground and quickly burrow around. SpongeBob, meanwhile, has a classic butt stomp and a dash kick.</p>


<p>This gives them some pretty distinct differences and uses when exploring the levels and getting into scuffles with enemies. When facing off against an enemy that launches explosives, SpongeBob has to time a dash kick to turn those explosives back at an enemy, while Patrick can grapple to grab, and then just chuck them back. Of course, you can also just avoid the explosives and go and whale on the enemy to eventually batter them into submission!</p>
<p>But really, this switching mechanic will be great for raising the skill ceiling of the game, potentially making this a speedrunner’s dream. Some of the game challenges, like the more abstract levels of the Plankton Portal Challenges, and trickiest paths in regular levels will need you to switch back and forth, making use of both their abilities in quick succession to get through them. This is still a kids game, though, so you will still be able to complete it and get a full experience without mastering technical button timings, but it’s still great to see this.</p>

<p>Speaking of the levels, the adventure will take you to places like Neptune’s Palace, Atlantic City, Mount Bikini and beyond, and there will be some surprising transformations along the way. Jellyfish Fields, for example, is now all snowed in which… well, it doesn’t make much sense for under the water, but let’s just go with it?</p>
<p>Levels are designed to be more open this time around and really encourage exploration and trying out both sets of abilities. There’s more of a collectathon vibe to the game with hidden chests that will contain currency, costumes, and memorabilia from the adventure that will go back to fill out parts of The Floating Patty, a new restaurant that floats above the sea surface.</p>
<p>After The Cosmic Shake played it a bit too safe as a follow up to Rehydrated, expanding the gameplay with Patrick as a foil to SpongeBob is a great way to inject new life into the series. All of this should be sea shanties to the ears of fans of SpongeBob video games, both young and not-so-young.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/08/spongebob-squarepants-titans-of-the-tide-preview-spectral-starfish-and-sponge/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Cronos: The New Dawn (Switch 2) - Strong Story Elevates Otherwise Safe Survival Horror]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/cronos-the-new-dawn</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-cronos-the-new-dawn-switch-2-strong-story-elevates-otherwise-safe-survival-horror.1291353/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Cronos: The New Dawn Review - Screenshot 1 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158541/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure><p>In the run-up to the launch of Bloober Team’s new IP, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cronos-the-new-dawn">Cronos: The New Dawn</a>, chances are you saw one or two (or ten) comparisons to EA’s <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps3/dead_space">Dead Space</a> series. And yes, while there are definitely some similarities between the two, I’d feel more comfortable describing Cronos as an amalgamation of nearly every major survival horror game ever released.</p>
<p>This is both good and bad. In one sense, Cronos is the quintessential survival horror, taking all the best elements from <strong>Resident Evil</strong>, <strong>Silent Hill</strong>, <strong>Alone in the Dark</strong>, and the aforementioned Dead Space, making for an experience that genre fans will relish. On the other hand, it never really attempts anything new to call its own, and although its setting and story certainly elevate it, there’s little here that hasn’t already been done elsewhere.</p>
<p>Taking place primarily within the ruined city of New Dawn, which itself is based upon the historical district of Nowa Huta in Kraków, you take on the role of The Traveler tasked with locating rifts within the world to travel back in time to the 1980s. There, she must extract the ‘essence’ of individuals who perished during a devastating event known as The Change in which humans morphed into grotesque monsters called Orphans.</p>
<figure><a title="Cronos: The New Dawn Review - Screenshot 2 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158533/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Cronos’ narrative is undoubtedly the game’s strongest aspect. It presents a consistently intriguing mystery, withholding enough crucial information while giving you <em>just</em> the right amount to keep you invested. Like all great survival horrors, a lot of the backstory is found within the environment, with messages hastily scrawled upon walls, journals revealing more personal struggles during The Change, and government notices urging solidarity in the face of extinction. It’s cool stuff, and I sincerely hope the game does well enough to warrant a sequel or prequel – there’s definitely potential.</p>
<p>The Traveler is also a surprisingly compelling protagonist, though I could understand if some folks don’t gel with her. She’s all business, with a cold, detached, almost robotic demeanour, albeit one that occasionally falters as she begins to struggle with hallucinations. She often comments on her surroundings, and it’s exactly how I imagine Samus would verbally record data as she’s traversing Zebes or Tallon IV… y’know, if you ignore her portrayal in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/metroid_other_m">Metroid: Other M</a>. If you’ve played HouseMarque’s PS5 exclusive <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/returnal">Returnal</a>, you could also draw favourable comparisons with Selene Vassos.</p>
<figure><a title="Cronos: The New Dawn Review - Screenshot 3 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158538/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Gameplay is the classic survival horror combination of combat and puzzle-solving, utilising the over-the-shoulder camera perspective made popular by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/resident_evil_4">Resident Evil 4</a>. You’ll start with a standard pistol, but shotguns, carbines, and rocket launchers are all up for grabs as you progress. Interestingly, in another nod to Metroid, every weapon has a charge shot, which deals significantly more damage and can pierce multiple targets at once. It’s advisable to use this almost exclusively, though the time needed to charge your shot leaves you exposed, naturally.</p>
<p>Thankfully, you can upgrade your charge shot — along with almost every aspect of The Traveler’s capabilities — via terminals in safe rooms. You’ll hoard a whole bunch of energy along your travels while also nabbing the odd ‘Core’ (some of which are gifted, believe it or not, by cute cats throughout the game world), the combination of which grants you improved health, weapon damage, and more. The safe rooms themselves are obvious homages to Resident Evil, featuring save stations, storage boxes, and even a relaxed, ethereal background melody to signify that, yes, you can take it easy here.</p>
<figure><a title="Cronos: The New Dawn Review - Screenshot 4 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158537/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Safe rooms are handy because the rest of Cronos is absolutely rife with danger. Just one Orphan can prove deadly if you’re not careful, but facing off against multiple enemies at once is often a recipe for disaster. Careful resource management proves crucial, and this includes procuring fuel for your makeshift flamethrower.</p>
<p>Like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/resident_evil">REmake</a>, downing Orphans often isn’t enough, as others can merge with dead bodies, thus gaining new abilities along with added strength and armour. Burning bodies with a quick tap of ‘L’ will save you a lot of hassle, and this can even be used against active enemies, slowing them down enough to land a charged headshot, using one of Switch 2's multiple control options.</p>
<p>You can use the standard twin-stick setup if you wish, and this is perfectly viable, but I opted for a combination of stick aiming and gyro controls. This worked really well for me after tinkering with the sensitivity, but you might be enticed by the additional mouse controls. You can set Mouse Mode to either the left or right Joy-Con, and it makes for a pretty accurate option once you get used to the increased sensitivity. I didn't much care for it, but this is less a commentary on the game and more Switch 2's mouse functionality in general.</p>
<figure><a title="Cronos: The New Dawn Review - Screenshot 5 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158534/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Some of the very best survival horrors strike an excellent balance between giving you agency against your enemies while encouraging you to avoid unnecessary encounters. Unfortunately, this is one area where Cronos falters. Should the Orphans spot you (which in many scenarios is almost guaranteed), they prove to be exceptionally quick and relentless, making running away a tricky proposition, especially in more claustrophobic environments. As such, you’re often forced to engage in combat whether you want to or not, and this can severely diminish the sense of fear, making enemies less of a threat and more of a nuisance.</p>
<p>While the creatures eventually lose their initial impact from a gameplay perspective, the excellent visual design remains consistent throughout. Though not particularly gory, it's a very <em>gooey</em> game, with writhing masses plastered over walls and floors through which enemies often emerge with a rather sickening squelch.</p>
<p>In fact, the sound design is great across the board. The voice acting is particularly strong, with a great performance from headliner Kelly Burke as The Traveler, along with a host of actors portraying support characters, with plenty of audio logs to nab throughout. The synth-heavy soundtrack is also a real treat, lending the sci-fi setting a good sense of atmosphere.</p>
<figure><a title="Cronos: The New Dawn Review - Screenshot 6 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158532/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>As for how Cronos holds up on Switch 2, it’s mostly good news. You’re looking at a pretty solid 30fps which occasionally struggles during more hectic encounters, though it’s rarely anything to be too concerned about. To achieve this, visual cutbacks have been made; you’ll sometimes see assets that look like they’ve not fully loaded in, but no, that's intentional in order to achieve a stable frame rate. Although The Traveler looks fine in her elaborate sci-fi getup, characters without helmets or other face coverings can look a little iffy.</p>
<p>There’s one major technical issue that needs addressing, too, and it’s one that Bloober Team is aware of and keen to fix ASAP. Currently, if you start playing the game in handheld mode and switch over to docked mode, it hard crashes; just straight-up shuts down and kicks you back to the home screen. While I appreciated the heads-up beforehand, this is the kind of issue that might make your average consumer seek a refund; it’s absurd. You’re playing the game on the Switch 2, and you can’t… y'know, <em>switch</em>. We’re confident this will be fixed very soon, but for now, stick to either docked or handheld mode and refrain from switching mid-game.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Although Cronos: The New Dawn doesn't quite reach the heights of Bloober Team's excellent <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/silent_hill_2">Silent Hill 2</a> remake, it's nevertheless the result of a studio that has levelled up significantly from the days of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/layers_of_fear_legacy">Layers of Fear</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/blair_witch">Blair Witch</a>. It's a celebration of survival horror, paying homage to all the genre greats effectively, although failing to do anything truly original.</p>
<p>That said, the setting and story really help elevate the experience. This is a solid Switch 2 version (assuming a rather unpleasant bug gets fixed soon), and there's real potential here for Cronos to become a central pillar of the genre going forward, should Bloober choose to expand upon it in the future.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/cronos-the-new-dawn]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Super Meat Boy 3D Preview - A Perfect Adaptation]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/super-meat-boy-3d-preview-perfect-adaptation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/super-meat-boy-3d-preview-a-perfect-adaptation.1291350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Super Meat Boy</em> will <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/super-meat-boy-10th-anniversary" rel="nofollow">always be remembered</a> not only as an amazing and novel platformer but an undeniably important game in the rise of the indie gaming scene. It has quite the legacy and seeing the recent reveal taking it to 3D, I was skeptical to say the least.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Meat Boy</em> is well-known for its fast, punishing gameplay that is all about trying over and over again. You might eventually finish a level under 15 seconds, but you died 30 times to get to that one perfect run.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Thankfully, <em>Super Meat Boy 3D</em> maintains all of that. That same classic feeling of try, die, try again is back and in glorious 3D. I’m sure that I was not the only one who was afraid we might see some strange open world collectathon take on <em>Meat Boy</em>, but thankfully I can say that's not the case.</p>



<p>I played close to 10 or so levels from <em>Super Meat Boy 3D,</em> and they all felt like classic <em>Super Meat Boy</em>. They were lean, punishing, and exacting. Finally getting the rhythm of one section to the next was just as satisfying now as it was 15 years ago.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Most importantly, controlling Meat Boy has been translated perfectly to 3D. Meat Boy is fast, splats to walls, and slides just as you’d expect. He’s also just as floaty and you have a lot of control while he’s in the air.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meat Boy’s movement can create some issues while playing, though. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Moving around so quickly and in 3D space, the camera has to follow Meat Boy. The viewpoint is quite a wide view to see a lot of the level, but Meat Boy is small in the center of your screen. That means that it is sometimes very difficult to gauge where Meat Boy is in terms of depth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There were more than a few times I whiffed a jump completely as I didn’t realize that Meat Boy was that far out. I’m not sure how, but something to make that more clear would help immensely on some levels.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One smaller problem comes up sometimes, too, though way less frequently. With the open nature of 3D, there are some shortcuts you can use to quickly make your way through the level.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The few times I found and used one, the camera moved quicker than it had before and there were brief moments the foreground blocked what I could see. Again, though, those were pretty few and far between.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A final thing I want to mention is the visual design. A big part of the original game is the huge blood sprays and blood covering saws, walls, and more as you die again and again. That is of course a part of <em>Super Meat Boy 3D</em>, and it all looks great.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The art style is cartoony and bright in some respects, but it makes for a great contrast to the bloody nature of the carnage being wreaked on poor ol’ Meat Boy. Plus, I don’t know if I’m ever going to get old of seeing a saw cut Meat Boy in half, one part of his body thrown across the level and flopping about. &nbsp;</p>

<h2>Super Meat Boy 3D Preview | Final Thoughts&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Overall, I was incredibly impressed with<em> Super Meat Boy 3D </em>and think it’s a great example of how to translate the gameplay people fell in love with to the 3D space. All the signs are there that this will be a great platformer for everyone and the perfect game for <em>Super Meat Boy</em> fans.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p>Super Meat Boy 3D<em> was previewed at a press event.&nbsp;</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew is the Editor in Chief at TechRaptor. Conned into a love of gaming by Nintendo at a young age, Andrew has been&nbsp;chasing the dragon spawned by Super… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-otton">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/super-meat-boy-3d-preview-perfect-adaptation]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong's early mods sand off its more annoying edges, including double damage and distant spawns]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksongs-early-mods-sand-off-its-more-annoying-edges-including-double-damage-and-distant-spawns</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksongs-early-mods-sand-off-its-more-annoying-edges-including-double-damage-and-distant-spawns.1291347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Also, no more having find room in your pockets for that pesky compass</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Shhhhh. If we're quiet, we might be able to avoid discourse with this one. If you've <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-walkthrough">spent your weekend playing</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> and found that the likes of enemies inflicting double damage and spawns being miles away put a dampner on the fun, mods can help. </p>
<p>I know, I know, these are videogames and we must take their difficulty with the utmost seriousness. How else are any of us supposed to learn important life lessons, like 'press button dodge at this point', unless we go through hours of frustration trying to beat one boss (or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-tips-and-tricks">look such info up</a>)? As such, I stress that these mods, like all mods, are entirely optional. No need to shout at people for using them. Save your voice for singing love ballads to Hornet during breaks in the action.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Right, now I've addressed the very powerful elephant in the room, let's take a gander at Skong's Nexus Mods page, which has filled out nicely now the metroidvania's got a weekend under its belt. Silksong's most endorsed mod thus far is one by Baiker that stops enemies and "normal bosses" from <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/16">dishing out double damage</a>, while leaving hazards free to keep on punishing you. Don't look at the comments on it, if you've not got your internet argument observation popcorn handy.</p>
<p>Also up there in both the download and endorsement rankings is <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/28">a mod</a> from XiaoHaiNB, which adds health bars and damage numbers to baddies. Probably my favourites so far are the death counters. You've got a choice of two from modders <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/18">Rexxah</a> and <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/14">NordboDev</a>, and they'll just sit there on your HUD, reminding you how many times your abilities have proven to be a bit too hollow shite.</p><p>Going back to the easening up, there's '<a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/46">Stakes of Marika - Rebirth Anywhere</a>' from modder Kassent. As you might expect, this one takes a bit of inspiration from FromSoft's Ancient Hoop by ensuring that "when you die in a scene, you will respawn at the scene entrance instead of at a bench miles away". It also lets you set custom respawn points, which is cool.</p>
<p>For those annoyed by Silksong's insistence on not being able to check where you are on the map at a glance, there's '<a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/21">Always Have Compass Effect</a>' by Synthlight, which does what it says on the tin. The same modder's stepped in with a mod that makes <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/53">delivery items less fragile</a> than a shipment of unpacked wine glasses precariously balanced to form a 20 foot tall tower and positioned next to some partially lit fireworks.</p>
<p>The final mod that's caught my eye so far is <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/25">this one</a> for lore enthusiasts, which ensures you only have to kill a single enemy to be able to read their species' journal entry.</p>
<p>Make sure to check the requirements of each of these if you fancy giving them a go, as most require the likes of <a href="https://github.com/BepInEx/BepInEx/releases/">BepInEx</a> and <a href="https://melonloader.co/">MelonLoader</a> to get up and running.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksongs-early-mods-sand-off-its-more-annoying-edges-including-double-damage-and-distant-spawns]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sold at 73% Off, This HP Laptop With Office 365 and 384GB Storage Is Flying Off Amazon’s Shelves]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sold-at-73-off-this-hp-laptop-with-office-365-and-384gb-storage-is-flying-off-amazons-shelves-2000623973</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sold-at-73-off-this-hp-laptop-with-office-365-and-384gb-storage-is-flying-off-amazon%E2%80%99s-shelves.1291341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>HP has dozens of laptops in its lineup right now, but there’s one model that still commands attention because it combines price, performance (Intel N150, 384GB storage, 32GB RAM, Microsoft 365), and daily use practicality. On Amazon, it has collected well <strong>over 1,500 reviews with an average rating of 4.5 out of 5</strong> when bought at full price, but now the story is quite different: <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3965/">at a whopping 73% discount, this HP “everyday” laptop costs just $399 compared to its normal price of $1,499</a>. And then on top of that discount, Amazon tosses in some extras straight into the box (wireless mouse, optical drive, 256GB SD card, and 1-Year Office 365) which makes this deal not worth passing up.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3965/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>What Does $399 Get You?</h2>
<p>For starters, you’re getting a reliable <strong>machine powered by Intel’s Quad-Core N150 processor</strong> which at clock speeds up to 3.4GHz provides smooth performance for day-to-day use. Which is to say, from streaming and surfing to document work and hopping on Zoom calls, everything is responsive. The integrated Intel UHD graphics chip serves up smooth video for casual gaming or just reading content online.</p>
<p>Then toss that in with <strong>32GB of RAM and it becomes even smoother</strong>:&nbsp;switching between apps isn’t hung up, and demanding tasks run without forcing you to close programs all the time. Storage capacity will not be a problem either: you’ve got 128GB of UFS onboard, and then there’s a provided 256GB SD card, which brings your <strong>storage to a whopping 384GB</strong>.</p>
<p>This is where things get very interesting: Microsoft 365 comes with the laptop (you <a href="https://gizmodo.com/download/microsoft-365">can download it here</a>). You receive <strong>a year’s subscription in full (worth $130)</strong>&nbsp;and it’s even the <strong>AI-powered version with Copilot thrown in</strong>. Think of having Word for writing papers or reports, Excel for calculating with pre-formatted formulas, PowerPoint for creating professional-grade presentations, Outlook to sort your email, and even Teams for working online. The Copilot AI feature in Office makes tasks like summarizing papers, writing messages, and scheduling calendars faster and more hands-off.</p>



<p>It doesn’t stop there, though. Aside from Office 365, the laptop package includes a <strong>wireless mouse and an optical drive</strong>, two easy but useful features that spare you the trouble of rushing to the store for accessories on purchasing day. A DVD drive in 2025 is not standard, but it’s useful if you’ve got old discs with photos, films, or software that you still want to use</p>
<p>On the software side, Windows 11 Pro powers all this and couples clean looks with helpful features like Snap Layouts to keep windows neatly organized on screen. For something portable and lightweight, the 14-inch version fits easily into a backpack and won’t weigh you down. Battery life is also good enough to get you through a day of use without having to be constantly recharged, another plus if you find yourself stuck away from a desk for hours.</p>
<p>Deals at this level don’t usually stick around long when word gets out, make sure you don’t miss it.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3965/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sold-at-73-off-this-hp-laptop-with-office-365-and-384gb-storage-is-flying-off-amazons-shelves-2000623973]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MachineGames Teases 'We're Not Done With Wolfenstein Yet']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/machinegames-teases-were-not-done-with-wolfenstein-yet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/machinegames-teases-were-not-done-with-wolfenstein-yet.1291335/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"We have a story to tell," studio head hints.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">MachineGames seemingly hasn't finished with its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/franchise/wolfenstein"><u>Wolfenstein</u></a> series just yet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While it's been over half a decade since we last punched a Nazi in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/wolfenstein-youngblood"><u>Wolfenstein: Youngblood</u></a>, studio head Jerk Gustafsson has hinted the team would very much like to go back to the Wolfenstein universe to tie up BJ Blazkowicz's story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While both Youngblood and the 2019 VR title Cyberpilot touched on the wider Blazkowicz family's fortunes, we haven't actually played as series stalwart Blazkowicz since 2017's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/wolfenstein-2-the-new-colossus"><u>The New Colossus</u></a>. And it's BJ's story that seems to intrigue Gustafsson most — in fact, it seems Blazkowicz's story was <em>always</em> meant to be told in three parts.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In a new interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E189QG28rnE" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Noclip</u></a>, Gustafsson said the team had "always seen [BJ's story] as a trilogy," adding: "That journey for BJ, even during those first weeks at [id Software], when we mapped out New Order — we still had the plan for at least [BJ], what would happen in the second one and what would happen in the third one.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I think that's important to say, because⁠ — at least, I hope ⁠— we're not done with Wolfenstein yet. We have a story to tell," he added (thanks, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/after-indiana-jones-it-sounds-like-machinegames-is-ready-to-make-another-wolfenstein-game-we-have-always-seen-this-as-a-trilogy/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>PC Gamer</u></a>).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The last Wolfenstein game was 2019's Wolftenstein: Youngblood, Set in 1980, 19 years after BJ Blazkowicz ignited the second American Revolution, it introduced the next Blazkowicz generation to the fight against the Nazis. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/07/25/wolfenstein-youngblood-review"><u>In IGN's review, we awarded it a middling 6.5</u></a>, calling it "aggressively okay." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">MachineGames' latest offering, however, was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle"><u>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review"><u>which secured 9/10</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/machinegames-teases-were-not-done-with-wolfenstein-yet]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones devs MachineGames tease another Wolfenstein game - "we have a story to tell"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/indiana-jones-devs-machinegames-tease-another-wolfenstein-game-we-have-a-story-to-tell</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-devs-machinegames-tease-another-wolfenstein-game-we-have-a-story-to-tell.1291323/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>New Order and New Colossus are part of a planned trilogy, after all</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>ZeniMax Media</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>In good news for those saddened by their inability to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vhFPl27xoxg">stamp on Hitler's head</a> in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones And The Great Circle</a>, Machine Games are once again making noises about developing a third Wolfenstein game.
</p><!--more-->
<p>Speaking during a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E189QG28rnE">a No-Clip documentary</a> about the previous two MachineGames-created Wolfenstein games - <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/wolfenstein-the-new-order">Wolfenstein: The New Order</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/wolfenstein-ii-the-new-colossus">Wolfenstein II: The New Colossus</a> - studio head Jerk Gustafsson commented briefly that they still have an outline for a third game, and "hope" to someday complete the story of B.J. Blazkowicz.</p>
<p>"That journey for BJ, even during those first weeks at id, when we mapped out New Order, we still had the plan for at least [BJ], what would happen in the second one and what would happen in the third one," the developer observed. "I think that's important to say, because - at least I hope - we're not done with Wolfenstein yet. We have a story to tell."</p>
<p>I find the prospect of a third Wolfenstein game from MachineGames... interesting. Few big budget shooters have courted the thunder of Topicality quite like New Colossus, an alternate-history fable set in a United States that has been conquered by the Nazis. Back in 2017, I offered some rather grandiose and theory-drenched Opinions about how New Colossus <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wolfenstein-2-the-new-colossus-politics">"takes the white dudebro hero apart"</a>, following the election of Donald Trump. Hunter Pauli <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/b-j-blazkowicz-and-the-shallow-diversity-of-games">wrote a great rebuttal</a>, commenting that "for a series built around the deconstruction of Aryan bodies, it's taken a long time for players to take the hint that Wolfenstein's ubermensch William Blazkowicz is Jewish."</p><p>I don't know about you, but 2017 feels like a billion years ago to me. Since then, Trump has won a second term and initiated a bunch of crackpot and draconian measures against migrants and marginalised people. Russia have invaded Ukraine in what has become the largest armed conflict in Europe since the Second World War. Israel are shelling and starving hundreds of thousands of people in Gaza with the US government's backing - an invasion that has contributed to a crisis of legitimacy in the USA and UK, where elites characterise support for Palestinians as terrorism.</p>
<p>I do not envy any Wolfenstein writer trying to make something approximating a mainstream commercial first-person shooter that alludes to any of this. But then again, there is no such thing as "a simpler time".</p>
<p>In terms of the business of games development, the ground has also shifted considerably beneath MachineGames' feet. They're now owned by Microsoft, via the latter's purchase of ZeniMax Media. Microsoft, of course, are on something of a cost-cutting spree. As reported by <a href="https://www.tweaktown.com/news/106506/machinegames-financials-reveals-indiana-jones-developer-has-6-profit-margin/index.html?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=facebook">Tweaktown</a>, MachineGames made <a href="https://www.allabolag.se/bokslut/machinegames-sweden-ab/uppsala/datautveckling-systemutveckling-programutveckling/2K34T6JI5YDOJ">a small profit in 2024</a>, but that means nothing without understanding how it fits into the parent company's wider fortunes. MachineGames have <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/wolfenstein-machinegames-cancelled-unannounced/">cancelled at least one unannounced game between 2022 and 2024</a>.</p>
<p>Microsoft, meanwhile, stand accused of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-culture-of-intimidation-retaliation-and-oppression-how-microsofts-gaza-stance-fuelled-an-industry-spanning-boycott">abetting the genocide in Gaza while quelling internal criticism of their business links to Israel</a>. A number of ZeniMax staff have signed an <a href="https://noazureforapartheid.com/petition/">open letter</a> calling for Microsoft to divest from the Israeli armed forces.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/indiana-jones-devs-machinegames-tease-another-wolfenstein-game-we-have-a-story-to-tell]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This $2700 Dell Laptop Is Practically Free Right Now, With Amazon Clearing Stock Until It Sells Out]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-2700-dell-laptop-is-practically-free-right-now-with-amazon-clearing-stock-until-it-sells-out-2000623966</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-2700-dell-laptop-is-practically-free-right-now-with-amazon-clearing-stock-until-it-sells-out.1291317/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Dell is one of those omnipresent American brands that dominate the mass laptop market, and if you need to gear up for back-to-school or switch out your office configuration, Amazon just debuted a deal that’s hard to pass up.</p>
<p>Now, the Dell Inspiron <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3962/">15-inch touchscreen laptop (Intel 10 Core i5 1334U, 32GB DDR4 RAM, 1TB PCIe SSD) can be purchased for $699, down from its usual $2,699 price tag</a>. That’s a <strong>huge 74% discount</strong> and it brings a premium-level device into a price range that feels almost unbelievable. On top of that, you’ll get a <strong>free 8-in-1 USB-C hub</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3962/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Powerful Yet Affordable</h2>
<p>The heart of this device is its <strong>13th Gen Intel Core i5-1334U processor which has 10 cores and 12 threads</strong> to make multitasking responsive without slowing you down. Toss in generous 32GB of DDR4 RAM and you have the room to run all your day-to-day applications and resource-intensive tasks simultaneously without skipping a beat.</p>
<p>The 1TB PCIe NVMe SSD also offers plenty of space for files, movies, and downloads, and keeps start-up quick and applications snappy. No longer just sitting around waiting for stuff to load: everything just opens up immediately. For students with speedy access needed to class material or businesspeople working on large projects, that kind of performance is a huge difference in everyday use.</p>



<p>And of course, the screen is a major part of the experience and Dell hasn’t cut corners on it: This Inspiron laptop<strong> features a 15.6-inch Full HD touchscreen</strong> with an anti-glare finish and narrow borders so you enjoy sharp images and vibrant colors without distracting reflections. It’s the kind of screen that makes video calls clear and day-to-day browsing easier on the eyes. Combined with Intel Iris Xe graphics, you’ll also enjoy smoother graphics for light gaming or creative use like photo editing.</p>
<p>WiFi 6 is offered in this laptop, so you’ll get faster and more stable internet connections which is perfect if you spend a lot of time streaming, working from home, or on video calls. On top of Bluetooth and a solid port set, like Type-C, Type-A, HDMI, and even an SD card reader, you already have enough flexibility to attach your favorite peripherals or extend your setup with ease. And to top it all off, <strong>the bundle includes an 8-in-1 USB-C hub</strong>&nbsp;so more ports to connect external monitors, storage devices, or even wired broadband with RJ-45.</p>
<p>Windows 11 Pro in S Mode comes pre-installed with business-ready features available along with a personal and streamlined environment. That is, you can upgrade your workflow from day one without the additional time of configuring. And yet the device depends on performance and functionality without compromising on a sleek, modern design in black that slices well on a desk or on the move.</p>
<p>Deals like this don’t tend to linger long during high-demand periods like back-to-school, so if you’ve been considering an upgrade, this price drop makes the decision an easy one.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3962/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-2700-dell-laptop-is-practically-free-right-now-with-amazon-clearing-stock-until-it-sells-out-2000623966]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us season two wins series another Emmy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-two-wins-series-another-emmy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-season-two-wins-series-another-emmy.1291308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>HBO</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The second season of The Last of Us, which comprised seven episodes, has won its first Emmy.</p>
<p>At this weekend's Creative Arts Emmys, The Last of Us took home the award for Outstanding Sound Editing for a Comedy or Drama Series for the second season's second episode, known as Through the Valley.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>
You can check out the full list of this weekend's winners via <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/09/creative-arts-emmys-2025-winners-list-1236509478/">Deadline</a>. </p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hbos-the-last-of-us-live-action-tv-adaptation-has-been-nominated-for-24-emmys">first season of The Last of Us was nominated for 24 Emmys</a>. It went on to win eight, including <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hbos-the-last-of-us-wins-eight-emmys-including-outstanding-guest-actor-for-nick-offermans-bill">Outstanding Guest Actor for Nick Offerman's portrayal of Bill</a>.</p>
<p>The second season wrapped earlier this year, with a third season already confirmed to be in the pipeline. Back in July of this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/neil-druckmann-steps-away-from-hbos-the-last-of-us-tv-adaptation">The Last of Us video game creator Neil Druckmann announced he was stepping away from his creative involvement in HBO's TV adaptation</a>, calling this a "difficult decision".</p>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-8th-september-finished-hollow-knight-silksong-yet-and-did-you-read-our-bumper-until-dawn-making-of">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-two-wins-series-another-emmy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater New Comparisons Highlight Surprisingly Good Quality of Pachislot Cutscenes]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-new-comparisons-quality-pachislot/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-new-comparisons-highlight-surprisingly-good-quality-of-pachislot-cutscenes.1291302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>While <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater/">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> is undoubtedly the best-looking version of the third entry in the series created by Hideo Kojima, the pachislot version released a few years ago doesn't look bad at all, even surpassing the Unreal Engine 5 remake developed by Virtuos in some regards.</p>



<p>Two new comparison videos shared by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Cycu1">Cycu1</a> on YouTube put the remake running side by side with the HD remake developed by Bluepoint which was re-released two years ago as part of the Master Collection Vol.1 on PC and consoles and recordings of the same cutscenes recreated for the pachislot version of the game, highlighting how the latter don't look bad at all, sometimes even surpassing the Unreal Engine 5-powered remake in some instances like lighting, although this was to be expected, considering these cutscenes are not running in real time.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Metal Gear Solid 3 Delta vs Pachinko vs Original Graphics Comparison | Fox Engine vs Unreal Engine 5" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LNcn0e6hOD8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Metal Gear Solid Delta vs Pachinko All Cutscenes Graphics Comparison | Fox Engine vs Unreal Engine 5" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xBAeELm58JU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Despite launching with issues, including a 60 FPS cap on PC, which can be increased with mods, Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater has proven to be a smashing success, becoming <a href="https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-million-seller-day-one/">a million seller</a> right on day one, as confirmed by Konami last week. The game's success on the market was fully expected, considering this is the first new release in the series in a long time and the fact that all the changes made to the original experience enhance it quite a bit without taking away what still makes Snake Eater one of the best entries in the series, if not the very best. You can learn more about the remake now out on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S worldwide by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-ps5-review-based-on-a-hideo-kojima-game/">review.</a></p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-new-comparisons-quality-pachislot/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Finally Lets Us Cuddle The Trainers]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-center-trainer-plush-n-marnie-lillie-2000623942</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-finally-lets-us-cuddle-the-trainers.1291299/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>For too long <em>Pokémon</em> games have set us as rivals to other trainers, forced to complete against the likes of N, Leon and Marnie, rather than provide them with what they truly need: support and love. But thankfully that’s all about to end with the arrival of trainer plushies on the Pokémon Center store.</p> <p>It’s quite something that this hasn’t happened before. But as The Pokémon Company continues its true purpose—<a href="https://kotaku.com/mega-evolved-pokemon-plush-gengar-gardevoir-2000618808">creating plushies of everything imaginable</a>—its attention has finally turned to the human component of the games. Five trainers have arrived on the store in snuggly form: Lillie (<em>Sun</em> and <em>Moon</em>)<em>,</em> Cynthia (<em>Diamond</em> and <em>Pearl</em>)<em>,</em> N (<em>Black</em> and <em>White</em>), Leon, and Marnie (both <em>Sword</em> and<em> Shield</em>). Each is depicted in a chibi style, rather than their more lifelike appearance in the games, between seven and nine inches tall.</p> <p>There do seem good reasons to have gone for the short, big-headed chibi approach, given the somewhat <em>problematic</em> nature of some fans’ relationships with the human characters in&nbsp;<em>Pokémon&nbsp;</em>games. Characters like Lillie, for instance, are 11, while people like Marnie and Cynthia are ambiguously aged, most likely a teenager and a 20-something respectively. Within the world of the card game, such characters tend to fetch the highest resale prices, with the grim term “waifu tax” usually applied. (N is 20, and Leon is “an adult” for what it’s worth, while Leon’s little brother Hop surprisingly isn’t included in this first set.) Life-size plushies of any of them would be…a whole thing, and even to-scale renditions could get weird. Certainly even more troubling ground than the <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-life-sized-gardevoir-plush-import-center-buy-1851752663">$449 life-size Gardevoir</a> that’s as <a href="https://www.pokemoncenter.com/product/72-10419-101/gardevoir-poke-plush-63-in">sold out</a> as you’d expect.</p>

 <p>Anyway, the result is super-cute human plushies for the very first time. Leon seems like a great choice, especially if you buy a Charizard to go with him, but I imagine N and Marnie will be the two most popular, given the former was such a charming rival in&nbsp;<em>Black&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>White</em> as the leader of Team Plasma, while Marnie’s meanness and Dark-type preferences made her the most entertaining rival in&nbsp;<em>Sword</em> and&nbsp;<em>Shield</em>.</p> <p>It does rather raise the question of which other game characters should receive the plushie transition. My preference has to be&nbsp;<em>Diamond</em> and&nbsp;<em>Pearl</em>‘s Barry, but purely because “Barry” is such a funny name for a child to have. It is a name only allowed to truck drivers in their 40s. No child should ever be called Barry. Carmine from&nbsp;<em>Scarlet&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Violet</em>‘s DLC is another obvious choice, because she was just so damn cool. Oh, and to state the obvious, Misty and Brock! Oh, and please may we not forget Opal. Presumably the only reason there’s no Grusha in this first set is because it’s impossible to capture that beautiful boy in any doll.</p> <p>Oh it got weird again.</p> <p>These new trainer plushies are currently available on the <a href="https://www.pokemoncenter.com/en-au/category/new-releases">Australian</a>, <a href="https://www.pokemoncenter.com/en-gb/category/new-releases">UK</a> and <a href="https://www.pokemoncenter.com/en-nz/category/new-releases">New Zealand</a> stores, and will appear on <a href="https://www.pokemoncenter.com/category/new-releases">the U.S. store</a> in the next couple of hours. Click on for pictures of them all.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-center-trainer-plush-n-marnie-lillie-2000623942]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Bethesda exec Pete Hines claims subscriptions services are undercutting developers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/former-bethesda-exec-pete-hines-claims-subscriptions-services-are-undercutting-developers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-bethesda-exec-pete-hines-claims-subscriptions-services-are-undercutting-developers.1291293/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">September 8, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Former Bethesda head of publishing Pete Hines wonders whether subscription services like Xbox Game Pass are selling developers short.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The industry veteran, who spent 24 years at The Elder Scrolls and Starfield maker before </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bethesda-s-head-of-publishing-pete-hines-is-retiring-now-starfield-has-launched">retiring after the latter launched</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.dbltap.com/features/24-years-bethesda-with-pete-hines">quizzed by DBLTAP</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> about the rise of subscription platforms and the impact they're having on the people who make video games.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The vital context is that Hines helped Bethesda publish several titles, including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Redfall</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush,</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Starfield</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, that debuted on Xbox Game Pass.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When asked what success looks like for developers on those platforms—don't forget, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/aarongreenberg/status/1649431572137779203">heralded as triumph</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> by Microsoft's VP of game marketing Aaron Greenberg before the company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-closes-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-alpha-dog-studios">shut down developer Tango Gameworks</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">—Hines suggested it has become even harder for studios to generate returns because platforms like Xbox Game Pass don't adequately value or reward their work.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I'm not working in any of these companies anymore, and so I don't assume that everything I knew while I was in the industry still holds true today. At the same time, I'm involved enough to know I saw what I considered to be some short sighted decision making several years ago, and it seems to be bearing out the way I said," he said.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/silksong-channels-kim-kardashian-developers-unite-for-palestine-and-former-polygon-staffers-become-rogue-patch-notes-21" target="_self" data-discover="true">Silksong channels Kim Kardashian, developers unite for Palestine, and former Polygon staffers become Rogue - Patch Notes #21</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Subscriptions have become the new four letter word, right? You can't buy a product anymore. When you talk about a subscription that relies on content, if you don't figure out how to balance the needs of the service and the people running the service with the people who are providing the content—without which your subscription is worth jack shit—then you have a real problem."&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Hines says devs are being bundled into an ecosystem that doesn't value their work">Hines says devs are being bundled into an ecosystem that doesn't value their work</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hines said companies looking to make subscriptions a cornerstone of their business must properly "acknowledge, compensate, and recognize" what it actually takes to create products for those platforms. Right now, he feels there's a "tension" between the investment studios are making and the returns they're seeing off the back of those subscription deals.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"That tension is hurting a lot of people, including the content creators themselves, because they're fitting into an ecosystem that is not properly valuing and rewarding what they're making."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Microsoft launched Xbox Game Pass in 2017 and said the service would offer day one access to all Xbox Game Studios titles. The company eventually </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-increasing-price-of-xbox-game-pass-introducing-new-standard-plan-that-ditches-day-one-access">dialled back on that promise</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> by introducing a new "standard" plan that only includes access to select first-party titles at launch.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/2k-confirms-layoffs-at-civilization-developer-firaxis" target="_self" data-discover="true">2K confirms layoffs at Civilization developer Firaxis</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That pivot came after Microsoft spent $68.7 billion acquiring Call of Duty maker Activision Blizzard.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Xbox boss Phil Spencer said the merger demonstrated the company's ongoing commitment to video games. Since completing the deal, Microsoft has shuttered multiple studios, cancelled a litany of projects, and made significant redundancies.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/former-bethesda-exec-pete-hines-claims-subscriptions-services-are-undercutting-developers]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>