<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 11:37:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What We Played – Concord, Age of Mythology: Retold & Star Wars Outlaws]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/what-we-played-concord-age-of-mythology-retold-star-wars-outlaws/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-we-played-%E2%80%93-concord-age-of-mythology-retold-star-wars-outlaws.968154/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/what-we-played-concord-age-of-mythology-retold-star-wars-outlaws/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>And so it begins. The week after Gamescom feels like a dam-break for the games industry, and the first of this year’s big holiday releases are arriving, this time in the shape of Star Wars Outlaws. I loved my <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/30/star-wars-outlaws-preview-this-is-the-open-world-game-youre-looking-for/">first hands on</a>, and with the full release it seems like the perfect time to grab a Ubisoft Premium subscription to play it. So I’ve even been playing via Luna here and there, and thus far it’s the Star Wars adventure I needed right now. Beyond that, I’m catching up on my Gamescom writing, as well as sneaking in some Overwatch 2, Concord and Age of Mythology: Retold.</p>
<p><strong>Aran</strong> has had a quieter week on the gaming front, but he’s still been playing Beyond Galaxyland for review and a couple of matches on FC24. Meanwhile, <strong>Gamoc</strong> has been playing Star Wars Outlaws for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/26/star-wars-outlaws-review/">our review</a> as well as Hunt: Showdown 1896.</p>

<p><strong>Nic B</strong> is stuck in a card-based loop, as he’s pretty much exclusively played MTG Arena. <strong>Nick P</strong> has&nbsp;been putting a lot of time in Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth and The Casting of Frank Stone for review! As always, a little Dead by Daylight and Fortnite on the side.</p>
<p><strong>Ade</strong> took a punt on Black Myth Wukong, but it hasn’t really landed with him, “It was getting some good buzz online and had picked up a whole lot of 5 star player reviews on the PS Store, so I thought it would be decent. Visually the game looks amazing and its interpretation and presentation of Chinese Mythology is absolutely phenomenal… unfortunately the combat totally sucks. It’s messy, imprecise, and plays more like a bad button masher. There’s no sense of contact or impact to any of the, admittedly very pretty, spells and attacks. So, after giving the game several hours, I can’t see myself going back to it. For anyone thinking about picking it up, better off giving it a miss I’d say. On the plus side, I’m keeping occupied playing Wild Bastards for review instead!”</p>


<p>Having abandoned the mean streets of Night City and New Vegas for a week, <strong>Jim</strong> has been absolutely glued to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/concord-review-a-fun-frenetic-hero-shooter/">Concord</a>. It’s scratching that hero shooter itch I’ve had since first peeling away from Overwatch, making subtle tweaks to the genre and presenting a cast of characters who are all really fun to play as.</p>
<p>As this week’s king of the shooty stuff, <strong>Tuffcub</strong> has been mostly playing the sequel duo of Destiny 2 and Space Marine 2. His first impressions? “GRRRRRRRRRRR MEN GRRRRR SHOOT STUFF GRRR”. So, there you go.</p>
<p>And rounding things out this week is&nbsp;<strong>Tef</strong>, who’s also been on the Gamescom write up train, but also caught a train to go play a couple games that don’t involve trains. Whatever could they be? You’ll find out over the next couple weeks. He’s also got back to Emio: The Smiling Man for our Famicom Detective Club review.</p>
<p>What about you, what have you played?</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Visions of Mana Dev Reportedly Being Shut Down by NetEase]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-dev-reportedly-being-shut-down-by-netease</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/visions-of-mana-dev-reportedly-being-shut-down-by-netease.968151/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-dev-reportedly-being-shut-down-by-netease<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Chinese video game company NetEase has reportedly laid off most staff at Visions of Mana developer Ouka Studios with plans to shut it down altogether.</p><p>Anonymous sources familiar with the situation told <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-08-30/tencent-netease-rethink-japan-approach-as-game-strategy-stalls?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTcyNDk3ODYwMSwiZXhwIjoxNzI1NTgzNDAxLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTSVVYOExUMVVNMFcwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJBRDcxOUY5NDBGRTk0MzNBOERCNzI2OEJDOTY3NzY3QyJ9.NXgxdAhnQilzn9xmn3yS-AAgzBHV84_10DD-MHWBs7M" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloomberg</a> that the studio, which only opened in 2020, will be kept afloat by the few remaining members until its final games have been released. <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/visions-of-mana">Visions of Mana</a> only launched yesterday, August 29, 2024, and earned high critical praise. (IGN's <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-review">Visions of Mana review</a> returned an 8/10.)</p><p>The closure of Ouka Studios is reportedly due to major Chinese companies like NetEase and its rival Tencent shifting away from a Japan-centric approach.</p><p>Bloomberg reported that Tencent is also reconsidering how much it invests in Japanese video game developers and has already backed out of several funding commitments. It had secured the rights to develop and publish the mobile version of anime-inspired game Blue Protocol, for example, but on August 28 <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/worldwide-release-cancelled-for-amazon-games-live-service-mmo-blue-protocol">Bandai Namco announced Blue Protocol would be shut down altogether</a> and its worldwide release, set to be handled by Amazon Games, was cancelled.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Visions of Mana Gameplay Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>One source said the success of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-review-pc">Black Myth Wukong</a>, which sold <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-sells-an-incredible-10-million-copies-in-just-3-days">a staggering 10 million copies in three days</a> and comes from a relatively small Chinese developer, has also inspired NetEase and Tencent to look for investments domestically. These Chinese companies have otherwise found their visions misaligned with the Japanese developers they looked to invest in, according to the report.</p><p>NetEase told Bloomberg it had "nothing to announce" regarding the closure of Ouka Studios. Tencent said it is "always making necessary adjustments to reflect market conditions."</p><p>The past two years have seen countless video game industry layoffs as big companies including Microsoft, Sony, and the embattled Embracer Group have not just cut jobs but shut down entire studios.</p><p>Microsoft <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-closes-redfall-developer-arkane-austin-hifi-rush-developer-tango-gameworks-and-more-in-devastating-cuts-at-bethesda">shut down Redfall developer Arkane Austin</a> alongside Hi-Fi Rush and Ghostwire Tokyo developer Tango Gameworks in May 2024 in <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/shock-and-anger-as-xbox-shuts-down-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-more">a move met with shock and anger by industry peers and fans</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/saints-row-developer-volition-shut-down-by-embracer-group">Embracer Group shut down Saints Row developer Volition in 2023</a>, while <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-significant-playstation-layoffs-affecting-900-staff-london-studio-to-close">Sony shut down its London Studio in March 2024</a> amid layoffs affecting 900 staff across the PlayStation business.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Confirms Console Performance Specs, Crossplay and Cross-Save Details, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-confirms-console-performance-specs-crossplay-and-cross-save-details-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-confirms-console-performance-specs-crossplay-and-cross-save-details-and-more.968148/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-confirms-console-performance-specs-crossplay-and-cross-save-details-and-more<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> publisher Focus Entertainment has answered a number of burning questions fans had about the soon-to-be released action game in a <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/68-august-community-update" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FAQ</a> that addresses everything from console performance specs to cross-play.</p><p>Space Marine 2 sees Titus of the Ultramarines go up against the Tyranid horde as well as the forces of Chaos in a sequel that arrives 13 years after its predecessor. It includes a campaign that can be played co-op, a PvE Operations mode, and a PvP mode.</p><p>Let’s start with the console performance specs. On PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X, Quality Mode enables 4K resolution at 30 frames per second, and Performance Mode enables “up to” 60fps at 1080p resolution. Focus said that on the less powerful Xbox Series S, the Quality Mode allows for 1440p at 30fps, and Performance Mode is unavailable.</p><p>As for PC, it’s a mixed bag. DLSS2 / FSR2 is available at launch, but DLSS3 / FSR3 is “planned for post-launch.” Ray tracing / HDR is not supported. Wide-screen support won’t be available right at launch, unfortunately. Focus said it’s planned to hit the game by the end of September.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Multiplayer Modes Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Similarly, full Steam Deck support is being worked on but isn’t ready yet. That’s coming by the end of the year. There are no plans for official mod support, perhaps unsurprising given Space Marine 2 is an officially licensed Games Workshop title.</p><p>Focus confirmed that in campaign mode, progression is saved on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X and S while playing offline. However, for the PvE mode, called Operations, you need to be online to ensure your progress in that mode is saved. Offline progression does not carry over to your next session. Focus said players should stay online to keep all earned perks, skins, and other rewards.</p><p>Cross-platform saves are supported via the platform Prism Ray Online Services (PROS), which Focus uses for a number of its games. LAN play is not supported.</p><p>There’s full crossplay between Steam, Epic Games Store, PS5, and Xbox Series X and S players from day one, Focus confirmed. You can play the campaign and PvE modes without any restriction, but when it comes to the PvP mode, called Eternal War, crossplay is split between PC players in one pool (Steam and EGS) and console players in another (PS5 and Xbox Series X and S). Focus said this is “for fairness and balancing purposes,” perhaps hinting at the advantage mouse and keyboard users on PC might have against controller players.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>In Operations mode, your squad can only include one Space Marine of each class. In Eternal War mode, however, there is a limit of two players per class and per team. “No all-Sniper teams, but you'll have plenty of strategic variety!” Focus said. There is no friendly fire in either of the three game modes, so don’t go in expecting a Helldivers 2 kind of experience.</p><h2>You can check out the Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 launch FAQ in full below:</h2><p><strong>Will my progression be saved when playing offline?</strong></p><p>Be reassured, in Campaign Mode, your progression will be saved on PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S while playing offline.</p><p>For Operations Mode (PvE), you will need to be online to ensure your progress in PvE is saved. Offline progression will not carry over to your next session, so make sure you're connected to keep all earned perks, skins, and other rewards.</p><p><strong>Does cross-platform save work well?</strong></p><p>➡️Yes, cross-platform saves are fully functional through the platform Prism Ray Online Services (PROS).</p><p><strong>Is PvE/PvP playable via LAN?</strong></p><p>➡️LAN play will not be supported.</p><p><strong>Will the game support crossplay, and can it be toggled off?</strong></p><p>➡️Yes, full crossplay between Steam, Epic Games Store, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S players will be supported from Day One.</p><p>You will be able to play the Campaign and PvE modes without any restriction, but note that for fairness and balancing purposes, crossplay for the PvP mode “Eternal War” will be split between PC players in one pool (Steam &amp; EGS) and console players in the other one (PlayStation 5 &amp; Xbox Series X|S).</p><p>You will also have the option to disable crossplay functionality if you prefer to only play with those using the same platform as yours.</p><p><strong>Are there any restrictions for what classes can be played in “Operations” mode (PvE)? What about “Eternal War” (PvP)?</strong></p><p>➡️Your squad may only include one Space Marine of each class in “Operations” mode. In “Eternal War” mode, there is a limit of two players per class and per team.</p><p>No all-Sniper teams, but you'll have plenty of strategic variety! 🎯</p><p><strong>Is there friendly fire when playing Campaign, Operations or Eternal War modes?</strong></p><p>➡️There is no friendly fire in either of the 3 game modes.</p><p><strong>What are the performances like? on PC and on Console?</strong></p><p>On PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S, is there a performance mode, quality mode, and what FPS can we expect? And other specific details.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Quality Mode: 4K resolution at 30FPS.</li><li>Performance Mode: Up to 60FPS at 1080p.</li><li>Please note that on Xbox Series S, the Quality Mode will allow for 1440p at 30FPS and the Performance Mode will not be available.</li></ul><p><strong>What kind of communication tools will we have in-game?</strong></p><p>➡️There is a Voice Chat, a Communication Wheel with preset messages and a Text Chat (exclusive to PC versions) to facilitate your exchanges with your teammates.</p><p><strong>Does the game support the haptic features of the DualSense controller?</strong></p><p>➡️We support force triggers on the DualSense controller, but not haptic feedback at launch.</p><p><strong>What about RayTracing, DLSS, and other PC-specific technologies?</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>DLSS2 / FSR2: Available at launch.</li><li>DLSS3 / FSR3: Planned for post-launch.</li><li>RayTracing / HDR: Not supported.</li></ul><p><strong>Is the game compatible with wide screens?</strong></p><p>➡️Wide screen support is planned. While it won't be available right at launch, we're working on implementing it by the end of September.</p><p><strong>Will the game be playable on Steam Deck?</strong></p><p>➡️We are working on official Steam Deck support, but it's not ready yet. We’re currently targeting the end of the year for full Steam Deck support.</p><p><strong>Will the game have official mod support (e.g., NexusMods, mod.io)?</strong></p><p>➡️We currently have no plans for official mod support.</p><p><strong>What anti-cheat system is in place?</strong></p><p>➡️We will be using Easy Anti Cheat on PC at launch.</p><p><strong>Does the game use DRM software (ie. Denuvo…)?</strong></p><p>➡️No.</p><p><strong>Will the game be available Day One on GeForce Now?</strong></p><p>➡️Yes.</p><p><strong>Will the game be available through the Xbox Game Pass?</strong></p><p>➡️No.</p><p><strong>Can the HUD elements be removed? Is there a “Cinematic” mode available?</strong></p><p>➡️Though there is no actual “Cinematic” mode available where all of the UI elements can be turned off at once, all of them can be individually displayed or removed through the Settings menu. Only the crosshair, enemy attacks and missions objective pop-ups will be visible.</p><p>Three options are available: ON, OFF or DYNAMIC, with “Dynamic” meaning that the UI elements you’ve chosen will appear when you need it most (for example, during combat) and disappear otherwise.</p><p><strong>Will I be able to pre-load the game, and if so, when will pre-load be available?</strong></p><p>➡️Your ability to pre-load Space Marine 2 depends on your platform of choice:</p><p>On Xbox Series X|S: Pre-loading is already available. You will download the full game as soon as you pre-order either of the game’s versions. The game will unlock on September 5 or September 9 depending on whether you purchased the Standard, Gold or Ultra Edition.</p><p>On PlayStation 5: Pre-loading will be available on September 3 at 11:00 AM UTC if you have pre-ordered the Gold or Ultra Edition, to allow you to play up to 4 days before the official release. If you have pre-ordered the Standard Edition, pre-loading will start on September 7 at 4:00 PM UTC and the game will unlock on September 9, the day of release.</p><p>On PC: Pre-loading will not be available.</p><p><strong>Do I need to have played the first Space Marine to enjoy Space Marine 2?</strong></p><p>➡️Having played Space Marine is absolutely not a requirement for playing and enjoying Space Marine 2. Both games’ storylines can be enjoyed individually, and both offer brutal third-person action gameplay. You may be missing some very specific references, but that won’t stop you from enjoying the bigger picture at all.</p><p><strong>What are the game's accessibility options?</strong></p><p>➡️You can enlarge the size of subtitles to make them easier to read, as well as 3 different colour blind modes.</p><p><strong>Which languages will be available?</strong></p><p>➡️The game is fully voiced in 7 languages: English, French, German, Spanish, Russian, Japanese and Mandarin Chinese.</p><p>➡️All the texts are available in no less than 17 languages: English, French, German, Italian, Russian, Czech, Polish, Ukrainian, Spanish, Spanish (Latino-American), Japanese, Korean, Brazilian Portuguese, Mandarin Chinese, Traditional Chinese, Thai and Turkish.</p><p><strong>At what time does the game release?</strong></p><p>➡️Mark your calendars:</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/30/sm1-1725009863288.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/30/sm2-1725009863289.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/30/sm3-1725009863290.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Earlier this week, Focus confirmed <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-post-launch-roadmap-includes-new-maps-a-horde-mode-and-more">what fans can expect from Space Marine 2’s seasonal post-launch content model</a>. Season 2 runs from October until the end of 2024, and includes a new Operations map, a new enemy, a harder difficulty level, a new weapon, and various other improvements.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Confusion over Black Myth: Wukong's missing Xbox release follows claims of PlayStation exclusivity]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/confusion-over-black-myth-wukongs-missing-xbox-release-follows-claims-of-playstation-exclusivity</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/confusion-over-black-myth-wukongs-missing-xbox-release-follows-claims-of-playstation-exclusivity.968145/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/confusion-over-black-myth-wukongs-missing-xbox-release-follows-claims-of-playstation-exclusivity<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>No word yet on Xbox launch.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Black-Myth-Wukong-opening.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Game Science</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Rumours of a PlayStation exclusivity deal for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/black-myth-wukong">Black Myth: Wukong</a> have arisen, causing confusion around its forthcoming Xbox release.</p>
<p>Black Myth: Wukong released earlier this month across PC and PlayStation 5, with an Xbox version still awaiting a launch date. Back in June, developer <a href="https://www.heishenhua.com/news/detail?id=11">Game Science</a> stated it was "optimising" the Xbox Series X/S version of the game "to meet our quality standards".</p>
<p>As such, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-wont-be-on-xbox-at-launch">Black Myth: Wukong was not released on Xbox</a> simultaneously with PC and PlayStation. "We apologise for the delay and aim to minimise the wait for Xbox users. We will announce the release date as soon as it meets our quality standards," Game Science said at that time.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Here's a trailer for Black Myth: Wukong. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zW65D4usKSs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Reports have since circulated the reason for this ongoing delay is due to technical issues with Black Myth: Wukong's Xbox version.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, leaker <a href="https://x.com/eXtas1stv/status/1827840322623119683">eXtas1s</a> claimed to have spoken to Xbox developers during <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a>, and reported the game is "suffering from a bug known as 'memory leak', which can cause significant crashes that could compromise the performance" of Xbox consoles. As a result, eXtas1s said Black Myth: Wukong "has not passed Xbox's bug detection tests and has therefore been indefinitely delayed until they manage to optimise the game for Series X/S".</p>
<p>However, following word of technical issues with the Xbox version, other sources have said the reason for the delay is actually due to an undisclosed exclusivity deal made between the Black Myth: Wukong developer and PlayStation.</p>
<p>
The exclusivity deal has been corroborated by <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/08/27/new-report-sheds-light-on-why-black-myth-wukong-isnt-on-xbox/">Forbes</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-xbox-delay-due-to-sony-exclusivity-deal-not-tech-issues-according-to-source">IGN</a> sources, though the exact terms of this alleged deal remain unknown. Previous claims of tech issues causing a delay to the Xbox release are "inaccurate", IGN was told.
</p>
<p>The exclusivity agreement was subsequently disputed by journalist Jeff Grubb. Speaking as part of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/YOf7LJRiDww?t=1432s">Giant Bomb's Game Mess Decides podcast</a>, Grubb said "Sony has no money marketing deal to keep [Black Myth: Wukong] off of Xbox" consoles, as per his sources.</p>
<p>"Now, is there some other thing that's happened here, where Sony showed up and said 'hey, here's some help to get this game on PlayStation', and maybe there was an exchange of value on that side of things? I guess that's possible," Grubb said. "Or maybe it's more simple than that... and it's like, well, you put the game on PlayStation if you are Game Science because there are more PlayStations in China than Xboxes." Grubb noted the majority of the game's sales and player base is from China. "Maybe Xbox doesn't even occur to [Game Science] on first blush."</p>
<p>While Grubb stated he was speculating on whether Sony did give Game Science a hand with Black Myth: Wukong's release, as "far as [he] could tell" and from what his sources have told him, "there is no exclusivity deal" in place.</p>
<p>XboxEra's Nick "Shpeshal Nick" Baker also believes this to be the case. Resharing Paul Tassi's post regarding Black Myth: Wukong's alleged exclusivity deal, <a href="https://x.com/Shpeshal_Nick/status/1829299883481936230">Baker</a> wrote: "I heard there was a misunderstanding around this stuff. I heard Sony only paid to help get the port done. No exclusivity."</p>
<p>Windows Central's <a href="https://x.com/JezCorden/status/1829335350482706717">Jez Cordon</a> then replied simply: "No misunderstanding here."</p>
<p>Game Science, Sony and Microsoft have all refrained from confirming or denying these reports. </p>
<p>However, back in June, Microsoft appeared to hint there was some kind of Black Myth: Wukong exclusivity deal in place with Sony.</p>
<p>In a statement shared with <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/hotly-anticipated-black-myth-wukong-is-delayed-on-xbox-for-optimizations-and-now-microsoft-has-responded">Windows Central</a> earlier this summer, a Microsoft spokesperson said: "We're excited for the launch of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-review">Black Myth Wukong</a> on Xbox Series X/S and are working with Game Science to bring the game to our platforms. We can't comment on the deals made by our partners with other platform holders, but we remain focused on making Xbox the best platform for gamers, and great games are at the centre of that."</p>
<p>Eurogamer has reached out to Game Science, Microsoft and Sony for further comment on Black Myth: Wukong's Xbox release and alleged PlayStation exclusivity.</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/black-myth-wukong-screenshot-spirits00008.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer/Game Science</cite></span></figcaption></figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/black-myth-wukong-review-header.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer / Game Science</cite></span></figcaption></figure>
<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Black Myth: Wukong broke records earlier in the month by becoming <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-already-steams-most-played-single-player-game-of-all-time">the most popular single-player game by peak concurrent users in Steam history</a> and establishing itself as the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-continues-to-attract-record-breaking-numbers-of-players">most-viewed game on Chinese live-streaming platforms</a> on its first day of release.</p>
<p>Last Friday, the Black Myth: Wukong team announced the game had <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-continues-its-dominance-with-new-milestone">shifted an impressive 10m copies across platforms</a>. According to Niko Partners analyst Daniel Ahmad, "this makes it one of the fastest-selling games of all time, surpassing <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-walkthrough-8042">Elden Ring</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hogwarts-legacy">Hogwarts Legacy</a> in the same timeframe".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Test Drive Unlimited: Solar Crown year 1 roadmap has a surprise trip to Ibiza]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-year-1-roadmap-has-a-surprise-trip-to-ibiza/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-year-1-roadmap-has-a-surprise-trip-to-ibiza.968142/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-year-1-roadmap-has-a-surprise-trip-to-ibiza/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>In a big pre-launch surprise, KT Racing has revealed that Ibiza will be coming to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown">Test Drive Unlimited: Solar Crown</a> just three months after launch, as part of the year one content roadmap.</p>
<p><iframe title="Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown | Post-Launch Content Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b_6hzDhBWis?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Launching on 12th September, Test Drive Unlimited: Solar Crown will feature a 1:1 recreation of Hong Kong Island to race around, but the announcement that Ibiza will return to the game this year is a massive fan-pleaser – it was the setting for TDU2 13 years ago. Once again, this is a 1:1 recreation, though of the city and its outskirts and not of the full island.</p>
<p>The first two seasons will also include free Solar Pass progression tracks that can eventually unlock new cars, before Season 3 focuses in on the Clan Wars, and Season 4 brings back another fan-favourite with the Casino.</p>
<p>Here’s the breakdown from KT Racing:</p>

<p><strong>Season 1 – Launch content from September 12, 2024</strong></p>
<p><em>The Solar Crown competition opens its doors! Once the game is released, the most competitive players will be able to embark on a series of races and frantic challenges to climb the ranks, collect Solar Points and climb to the top of the leaderboard in the hope of becoming the next Solar King/Queen. This first season also includes 60 player levels, 50 Sharps/Streets clan progression levels and a free 25-level Solar Pass featuring various rewards, including cosmetics and an exclusive car.</em></p>
<p><strong>Season 2 – Ibiza city makes its comeback</strong></p>
<p><em>This second season marks the return of a familiar location that TDU2 fans have known for 13 years: Ibiza (Eivissa in Catalan) is back in TDUSC, more splendid than ever. Players will be able to discover the city and its outskirts, recreated at 1:1 scale in the KT Engine, offering players a different and complementary experience to Hong Kong Island, 3 months after the game’s release. The season will be accompanied by an island-exclusive clan progression with 20 new levels, a Solar Pass, new rewards and exclusive cars, including 5 car models revisited for the occasion.</em></p>
<p><strong>Season 3 – Clan War, a constantly evolving game mode</strong></p>
<p><em>This third season revolves around a clash between the Sharps (whose members consider themselves the elite of sophistication and luxury) and the Streets (provocative and sometimes extreme, seeking to make their mark) across Hong Kong Island and Ibiza/Eivissa, with the arrival of the clan war. This season will also feature 30 new clan progression levels and seasonal content additions.</em></p>
<p><strong>Season 4 – The Casino, an iconic location in the Unlimited series</strong></p>
<p><em>The fourth and final season of Year 1 marks the grand return of the Casino, a favorite of Test Drive Unlimited 2 fans. This new Solar Crown version of the Casino will offer players the chance to wager their virtual currency through a variety of activities, including poker and slot machines. In addition to bringing 50 player levels, the Casino will allow players to win exclusive new cars, cosmetics and rewards.</em></p>
<p>Obviously, alongside these seasonal content updates, KT Racing will be updating the game in tandem with player feedback. There will be ongoing work on the cameras and steering wheel animations in first person cockpit views, for example. They are also considering fan requests like Real Estate, motorcycles and more.</p>
<hr>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/07/07/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-announced-release-date-consoles/">Announced way back in 2020</a>, it’s been a long wait for fans of earlier games in the series – the last of which arrived in the early 2010s for PS3 and Xbox 360 – to have a true confirmation of when Solar Crown will be released. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/07/07/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-announced-release-date-consoles/">First planned for September 2022</a>, KT Racing has been afforded a further two years to bring their vision for Test Drive Unlimited to fruition.</p>
<p>Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown will take players to Hong Kong Island, featuring a full-sized recreation of reality, with a blend of built up cities and the thick wilderness. There will be plenty of high speed racing to be found within this game and setting, and players will choose between the Sharp and Street clans that vie for supremacy on Hong Kong’s roads, but TDU has always been about celebrating cars and car culture, as much as the racing itself. The intention is for this to be more of a social driving MMO, in contrast to the car bonanza of other open world racers.</p>
<p><em>Source: press release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Floops Big House Adventure is a Nickelodeon Saturday morning gross-out shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/floops-big-house-adventure-is-a-nickelodeon-saturday-morning-gross-out-shooter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/floops-big-house-adventure-is-a-nickelodeon-saturday-morning-gross-out-shooter.968136/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/floops-big-house-adventure-is-a-nickelodeon-saturday-morning-gross-out-shooter<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>“90's references galore!”</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/floops-big-house-adventure.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Buttery Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>I won an awful <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-board-games-on-pc">board game</a> from Nickelodeon once. I say “won”. Actually, I got disconnected phoning into a competition line after I’d gotten through, got upset loudly, my mum called them to complain, they fast tracked me to the next competition thing, I got the quiz answer wrong, and the presenter pretended he’d heard the right answer and pulled a prize out of the big prize bucket. It was a copy of The Game of Life, possibly the least exciting board game a child can win.</p>
<p>The game was dog water, and there’s probably a lesson in there somewhere about how cool and good it is to whine until you get free things, but we don’t have time for that. Instead, I’d like to draw your attention to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/floop-big-house-adventure">Floops Big House Adventure</a>. It’s a grungy, slimy, Aaahh!!! Real Monsters meets Ren and Stimpy Saturday morning shooter. Some of you will already hate it from the header screenshot, I imagine. Personally, the art drew me right in.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Floops Big House Adventure Release Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X-M3NY-u7GI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Floops Big House Adventure Release Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X-M3NY-u7GI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/X-M3NY-u7GI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X-M3NY-u7GI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>It’s pretty simple as far as the shooting of it all goes. Horrible little bastards come at from all angles, and you do gun violence at them with a selection of collectable weapons. Floop farts when you get hit, and his life is measured out in tacos, to paraphrase T.S Eliot. Shoot enough horrible little bastards, and a horrible big bastard shows up.</p>
<p>There’s some hopping hairball freaks that look perpetually pained until they jump, at which time their agonised gaze twists into a faint flatulence smile, as if temporarily relieved from crippling joint pain. There’s some Bart Vs The Space Mutants-ass tentacle blobs. There’s an upgrade shop ran by a smoking, anus-headed gentlemen named Bob.</p>
<p>I played with mouse and keyboard, but it’s a little stiff like that, so controller is the way to go here - it gets more bullet-hellish as you progress. So say the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2783290/Floops_Big_House_Adventure/">Steam page</a>:</p>
<blockquote>FEATURES
<ul>
<li>Fast runs - Floops can be beat in under 20 minutes!</li>
<li>Retro Saturday morning cartoon action!</li>
<li>Nostalgic Nickelodeon art style!</li>
<li>90's references galore! Spot them all throughout Floops House.</li>
<li>Random waves will have you on your toes as cartoon mayhem erupts. Learn the various enemies attacks and patterns to rack up the high score!</li>
<li>Item synergies and boosts await! Try them all to see what unique combos you can come up with.</li>
<li>Hardcore Mode! Defeat the game with healing restrictions to test your mettle.</li>
<li>Fun costumes to equip!</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>20 minutes, you say! That’s just enough time to eat several massive bowls of cereal and a couple of lollipops marketed as Too Sour To Handle unless you’re a real enough dude. I actually don't miss the 90's at all, now I think about it.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft, Nintendo praised for improvements to use of minerals from conflict zones]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-nintendo-praised-for-improvements-to-use-of-minerals-from-conflict-zones</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-nintendo-praised-for-improvements-to-use-of-minerals-from-conflict-zones.968124/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-nintendo-praised-for-improvements-to-use-of-minerals-from-conflict-zones<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>While Sony results regress.</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>
An annual report into the use of minerals sourced from conflict zones by major technology companies has praised Microsoft and Nintendo for their efforts to improve over the past year. 
</p>
<p>
But the same report - compiled by former GamesIndustry.biz writer Brendan Sinclair, now at <a href="https://www.unlosingwriter.com/microsoft-improves-conflict-minerals-sourcing-as-sonys-backslide-continues/">Unlosing Writer</a> - also highlighted how Sony had regressed.
</p>
<p>
The use of minerals in hardware manufacturing - most commonly tin, tantalum, tungsten and gold - is tracked by US and EU legislation to ensure companies disclose the countries and specific mines where their resources originate in a bid to ensure these operations aren't funding human rights abuses. 
</p>
<p>
This year's report reflects on an overall dip in standards caused by the Covid pandemic - when inspections were more difficult and conditions more opaque - to the situation this year, which has seen improvements by several major brands. 
</p>
<p>
Microsoft reports that 87 percent of its mineral sources had passed its audit this year, up from 65 percent previously. Nintendo, meanwhile, improved from 95 percent to 100 percent. 
</p>
<p>
"Nintendo has also continued to do business with partners in the DRC and neighbouring countries, which is a good sign," Sinclair wrote. "Before 2022, Nintendo had embraced a policy of not sourcing minerals from conflict-affected and high risk areas, which helped ensure it wasn't funding human rights abuses in those regions, but actually ran against international guidance because in many such places, the mineral trade is the best opportunity to build the local economy and grow political stability that could help end the violence."
</p>
<p>
Sony, however, reported that it's ongoing slide in standards had continued, with just 69 percent of mineral sources up to scratch. It's the third year in a row its percentage has slipped, from in the low 80s previously.
</p>
<p>
Meta saw its pass rate increase from 89 percent back up to 95 percent, where it had sat previously. Logitech also improved, with a 98 percent conformant rate, up from 96 percent last year. 
</p>
<p>
Apple maintains a 100 percent conflict-free audit, though only after acting to removing problem cases as they're identified.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Batman Game Set in Matt Reeves Universe Reportedly in Development]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/batman-game-set-in-matt-reeves-universe-reportedly-in-development/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/batman-game-set-in-matt-reeves-universe-reportedly-in-development.968115/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/batman-game-set-in-matt-reeves-universe-reportedly-in-development/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Batman game might be in development, according to a new rumor <a href="https://puck.news/how-the-wbd-fire-sale-could-play-out/?_cio_id=f6c60601ab8301dced02&amp;utm_campaign=What+I%27m+Hearing+-+LEADS+%288%2F29%2F24%29&amp;utm_content=What+I%27m+Hearing+-+LEADS+%288%2F29%2F24%29&amp;utm_medium=email_action&amp;utm_source=customer.io&amp;utm_term=f6c60601ab8301dced02" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> by film insider Matthew Belloni from Puck News. The article is behind a paywall, but the relevant excerpt was <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1f4pr5v/a_game_set_in_matt_reeves_the_batman_universe_is/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">posted</a> on Reddit:</p>
<p><em>Back in 2020, AT&amp;T tried to sell the Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment video games unit for a cool $4 billion. But months later, it was deemed “too valuable to unload.” Then, when Zaslav took over, many advised him to offload games. But Zaz still sees the games unit as strategic, especially as the various WBD divisions are beginning to collaborate more closely on properties like the upcoming Penguin HBO show and game, both seeded in the 2022 The Batman movie.</em></p>
<p>The game is reportedly set in the Batman universe created by Matt Reeves with the film released theatrically two years ago. While Belloni seems to link this project to the Penguin HBO show (due to air its eight episodes from September 19 to November 10), it appears unlikely that the game is actually centered on the Penguin himself unless it has a strategy focus. The villain certainly isn't known for his action prowess.</p>
<p>A Batman protagonist is certainly easier to imagine, especially after the <a href="https://wccftech.com/warner-bros-games-revenue-decline-suicide-squad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flop</a> of Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League, made by the studio behind the beloved Arkham trilogy. Even so, it is strange that Warner Bros. has approved a game set in a separate universe from the main DCU crafted by James Gunn, who previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/dcu-will-connect-games-movies-and-tv-says-james-gunn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> films, TV shows, and games would all be connected.</p>
<p>It may be a while until we learn more about this project. However, Batman fans can look forward to <a href="https://wccftech.com/batman-arkham-shadow-is-an-exclusive-meta-quest-3-vr-game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Arkham Shadow</a>, a Virtual Reality sequel to Arkham Origins in development at Camouflaj for the Meta Quest 3.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Konami's Castlevania Dominus Collection bundles up three DS hits and one arcade remaster for £20 or $25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/konamis-castlevania-dominus-collection-bundles-up-three-ds-hits-and-one-arcade-remaster-for-20-or-25</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/konamis-castlevania-dominus-collection-bundles-up-three-ds-hits-and-one-arcade-remaster-for-%C2%A320-or-25.968112/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/konamis-castlevania-dominus-collection-bundles-up-three-ds-hits-and-one-arcade-remaster-for-20-or-25<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Here’s one we missed from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-maw-whats-new-in-pc-games-this-week-9">this week’s release round-up</a>, possibly because Konami appear to have given it precisely zero promotion: the Castlevania Dominus Collection, a four-game bundle spanning PC ports of three well-regarded DS Castlevanias, plus a redesigned version of Castlevania Haunted Castle, the first <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/video-game-franchises/castlevania">Castlevania</a> game to grace an arcade machine. It’ll set you back $25, £20 or €25, and my drive-by analysis of the trailer below is that they've done a decent job with the ports.</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Castlevania Dominus Collection Trailer (PEGI) | KONAMI" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TNcsjS7TY0w?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Castlevania Dominus Collection Trailer (PEGI) | KONAMI</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TNcsjS7TY0w?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/TNcsjS7TY0w?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TNcsjS7TY0w" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The DS games in question are Castlevania: Dawn Of Sorrow, in which you can combine souls to make weapons, Castlevania: Portrait Of Ruin, which sees you switching between two protagonists with different abilities, and Castlevania Order of Ecclesia, in which you scour Dracula’s Castle for magic glyphs. All have naturally been reorganised to fit on a single screen, with inventory and map stuff over on the right. In the case of fiddlier DS-specific flourishes, like Dawn Of Sorrow’s drawing mechanic, they’ve come up with some… <a href="https://x.com/KZXcellent/status/1828457055134347594">straightforward solutions</a>. The port of Haunted Castle, meanwhile, includes both a redesigned version with more elaborate pixelart and a straight port of the original. </p>
<p>Oh hang on, I get why we missed this from the round-up. They shadow-dropped it during one of those Nintendo Direct things the Silksong people keep shrieking about, which also brought news that Konami’s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1932640/Suikoden_III_HD_Remaster_Gate_Rune_and_Dunan_Unification_Wars/">Suikoden 1 and 2 HD remasters will arrive in March</a>. Konami are doing a brisk trade in revivals of various kinds at the minute, with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/after-three-hours-of-bloobers-silent-hill-2-its-unclear-who-is-remaking-who">a new version of Silent Hill 2</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/does-metal-gear-solid-need-a-new-kojima-konami-have-many-people-in-mind-but-its-difficult">a new-ish version of Metal Gear Solid 3</a> on the cards.</p>
<p>My thoughts inevitably turn to the future of the Castlevania series. Our buddies the Belmonts and old man Dracula have <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8s6pu6QvkxY">found another lease of life/undeath on Netflix</a>, but it’s been a while since the last actual new Castlevania game, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/castlevania-lords-of-shadow-2-review">underwhelming</a> Lords Of Shadow 2. Konami appear content right now to loan their various vampires and vampire-killers out to games like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/v-rising-is-getting-a-free-castlevania-crossover-to-coincide-with-its-10-launch">V Rising</a>. I’d really love to play a Sonic Mania-style reboot of the 2D series. In the meantime, you can check out the Dominus Collection on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2369900/Castlevania_Dominus_Collection/">Steam</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect board game available to pre-order, with £240 miniatures bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-board-game-available-to-pre-order-with-240-miniatures-bundle</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-board-game-available-to-pre-order-with-%C2%A3240-miniatures-bundle.968106/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-board-game-available-to-pre-order-with-240-miniatures-bundle<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Priority: Hagalaz tells original branching story set during ME3.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-08-30-103336.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>BioWare / Modiphius</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
There's a new <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect">Mass Effect</a> game due to launch in October 2024 - but no, this isn't <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect-5">Mass Effect 5</a>. 
</p>
<p>
Instead, Mass Effect: Priority Hagalaz is a board game for one to four players with a branching narrative, set during the events of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect-3">Mass Effect 3</a>. 
</p>
<p>
As Shepard, Liara, Tali, Garrus and Wrex, you must secure vital information for the Reaper War effort from a crashed Cerberus cruiser, via missions that unlock new story oppurtunities and earn further loyalty from your squadmates.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mass Effect: The Board Game - Priority Hagalaz (Official Trailer)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JnnuVHz7cgo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mass Effect: The Board Game - Priority Hagalaz (Official Trailer)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JnnuVHz7cgo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JnnuVHz7cgo?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Mass Effect: Priority Hagalaz trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JnnuVHz7cgo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Priority Hagalaz seems to fit the feel of Mass Effect well, then, but it also looks the part. There's some gorgeous artwork showing Shepard in action and the crashed Cerberus vessel. Also, if you're willing to pay, you can choose to additionally add an army of highly-detailed miniatures to play with.
</p>
<p>
The base <a href="https://modiphius.net/pages/mass-effect-board-game">Mass Effect: Priority Hagalaz board game</a> is priced at £40, and comes with everything you need to play. But if you fancy upgrading with a set of better miniatures, <a href="https://modiphius.net/collections/mass-effect-the-board-game">you can pay up to £240</a> for a bundle of various other packs, including Shepard (male and female) and squadmates, plus Reaper and Cerberus enemy forces.
</p>
<p>
BioWare's upcoming Mass Effect video game continuation is set to return to the franchise's home of the Milky Way after its excursion to Andromeda. We're not expecting that to arrive for a few more years, however, since the developer has been focused on finishing <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/whisper-it-but-dragon-age-the-veilguard-has-me-thinking-the-unthinkable-it-looks-like-bioware-is-back">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Gamescom Hands-On Preview – Bigger and Better Than Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gamescom-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-gamescom-hands-on-preview-%E2%80%93-bigger-and-better-than-ever.968097/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gamescom-preview/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> is, without a doubt, one of the most anticipated games releasing next year on PC and consoles, and the excitement was palpable during Gamescom 2024, with extremely long lines to try out the game for the very first time since its announcement. During the show, I also had the chance to try out the next entry in the CAPCOM series, playing through a single-player quest that acted more as a tutorial before jumping into a more challenging multiplayer quest focused on hunting the powerful Alpha Doshaguma.</p>
<p>From a gameplay perspective, there isn't a whole lot to say about the single-player quest other than that it served as a decent introduction to some of the series' basic mechanics, story, and setting. Though I never truly cared for the story in any Monster Hunter game, I appreciated how the main character and Palico are now fully voiced, which definitely helped immersion and made me feel more engaged with the characters and world. This quest also showed effectively how the formula has been further streamlined over World and Rise, providing some welcome quality-of-life improvements that continue to address some of the clunkiness the series was known for in the past. I particularly appreciated the Seikret, a dinosaur-meets-bird creature that hunters can use to move around the vast world of Monster Hunter Wilds. This introduction seems to strike a great balance between the scripted mounted animals of World and the Palamutes of Rise, giving players the chance to do quite a few things while mounted, including, for the first ever in the series, switching between two different weapons. This is sure to influence build crafting on the final game quite a bit, as players will likely have to strike a balance for skills that work with both of their weapons of choice.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Monster-Hunter-Wilds-Gamescom-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>While riding on a Seikret allows the hunter to use ranged weapons, having never really used the bow or the bowguns, I opted to go with the two weapons I was more comfortable with: the Long Sword and the Great Sword. Needless to say, I felt instantly at home with both, although my lack of knowledge of Doshaguma forced me to go for more forgiving Foresight Slashes than Iai Spirit Slashes with the Long sword. Though familiar, I appreciated some welcome changes for both weapons. The Long Sword's basic combo string and Foresight Slash, for example, are both enhanced when the Hunter reaches the highest Spirit level, giving users more reasons to hold onto their powered-up Spirit Thrusts and stay at the red Spirit level for longer. For the Greatsword, on the other hand, I did not have much time to discover all the new tweaks that the game will introduce, but the weapon felt as slow yet powerful as it always did, featuring the full array of moves seen in Monster Hunter World.</p>
<p>The biggest change for both weapons, and I'd say the combat as a whole, is the introduction of Focus Mode, which gives players the chance to be more accurate with their attacks, and makes it easier than ever to break parts, as wounds are highlighted when the mode is active. Attacks in Focus Mode can also be woven seamlessly into regular offense, so I expect it will be a big part of the Monster Hunter Wilds gameplay.</p>
<p>One more feature that will set the new entry in the series apart from the rest of the series is its big world, which is more dynamic than ever. During the fight against Alpha Doshaguma, I was caught in a sandstorm, which heavily impacted the combat scenario with limited visibility. My fight was also interrupted by another powerful monster at some point, prompting more environmental changes that looked impressive. Sadly, it was difficult to fully appreciate all this due to the roughness of the PlayStation 5 demo. Resolution was obviously rather low, and the demo never ran at higher than 30 FPS, which threw me off quite a bit, coming from the high framerate experience easily achievable with World and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/monster-hunter-rise-pc-dont-fear-the-rampage/">Rise on PC</a>. As there's still some time before the game's release, I would expect this to improve considerably in the final release.</p>
<p>While Monster Hunter Wilds doesn't revolutionize the series' formula in any way, it competently continues to smooth out some of the formula's rough edges to present a more engaging experience. This little taste of the experience left me hungering for more, and I really cannot wait to see what surprises the game has in store for hunters when it launches on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S next year.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2's free strategy game Kingdoms update is coming in three parts, with the first due in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2s-free-strategy-game-kingdoms-update-is-coming-in-three-parts-with-the-first-due-in-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/darkest-dungeon-2s-free-strategy-game-kingdoms-update-is-coming-in-three-parts-with-the-first-due-in-2024.968094/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2s-free-strategy-game-kingdoms-update-is-coming-in-three-parts-with-the-first-due-in-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Also, look forward to some paid DLC about night-soil</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Kingdoms-beast-update.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Red Hook</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/darkest-dungeon-2">Darkest Dungeon 2</a>'s Kingdoms mode - a free turn-based boardgame reimagining of the hellish roguelike roadtrip <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> - will release in three modules, Red Hook have announced. The first of this fearful trio, Hunger Of The Beast Clan, is down to launch in Q4 2024, which translates to sometime during the period 1st October to 31st December.</p>
<p>It'll accompany a new paid Darkest Dungeon 2 DLC, Inhuman Bondage, which introduces a new region, a new hero with "...unique" mechanics and a fresh faction of seemingly excrement-themed fiends to slaughter.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
In case you missed it, I <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2s-free-kingdoms-update-remixes-the-first-two-games-into-a-turn-based-strategy-game">spoke to Red Hook about the Kingdoms update at GDC this year</a>. It's both a "remix album" of ideas from each Darkest Dungeon game and a top-down strategy spin-off where you shuffle wagonloads of heroes around a node-based map, defending taverns against waves of eldritch creatures. In addition to training and equipping your heroes and keeping them sane, you'll need to complete a quest chain to track down a boss. Battles are much as in the main Darkest Dungeon 2 campaign, but hero recruitment and progression harken back to the first game's town-dungeon loop.
</p>
<p>
From the looks of things, each Kingdom module will introduce a new enemy faction. As you'd expect, Hunger Of The Beast Clan features the Beastmen, a marauding mass of pugnacious piggies. Back at GDC, Red Hook told me that the other two factions are the Coven (witches) and the Crimson Courtiers (perma-debuff-inflicting insect vampires). No clue what order they'll arrive in.
</p>
<p>
As for the Inhuman Bondage DLC, the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/?emclan=103582791472084254&amp;emgid=4586440679309658784">Steam announcement post</a> tantalises with the prospect of "ancient sepulchers oozing with the gelatinous night-soil of a thousand corpses". Liquid cadaver poop, how fun! The new area is the Catacombs, which is said to be equivalent in size to the existing Sluice, an unmappable and thus, unpredictable optional region. I wonder if it'll be similarly confusing. It sure sounds like it's going to be smelly. Thank god "digital scent technology" never went mainstream, eh. 
</p>
<p>
I'm also pretty curious about this new hero. Darkest Dungeon's heroes aren't exactly known for playing fantasy RPG classes straight, so if they're explicitly branding this one "...unique", it must be a warped creation indeed. Look at those full stops, oozing with suspense. Could the new hero be composed of gelatinous night-soil? Yeah, let's dwell on that image.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Visions of Mana developer Ouka Studios reportedly set to close, days after game's release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/visions-of-mana-developer-ouka-studios-reportedly-set-to-close-days-after-games-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/visions-of-mana-developer-ouka-studios-reportedly-set-to-close-days-after-games-release.968091/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/visions-of-mana-developer-ouka-studios-reportedly-set-to-close-days-after-games-release<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Parent company NetEase behind the decision.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/p6_3-53gr1i892.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Square Enix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Ouka Studios, the developer of the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> published action-RPG Visions of Mana, is reportedly set to close as its parent company NetEase has cut "all but a handful of jobs".
</p>
<p>
The news comes as part of a report from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-08-30/tencent-netease-rethink-japan-approach-as-game-strategy-stalls">Bloomberg</a> on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/tencent">Tencent</a> and NetEase, two of China's biggest game publishers, both of which are scaling back investment in Japanese studios.
</p>
<p>
Ouka Studios opened in 2020 and hired staff from the likes of Capcom and Bandai Namco, but with the majority of staff laid off, those who remain will oversee the release of the studio's final games before it shuts.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Visions of Mana | Launch Date Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/slGNz-ySDfY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Visions of Mana | Launch Date Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/slGNz-ySDfY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/slGNz-ySDfY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Visions of Mana | Launch Date Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=slGNz-ySDfY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>

In a follow-up post on social media, reporter Takashi Mochizuki added that NetEase has been cutting staff at Ouka Studios since at least spring this year.
</p>
<p>
Visions of Mana released earlier this week, but it would appear the decision to shut the studio is not an immediate reaction to the launch.
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Seeing reactions to the story in English, I can add one thing that is in the Japanese version of the same story: NetEase has been cutting staff at Ouka for a while, since this spring at least.<a href="https://t.co/NxoCMo0bTZ">https://t.co/NxoCMo0bTZ</a></p>— Takashi Mochizuki (@6d6f636869) <a href="https://twitter.com/6d6f636869/status/1829342570042048776?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 30, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
According to Bloomberg sources, Tencent has already backed out of several funding commitments for new games as it reconsiders investment in the Japanese games industry.
</p>
<p>
One such deal was with Bandai Namco to publish the mobile edition of MMORPG Blue Protocol, but earlier this week it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bandai-namco-and-amazon-games-published-mmorpg-blue-protocol-has-worldwide-release-cancelled">announced the game would end service early next year</a>.
</p>
<p>
Tencent has reportedly been frustrated with Japanese developers, due to a mismatch in ambition. Where the Chinese company is seeking large franchises to take global and has set high expectations, Japanese developers seek to tightly control their franchises. That's in addition to a shrinking industry post-Covid, resulting in mass layoffs.
</p>
<p>
In an emailed statement to Bloomberg, Tencent said it remains committed to its partner studios and developing its business in Japan.
</p>
<p>
NetEase, meanwhile, had "nothing to announce" with regards to the closure of Ouka. "In supporting studios outside China, we craft our strategy based on our goal of providing better gaming experiences to local and global players," a NetEase spokesperson said. The company is "thus always making necessary adjustments to reflect market conditions."
</p>
<p>
Tencent is reportedly working on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-mobile-game-reportedly-in-development-at-tencent">mobile games based on Elden Ring</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-14-is-reportedly-coming-to-mobile">Final Fantasy 14</a>, though it also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tencent-cancels-unannounced-nier-mobile-game">cancelled an unannounced NieR mobile game</a> earlier this year.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy partner with Annapurna to co-finance Control 2 and explore Control and Alan Wake TV and film adaptations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/remedy-partner-with-annapurna-to-co-finance-control-2-and-explore-control-and-alan-wake-tv-and-film-adaptations</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-partner-with-annapurna-to-co-finance-control-2-and-explore-control-and-alan-wake-tv-and-film-adaptations.968088/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/remedy-partner-with-annapurna-to-co-finance-control-2-and-explore-control-and-alan-wake-tv-and-film-adaptations<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>The poster has a big pile of money behind it</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/control_ultimate_edition_2.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Remedy Entertainment</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Remedy were “thrilled as Finnish people can be” to <a href="https://www.remedygames.com/article/remedy-and-annapurna-announce-a-strategic-cooperation-agreement">announce yesterday</a> that they’ve secured funding for a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/control-review">Control</a> sequel in a co-financing deal with Annapurna, who are also helping the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/alan-wake">Alan Wake</a> studio bring their connected universe to “film, TV, and beyond”.</p>
<p>While I’m pretty jazzed to see what the coffee-addled minds that brought us <a href="https://youtu.be/qAtWVCKKOHk">Threshold Kids</a> can conjure up under that tantalising ‘beyond’ label, I’ll skip the speculation from now. Here’s the skinny from Remedy’s communications director Thomas Puha:</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Alan Wake 2: HERALD OF DARKNESS Live Performance at The Game Awards (Old Gods of Asgard)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yQ9Ydz7jo6I?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Alan Wake 2: HERALD OF DARKNESS Live Performance at The Game Awards (Old Gods of Asgard)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yQ9Ydz7jo6I?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/yQ9Ydz7jo6I?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yQ9Ydz7jo6I" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<blockquote><p>What does that mean for you, our dear fans? Above all it means Remedy is able to make Control 2 exactly the game we want it to be, while we now also have an incredible partner to extend our IPs to other mediums. We are also going to be publishing Control 2 ourselves. When I look at all the games we have in the pipeline, the future of Remedy is incredibly exciting. You can trust us to keep bringing you incredible video game experiences.</p></blockquote>
<p>And here’s what Sammy-Sammy Lake-Lake had to say about it. I can call him that because we’re mates*:</p>
<blockquote><p>“I’m absolutely thrilled (yes!) by this opportunity to expand the story of Alan Wake and our whole Remedy Connected Universe to mediums beyond games, and to build all of this in close collaboration, games, film, TV, and other mediums as well, as one unified vision. I trust Annapurna are the perfect partner for us to make this dream come true.”</p></blockquote>
<p>*Not actual mates</p>
<p>This does all mean that AMC’s Alan Wake show won’t be happening, however. "We have moved on from AMC amicably as their rights to Alan Wake expired,” Puha told <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/horror-shows/remedy-confirms-the-alan-wake-amc-tv-series-is-dead-as-it-confirms-new-partnership-with-annapurna-to-develop-and-produce-control-and-alan-wake-franchises-for-film-and-television/">Games Radar</a>.</p>
<p>Annapurna are, of course, them behind games like beloved<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-space-games-on-pc"> space</a> puzzler <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/outer-wilds">Outer Wilds</a>, secret best game ever made <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/neon-white">Neon White</a>, and we-saw-the-internet-coming-em-up <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/stray">Stray</a>, all published under their Annapurna Interactive label. On the other side of the coin, Annapurna have a mixed reputation for looking after partner developers. A couple years back, People Make Games put out a <a href="https://youtu.be/xDPzZkx0cPs">report</a> about “Three Indie Superstars Accused of Emotional Abuse”, all of whom had published games under Annapurna Interactive, who were allegedly unsupportive during the highlighted cases.</p>
<p>Remedy’s most recent game was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/alan-wake-2">Alan Wake 2</a>, which had<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/alan-wake-2-fastest-selling-remedy-game-but-yet-to-turn-a-profit"> yet to turn a profit</a> as of this February. “A stylistic tour de force and one of the most unique and confident horror games in recent years,” decreed Katharine (RPS in peace) in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-2-review">her review</a>. “It might not hit every beat perfectly, but Remedy's daft and over the top sense of humour help bring much-needed levity to its genuine thrills and jump scares.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Patch Notes #2: How does the game industry survive beyond 2025?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/patch-notes-2-how-does-the-game-industry-survive-beyond-2025-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/patch-notes-2-how-does-the-game-industry-survive-beyond-2025.968082/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/patch-notes-2-how-does-the-game-industry-survive-beyond-2025-<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We're back, and I mean that in a very literal sense. We've just returned from Gamescom 2024 where this (rather fatigued) editor had a wonderful time catching up with old faces and new.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Most of our week was spent flitting between the business areas, chatting all things video games with developers, publishers, studio leaders, and pretty much anybody PR would let us in a room with. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/program/gamescom">Our ongoing Gamescom coverage is right here, so do tuck in</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Outside of the show, the flags were cracking, the bratwurst was sizzling, and the Kolsch was flowing. I know, because that's pretty much all I could hear from my hotel room in Alter Markt. Yes, I chose to slap myself in the middle of a market square bustling with interlopers whose sole purpose in life was to prevent me from sleeping. Yes, it was a colossal mistake. Yes, I resent everyone involved. Will I learn from that fatal error and book a room in a more sedate location next year? Look, I'll give it a shot.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mistakes are opportunities for growth, and that rather fortuitously brings me onto the subject of this edition of Patch Notes: how can the game industry learn from its own repeated failings to ensure we don't just 'survive until 2025,' but thrive in the years beyond?</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a question I desperately needed to answer heading to Gamescom. I'd seen the phrase 'survive to 2025' tossed around on social media, and it seems to imply all the industry needs to do is collectively endure until the turn of the year. At that point, I suppose, the chaos that has dominated the news cycle since 2023 (layoffs, funding woes, and studio closures) will dissipate into the aether.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A warm sun will rise on a rejuvenated industry, ushering in a new era of stability and prosperity. Those who remain will breathe a collective sigh of relief, safe in the knowledge that, this year, things will be different. It feels like optimism bordering on wilful disbelief.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Many of those I spoke with at the show agreed. There was a sense the industry too often surrenders itself to a vicious cycle of growth and collapse perceived as unavoidable. It isn't–but only if we learn, and I mean really learn, from our mistakes. To help us do that, I collected reams of advice from industry experts that might hopefully allow us to break the cycle.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The view from the show floor: Long term survival will demand creative clarity, frequent reality checks, and the slow demise of capitalism">The view from the show floor: Long term survival will demand creative clarity, frequent reality checks, and the slow demise of capitalism</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"If the question is 'what do we do about capitalism?' then you're into a very different set of economic, philosophical, and political issues," says Ustwo Games lead producer John Lau.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He suggests the industry needs to address the "incentivisation structures" that are currently in place on a commercial level in order to survive. It's a big ask, but on the upside, building incentivisation structures is exactly what developers do for a living.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"What is it we can do to identify where things aren't working and then slowly chip away at those things? If that feels too big, I would say it's about understanding you are at the mercy of these forces," he adds. "You cannot ignore them. You cannot ignore the fact you're in a commercial industry. Therefore you must educate yourself. One has to build commercial literacy–among colleagues and co-workers."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Building literacy means fully engaging with the issues that have smashed through the industry like a wrecking ball. Burying our heads in the sand is no longer an option. "You can't just say 'hey, look, I'm an artist. I'm making art. I've got big ideas.' Yes, that's fantastic. But the image of a game developer as a lone artist [is outdated]," he continues.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"If that's what you're doing, you are leaving yourself incredibly vulnerable to these flawed, dysfunctional structures. You have to understand the commercial environment you're working in is part of the problem–as much as [the creative question of] 'how do I make a person feel this way?'"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hooded Horse chief product officer Ashkan Namousi says longevity is rooted in sustainable business practices. It's a soundbite we've heard often. Mainly when companies are punting thousands of workers out of the door in pursuit of "sustainable growth." But for Namousi, a sustainable enterprise is one governed by leaders who aren't over-zealous, under-prepared, and dancing to the intoxicating tunes of external stakeholders.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It's about always focusing on effectiveness and cost effectiveness, and trying not to get carried away with unfettered creativity and ambition–without reflection and without control," he says. "[That ambition] is constantly fed into by other stakeholders who want a stake in what you do. They almost way you to say 'I need $20 million,' because they think if you're going to have 400 percent ROI, so they'd much rathe go in with $20 million than $2 million so they can take a bigger share of revenue, they can have a bigger buyout, they can get the IP–all that jazz.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Focus on being effective and creating new ideas for you and your company. Stay focused on 'what is the kind of game you're making? What is the target audience?' Don't just take any deal that comes your way. Believe in your creative vision and the potential of the game. You also need to have a reality check. What happens if it doesn't [find success]?"</span></p><p>Image via Gamescom</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If we don't knock it out of the park and haven't prepared accordingly, the cycle will repeat. Atari CEO Wade Rosen believes its almost human nature to lean into the perceived inevitability of it all, but feels we can dismantle the wheel by fighting that urge.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It's knowing [you should] stash some cash away for a rainy day and not just immediately plow it back into development or projects and assume that's going to project into the future. It's really looking more to the future than the past, and understanding that the past is not the most accurate predictor–especially the short term past," he says.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It's realizing that when things are good, they're not always going to be good. And when they're bad, they're not always going to be bad. And having enough cash in the bank to survive those downturns without having to drastically cut teams, but that also means having the discipline to not drastically increase teams as well."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Money is the problem, then? Or at the very least, how it's perceived and distributed across the industry. Glowmade co-founder Jonny Hopper says we need to be "realistic" about spending, especially when–as was the case during the pandemic–it feels like investing massive sums of cash is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>the</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> golden ticket to exponential growth.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Certainly, when you're [a small studio] money is terrifying. I think you need to get comfortable with that," he adds. "What's happened is, we've seen some really big players–and COVID started it because there was massive demand–send money flooding [into the market]. Everyone was sat at home playing games, and suddenly there was loads of money and loads of demand."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hopper feels we're now in a period of "readjustment," but reiterates we have to learn from that era of flagrant, unadulterated spending to avoid falling back into old habits when the good times come around again. When investors are whispering sweet nothings in your ear, promising you the world and decadent amounts of ROI, it's vital to remember precisely what you set out to achieve.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Have clarity about your vision," says Rebellion art director Ryan Greene, explaining how to stay on the straight and narrow during production. "Know what you want to make. How much time it will take to make. And the person power you'll need to make it. Make the game you can make, and not necessarily the game you want to make. It takes a lot to do that. To really distill the soul of your game and then focus on it. Don't get distracted by other stuff."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Words to live by? We'll let you decide.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Status Report: The headlines that matter">Status Report: The headlines that matter</h2><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/microsoft-and-activision-blizzard-accused-of-bad-faith-bargaining-by-raven-software-union-workers">Microsoft and Activision Blizzard accused of 'bad faith bargaining' by Raven Software union workers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Microsoft's merger with Activision Blizzard turned into something of a PR nightmare. The company had to defend itself against accusations of rampant monopolisation from regulators and convince the masses that a $68.7 billion splurge would be a Very Good Thing. The 1,900 layoffs that followed probably didn't do the company any favors in that regard, but the labor neutrality agreement it signed with Communications Workers of America in 2022 was a clear and obvious win. It has enabled multiple unions to arise unimpeded within Microsoft's hallowed halls, but are those developers actually being heard? The unionized workers at Activision Blizzard subsidiary Raven Software would say 'no,' and have now filed a complaint with the National Labor Relations Board expressing as much. Is Microsoft about to turn a huge win into a colossal loss? Let's wait and see.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/animal-crossing-pocket-camp-is-shutting-down-in-november-then-reopening-as-a-paid-game">Animal Crossing: Pocket Camp is shutting down in November, then reopening as a paid game</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">How very Nintendo. As you'd expect from a company that seems to operate on a different wavelength from the rest of the industry, the Super Mario maker is shutting down </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Crossing: Pocket Camp</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in November–but only to relaunch the mobile title as a paid app. The premium version will support save data transfer so players can protect their delectable homeware collection, cherished bells, and insurmountable debt. Whether by hook or crook, you've gotta pay Mr. Nook.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/black-myth-wukong-has-sold-10-million-copies-in-five-days">Black Myth: Wukong has sold 10 million copies worldwide</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Shifting 10 million copies would be a startling achievement for any studio. But moving that many copies in one week when you were, until recently, a relatively unknown indie developer that had previously launched a grand total of zero titles? Utter madness. For context, it took </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Starfield</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> around two weeks to attract 10 million players, and that was a first-party Xbox Game Studios title that debuted on Game Pass. Sony's latest and greatest </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Marvel's Spider-Man 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> reached 10 million sales in around four months. Welcome to the big leagues. Now, if only Black Myth developer Game Science would address those workplace toxicity allegations.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Feature Creep: Originals and interviews for the discerning reader"><span>Feature Creep: Originals and interviews for the discerning reader</span></h2><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/firaxis-big-swing-with-civilization-vii-convincing-players-to-actually-finish-their-games">Firaxis' big swing with Civilization VII? Convincing players to actually finish their games</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Fewer than 50 percent of players completed their games in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization V</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">I. it's a statistic that haunted developer Firaxis, pushing it consider how it can bump those rookie numbers up with the sequel. One tactic? Bottle the unadulterated fun of exploring a brand new world and sprinkle it everywhere. Another? Tweak pacing by implementing a new age system. One more? Reveal that metric to a reporter so they'll stick it in a headline and make your players feel deeply ashamed. That last one is on me.&nbsp;</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/-a-rising-tide-floats-all-boats-xbox-on-the-universal-benefits-of-accessible-design">'A rising tide floats all boats': Xbox on the universal benefits of accessible design</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> This interview with Xbox senior accessibility product manager Kaitlyn Jones and principal designer Chris Kujawski was a personal highlight of Gamescom 2024. The console maker has been leading by example in the accessibility space for years, and it was fascinating to learn more about its broader design philosophy when it comes to developing inclusive hardware like the recently announced Xbox Adaptive Joystick.&nbsp;</span></p></div></li></ul></div><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/iterative-narrative-design-for-video-games-an-indie-approach">Iterative narrative design for video games–an indie approach</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">We've all heard the phrase 'kill your darlings,' but what if killing them also flatlines your workflow? Expert Game Developer blogger Leander Burger discusses how to avoid that undesirable outcome by explaining how they quickly&nbsp;and effectively iterate on narrative content.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/book-excerpt-animal-crossing">Book Excerpt: Animal Crossing tracks the rise of the original cozy life sim</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">What's better than playing Animal Crossing with a nice mug of tea? What about learning how your favourite slice-of-life simulator was wrestled into being (ideally with a nice mug of tea)? In this excerpt from Boss Fight Books' recent release, video game preservationist and historian Kelsey Lewin tells the story of how a mundane-sounding game full of bug-catching, letter-writing, and furniture-collecting became one of Nintendo's most-loved franchises.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gamescom-2024-a-record-breaking-year-for-the-world-s-largest-games-event">Gamescom 2024: a record-breaking year for the world's largest games event</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Intrepid Omdia analysts George Jijiashvili and Liam Deane once again ventured to the booth-strewn metropolis of the Koelnmesse in search of meaty insights and hot takeaways. Their read this year? Global publishers are flexing their muscles, AI is becoming increasingly visible, and event attendance was through the roof.&nbsp;</span></p></div></li></ul></div></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three Fallout Games Are Free on Epic Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/three-fallout-games-free-epic-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/three-fallout-games-are-free-on-epic-right-now.968073/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/three-fallout-games-free-epic-games/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-55173">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Epic Games is giving away three <strong>free </strong>Fallout games on PC through the Epic Games Store until September 5. This one-stop collection features Fallout, Fallout 2, and Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel, and it’s the perfect introduction for anyone wanting to explore the origins of this stellar post-apocalyptic series.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-back-to-the-beginning">Back to the Beginning</h2>



<p>Fallout debuted in 1997 exclusively on PC, followed up shortly after with Fallout 2. In 2001, Fallout Tactics was released as something of a spin-off title, but it kept much of what made the original games so enjoyable and popular.</p>



<p>It’s a far cry from the action RPG elements that you might be used to from the ‘modern’ games, but anyone wanting to explore the birth of this legendary franchise should at least <strong>try </strong>Fallout and Fallout 2.</p>



<p>Until September 5, you can secure this trio of titles on Epic Games, and once you’ve picked them up, they’re yours to keep forever. It’s not the first time they’ve been offered for free, but it’s another solid opportunity to pick up three great games without paying a penny for them.</p>



<p>Fallout is still experiencing rampant popularity following the success of the Fallout television show that debuted on Prime Video in April. The series saw millions of players find their way into the series and titles like Fallout 76 broke all-time high player count records.</p>



<p>Will you be landing the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/bundles/fallout-classic-collection" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Fallout classic collection on Epic Games</a>?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/">XDefiant is in danger of failing</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-forever-winter-early-access-september/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-forever-winter-early-access-september/">The Forever Winter Launches Into Early Access This September</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Developer Fun Dog Studios finally graces us with a release date for their PvPvE extraction shooter in which you play a nobody!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/">EXCLUSIVE – XDefiant is on Borrowed Time as Player Numbers Decline Rapidly</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to several sources at Ubisoft, Ubisoft San Francisco has until the end of Season 3 of XDefiant to improve the game’s bleak player numbers.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-can-you-play-space-marine-2-release-times/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-can-you-play-space-marine-2-release-times/">When Can You Play Space Marine 2? – Full Release Times</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ahead of the game’s release, developer Saber Interactive has announced full unlock and release times for when you can play Space Marine 2.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-wukong-has-exclusivity-deal-with-playstation-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-wukong-has-exclusivity-deal-with-playstation-its-claimed/">Black Myth: Wukong Has Exclusivity Deal With PlayStation, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to a new report, Black Myth: Wukong isn’t on Xbox yet because of an exclusivity deal with PlayStation</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord Review – A fun, frenetic hero shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/concord-review-a-fun-frenetic-hero-shooter/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-review-%E2%80%93-a-fun-frenetic-hero-shooter.968064/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/concord-review-a-fun-frenetic-hero-shooter/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>I’m really struggling with <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/concord">Concord</a> – struggling to put it down, that is. <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/sony">Sony</a>’s latest live service gamble is a fun, frenetic hero shooter touting beautifully polished gunplay and a persistent story told through weekly character-focused cinematics.</p>
<p><iframe title="Concord - Launch Trailer I PS5 &amp; PC Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xQB_2FF2G1o?start=1&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>To say the odds are stacked against Concord would be an understatement. Not only is this a new IP and a new developer (<a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/firewalk-studios">Firewalk Studios</a>), it’s going up against some gnarly juggernauts while also daring to eschew the zero-cost entry of its free-to-play rivals. After years spent throwing money at loot boxes and time-hungry battle passes, paying a one-time fee feels weirdly refreshing in the knowledge that every piece of playable content will be instantly unlocked when it becomes available without needing to grind out challenges against the clock or scrabble for in-game currency.</p>


<p>At launch, Concord features a total of 6 modes, 12 maps, and 16 Freegunners. Each of the game’s space-faring mercenaries has their own unique kit, slotting nicely into one of several loose archetypes. For example, 1-OFF – the Concord crew’s cleaning-obsessed robot – can use his primary weapon and deployable gadget to suck up enemy projectiles, charging his high-damage trash grenades in the process.Meanwhile, Vale’s loadout is a little more straightforward, packing a punchy sniper rifle, trip mines, and a high vertical leap that can give her the drop on unsuspecting enemies below.</p>
<p>There are a number of interesting deviations away from the established hero shooter formula, such as the omission of “ultimate” abilities. Considered a subgenre staple, their removal encourages players to focus on the core kit of each hero and how they synergise with squadmates, instead of trying to line up a table-turning set piece with a single, well-timed button press.</p>


<p>This also benefits the quicker tempo of Concord’s game modes, which are more akin to those of a <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/call-of-duty">Call of Duty</a> game rather than <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/overwatch">Overwatch</a>. Takedown is your bog standard team deathmatch with Trophy Hunt copying COD’s Killed Confirmed match rules, only awarding points if players retrieve the glowing node left behind by downed enemies. Meanwhile Area Control and Signal Chase are more objective-focused with teams battling to claim territory then defend it from invaders. Concord also features a more competitive “Rivals” playlist – in Cargo Run and Clash Point you fight across multiple rounds with no respawns</p>
<p>It’s a decent amount of content for players on day one with more maps, modes, and Freegunners on the way. A couple of additional arenas may have been nice though it seems Firewalk Studios has focused where it matters most, presenting a cast of heroes that all feel fun to play. Firing weapons and using abilities is seamless, with all but a couple of Freegunners being able to perform evasive dodge manoeuvres and a double (or even a triple) jump. Firefights take on an even more tactical dimension thanks to Concord’s tight level designs, weaving together open spaces, crowded interiors, and vertical climbs to great effect.</p>
<p>The desire to master your favourite Freegunners will keep you coming back match after match, unlocking rewards as you progress. However, customising your crew is one of the only areas where Concord disappoints at launch. There’s a real lack of interesting cosmetics and accessories with most unlockable skins being recoloured versions of each hero’s base appearance. As a premium game, Concord doesn’t need to flog glitzy costumes to wring cash out of its players, though it wouldn’t hurt to have at least a few eye-catching designs for each Freegunner.</p>

<p>Something you will want to focus on unlocking is the different “Variants” for your favourite heroes. Each one adds a perk-like Combat Trait that can change your playstyle. For example, Lennox I will reload his equipped gun when dodging, whereas Lennox II grants an extended magazine for both of his weapons. Hopefully, as Concord rolls out its roadmap of new content and features, we’ll get more ways to deeply customise our crew’s visuals as well as how they play.</p>
<p>Hopefully we’ll get to know them better, too. Each week, Firewalk will add a new in-game vignette, cinematics that look to fill in some of Concord’s backstory. With the second of these videos having only just debuted, precisely how much these will enrich the overall experience remains to be seen. So far, we’ve been treated to some banter between crewmates and some light probing into the game’s wider lore. Speaking of which, Concord features a meaty codex called the Galactic Guide, a space map teeming with planets, travel routes, characters, and other info for those who want to immerse themselves in this sci-fi universe. As hooked as I am, the overwhelming mass of lore entries and walls of text don’t feel like an intuitive way of presenting this sprawling archive of world-building.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy Partners with Annapurna Interactive for Control 2; Films and TV Shows Also Planned]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/remedy-partners-with-annapurna-interactive-for-control-2-films-and-tv-shows-also-planned/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-partners-with-annapurna-interactive-for-control-2-films-and-tv-shows-also-planned.968058/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/remedy-partners-with-annapurna-interactive-for-control-2-films-and-tv-shows-also-planned/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Remedy has announced a new partnership with Annapurna Interactive on various projects, starting with Control 2. The sequel will be co-financed (with an even split) between the two companies, even though the IP remains in the hands of Remedy, which will be self-publishing Control 2. But the deal is also important because it aims to bring Control and Alan Wake to film and television, leveraging Annapurna's expertise in those mediums.</p>
<p>Tero Virtala, CEO of Remedy Entertainment, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>At Remedy, our primary focus continues to be what we do best—crafting industry-defining video games that have earned us global recognition. Now, the time is right to expand the reach of Remedy's beloved franchises to an even broader global audience through film, television, and more. In Annapurna, we have found an outstanding partner who shares our ambition and passion for immersive storytelling. We are excited to see them bring the universes and characters we have created to life in new mediums, thanks to this unique deal.</em></p>
<p>Hector Sanchez, Annapurna's President of Interactive and New Media, stated:</p>
<p><em>This deal with Remedy isn't just about adapting great games—-it's about breaking new ground in how companies can collaborate. By backing Remedy's move toward self-publishing, we're putting our faith in their vision. We know from experience that Remedy is a first-class games development partner, and we’re excited to share their work with an even wider audience by bringing the Control and Alan Wake universes to film, television, and beyond.</em></p>
<p>Creative Director Sam Lake added:</p>
<p><em>I’m absolutely thrilled (yes!) by this opportunity to expand the story of Alan Wake and our whole Remedy Connected Universe to mediums beyond games and to build all of this in close collaboration, games, film, TV, and other mediums as well, as one unified vision. I trust Annapurna are the perfect partner for us to make this dream come true.</em></p>
<p>Control 2 is currently getting close to starting production, so it may be another couple of years before we see its release. Meanwhile, the Finnish studio continues working on Codename Condor (a Control multiplayer spin-off) and the Max Payne 1&amp;2 Remake, while Kestrel (a live service game) was <a href="https://wccftech.com/remedy-cancels-co-op-multiplayer-game-project-kestrel-formerly-vanguard-will-focus-on-alan-wake-and-control/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">canceled</a> in May.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord 1-OFF Guide: Tips, Variants, and Abilities]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/concord-1-off-guide-tips-variants-and-abilities/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-1-off-guide-tips-variants-and-abilities.968025/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/concord-1-off-guide-tips-variants-and-abilities/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>In this <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/concord">Concord</a> 1-OFF guide we’ll be giving an overview of the Northstar crew’s resident robot cleaner. At first, it’s not entirely clear what his role on the battlefield is, and with 1-OFF being such an easy target for enemies to hit, they’ll make short work of him if you fail to grasp the basics of his nuanced loadout.</p>
<p><iframe title="Concord - 1-0FF Abilities Trailer | PS5 &amp; PC Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dMesmz2wpgA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>1-OFF slots nicely into the tank archetype of character. Thanks to a meaty health bar and abilities designed to soak up damage, he’s a great pick for players wanting to wade into the frontline, drawing attention away from more vulnerable teammates as they lay down support fire. Like Emari, he’s particularly useful when locking down zones in objective-based modes such as Area Control and Signal Chase.</p>


<h2>Concord 1-OFF Guide: Loadout</h2>
<p><strong>CC-1898 Industrial Vacuum</strong></p>
<p>1-OFF’s primary weapon does what it says on the tin. Pulling the trigger while aimed toward enemies will vacuum up any incoming bullets and projects, effectively nullifying any damage they might do.</p>

<p><strong>Pressure Blaster</strong></p>
<p>Switching weapons will turn 1-OFF’s vacuum into an air cannon that shoots a constant stream that’s most effective at mid range. The damage output isn’t particularly great though it can help pick off stragglers and cause panic.</p>
<p><strong>Air Barrier</strong></p>
<p>When deployed, this vent-like gadget emits an air geyser that swats away bullets and projectiles, acting somewhat similarly to 1-OFF’s vacuum.</p>
<p><strong>Trash Bomb</strong></p>
<p>A powerful thrown grenade that will also push back enemies caught in its blast radius. The more projectiles 1-OFF vacuums, the more grenade charges you’ll have.</p>

<h2>Tips on how to play 1-OFF</h2>
<ul>
<li>When a match starts you’ll want to be in the vanguard, ideally supported by a Jabari or Daw who can dish out health and keep you in the fight.</li>
<li>Create a protective barrier for your team by aiming your vacuum where enemy fire is at its most concentrated. Deploy air vents near objectives and in tight spaces, allowing viable pathways for squadmates to retreat.</li>
<li>Switch to the Pressure Blaster when you have the upper hand in a teamfight to help overpower the remaining enemies. Making sure both of 1-OFF’s weapons are regularly reloaded between bouts of actions.</li>
<li>Don’t forget to use your Trash Bombs. Save them for situations where you’re fighting at close range, in tight spaces.<br>
1-OFF doesn’t have a double jump or dodge, so your mobility options are limited. If you need to retreat, don’t turn your back to the enemy team – walk backwards while using the vacuum and air vents.</li>
</ul>


<p>Each playable hero in Concord has one or more Variants, defined by perk-like abilities that can change their playstyle. These can be obtained by completing in-game challenges with plans for more to be added to the game regularly.</p>
<p><strong>1-OFF Variant 1: Trash Dispenser</strong></p>
<p><em>More Trash Bombs with higher damage.</em></p>
<p>This Concord 1-OFF guide has covered the basics of using this unique, fun-to-play tank hero. Sadly, the game’s practice range doesn’t do a great job of demonstrating how certain Fregunners work so you’ll need to get some in-match experience. His loadout won’t appeal to damage-focused players though 1-OFF is relatively easy to pick up and slots nicely into most team compositions.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Memories Off Sousou: Not always true adds PS5 version, delayed to early 2025 in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/memories-off-sousou-not-always-true-adds-ps5-version-delayed-to-early-2025-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/memories-off-sousou-not-always-true-adds-ps5-version-delayed-to-early-2025-in-japan.967995/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/memories-off-sousou-not-always-true-adds-ps5-version-delayed-to-early-2025-in-japan<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Chinese version also planned for release in Asia.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > MAGES. [510 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/colopl/mages">MAGES.</a> has delayed <a title="Genres > Romance Visual Novel [56 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel/romance-visual-novel">romance visual novel</a> <em><a title="Games > Memories Off Sousou: Not always true [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/memories-off-sousou-not-always-true">Memories Off Sousou: Not always true</a></em> from its previously planned 2024 release window to early 2025 in Japan, as well as <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000130.000046985.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that it will now launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,838 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> alongside its previously announced <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,139 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,919 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,120 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> versions. <span id="more-911175"></span></p><p>Additionally, MAGES. announced plans to release an Asian version with support for Simplified Chinese and Traditional Chinese language options. <a href="https://memoriesoff.jp/sousou/zh-hans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Simplified Chinese</a> and <a href="https://memoriesoff.jp/sousou/zh-hant/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Traditional Chinese</a> official websites were also opened alongside its <a href="https://memoriesoff.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Japanese website</a>.</p><p>The game’s voice cast was also announced:</p><ul><li>Sae Sunomiya (voiced by Lynn)</li><li>Nene Amaha (voiced by Ai Kakuma)</li><li>Kazune Kitakata (voiced by Hitomi Sekine)</li><li>Forster Mary Akira (voiced by Ami Aimoto)</li><li>Setsuka Nakamori (voiced by Aya Yamane)</li><li>Itsuki Kusumegi (voiced by Yuuya Hirose)</li><li>Arata Ootaki (voiced by Tomoya Itou)</li><li>Shin Inaho (voiced by Junji Majima)</li><li>Hikari Kurauchi (voiced by Riona Imaizumi)</li><li>Tsubame Minami (voiced by Haruna Ikezawa)</li></ul><p>View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/memories-off-sousou-not-always-true/august-29-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><!-- AD: content -->
        <div id="carousel_911180"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloomberg: NetEase Games plans to close Visions of Mana developer Ouka Studios]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/bloomberg-netease-games-plans-to-close-visions-of-mana-developer-ouka-studios</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloomberg-netease-games-plans-to-close-visions-of-mana-developer-ouka-studios.967965/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/bloomberg-netease-games-plans-to-close-visions-of-mana-developer-ouka-studios<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Few remaining staff to reportedly oversee final rollout of games.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > NetEase Games [354 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netease-games">NetEase Games</a> has cut “all but a handful of jobs” at Tokyo-based subsidiary <a title="Companies > Ouka Studios [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netease-games/ouka-studios">Ouka Studios</a>, which just shipped <em><a title="Games > Visions of Mana [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/visions-of-mana">Visions of Mana</a></em> under contract for <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,290 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>, and plans to close the studio, according to a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-08-30/tencent-netease-rethink-japan-approach-as-game-strategy-stalls?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTcyNDk3ODYwMSwiZXhwIjoxNzI1NTgzNDAxLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTSVVYOExUMVVNMFcwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJBRDcxOUY5NDBGRTk0MzNBOERCNzI2OEJDOTY3NzY3QyJ9.NXgxdAhnQilzn9xmn3yS-AAgzBHV84_10DD-MHWBs7M" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bloomberg report</a> citing people familiar with the matter. <span id="more-911162"></span></p><p>(<strong>Update 10:40 p.m.:</strong> According to Bloomberg writer Takashi Mochizuki, NetEase Games <a href="https://twitter.com/6d6f636869/status/1829342570042048776" rel="noopener" target="_blank">has been cutting staff</a> at Ouka Studios since the spring.)</p><p>The few staff that remain at the studio will reportedly oversee the rollout of its final games. Back in 2022, two years after its establishment in 2020, Ouka Studios <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2022/03/netease-games-sakura-studio-outlines-three-new-titles-in-development-for-console">outlined</a> three projects that were currently in development: an <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,319 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> featuring an <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,726 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> with unique allies, a new-style battle game based on a popular series, and an original <a title="Genres > Co-Op [198 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> featuring gigantic enemies.</p><p>In an email, a NetEase Games representative told Bloomberg it has “nothing to announce” regarding a potential closure of Ouka Studios, and that it is seeing progress at the many Japanese studios it is invested in.</p><p>“In supporting studios outside China, we craft our strategy based on our goal of providing better gaming experiences to local and global players,” the NetEase Games spokesperson said. The company is “thus always making necessary adjustments to reflect market conditions.”</p><p>NetEase Games also owns the <a title="People > Toshihiro Nagoshi [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/people/toshihiro-nagoshi">Toshihiro Nagoshi</a>-led <a title="Companies > Nagoshi Studio [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netease-games/nagoshi-studio">Nagoshi Studio</a>, the Goichi “Suda 51” Suda-led <a title="Companies > Grasshopper Manufacture [271 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netease-games/grasshopper-manufacture">Grasshopper Manufacture</a>, and the Hiroyuki Kobayashi-led <a title="Companies > GPTRACK50 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netease-games/gptrack50">GPTRACK50</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>According to Bloomberg, NetEase Games rival <a title="Companies > Tencent [193 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tencent">Tencent</a> is also reconsidering the pace and scale of its investment in Japan, having already backed off from at least several funding commitments for new titles.</p><p>In a statement, Tencent told Bloomberg that it remains committed to its partner studios and developing its business in Japan.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Forever Winter Launches Into Early Access This September]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-forever-winter-early-access-september/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-forever-winter-launches-into-early-access-this-september.967953/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-forever-winter-early-access-september/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-55168">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>As a long-time fan of the extraction shooter genre, I love to see new projects enter the scene and give the top dogs a run for their money. We need more variety and more evolution within the genre. One studio that aims to shake things up is Fun Dog—an indie studio working on their first major project: The Forever Winter. I’ve been eyeing this one—especially—for a while, and now the team has finally unveiled its Early Access release date for The Forever Winter!</p>



<p>We don’t have to wait long<span>. The Forever Winter launches into Steam Early Access on&nbsp;<strong>September 24,&nbsp;</strong></span>approximately three weeks from this writing. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Declaration of War - The Forever Winter EA Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z2izSjSXoq8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>According to the release date announcement, we’ll choose from one of five characters, each with a unique personality and playstyle—similar to a hero shooter, I would say. However, the core focal point of the game remains the same: We enter the battlefield as scavengers, track down loot, complete quests for either one of the warring factions, and extract before things go haywire.</p>



<p>Furthermore, as part of the announcement, the team revealed the intended price for The Forever Winter. The game will normally cost <strong>$29.99</strong>, but they’ll launch with an early adopters discount, which brings the total down to <strong>$27 for a limited time</strong>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Speaking of popular shooters, following a rapid decline in player numbers, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">XDefiant appears to be on borrowed time</a> not long after its release!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/">EXCLUSIVE – XDefiant is on Borrowed Time as Player Numbers Decline Rapidly</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to several sources at Ubisoft, Ubisoft San Francisco has until the end of Season 3 of XDefiant to improve the game’s bleak player numbers.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-can-you-play-space-marine-2-release-times/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-can-you-play-space-marine-2-release-times/">When Can You Play Space Marine 2? – Full Release Times</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ahead of the game’s release, developer Saber Interactive has announced full unlock and release times for when you can play Space Marine 2.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-wukong-has-exclusivity-deal-with-playstation-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-wukong-has-exclusivity-deal-with-playstation-its-claimed/">Black Myth: Wukong Has Exclusivity Deal With PlayStation, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to a new report, Black Myth: Wukong isn’t on Xbox yet because of an exclusivity deal with PlayStation</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-crossplay-details-announced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-crossplay-details-announced/">Space Marine 2 Crossplay Details Announced</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ahead of the game’s September 6 release, developer Saber Interactive has announced details regarding crossplay for Space Marine 2.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Forever Winter launches in Early Access on September 24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/the-forever-winter-launches-in-early-access-on-september-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-forever-winter-launches-in-early-access-on-september-24.967935/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/the-forever-winter-launches-in-early-access-on-september-24<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The only way to weather the storm is to sail directly into it.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Cooperative tactical <a title="Genres > Survival [314 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> <a title="Genres > Horror [472 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> <a title="Genres > Third-Person Shooter [1,233 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/tps">third-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > The Forever Winter [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-forever-winter">The Forever Winter</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,120 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2828860/The_Forever_Winter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on September 24, developer <a title="Companies > Fun Dog Studios [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fun-dog-studios">Fun Dog Studios</a> announced. <span id="more-911157"></span></p><p>The Early Access version will feature four maps and one work-in-progress map, as well as five characters, each with their own baggage and play styles. Further content will be added to the game throughout the Early Access period.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Fun Dog Studios:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In <em>The Forever Winter</em>, players are a scavenging survivor, leading a community of like-minded individuals who only want to be left alone. Unfortunately, AI controlled factions like <a title="Games > Europa [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/europa">Europa</a> and Eurasia control all of the world’s existing resources, and are at constant war with each other to secure more. This means the player must navigate these battlefields to collect the needed resources for their communities to survive.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Prepare for Hell</strong> – Players join up at the community hub where they can buy from vendors selling weapons, pharmaceuticals, and additional gear to prepare for the maze ahead, accept missions or dirty jobs from NPCs and rival factions and more.</li><li><strong>Player-Versus-Environment-Versus-Environment Scenario System</strong> – Enemies have their own goals and agendas, operating in coordinated groups, and undertaking full-scale battles. Enemy AI deploys enemies in squads based on their current objectives, with each squad reacting differently to player <a title="Genres > Action [2,134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s. As the player gets more powerful or makes a bigger mark on the battlefield, the enemy will deploy more (and stronger) firepower to counter. And players will never be stronger than the enemy.</li><li><strong>Brace the Cold Challenges Ahead</strong> – While surviving is always the primary goal, players can earn more XP, gear and money by taking on quests. Each quest has varying threat levels commensurate with their risk and reward: harder quests give larger reputation rewards that increase your faction standings, earn more credits, and get rewarded with more powerful gear.</li><li><strong>Increase Skills and Gear Up to Survive</strong> – Spend accumulated resources between sessions to level up health, speed, accuracy and reload speed that give you a fighting chance against The Forever Winter’s relentless enemies.</li><li><strong>Prioritize <a title="Genres > Stealth [68 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">Stealth</a> and Teamwork</strong> – Coordinate with your squad to outsmart enemies and avoid detection to gain the upper hand, or tactically plan battles and ambushes to win guerilla engagements. Just don’t take the enemy head-on. You won’t live to tell the tale.</li><li><strong>Death is Just the Beginning (Again)</strong> – If your squad dies, the run’s over. And death is unforgiving. If you fall in battle, you’ll lose everything in your inventory for that session, and have to start over from scratch. Build up a stash back at base between sessions to keep the upper hand in the future.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Declaration of War - The Forever Winter EA Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z2izSjSXoq8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Website Needs Just Three Rules]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/supper-mario-broth-twitter-trivia-history-nintendo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-website-needs-just-three-rules.967920/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/supper-mario-broth-twitter-trivia-history-nintendo<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you've ever been really bored while visiting a website, you may have clicked around a lot and noticed some of them have rules. Sometimes those are for commenting (<a href="https://aftermath.site/commenting-policy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">we have those!</a>); sometimes, for sites that are particularly prominent (or are full of themselves), they'll take the form of publicly-available editorial guidelines.</p><p>While those might <em>seem </em>necessary, I have recently encountered evidence that they can all probably be replaced by just three rules. And that any website without rules should probably institute the same three.</p><p><a href="https://x.com/MarioBrothBlog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The evidence comes courtesy of Supper Mario Broth, the quite frankly <em>exceptional </em>social media account</a> responsible for posting all the best Nintendo trivia and tidbits. Lately they've got a little worn down after posting <a href="https://x.com/MarioBrothBlog/status/1829026401325920713" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">some mildly incorrect information</a> and/or stuff that wasn't explained down to the most minute detail, which led to encounters with some of the most annoying and terrible people in the world (Nintendo pedants).</p><p>I sympathise! It's tough working with hard facts in the public eye because, as humans, we all make mistakes. And in fields where people are as weird and passionate as video games, even when you get things <em>right</em>, you might express them in a way that leads to confusion, and then you may as well have got it wrong because you'll get the same angry and abusive messages regardless.</p><p>In response, Supper Mario Broth posted this yesterday, and I don't think I've seen a better set of rules not just for a single account, but for how we should all conduct ourselves on the internet:</p><div><figure><div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">After deliberating on the situation, I have decided that I do not wish to stop posting. Instead, I will implement the following NEW RULES that should address most issues with the blog and drastically reduce any stress it has been causing me. Thank you very much for your support. <a href="https://t.co/x0I222jZJ6">pic.twitter.com/x0I222jZJ6</a></p>— Supper Mario Broth (@MarioBrothBlog) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarioBrothBlog/status/1829014182940774742?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 29, 2024</a></blockquote></div></figure></div><p>Perfect! Firstly, good for them, this is the best possible way to deal with the worst possible people. Secondly, I am now considering getting all three rules tattooed on me somewhere.&nbsp;</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo IV’s Next PTR To Start September 4]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/diablo-ivs-next-ptr-to-start-september-4/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-iv%E2%80%99s-next-ptr-to-start-september-4.967899/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/diablo-ivs-next-ptr-to-start-september-4/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Diablo IV's <a href="https://wccftech.com/diablo-iv-vessel-of-hatred-gamescom-qa-diablo-is-the-healthiest-its-been-since-launch/">next expansion</a> isn't far away, with the release date being officially set for October 8, 2024. However, before that happens, players will experience Diablo IV on the PTR (Public Test Realm) from September 4 through September 11. In this version of the PTR, players will experience the new character progression, which has experienced many changes. There are also major updates to the loot system (Sacred items will no longer drop and existing ones will be marked as Legacy items), the Paragon system (all Paragon Levels will be shared across all your characters on the same Realm), and new Difficulty Tiers (Normal, Hard, Expert, and Penitent) that replace the old World Tiers. Then there's the Torment difficulty, which will be tied to progression in the Pit.</p>
<p>Those who choose to participate in the PTR for Diablo IV will also be able to experience the new Class Skills and Passives, the new Paragon Boards (each class receives an extra one), and the brand-new Runeword system.</p>
<p><iframe title="Diablo IV | Campfire Chat 2.0 PTR Update | August 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ux9zeqdMF-g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<p>Runewords are essentially a way for Diablo IV players to craft their own skills. There are two types of Runes called Ritual and Invocation. Runes of Ritual specify the actions you need to take to trigger the Runes into working, whereas Runes of Invocation gives you a powerful effect once you have done the actions to trigger it. For example, BacJah is a Runeword composed of Bac and Jah. The former stipulates that the character gains 50 Offering (a new resource used for Runewords) every 5 meters traveled; the second that upon gathering 500 Offering, the next Evade is replaced with the Sorcerer's Teleport skill.</p>
<p>Indeed, Runewords can provide access to Skills from other Classes, as well as increasing your movement speed and other stuff. There will be 17 Runes of Ritual and 28 Runes of Invocation available at launch. Beware that outside PTR 2.0, Runewords will be exclusive to owners of <a href="https://wccftech.com/diablo-iv-vessel-of-hatred-gamescom-qa-diablo-is-the-healthiest-its-been-since-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vessel of Hatred</a>. The <a href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-gb/diablo4/24130178/the-2-0-ptr-what-you-need-to-know?blzcmp=blizzard-news#Runewords" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog post</a> on the Blizzard website details all of the hotfixes and tweaks made to each class.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PUBG: Battlegrounds’ Director Discusses the Importance of the Game’s Community]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pubg-battlegrounds-director-discusses-the-importance-of-the-games-community</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pubg-battlegrounds%E2%80%99-director-discusses-the-importance-of-the-game%E2%80%99s-community.967863/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pubg-battlegrounds-director-discusses-the-importance-of-the-games-community<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>PUBG: Battlegrounds celebrated its seventh anniversary this year, and it’s still going strong. The free-to-play battle royale shooter has welcomed millions of players from around the world during those seven years, and the development team has been focused on releasing new content and updates to keep that massive community engaged.</p><p>“The key thing that I’ve learned over the past seven years is how important fans are,” said Taehyun Kim, Production Director of PUBG: Battlegrounds. “Our game has been serviced globally and it has been played in many countries and by many people around the world. So we keep looking for ways to satisfy diverse countries and diverse fans.”</p><p>Kim has been a member of the PUBG team since its initial phase of development in 2016. He worked his way up to Production Director, where he is now responsible for guiding all aspects of the game’s progress. We got a chance to sit down and chat with him in Cologne, Germany, where he and his team were on hand for gamescom.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Throughout our discussion, Kim stressed how vital he thinks it is for developers to stay in contact with their player base. He’s even been going out of his comfort zone to engage with fans publicly in new ways.</p><p>“I had a livestream with Korean users, and it was really, really challenging,” Kim said. “I’m a developer, not a professional emcee, so I was afraid. ‘Oh, what if I make a mistake in front of this many people in real time?’ But I think, of course it is difficult, but I need to keep challenging myself and I have to continue this effort.”</p><p>That effort is one of the reasons he came to Cologne. He attended PUBG: Hot Drop Cologne, an in-person event that allowed fans to meet the game’s devs, partners, and other special guests. It was one of the first times Kim has had direct contact with Western players, which is something he wants to continue to improve at.</p><p>“I’m Korean, and I’m more comfortable speaking in Korean, so I have been communicating with Korean users using livestreaming,” he said. “But that was kind of my preparation to more effectively communicate with Western and English-speaking users. Currently we are looking forward and we are looking at different ways to more effectively communicate with our users around the world. So starting with this gamescom, we are going to keep continuing this effort to communicate with our fans.”</p><p>Of course, building a community relies on more than devs connecting with players. It’s also about allowing players to form connections with each other. August was Clan Month, which added weekly clan challenges and a new rewards system. It also allowed players to join the fan clans of eight popular esports teams. It all builds to a special tournament at the end of the month, when clan members get the chance to team up with professional players.</p><p>“For the clan system, what we want to offer to our players is to create an environment where they can create a new community and they can enjoy the game together, they can complete the missions together, and get the rewards together,” Kim said. “So doing this, they can enjoy the game with more fun with their squadmates and their clan members.”</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/27/pubg-key-art-1724780420723.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Kim and his team also know that for a community to stay active, they need updates and new content. He stressed that he and the dev team have a clear design philosophy and are very careful about what actually gets incorporated into the game.</p><p>“Through our communication events in Korea, I’ve learned that what is more important is not to do something big, but to do something consistently,” he said. “Our theme is survival, so we do not want to undermine this core gameplay.”</p><p>With a player base as huge and diverse as PUBG’s, player feedback comes from every corner of the world. Different players want different things, some of which directly contradict each other. So Kim and his team have to always keep that design philosophy in mind.</p><p>“For us, community feedback is very important, but we are getting a lot of feedback from many countries and from many types of users,” he said. “Sometimes, feedback is very different, even for just one feature. So we think what is important is we need to incorporate the feedback which is more relevant to our game and also we need to set a benchmark that the incorporation process should not undermine our core gameplay.”</p><p>As always, PUBG: Battlegrounds has plenty for players to look forward to. A zombie mode is on the way, an upgrade to Unreal Engine 5 is in the works long-term, and Kim said there are plans for plenty of other things that he can’t reveal yet. If you want to get in on the action, you can download PUBG: Battlegrounds for free on PC, PS4/5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, and a mobile version is available on iOS and Android.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark and Darker Mobile Combines Genres to Give Players a Unique Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dark-and-darker-mobile-combines-genres-to-give-players-a-unique-experience</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-and-darker-mobile-combines-genres-to-give-players-a-unique-experience.967860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dark-and-darker-mobile-combines-genres-to-give-players-a-unique-experience<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Every run is high risk, high reward.</h2></div><section><p>Dark and Darker Mobile is an upcoming RPG from PUBG publisher Krafton that’s aiming to give players a unique experience on mobile devices. It’s an extraction game that combines elements of battle royales, dungeon crawlers, and RPGs to keep gameplay fresh and give players that “one more run” feeling.</p><p>“You are a beginning adventurer going into the dungeons,” said Joonseok Ahn, the Executive Producer and Head of Production of Dark and Darker Mobile. “The setting is of a medieval, low-fantasy world. It’s about competing and exploring in the dungeons.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>You can choose one of six different classes for your character: Fighter, Cleric, Rogue, Wizard, Ranger, or Barbarian. Each class has different stats and skills that shape their combat style, with some classes focusing on melee attacks, others ranged, and others on magic. But classes that broadly have similar styles will have inherent skills that change how they engage in combat.</p><p>“There are active skills and passive skills. For example, as a Fighter, if you block yourself with a shield, then you’ll gain an advantage,” Ahn said. “We’ve also differentiated the armor of each class. For instance, a Fighter or Cleric will wear something metal, and a Wizard will wear cloth.”</p><p>Gameplay sees you dive into dungeons with the goal of gathering as much loot as you can and escaping. You can form a party of up to three members, either by grouping up with friends or recruiting AI-controlled mercenaries to help you. You can meet and recruit mercenaries of different classes, and they’ll level up with you as you explore dungeons. You can then promote them, allowing them to learn new skills or increase their equipment level.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Monsters roam the corridors of each dungeon, and killing them will reward you with more loot. But be careful, because your fellow players are trying to secure that loot too. They can catch you unaware and attack, prompting PvP battles to the death.</p><p>“That is the biggest advantage we have for Dark and Darker Mobile — it is a competitive, progression-based dungeon crawler,” Ahn said. “We started from the notion that there really aren’t these kinds of swordplay-based extraction games in a classic medieval RPG setting. We believe we are defining this genre as a pioneer.”</p><p>Monsters and fellow players aren’t the only threats. Each dungeon will have unique traps you need to keep an eye out for, and you’ll also have to contend with the Darkswarm, a constantly encroaching darkness that will kill players caught within it. This is where the battle royale elements come in. Where the Darkswarm will shrink is unpredictable, forcing players to adapt on the fly. And as it shrinks, it forces players into smaller areas, making PvP encounters inevitable.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/27/dndm-key-art-3-1724779788504.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>When it’s time to face off with your fellow players, it’s not all about brute strength. You need to strategize, consider the weapons being wielded by yourself and your opponent, and how you can use the environment to your advantage.</p><p>“We have a physics-based combat system. You can find that in many console and PC games, but not as much in mobile games,” Ahn said. “For instance, there are interactions with the terrain or objects. So if you swing a big weapon, then you can get stuck in the terrain.”</p><p>As you explore each dungeon, you can find escape portals that will allow you to evacuate with whatever loot you’ve gathered. Or you can choose to stay in the dungeon to gather more loot, but if you die, you lose everything. That risk vs. reward system is at the heart of the choices you’ll have to make during every run.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/27/dndm-key-art-4-1724779823584.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Ahn stressed that community feedback has been vital as he and his team continue refining Dark and Darker Mobile. The game had two rounds of beta tests, and the team has talked to regional focus groups to get as much feedback as possible.</p><p>“The motto of our development is to gather as much user feedback as we can, which is why we were engaged with two rounds of beta tests,” Ahn said. “We will open a Discord developer channel and gather feedback, and then apply this feedback to our updates. We try as much as possible to incorporate all the feedback to show that it’s reflected in the build itself. As an example, based on the first beta test, we incorporated feedback in the second beta test that was well received by users. Developers will be very open to communicating.”</p><p>Dark and Darker Mobile is scheduled to release later this year. After release, they plan to have seasonal updates every 6–8 weeks that introduce new classes or new maps. Stay tuned to IGN for more news in the lead-up to release.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>