<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 19:09:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A retro hardware maker willing to pay Trump’s tariffs is suspending US shipments anyway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/651007/retrotink-us-shipments-suspended-trump-tariffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-retro-hardware-maker-willing-to-pay-trump%E2%80%99s-tariffs-is-suspending-us-shipments-anyway.1167153/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/651007/retrotink-us-shipments-suspended-trump-tariffs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>RetroTINK, a company that sells hardware for playing retro consoles on modern screens, says it will be temporarily suspending US shipments — even though the company wants to pre-pay President Donald Trump’s tariffs, <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/04/us-retrotink-shipments-are-being-temporarily-suspended">as reported by <em>Time Extension</em></a>.</p><p>The company is suspending shipments “due to lack of guidance on how tariffs will be collected starting May 2nd,” RetroTINK’s Mike Chi <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/retrotink.com/post/3lmsr6nja6k2x">says on Bluesky</a>. “Without proper procedures in place, the risk of delays and lost packages is simply too high.” The company will resume shipments “as soon as we understand how to pre-pay tariffs on behalf of the customer,” he says.</p><p>In a post <a href="https://www.retrotink.com/blog/tariff-update-last-call-for-us-orders">on its website</a>, the company says that “we have not received guidance from the government on how US shipments will be processed.” April 23rd will be the last day to make non-expedited orders and April 28th will be the last day to make expedited orders for US-bound shipments.</p><p>Chi also <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/retrotink.com/post/3lmsr6njf2t2x">says that</a> the company expects that the situation “will be resolved eventually – but it is impossible to say when or how.”</p><p>President Donald Trump announced wide-ranging tariffs <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/642240/trump-tariffs-imports-apple-manufacturing">on April 2nd</a>, and while he lowered them to 10 percent for many countries shortly after they went into effect <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/646029/trump-announces-a-90-day-pause-on-tariffs-outside-of-china">a week later</a>, the US currently has <a href="https://www.theverge.com/politics/646604/trump-tariffs-reciprocal-pause-canada-mexico-china-de-minimis">a 145 percent tariff</a> in place on goods imported from China.</p><p>RetroTINK isn’t the only small business in games dealing with issues created by the tariffs. Fangamer, for example, is <a href="https://www.fangamer.com/collections/pizza-tower/products/pizza-tower-game-collectors-edition-nintendo-switch">delaying preorders</a> of the <em>Pizza Tower Collector’s Edition</em> because of “new tariffs targeting manufacturing in China that have made it impossible for us to estimate the CE’s final price.”</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playdate’s second season of games starts in May]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/648193/playdate-season-2-games-price-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playdate%E2%80%99s-second-season-of-games-starts-in-may.1167150/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/648193/playdate-season-2-games-price-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news">News</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>One of the new titles comes from the studio behind FTL and Into the Breach.</p></div></div><div><div><p>One of the new titles comes from the studio behind FTL and Into the Breach.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-04-17T17:20:00+00:00">Apr 17, 2025, 5:20 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Photo: Vjeran Pavic / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-webster">Andrew Webster</a> <span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Playdate is about to get a big batch of new games. Today, Panic confirmed the first details of the handheld’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/31/24284707/playdate-season-2-release-date">upcoming season 2</a>, which will include 12 new games and run from May 29th to July 3rd, with two titles releasing each week. The full season will cost $39.</p><p>When the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23025390/playdate-handheld-portable-gaming-console-review">Playdate first launched back in 2022</a>, it similarly came with a number of games from notable developers that released over time. The idea was that every Playdate owner would receive these mystery games at the same time as they launched weekly throughout the season, but ensuing shipping delays put a wrench in that plan. Panic says that with this second season it “hopes to deliver on that original idea,” while adding that the season will also include “a must see surprise for all those who want something… a little different.”</p><p>In addition to the date and price of season 2, Panic also revealed four of the games that will be featured. They include:</p><div><ul><li><span><em><a href="https://play.date/games/fulcrum-defender/">Fulcrum Defender</a></em>, a “crank-powered, arcade action game” from Subset Games, the studio behind strategy classics <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/26/17053172/into-the-breach-review-pc-steam-ftl">Into the Breach</a></em> and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/4/3/5577792/best-new-apps-ftl-for-ipad">FTL: Faster Than Light</a></em>.</span></li></ul></div><div><ul><li><span><em>Taria &amp; Como,</em> a “physics-based puzzle platformer where movement is built around swinging instead of jumping,” from Popseed Studio Inc and JuVee Productions.</span></li><li><span>A classic-style point-and-click adventure from Pixel Ghost called <em>Shadowgate PD</em>.</span></li><li><span>And <em>Dig! Dig! Dino!</em> from Dom 2D and Fáyer, which is about, well, digging dino bones.</span></li></ul></div><p>Panic also announced a new yellow case for the handheld, which is available to order today for $34.</p></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Installer</h2><p><span>A weekly newsletter by David Pierce designed to tell you everything you need to download, watch, read, listen to, and explore that fits in The Verge’s universe.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2: The Best Perk Choices For Support Heroes]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-support-perk-mercy-kiriko-juno-zenyatta-lucio-1851776618</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-the-best-perk-choices-for-support-heroes.1167141/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/overwatch-support-perk-mercy-kiriko-juno-zenyatta-lucio-1851776618<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="d71c6b2b7bb8f01c866b31093c36e9e7" data-recommend-id="image://d71c6b2b7bb8f01c866b31093c36e9e7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ana swings her sleep dart gun behind her during a highlight intro." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Ana swings her sleep dart gun behind her during a highlight intro." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment / Samuel Moreno / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d71c6b2b7bb8f01c866b31093c36e9e7" data-recommend-id="image://d71c6b2b7bb8f01c866b31093c36e9e7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ana swings her sleep dart gun behind her during a highlight intro." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>As exciting as the return of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-loot-boxes-season-15-skins-cosmetics-1851762971&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-loot-boxes-season-15-skins-cosmetics-1851762971">Loot Boxes</a></span> is, the biggest change for <em>Overwatch 2</em> is season 15’s perk system. Whether they’re small tweaks for healing or new mobility options, healers need to choose the right upgrades. To make that a bit easier, we’ve narrowed down the best perk choices for each Support hero so you can keep your team alive.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195460" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="195460,196880,196049" data-current="195460"><div><p>Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20938.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><ol data-type="List" data-style="Number"><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#ana&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#ana">Ana</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#baptiste&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#baptiste">Baptiste</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#brigitte&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#brigitte">Brigitte</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#illari&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#illari">Illari</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#juno&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#juno">Juno</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#kiriko&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#kiriko">Kirko</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#lifeweaver&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#lifeweaver">Lifeweaver</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#lucio&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#lucio">Lucio</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#mercy&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#mercy">Mercy</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#moira&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#moira">Moira</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#zenyatta&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#zenyatta">Zenyatta</a></span></li></ol><hr><h2 id="h203722"><a id="ana"></a>Ana</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Biotic Bounce</strong> buffs Ana’s Biotic Grenade so that it will still explode on contact, but then also bounce and cause a second explosion. It’s perfect for healing/dealing more damage or potentially making up for a terrible throw.</li><li><strong>Shrike</strong> provides an amazing buff to Nano Boost - Ana receives the effects as well when she uses it. Two nano-boosted players can change the tide of a battle far better than one.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203723"><a id="baptiste"></a>Baptiste</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>I recommend choosing the <strong>Field Medicine</strong> perk simply because it comes into play more often than the other choice. It upgrades Baptiste’s Immortality Field to heal nearby allies with 80 health and himself with 40 health when the object is destroyed.</li><li>The <strong>Rocket Boots</strong> perk allows for a horizontal dash during an Exo Boots jump. This is the better option because the other perk hampers his healing capabilities. Also, more mobility is always cool.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203724"><a id="brigitte"></a>Brigitte</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Morale Boost</strong> extends the length of a Whip Shot-triggered Inspire by three seconds. It’s a bit situational, but it almost doubles the amount of time Inspire usually lasts.</li><li><strong>Quick Fix</strong> upgrades Brigitte’s Repair Packs to be more effective for critical health allies, giving them another 35 instant health. Receiving 60 instant health is a lot better than 25.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203725"><a id="illari"></a>Illari</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Rapid Construction</strong> helps Illari heal allies more often by accelerating Healing Pylon build time by 300% and reducing its cooldown by 1.5 seconds. </li><li><strong>Solar Power</strong> brings a bit of Moira into Illari’s toolkit, making it so that a fully charged Solar Rifle hit will replenish 12.5% solar energy, up to an overfill amount of 50%.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203726"><a id="juno"></a>Juno</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Every Support hero’s goal is to provide more healing, which is why <strong>Familiar Vitals</strong> is the best minor perk for Juno. Pulsar Torpedoes lock onto allies 35% faster with it.</li><li><strong>Master Blaster</strong> upgrades her Mediblaster primary fire to crit enemies. With how great her healing already is, increasing her damage output is the next priority.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203727"><a id="kiriko"></a>Kiriko</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Urgent Care</strong> is a great perk to ensure you quickly heal those who need it. Choosing this will increase Healing Ofuda speed by 50% when seeking an ally in critical health. </li><li>Protection Suzu is already helpful for keeping your teammates alive, but the <strong>Foxtrot</strong> perk will make their escape more likely by providing a 40% movement speed bonus for two seconds.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203728"><a id="lifeweaver"></a>Lifeweaver</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Life Cycle</strong> is the more useful perk due to how much healing it provides. Not only does it constantly regenerate 10 health per second for Lifeweaver, but it also drops a 250 health healing seed when he dies.</li><li>While extra damage is nice, <strong>Lifeweaving</strong> will usually be the preferred major perk choice. It adds an extra 20 healing to a Healing Blossom projectile if used within three seconds after a Rejuvenating Dash.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203729"><a id="lucio"></a>Lucio</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Groovin’</strong> regenerates four ammo per second while wall riding, which is a no-brainer pick because you’ll be doing that a lot anyway.</li><li>Buffing your Crossfade music choice with Amp It Up is a common ability usage. The <strong>Noise Violation</strong> perk adds another buff by increasing Crossfade’s range by 150% so that you can reach more teammates.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203730"><a id="mercy"></a>Mercy</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Angelic Recovery</strong> provides you with 15 health every second your Caduceus Staff is attached to a full health ally. This will typically be the better choice since you’ll spend more time pocketing someone or healing nearby allies than needing to fly across a map.</li><li><strong>Chain Boost</strong> upgrades your damage amplification beam to tether toward a second ally. This is perfect whether you’re trying to take an objective or hold one down.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203731"><a id="moira"></a>Moira</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>The <strong>Vanish</strong> perk increases Fade’s duration by 0.5 seconds. That doesn’t sound like much, but the extra time gives plenty more leeway for repositioning.</li><li>Biotic Orb can be a finicky ability, especially since it recovers health over time. The <strong>Ethical Nourishment</strong> major perk tweaks the ability so that the first 50 healing is instant for any ally that comes into contact with it.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h203732"><a id="zenyatta"></a>Zenyatta</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Zenyatta has always lacked mobility, which is why <strong>Ascendance</strong> is an amazing perk. It allows him to hover for three seconds if you hold after a double jump.</li><li><strong>Duality</strong> brings both sides of Zenyatta’s gameplay together, healing Orb of Harmony targets with 20% of his damage dealt to Orb of Discord targets.</li></ul><hr><p><br>While the above perks will be the most consistently helpful, every perk is pretty practical depending on your match. I suggest keeping an open mind with these buffs and messing around with them in quick play. If you also dabble in other character classes, we’ve got you covered with the best <em>Overwatch 2</em> perks for both the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-tanks-best-perks-dva-doomfist-hazard-orisa-1851771469&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-tanks-best-perks-dva-doomfist-hazard-orisa-1851771469">tank heroes</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-perks-dps-widowmaker-tracer-hanzo-cassidy-1851776302&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-perks-dps-widowmaker-tracer-hanzo-cassidy-1851776302">damage heroes</a></span>.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda Fans Are Worried Tears of the Kingdom's Switch 2 Version Won't Support Cloud Saves]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/zelda-fans-are-worried-tears-of-the-kingdoms-switch-2-version-wont-support-cloud-saves</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-fans-are-worried-tears-of-the-kingdoms-switch-2-version-wont-support-cloud-saves.1167135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/zelda-fans-are-worried-tears-of-the-kingdoms-switch-2-version-wont-support-cloud-saves<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The cloud situation is a bit foggy.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch 2 is set to get special enhanced versions of several Switch 1 games, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a>. A newly spotted disclaimer has fans worrying some games, or at least one game, won't support Nintendo's cloud save functionality as they'd hope.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Over the last day or so, users have been noticing that Nintendo's pages for <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/The-Legend-of-Zelda-Tears-of-the-Kingdom-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-2787249.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tears of the Kingdom</a>'s Switch 2 edition carries the following disclaimer: "Please note: this software does not support the Nintendo Switch Online paid membership’s Save Data Cloud backup feature."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Per <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-switch-2-editions-of-the-legend-of-zelda-botw-totk-do-not-support-cloud-saves-saves-can-still-be-transferred-however.1166340/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ResetEra</a>, the page for <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/The-Legend-of-Zelda-Breath-of-the-Wild-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-2787250.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild - Switch 2 Edition</a> also apparently carried this disclaimer at one point, as did <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/Super-Mario-Party-Jamboree-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-Jamboree-TV-2785806.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</a>. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Though it's since disappeared from those pages, the Tears of the Kingdom still has the disclaimer as of this writing. The Japanese page though, per <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-edition-zelda-games-wont-support-cloud-saves-to-backup-your-data" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eurogamer</a> via machine translation, does not carry the same disclaimer; only the US and EU pages seem to be showing it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has reached out to Nintendo for clarification on the matter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If this holds true, this could create some confusing scenarios for players. Nintendo's cloud save option for NSO members is handy, for one. It makes carrying games across systems, or juggling storage space for games without losing your saved progress, a little less stres-inducing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Actually importing a save file from the original Switch to the Switch 2 Edition of Tears of the Kingdom does seem to still work. The Nintendo page noted an additional save slot for the Switch 2 Edition, where one can start a brand-new journey or "continue a previous one with your existing save data." Nintendo does note that save data created in the second save data slot cannot be trasnferred to the Nintendo Switch 1 version of Tears of the Kingdom.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's a confusing situation that can possibly lead to some stress, as players would likely not want to lose a save file they've dumped many, many hours into when upgrading versions. Hopefully, this gets cleared up soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Switch 2 Edition does have a few reasons for prospective Switch 2 owners to upgrade, including the Zelda Notes app, which comes packed with helpful guiding content, lore, and even <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/switch-2-zelda-ports-will-let-players-repair-equipment-with-the-zelda-notes-app-if-theyre-lucky">some potential equipment repair options</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4 Is Crossing Over With Dark Fantasy Manga Series Berserk For Its First IP Collab]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab/1100-6530944/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab.1167126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab/1100-6530944/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530944">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-iv/" data-ref-id="5000-504255">Diablo 4's</a> first external IP crossover event is coming, and it's with none other than the dark fantasy masterpiece, Berserk.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard hasn't gone into too much detail on what all the crossover will entail, so far only tweeting out a short animated teaser showing a Brand of Sacrifice-marked Barbarian outfitted with Berserk's iconic Berserker armor and Dragonslayer sword. Considering the teaser doesn't say Diablo 4 specifically (and lists iOS and Android), it looks like the event will come to both Diablo 4 and the free-to-play <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-immortal/" data-ref-id="5000-489022">Diablo Immortal</a>. No other details, including dates for the event or what all it will entail, have been officially announced.</p><p dir="ltr">For those not in the know, Berserk, by the late author Kentaro Miura, is considered a seminal work in the manga space. Not for the faint of heart, it tells the tale of the mercenary known as Guts and his quest to survive a punishing dark fantasy world. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/berserk-creator-kentaro-miura-has-passed-away/1100-6491749/" data-ref-id="1100-6491749">Miura passed away in 2021</a>, leaving the longrunning manga unfinished, though <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/berserk-manga-to-continue-in-2022/1100-6504227/" data-ref-id="1100-6504227">new chapters created by Miura's friend Kouji Mori</a>, alongside Miura's various assistants and apprentices, have slowly been released since Miura's death.</p><p dir="ltr">The manga's influence, from its dark fantasy themes to its iconic suits of armor and weapons, can be seen everywhere. Anytime a character uses a comically oversized sword, Berserk is likely the inspiration, and games like From Software's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/dark-souls/" data-ref-id="5000-83346">Dark Souls</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/elden-ring/" data-ref-id="5000-497664">Elden Ring</a> haven't shied away from wearing their Berserk influences for all to see.</p><p dir="ltr">While Berserk is the first external IP to be featured in Diablo (with another IP crossover slated for later this year, according to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-2025-roadmap-highlights-new-crossovers-endgame-updates/1100-6530666/" data-ref-id="1100-6530666">Diablo 4's 2025 roadmap</a>), both Diablo 4 and Diablo Immortal did crossover with another Blizzard IP, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a>, last year. That crossover was to celebrate World of Warcraft's 20th anniversary, and saw a number of pricey WoW-themed armor sets and cosmetics inspired by some of the game's iconic characters like Sylvanas Windrunner and The Lich King added to Diablo 4's premium shop. Various cosmetics and WoW-themed items also appeared in Blizzard's Diablo mobile game.</p><p dir="ltr">The Berserk crossover will be coming as part of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-8-is-all-about-bosses-and-its-bringing-back-a-fan-favorite/1100-6530012/" data-ref-id="1100-6530012">Diablo 4 Season 8, which will overhaul the game's endgame bosses</a> and see the return of a fan-favorite from Diablo 3, Belial. Diablo 4 Season 8 begins April 29.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New DLC Gets Price Cut Before Release Due To "Events Happening In The World"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-dlc-gets-price-cut-before-release-due-to-events-happening-in-the-world/1100-6530941/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-dlc-gets-price-cut-before-release-due-to-events-happening-in-the-world.1167123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-dlc-gets-price-cut-before-release-due-to-events-happening-in-the-world/1100-6530941/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530941">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Rockfish Games has announced that it's dropping the price of its upcoming DLC expansion for Everspace 2 ahead of its May 12 release due to "events happening in the world."</p><p>The expansion, Wrath of the Ancients, was originally going to cost $30. However, Rockfish Games reduced the price to $25. The studio also recently reduced the price of Everspace 2's first expansion, Titans, from $15 to $12.</p><p>Rockfish Games clarified that even though the price for Wrath of the Ancients has been lowered, no content has been cut from it. It contains new stories, side quests, enemies, and a new playable Wraith ship.</p><p>"As an independent studio, we are lucky to be in a position to be able to do this based on the support of an amazing community," Rockfish Games said in a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1128920/view/524214742651240614?l=english" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam blog post</a>. "If you were genuinely looking forward to giving us that little bit extra, thank you! We will have a new artbook and soundtrack gathering together content from our DLCs available when Wrath of the Ancients launches that you can put that money towards instead."</p><p>The studio didn't specify "events happening in the world," but acknowledged the rising costs of everything and feelings of uncertainty. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-prices-have-increased-in-some-regions-but-not-the-us/1100-6530829/" data-ref-id="1100-6530829">PS5 console</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-plus-prices-have-increased-in-certain-regions-but-not-the-us/1100-6530919/" data-ref-id="1100-6530919">PS Plus prices</a> have increased, and certain games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-defends-mario-kart-worlds-80-price-tag/1100-6530643/" data-ref-id="1100-6530643">Mario Kart World are now $80</a>. It's also possible that Rockfish Games is referring to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/esa-says-tariffs-will-have-a-detrimental-impact-on-entire-gaming-industry-not-just-nintendo/1100-6530636/" data-ref-id="1100-6530636">Trump tariffs that are impacting the video game industry</a>.</p><p>Everspace 2 is an open-world space shooter that follows Adam, a clone pilot who aims to escape the Demilitarized Zone of Cluster 34. It features a robust single-player campaign, plenty of side missions, loot, and additional challenges to partake it in. Everspace 2 is available on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones Might Get a Sequel, Hints Phil Spencer, Though He Certainly Sounds More Interested in Owned IPs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-might-get-a-sequel-hints-phil-spencer-though-he-certainly-sounds-more-interested-in-owned-ips/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-might-get-a-sequel-hints-phil-spencer-though-he-certainly-sounds-more-interested-in-owned-ips.1167102/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-might-get-a-sequel-hints-phil-spencer-though-he-certainly-sounds-more-interested-in-owned-ips/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During a wide-ranging interview <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/microsoft-phil-spencer-minecraft-movie-fallout-season-2-1236352653/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with Variety</a>, Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer also discussed the success of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle. The executive appeared to hint at the potential for a sequel, but he also made it clear that he'd like Microsoft-owned studios to work first and foremost on owned franchises (which Indiana Jones is obviously not, being licensed by Disney).</p>
<p><em>I will say, we’re really happy with “Indy” and the players and the reception. We do think there’s life in that franchise, and I’m just gonna leave it at that. We’re launching on PlayStation here pretty soon. I think that’ll be a cool moment. I was really inspired by Machine Games taking someone else’s IP and doing something so unique, and I’m inspired about what that team can do next. Certain people were kind of pushing them on the first person versus third person. And I think once you play it, you realize you are Indy. But going forward, I also want to give the teams the ability to do our own games and our own franchises. We have a lot of room to tell new stories, as well. And I want to make sure that’s an option for us.</em></p>
<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle has just launched on Sony's PlayStation 5 console, around four months after its debut on PC and Xbox Series S|X. PlayStation 5 Pro <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-playstation-5-pro-global-illumination-improvements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">offers the best way to play the game on consoles</a>, although the PC version with path tracing enabled remains superior for those with the hardware to run it.</p>
<p>A story DLC called The Order of Giants is scheduled to be released later this year. Of course, a full-fledged sequel is what fans really want after playing the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-indiana-at-his-finest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">excellent base game</a>. It sounds like it could happen, provided that Disney reaches a deal with Microsoft.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playdate's second season includes brand-new game from FTL and Into the Breach studio]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/playdates-second-season-includes-brand-new-game-from-ftl-and-into-the-breach-studio</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playdates-second-season-includes-brand-new-game-from-ftl-and-into-the-breach-studio.1167087/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/playdates-second-season-includes-brand-new-game-from-ftl-and-into-the-breach-studio<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Plus a new Shadowgate and more.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/playdate-promotional-art.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Playdate</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
We <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playdate-season-2-drops-in-2025-but-firm-release-details-price-and-games-all-still-to-be-finalised">already knew it was coming</a>, but Playdate - the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playdate-is-weird-and-kind-of-ace">cute boutique handheld console with the crank</a> - has just announced its second second of games, and one of those is a brand-new project from the massively acclaimed studio behind FTL and Into the Breach.
</p>
<p>
As announced <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H4faUwfDw5o">during Playdate's latest showcase</a>, FTL developer Subset Games' <a href="https://play.date/games/fulcrum-defender/">Fulcrum Defender</a> is "totally different" to the studio's earlier titles, and sees players attempting to survive for as long as possible while holding back wave after wave of incoming enemies. Aiming utilises the crank as foes approach from all sides on the radar-like screen, with attack patterns growing more complex over time. As things progress, upgrades such as new weapons can be unlocked, with the key to survival being a "smart build and good aim".
</p>
<p>
"I wanted to make a replayable experience that starts off slow and relaxing, but gradually ramps up until it becomes frantic chaos," primary developer Jay Ma explained of Fulcrum Defender in today's Playdate announcement. "Originally I did not plan on finishing this game, I was making it as a form of self-therapy. I have been struggling with Long COVID... and I wanted to prove to myself that I could still make games in my current state."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Playdate Update #7 - 04/17/25" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H4faUwfDw5o?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Playdate Update #7 - 04/17/25</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H4faUwfDw5o?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/H4faUwfDw5o?autoplay=1" title="Playdate Update #7 - 04/17/25">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Playdate's season two showcase.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H4faUwfDw5o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Fulcrum Defender is one of 12 new games coming to Playdate as part of Season Two, with three more having so far been revealed in detail. There's developer Pixel Ghost's <a href="https://play.date/games/shadowgate-pd/">Shadowgate PD</a>, for instance, which reimagines the classic point-and-click adventure series with new music, art, and features. It follows players - in the role of The Seed of Prophecy - as they travel deep into the titular living castle in a bid to defeat the evil Warlock Lord who resides there.
</p>
<p>
That's alongside <a href="https://play.date/games/taria-and-como/">Taria &amp; Como</a>, a physics-based puzzle platformer built around swinging rather than jumping. Developed by Popseed Studio Inc and JuVee Productions, it charts the adventures of Taria, a young girl with a prosthetic leg, who sets out to rescue her sister Como in a world that constantly underestimates her.
</p>
<p>
And finally for the full reveals, there's <a href="https://play.date/games/dig-dig-dino/">Dig! Dig! Dino!</a>, from Dom 2D (Flinthook) &amp; Fáyer (Arco). This one casts players as a crew of palaeontologists in a game about digging for dinosaurs bones, analysing strange artefacts, and uncovering long-buried secrets. "Sell off coins and treasure to build an arsenal of digging tools," explains its announcement, "then upgrade them to go deeper and find even more bones and loot!"
</p>
<p>
Playdate's second season <a href="http://play.date/games">costs $39 USD</a> and will see two of its 12 included games release each week between 29th May and 3rd July. There's also a tease for a "must-see surprise" that'll be "something a little different". Season Two's remaining eight games will be properly revealed at a later date, but their titles and developers have been announced as follows:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Chance's Lucky Escape - Developed by Goloso Games (Spike II: The Great Emu War) and Julia</li>
<li>Minamata (The Crimson Diamond)</li>
<li>Otto's Galactic Groove - Developed by Team Otto (Skwish)</li>
<li>Catchadiablos - Developed by Amano Games (Pullfrog Deluxe)</li>
<li>The Whiteout - Developed by Scenic Route Software (Post Hero, Generations)</li>
<li>Black Hole Havoc - Developed by Cosmic Bros (Jolly Chimp Champ)</li>
<li>Wheelsprung - Developed by Nino van Hooff (Gravity Express) and Julie Bjørnskov (Escape the Arcade)</li>
<li>Tiny Turnip - Developed by Luke Sanderson (Paper Pilot)</li>
<li>Long Puppy - Developed by Indiana-Jonas (Surmount)</li>
<li>▀▄▀▄▀▄ - Developed by Dustin Mierau (Playmaker, Path, Napster)</li>
</ul>
<p>
And if you haven't yet picked up a Playdate, they're now <a href="http://shop.play.date/">readily available on creator Panic Inc's store</a> for $229 USD, with refurbished units costing $179. A new cover in the same shade of yellow as the Playdate has also been released for $34 - just be aware those prices don't include shipping or taxes, which can be pretty substantial outside the US.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How OTK Lost Its Way]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/otk-asmongold-mizkif-twitch-youtube-sponsors-controversy-report</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-otk-lost-its-way.1167084/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/otk-asmongold-mizkif-twitch-youtube-sponsors-controversy-report<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>When OTK – short for One True King – was founded in 2020, it was far from the first streamer conglomerate/production company/lifestyle brand to plant its flag, but what it had going for it was its unique mix of personalities. Where the likes of 100 Thieves and FaZe Clan began with feet firmly in the esports world, and others like the once-Pokimane-fronted OfflineTV prided themselves on cozy wholesomeness, OTK was the result of Twitch’s edgelord past meeting its brand-friendly present. Having Zack “Asmongold” Hoyt, Matthew “Mizkif” Rinaudo, Tim "Esfand" Esfandiari, and Rich Campbell on the starting bench as owners lent the organization an authentically messy appeal. Flash forward five years, though, and OTK is facing an uncertain future. Streamers were its greatest asset, but they’ve also proven to be its biggest stumbling block.</p><p>At the tail end of last year, OTK <a href="https://x.com/OvileeMay/status/1870219477100703982?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">laid off employees</a> working in production, sales, and marketing, reducing full-time headcount from around twenty to around five, according to former OTK employees, whom Aftermath granted anonymity as they were not authorized to speak publicly on these matters. This was the culmination of an arc that began promisingly, with ambitious ideas from streamers, behind-the-scenes staff, and Tips Out (the organization’s fifth co-founder and main strategic mind), but which ultimately descended into public-facing scandals and conflicting priorities on the part of some of the aforementioned streamers, who also co-owned the organization.&nbsp;</p><p>"It’s really about accountability, right?” a former OTK employee told Aftermath. “When you have creators that are owners in the organization, you can't tell them anything. You can't do anything.”</p><p>Aftermath reached out to OTK multiple times in the weeks before this report’s publishing. The company declined to comment on most of what follows. An OTK spokesperson told Aftermath: “OTK's vision and business model remains the same as it has for the past several years: to be the best influencer-led gaming brand in digital. We continue pursuing this endeavor each and every day.”</p><h2>The Power Of Friendship</h2><p>OTK’s earliest days were characterized by a palpable sense of fun. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GSTRk9IUyeU" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a 2020 video</a> introducing the collective to fans, Hoyt outlined his vision: "We came up with this idea of making an org and building an org around our friends – and building the org around friendship in general." Streams and videos suggested that he and his fellow mostly-<em>World of Warcraft</em> streamers had, indeed, figured out how to monetize their friendship. There was a shenanigans-laden <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2aFIzyQWLA8&amp;t=922s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Friendsgiving</a>, a <em>Pokémon </em>card-powered <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xjfTq_mf8to" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">charity drive</a>, a (purposefully) budget <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XlX_tGl9aKc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pro wrestling show</a>, and eventually, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Z08svBFA3U&amp;t=674s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a content house</a>. Over time, additional members like Nick “Nmplol” Polom, Chance “Sodapoppin” Morris, Emily "Emiru" Schunk, Emily "ExtraEmily" Zhang, and Will Neff joined as well, though not all in ownership capacities.</p><p>The vibe of OTK’s initial events was often loose and low-stakes. Streamers drank and laughed. Living spaces were cluttered. Camera angles were awkward. Overlays were minimal. OTK’s streamers made it feel like they were messing around and somebody just so happened to leave a camera in the room.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="What is OTK? ft. Asmongold, Mizkif, Esfand, Rich Campbell, Tips Out" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GSTRk9IUyeU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>But OTK was still very much a business, one founded by creators who’d spent their careers regularly behaving in ways that were not brand-friendly, but which was intended to cause brands to see dollar signs and feel an overwhelming urge to slap their logos on the organization’s content.</p><p>"You had Nick, Mizkif, and Asmon collaborate on stream, and you had, like, 57,000 people watching,” one former OTK employee told Aftermath. “You're like 'This is a goldmine to monetize.’ Any brand would be absolutely over the moon to have those kinds of numbers. And obviously it was during the covid age of Twitch, where we saw the big [viewership] boom. So it was a match made in heaven. … [OTK] wanted to make events and monetize these streams where they can put all their brands together, and it can yield insane budgets – getting clearance for six, almost seven-figure budgets for shows or episodes or stuff like that."</p><figure><blockquote><p>It was a match made in heaven.</p></blockquote></figure><p>Over time, this meant that OTK had to professionalize. Brands didn’t necessarily want to attach their names to messy rooms and wanton weirdness. They wanted to be part of a polished product.&nbsp;</p><p>"When you scale up to these businesses, when you're asking them for more money, they're pitching it in front of their CEO, CMO, VP of marketing, etc,” the former OTK employee said. “The way [OTK's content] looked back then, it just didn't look appealing. [Brands aren’t] going to commit money to this when you're competing against TV, traditional media buying, and all that stuff [where] everything's well polished."</p><p>So, in some cases, OTK upped its production values. It leaned on consistent formats like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OifbsgAeCDk&amp;list=PLKm9gGMelbSjtSbcsAKZo00ViCfCrEErX" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Schooled</a>, in which star-studded streamer lineups competed to answer questions based on knowledge they should have acquired in school, and sold brands not just on mid-episode placements but season-long sponsorships, social media clips, ad reads, newsletter mentions, and more. Big-name brands like Coinbase, Gatorade, Mountain Dew, Razer, Intel, and eventually Progressive latched onto the nascent venture.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="ESFAND THERE'S JUST NO WAY - OTK ft. MitchJones, Jinny and more..! #ad" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XlX_tGl9aKc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Then 2022 saw two major scandals rock the org: In September of that year, Rinaudo was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/20/23363760/mizkif-trainwreckstv-sexual-harassment-twitch-adrianahlee" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">accused of covering up</a> a sexual assault incident between two other streamers, and OTK <a href="https://x.com/OTKnetwork/status/1572387360247271427" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">suspended him</a> pending the results of a third-party investigation. In a <a href="https://x.com/OTKnetwork/status/1609361988467183616/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">statement</a> in December, OTK wrote that the investigation “did not find direct evidence that Mizkif attempted to minimize or cover up sexual assault as alleged.” The statement also noted that Rinaudo had <a href="https://x.com/Vahn16/status/1579588035595075585" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">publicly</a> demonstrated a "callous disregard towards the severity of sexual misconduct and racial prejudice in our space" and would remain off OTK’s board of directors until "he demonstrates to the board that he is capable of upholding our organization's values.” Aftermath reached out to Rinaudo to ask whether or not he’d been reinstated but did not receive a response as of this publishing.&nbsp;</p><p>In December 2022, Campbell, another founder, <a href="https://x.com/RichWCampbell/status/1603869600969547785" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">resigned from OTK</a> following <a href="https://www.sportskeeda.com/esports/what-allegations-former-otk-co-founder-rich-campbell" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sexual assault allegations</a>. He more or less disappeared off the internet until 2024, at which point news broke that he’d <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/entertainment/rich-campbell-files-3-6m-defamation-lawsuit-over-sexual-assault-allegations-2458787/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">filed a defamation suit against one of his accusers for $3.6 million</a> in damages after she sued him. Aftermath reached out to Campbell’s lawyer for more details about the current status of the case but did not receive a reply.</p><p>Smaller controversies also took place in 2022, like Hoyt <a href="https://www.sportskeeda.com/esports/breaking-asmongold-s-2022-5-month-hiatus-getting-banned-alternate-channel-controversies" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">getting suspended from Twitch</a> for what the platform called "hateful and unmoderated conduct" in his <em>Diablo Immortal</em> chat. Even the sorts of events that felt tailormade to attract sponsors – for example, the annual OTK Expo, which began in 2022 as an attempt at a more scripted-and-staged, prim-and-proper video game showcase – ultimately suffered as a result of scandals, according to ex-OTK staff.</p><p>"We cared deeply about indie games, indie developers, and the people in the industry,” a former OTK employee told Aftermath of the OTK Expo. “[But] there's a lot of sponsors that just straight up didn't want to work with us after the Mizkif stuff, after Asmongold's first incident."&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><figure><blockquote><p>The first thing any brand safety person from any of these big Fortune 500 brands sees when they type out OTK is sexual assault.</p></blockquote></figure><p>"[Allegations are] an absolutely soul-crushing thing for any sales person or marketing person trying to pitch a brand,” another former OTK employee told Aftermath. “The first thing any brand safety person from any of these big Fortune 500 brands sees when they type out OTK is sexual assault. Pitching that would be putting themselves in the crossfire of 'Why are you even here at this job if you're not flagging this early on?' So slowly, it became very difficult for OTK to sell itself [to brands]. … And the more you're spending with a brand, the more money you're asking, the more due diligence happens with a brand."</p><p>In 2022, the organization also began to expand. With Tips Out, who’d previously founded and run a <em>World of Warcraft</em> esports company called Classic Dueler’s League, leading the charge, the minds behind OTK started a sister company: Starforge Systems, which specialized in gaming PCs. Two more followed shortly after in 2023: <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/otk-network-launches-indie-game-and-publishing-company-mad-mushroom-301847679.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mad Mashroom</a>, an indie game publisher that, on paper, synergized nicely with the OTK Expo, and <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/otk-network-unveils-newest-collaboration-with-creator-centric-talent-management-company-301757576.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mythic Talent</a>, a creator management company that now counts among its roster stars like Case “Caseoh” Baker, as well as OTK mainstays like Hoyt, Rinaudo, and Morris. Starforge and Mythic went on to become successful businesses in their own rights.</p><p>"[OTK’s issues] make it really hard to build a sustainable business, which I think is why OTK has diversified so many times into a PC company, talent management company, and a video game publisher,” a former OTK employee told Aftermath. “It was like 'Hey, we can use OTK as this tip of the spear, a marketing campaign into the parts of the industry that are typically really low margin, and if we don't spend anything on marketing, that can actually increase our margin.’"</p><p>The official OTK spokesperson took a similar, albeit sunnier view of the company’s strategy: “In many ways, OTK is the nucleus that supercharges all of our other entities. Through our content, brand, and corporate support, OTK helps establish new businesses in a fraction of the time it would normally take.”</p><h2><strong>There’s No “I” In Stream</strong></h2><p>As time went on, another difficulty arose: Streamers began to lose interest. Former OTK employees characterized this as less of an individual issue, like the controversies, and more of a systemic problem. Livestreaming does not incentivize long-term planning and collaboration; rather, streamers are taught by the never-ending Groundhog Day loop of viewer numbers, subscriptions, and donations to hyperfixate on the here and now. Which trends should you chase to keep your channel’s numbers up? How should you capitalize on a big moment? What’s going to benefit you more: slowly and meticulously contributing to a team effort or betting on yourself?&nbsp;</p><p>"Initially, the creators thought [OTK] was fun, like 'Oh, I'll do a show here, do a show there.' And then suddenly it's like 'We need you to do a show every other week.' That creator's not happy,” said an ex-OTK employee. “So it was painful! Sometimes we would have a show, expected deliverables with talent, and [a creator’s] excuse was 'I don't want to show up. I have sponsored stuff [on my own channel].' And what quickly happened was, creators realized they could just say no, and there was no accountability."</p><figure><blockquote><p>What quickly happened was, creators realized they could just say no.</p></blockquote></figure><p>Since many of OTK’s creators also co-owned the company, they couldn’t be fired or meaningfully reprimanded for no-showing OTK programming. This, according to ex-employees, was exacerbated by the fact that while creators who did not partially own OTK were paid a salary, OTK did not directly compensate creator-owners for OTK projects but instead offered them a mix of brand deals, equity in the company, cuts of sponsorships, ad revenue, and services provided by staff (graphics for a show, help starting up a new podcast, marketing assistance, etc).&nbsp;</p><p>"They had all these utilities and all these resources,” said an ex-OTK employee. “Oh, you want to start a podcast? Perfect. We'll do it all for you. We'll only take a portion of the ad revenue [and/or] sponsorship revenue from any of the deals we've signed. So there were a lot of freemium benefits for all the creators at OTK."</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="We Put 14 Streamers On A Real Ranch!" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sDADGM7NOA0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>As a result, ex-employees say, streamers continued to use these perks to benefit their personal brands after their excitement for the organization cooled.</p><p>"So what happened, especially this past year [2024], is creators realized that they were raking in money on their own individual deals: game deals, smaller brand activations, shows,” said the ex-OTK employee. “Absolutely enormous amounts of money. 'Why should I care [about OTK] when OTK doesn't compensate me for any of those things?’ [was basically how they approached it].”</p><p>Another ex-OTK employee pointed to Polom as an example of this phenomenon. Outside of a project that was considered his baby – <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLpRYRqpby1Lp7FjamW9XAy4J4J8_zsnl8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wild West</a>, a large-scale IRL stream that saw 14 streamers role-play as cowboys on a real ranch – he increasingly focused on his own channel over time. To an extent, the ex-employee understood where Polom was coming from.</p><p>"[Polom] focused more on his own stream because it blew up, and he's not interested in working in advertised events for OTK, because that's more or less what it was becoming,” said the ex-employee. “People were calling OTK 'AdTK,' because every single event we were doing was sponsored by some game, some show, some whatever."</p><p>Aftermath reached out to Polom for more details, but did not receive a response as of this publishing.</p><p>But former employees say streamers weren’t exactly turning up their noses at ads either.</p><p>"They complained about us having so many advertised and sponsored shows, yet these creators could easily self-fund a lot of these shows and not have sponsors on them, but they chose not to,” said an ex-OTK employee. “These creators had the option for their shows to be white label, sponsor free, no ads – to give their community what they want. And they chose not to. ... They didn't have to lose any money to put on the show. [The creators] were making money from sponsors and then not following their own sponsorship deliverables."</p><figure><blockquote><p>People were calling OTK 'AdTK,' because every single event we were doing was sponsored by some game, some show, some whatever.</p></blockquote></figure><p>The problem, as one ex-OTK employee sees it, is that streamers didn’t understand what they had.</p><p>"We'd say 'Hey, [group of creators], we're giving you all a $10,000 opportunity to play a game. We were able to work it out with a publisher,’” said a former OTK employee. “What did they do after we held their hand through the entire process? … [OTK staff] didn't get a thank you. Didn't get anything. It became another routine thing. It's very weird how this evolution of rhetoric within the company from the creators became 'I'm not being compensated. I'm not benefiting' even though they had a ton of shares, equity in the company, and they're getting brand deals out the wazoo."</p><p>Events that aired on streamers’ personal channels – rather than central OTK channels – stood to benefit streamers even more.&nbsp;</p><p>"OTK never took any ad revenue from any of Mizkif’s streams when all these big events were running,” said the former OTK employee. “We never took sub percentages. We never took donations. So these creators were given a full big spotlight that drew massive amounts of attention and awareness to them for free, and we never took anything other than a percentage of the brand deals that came through."</p><p>What OTK did take, former staff say, went where you’d expect it to: paychecks and production.</p><p>"You have to make a margin, you have to pay people a livable wage,” said the former employee. “Give it to OTK: We were well compensated compared to most gaming production companies/media companies out there. I'll give it to Tips and the team for doing that."</p><p>“Production cost was mostly where cost and spend went,” the former employee added. “Salaries played their role, but production costs were crazy at times.”</p><p>Staff felt frustrated when they would bring a project fully to term, only for creators to drop the ball at the eleventh hour.</p><p>"We would have a merch drop,” said a former OTK employee. “We would go through a very tough refinement period of getting feedback, making sure the creators are really happy with it, and we're like 'Alright, it's time to launch. This is your merch. This is everything you guys wanted. You designed it.' And it was like pulling teeth to get them to promote it. This is their stuff! But they don't want to make a post about their merchandise."</p><figure><blockquote><p>Somebody else would have to go onto their accounts and pin things in the chat, promote or push from their accounts, push from their Reddit, post on their social media channels.</p></blockquote></figure><p>"Year three, it was very obvious that creators were checked out,” said another ex-OTK employee. “It was a nightmare to get any deliverables done, to get them to post, to promote the shows. You probably saw it all the time: People are like 'Oh, I didn't even hear about this show. The creators didn't even talk about it blah, blah, blah.' Somebody else would have to go onto their accounts and pin things in the chat, promote or push from their accounts, push from their Reddit, post on their social media channels."</p><p>To an extent, this makes sense: As I’ve <a href="https://aftermath.site/stream-big-book-excerpt-twitch-dream-face-reveal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">written a whole book about</a>, streaming is a more taxing job than people give it credit for. Those at the top of the food chain are constantly juggling daily streams, YouTube channels, TikToks, Instagrams, collaborations, travel, and more. They regularly burn out. It’s not surprising that some decided to shake a burdensome weight off their shoulders when they saw an opportunity.</p><p>"I think a lot of people just want what's simpler, what they know and what is going to [put them on the path of least resistance]. It’s a very natural instinct we all have,” said an ex-OTK employee. “[Creators’] core product, their core business, which is their own streams, they're all crushing it. … A lot was great working with these creators and having them invested in the day-to-day business stuff, but the lack of communication skills, organization structure stuff for these creators was absolutely a fucking mess sometimes."&nbsp;</p><p>Another pointed out that not all creators treated OTK events the same way. Some participated more than others. "ExtraEmily was super active. Cyr was great," the ex-staffer said, referencing two OTK creators who are not owners.</p><h2><strong>The Asmongold Problem</strong></h2><p>Then late 2024 arrived, and Hoyt, who’d begun consistently banging the anti-DEI drum to his millions of viewers <a href="https://aftermath.site/sweet-baby-detected-conspiracy-theory-steam" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the year prior</a>, made his radicalization impossible to ignore by going on <a href="https://aftermath.site/asmongold-apology-palestine-hasan-piker-twitch-youtube" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a racist rant against Palestinians</a> in October, calling them “inferior” and adding that “I’m not going to cry a fucking river when people who have genocide that’s baked into their laws are getting genocided.” The entire Twitch community was taken aback, and even Tips Out <a href="https://x.com/TipsOut/status/1846302400988303489" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">published a statement</a> breaking with his fellow co-owner’s “dehumanizing” stance. Twitch suspended Hoyt, and he apologized for his statements shortly after. At the time, he also stepped away from leadership duties at OTK, Starforge, and Mad Mushroom.&nbsp;</p><p>However, in the months that followed, the overall tenure of Hoyt’s broadcasts did not change. After Trump got reelected in November, Hoyt leaned further into far-right politics. Some remaining sponsors opted to abandon ship.</p><figure><blockquote><p>Why would you want to be part of an indie game show when Asmongold just spouts about DEI all the time?</p></blockquote></figure><p>"Asmongold's comments on the Middle East were kinda the nail in the coffin for [for those of us who got laid off],” said an ex-OTK employee. “It was a really tricky situation because, yes, Asmongold is entitled to his opinion, beliefs, whatever he thinks, but when you are the owner, founder of a company that you publicly own, and there's people that work at it, it impacts what you say. You're no longer the only one at it."</p><p>"Why would you want to be part of an indie game show when Asmongold just spouts about DEI all the time? It's very contradictory,” said another ex-OTK employee, referencing the OTK Expo. “It just sucks that Asmongold became so radicalized, because he [was] the owner of the company. ... Even if you do believe all this stuff, which is completely fine, you have some sort of responsibility as a creator to not be so radical. I mean, you guys are toying with my job, you know?"</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="My Plans Moving Forward" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RSI-N-QHNTQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>In the months that followed, OTK associates like Schunk <a href="https://www.sportskeeda.com/us/streamers/news-just-stop-collaborating-asmongold-fans-react-emiru-talks-issuing-apology-working-people-said-sh-ty-things" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">faced backlash for associating with Hoyt</a>, while big streamers like Cinna <a href="https://www.sportskeeda.com/us/streamers/news-cinna-talks-nmplol-asmongold-s-recent-controversial-opinions-insinuates-emiru-otk-members-cut-ties" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">suggested</a> that Schunk and others should cut ties with him.</p><p>In November 2024, another divisive creator who’d joined OTK in 2021, Tectone, <a href="https://www.sportskeeda.com/us/streamers/news-tectone-announces-resigned-otk-days-former-girlfriend-pinkchyu-accused-sexual-abuse" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">resigned</a> following sexual abuse allegations. When layoffs hit the company in December, employees say they hadn’t been explicitly warned they were coming, but given the year OTK had endured, some felt it was only a matter of time.</p><p>“The writing was on the wall,” said one ex-OTK employee.</p><p>"The money just kind of dried up, and to protect the other subsidiaries, people had to get let go,” said another, who added that they remain proud of what the organization was able to accomplish, despite all the difficulties. “I think we put on some of the best shows ever on Twitch: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLpRYRqpby1Lp7FjamW9XAy4J4J8_zsnl8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wild West</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fA1xMBDTGnE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Melee II and III</a>. We put on an MMA show that was unlike anything we've ever seen before [on Twitch]."&nbsp;</p><p>At this point, OTK’s future is uncertain. Hoyt <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/twitch/asmongold-reveals-that-he-has-officially-left-otk-amid-changes-to-org-3141010/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> during a February 2025 broadcast that he is no longer involved with OTK “at all, pretty much.” He went on to explain that his “extreme” and “polarizing” political content played a major role – and that it did, indeed, make it “harder to find sponsors.”&nbsp;</p><p>"I also don't want to put anybody else at risk by doing that,” he said during the stream. “So that's why I separated myself and I didn't want to have anything to do with that. This is a mutual thing, right? And, even if it wasn't, I still would agree with them."</p><figure><blockquote><p>The writing was on the wall.</p></blockquote></figure><p>But by that point, a measurable amount of damage had already been done: People had already lost their jobs.&nbsp;</p><p>Following the departures of Hoyt, Campbell, and others, OTK’s lineup of owners now looks quite different than it did when it started, with Esfandiari, Rinaudo, Tips Out, Polom, Morris, and Schunk listed as owners, while others, like variety streamers Cyr and Will Neff, are simply content creators under the organization. (Hoyt declined to comment on whether or not he’s still a stakeholder in the organization.) Now OTK is rebuilding. The company is set to host <a href="https://x.com/OTKGamesExpo/status/1890098673117479204" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">another OTK Expo</a> in May. It might end up looking similar to those of previous years, as it will be filmed in the same studio. But behind the scenes, the latest iteration is leaning on contractors – a few of whom used to be OTK employees – instead of a full production team. It’s unclear how many sponsors the show will be able to attract.</p><p>The most notable motion out of OTK this year has been the establishment of yet another spinoff, a marketing company called Cross Realm Inc. Cross Realm has already <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/03/20/3046162/0/en/KICK-Announces-KICK-Partner-Fast-Track-Program-with-OTK-Subsidiary-Cross-Realm-Inc.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">brokered a deal with gambling-powered Twitch rival Kick</a> to fast-track streamers through the platform’s application process. "At the end of the day, Kick has the cash, and OTK needs it," said an ex-OTK employee.&nbsp;</p><p>Bigger changes are coming, both in front of and behind the camera.</p><p>“Just know that we’re trying to make changes to make [OTK] a better org, and you’ll probably hear more about that in the future, the immediate future," Neff, who joined OTK in 2024, <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/twitch/otk-member-reveals-huge-changes-coming-to-org-amid-asmongold-drama-3133678/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> during a February stream. "And if we can’t make it a better place, if we can’t make it a happier, healthier place, then I’ll have to reevaluate where I stand.”&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="(1/2) FEB/15/'25 'Its the weekend and so its time to come all over this kingdom'" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6KVI352C-VY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>During a March stream, Rinaudo downplayed both his role in what remains of OTK and OTK as a whole.&nbsp;</p><p>“We don’t do anything,” he <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/twitch/mizkif-opens-up-about-his-future-in-otk-as-company-restructures-after-asmongold-drama-3159568/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> in response to a viewer question about whether he’d stick around following Hoyt’s departure. “Why would I leave? For what? Another org? There’s no point. I think OTK is just more so a group of content creators nowadays, more so than it is anything else. It’s not really an org.”</p><p>This fits with the changing economics of livestreamed events. Where once organizations like OTK, as well as <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2022/09/27/ludwig-youtube-twitch-offbrand-agency-xqc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ludwig Ahgren’s Offbrand</a>, signaled the rise of a Twitch meta built around glitzy productions, reality – known primarily for its harshness and pretty much nothing else – had other plans. Offbrand Productions launched in 2022 to help other creators roll out the sorts of ambitious, almost television-like bonanzas that helped Ahgren’s star ascend, but it shut down in December 2024. “Our people worked hard and made amazing content, but we failed to make the events business sustainable," Offbrand <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LudwigAhgren/comments/1hdsghe/offbrand_productions_shut_down_offbrand_games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote at the time</a>. Former OTK employees couldn’t help but feel sympathy pangs.&nbsp;</p><p>“You even saw Offbrand, they tried to give it an entire go, and they ran into the same things,” said one ex-OTK employee. “I know the exact same feeling that they felt. A lot of brands got smarter, too. They realized 'Cool, you guys are pulling in a lot of viewers, but it's just not the same.' The conversion isn't there for a lot of brands."&nbsp;</p><p>Skyrocketing viewership numbers, brands have come to realize, look nice, but in the world of livestreaming, bigger isn’t necessarily better.</p><p>“Does it really help that Asmongold is the one trying to market a cute, cozy indie game, or that Tectone is the one trying to sell a PC? Maybe it does for the first six months,” said a former OTK employee. “But beyond that, it's actually probably more harmful than it is helpful.”</p><figure><blockquote><p>I think OTK will transform to a similar capacity that [Cenat's] AMP is and FaZe Clan is and Offline TV is. It's a name for a group rather than a company.</p></blockquote></figure><p>Some ex-OTK employees think we’ve already caught a glimpse of the future. Events are thriving on Twitch, but in some ways, the new breed harkens back more to the low-budget-looking chaos of OTK’s early content than to the productions of the AdTK era. Kai Cenat, a streamer so popular that he’s crossed over into the mainstream, made his name on <a href="https://aftermath.site/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-kai-cenat-therapist" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">video game marathons</a> that required little more than a few cameras and a room. Admittedly, as he’s grown, he’s leveled up his approach with high-budget commercials and a mind-bogglingly deep roster of celebrities, but others have applied a more modest version of his formula <a href="https://aftermath.site/ironmouse-twitch-subscriber-record-kai-cenat-2024" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to impressive success</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>"I think creators will copy Kai Cenat and his subathon kind of structure, where they'll invest in a singular room setup,” said an ex-OTK employee. “Extravagant plans, things that are usually run by a group, they'll outsource it. Even something like <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/after-losing-his-father-to-cancer-mega-streamer-shroud-is-running-a-january-fragathon-where-hell-donate-to-cancer-research-for-each-in-game-kill/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shroud's Fragathon</a>, we'll see those, and they'll be around. I think we'll just see a lot less of 'Every quarter, a new game show, etc.’ … I think OTK will transform to a similar capacity that [Cenat's] AMP is and FaZe Clan is and Offline TV is. It's a name for a group rather than a company."&nbsp;</p><p>"There is a huge production team and a huge production budget behind a lot of Kai Cenat's subathons and events,” said another ex-OTK employee. “They're just tucked away in a different room, doing cams, doing [operations]. But I think the audience has shifted away from shows. When you're watching Kai in his bedroom and he's doing a cool event, it's like you're hanging out with a friend. It's like you're there. … We didn't adapt to the audience. We just kept doing what we had been doing for the past four years, and the market changed, and we were behind it."</p><p>OTK, then, was a learning experience for all involved, in both personal and professional senses.</p><p>"I'm a very long-time viewer and member of these communities, so when I first got hired at OTK, it was somewhat of an honor for me to end up working for these guys,” said a former OTK employee. “I really thought it was going to be something different. It was bittersweet."</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Outlaws: A Pirate’s Fortune DLC Arriving Next Month, Leaked Trailer Reveals]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-a-pirates-fortune-dlc-arriving-next-month/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-a-pirate%E2%80%99s-fortune-dlc-arriving-next-month-leaked-trailer-reveals.1167072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-a-pirates-fortune-dlc-arriving-next-month/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The release date and trailer for <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-star-wars-outlaws-patch-drops-forced-stealth-missions/">Star Wars Outlaw's</a> next DLC expansion, A Pirate's Fortune, have leaked online ahead of its scheduled reveal during Star Wars Celebration tomorrow, with the currently unlisted trailer appearing on <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-a-pirates-fortune-reveal-trailer-launches-on-may-15th.1167036/">ResetEra</a>. Since publishing, Ubisoft has taken the trailer down.</p>
<p>Both the trailer and the video's description spoil the surprise that players will be able to step back into the boots of Kay Vess and experience an adventure with fan-favorite character Hondo Ohnaka on <strong>May 15, 2025</strong>, with the DLC including its own season pass, just as the first DLC, Wild Card, did.</p>
<p>A press release from Ubisoft also reveals that a demo for Star Wars Outlaws will be made available starting today on PS5, Xbox Series X/S and PC. The demo will be approximately three hours long, featuring "<em>parts</em>" of the full game, hinting that you'll likely get to jump around in the game's story so you can experience major aspects like open-world exploration, ship battles, and stealth missions. Save data from the demo will not carry over to the full game, should you choose to pick it up.</p>
<p>The new expansion will also feature cosmetic items inspired by the recent television series Star Wars: Skeleton Crew, including an outfit for Nix, a trophy for the speeder, and trinkets for your speeder and Kay's ship, the Trailblazer.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>This new trailer doesn't reveal too much about the story for A Pirate's Fortune, only that you'll be pitted against Stinger Tash and her band of Rokana Raiders while you race against them to do a bit of tomb raiding in the Khepi Tomb.</p>
<p>A Pirate's Fortune is the second of two planned DLCs for Star Wars Outlaws, after which Ubisoft is likely to announce that it has moved on to future projects, especially when considering that, by Ubisoft's admission, Outlaws did not have the <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-has-only-sold-1-million-copies-since-launch-learning-curve-assassins-creed-shadows/">commercial performance</a> Ubisoft was expecting from it.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frostpunk 3 could launch "as early as 2027", with an untitled "larger-scale" 11 bit game planned for 2029]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frostpunk-3-could-launch-as-early-as-2027-with-an-untitled-larger-scale-11-bit-game-planned-for-2029</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/frostpunk-3-could-launch-as-early-as-2027-with-an-untitled-larger-scale-11-bit-game-planned-for-2029.1167066/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frostpunk-3-could-launch-as-early-as-2027-with-an-untitled-larger-scale-11-bit-game-planned-for-2029<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>This War Of Mine company bolsters mixed financial results with big announcements</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/frostpunk-2-city-heart.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>11 bit Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
 "The next project set in the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/frostpunk">Frostpunk</a> universe" is even now in production, developers 11 bit have <a href="https://ir.11bitstudios.com/en/news/11-bit-studios-boldly-invests-in-new-titles/">revealed</a> in their latest annual financial results. Whether it be known as Frostpunk 3, Fro3tpunk, Frostpunk: Revengeance, or some other variation of Frostpunkage, it could launch "as early as 2027". 11 bit have also begun development of a "larger-scale title", which they're hoping to release in 2029. 
</p>
<p>
The financial results paint a mixed picture of 11 bit's fortunes in 2024 - hence the decision to bejazzle the investors with talk of another Frostpunk game. On the one hand, 11 bit have experienced "the highest sales in the company's history", driven by <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/frostpunk-2">Frostpunk 2</a>'s release and legacy sales of Frostpunk and This War Of Mine. On the other, there hasn't been a "corresponding increase" in profit margins, mostly thanks to the cancellation of Project 8, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frostpunk-developers-share-new-details-of-project-8-their-ill-fated-fantasy-game-about-grieving">a third-person fantasy adventure with a theme of working through grief</a>. 
</p>
<p>
11 bit have also seen some disappointments in their publishing division: historical RPG <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-thaumaturge">The Thaumaturge</a> and Pied Piper sim <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/creatures-of-ava">Creatures of Ava</a> have "failed to resonate with gamers", though the experimental satire <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/indika">Indika</a> has apparently done rather well.
</p>
<p>
Frostpunk 2's initially strong showing, meanwhile, has been blunted by mixed player reviews. "We hope that upcoming DLCs, including new gameplay features, will improve the ratings Frostpunk 2 has received from players," CEO Przemysław Marszał comments in the release. (Our own <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frostpunk-2-review">Frostpunk 2 review</a> summed it up as "an atmospheric, bold attempt to reinvent its own society-moulding subgenre whose story and building features too often frustrate with too few options or distract with too many.") 
</p>
<p>
11 bit have some larger hunks of coal in the boiler this year. On the publishing front, there's Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault, "a sequel to the company's most successful third-party title to date", in which you must farm dungeons for goodies to flog in your village store. There's Death Howl, which some oaf who can't be arsed to think of a new description <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/11-bits-latest-curiosity-death-howl-is-a-sorrowing-open-world-deckbuilder-set-in-the-nordic-stone-ages">once described</a> as "a sorrowing open world deckbuilder set in the Nordic Stone Ages". As for in-house games: 11 bit's big bet this year is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-alters">The Alters</a>, in which one man and his many clones must collaborate to operate a rolling spacebase.
</p>
<p>
It's a while away, but: hopes for the next Frostpunk? At the risk of getting myself thrown off a glacier by the faithful, I wonder if it might be time for a change of genre. Perhaps a party-based RPG, like Wartales, with players scouring the icelocked crannies of New London for firewood.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Berserker: Khazan's New Game Plus Gives You Access To Sick New Gear And More Ways To Style Your Fit]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/first-berserker-khazan-new-game-plus-legendary-transmog-1851776611</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-berserker-khazans-new-game-plus-gives-you-access-to-sick-new-gear-and-more-ways-to-style-your-fit.1167060/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/first-berserker-khazan-new-game-plus-legendary-transmog-1851776611<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>New Game Plus is a staple of the soulslike genre. So it shouldn’t come as a surprise that <em>The First Berserker: Khazan</em> provides this option after finishing its campaign for the first time. If you want to know how this popular feature works in this challenging adventure, read on to learn how to start New Game Plus and to know what’s different in your second playthrough and beyond.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197527" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage Part 2 Is Short, Shocking, And Strangely Satisfying" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="169" data-playlist="197527,197525,197298" data-current="197527"><div><p>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage Part 2 Is Short, Shocking, And Strangely Satisfying</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197527/197527_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197527/197527_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197527/197527_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23057.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h135296"><a id=""></a>How to start New Game Plus</h2><p>Before you can start New Game Plus in <em>The First Berserker: Khazan</em>, you’ll need to beat the game’s final boss. Afterward, it’ll be time to decide if you’re ready to move on to New Game Plus, or if you’d like to stay in your current playthrough so that you can finish any bonus missions or grind any weapons and armor you haven’t scored yet.</p><p>Whenever you’re ready, <strong>you can start New Game Plus by speaking to the Phantom in the Crevice and choosing “Begin the next journey.”</strong></p><p>Just be aware that <strong>moving to New Game Plus is a permanent choice</strong>.</p><figure id="" data-id="ae29b22fcabdd329bc33801959b97baf" data-recommend-id="image://ae29b22fcabdd329bc33801959b97baf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist chooses New Game Plus by speaking with an armored NPC." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The protagonist chooses New Game Plus by speaking with an armored NPC." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Neople / Billy Givens / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ae29b22fcabdd329bc33801959b97baf" data-recommend-id="image://ae29b22fcabdd329bc33801959b97baf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist chooses New Game Plus by speaking with an armored NPC." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h135297"><a id=""></a>What’s different in New Game Plus?</h2><p>New Game Plus in <em>The First Berserker: Khazan</em> functions how genre fans have come to expect. You’ll carry over your stats, skills, weapons, collectibles, etc, into New Game Plus, but your mission progress will be reset. As such, you’ll need to work way through the entire game again on your quest to get even stronger.</p><p>While you’ll retain all of your powerful gear and levels, <strong>you’ll face a much more formidable challenge in New Game Plus</strong>, though. Enemies and bosses will hit harder and take even more damage than they did in your first playthrough, ensuring that you’ll have to be even more adept at dodging, blocking, and finding attack windows than ever before.</p><p>All of this is pretty standard stuff, but there is one unexpected thing locked behind New Game Plus: <strong>You’ll now have access to transmog options</strong> by interacting with a mannequin at the Crevice. This allows you to wear your most powerful gear while sporting your favorite look from another set. Awesome.</p><p>If you decide to go for a third run of the game, <strong>you’ll also gain access to crafting Legendary gear on NG++</strong>, which is currently the game’s highest tier of weapons and armor. It takes a lot of work to get there, but it’ll be worth it if you’re the type of person to want the very best gear a game has to offer.</p><hr><p><br><em>The First Berserker: Khazan</em> is available now on PS5, Xbox Series S/X, and Windows PCs.  </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Original 1977 Cut Of Star Wars Will Be Screened For The First Time In Over 46 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-iv-a-new-hope-george-lucas-movie-1851776565</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-original-1977-cut-of-star-wars-will-be-screened-for-the-first-time-in-over-46-years.1167024/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/star-wars-iv-a-new-hope-george-lucas-movie-1851776565<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The <em>Star Wars: Episode IV – A New Hope </em>you remember watching wasn’t original. Let me take that back: it wasn’t <em>the </em>original version of the first <em>Star Wars </em>film to crash land in theaters in 1977. But after over more than 46 years of being locked away in a temperature-controlled tomb in England, the public will get to see the first cut, a special, extra-colorful and well-preserved “dye-transfer imbibition” print of the movie, and George Lucas likely won’t be too happy about it.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196406" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="102" data-playlist="196406,194499,196842" data-current="196406"><div><p>Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21954.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The upcoming <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/films/0/star-wars-original-print-george-lucas-bfi/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/films/0/star-wars-original-print-george-lucas-bfi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">British Film Institute’s Film on Film Festival</a></span> will open in June with a screening of a rare Technicolor film print of the original <em>Star Wars</em> film that was released during its initial run in Britain. While it has been released on home video, this will be the first time the public will be able to watch it in theaters since December 1978. If Lucas had it his way, the world would probably have never seen it.<br></p><p>George Lucas has been tinkering with <em>Star Wars: Episode IV – A New Hope </em>for years, attempting to revamp the film with additional scenes here, a new opening sequence there, and a slew of special effects changes. The first changes happened in 1981, when a new cut with the subtitle added replaced the 1977 original print. Since then, Lucas has spent decades avoiding being beholden to his first attempt at his magnum opus. Since 1997, theaters have only been permitted to screen the rejigged, updated version. To Lucas, the version the British Film Institute will be screening “is not very good,” and he won’t acknowledge its existence.</p><p>“The Special Edition, that’s the one I wanted out there. The other movie, it’s on VHS, if anybody wants it. I’m not going to spend the—we’re talking millions of dollars here—the money and the time to refurbish that, because to me, it doesn’t really exist anymore,” Lucas told <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/star-wars-original-cut-edit-screening-george-lucas-1236191847/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/star-wars-original-cut-edit-screening-george-lucas-1236191847/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the <em>Associated Press</em></a></span> in 2004. “It’s like this is the movie I wanted it to be, and I’m sorry you saw a half-completed film and fell in love with it. But I want it to be the way I want it to be.”</p><p>Unfortunately for him, Lucasfilm and Disney gave permission to the BFI to screen the original print of the <em>Star Wars</em> film. He may believe “a film belongs to its creator,” according to what he told the audience during his masterclass seminar at last year’s Cannes Film Festival. But, when you <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://thewaltdisneycompany.com/disney-to-acquire-lucasfilm-ltd/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://thewaltdisneycompany.com/disney-to-acquire-lucasfilm-ltd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sell your company</a></span> for $4 billion, you quickly learn it does not. After the two screenings at the BFI Film on Film Festival, the movie is “going straight back to the Master Film Store and those sub-zero conditions” which maintained the film’s pristine quality over the decades, according to BFI National Archive’s Senior Curator of Fiction and Programme Director of the festival James Bell.</p><p>The festival will open on June 12 in London.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Charizard Premium Collection Is Back in Stock at Amazon For Just $50]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-charizard-premium-collection-back-in-stock-amazon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-charizard-premium-collection-is-back-in-stock-at-amazon-for-just-50.1167012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-charizard-premium-collection-back-in-stock-amazon<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">This box gives you ten chances to pull something unforgettable.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s be real: I don’t need another <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-pokemon-tcg-deals">Pokémon card bundle</a>. But the moment I saw the Charizard ex Super Premium Collection on sale, something in my brain short-circuited. My body? Fully ready for yet <em>another</em> unnecessary purchase. And at <a href="https://zdcs.link/9yXRm6?object_uuid=d18afbef-ba9c-4fc0-b09c-5dbe79fed3de&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">under $50, this box is stacked</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’re getting a foil Charizard ex promo, plus matching Charmander and Charmeleon to complete the fiery trio. There’s even a Charizard display figure (because, of course, there is), and—get this—ten booster packs. Not five. Not six. Ten. That’s ten chances to pull something ridiculous. </p><div catalogid="e45a74c9-b9d4-478c-991d-5d8e613269a4" id="218886"><div id="218886" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG Charizard ex Super Premium Collection</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The set includes packs from Twilight Masquerade, Stellar Crown, Paradox Rift, Temporal Forces, and Obsidian Flames—some of the most exciting recent drops in the TCG lineup.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To help you further in your quest for great pulls, here are some of my favorite chase cards from these Pokémon TCG sets. Or, if you're done with chasing singles in boosters and fancy just picking up a couple of single cards instead of splashing out on this deal, I've included some handy offers from TCG Player to make sure you're getting the best price.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">My Favorite Twilight Masquerade Cards</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">I want Perrin and Hisuian Growlithe purely for the art. GIDORA nailed the emotional bond between a Trainer and her Pokémon, and the way the two illustrations pair up makes pulling just one feel like an incomplete thought. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the other end of the spectrum, Dragapult ex is is terrifyingly efficient and might be the best Pokémon ex in the set. Carmine is the real money card here though, continuing the trend of playable, stylish Trainer cards dominating the top of the market. Throw in cozy Eevee vibes and a surprisingly playable Ursaluna, and you’ve got a set with range.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">My Favorite Stellar Crown Cards</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Stellar Crown is what happens when nostalgia and artistry shake hands. Squirtle and Bulbasaur show off their bird-watching hobbies in some of the most charming cards I’ve seen in years. Then there’s Terapagos ex, which looks like it belongs in a jewelry store, not a binder. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hydrapple and Dachsbun are slightly more niche but still desirable thanks to lush illustrations and just enough playability to make you think twice before selling. I think this set knows what it's doing: hook you with Kanto starters, then keep you around with glittering, high-rarity flex pulls.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">My Favorite Paradox Rift Cards</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Paradox Rift wants to make a statement. Roaring Moon ex is the best pull here, both in power and price, and Groudon isn’t far behind with volcanic drama cranked to eleven. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Iron Valiant and Altaria offer very different flavors of future aesthetic, and somehow they both work. Iron Hands ex might not be pretty, but it’s still a beast in competitive decks. If you're after a set that brings both gorgeous artwork and raw pressure, this is the one to crack.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">My Favorite Temporal Forces Cards</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Temporal Forces is part prehistoric brawl, part retro sci-fi. Raging Bolt ex leads the pack with one of the strongest attacks in Standard, and Iron Crown ex isn’t far behind, fueling Future decks with wild efficiency. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Walking Wake ex wins big on artwork alone, thanks to Suicune’s eternal popularity, and Gouging Fire holds its own with surprise jungle-dino energy. Even Iron Leaves ex has sneaky-good utility. I want every single one of these cards for a different reason, which is exactly how a good set should work.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">My Favorite Obsidian Flames Cards</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Charizard ex is the undisputed king here, with two of the most sought-after variants in the entire block. The Special Illustration Rare version is especially gorgeous, all fire and fury, while the gold Hyper Rare keeps things flashy. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ninetales and Cleffa bring artistic value, and I think Cleffa might be the most unexpectedly stunning card in the set. Pidgeot ex also deserves a shout for balancing playability with an ultra-stylized take on a Gen I classic. This is one of those sets where almost every big pull earns its spot.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 17, 2025 2:04 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>