<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 18:54:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Games Store’s Mega Sale kicks off with a free Dragon Age: Inquisition download]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/16/24158138/epic-games-store-mega-sale-dragon-age-inquisition-free-deal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-games-store%E2%80%99s-mega-sale-kicks-off-with-a-free-dragon-age-inquisition-download.873246/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/16/24158138/epic-games-store-mega-sale-dragon-age-inquisition-free-deal<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you’re a PC gamer with time to kill this summer, the Epic Games Store has come through with a chance to scoop up a bunch of titles on the low. In fact, you can take advantage of the <em>Fortnite</em> maker’s “Mega Sale” without spending a single dime. In addition to deep discounts on top games, you’ll be able to scoop up one free game each week from the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/sales-and-specials/mega-sale">Epic Games Store</a> through the sale’s June 13th closing date, starting with <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/dragon-age-inquisition-game-of-the-year-edition-2f0cbd"><strong><em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em>’s Game of the Year Edition</strong></a><strong>. </strong>It comes with all of the game’s three main add-ons, plus the Deluxe Edition’s bonus mounts, gear, and weapons.</p><p><em>Inquisition</em> features developer BioWare’s patented branching storylines, deep action roleplaying combat systems, an open-world structure, and an evolving diplomacy system that has you, as the so-called Inquisitor, making world-changing decisions that your companions and opponents may or may not like. It’s still worth playing all these years later, especially with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/4/23987808/dragon-age-dreadwolf-trailer-summer-2024-bioware">a new series entrant on the way</a>.</p><div><p>You’ll find many other titles on sale for your coinage in the Epic Games Store Mega Sale, including newer hits like <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/alan-wake-2"><em>Alan Wake 2</em> down to $39.99</a> ($10 off), <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/ea-sports-fc-24"><em>EA Sports FC 24</em> for $13.99</a> ($56 off), and Ubisoft’s online pirating adventure <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/skull-and-bones"><em>Skull and Bones</em> for $29.99</a> ($30 off). You can also explore the wizarding world in <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/hogwarts-legacy"><em>Hogwarts Legacy</em> for $29.99</a> ($30 off) and play some of Sony’s best PS4 titles on PC with the likes of <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/god-of-war"><em>God of War</em></a> ($24.99, $25 off), <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/the-last-of-us-part-1"><em>The Last of Us Part I</em></a> ($40.19, about $20 off), and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/marvels-spider-man-remastered"><em>Marvel’s Spider-Man Remastered</em></a> ($35.99, $24 off).</p></div><div><p><em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em> Game of the Year Edition includes the base game and all of the DLC for BioWare’s acclaimed action RPG. The dynamic open-world title puts you in the shoes of the Inquisitor, giving you influence to shape the open-world realm and the lives of the inhabitants within as you protect them from mythical threats.</p></div><div><p><em>Alan Wake 2 </em>is the culmination of everything Remedy Entertainment has been building toward. The inventive third-person survival game is both horrifying and strange, with dual campaigns that are more than a little meta.</p></div><p>If you want the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24155407/apple-ipad-air-review-2024">newest iPad Air with M2</a>, it’s going to cost you at least $599 for the 11-inch model. It’s a less impressive upgrade over its predecessor than the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24155440/apple-ipad-pro-2024-review">well-reviewed iPad Pro</a>, however, and the original still holds up well if you just need a solid tablet that should continue to receive most new iPadOS features for the foreseeable future. You’d get considerable savings, too, as the base <strong>M1 iPad Air</strong> with 64GB of storage is down to $399 ($200 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/2022-Apple-iPad-10-9-inch-Wi-Fi/dp/B09V3HN1KC?tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com">Walmart</a>, a new all-time-low price that beats the previous record by a full $100. The 256GB M1 iPad Air also has a new price record of $599 ($150 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/2022-Apple-iPad-10-9-inch-Wi-Fi/dp/B09V3H386P?tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> in select colors.</p><p>It’s possible Apple or its retail partners will keep the 2022 Air around as a value buy, so maybe this steep discount reflects a pending permanent price cut. Whatever the case, $399 is a fantastic price for the tablet. Compared to the refresh that launched just yesterday, it’s really only missing out on <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/7/24146454/apple-pencil-pro-ipad-stylus-price-availability-features">Apple Pencil Pro</a> support, the M2-exclusive Apple Pencil hover feature, and Wi-Fi 6E (but Wi-Fi 6 is still good). There’s also no option to step up to a bigger 13-inch model. Otherwise, it still has more power than most people will likely ever need in a tablet, with its biggest strengths being a beautiful 10.9-inch Liquid Retina display, a lightweight profile, and support for the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MU8F2AM-A-Pencil-Generation/dp/B07K1WWBJK?tag=theverge02-20">second-gen Apple Pencil</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Magic-Keyboard-11-inch-iPad-Generation/dp/B0863BQJMS?tag=theverge02-20">the original Magic Keyboard</a>.</p><p><h5><a href="https://www.theverge.com/22979828/apple-ipad-air-2022-review">Read our Apple iPad Air (2022) review</a>.</h5></p><div><p>The 2022 iPad Air retains the iPad Pro-esque redesign of the 2020 model but does away with the A14 Bionic processor in favor of Apple’s fast M1 chip. It also comes in one of five colors and boasts a 12MP front-facing camera with support for Apple’s Center Stage feature.</p></div><div><div><h2>Verge Deals on X<!-- --> <!-- --> / </h2><p>Join more than 50,000 followers and keep up with the best daily tech deals with @vergedeals</p></div><p><a href="http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud">Follow us!</a></p></div><p><h3>Don’t miss these other great deals</h3></p><div><ul><li>Whether you’re getting the new <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/7/24150360/google-pixel-8a-price-specs-camera-best-take-magic-editor">Pixel 8A</a> or have one <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23912370/google-pixel-8-pro-review-camera-assistant-magic-editor-best-take-audio-eraser">of the family’s loftier devices</a> and need a new pair of wireless earbuds, we typically recommend <strong>Google’s Pixel Buds Pro, </strong>which are down to $139.99 ($60 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Google-Pixel-Buds-Pro-Headphones/dp/B0B1N7SGMZ?tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://howl.me/cmgnN6MgbxZ">Best Buy</a>, and <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=vergeroudupdeals051624&amp;veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGoogle-Pixel-Buds-Pro-Wireless-Earbuds-with-Active-Noise-Cancellation-Bluetooth-Earbuds-Lemongrass%2F449765781">Walmart,</a> matching the all-time low. The Pixel Buds Pro earn their merit as a very competent pair of earbuds when it comes to common qualities, such as very good sound with solid noise cancellation, long battery life, and reliable connectivity that evaded some older models. You can have an enjoyable listen paired with any phone, but they’re even better if you have a Pixel thanks to exclusive features like spatial audio. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23281445/google-pixel-buds-pro-noise-canceling-earbuds-review">Read our review</a>.</li><li>The <strong>Hatch Restore 2</strong>, one of our <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23291925/best-sleep-tech-trackers-earbuds-wearables">favorite sleep gadgets</a>,<strong> </strong>is down to $169.99 ($30 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C67ZDQLX/?tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://hatch.sjv.io/c/482924/1067883/13693?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hatch.co%2Frestore">Hatch</a>, which is only $10 more than the all-time low. Besides the generous assortment of built-in sleep sounds, it features an embedded dot-matrix LED clock and a light that glows just bright enough to keep you from stubbing your toe on the nightstand during midnight bathroom runs. It can also play sunrise alarms that wake you up with gradual gentle sounds designed not to disrupt your circadian rhythm. You can sign up for Hatch Plus ($4.99 a month or $49.99 a year) to add custom unwind routines, music, meditation, sleep guidance, and other exclusive content. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23673132/hatch-restore-2-review-tiktok-sleep-tech">Read our review</a>.</li><li>Now through May 31st,<em> <strong>Metal Gear Solid: Master Collection Vol. 1</strong></em> for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X / S, and Nintendo Switch is down to $24.99 ($35 off) at <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-8836598-13142092%3Fsid%3Dvergeroundupdeals051624%26url%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Felectronics.woot.com%252Foffers%252Fmetal-gear-solid-master-collection-vol-1z">Woot</a>, which is the lowest price we’ve seen so far. The collection includes the most classic games from the stealth ops franchise. You’ll get the first three <em>Metal Gear Solid</em> games that launched on the PS1 and PS2, <em>Metal Gear</em> and <em>Metal Gear 2</em>, and <em>Snake’s Revenge</em>, which is a spiritual, noncanonical successor to the original <em>Metal Gear</em> that was only released in North America for the NES. The disc also packs digital art books, screenplays, cinematic videos, graphic novels, and digital soundtracks to enjoy.</li></ul></div><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p> / <span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we've tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hades 2's First Patch Makes You Faster]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hades-2-first-patch-faster-sprint-dash-resources-1851482260</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hades-2s-first-patch-makes-you-faster.873243/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/hades-2-first-patch-faster-sprint-dash-resources-1851482260<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Supergiant Games’ roguelike <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hades-2-tips-beginner-start-1851459493&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hades-2-tips-beginner-start-1851459493">Hades 2</a></span> has been out in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/im-skipping-hades-2-early-access-1851459155&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/im-skipping-hades-2-early-access-1851459155">early access</a></span> for a little over a week and a half and it’s been a pretty wonderful (and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hades-2-hot-characters-gods-character-art-portrait-1851461870&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hades-2-hot-characters-gods-character-art-portrait-1851461870">disgustingly hot</a></span>) time so far. However, some players have had difficulty adjusting to protagonist Melinoë’s dash, as well as her ability to sprint. Luckily for those folks, Supergiant Games is already on it and <em>Hades 2</em>’s first patch is addressing speed first and foremost.</p><div data-video-id="196539" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Innovative Hades-Like Feels Built For Speedrunners" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="278" data-playlist="196539,196848,195891" data-current="196539"><div><p>This Innovative Hades-Like Feels Built For Speedrunners</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196539/196539_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196539/196539_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196539/196539_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196539/196539_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22094.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>As of today’s patch, Melinoë’s sprint (which did feel a little too slow) has been sped up to make her “innately faster.” Her sprint is also much more responsive, since some players found it a little difficult to turn while they were running, which I’m sure became a pain in the ass in some late-game areas that are positively swarming with things trying to kill you.<br></p><p>Melinoë’s dash has also been ever so slightly tweaked so that players can dash out of recovery animations faster. It isn’t that she would necessarily get stunlocked by damage, but I did find she was a bit too slow to dash away from enemies after being struck. Now, she should have the same urgency I have as I slam on the dodge button so as to not lose one of my death defiances on an otherwise phenomenal run of the game.<br></p><p>Melinoë’s dash in <em>Hades 2</em> has been a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/HadesTheGame/comments/1cm8jc5/melino%C3%AB_taking_her_sweet_time_after_i_press_x/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HadesTheGame/comments/1cm8jc5/melino%C3%AB_taking_her_sweet_time_after_i_press_x/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">little controversial</a></span> since it is markedly slower than Zagreus’ from <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hades-the-kotaku-review-1845204803&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hades-the-kotaku-review-1845204803">the first game</a></span>. Her dash leaves a trail that she must recover before she can dash again, which is a pretty drastic change from Zagreus, who was able to dash again pretty instantaneously. He was even able to collect boons that granted him multiple extra dashes before he tired. While I wouldn’t mind seeing Supergiant tweak Melinoë’s kit, I think this difference especially makes them unique characters that promote different playstyles. I’d hate to see Melinoë’s footprint stamped out of the game because of the studio’s responsiveness to feedback.<br></p><p>Speaking of faster, <em>Hades 2</em>’s first patch is also speeding up <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/how-to-get-bronze-hades-2-fishing-rod-1851465960&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/how-to-get-bronze-hades-2-fishing-rod-1851465960">resource gathering</a></span>. The sequel introduces crafting and multiple different gathering tools that must be unlocked in order to obtain the resources to craft what the game refers to as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hades-2-incantations-unlock-first-tips-1851461926&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hades-2-incantations-unlock-first-tips-1851461926">incantations</a></span>, which often amplify Melinoë’s abilities and add mechanics and features, like farming. However, you can only use one resource gathering tool at a time, meaning you have to pick if you are prioritizing plants, fishes, ores, or other materials for each run. In my experience, a good run culminating in a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;http://v&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://v/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">diabolical showdown against Chronos</a></span> at the very end could take about 40-50 minutes, meaning that’s a hefty chunk of time to not be gathering other materials.<br></p><p>Now, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;http://v&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://v/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Hades 2</em></a></span><em> </em>players will be able to collect from <em>any</em> resource point that they find during a run so long as they have the associated gathering tool unlocked. So if you’ve unlocked the spade or the pickaxe, you don’t need to have them equipped to dig up seeds or mine ore, respectively. Toggling a specific gathering tool will allow you to gain as much from the resource points as you could prior to this patch, while “resources for tools you do not prioritize will appear far less often,” according to the patch notes.<br></p><p>Elsewhere, Supergiant has issued tiny (but consequential) fixes, like showing your currency when you’re at a Well of Charon, or repeating the tutorial for Grasp upgrades at the Altar of Ashes. Anecdotally, a friend of mine made it to the third region of the game without upgrading their Grasp to have more passive buffs because they just didn’t know how to do it. If you’ve been there, you know that region is hard as hell even <em>with </em>upgrades, and players have reported that the game does a poor job of explaining the system. As of this patch, more players will hopefully know how to upgrade their Grasp and get beefed up for their fight with Chronos.<br></p><p>For the entirety of the patch notes, which are mostly directed at feedback the team’s received since launch, check them out <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1145350/view/4175477072263852699&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1145350/view/4175477072263852699" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a></span>. Supergiant mentions that with this first patch out of the way, it’ll be working on balance changes next, which tells me that I better fit in a win soon before the team nerfs my favorite boons/builds.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Xbox Feature Could Save Players Loads Of Time]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-series-x-s-preload-update-mouse-keyboard-cloud-1851482275</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-xbox-feature-could-save-players-loads-of-time.873240/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/xbox-series-x-s-preload-update-mouse-keyboard-cloud-1851482275<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="939d05e2d07055a8b62640c4ea59c8ec" data-recommend-id="image://939d05e2d07055a8b62640c4ea59c8ec" data-format="jpg" data-width="1460" data-height="821" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Baldur's Gate 3's heroes pre-download their next update. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Baldur's Gate 3's heroes pre-download their next update. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Larian Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="939d05e2d07055a8b62640c4ea59c8ec" data-recommend-id="image://939d05e2d07055a8b62640c4ea59c8ec" data-format="jpg" data-width="1460" data-height="821" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Baldur's Gate 3's heroes pre-download their next update. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Modern games get patched all the time, and there are few things more low-key annoying than sitting down to dig into a meaty RPG or hop into a quick deathmatch only to see you’ve got to download an 8GB update. You start scrolling TikTok or dropping memes in the group chat and by the time you realize the game’s finally ready, the night’s over and you’ve got to get to bed so you don’t feel like hell in the morning. It happens <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/BaldursGate3/comments/1asekt8/patch_6_size_on_xbox_is_way_bigger_than_announced/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BaldursGate3/comments/1asekt8/patch_6_size_on_xbox_is_way_bigger_than_announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">all the time with <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em></a></span>. </p><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,191188,196230" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>This should soon be a thing of the past on Xbox Series X/S, at least for some games. Microsoft recently confirmed an “Update Pre-Download” feature is being tested on the Insider program to install updates ahead of time so they don’t interfere with when you’re actually trying to play. “Games that enable support for update pre-download will allow updates to be downloaded days before they are scheduled to release, so you can jump in and start playing right when the update goes live!” the company <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/hardware-network/xbox-insider-release-notes/console/alpha/2024/05/alpha-2406-240509-2000&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/hardware-network/xbox-insider-release-notes/console/alpha/2024/05/alpha-2406-240509-2000" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote in the latest release notes</a></span>. </p><p>Multiplayer pirate sim <em>Sea of Thieves </em>will be the first game to support this feature, though it will presumably work on many other games as well by the time it’s rolled out for everyone. PlayStation 5 already has something like this so many third-party publishers already support a version of it. And since Microsoft has bought up many of the biggest games, I expect things like <em>Call of Duty</em>, <em>Diablo 4</em>, and <em>Overwatch 2</em> to utilize it as well. </p><p>Microsoft has been working on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/05/15/xbox-may-update-2024/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/05/15/xbox-may-update-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">some other neat features</a></span>, too. Mouse and keyboard support for cloud gaming has arrived for a bunch of games including <em>Cities: Skylines</em>, <em>The Sims 4</em>, <em>Fortnite</em>, and <em>Doom 64</em>. The company also recently revealed a new accessibility peripheral called the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.byowave.com/product/proteus-controller-kit-vip&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.byowave.com/product/proteus-controller-kit-vip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xbox Proteus controller</a></span>. It’s modular, supports all sorts of different wireless configurations, and looks like the futuristic microbots from <em>Big Hero 6</em>. The device ships this fall starting at $300. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Details On New Valve Game ‘Deadlock’ Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/details-on-new-valve-game-deadlock-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/details-on-new-valve-game-%E2%80%98deadlock%E2%80%99-leaked.873234/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/details-on-new-valve-game-deadlock-leaked/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>New details have emerged about Valve’s new game in development, including that it will officially be called Deadlock. During it’s development at Valve, the game had been known as Neon Prime and Citadel.</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://twitter.com/gabefollower/status/1791110448114188557" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gabe Follower on Twitter</a>, there is a lot of new information about the game. </p>



<p>Deadlock will reportedly be a 6 vs 6 third-person hero shooter. The game will feature a large map with four lanes to attack that have tower defense mechanics as well as various items and abilities to utilize. Gabe Follower adds that Deadlock will have a fantasy setting “mixed with steampunk. Magicians, weird creatures and robots.”</p>



<p>Lastly, they say that the game will feature fast travel using floating rails “similar to Bioshock Infinite”.</p>



<p>As of publishing, this information has yet to be confirmed by Valve nor has it been independently verified by Insider Gaming. Because of that, take all information on Deadlock, including the name, with a grain of salt.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Valve for comment. Should a response be received, this story will be updated accordingly.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the rumors surround Valve’s new game Deadlock? For more Insider Gaming, read our full review of the Arena Breakout: Infinite Beta, and subscribe to the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>&nbsp;to keep up to date with all things gaming.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phoenix Labs lays off over 100 staff, cancels all upcoming projects]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/phoenix-labs-lays-off-over-100-staff-cancels-all-upcoming-projects</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phoenix-labs-lays-off-over-100-staff-cancels-all-upcoming-projects.873231/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/phoenix-labs-lays-off-over-100-staff-cancels-all-upcoming-projects<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Studio to focus on serving Dauntless and Fae Farm communities going forward.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Phoenix Labs [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/garena/phoenix-labs">Phoenix Labs</a> has reportedly laid off over 100 employees and canceled development on all non-<em><a title="Games > Dauntless [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dauntless">Dauntless</a></em> and <em><a title="Games > Fae Farm [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fae-farm">Fae Farm</a></em> projects. <span id="more-883182"></span></p><p>In a message to posted on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7196925181712343042/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a>, the studio said that it will focus on serving the communities of its two live service games <em>Dauntless</em> and <em>Fae Farm</em> going forward, and that “work on all other projects at the studio” has been canceled.</p><p>According to <a href="https://twitter.com/sweetpotatoes/status/1791158439684587999" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Polygon reporter Nicole Carptenter</a>, speaking to two sources at the studio, over 100 employees were impacted by the cuts, and one of the canceled games was nearing an announcement.</p><p>“This restructure has not come easily, and truly has been the last resort to ensure Phoenix Labs can survive, and thrive in the long term,” the studio said. “It’s impossible to put into words how deeply we value every talented individual who has contributed their hard work and passion to every project at our studio.”</p><p>Get the full message from Phoenix Labs below.</p><blockquote><p>Today is an incredibly difficult day. After a long period of evaluating how to navigate our economic environment, we have had to significantly restructure the company to pave a path for a strong future.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>We are reorganizing Phoenix Labs to focus on our best-in-class live service titles, <em>Dauntless</em> and <em>Fae Farm</em>, and serving their communities.</p><p>This unfortunately means canceling work on all other projects at the studio, which will impact many of our colleagues immediately. We are giving<br>notices to everyone whose roles are affected.</p><p>This restructure has not come easily, and truly has been the last resort to ensure Phoenix Labs can survive, and thrive in the long term. It’s impossible to put into words how deeply we value every talented individual who has contributed their hard work and passion to every project at our studio.</p><p>We are doing all we can to help our departing team members in this interim period and encourage any studios looking for incredible talent to speak with the one-of-a-kind people that have been a part of Phoenix Labs’ journey.</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Warzone: How To Unlock The Black Ops 6 "Sally" Weapon Blueprint]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-how-to-unlock-the-black-ops-6-sally-weapon-blueprint/1100-6523521/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-warzone-how-to-unlock-the-black-ops-6-sally-weapon-blueprint.873228/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-how-to-unlock-the-black-ops-6-sally-weapon-blueprint/1100-6523521/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523521">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">The latest update to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone/" data-ref-id="5000-572198">Warzone</a> seems to have slipped in a secret weapon blueprint that teases this year's upcoming Call of Duty game, which is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-file-text-might-maybe-possibly-point-to-new-game-reveal-this-month/1100-6523127/">rumored to be Treyarch's Black Ops 6</a>. Here we'll explain how you can unlock the "Sally" weapon blueprint for the 9mm Daemon.</p><h2 dir="ltr">The Sally weapon blueprint explained</h2><p dir="ltr">The Sally weapon blueprint is an akimbo version of the 9mm Daemon pistol, and the cosmetic is skinned to look like the iconic pistols from the cover of 2010's Call of Duty: Black Ops. In Black Ops 1's Zombies mode, the M1911 starter pistol could also be Pack-a-Punched to become the powerful "Mustang and Sally" akimbo variant.</p><p dir="ltr">Treyarch has <a href="https://twitter.com/Treyarch/status/1790842985929744580">tweeted a response</a> to a player's mention of Warzone's secret weapon blueprint, so it is very likely a purposeful tease of their upcoming title.</p><h2 dir="ltr">How to get the Sally weapon blueprint</h2><p dir="ltr">To unlock the Sally blueprint, you'll need to find the 9mm Daemon in a match of Warzone and get a kill with the gun. <strong>Getting your first kill with the pistol</strong> will complete the secret challenge called "She Never Lets Me Down," and the blueprint will be available for use in both MW3 and Warzone.</p><p dir="ltr">This will only unlock the Sally blueprint for whoever picks it up and gets a kill with it, but after you or a teammate unlocks the weapon, it can then be dropped mid-match for any remaining teammates to try and unlock the blueprint for themselves.</p><p dir="ltr">The 9mm Daemon is <strong>very rare </strong>ground loot that can reportedly be found across various modes in standard battle royale and Resurgence. <strong>This gun can be found as loot on the ground or scavenged from supply boxes.</strong></p><p dir="ltr">Some players claim that the spawn rates are better in Warzone's Fully Loaded LTM for Rebirth Island, but there don't seem to be any guaranteed spawn locations for the 9mm Daemon.</p><p dir="ltr">For more on Warzone, make sure to check out our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-how-to-do-rebirth-islands-champions-quest-nuke-challenge/1100-6522448/">full guide for completing Rebirth Island's Champion's Quest</a> nuke challenge. Here's how you can get <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-complete-the-new-rebirth-island-easter-egg-in-cod-warzone/1100-6522402/">Season 3's "Redacted" weapon blueprint</a> in Warzone.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameSquare launches Faze Media]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/gamesquare-launches-faze-media</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamesquare-launches-faze-media.873225/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/gamesquare-launches-faze-media<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content_above">



<p>
If you click on a link and make a purchase we may receive a small commission.  <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/editorial-policy">Read our editorial policy</a>.
</p>
    <div>
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-type="article">


<header>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Faze Clan's Richard Bengston will lead the firm, while investor Matt Kalish joins the board</p>

    </div>


  

    

</header>  <div>



            <p>GameSquare has unveiled Faze Media, a creator-focused IP and media firm.</p>
<p>The multimedia company aims to expand the licensing and sponsorship opportunities for the Faze Clan brand.</p>
<p>Faze Media will be overseen by CEO Richard Bengston. He was a co-founder of the Faze Clan esports outfit.</p>
<p>Additionally, the new firm secured a $11 million investment from Matt Kalish. Kalish will join as a board member of Faze Media.</p>
<p>According to the deal's details, GameSquare will own 51% of Faze Media, while Kalish maintains 49% ownership.</p>
<p>"We are thrilled to better capitalize this business for growth with $11 million in new capital from Matt, and to strengthen the FaZe Media board with his addition," said GameSquare CEO Justin Kenna.</p>
<p>"Matt deeply believes in the power of founder and creator-led organizations and shares the vision to return FaZe back to its roots by empowering its creators."</p>
<p>The news comes after GameSquare completed its acquisition of Faze Clan back in March.</p>



        </div>
        </article>

  
    </div>


  
      </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phoenix Labs lays off staff, cancels games in major restructuring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/phoenix-labs-lays-off-staff-cancels-games-studio-fate-unknown</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phoenix-labs-lays-off-staff-cancels-games-in-major-restructuring.873222/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/phoenix-labs-lays-off-staff-cancels-games-studio-fate-unknown<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Phoenix Labs appears to be executing another round of layoffs, eliminating what may be over 100 employees. Former employees on LinkedIn are reporting the loss of their jobs and stating that all projects in development have been cancelled.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Word of the layoffs also comes from Polygon senior reporter </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/sweetpotatoes/status/1791158439684587999">Nicole Carpenter,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> who says some laid-off developers mentioned they were laid off during a mass Zoom call.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Phoenix Labs has now confirmed that it laid off employees earlier today. The company wrote in a statement that it did so to "focus on our best-in-class live service titles, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dauntless</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fae Farm</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and serving their communities."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company said this restructuring is a "last restore to ensure Phoenix Labs can survive, and thrive in the long term."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On LinkedIn, former principal engineer Kris Morness said the layoffs were ordered Phoenix Labs owner </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.forte.io/">Forte</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The blockchain platform apparently acquired Phoenix Labs "over a year ago" in an unpublicized transaction. He corroborated a post from former UX lead Noah Watkins that said the studio's next game was just a few weeks away from being announced.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Watkins said that game was "weeks away" from launching in Early Access.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Why is Phoenix Labs laying off employees?">Why is Phoenix Labs laying off employees?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Phoenix Labs spent 2023 wrestling with major organizational changes, culminating in a series of layoffs in</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-i-dauntless-i-dev-phoenix-labs-lays-off-30-employees"> May</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/dauntless-developer-phoenix-labs-has-laid-off-34-support-workers">December</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The layoffs in May followed the company breaking away from parent company Garena, developers of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Garena Free Fire</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Lining up that timeline with Morness' claim about Forte, it seems likely that the blockchain platform was a key part of the shift in ownership. It's unknown why its involvement wasn't publicized.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Phoenix Labs did not address this purchase in its announcement.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/reshuffle-at-dauntless-dev-phoenix-labs-as-ceo-and-coo-step-down">September,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> CEO Jesse Houston and COO Jeanne-Marie Owens stepped down from their roles for "personal reasons." At the time, Houston stated that "the future has never looked brighter" for Phoenix Labs. He praised the "amazing pipeline" of games in development.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It now seems that pipeline has been closed off. This is of course another in a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/keyword/layoffs">long line of game industry layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that have led to thousands of workers losing their jobs since the start of 2023.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Update 5/16: </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">This story has been updated with confirmation from Phoenix Labs about ongoing layoffs.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Phoenix Labs for comment and will update this story when a response is issued.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision announces new studio, Elsewhere Entertainment, to make a narrative-based AAA franchise]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/activision-announces-new-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-to-make-a-narrative-based-aaa-franchise/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=activision-announces-new-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-to-make-a-narrative-based-aaa-franchise</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-announces-new-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-to-make-a-narrative-based-aaa-franchise.873219/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/activision-announces-new-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-to-make-a-narrative-based-aaa-franchise/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=activision-announces-new-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-to-make-a-narrative-based-aaa-franchise<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="316" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Activision has <a href="https://blog.activision.com/activision/2024/activision-announces-new-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-all-new-franchise-development" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced on its blog</a> today that it is forming Elsewhere Entertainment, a new studio that will focus on a new narrative-based “genre-defining” AAA franchise. We don’t know what that franchise will be, nor what genre it will be defining, but we do know it will be headquartered in Warsaw, Poland.</p> <p data-characters="391" data-current-count="391" data-injectable="false">Activision states that the developer will be “built from the ground up” and will establish “an environment that inspires bold and diverse ideas.” The team will consist of “storytelling experts” who have worked on such franchises as “<em>The Last of Us</em>, <em>Uncharted</em>, <em>The Witcher</em>, <em>Cyberpunk</em>, <em>Destiny</em>, <em>Tom Clancy’s The Division</em>, and <em>Far Cry</em>.” That’s a lot of storytelling experts.</p> <p data-characters="227" data-current-count="618" data-injectable="true">It’s hard not to be cynical about a studio established by a company whose parent <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/redfall-and-hi-fi-rush-developers-shut-down-in-another-awful-wave-of-microsoft-cuts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">just shut down a handful of talented studios</a>. It sounds like, “Why are you buying a Mercedes when you just defaulted on your last car loan?”</p>
 <p data-characters="178" data-current-count="178" data-injectable="false">“Elsewhere is opening its search for best-in-class talent from across the industry,” the release says. Yeah, I think you might know a few people who are now looking for work.</p> <p data-characters="203" data-current-count="381" data-injectable="false">I know that it’s never quite that simple, but it just seems really galling for Activision to trumpet its founding of a AAA studio so soon while Microsoft keeps <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/microsoft-lays-off-1900-employees-from-activision-blizzard-and-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">making huge cuts</a> across its subsidiaries.</p> <p data-characters="219" data-current-count="600" data-injectable="false">Hopefully, Elsewhere Entertainment will do well. I don’t know what “narrative-based” means to an executive and “genre-defining” is nothing but PR speak, but at least I don’t see the words “live service.”</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Core Keeper gets a 1.0 and console release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/core-keeper-gets-a-1-0-and-console-release-date/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=core-keeper-gets-a-1-0-and-console-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/core-keeper-gets-a-1-0-and-console-release-date.873216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/core-keeper-gets-a-1-0-and-console-release-date/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=core-keeper-gets-a-1-0-and-console-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="235" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Pugstorm and Fireshine Games have announced the official launch date for <em>Core Keeper</em> 1.0 and all console ports. The developer and publisher have confirmed the game will finally leave Steam Early Access and hit consoles simultaneously. </p> <p data-characters="485" data-current-count="485" data-injectable="true">The <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/top-games-like-stardew-valley/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cozy sandbox adventure game</a> <em>Core Keeper</em> will leave early access on PC and launch on PS4, PS5, Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X/S on <strong>August 27, 2024</strong>. After initially releasing in March 2022, the game has been on a long Early Access road to get to this point, with new biomes, mechanics, and bosses added each step of the way. The complete package that forms the final game later this year will contain everything the developer has added and worked on with its community.</p>
 <h2 id="h-core-keeper-s-1-0-and-console-release-will-get-a-final-content-trailer-next-month" data-injectable="false"><em>Core Keeper</em>‘s 1.0 and console release will get a final content trailer next month</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Core Keeper - Console &amp; PC 1.0 Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ga6q6vUluzE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="513" data-current-count="813" data-injectable="true">Since its initial launch on PC in Steam Early Access, <em>Core Keeper</em> has grown with new features, biomes, items, and more in every update. Senior Brand Manager for Fireshine Games Vincent Coates said in a press release with this announcement, “It’s been amazing to see over 2 million players discover the charm, mystery and fun of <em>Core Keeper</em> throughout the game’s time during Steam Early Access, and we can’t wait for even more to discover everything it has to offer with the full launch.”</p>
 <p data-characters="254" data-current-count="254" data-injectable="false">The final trailer for the 1.0 and console launch will be released in June. This will be the biggest launch for the game since its Early Access debut, so there might even be a few surprises lumped in with the new versions to show off when the video debuts</p> <p data-characters="379" data-current-count="633" data-injectable="true">I’ve been playing <em>Core Keeper</em> since its Early Access launch and have thoroughly enjoyed how each update has added more depth to the game, instead of just tacking on a new area with the same tired mechanics. It’s an intriguing title because it forces you to tentatively explore a very alien world underground where you must defeat colossal monsters in order to escape.</p>
 <p data-characters="363" data-current-count="363" data-injectable="false">I’ll never forget the first time I found Ghorm the Devourer, a giant worm that travels in a wide circle around the map, and how I managed to kill it with traps, bombs, and a lot of luck. Each boss defeated opens up a new part of the world and a way to expand your base, the plants you farm, your armor and weapon sets, and the strange magics of this world. </p> <p data-characters="294" data-current-count="657" data-injectable="false">I’ve been longing to play<em> Core Keeper</em> on PS5 for ages. It’s a game I’ve already sunk dozens of hours into and can’t wait to play again, exploring every biome, unlocking every merchant, and building up an arsenal of cheeky weapons to hopefully take down every boss I can.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: PO’ed: Definitive Edition]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-poed-definitive-edition/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=review-poed-definitive-edition</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-po%E2%80%99ed-definitive-edition.873210/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-poed-definitive-edition/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=review-poed-definitive-edition<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="275" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">When Nightdive Studios announced that they’d be remastering <em>PO’ed</em>, I <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/im-the-fool-nightdives-poed-definitive-edition-is-actually-real/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">thought they were joking</a>. It was April 1st, and they posted a trailer that starts off rather deceptively. But here it is. I’m not sure I really wanted to play <em>PO’ed</em>, but now I’ve played all of it.</p> <p data-characters="406" data-current-count="406" data-injectable="true"><em>PO’ed</em> was initially released in 1995 on the doomed 3DO Interactive Multiplayer before getting a 1996 port on PlayStation. The first-person shooter genre was still in its infancy, and while these early years resulted in classics like <em>Doom, Quake, </em>and <em>Duke Nukem 3D</em>, it’s also a graveyard for countless others that are now largely forgotten. If it isn’t obvious, <em>PO’ed </em>belongs in the latter category.</p>
 <p data-characters="373" data-current-count="373" data-injectable="false">I hadn’t played it before. There was a copy in one of those early-PS1 cardboard longboxes in the basement of the game store I briefly ran, and I didn’t touch it. There was probably a reason it was in the basement (my guess is disc rot), and I wasn’t <em>that</em> curious. However, reviews at the time of its release weren’t <em>terrible</em>. Though, they probably should have been.</p> <figure data-current-count="673" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="203" data-current-count="203" data-injectable="false"><strong><strong><strong>PO’ed: Definitive Edition (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2697470/POed_Definitive_Edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PC</a> [Reviewed], <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/poed-definitive-edition-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Switch</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0913-PPSA22307_00-0180316664507147" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PS4</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0913-PPSA22307_00-0180316664507147" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PS5</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/poed-definitive-edition/9pcg4c64qh9f" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox One</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/poed-definitive-edition/9pcg4c64qh9f" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Series X|S</a>)<br>Developer: Any Channel</strong></strong>, Nightdive Studios<strong><strong><br>Publisher: Nightdive Studios<br>Released: May 16, 2024<br>MSRP: </strong></strong>$19.99</strong></p> <p data-characters="350" data-current-count="553" data-injectable="true"><em>PO’ed</em> has enough going for it to separate itself from the pack of FPS games that were coming out at the time. Notably, using the SlaveDriver Engine, it was much better at 3D environments, even though they were incredibly basic. It’s also a lot weirder with the default weapon being a frying pan, a chef protagonist, and walking butts for enemies.</p>
 <p data-characters="277" data-current-count="277" data-injectable="false">The story involves Ox, the protagonist, being stranded out in the furthest reaches of space where the locals are hostile. There isn’t much storytelling within the game itself, so it’s not too far off from many FPS games at the time, right down to the abstract environments.</p> <p data-characters="391" data-current-count="668" data-injectable="true">But the level design is a lot different than much of what you’d see at the time. Environments are often huge, open areas. Much of the time, you get around with the help of a jetpack. It’s actually rather impressive, since corridors were the main locale for a lot of ‘90s gunfights. Nevermind that a lot of the surfaces are just flat-shaded, at least we aren’t looking at dirty walls.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe loading="lazy" title="PO'ed: Definitive Edition Announcement Trailer | Nightdive Studios" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0nLgTVr_JcA?feature=oembed&amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;origin=https://www.destructoid.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="232" data-current-count="532" data-injectable="true">Having large environments meant that the developers were delving into some unexplored territory, and while I’d argue that there’s a decent amount of talent on display in <em>PO’ed</em>, it doesn’t really coalesce in an enjoyable way.</p>
 <p data-characters="411" data-current-count="411" data-injectable="true">The goal of every level is to simply find the teleporter out of it, but they needed to make that a challenge <em>somehow</em>. Often, this means that you’re scouring through maze-like environments looking for the damned thing, but then there are others where the goal is not so clear. Sometimes you have to kill all the enemies in the area, and other times you need to activate a series of switches to make it through.</p>
 <p data-characters="500" data-current-count="500" data-injectable="true">The maze-like environments are bad enough. As I said, a lot of the textures are just flat colors. This can get extremely disorienting, especially when you add <em>PO’ed’s </em>penchant for verticality. I never really got stuck, but I think that was largely just luck. However, I was often uncomfortable, and regularly very confused. Sometimes I would trip over the teleporter’s location within moments of starting a level and of the game’s three secret levels, I found two of them by complete mistake.</p>
 <p data-characters="214" data-current-count="214" data-injectable="false">I didn’t <em>want</em> to find these secret levels. The normal levels were painful enough, that I didn’t want to extend it any further. They were the first warm teleporters I found to cuddle up to, and they betrayed me.</p> <figure data-current-count="514" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="228" data-current-count="228" data-injectable="false">I found myself comparing <em>PO’ed</em> to <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/william-shatners-tekwar-is-the-technological-future-of-crap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">William Shatner’s TekWar</a></em> for much of the game’s runtime. <em>TekWar</em> also liked to experiment with open environments. But most starkly, they both have the same approach to difficulty balancing.</p> <p data-characters="381" data-current-count="609" data-injectable="true">Since many of the levels are large, open areas, this can mean a lot of enemies are constantly shooting at you from all directions. The worst are any sort of flying foe, because they are extremely difficult to hit on medium settings. Even if you stay mobile and fly around with your jetpack, you’re going to take a lot of hits. There’s not much choice to it, damage will happen.</p>
 <p data-characters="413" data-current-count="413" data-injectable="true">So, to offset this, <em>PO’ed </em>gives you a massive health bar and dumps healing items in stacks all over the place. In order to make later levels more difficult, they just reduce how many stacks of health kits they provide. I mean, that works, it’s just the least well-thought-out and elegant way to do it. It also means that the screen flashes a lot and your dude keeps grunting. It’s not a very fun experience.</p>
 <p data-characters="177" data-current-count="177" data-injectable="false">Speaking of sounds, there’s barely any music. I had to check to make sure it wasn’t just a bug that prevented music from playing during levels, but there really isn’t any.</p> <figure data-current-count="477" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="263" data-current-count="263" data-injectable="false">The <em>Definitive Edition</em> is inarguably the best way to experience <em>PO’ed</em>. Its transition to the KEX Engine means it’s capable of higher resolutions and interpolation to smooth out movement. It also means mouse-look, which wasn’t possible on the 3DO or PS1.</p> <p data-characters="397" data-current-count="660" data-injectable="true">Nightdive did a decent job of upgrading <em>PO’ed</em>. They didn’t go all the way with it like they did with some previous titles. I asked Director of Business Development Larry Kuperman if they updated the art in any way. “Yes, to the art,” he said. “Tweaked more than redone.” He also said, “Not sure I want to compare what we did for <em>PO’ed</em> to anything close to <em>Dark Forces</em>, Zoey.”</p>
 <p data-characters="446" data-current-count="446" data-injectable="true">So, in comparison to the <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-star-wars-dark-forces-remaster/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Star Wars: Dark Forces</a></em> remaster, it’s not quite as overhauled. Enemy sprites are still low-resolution mashes of pixels. There weren’t really any cutscenes to redo, either. It’s largely “just” a source port, but it still does wonders for the game. But considering that <em>PO’ed</em> isn’t a guaranteed seller like a game with the <em>Star Wars </em>name on it, it’s not surprising they didn’t give it a complete facelift.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="369" data-current-count="669" data-injectable="true">The best thing I can say about <em>PO’ed</em> is that it can be completed in around three hours. Aside from that, I really didn’t enjoy it. It’s not the worst FPS I’ve played. For all its problems, it at least isn’t bland. It has its high points, demonstrates a capable development team with a willingness to experiment, it just didn’t result in a fun final product.</p>
 <p data-characters="518" data-current-count="518" data-injectable="true">I also must commend Nightdive Studios for having the guts to remaster a game that can’t even claim a cult following. <em>PO’ed</em> isn’t notoriously bad, but it would probably be better if it was. I’m not sure I’ve ever heard it come up in conversation. I might never have played it had it not been for Nightdive, and for that, I’m grateful in a very strange way. Even if a game is obscure or outright bad, I always love seeing them get dusted off and restored to working order. I just never want to play it again.</p>
 <p data-characters="79" data-current-count="79" data-injectable="false"><sub>[This review is based on a retail build of the game provided by the publisher.]</sub></p>

<div>
<p>
4.5 </p>
<div>
<p>
Below Average </p>
<p>
Have some high points, but they soon give way to glaring faults. Not the worst, but difficult to recommend. </p>
</div>
</div>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eric “ConcernedApe” Barone Can’t Let Go Of Stardew Valley]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/stardew-valley-concernedape-haunted-chocolatier-interview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eric-%E2%80%9Cconcernedape%E2%80%9D-barone-can%E2%80%99t-let-go-of-stardew-valley.873207/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/stardew-valley-concernedape-haunted-chocolatier-interview<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The lights temporarily brighten on the stage of The Town Hall, a historic New York City venue, and a crowd of over 1,000 people hushes into anticipatory silence. The conductor of the orchestra has just announced that a special guest is in the building. Moments later, <em>Stardew Valley</em> creator Eric “ConcernedApe” Barone, clad in dark slacks, a yellow shirt, and a plain jacket, takes the stage. The audience goes absolutely bananas. You’d be forgiven for thinking, even after taking in nearly an hour of beautifully-performed music, that the <em>real </em>rockstar has finally arrived.</p><p>This was the scene earlier this year at the New York City stop of Stardew Valley: Festival of Seasons, a worldwide tour featuring orchestral renditions of <em>Stardew Valley</em> songs. Originally released in 2016, <em>Stardew Valley</em> is no longer just a game. It’s an institution, a cozy-game genre progenitor that continues to grow via both community efforts and official updates from Barone, who – despite embarking on a new project in <a href="https://www.hauntedchocolatier.net/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Haunted Chocolatier</em></a> – cannot bear to part with it. It’s also more than just a game. There’s now <em>Stardew Valley</em> merchandise, the aforementioned tour, a board game, and as of this week, <a href="https://stardewvalleycookbook.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an official cookbook</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Though <em>Stardew Valley</em> did not invent the farming genre – and obviously took a lot of inspiration from <em>Harvest Moon</em> – it certainly triggered the avalanche of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games-like-stardew-valley-the-best-farming-games-on-pc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">similar farming games that followed</a>. On top of that, numerous games have farming and other life sim elements in them now, regardless of genre. <em>Palworld </em>and <em>Hades 2</em> immediately spring to mind, and that’s just from the past few months. <em>Stardew Valley</em>’s popularity, meanwhile, is enduring, with sales <a href="https://twitter.com/ConcernedApe/status/1762195335936627147" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hitting the 30 million mark</a> in February just before the release of the rabidly-anticipated 1.6 patch in March.</p><figure><figcaption>Stardew Valley: Festival of Seasons</figcaption></figure><p>Barone, in turn, has become a singular figure in the world of video games. Once a (largely) solo developer kept afloat by his girlfriend and propelled forward by little more than an ambitious dream, he’s now the captain of a vastly larger and more recognizable ship than the one he started out in. He wrestles with this. On one hand, he appreciates all the praise. He recognizes that people have connected to <em>Stardew Valley</em>’s world and characters on a very deep level. That means everything to him.</p><p>"There's certain aspects to <em>Stardew Valley</em> now that are inextricable from the community that's formed around it,” Barone told Aftermath. “How everyone feels about all the different characters and the interpretations [of them]. … To be in the same room with all of these souls [at the concert], it's a special feeling. It's a reminder that my work does impact real people."</p><p>On the other hand, he doesn’t view himself as that big of a deal, even if fans do.</p><p>"I'm just a dude that made a game,” Barone said. “I was just making the game I wanted to play. What I would say is, I was tapping into a certain zeitgeist that I wasn't aware of, or conscious of, but I wasn't the only one who was feeling that way. We wanted to play games that were a little bit different. ... I think if I hadn't done it, someone else probably would have in a similar timeframe."&nbsp;</p><figure><blockquote><p>To be in the same room with all of these souls, it's a special feeling. It's a reminder that my work does impact real people.</p></blockquote></figure><p>On stage at The Town Hall, Barone ran through <a href="https://twitter.com/Vahn16/status/1763416421168533802" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a joke-y version of his origin story</a>. He used to make music that nobody wanted to listen to, he said, but “after many years of failure, I finally discovered the secret: all I had to do was develop an entire video game from scratch, and then you guys would finally listen to my music.” The audience ate it up, laughing and cheering in response.</p><p>There was a kernel of truth to the bit, though. "I wanted to make music and somehow have a career making music,” he explained to Aftermath. “I would have been happy with any form that took, but when I was in high school, my original dream was to be in a band and go on tour and play shows. Little dingy venues – that would have been awesome. But I quickly realized that's not an easy thing to materialize. So then I shifted into electronic music, and I would have been happy if I could have been successful just online doing that. But that also didn't work out. So eventually, I finally got the music out by making a video game. I'm happy now because I still get to make music and have it be part of something that people are interested in and want to listen to."</p><figure><figcaption>Stardew Valley: Festival of Seasons</figcaption></figure><p>Now Barone has many more eyes on him than he ever would’ve amassed playing in a band, but it’s a different kind of fame. Barone does his best to entertain his followers inside the game and out – especially online, where he continues to personally keep them abreast of what’s coming next, something many developers who’ve sold even a fraction of 30 million copies would’ve handed off to somebody else by now. To him, entertaining is just part of the job, whether on stage or on Twitter.</p><p>"It's just yet another aspect of game development. I've always had kind of a scrappy 'If someone else can do it, why not me' type of approach," Barone said. "I kind of see myself as an entertainer. … I feel a pressure to have a presence because there's a million people who decided to follow me. I don't want to just do nothing, you know?”</p><p>But Barone’s hands-on approach to all aspects of <em>Stardew Valley </em>stems from far more than mere obligation. The game began as an extremely personal solo project, and even though it’s grown into a millions-selling multimedia behemoth, he still feels intimately connected to it.</p><p>“I feel responsible for any issues that people have, or if anyone doesn't enjoy the game or has a bad time,” he said. “It's not only with <em>Stardew Valley</em>, but anything related to <em>Stardew Valley</em>: the merchandise, the board game, the concert – anything like that. It's weird because <em>Stardew </em>has grown into something beyond me, but at the same time, I still feel very personally responsible for the brand and the concept of <em>Stardew Valley</em>."&nbsp;</p><p>This, in a way, is how the game’s 1.6 update came about. Barone now works with a team on <em>Stardew Valley</em>’s more technical aspects, and he wanted 1.6 to focus on technical tweaks and nothing more. But then he began to dread what fans might think if he didn’t go all out on yet another update. So he paused work on <em>Haunted Chocolatier</em>, his long-awaited but still mysterious second game, to return to <em>Stardew Valley</em>.</p><p>“It wasn't something that was necessarily planned,” Barone said. “I was like 'I can't just release a technical update, because if I say there's a new <em>Stardew Valley</em> update, and there's literally no new content, I feel like people will be disappointed.' So at first it was just the Desert Festival, but I have this problem where once I start, I can't stop. I'm thinking 'Oh, this isn't enough. It'd be really cool to add this. I would love to add this.'”</p><figure><blockquote><p>I feel responsible for any issues that people have, or if anyone doesn't enjoy the game or has a bad time. It's not only with <em>Stardew Valley</em>, but anything related to <em>Stardew Valley</em>: the merchandise, the board game, the concert – anything like that.</p></blockquote></figure><p>In these moments, Barone isn’t just motivated by a fear of letting down <em>Stardew</em>’s devoted legions. He’s also keenly aware of the impact the game has had on some players’ lives.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>“Once I reopen the book on <em>Stardew</em>, I always have a hard time closing it again because I always want to add more things, make it better, make it cooler, make people happy,” Barone said. “It's exciting. Every single thing I'm adding, I'm thinking about how people are going to play this and talk about it and love it. It's gonna be part of their experience. It could make a memory that they might cherish forever. That's a special thing. It's hard for me to not want to do that.”</p><p>That’s not to say Barone is trapped in an eternal, unchanging loop of returning to <em>Stardew Valley</em>. Version 1.6 was the first time he allowed somebody else to leave their fingerprints on the game’s content – its art, especially – and not just technical and programming elements. Barone added a longtime <em>Stardew Valley</em> modder who goes by the handle FlashShifter to the team <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/how-a-stolen-car-led-the-creator-of-mega-mod-stardew-valley-expanded-to-every-modders-dream-of-working-with-eric-barone-on-update-16/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">after the latter’s car was stolen</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>"He had his car stolen, so he was in a bad situation,” said Barone. “He was like 'Hey, do you want to meet up and get lunch? I'd like to ask you something.’ He was wondering if I would take him on to do some work for <em>Stardew Valley</em>. At the time I was neck deep in working on 1.6 stuff, so I was like 'OK yeah, why not?' … He's studied <em>Stardew Valley</em>'s art style so his mod would seamlessly integrate and look like it fit in <em>Stardew Valley</em>'s world. I feel like he's one of the few people on Earth who really knows how to draw stuff in the exact <em>Stardew Valley</em> art style, which is kind of a specialized skill.”</p><figure><figcaption>FlashShifter</figcaption></figure><p>Barone is uncertain where he wants to go from here. For now he’s working on making sure that 1.6 is bug-free and available on as many platforms as possible, but afterwards he’ll have to make up his mind about a particularly bothersome fork in the road. There is of course the option to let <em>Stardew Valley</em> lie dormant while he completes version 1.0 of <em>Haunted Chocolatier</em>, but he also ended up assembling a “cool team” to get 1.6 across the finish line. Perhaps, he figures, they could keep expanding <em>Stardew Valley </em>in his absence. Well, within limits.&nbsp;</p><p>“It would probably be difficult, and it would probably inevitably mean that I would not focus on <em>Haunted Chocolatier</em> because I would feel like I want to weigh in on and contribute to stuff,” he said of letting the team take the wheel on <em>Stardew Valley</em>. “I have some ideas for things that can be done for <em>Stardew Valley</em> that are less content creation and more technical in nature – more straightforward.”</p><p>Potential (though not set in stone) examples include additional maps for the game’s mines, a new farm type, or a new monster. “It's not like coming up with whole new characters and events and stuff like that,” Barone said. “That's the stuff I feel like I 100 percent have to be doing."&nbsp;</p><figure><blockquote><p>I don't feel like I owe anyone anything when it comes to<em> Haunted Chocolatier</em>. It's a game that I'm deciding to make. I don't need to make it.</p></blockquote></figure><p>He does want to get back to <em>Haunted Chocolatier</em>, though – not because he feels like expectant fans are breathing down his neck, but because, as with <em>Stardew Valley</em>, this one’s personal.&nbsp;</p><p>"[Fan expectation] definitely puts pressure on me,” he said, “but it's better to have a delayed game that's actually good than a bad game that's on time. When it's ready, that's when I'll release it. I'm not too concerned with the pressure. I don't feel like I owe anyone anything when it comes to<em> Haunted Chocolatier</em>. It's a game that I'm deciding to make. I don't need to make it."</p><p>At this point, Barone doesn’t really <em>need </em>to do anything. <em>Stardew Valley</em> has sold more copies than most developers – indie or triple-A – could ever hope. And while he’s living better than he was when <em>Stardew Valley</em> was just a sprout peeking out of the soil, he says he hasn’t done anything “extravagant.” That’s by design. Barone just wants to keep doing things the way he always has.</p><p>“Before making <em>Stardew Valley</em>, I spent all day hunched over the computer,” he said. “I still spend all day hunched over the computer. … My goal in life isn't about making money. I want to create things and share them with the world. That's what it's all about. That's what I'm doing. That's what I will do, regardless of any other circumstances, as long as I can financially support myself to be able to do that. If I couldn't, I would get a job and spend my free time creating stuff to try to get back to doing that."</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prison Architect 2 Preview – Incarcerating the third dimension]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/16/prison-architect-2-preview-incarcerating-the-third-dimension/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/prison-architect-2-preview-%E2%80%93-incarcerating-the-third-dimension.873186/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/16/prison-architect-2-preview-incarcerating-the-third-dimension/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>There’s something very different about <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/prison-architect-2">Prison Architect 2</a> compared to the original, and I’m not just talking about the jump from 2D to 3D. This game’s whole conception and creation has charted a very different path when compared to the “Early Access before Early Access was a thing” release and public development of the first game. Developed by Double Eleven and now under the stewardship of Paradox Interactive, its creation and planned future will be much more like a <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/crusader-kings-3">Crusader Kings</a> or <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/cities-skylines">Cities: Skylines</a>, with a base game to be followed by a steady chain of expansions and DLC.</p>
<p>Yet there’s suddenly some uncertainty floating around Prison Architect 2. Announced at the start of this year, it’s been delayed twice, and has now been revealed that Double Eleven has <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/14/prison-architect-2-developer-double-eleven-breaks-up-with-paradox-interactive/">handed over continued development and support to Brazilian team Kokku</a>. To the backdrop of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/04/18/we-let-you-down-cities-skylines-2-dlc-being-refunded-amidst-player-dissatisfaction/">Cities: Skylines 2’s troubles</a>, that feels like cause for concern, but also for a little optimism –&nbsp;it’s not being forced out the door and the stated reason for the delays is to optimise the game further for lower-end hardware.</p>



<p>I’ve been able to sample the first handful of levels from the game’s career and… well, it’s Prison Architect, but translated into a full 3D game engine –&nbsp;the original had a kind of hacky 3D mode, but this has been designed from the ground up for it. Prison Architect 2 does a really good job of keeping the look and feel of the original game, thanks in large part to the character designs with their perfectly spherical heads, tubular bodies and Rayman hands. You can almost strip away that extra dimension by angling the camera to look straight down on your prison, which can help when laying out buildings, rooms and all the rest.</p>
<p>Something certainly very important for existing fans will be that Prison Architect 2 retains the same construction mechanics as the original. Walls still take up squares on the grid, so a 4×3 cell requires you to lay foundations with a 5×4 footprint, and you have to drag to create a four-sided room as opposed to building one wall at a time. Then, when creating rooms within a larger building still has placing walls and assigning a room’s role handled separately. A Two Point Hospital, for example, combines those two steps into one, which is more immediate, but doesn’t have the same ad hoc flexibility of Prison Architect.</p>

<p>While there is a dedicated tutorial, it almost feels redundant by the career’s opening, which gives you example prisons and hands out missions to complete fundamental tasks. For one prison it was to simply open up a new wing with another 10 prison cells, then it was to give staff a break room and laundry, to cut down on inmate violence through a mixture of building solitary cells and an infirmary, and then getting to the root of the matter by addressing inmate needs for socialising. Each level is wrapped up in a little bit of dialogue from the CEO, Warden, Guards or other characters, pitching the objective before letting you just get on with things, and then quipping as you complete them.</p>

<p>To be honest, you can barely call these scenarios, and as soon as you complete an objective you’re whipped straight back out to the career map –&nbsp;a city and the surrounding countryside –&nbsp;and can pick from the other missions currently available to you. However, what these early levels do provide is a great set of examples for how you might consider building your own prisons in the sandbox mode. One level had some really nice self-contained cell blocks with built in showers, common rooms and more, while others previewed the challenges of having a prison split across a road, or with no room to expand horizontally.</p>
<p>And so we come to what is probably the main appeal to the jump to 3D: multi-floor prisons. This just allows for so much more nuanced creativity in how you might want to lay out your prison, and it’s very straightforward to do. You can switch levels on the right side of the screen or with keyboard hotkeys, and then simply set out walls using the exact same construction tools as for the ground floor. Just make sure that you link floors with staircases, use vertical pipes and wiring to connect up the utilities, and you’re pretty much good to go. Heck, if you’re happy with a prison block layout, just select it, clone it, move up a level and drop it in place again. It’s (almost) exactly that easy!</p>
<p>Of course, it doesn’t have to be a building up there, and you could think of making gantries to overlook a yard, try to create a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panopticon">Panopticon prison</a>, and plenty more besides.</p>

<p>That said, I wish we had more time within these spaces to explore and learn from what Double Eleven has created. Most management sims would let you carry on after completing a scenario’s main objectives, or have the first few levels cover all of the basics, but the first five levels here barely touch upon how to really dig in and manage your prison. It’s through my own curiosity that I sought to grasp how you unlock more room types, more approaches to incarceration or rehabilitation, and the various views and info panels to see how things are running. Those will certainly feature in more career missions to come, but splitting things apart this much is a slightly atypical way of presenting this to players.</p>
<p>I will also say that, while Paradox has said on multiple occasions that Prison Architect 2 has builds certified for all platforms, it does still feel like it needs some refinement before release. I faced crashes upon level exit, some flakiness with item placement and interaction, and just some oddities with the build tools. They’re intuitive on the whole, but I do wish that rooftop items were automatically elevated if you build an additional floor on top, for example.</p>
<p>Still, for fans of the original, I think there’s plenty reason to be optimistic and look forward to this game. Between now and September, new developer Kokku will be refining, polishing and and really honing this game, but from what we’ve seen so far, this is undeniably Prison Architect… in 3D.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lorelei and the Laser Eyes has turned me into a puzzle sicko]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/24157530/lorelei-and-the-laser-eyes-review-switch-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lorelei-and-the-laser-eyes-has-turned-me-into-a-puzzle-sicko.873183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/24157530/lorelei-and-the-laser-eyes-review-switch-steam<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I’ve probably spent more time in <em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</em> jotting down notes and theories than I have actually playing the game. The latest release from Simogo — the Swedish studio behind eclectic titles like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/2/21/4013456/year-walk-iphone-ipad-vision-quest-game"><em>Year Walk</em></a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/10/17/4844472/device-6-iphone-ipad-report"><em>Device 6</em></a> — is a mystery game that is absolutely dense with puzzles. The sheer scale of it is initially intimidating. Everything in the game is locked behind a door of some kind, and figuring out how to open them involves navigating a deluge of cryptic, strange, and often confusing clues. But once I gave myself over to the game’s logic, it all made a certain kind of sense. Eventually, it was all I could think about, and I have the notebook full of scribbled solutions to prove it.</p><p>There’s very little setup. You arrive at a seemingly abandoned hotel in the woods, prompted by a mysterious letter from a cult film director, and from there, well, you’ll have to figure it out yourself. There are some overt goals, like finding some missing script pages for the director, but mostly, the job is to solve puzzles to open up more of this monochrome world and thus learn more about what the hell is going on. The story and puzzles are tightly intertwined, so each solution usually comes with a fresh nugget of narrative. Those nuggets get increasingly weird, full of ghosts, murder, mazes, and obscure movies. And coffee. It’s sort of like if David Lynch designed an escape room.</p><p>It’s intimidating at first because <em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes </em>locks literally everything away. Once you get into the hotel grounds — which, naturally, involves figuring out the code for a padlock — virtually every part of the building is inaccessible, hidden behind some kind of puzzle to solve, which then leads to another puzzle. The first time I unlocked a door, I was so excited, only to discover the only thing inside was a locked safe.</p><div><p>It’s sort of like if David Lynch designed an escape room</p></div><p>Often, those puzzles seem to make no sense at all. It required some patience (and faith in the developers), but eventually, I was able to slowly start finding solutions, and each one brought a new insight. Here’s a small list of some of the things you’ll need to deal with to find answers in <em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</em>: Roman numerals, the Greek alphabet, modern art, obscure (fictional) Italian movies, the phases of the Moon, PS1-era video games, and, unfortunately, basic math.</p><p>It all sounds like too much until you realize that every solution is somewhere inside the game itself. Once I came to the realization that <em>everything</em> was a clue, it all clicked into place. It’s still incredibly hard, but that “ah ha” moment made it clear that it was at least possible, which helped me push forward. If I couldn’t solve something, it was almost always because I didn’t have the right information yet. Thankfully, <em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</em> gives you a lot of tools to find that information; the main character has a photographic memory, so you have a running list of every important document, image, and memory for future reference. Even still, I’d say a notebook is required for working out some of the more difficult solutions.</p><div><p><cite>Image: Annapurna Interactive</cite></p></div><p>There’s a remarkable cohesiveness to the game, where the various elements build on top of each other, and nothing is there by chance. Even the most obscure detail makes sense eventually. It’s hard to think of another game where every part seems to connect in such a natural way. The closest equivalent might be <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/1/27/10841320/the-witness-review-ps4-pc"><em>The Witness</em></a>, but <em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes </em>links its story and gameplay on a deeper level and does so with an enviable amount of style and personality.</p><p>That shouldn’t be a surprise coming from the team behind the slick <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/25/20882183/sayonara-wild-hearts-interview-switch-ps4-apple-arcade-simogo"><em>Sayonara Wild Hearts</em></a>. The studio’s new game has the dark undertone of noir but with visual influences ranging from classic video games to Saul Bass to Lynch. It’s also a surprisingly playful experience, full of delightful interactions; at a certain point, you can even mail-order playable cartridges for an in-universe Game Boy. It’s weird and unsettling and lovable, and it looks great doing it.</p><p><em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes </em>is also part of a truly incredible run of recent indie games, including the likes of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24152085/hades-2-steam-deck-performance"><em>Hades II</em></a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24147616/manor-lords-steam-early-access"><em>Manor Lords</em></a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24153478/crow-country-review-steam-ps5-xbox"><em>Crow Country</em></a>, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24152153/animal-well-review-switch-ps5-steam-videogamedunkey"><em>Animal Well</em></a>. It’s a tough crowd to stand out in, but <em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</em> does just that with its seamless blend of puzzles, style, and eerie worldbuilding. Just make sure you have a notebook handy.</p><p><small>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes<em> launches May 16th on the Nintendo Switch and Steam.</em></small></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I’m going to watch the MoviePass documentary for one reason only]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24158282/moviepass-max-documentary-trailer-schadenfreude</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i%E2%80%99m-going-to-watch-the-moviepass-documentary-for-one-reason-only.873180/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24158282/moviepass-max-documentary-trailer-schadenfreude<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="WOb47Y">Max has released a trailer for its documentary <em>MoviePass, MovieCrash</em>, coming to the streaming service on May 29. And frankly, it looks awful. The trailer makes the film look like the worst kind of bubbly, hyperbolic TV news report, full of over-the-top voiceover, staccato sound bites, and sensationalist quotes, all trying to inject riffy, bouncy energy into a story that doesn’t need <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/01/31/style/jeuje-zhoosh-zhuzh.html">zhuzhing up</a>. The actual doc may be nothing like this; trailers are notoriously unreliable about reflecting what a movie is actually like. But either way, I don’t care. I’m all in, for one reason: I just want to see the faces of the people behind the story I followed with absolute nonstop disbelief for two full years of “Oh God, what <em>now</em>?” schadenfreude.</p>
<p id="nI7VsE">MoviePass was around for six years as a largely under-the-radar, somewhat pricey subscription service for movie tickets before analytics firm Helios and Matheson acquired it. In 2017, the revamped company introduced an unbeatable subscription service: Members could get unlimited movie tickets for about $10 a month. “How could this business model possibly work?” industry-watchers asked at the time. The answer: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20872984/moviepass-shutdown-subscription-movies-helios-matheson-ted-farnsworth-explainer">It couldn’t</a>. Helios and Matheson lost hundreds of millions of dollars on the project, while visibly, awkwardly, and very publicly flailing to redefine the company’s intentions every few weeks.</p>
<p id="KlI5Bs">While all this was happening, I was the Movies Editor over at The Verge, and we reported on <a href="https://www.theverge.com/culture/2018/7/31/17634990/moviepass-theater-disrupting-film-subscription-service/archives/2">every new beat in the story</a> as it happened, because our readers loved knowing what new nonsense MoviePass was up to. What made the story so fascinating and engaging was how absolutely clear it was that Helios and Matheson did not know anything about the industry it was trying to disrupt, and how rapidly it kept changing the story about what MoviePass was intended to do.</p>
<p id="8GYDsN">The company clearly thought its subscriber base would give it leverage over the industry, and was willing to endure huge losses while it tried to figure out what to do with that leverage. One week, it was effectively trying to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/26/16936952/moviepass-amc-theatre-feud-movie-tickets-deceptive-earnings-statement">blackmail theater chains</a> into giving it discounts, or risk MoviePass diverting its subscribers to different chains. Similarly, it tried to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/2/17073386/moviepass-limited-access-red-sparrow-death-wish-amc-film-studio-negotiations">extort studios into paying it for advertising</a>, or risk the service blocking subscribers from buying tickets to those studios’ latest movies.</p>
<p id="OEizjy">At one point, the company boasted about <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/5/17083280/moviepass-location-based-user-tracking-data-privacy-app-policy-changes">the tracking data it was collecting on its subscribers</a> with the intention of selling that data to investors; after a backlash, it <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/13/17113872/moviepass-ceo-apologizes-open-letter-location-tracking-comments">abruptly walked that idea back</a>. Then MoviePass suddenly <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/19/16909414/moviepass-ventures-distribute-movies-sundance">announced it would become a film distributor</a>. Meanwhile, it changed its pricing and the services it offered too many times to count, often with no notice for subscribers, who would suddenly find themselves opted into new plans, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/28/17916256/moviepass-forcing-former-users-opt-out-new-plan-monthly-charge">even if they’d already left the service</a>. At its lowest point, the company sent out a cutesy email claiming it had <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/7/18073750/moviepass-staffed-by-dogs-director-of-barketing-chloe">hired a dog as its new marketing director</a>, and apologizing for the “ruff” time subscribers were having with the service. The <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/14/17691022/moviepass-q2-earnings-report-operating-losses-shareholder-lawsuit">company’s shareholders sued</a>. The <a href="https://variety.com/2019/biz/news/moviepass-class-action-subscriber-1203126638/">subscribers did, too</a>.</p>
<p id="loI5h3">I don’t need to watch <em>MoviePass, MovieCrash</em> for a summary of all this — I lived it, and not that long ago. What I want is to see the people behind the debacle. Throughout the two-year barrage of frantic, nonstop news about MoviePass’ endless abrupt retoolings, the public face on every new debacle was CEO Mitch Lowe. But there were obviously so many more people battling for control behind the scenes, desperately trying to land on the solution that would turn the ship around. All I want from a MoviePass documentary is to know what it was like for everyone who wasn’t Lowe, who wasn’t in front of the cameras trying to justify how Helios and Matheson was hemorrhaging money, being <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/17/17991880/moviepass-fraud-investigation-attorney-general-new-york">investigated for fraud</a>, and <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/moviepass-parent-company-helios-and-matheson-delisted-from-nasdaq-2019-2">watching its stock plummet 99 percent</a>. I just want to put faces to this wild, freewheeling disaster, at long last.</p>
<p id="7SgfVG">Here’s the official rundown on the film, from Warner Bros. Discovery and HBO Original:</p>
<blockquote><p id="jEBs2E">The HBO Original documentary MOVIEPASS, MOVIECRASH, directed by award-winning filmmaker Muta’Ali (HBO’s “Yusuf Hawkins: Storm Over Brooklyn”), debuts WEDNESDAY, MAY 29 at 9:00 p.m. ET/PT on HBO and will be available to stream on Max. In a span of eight years, MoviePass went from being the fastest growing subscription service since Spotify to total bankruptcy, losing over $150 million in 2017 alone. MOVIEPASS, MOVIECRASH chronicles the company’s beginnings as an innovative movie ticketing model beloved by cinema goers, exploring the visionary mission of its entrepreneur co-founders, its impressive early successes, and its precipitous downfall caused by mismanagement and corporate greed. </p></blockquote>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fae Farm Developer Phoenix Labs Lays Off Over 100 People]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fae-farm-developer-phoenix-labs-lays-off-over-100-people/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fae-farm-developer-phoenix-labs-lays-off-over-100-people.873177/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fae-farm-developer-phoenix-labs-lays-off-over-100-people/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Phoenix Labs, the studio behind Fae Farm and Dauntless, is laying off over 100 people. According to <a href="https://twitter.com/sweetpotatoes/status/1791158439684587999">Polygon’s Nicole Carpenter</a>, the studio announced the layoffs “over one big Zoom call”.</p>



<p>In a released statement, Phoenix Labs says that the decisions are being done as part of a reorganization of the company. This includes cancelling “all other projects” outside of Fae Farm and Dauntless.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Major layoffs at Fae Farm, Dauntless dev Phoenix Labs today. Two sources said over 100 people have been impacted. On LinkedIn, a former worker said all in development games have been cancelled, including one about to be announced. Devastating news — so sorry to those impacted. <a href="https://t.co/H4LLH6jY3C">pic.twitter.com/H4LLH6jY3C</a></p>— Nicole Carpenter (@sweetpotatoes) <a href="https://twitter.com/sweetpotatoes/status/1791158439684587999?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 16, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>“After a long period of evaluating how to navigate our economic environment, we have had to significantly restructure the company to pave a path for a strong future,” they said. “We are reorganizing Phoenix Labs to focus on our best-in-class live service titles, Dauntless and Fae Farm, and serving their communities.</p>



<p>“This unfortunately means canceling work on all other projects at the studio, which will impact many of our colleagues immediately. We are giving notices to everyone whose roles are affected. This restructure has not come easily, and truly has been the last resort to ensure Phoenix Labs can survive, and thrive in the long term.”</p>



<p>The studio says that it’s doing “all we can” to help those who are being let go from the company. It also  “encourage[s] any studios looking for incredible talent to speak with the one-of-a-kind people that have been a part of Phoenix Labs’ journey.”</p>



<p>Since the start of 2024, the gaming industry has seen roughly 10,000 people let go in some way. </p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the latest layoffs, this time at Fae Farm studio Phoenix Labs? For more Insider Gaming, check out the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-sports-college-football-25-release-date-and-cover-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date for EA Sports College Football 25</a>, and subscribe to the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>&nbsp;to keep up to date with all things gaming.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15 Games to Get During Devolver’s Birthday Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/15-games-to-get-during-devolvers-birthday-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/15-games-to-get-during-devolver%E2%80%99s-birthday-sale.873174/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/15-games-to-get-during-devolvers-birthday-sale<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Devolver has been going strong for 15 years now and has established a reputation for publishing high-quality indie games from around the world across a wide range of genres. From the early days of Serious Sam and Hotline Miami, to more recent hits like Cult of the Lamb and Inscryption, the publisher has a track record of allowing small, creative teams to flourish.</p><p>To celebrate their 15th birthday, Devolver is hosting a huge sale on their entire catalog of games from May 16–23 on Steam. Since they’re turning 15, we figured it only made sense to showcase 15 lesser-known gems from their roster that you can get for super cheap during the sale:</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/ronin-ninja-platforming-with-a-gory-reward-pax-south-2015"><u><strong>Ronin</strong></u></a></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $2.59 (80% off)</strong></p><p>Released in 2015, Ronin is a turn-based action-stealth platformer created by Polish developer Tomasz Wacławek while he was working as a designer at Shadow Warrior studio Flying Wild Hog. Inspired by the likes of Gunpoint, Ronin is about a young girl determined to strike down five prominent figures of a powerful corporation, one at a time. Over its 15 missions, you carefully plot your movements to set up the perfect strike before retreating back into the shadows. Throw in a handful of ninja gadgets — including, of course, a trusty grappling hook — and Ronin is well worth its short and sharp playtime.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/okhlos-official-launch-trailer"><u><strong>Okhlos</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $2.59 (80% off)</strong></p><p>Greek mythology has always been ripe for satire, and 2016’s Okhlos joined in on the fun. Set in ancient Greece under the omnipotent rule of Olympian gods, you’re tasked with mobilising people tired of the abuse suffered at the hands of their rulers through philosophical teachings, convincing them to break free from the chains of Mount Olympus and establish an ochlocracy — literal mob rule. Going from city to city, players look to recruit warriors, peasants, slaves, and even livestock to topple the status quo through eight procedurally generated locations. As you progress, you can unlock special units or swap them for one of 100 legendary heroes to upgrade your mob and increase their savagery. Each run is different, and you may find yourself taking command of the likes of Heracles, Leonidas, Pandora, or even Socrates to turn your mischievous gang into a formidable army. It’s total anarchy in the birthplace of democracy!</p><h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mcTW8TyKtaM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><strong>High Hell</strong></u></a></h2><p><strong>On sale for: 80% off (Soundtrack Bundle)</strong></p><p>First exploding onto the indie scene with roguelike shooter Heavy Bullets, Brazilian developer Terri Vellmann and American rapper Doseone teamed up once again for 2017’s High Hell. It’s a neon-soaked, arcade-action first-person shooter that sees you descend upon an underground criminal enterprise with the most blessed of shotguns, bringing lethal salvation to those who have fallen from the light. Righteous fury and fancy footwork are crucial to surviving an escalating, absurd series of outlandish missions. Don’t be surprised to find yourself popping brainwashed chimps, defacing corporate effigies, and dismantling the business dealings of the unrepentant cartel in this vibrant, psychedelic remix of the classic first-person shooter.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pl3w5baycdw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><strong>Not a Hero</strong></u></a></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $3.99 (80% off)</strong></p><p>Long before the critically acclaimed, award-winning OlliOlli World and Rollerdrome, UK-based studio Roll7 dipped its toe into the world of action platforming with 2015’s Not A Hero, a raucous ballet of blood, bullets, and a political incumbent calling himself BunnyLord. You play as Steve, a former assassin turned campaign manager, sent out by BunnyLord to clean up the city by “shooting crime in the face.” You add additional crew members as the campaign picks up steam, including the shotgun-toting Cletus, hip-thrusting SMG master Jesus, and the dangerously enthusiastic katana-wielding Kimmy. You quickly find yourself murdering your way through gangs and police officers alike in the pursuit of winning the mayorship. Shoot, slide, dive, and duck behind a political platform built on ethics, accountability, and an inordinate amount of gunfire.</p><h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Br686sJTnmw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><strong>SPACEPLAN</strong></u></a></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $0.98 (67% off)</strong></p><p>SPACEPLAN is an experimental piece of interactive fiction based partly on developer Jake Hollands’ total misunderstanding of Stephen Hawking’s A Brief History of Time. Launched in 2017, SPACEPLAN started life as an idle, browser-based “clicker” game (this was a thing back in the late 2010s) but soon expanded into a full game that was eventually released on both PC and mobile platforms. The game is beautiful in its simplicity: use manual clicks and the passage of time to create and launch potato-based devices and probes from your nondescript satellite orbiting a mysterious planet. Essentially, you can either spend this time unlocking the mysteries of the galaxy or just kill some time.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/crossing-souls-demo-gameplay-video"><u><strong>Crossing Souls</strong></u></a><strong></strong></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $2.99 (80% off)</strong></p><p>Nostalgia has always been a big thing for gamers, and that’s apparent in 2018’s Crossing Souls, developed by Spanish indie studio FourAttic (named after their “office,” which was literally an attic). Inspired by the dreamlike, Spielbergian wonder of classic ’80s fantasy, sci-fi, and coming-of-age movies, Crossing Souls takes you on a cinematic adventure through California in the midst of a supernatural event that rocks a small community. Taking control of five friends, each one with their own skills and combat styles (not to mention typically ’80s personality traits), you’re charged with flitting between each character on the fly, using each kid's specialties to overcome obstacles and the bad guys’ weaknesses. Featuring a nostalgia-inducing cinematic score that evokes peak John Williams, wonkily animated cutscenes, and dozens of easter eggs, Crossing Souls is a joyful trip back to when VHS fuzz was the worst of your problems.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2014/07/25/gods-will-be-watching-review"><u><strong>Gods Will Be Watching</strong></u></a><strong></strong></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $1.99 (80% off)</strong></p><p>Gods Will Be Watching is the first full-fledged release from narrative-driven developer Deconstructeam. Originally developed as an entry for the Ludum Dare game jam back in 2013, Gods Will Be Watching caught the eye of Devolver, who stepped in to help turn it into a full game. The result divided opinion upon its release in 2014, with some critics and players finding it difficult to get past the game’s intentionally punishing mechanics, despite acknowledging the team’s talent. Pitched as a minimalistic sci-fi point-and-click thriller centred on despair, commitment, and sacrifice, this was perhaps to be expected. Nevertheless, Deconstructeam soon implemented The Mercy Update as a way of helping players make the tough decisions that affect their entire crew’s wellbeing. It remains an innovative departure from the traditional point-and-click adventure, taking place in six intimate, tension-filled scenarios linked together through a narrative of interstellar espionage.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/11-minutes-of-gato-roboto-gameplay-pax-west-2018"><u><strong>Gato Roboto</strong></u></a><strong></strong></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $1.99 (75% Off)</strong></p><p>2019 introduced Devolver-owned studio Doinksoft to the world with the Oregon outfit’s debut title, Gato Roboto. Featuring classic NES-inspired monochromatic visuals, the game follows a cat named Kiki attempting to save her owner after they crash land on an alien planet, forcing Kiki to don a mech suit and explore the planet's depths. Pet-troidvania, Meow-troidvania, Mechtroidvania…whatever your genre-bending description of choice, Gato Roboto sees you exploring the underground labyrinth of a deep space outpost, uncovering the dastardly deeds that unfolded before your arrival. Curiosity will often get the better of your feline instincts, as you’ll also need to venture outside your trusty mech and risk all nine lives to explore otherwise inaccessible areas. Secrets abound in this purrfect ode to classic puzzle platformers. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/bleak-sword-dx-official-pc-and-nintendo-switch-launch-trailer"><u><strong>Bleak Sword DX</strong></u></a><strong></strong></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $5.99 (40% off)</strong></p><p>Sleek, thrilling, and wonderfully cruel, Bleak Sword DX is a dark fantasy action game by Spanish developer more8bit, otherwise known as Luis Moreno Jimenez. Originally released for Apple Arcade in 2019, Bleak Sword DX builds on the original game, offering expanded gameplay mechanics, narrative elements, and atmospheric world-building. Its unique, condensed art style is reminiscent of 8-bit classics, but with a modern twist that blends 2D sprites with 3D environments. The game is centred around 12 chapters of cursed diorama battlefields, where your hero must lift the curse of the legendary Bleak Sword by eliminating the hostile creatures in each environment. Somewhat soulslike in its levelling system, you gain experience points by clearing stages but lose those not used for levelling up after dying twice in a stage. Not for the faint of heart, but a hell of a lot of fun.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2015/04/13/titan-souls-review"><u><strong>Titan Souls</strong></u></a></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $1.49 (90% off)</strong></p><p>Speaking of soulslikes, what happens when an indie developer takes the brutal “one more try” philosophy of that genre and adds a boss rush on top? Well, Titan Souls is your answer. Conceived and prototyped during Ludum Dare #28, Titan Souls is an open world, top-down action-adventure, where your hero’s only weapon is a single arrow and you can only take one hit. The goal is to defeat 20 giant monsters (21 on hard mode) called the Titans. Just like you, they only take one hit to die, but they also only have one way to be defeated. During combat, you must figure out how each Titan behaves and identify their fatal weakness. The twist is that your single arrow must be charged before it can be shot and has to be retrieved before it can be reused. Oh, and you can only perform either action while not moving, making you a sitting target for the Titans. Did we mention it’s quite hard?</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tl07NG4ZY5c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><strong>Heave Ho</strong></u></a></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $3.99 (60% off)</strong></p><p>Heave Ho tasks up to four players with a simple goal: don’t fall to your death! Created by French developer Le Cartel and released in 2019 for PC and Switch, players take control over a gurning disembodied head with a pair of stretchable arms, using their iron-like grip and the outstretched hands of their friends to grapple across each level on their way to victory. Clambering across one another’s dangling bodies and swinging your pals to safety in a wobbly mass of limbs is made all the more silly by customising your character with all manner of ridiculous accessories and zany accoutrement in a vain attempt to remember who you are.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/olija-review"><u><strong>Olija</strong></u></a></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $4.49 (70% off)</strong></p><p>Another French developer saw their game published by Devolver in 2021, though it came by way of Japan. Thomas Olsson conceived his debut game Olija after moving to Japan, collaborating with a team they dubbed Skeleton Crew, a Japanese saxophonist, a shakuhachi player, and his wife to bring his vision to life. Inspired by Moby Dick, Pirates of the Caribbean, and Prince of Persia, Olija is a game about Faraday, a man shipwrecked and then trapped in the mysterious country of Terraphage. Armed with a legendary harpoon, he and other castaways try to leave this hostile country to return to their homelands. The game mixes exploration and quickfire combat through the use of Faraday’s Harpoon, challenging you to rethink movement through platforming, puzzle, and combat. Inspired by swashbuckling tales and cinematic adventure games, Olija is a story about facing the unknown in adversity.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/boomerang-x-review"><u><strong>Boomerang X</strong></u></a><strong></strong></h2><p><strong>On sale for: 75% Off (Soundtrack Bundle)</strong></p><p>Continuing the theme of weapon-based traversal in 2021, Boomerang X from developer DANG! is like a rollercoaster ride of fast-paced first-person shooting taken from the classic hardcore boomer playbook. Armed with a magical boomerang, slice, fly, and dive through flocks of evil Ghibli-esque creatures in this acrobatic arena boomer(ang) shooter. As you catapult yourself through the air, the power drawn from the creatures you defeat can be used to slow time and recalibrate your airborne attacks. They really should have called it Doomerang.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/the-first-12-minutes-of-pikuniku"><u><strong>Pikuniku</strong></u></a></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $2.59 (80% off)</strong></p><p>Pikuniku is a puzzle-exploration game that takes place in a strange but playful world where not everything is as happy as it seems. The brainchild of French-British indie collective Sectordub (Arnaud De Bock, Rémi Forcadell, Alan Zucconi, and Calum Bowen), Pikuniku sees you take control of the titular Piku as he helps peculiar residents overcome their mundane struggles, uncovers a deep state conspiracy, and starts a little revolution on his delightful dystopian adventure. The majority of puzzles involve kicking and pushing objects to open doors and access rooms, but Piku can also lasso his legs to swing from hooks or curl into a ball and roll, allowing you to move around faster and reach higher or previously inaccessible areas. Pikuniku also features a local co-op mode with nine levels, in which a second player controls Niku, Piku’s orange pal.
</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/stories-untold-nintendo-switch-release-date-trailer"><u><strong>Stories Untold</strong></u></a></h2><p><strong>On sale for: $1.99 (80% off)</strong></p><p>Developed by No Code, the Glasgow-based studio spearheaded by John McKellan (Alien: Isolation) and Omar Khan, 2017’s Stories Untold is a narrative-driven experimental adventure game that bends the genre into something unique. Combining a mix of classic text-adventure, point-and-click, and first-person puzzle games, four short stories are packaged together into a single mysterious anthology that pulls together ’80s retro nostalgia, innovative and experimental gameplay, and tense, psychological horror.</p><p>On top of this sale, Devolver will be celebrating its 15th birthday by dipping into its archives for a series of blogs on <a href="https://www.devolverdigital.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>its official website</u></a> that take a trip down memory lane. If you’ve ever wondered which Devolver Digital T-shirts changed the game for video game merchandise, what their top 15 soundtrack entries are, their favourite game trailers, or even what their most impressive event spaces are from over the years (who could forget their iconic E3 parking lot space?), then wonder no more.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows Has Day-One Missions Only Available Through Season Pass or by Preordering]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-has-day-one-missions-only-available-through-season-pass-or-by-preordering</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-has-day-one-missions-only-available-through-season-pass-or-by-preordering.873171/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-has-day-one-missions-only-available-through-season-pass-or-by-preordering<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> players won't have access to all of the game's day-one missions due to Ubisoft locking one behind the Season Pass and another behind a preorder bonus.</p><p>As is standard for the publisher, Shadows will launch in a handful of different versions — the Standard Edition at $69.99, the Gold Edition at $109.99, the Ultimate Edition at $129.99, and the Collector's Edition at $279.99 — but only those who preorder the Gold Edition or higher get access to both additional missions on launch day.</p><p>Preordering the game doesn't come at any extra cost (just the commitment to buy), meaning one of these missions is on the easier side to get, but the Season Pass is currently only available in the more expensive versions of the game, which cost an additional $40 at the absolute minimum. Ubisoft will likely sell the Season Pass separately later, and likely for $40, but it has so far not confirmed this.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Assassin's Creed Shadows - Exclusive Concept Art</h3></div></output><p>Ubisoft has yet to share meaningful details on the two missions either, but announced that the preorder bonus is called Thrown to the Dogs, and released artwork featuring dual-protagonist Naoe with a dog at her side. As for the Season Pass mission, Ubisoft has only said players must "infiltrate a secret society from the inside."</p><p>The decision to lock day-one content behind additional requirements is perhaps unsurprising to some who experienced the same when Ubisoft announced the different editions of <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a>, its sci-fi open world adventure launching August 27.</p><p>Fans shared their frustration online when <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-jabba-the-hutt-mission-locked-behind-season-pass">a Jabba the Hutt mission was similarly locked behind the Season Pass</a> despite being ready day-one, but <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-responds-to-star-wars-outlaws-season-pass-backlash-insists-jabba-the-hutt-is-part-of-the-experience-for-all-players">Ubisoft insisted this was an "optional, additional"</a> mission that won't impact the overall experience much. The publisher seemingly didn't take fan upset to heart as it's done the same again with Shadows.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Assassin's Creed Shadows - Reveal Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>The upcoming Assassin's Creed game was fully revealed on May 15, 2024 as a Japanese-set entry where players take control of two protagonists: the stealthy shinobi Naoe and the action-orientated Yasuke, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/who-is-yasuke-assassins-creed-shadows-black-samurai-explained">who's a real figure from Japanese history</a>.</p><p>IGN had a wealth of exclusive content on the reveal, and you can read about all the gameplay changes, story beats, and open-world assassinating coming with Shadows <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-inside-ubisofts-ambitious-open-world-japan">in our extensive interview with the development team</a>.</p><p>If that's not enough, check <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/when-and-where-is-assassins-creed-shadows-set">our analysis and explanation of where and when Shadows is set</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-40-details-you-need-to-know">40 key details we've learned about the game</a>. You can also watch <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/assassins-creed-shadows-trailer-breakdown-secrets-theories-and-details-you-might-have-missed">our full breakdown of the cinematic trailer</a> to discover all its hidden details, Easter eggs, and more.</p><p>Shadows launches November 12, 2024 for those buying <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date-collectors-edition">the Gold, Ultimate, or Deluxe Editions</a>, while the Standard Edition is available on November 15, 2024.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Project Mugetsu Ability Tier List]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/project-mugetsu-ability-tier-list/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=project-mugetsu-ability-tier-list</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/project-mugetsu-ability-tier-list.873165/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/project-mugetsu-ability-tier-list/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=project-mugetsu-ability-tier-list<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="333" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">With over 50 abilities across all evolutions and more added with each update, it’s hard to keep track of which abilities in <em>Project Mugetsu</em> are the best and worth equipping. We’ve put together this <em>Project Mugetsu</em> ability Tier List so you can determine which abilities you want to go for and which evolution can use them.</p> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"></figure> <h2 id="h-project-mugetsu-ability-tier-list-may-2024" data-injectable="false"><em>Project Mugetsu</em> Ability Tier List (May 2024)</h2> <p data-characters="709" data-current-count="1009" data-injectable="true">Included in this <em>Project Mugetsu</em> Ability Tier List are all of the abilities available as of May 2024 and the inclusion of the newly released Update 2. While most abilities in <em>Project Mugetsu</em> are viable, those in S Tier are arguably overpowered and considered the best abilities in the game in all aspects. A Tier abilities are also very strong and you can almost always count on, though don’t quite reach the potential of the S Tier abilities. Those in the B Tier may have situational uses but overall are outperformed by those in the higher tiers, while those in the C Tier are a bit under tuned at the moment and should try to be avoided. Here is our <em>Project Mugetsu</em> Ability Tier List as of May 2024:</p>
 <h3 id="h-s-tier" data-injectable="false">S Tier</h3> <ul data-found-items="17" data-items-injection="true" data-current-count="680" data-injectable="true"> <li data-index="0"><strong>Air Walk</strong> – All</li> <li data-index="1"><strong>Arrogante</strong> – Resurrection</li> <li data-index="2"><strong>Arrow Gate</strong> – Bow</li> <li data-index="3"><strong>Fear</strong> – Voltstanding</li> <li data-index="4"><strong>Flashstep</strong> – All</li> <li data-index="5"><strong>Garganta VL </strong>– Hollow</li> <li data-index="6"><strong>Ichimonji</strong> – Shikai</li> <li data-index="7"><strong>Kamishini no Yari</strong> – Bankai</li> <li data-index="8"><strong>Los Lobos</strong> – Resurrection &amp; Segunda</li> <li data-index="9"><strong>Murcielago </strong>– Resurrection &amp; Segunda</li> <li data-index="10"><strong>Nozarashi </strong>– Shikai</li> <li data-index="11"><strong>Punch Leap</strong> – All</li> <li data-index="12"><strong>Ryujin Jakka</strong> – Shikai</li> <li data-index="13"><strong>Trapping Arrow</strong> – Bow</li> <li data-index="14"><strong>Triple Arrow</strong> – Bow</li> <li data-index="15"><strong>Triple Crescents</strong> – All</li> <li data-index="16"><strong>Zankai No Tachi </strong>– Bankai</li> </ul>
 <h3 id="h-a-tier" data-injectable="false">A Tier</h3> <ul data-found-items="32" data-items-injection="true" data-current-count="1280" data-injectable="true"> <li data-index="0"><strong>Almighty Thrust</strong> – Fist</li> <li data-index="1"><strong>Arrancar Roar</strong> – Hollow</li> <li data-index="2"><strong>Bakaudo 1 </strong>– Soul Reaper</li> <li data-index="3"><strong>Blade Thrust</strong> – Sword</li> <li data-index="4"><strong>Bullet Cero</strong> – Hollow</li> <li data-index="5"><strong>Byakurai</strong> – Soul Reaper</li> <li data-index="6"><strong>Cero Gates </strong>–<strong> </strong>Hollow</li> <li data-index="7"><strong>Cero Stomp</strong> – Hollow</li> <li data-index="8"><strong>Chain Pull</strong> – Hollow</li> <li data-index="9" data-injectable="true"><strong>Exploding Arrow</strong> – Bow</li>
 <li data-index="10"><strong>Flash Cero</strong> – Hollow</li> <li data-index="11"><strong>Flash Escape</strong> – All</li> <li data-index="12"><strong>Haien</strong> – Soul Reaper</li> <li data-index="13"><strong>Kamishini</strong> – Shikai</li> <li data-index="14"><strong>Kick Crash</strong> – Fist</li> <li data-index="15"><strong>Minazuki</strong> – Shikai</li> <li data-index="16"><strong>Multi Barrage</strong> – Fist</li> <li data-index="17"><strong>Pantera</strong> – Resurrection</li> <li data-index="18"><strong>Quincy Sword</strong> – Quincy</li> <li data-index="19" data-injectable="true"><strong>Santa Teresa</strong> – Resurrection</li>
 <li data-index="20"><strong>Senbonzakura </strong>– Shikai</li> <li data-index="21"><strong>Senbonzakura Kageyoshi</strong> – Bankai</li> <li data-index="22"><strong>Senkaimon</strong> – Soul Reaper</li> <li data-index="23"><strong>Shadow</strong> – Quincy</li> <li data-index="24"><strong>Shadow Gate </strong>– Quincy</li> <li data-index="25"><strong>Sheathed Slashes </strong>– Sword</li> <li data-index="26"><strong>Speeding Arrow</strong> – Bow</li> <li data-index="27"><strong>Shun Shun Rika</strong> – Fullbringer</li> <li data-index="28"><strong>Tiburon</strong> – Resurrection</li> <li data-index="29"><strong>Tormenta</strong> – Resurrection</li> <li data-index="30"><strong>Thunderbolt</strong> – Voltstanding</li> <li data-index="31"><strong>Zangetsu</strong> – Shikai</li> </ul>
 <h3 id="h-b-tier" data-injectable="false">B Tier</h3> <ul data-found-items="17" data-items-injection="true" data-current-count="680" data-injectable="true"> <li data-index="0"><strong>Arrow Volley</strong> – Bow</li> <li data-index="1"><strong>Bakaudo 8</strong> – Soul Reaper</li> <li data-index="2"><strong>Bakaudo 9 Horin</strong> – Soul Reaper</li> <li data-index="3"><strong>Bakaudo 61 Rijujujukoro</strong> – Soul Reaper</li> <li data-index="4"><strong>Bakaudo 104</strong> – Soul Reaper</li> <li data-index="5"><strong>Bala</strong> – Hollow</li> <li data-index="6"><strong>Bala Barrage</strong> – Hollow</li> <li data-index="7"><strong>Blade Smash</strong> – Sword</li> <li data-index="8"><strong>Daiguren Hyorinmaru</strong> – Bankai</li> <li data-index="9"><strong>Dual Kick</strong> – Fist</li> <li data-index="10"><strong>Geldschrank</strong> – Quincy</li> <li data-index="11"><strong>Ginto Grenade Toss</strong> – Quincy</li> <li data-index="12"><strong>Gochutekka</strong> – Soul Reaper</li> <li data-index="13"><strong>Gravitas</strong> – Resurrection</li> <li data-index="14"><strong>Hyorinmaru</strong> – Shikai</li> <li data-index="15"><strong>Reishi Reinforcement</strong> – Quincy</li> <li data-index="16"><strong>Sword Jabs</strong> – Sword</li> </ul>
 <h3 id="h-c-tier" data-injectable="false">C Tier</h3> <ul data-found-items="6" data-current-count="240" data-injectable="false"> <li><strong>Bala Toss</strong> – Hollow</li> <li><strong>Brazo</strong> – Fullbringer</li> <li><strong>Explosion</strong> – Volstanding</li> <li><strong>Ginto Gritz</strong> – Quincy</li> <li><strong>Tensa Zangetsu</strong> – Bankai</li> <li><strong>Volcanica</strong> – Resurrection</li> </ul>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony’s new PlayStation PC overlay is a simple start]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/16/24158246/sony-playstation-pc-overlay-hands-on</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony%E2%80%99s-new-playstation-pc-overlay-is-a-simple-start.873156/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/16/24158246/sony-playstation-pc-overlay-hands-on<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Ghost of Tsushima Director’s Cut</em> debuts on PC today, and it’s the first game to feature Sony’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/17/24132846/sony-playstation-pc-overlay-shared-trophies-ghost-of-tsushima">new PlayStation PC overlay</a> and shared Trophies system. I’ve had a chance to get a first look at this new overlay, and my initial impression is that it’s really unobtrusive, clean, and simple.</p><p>There are five main sections here: search, friends, Trophies, profile, and settings. Search lets you find other PlayStation players and add them as friends, whereas the friends section lists both your online and offline friends. You can see your friends’ Trophies, but you can’t message friends or party chat from this overlay, unfortunately. You’ll have to use in-game chat if you want to speak to a console friend, or just use Discord.</p><div><figcaption><em>The PlayStation PC overlay in action.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>GIF by Tom Warren / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>The Trophies system works just as you’d expect, by syncing <em>Ghost of Tsushima Director’s Cut </em>trophies from the PS5 version of the game to PC, and vice versa. You just sign in to your PlayStation Network ID, and the overlay and Trophies are both available.</p><p>The profile section lets you view all your existing Trophies across all your PlayStation games, and the settings section is largely web links to account management, privacy settings, and PlayStation support. There are settings to enable or disable notifications for Trophies, and the ability to see who you’ve blocked on PSN.</p><p>Overall, the PlayStation PC overlay works much like Steam’s, in the sense that it’s only active within a game. Sony hasn’t created something that’s constantly running in the background like Nvidia’s GeForce Experience or Microsoft’s Xbox Game Bar. </p><div><figcaption><em>A trio of notifications will greet you if you haven’t disabled GeForce Experience and the Steam overlay pop-ups.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Screenshot by Tom Warren / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>I did notice that if you haven’t disabled notifications for the GeForce Experience and Steam overlays, then you’ll get a trio of pop-up notices when you start <em>Ghost of Tsushima Director’s Cut </em>because the PlayStation one also has its own notification<em>. </em>Unfortunately, there’s no way to disable the PlayStation notification, as the pop-up notifications toggle doesn’t affect this particular message.</p><p>Still, the overlay looks and feels lightweight, even if it’s a little basic right now. Nixxes Software, the in-house port developer that Sony acquired in 2021, helped create it, and I’m hoping this simple start will lead to even more features in the future. It sure would be great to have the option of using the voice chat features of the PlayStation Network instead of having to use in-game chat or Discord. Sony is increasingly investing in the PC space, so there’s a good chance this PlayStation overlay improves over time.</p><div><p><em>Ghost of Tsushima Director’s Cut </em>is available now <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F2215430%2FGhost_of_Tsushima_DIRECTORS_CUT%2F">on Steam</a> and the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/ghost-of-tsushima">Epic Games Store</a>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uh-oh, I Already Hate What Final Fantasy XIV: Dawntrail Is Doing To This Job]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-astrologian-job-changes-1851482090</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/uh-oh-i-already-hate-what-final-fantasy-xiv-dawntrail-is-doing-to-this-job.873153/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-astrologian-job-changes-1851482090<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-expansion-release-drop-1851420406&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-expansion-release-drop-1851420406"><em>Dawntrail</em></a></span>, the next expansion for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-subscription-free-trial-download-1851428987&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-subscription-free-trial-download-1851428987"><em>Final Fantasy XIV</em></a></span>, is just around the corner with a July 2 release date. Ahead of its launch, Square Enix pulled the curtain back on the job changes players can expect to see during the developer’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oh5piV-0MWQ&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oh5piV-0MWQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">latest live letter</a></span>, which included our first in-depth look at the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-dawntrail-job-classes-free-trial-xbox-1850691863&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-dawntrail-job-classes-free-trial-xbox-1850691863">new Viper and Pictomancer jobs</a></span>. But it was the changes to the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/feels-from-heals-healing-in-final-fantasy-xiv-is-super-1846465306&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/feels-from-heals-healing-in-final-fantasy-xiv-is-super-1846465306">Astrologian</a></span> job that caught my eye and, folks, it isn’t looking good.<br></p><div data-video-id="196646" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Dragon’s Dogma 2’s New Class Is A Twirling Death Machine" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="137" data-playlist="196646,196394,196742" data-current="196646"><div><p>Dragon’s Dogma 2’s New Class Is A Twirling Death Machine</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196646/196646_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196646/196646_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196646/196646_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196646/196646_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22202.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>Let’s first unpack how Astrologian currently works in <em>Final Fantasy 14</em>. Centered around a cosmic tarot aesthetic, Astrologian is a healer role (one of four in the game) whose kit focuses heavily on drawing cards from a deck to perform actions. Each card has a particular buff that only activates when applied to a party member of a specific role. The randomness of card draws and the requirements for playing them gives Astrologian a particular sense of improvisation as it keeps players on their toes. You can’t just hit a regular rotation of skills if the game randomly gives you your next action. Compared to other healer roles, which can feel stagnant and a bit “set it and forget it”, Astrologian lets me get more involved as a player.</p><p>At least that was the case—once <em>Dawntrail </em>releases all that will change. “The card system will no longer be random,” reads the official change as shown during the live letter, “and will instead simultaneously draw cards with offensive, defensive, and curative effects.” In addition, players will now be able to draw four cards within a 60-second window that they can play depending on the given situation (players can currently draw one card every 30 seconds). Each card pulled will have curative, damage, or buffing abilities. The big issue, at least in this Astrologian’s opinion, is that these changes take away the best part of the job—the randomness.</p><figure id="" data-id="6b0e36caf15822dc4107c2cb0fb73a11" data-recommend-id="image://6b0e36caf15822dc4107c2cb0fb73a11" data-format="jpg" data-width="1141" data-height="643" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A lalafell draws a tarot card" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A lalafell draws a tarot card" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6b0e36caf15822dc4107c2cb0fb73a11" data-recommend-id="image://6b0e36caf15822dc4107c2cb0fb73a11" data-format="jpg" data-width="1141" data-height="643" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A lalafell draws a tarot card" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>For a while, there has been a slow, but steady, shift with many of <em>FF14</em>’s jobs towards making them simpler. Healers have faced the brunt of this shift, so much so that the community has identified it as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-ff14-dawntrail-healer-job-rework-1851432853&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-ff14-dawntrail-healer-job-rework-1851432853">a major problem</a></span>. It isn’t an issue of whether <em>FF14 </em>is too hard or should be more friendly to newcomers— it’s very good at onboarding new adventurers, but it’s a question of job complexity. For healers, that complexity has felt lacking due to how relatively simple average healer gameplay is, which is often reduced to spamming attacks with one or two buttons and healing off the global cooldown with skills as needed. For new players, that simplicity can be helpful for learning the other many systems of the MMORPG but after hundreds of hours, it becomes boring.<br></p><p>Astrologian’s randomness has been a cure for healer boredom. While other healers have a fairly defined rotation, Astrologian has a built-in unpredictability that makes it exciting. For my first three expansions I played as a White Mage, but changed to Astrologian when I needed a job that gave me more to do in moment-to-moment combat. Making split-second decisions based on whatever the deck provides while in encounters makes healing a much more interesting affair and a much-needed alternative to other healing jobs. Taking that away feels like a major loss.</p><p>Although it wasn’t an entirely unexpected one. Ahead of <em>Dawntrail </em>players knew that Astrologian would be getting a rework, but were worried that it would be oversimplified, like the Summoner changes of Endwalker that sought to reduce the fabled two-minute rotation of the job into something easier to pick up. And honestly, it feels like our worries were valid with this erasure of card randomness. It’s part of a larger conversation about job simplification that even director <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-ff14-more-stressful-1851332485&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-14-ff14-more-stressful-1851332485">Naoki Yoshida has said</a></span> may have gone too far in recent updates.</p><hr><p>This doesn’t have to be an either-or situation though. That’s why we have multiple jobs, for multiple styles of play. There should be some jobs that allow for a more complex rotation for players who want that. This is why the coming changes to Astrologian feel like a loss.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision Finally Opens A Studio To Make Something Other Than Call Of Duty]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/activision-call-of-duty-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-1851481854</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-finally-opens-a-studio-to-make-something-other-than-call-of-duty.873150/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/activision-call-of-duty-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-1851481854<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/microsoft-activision-blizzard-acquisition-game-pass-1850923561&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-activision-blizzard-acquisition-game-pass-1850923561">Xbox-owned Activision</a></span> has revealed a brand new AAA studio in Poland that will develop something other than <em>Call of Duty,</em> which most of Activision currently works on. This should be good news! The industry needs more studios after thousands of layoffs. However, last week, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-closing-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-1851460685&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-closing-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-1851460685">Activision’s parent company, Microsoft, announced it was closing three video game studios</a></span>. So the response to this new studio opening hasn’t been entirely positive.<br></p><div data-video-id="196049" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="134" data-playlist="196049,196406,194328" data-current="196049"><div><p>This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21580.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>On May 16, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.activision.com/blog/activision/2024/activision-announces-new-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-all-new-franchise-development&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.activision.com/blog/activision/2024/activision-announces-new-studio-elsewhere-entertainment-all-new-franchise-development" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Activision officially revealed Elsewhere Entertainment</a></span>, a new internal studio recently formed in Warsaw, Poland. According to Activision’s press release, the new studio will be focused “exclusively” on developing a “new narrative-based,” “genre-defining AAA franchise.” </p><p>That seems to imply that this new studio won’t be another gear in the enormous <em>Call of Duty</em> content creation machine, unlike Raven Software and High Moon Studios. Activision has made headlines over the years for essentially taking <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/now-every-single-activision-studio-works-on-call-of-dut-1846798677&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/now-every-single-activision-studio-works-on-call-of-dut-1846798677">all of its studios and throwing them into the <em>Call of Duty</em> mines</a></span>. Perhaps this time, things will be different.</p><p>“Built from the ground up, Elsewhere Entertainment is a premier and standalone studio dedicated to establishing an environment that inspires bold and diverse ideas. The team’s underlying mission encourages everyone to explore and collaborate creatively to craft a franchise with an enduring legacy that resonates far beyond games,” reads Activision’s press release, which was seemingly written by someone who was also trying to set a new record for most buzzwords used in one paragraph. </p><p>Activision says Elsewhere Entertainment features staff who have previously worked on games like <em>The Last of Us, Uncharted, The Witcher, Cyberpunk, The Division, Destiny, </em>and <em>Far Cry. </em>The studio has seemingly gone public now as it continues to staff up and likely ramps up development on its first big game.<br></p><h2 id="h15469"><a id=""></a>The timing of this news is not great, Bob</h2><p>Of course, the timing of this reveal hasn’t gone over well online. Activision’s parent company—Xbox—was recently in the news after it suddenly closed three Bethesda-owned studios on May 7. </p><p>Things only got worse for Xbox after an all-hands meeting with Bethesda leaked and reportedly revealed that the company had shut down those studios due to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-bethesda-studio-closings-arkane-too-many-games-1851464885?rev=1715203138081&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-bethesda-studio-closings-arkane-too-many-games-1851464885?rev=1715203138081">resources and staff being spread too thin</a></span>. Xbox President Matt Booty reportedly said that shutting down these teams would help provide <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-bethesda-layoffs-high-impact-games-1851464703&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-bethesda-layoffs-high-impact-games-1851464703">more money and staff to  projects</a></span> as the company focuses on fewer, more “high-impact” games. </p><p>So, a big AAA studio being unveiled shortly after a bunch of people lost their jobs has gone over poorly online. And while Activision is its own large company with its own leaders and marketing plans, I understand why so many online are reacting poorly to the news. It’s likely that Activision was building Elsewhere Entertainment long before the Microsoft merger happened. But it’s extremely <em>unlikely </em>that Xbox leadership had no idea this studio existed or that it was going to be announced publicly around this time.</p><p>Personally, if I was an executive at <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reuters.com/technology/microsoft-hits-3-trillion-market-value-2024-01-24/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/microsoft-hits-3-trillion-market-value-2024-01-24/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one of the biggest tech companies in the world</a></span>, I’d probably wait at least, like, I don’t know...a month after closing studios down before letting another part of the corporation reveal a big new video game studio, even if that means delaying plans that have been in the works for months. But hey, what do I know? </p><p>&nbsp;.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fans Want This Pokémon X Animal Crossing Mashup To Be Real]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-animal-crossing-crossover-mashup-fan-art-1851482109</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fans-want-this-pok%C3%A9mon-x-animal-crossing-mashup-to-be-real.873147/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/pokemon-animal-crossing-crossover-mashup-fan-art-1851482109<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="6e51b2f8925946fe6f6a1453693b0932" data-recommend-id="image://6e51b2f8925946fe6f6a1453693b0932" data-format="gif" data-width="768" data-height="431" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Animal Crossing Haunter tries to scare the player." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Animal Crossing Haunter tries to scare the player." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->SpicyBeefu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6e51b2f8925946fe6f6a1453693b0932" data-recommend-id="image://6e51b2f8925946fe6f6a1453693b0932" data-format="gif" data-width="768" data-height="431" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Animal Crossing Haunter tries to scare the player." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>As someone who mostly passes through <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-the-kotaku-review-1842321314&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-the-kotaku-review-1842321314"><em>Animal Crossing</em></a></span><em> </em>each time a game comes out, it’s easy to draw comparisons between why people love that series and the ways in which players connect to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-predictions-mega-evolution-kalos-1851316456&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-predictions-mega-evolution-kalos-1851316456"><em>Pokémon</em></a></span>. Sure, in Nintendo’s life sim you’re not “capturing” all the animal villagers, but people still collect their favorites and set them up in homes with the same vigor people apply to seeking out their favorite <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-shiny-odds-scarlet-violet-ivs-red-gyarados-1850248457&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-shiny-odds-scarlet-violet-ivs-red-gyarados-1850248457">shiny Pokémon</a></span> or trying to get the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-what-are-ev-iv-training-1849905869&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-what-are-ev-iv-training-1849905869">perfect IV critter</a></span> in the latest RPG. That’s why seeing an artist make a mockup of an <em>Animal Crossing </em>game featuring iconic Pocket Monsters just makes perfect sense.</p><div data-video-id="196165" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="95" data-playlist="196165,192873,192610" data-current="196165"><div><p>What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21711.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>3D artist SpicyBeefu has created several short videos of different Pokémon reimagined as <em>Animal Crossing </em>characters. After <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.tiktok.com/@pen_paladin/video/7369202757389258030&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@pen_paladin/video/7369202757389258030" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TikTok creator pen_paladin</a></span> shared them, fans are wondering how Nintendo hasn’t already invested in this crossover. Some videos were inspired by other artists’ renditions of Pokémon as <em>Animal Crossing </em>characters, including <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://twitter.com/Gokuchan/status/1230665049645010944&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://twitter.com/Gokuchan/status/1230665049645010944" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gokuchan</a></span>’s drawing of the electric sheep Mareep, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://twitter.com/Yencatx/status/1156555444959080448&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://twitter.com/Yencatx/status/1156555444959080448" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yencatx’s</a></span> Sylveon as an <em>Animal Crossing </em>fox. But if I didn’t know these critters from <em>Pokémon</em>, I’d have no idea they weren’t already in Nintendo’s life sim.</p><p>There are some pretty creative mockups here, including Haunter, a gas-like ghost with disembodied hands. SpicyBeefu’s design makes it a little cuter and gives it a body so it can wear a little sweater. It’s adorable, even when it tries to spook the player.</p><p>“<em>Pokémon</em> leaning into the cozy game angle would make them MILLIONS,” TikTok user Darth_Nater59 said. “They could even tie this into <em>Pokémon Concierge</em>.”</p><p>For whatever it’s worth, <em>Pokémon </em>has made a few games that could be considered “cozy,” like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-cafe-mix-is-nothing-new-but-it-sure-is-cute-1844145989&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-cafe-mix-is-nothing-new-but-it-sure-is-cute-1844145989"><em>Pokémon Café ReMix</em></a></span> and <em>Hey You, Pikachu </em>back on the Nintendo 64. But something like a life sim that lets you take care of <em>Pokémon </em>outside of capturing and battling with them feels like an untapped market. Doing something exactly like <em>Animal Crossing</em>, in which animals are full-blown citizens with dialogue and routines, could feasibly work if it’s set in the right spaces in the universe. Netflix’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-concierge-show-series-netflix-review-1851137189?rev=1704310217663&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-concierge-show-series-netflix-review-1851137189?rev=1704310217663"><em>Pokémon Concierge</em></a></span><em> </em>is a good demonstration of this, as it’s all about taking care of Pokémon staying at a resort. But a setting like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/detective-pikachu-returns-pokemon-review-switch-1850915720&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/detective-pikachu-returns-pokemon-review-switch-1850915720"><em>Detective Pikachu</em>’s Ryme City</a></span>, which has Pokémon and humans coexisting as equals, could also facilitate such gameplay. If all else fails, they could set it in the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-mystery-dungeon-rescue-team-remake-coming-to-s-1840897357&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-mystery-dungeon-rescue-team-remake-coming-to-s-1840897357"><em>Mystery Dungeon </em>universe</a></span>, where every Pokémon talks. That cuts out the human element entirely. Let Pokémon vibe without humans coming in and locking them in Poké Balls, I say.</p><p>You can check out the rest of SpicyBeefu’s <em>Pokémon </em>x <em>Animal Crossing </em>matchups on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@spicyBeefu&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/@spicyBeefu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">her YouTube channel</a></span>.<br></p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madden NFL 25 Preorders Are Live - Here's How To Get A Free $10 Gift Card]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date/1100-6523515/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/madden-nfl-25-preorders-are-live-heres-how-to-get-a-free-10-gift-card.873144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date/1100-6523515/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523515">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Another football season, another installment of Madden. And while the 2025 NFL season is still quite a way off, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3PGHSM3?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">preorders for Madden NFL 25</a> are already open ahead of its <strong>August 16</strong> release, and you can get a <strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842409208262616989%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmadden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date%2F1100-6523515%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">free $10 gift card with your preorder at Best Buy</a></strong>. Three versions of the game are up for grabs--one of which comes bundled with a copy of EA Sports College Football 25 (which releases July 19), making it a great way to save money if you know you'll be picking up both later this year. We still don't know a whole lot about this installment of the iconic franchise, though EA Sports will likely give it the usual refresh with improved mechanics and animations, an updated Ultimate Team mode, and more.</p><p><strong>Read more: </strong>Check out our <strong><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-preorder-guide-ps5-xbox-series-x/1100-6523506/" data-ref-id="1100-6523506">EA Sports College Football 25 preorder guide</a></strong> for details on editions and bonuses for the revived NCAA football sim series.</p><h2>Madden NFL 25 Preorder Bonuses</h2><p>All Madden NFL 25 preorders come with bonus in-game content. The pricier the edition you pick, the more in-game goodies you'll get. If you opt for the standard edition of Madden NFL 25, you'll get the Cover Athlete Elite Player Item (TBA), two strategy items, Superstar Drip Gear (PS5 and Xbox Series X|S only), and the Legendary XP Boost (also exclusive to PS5 and Xbox Series X|S).</p><div title="6523515 - Madden NFL 25 Preorder Guide" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2381" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6523515 - Madden NFL 25 Preorder Guide" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842409208262616989%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmadden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date%2F1100-6523515%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842409208262616989%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmadden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date%2F1100-6523515%2F&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842409208262616989%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmadden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date%2F1100-6523515%2F&amp;event_type=click">Preorder Madden NFL 25 Standard Edition</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842409208262616989%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmadden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date%2F1100-6523515%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842409208262616989%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmadden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date%2F1100-6523515%2F&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842409208262616989%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmadden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date%2F1100-6523515%2F&amp;event_type=click">$70</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>Preorder the Madden NFL 25 standard edition to get the base game, Cover Athlete Elite Player Item, 2 Strategy Items, Superstar Drip Gear, and Legendary XP Boost. Preorders are currently live at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3PGHSM3?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842409208262616989%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmadden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date%2F1100-6523515%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Best Buy</a>, and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fsearch%2F%3Fq%3DMadden%2BNFL%2B25%26lang%3Ddefault%26start%3D0%26sz%3D20&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmadden-nfl-25-preorder-guide-bonuses-release-date%2F1100-6523515%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GameStop</a>. As mentioned above, if you preorder at Best Buy, you'll get a $10 gift card with your order.</p><p>The Xbox disc-based version of the game comes with Xbox Series X and Xbox One versions of the game thanks to dual entitlement. On PlayStation, the PS4 disc has a free upgrade to PS5, whereas the PS5 disc only works on PS5.</p><p>Madden NFL 25 at Amazon:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3PGHSM3?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation 5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3P668DV?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation 4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3P4HV27?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox</a></li></ul></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0006-PPSA18888_00-MADDEN25DELUXE00" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/UP0006-PPSA18888_00-MADDEN25DELUXE00&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0006-PPSA18888_00-MADDEN25DELUXE00">Preorder Madden NFL 25 Deluxe Edition</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0006-PPSA18888_00-MADDEN25DELUXE00" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/UP0006-PPSA18888_00-MADDEN25DELUXE00&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0006-PPSA18888_00-MADDEN25DELUXE00">$100</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>If you want to snag a couple of extra digital goodies or get on the gridiron early, the Madden NFL 25 deluxe edition might be a good investment. Along with the base game and everything included in the standard edition, you'll also get the following:</p><ul><li>Three days early access starting August 13</li><li>4,600 Madden Points</li><li>Early Access Ultimate Team Challenges</li><li>AKA Player Item</li><li>Cover Athlete Elite Player Item</li><li>Choice of 2 Strategy Items</li><li>Superstar Drip Gear (PS5 and Series X|S only)</li><li>Legendary XP Boost (PS5 and Series X|S only)</li></ul></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0006-PPSA04184_00-COLLEGEAFBBUNDLE/" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/UP0006-PPSA04184_00-COLLEGEAFBBUNDLE\/&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0006-PPSA04184_00-COLLEGEAFBBUNDLE/">Preorder Madden NFL 25 MVP Bundle</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0006-PPSA04184_00-COLLEGEAFBBUNDLE/" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/UP0006-PPSA04184_00-COLLEGEAFBBUNDLE\/&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0006-PPSA04184_00-COLLEGEAFBBUNDLE/">$150</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>The most exciting preorder is the Madden NFL 25 MVP Bundle. Not only does this get you the Madden NFL 25 Deluxe Edition, but you'll also get the EA Sports College Football 25 Deluxe Ddition. That's a $200 value. So if you know you'll be playing both titles this year, consider stepping up to this discounted bundle.</p><ul><li>Three days early access starting August 13</li><li>4,600 Madden Points</li><li>Early Access Ultimate Team Challenges</li><li>AKA Player Item</li><li>Cover Athlete Elite Player Item</li><li>Choice of 2 Strategy Items</li><li>Superstar Drip Gear (PS5 and Series X|S only)</li><li>Legendary XP Boost (PS5 and Series X|S only)</li></ul><p><strong>EA Sports College Football 25 Deluxe Edition</strong></p><p><em>Note: EA Sports College Football 25 is only available on PS5 and Xbox Series X|S. You should not buy this bundle if you play Madden on PS4 or Xbox One.</em></p><ul><li>Three days early access starting July 16</li><li>4,600 College Football Points</li><li>Heisman Hopeful Ultimate Team Pack (1 player item out 5)</li><li>Alma Mater Ultimate Team Pack (1 player item out of 134)</li><li>Cover Athlete Ultimate Team Pack (1 player item out of 3)</li><li>Bring Glory Home Ultimate Team Uniform Item</li></ul></div>                      </div>   </div><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apple-ipad-pro-ipad-air-2024-preorder-guide/1100-6523258/">Preorder Apple's 2024 iPad Pro And iPad Air - How To Get The Best Deal</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-preorder-guide-nintendo-switch/1100-6523267/">Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition Preorders Are Selling Out Fast</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-portal-restock-guide/1100-6520876/">PlayStation Portal Is Back In Stock At Multiple Major Retailers</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More Best Gaming &amp; Tech Deals This Week Links (3)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grab-7-awesome-dungeon-crawlers-for-only-15/1100-6523253/">Grab 7 Awesome Dungeon Crawlers For Only $15</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-deal-saves-you-over-50-for-12-month-membership/1100-6523230/">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate Deal Saves You Over $50 For 12-Month Membership</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-star-wars-and-marvel-disney-plus-blu-rays-have-arrived-but-you-may-want-to-order-soon/1100-6521604/">New Star Wars And Marvel Disney Plus Blu-Rays Have Arrived, But You May Want To Order Soon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/105566936584242225941?rel=author">Jon Bitner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523445&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazons-massive-4k-blu-ray-sale-gets-you-three-movies-for-only-33\/1100-6523445\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523419&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/metal-gear-solid-rex-model-kit-up-for-grabs-at-amazon-for-unusually-low-price\/1100-6523419\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523485&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/assassins-creed-shadows-is-ditching-an-iconic-franchise-feature\/1100-6523485\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523393&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lord-of-the-rings-and-the-hobbit-illustrated-editions-are-super-cheap-right-now\/1100-6523393\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523410&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/one-of-the-best-ways-to-remotely-play-ttrpgs-is-shutting-down\/1100-6523410\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523479&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/assassins-creed-shadows-preorder-guide-collectors-edition-release-date-bonuses\/1100-6523479\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523404&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lord-of-the-rings-animated-movie-gets-stunning-new-images\/1100-6523404\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523441&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-massive-loot-reborn-update-is-live-now-read-the-full-season-4-patch-notes\/1100-6523441\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523473&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/assassins-creed-shadows-trailer-shows-two-protagonists-launches-november-15\/1100-6523473\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523430&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/bloodborne-figma-action-figure-gets-big-discount-at-amazon\/1100-6523430\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523443&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/madden-nfl-25-release-date-early-access-info-deluxe-edition-and-more-reportedly-leaked\/1100-6523443\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6522205&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-1500-piece-lego-indiana-jones-set-is-on-sale-for-a-great-price\/1100-6522205\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-the-final-shape-resurrects-your-very-first-gun-as-a-new-exotic\/1100-6523471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523405&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/neuralink-claims-first-human-patient-is-playing-runescape-slay-the-spire-in-his-head\/1100-6523405\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523418&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/unicorn-overlords-unique-collectors-edition-gets-first-discount-at-amazon\/1100-6523418\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523486&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/huge-amazon-book-sale-free-kindle-unlimited-subscriptions-2-ebooks-ereader-deals-and-more\/1100-6523486\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523402&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tons-of-great-steam-deck-games-are-steeply-discounted-this-week\/1100-6523402\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523469&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2-gets-first-official-images\/1100-6523469\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523433&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-5000-piece-lego-lord-of-the-rings-set-is-a-sight-to-behold\/1100-6523433\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XDefiant minimum and recommended PC system requirements]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-minimum-and-recommended-pc-system-requirements/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=xdefiant-minimum-and-recommended-pc-system-requirements</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xdefiant-minimum-and-recommended-pc-system-requirements.873141/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-minimum-and-recommended-pc-system-requirements/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=xdefiant-minimum-and-recommended-pc-system-requirements<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="203" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">In preparation for&nbsp;<em>XDefiant’s&nbsp;</em>launch, Ubisoft <a href="https://twitter.com/PlayXDefiant/status/1791121436674801781" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has disclosed</a> the PC specs to get players ready. So, let’s dive into what minimum and recommended system requirements are needed.&nbsp;</p> <h2 id="h-all-xdefiant-pc-requirements" data-injectable="false">All XDefiant PC requirements</h2> <p data-characters="174" data-current-count="174" data-injectable="false">The <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/when-can-you-preload-xdefiant/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">XDefiant</a> </em>PC specs include various systems, from the minimum to Ultra 4K requirements. To cover all the bases, we’ll break down each <em>XDefiant</em> PC system requirements:</p> <h3 id="h-minimum-xdefiant-pc-requirements" data-injectable="false">Minimum XDefiant PC requirements</h3> <ul data-found-items="6" data-current-count="414" data-injectable="true"> <li><strong>Resolution:</strong> 1080p</li> <li><strong>CPU:</strong> Intel i3-10105F/AMD Ryzen3 3100</li> <li><strong>GPU:</strong> Intel ARC A380 (6GB)/Nvidia GTX 1050Ti (4GB)/AMD RX 5500 XT (4GB)</li> <li><strong>RAM:</strong> 8GB (Dual channel)</li> <li><strong>OS:</strong> Win10</li> <li><strong>Storage: </strong>35GB</li> </ul>
 <h3 id="h-recommended-xdefiant-pc-requirements" data-injectable="false">Recommended XDefiant PC requirements</h3> <ul data-found-items="6" data-current-count="240" data-injectable="false"> <li><strong>Resolution:</strong> 1080p</li> <li><strong>CPU:</strong> Intel i3-10105F/AMD Ryzen3 3100</li> <li><strong>GPU:</strong> Intel ARC A750 (8GB)/Nvidia GTX 1060 (6GB)/AMD RX 5500 XT (8GB)</li> <li><strong>RAM:</strong> 16GB (Dual channel)</li> <li><strong>OS:</strong> Win10</li> <li><strong>Storage: </strong>35GB</li> </ul> <h3 id="h-enthusiast-xdefiant-pc-requirements" data-injectable="false">Enthusiast XDefiant PC requirements</h3> <ul data-found-items="6" data-current-count="480" data-injectable="true"> <li><strong>Resolution:</strong> 1440p</li> <li><strong>CPU:</strong> Intel i5-10400/AMD Ryzen5 3600</li> <li><strong>GPU:</strong> Intel ARC A770 (16GB)/Nvidia RTX 2060 (6GB)/AMD RX 5600 XT (6GB)</li> <li><strong>RAM:</strong> 16GB (Dual channel)</li> <li><strong>OS:</strong> Win10/Win11</li> <li><strong>Storage: </strong>35GB</li> </ul>
 <h3 id="h-ultra" data-injectable="false">Ultra</h3> <ul data-found-items="6" data-current-count="240" data-injectable="false"> <li><strong>Resolution:</strong> 4K</li> <li><strong>CPU:</strong> Intel i7-9700K/AMD Ryzen7 3700X</li> <li><strong>GPU:</strong> Nvidia RTX 3080 (10GB)/AMD RX 6800 XT (16GB)</li> <li><strong>RAM:</strong> 16GB (Dual channel)</li> <li><strong>OS:</strong> Win10/Win11</li> <li><strong>Storage: </strong>35GB</li> </ul> <p data-characters="330" data-current-count="570" data-injectable="true">The most convenient aspect of&nbsp;<em>XDefiant’s&nbsp;</em>PC specs is the low space requirement of just 35GB across the board. This means that even those with a high-end setup can rest assured, knowing that their storage won’t be overly burdened. Both DX11 and DX12 are also supported, giving you the freedom to choose.&nbsp;</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Ubisoft</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="352" data-current-count="652" data-injectable="true">For those curious about&nbsp;<em>XDefiant’s&nbsp;</em>frame rate, it’s worth noting that it remains uncapped for maximum FPS. However, the game also provides the option to cap the frame rate, which can be beneficial for improving performance. You can easily adjust these settings from <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-will-not-use-skill-based-matchmaking-in-casual-game-modes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the game’s</a> menu using your preferred specifications.&nbsp;</p>
 <p data-characters="400" data-current-count="400" data-injectable="true">Due to&nbsp;<em>XDefiant’s&nbsp;</em>online play, a stable internet connection is required. The PC version is also supported by NVIDIA Reflex, a technology that reduces system latency and offers better responsiveness in gameplay. This can be particularly beneficial in fast-paced games like <em>XDefiant</em>. Those with high latency may want to close other applications on their device to fix the problem.&nbsp;</p>
 <p data-characters="96" data-current-count="96" data-injectable="false">Besides the specs mentioned above, <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/ubisoft-cancels-development-on-the-division-heartland/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft</a> suggests having an SSD for the best experience.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rap star Doja Cat says only "horrible and garbage" players use Fortnite's most over-powered weapon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/rap-star-doja-cat-says-only-horrible-and-garbage-players-use-fortnites-most-over-powered-weapon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rap-star-doja-cat-says-only-horrible-and-garbage-players-use-fortnites-most-over-powered-weapon.873120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/rap-star-doja-cat-says-only-horrible-and-garbage-players-use-fortnites-most-over-powered-weapon<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content_above">




  

<p>
If you click on a link and make a purchase we may receive a small commission.  <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/editorial-policy">Read our editorial policy</a>.
</p>
    <div>
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-type="article">


<header>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fortnite-chains-of-hades.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>    <div>



            <p>
US rapper Doja Cat has fired off a series of social media posts blasting "horrible" and "garbage" Fortnite players who use the game's powerful (many would say over-powered) Chains of Hades weapon. 
</p>
<p>
The Grammy Award-winning artist, whose hits include Say So, Paint the Town Red and Kiss Me More, posted a series of messages complaining about the Fortnite weapon in quick succession yesterday. A warning: Doja Cat uses extremely strong language which we reproduce below.
</p>
<p>
For the uninitiated, the Chains of Hades are a Greek god-themed whip weapon available this season with two uses: yoinking far-off players towards you, then following up with a blistering series of close-up swipes. They are really annoying... unless it's you using them.
</p>
<p>
Writing on social media platform X (<a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:https://twitter.com/dojacat/status/1790619105156030635">cached</a> by Google), Doja Cat had the following insight to share:
</p>
<p>
"If you're horrible and garbage at Fortnite make sure you grab a Chains of Hades whip to pass the time. Dumb cunts.
</p>
<p>
"If Fortnite knew what was good for them they'd get rid of Chains of Hades," she followed up with, two minutes later.
</p>
<p>
Responding to a fan who replied and said the Chains of Hades were their favourite weapon, Doja Cat <a href="https://twitter.com/lolm3gan/status/1790618760681762883">concluded</a>: "Because you're terrible."
</p>
<p>
Doja Cat is no stranger to Fortnite, and streams playing the game.
</p>
<p>
The artist is also featured in Fortnite via several songs featured in emotes ("Say So" was ubiquitous for a time, while the popular Joy skin - the game's first representation of a character with vitiligo - samples another Doja Cat track for its built-in emote).
</p>
<p>
Fortnite is even name-dropped in one of Doja Cat's tracks, Agora Hills. ('Cause love is pain, but I need this shit (Yeah) / We fuck too good when the bean kicks in / Like Fortnite, I'ma need your skin (Yeah) / Don't give a fuck where the penis been (Uh)'). 
</p>
<p>
So there's that.
</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Fortnite developer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-to-appeal-11m-fine-over-unfair-commercial-practices-aimed-at-children">Epic Games said it would appeal a €1.1m fine</a> from the Dutch consumer regulator over "unfair commercial practices aimed at children".</p>



        </div>


        </article>

  
    </div>


  
      </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NVIDIA RTX Remix NFS: Underground Mod Looks Stunning in New Video; GeForce NOW Adds Palworld and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nvidia-rtx-remix-nfs-underground-mod-looks-stunning-in-new-video/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-rtx-remix-nfs-underground-mod-looks-stunning-in-new-video-geforce-now-adds-palworld-and-more.873117/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nvidia-rtx-remix-nfs-underground-mod-looks-stunning-in-new-video/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>One of the most impressive NVIDIA RTX Remix mods currently in development is certainly the <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/need-for-speed-underground-rtx-remix" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Need for Speed Underground RTX remaster by alessandro893</a>, which received another showcase video recently.</p>
<p>This NVIDIA RTX Remix mod features path-traced global/direct illumination, upscaled textures, and more than 1,000 lights added. Some textures were generated by Stable Diffusion. The modder said this is his first work, and he's working on it alone. It is an early Alpha version, though 80% of the lighting job is done. Some of the cars are matte, and only a few cars (Skyline, MX5) have headlights at this moment.</p>
<p>To install the NVIDIA RTX Remix NFS: Underground mod, follow this procedure. Download the latest version (v0.0.4a), then unzip and copy the content of the mod directory into the game's root folder, respecting this file hierarchy:</p>
<p>mod<br>
└ .trex<br>
└ d3d9.dll<br>
└ dinput8.dll<br>
└ dxvk.conf<br>
└ NvRemixLauncher32.exe<br>
└ rtx-remix<br>
└ rtx.conf<br>
└ scripts<br>
└ SNDSTREAMS (optional, lossless audio)<br>
└ Sound (optional, lossless audio)</p>
<p>The rendering resolution is set to 4K by default. To set a custom resolution, users may edit the "scripts/NFSUnderground.WidescreenFix.ini" file. As for the original video settings of Need for Speed: Underground, the modder recommends setting everything to High except shadows and reflections.</p>
<p><br>
<a href="https://www.moddb.com/videos/underground-rtx1">Underground RTX - ModDB</a></p>
<p>For a higher quality video showcase, check out Digital Dreams' video below.</p>
<p><iframe title="[4K] Need for Speed Underground - Remaster RTX Remix! Insanely modded with RAYTRACING" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M-IpYREDgLE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In other NVIDIA news, the GeForce NOW cloud platform just received a few major additions to its library. The newly released games Men of War II and Die by the Blade are supported on GFN via Steam; if you want to read our take on the latter, check out <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/die-by-the-blade-a-chipped-katana/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Francesco's review</a>.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/GFN_Thursday-Palworld.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>This week's NVIDIA GeForce NOW Thursday update also adds support for the first-person strategy game Colony Survival (on Steam), Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition (on the Xbox app and PC Game Pass), and, last but not least, 2024's earliest and most unexpected commercial success: <a href="https://wccftech.com/palworld-summer-update-new-pals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Palworld</a>.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My favorite anime: Joaquim Dos Santos’ journey from Macross to Sword of the Stranger]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/anime/24157255/my-favorite-anime-joaquim-dos-santos-macross-sword-of-the-stranger</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/my-favorite-anime-joaquim-dos-santos%E2%80%99-journey-from-macross-to-sword-of-the-stranger.873114/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/anime/24157255/my-favorite-anime-joaquim-dos-santos-macross-sword-of-the-stranger<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="LY1n4l">As an animator, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24094777/spider-man-across-spider-verse-director-interview-anime">Joaquim Dos Santos</a> has steadily carved out a career boasting credits on some of the most influential American animated series of the past two decades. The 46-year-old animator and director has gone from directing episodes of <em>Justice League: Unlimited</em> and <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em> to co-directing one of the biggest animated features of last year: <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/23742233/spider-man-across-spider-verse-review"><em>Spider-Man: Across the Spider-Verse</em></a>.</p>
<p id="Qg9xoJ">Polygon recently had a chance to connect with Dos Santos, so we had to ask: <strong>What was your first favorite anime, and what’s your favorite anime now?</strong></p>
<p id="sYQ9tc">My Favorite Anime is Polygon’s column dedicated to collecting the stories of the biggest celebrity anime fans in the world, charting a path from their earliest introductions to Japanese animation, to the series and films they love today. Here’s what Joaquim Dos Santos had to say.</p>
<hr id="cAqt2G">
<h2 id="ujt0Yk"><strong>What was your first favorite anime?</strong></h2>

<p id="Qflo5q">Premiering on Japanese TV in 1982, <em>Super Dimension Fortress Macross</em> was co-produced by Studio Nue and Artland and based on an original concept by Shoji Kawamori, who would go on to become one of the series’ principal mechanical designers. Inspired by <em>Mobile Suit Gundam</em>, <em>Macross</em> is a sci-fi mecha anime that follows Hikaru Ichijyo, a civilian fighter pilot, who enlists to fight in a war between humanity and a technologically advanced species known as the Zentradi. During the Human-Zentradi conflict, Hikaru meets and falls in love with Lynn Minmay, an idol singer whose music inadvertently proves to be a critical asset in humanity’s war effort.</p>
<div id="wG02ZS"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uY4fme_AvW4?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="WvvuwD">The success of the original 36-episode series not only gave birth to the Macross anime franchise, but brought fame to three members of the show’s production staff: Kawamori, who would go on to be credited for popularizing the concept of transforming mecha in anime; Ichiro Itano, whose <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22370461/godzilla-vs-kong-anime-macross-plus">eponymous animation technique</a> would become synonymous with the Macross franchise and a widely recognized trope across Japanese animation; and Mari Iijima, the Japanese voice actress for Lynn Minmay, who successfully transitioned into a pop music career built in part on her character’s popularity.</p>
<p id="XGOngc"><em>Super Dimension Fortress Macross</em> has gained a reputation for its notorious inaccessibility in the West. Licensed by U.S. production company Harmony Gold USA, the original Macross anime was re-edited and broadcast in the United States as <em>Robotech</em> in 1985. In 2021, an agreement between Studio Nue and Harmony Gold USA <a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/news/2021-04-08/big-west-studio-nue-harmony-gold-usa-agree-to-global-distribution-of-macross-robotech/.171570">was announced</a> that would allow the global distribution of most of the Macross television sequels and films.</p>
<h2 id="LaGdMy"><strong>What’s your favorite anime now?</strong></h2>

<p id="uGIOQW">Directed by Masahiro Ando, who was previously known for his work as storyboarder and animator for films like 1995’s <em>Ghost in the Shell</em> and 1997’s <em>End of Evangelion</em>, <em>Sword of the Stranger</em> is an action-adventure film known for its impressive fight sequences and cinematography. </p>
<p id="nOVQ6Y">Set during the Sengoku period, the movie follows the story of an orphan named Kotaro who, while on the run from a band of Ming warriors, crosses paths with a mysterious ronin who has vowed to never unsheathe his sword again. Desperate to elude his captors, Kotaro “hires” the ronin to act as his bodyguard. Meanwhile, Luo-Lang, the second-in-command of the Ming warriors pursuing Kotaro, remains relentless not only in his search for the boy, but for a worthy opponent.</p>
<div id="4jI7dU"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jFh9M2iaxbA?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="ivvO9h">Speaking to Polygon earlier this year, Dos Santos mentioned Yutaka Nakamura was one of his favorite Japanese animators. Nakamura is considered by many to be one of the preeminent action animators working in the anime industry, lauded for his work on shows like <em>Cowboy Bebop</em>, <em>Fullmetal Alchemist</em>, <em>My Hero Academia</em>, and <em>One Punch Man</em>, among many others. Nakamura also worked on several key action sequences in <em>Sword of the Stranger</em>, including the climactic duel between the film’s nameless protagonist and Luo-Lang, one of the most impressive sword fights in animation history.</p>
<p id="naCIto">The impact of both <em>Macross</em> and <em>Sword of the Stranger</em> on Dos Santos’ sensibilities as an animator and storyteller is plain to see for anyone familiar with his work. His attention to detail and cinematography are heavily anime-inspired, as is his proclivity for character-driven stories with large ensemble casts and an emphasis on stylish action sequences. The gift of good anime keeps on giving.</p>
<p id="4dc4AR"><small><em>Sword of the Stranger</em></small><small> is available to stream on Crunchyroll.</small><small><em> Super Dimension Fortress Macross</em></small><small> is currently not available to stream in the US.</small></p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arena Breakout: Infinite Beta Review]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arena-breakout-infinite-beta-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arena-breakout-infinite-beta-review.873111/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/arena-breakout-infinite-beta-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Arena Breakout: Infinite is setting itself up to be a main challenger to juggernauts of the extraction shooter genre like Escape from Tarkov. But, after spending time playing the game’s closed beta, does it live up to the hype surrounding it, or are you better off sticking with what’s already out there?</p>



<h2 id="h-arena-breakout-infinite-review">Arena Breakout: Infinite Review</h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Arena Breakout Infinite Review | Buy, Wait, or Skip?" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aHCykP9O47E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>When you first load into Arena Breakout: Infinite, you’ll be welcomed by a series of tips and pointers to get your footing. If you’ve played Tarkov, you’ll immediately feel at home with how things are set up. You have your character – and militant, or SCAV –, your gear, supplies, traders, missions, and maps to choose from.  Again, all very familiar…for better or worse.</p>



<p>Outside of the action, the game’s user interface is friendlier than the ones it’ll often be compared to. Everything just seems easier to find. Quality-of-life features like quickly buying and equipping rations, easier storage organization, and even healing based on suggestions from the game are so nice that you’re left wondering why other games aren’t implementing these.</p>



<p>Even the after-match reports are special. After finishing a run, you’ll be shown a full report of everything that happened during the raid including a map that shows you everywhere you went and highlights key moments along with full breakdowns of every gunfight you were a part of.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-get-into-the-raid">Get Into The Raid</h2>



<p>Joining a raid is simple enough. You gear up, select your map, and choose whether you want to play Normal mode or enter the Forbidden Zone. Normal is the standard experience that’s more arcade-like in how people play while the Forbidden Zone caters to the more hardcore group of players. That’s likely because there’s far more to lose as not only do you have to pay Koen to enter, but your gear has to be worth at least 80,000 Koen.</p>



<p>Getting into raids took no time at all. The longest I waited was just about a minute to connect and deploy. There’s also a team system that, if you don’t already have a squad, will put you in one just as quickly. But should you not want to join a team, you can simply turn off automatching.</p>



<p>When in a raid, I’ll admit that it’s a mixed bag at this point. On the positive side of things, gun sounds are solid, and the use of your weapon feels pretty good. Submachine guns, shotguns, rifles, and pistols all feel different enough to add variety. </p>



<p>Gunplay itself feels strongest in close quarters. There was never a situation where I questioned how or why something happened in a gunfight. It all played out and felt exactly how I thought it should. At long distances, though, sometimes the guns just feel off. It’s kind of hard to explain without experiencing it yourself, but at times you feel like you’re aiming and using a BB gun as opposed to a rifle.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The two playable maps in the beta – Farm and The Valley – are nice, but they’re nothing to write home about. They feel a bit boring and lack the personality that you see in the maps of Tarkov and even in Lamang in Gray Zone Warfare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Speaking of Tarkov, there are a lot of one-to-one comparisons between the two with what’s offered. Like Tarkov, Arena Breakout: Infinite has traders who offer you missions as you progress. There are also items you can loot that are identical. Blue tape, anyone? I don’t want to compare too much to Tarkov here, but, I mean, that is the target audience for this game.</p>



<p>Going back to the gameplay, the AI feels a bit hit or miss. Sometimes, you’ll find yourself in a fun fight against a group or a boss like Ajax. Other times, well, you’ll just watch the AI run around aimlessly or stand there looking like a deer in headlights.</p>



<p>Visually, Unreal Engine 4 shines in making the game look good. There were some frame drop issues, but that’s something I chalk up to the game being in beta.</p>



<p>Of course, there’s the worry about monetization when the game fully launches. Being free-to-play means that microtransactions are coming. After all, the developers have to make money somehow. But how it works will be something to watch as it could turn the game into a pay-to-win experience.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-should-you-play-arena-breakout-infinite">Should You Play Arena Breakout: Infinite?</h2>



<p>At every step of the way, it’s clear that Arena Breakout: Infinite has its eyes set on both Escape from Tarkov and Gray Zone Warfare. The game offers several things that neither of its main competitors have while having gameplay that’s captivating enough to want to come back to.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the end of the day, however, it’s going to come down to what else Morefun Games does to the gameplay and the out-of-raid experience that makes players want to come back rather than feel like they need to. Also, how the team attacks monetizing a PC audience will play a big role in the success of the game.</p>



<p>For now, though,&nbsp;Arena Breakout: Infinite is one game that all players <a href="https://www.arenabreakoutinfinite.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">need to keep an eye on</a> and get into as soon as the opportunity arises.</p>













<hr>



<p>Arena Breakout: Infinite’s Closed Beta was reviewed on PC with a code provided from the publisher. For more on Insider Gaming’s reviews, view our full <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/review-policy/">review policy</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 16 Best Board Games for Couples to Play in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-couples</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-16-best-board-games-for-couples-to-play-in-2024.873105/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-couples<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>While there are plenty of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-2-player-board-games"><u>two-player board games</u></a> that are excellent, board games for couples to play together deserve their own special sub-category. A lot of two-player games are pretty hardcore <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-war-board-games"><u>war board games</u></a> or abstracts, for example, which are difficult categories for couples to agree over. Even if you can avoid such niche picks, two-player games also have a tendency to be fiercely competitive, which might also be a bad idea unless you’re both super forgiving. So here are our picks of the best games that balance the competitive and the cooperative, and the luck with the strategy, just so you can find a sweet spot to enjoy together.</p><h3>TL;DR The Best Board Games for Couples</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/3w7Xw" target="_blank">Race to the Raft</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/jdZwP" target="_blank">Sky Team</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/7L5YE" target="_blank">The Search for Lost Species</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/NwjJd" target="_blank">Fog of Love</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/8OxLd" target="_blank">Patchwork</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/1gZ6n" target="_blank">Codenames Duet</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/pPAX0" target="_blank">The Adventures of Robin Hood</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/3qlR3" target="_blank">Hive</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/Gymgq" target="_blank">Onitama</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/pPA7l" target="_blank">Five Tribes</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/w4NRR" target="_blank">The Fox in the Forest</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/RpwnK" target="_blank">7 Wonders: Duel</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/NwjJd" target="_blank">Schotten Totten</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/R6YmE" target="_blank">Splendor: Duel</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/lVLMP" target="_blank">Sea Salt &amp; Paper</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/GYwAE" target="_blank">Dorfromantik: The Board Game</a></li></ul><h2>Race to the Raft</h2><div id="195588"><p><h3>Race to the Raft</h3></p></div><p>Some of you may remember the movement puzzle games that were popular in the early days of the internet: they’re a clear predecessor to this bright and absorbing board game about guiding finicky cats to safety. Each cat will only travel over one colour of terrain, so it’s your job to work together to build a path for it to reach a raft before a blazing fire cuts it off. Your goal is hampered by the random nature of terrain cards you draw, the likelihood you’ll cut off another cat’s route with each play, and limited communication rules that may see you meowing desperately at one another to try and get a point across. Both challenging and hilarious, the game offers more than 80 scenarios of ever-increasing difficulty. </p><h2>Sky Team: Prepare for Landing</h2><div id="195589"><p><h3>Sky Team: Prepare for Landing</h3></p></div><p>What better way to say “I love you” than to take a flight together to an exotic destination? That’s what you get to do in Sky Team, with the notable catch that you’re playing as the pilot and co-pilot, and you have to work together to land the plane first. It’s far harder than it sounds: both of you have your own pool of dice and sets of instruments you must attend to using the results. Some of them even require you to balance the two values assigned by each player, a task made even trickier by the fact you can’t discuss strategy during the placement phase. At least that should avoid the potential for arguments when you find the dice pool is running short, the plane is tilting at a dangerous angle and there’s a queue of air traffic in front of you for the runway.</p><h2>The Search for Lost Species</h2><div id="195590"><p><h3>The Search for Lost Species</h3></p></div><p>Boasting an appealing theme and an ever-shifting puzzle dynamic, this app-driven game sees players racing to map the ecology of an island and discover a long-lost animal. This engaging skin hides a logic puzzle of fiendish complexity. Each animal on the island has several rules dictating where it lives: some of them are fixed and some change from game to game, revealed by the app as the players research. They must use these rules, and clues from their island exploration, to figure out what hexes hold which species and slowly pin down the location of the mysterious beast. It’s complex but plays quickly once mastered, and every game is a fresh puzzle thanks to the app. You can even work together against the app, although you’ll have to share one playing piece.</p><h2>Fog of Love</h2><div id="155164"><p><h3>Fog of Love</h3></p></div><p>We have to start a list like this with a game designed specifically to tell the story of a couple in a relationship. However, it isn’t your relationship but one that you’ll create between a pair of fictitious characters and then go on to explore its nuances and ups and downs. Although there’s a certain amount of blue and pink in the visuals it’s also open to same-sex relationships, too. Your couple each get a brew of secret traits and destinies and then go on to play through a number of scenes, making choices based on traits that affect the outcome. As an experimental game, there is no winner here in the strict sense, but you’ll win by enjoying a fascinating journey through an imagined relationship instead.</p><h2>Patchwork</h2><div id="162166"><p><h3>Patchwork</h3></p></div><p>Patchwork works because it’s a super simple synthesis of several clever concepts in one small package. Players buy geometric pieces using buttons to try and form a quilt with as few holes in it as possible. Each purchase also moves you forward on a time track, which intermittently earns you extra buttons or very useful single-square patches for your quilt, but the person last on the time track always takes the next turn. This lets you set up interesting plays like planning for double turns or trying to leapfrog your opponent to snatch a one-square patch. Gently addictive while it transfixes several parts of your brain at once, it’s no wonder it won a slew of awards and nominations.</p><h2>Codenames Duet</h2><div id="162167"><p><h3>Codenames Duet</h3></p></div><p>The original <a href="https://zdcs.link/kvOK6" target="_blank">Codenames</a> was a rare breakout hit into the wider world of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-parties-and-large-groups">party games</a>. Players laid out a grid of cards with words on them. Then one player per team had to give out single-word clues to try and link multiple words together in order to help their teammates identify which cards were coded to their side. Codenames: Duet is very similar but it’s been refined for two into a much sleeker <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-cooperative-board-games">cooperative game</a>. Now you’re trying to find fifteen clues between you before a timer runs out. Because you both take turns giving clues, downtime while someone thinks of a clue to give is almost eliminated, bringing a fun slice of party game magic to the table with just the two of you.</p><h2>The Adventures of Robin Hood</h2><div id="162168"><p><h3>The Adventures of Robin Hood</h3></p></div><p>Unlike the other games on this list, The Adventures of Robin Hood is a narrative-driven title where you retell the legend of the famous outlaw across nine scenarios. But it brings all sorts of clever ideas to the formula, making it intriguing and engaging to play. There are no board spaces for starters: instead, you measure your progress across the map with a long base on your wooden playing piece, trying to stay in printed shadows and out of sight of guards. The board is like an advent calendar, with hundreds of numbered pieces you can lift out and flip over to create the feel of a living, dynamic world you encounter by looking up the numbers in the included book. Can you and your partner work together to save Nottingham from the clutches of the evil Sheriff before Guy of Gisborne hunts you down? </p><h2>Hive</h2><div id="162169"><p><h3>Hive</h3></p></div><p>Played with delightful chunky plastic hexes, Hive is a game with an unfortunate tendency to make your skin crawl thanks to its insectoid subject matter. On the plus side, it also makes your brain crawl in all the best ways with its ever-escalating web of interlocking strategies. Each player has a Queen hex and you win by surrounding your opponent’s Queen with your pieces. There are four other types of insects, each with its own movement rules that you must leverage in pursuit of your goal. There are only eleven tiles on each side, which enter play one by one, and the Hive itself must always be a single conglomeration of tiles. That makes Hive easy to transport, set up and play, but the complex interaction of movement rules makes it devilishly hard to win.</p><h2>Onitama</h2><div id="162170"><p><h3>Onitama</h3></p></div><p>Onitama gets a lot of mileage out of a very simple idea. It’s played on a grid where each player starts with a master pawn and five students. Moving any of your pieces onto an opponent’s piece knocks it off the board and you win either by knocking out the enemy master or moving your own master to the opposite end of the board. The kicker is that the legal moves for your pieces depend on a random deal of cards: you have a choice of two each turn and the one you pick is discarded and refreshed from an extra card from the side of the board. This creates a fascinating and challenging interplay of cause and effect where you can see the likely path to plan ahead but the ever-changing roster of potential moves muddy the waters. </p><h2>Five Tribes</h2><div id="162171"><p><h3>Five Tribes</h3></p></div><p>You may have played the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-classic-board-games">classic board game</a> Mancala where you grab a handful of beads from a pit and pop one each in the following sequence of pits. Five Tribes translates this concept into a modern strategy game played on a grid of tiles. Each handful you pick up will consist of multiple color pieces and the final tile you drop one on determines what actions you take for that round. However, the changed board state then determines possible combinations for the next player to take, making each turn a mind-bending puzzle of balancing your own needs against your opponent’s opportunities. Add in an auction to determine the first player and you’ve got a modern classic. With two, Five Tribes lets you double your turns meaning there’s a whole other layer of using your first turn to set yourself up for a combo second turn.</p><h2>The Fox in the Forest</h2><div id="162172"><p><h3>The Fox in the Forest</h3></p></div><p>If you’ve ever played a traditional trick-taking game like Whist you might be baffled that such a thing could work with two. Yet that’s what The Fox in the Forest achieves thanks to its three-suit deck in which even-numbered cards work like standard playing cards, but odd-numbered cards all have a special power. The 3-value Fox, for instance, lets you change the trump suit while the 9-value Witch is treated as always being a trump. Its other clever coup is the scoring system which rewards you for winning either the majority or the minority of tricks, making it very hard to eke out a lead unless you can time your wins to perfection. Fast, fun and innovative, The Fox in the Forest is an incredible answer to a seemingly impossible question.</p><h2>7 Wonders: Duel</h2><div id="162173"><p><h3>7 Wonders: Duel</h3></p></div><p>While the original <a href="https://zdcs.link/e1jK6" target="_blank">7 Wonders</a> was a smash hit by itself, this two-player refinement is widely regarded as being even better. The core concept is the same: you’re drafting cards to make point-scoring sets representing aspects of an ancient civilization. Different types of cards represent different aspects such as military, technology or wonders of the world, and will give you bonuses and resources when added to your tableau. However, instead of the standard pick and pass drafting of the original game, 7 Wonders: Duel instead has players drafting from a pyramid of overlapping cards, most of which start face down and only become available when the cards atop them are taken. This adds a wonderful element of timing to the draft as you balance taking your best picks against giving more options to your opponent.</p><h2>Schotten Totten</h2><div id="155160"><p><h3>Schotten Totten 2</h3></p></div><p>A classic from back in 1999, Schotten Totten still holds up well today. Its central idea is that you’re battling across nine stones with each player trying to create Poker-style three-card combos on their own side, one card at a time. This creates the most delicious tension as your opponent wonders what meld you’re aiming for, and you worry whether you’ll draw the right cards to complete it. Just like Poker itself, there’s plenty of strategy in playing the probabilities, plus there’s an extra deck of special power tactics cards to spice things up. And if that wasn’t enough for you, you can also use the cards with their amusing cartoon art to play a completely different game called <a href="https://zdcs.link/GymrV" target="_blank">Lost Cities</a>.</p><h2>Splendor Duel</h2><div id="195790"><p><h3>Splendor: Duel</h3></p></div><p>The original Splendor, one of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-engine-building-board-games">best engine building games</a> around, already worked well with two, so you might wonder why a version exists that feels like it was specifically created for couples. The answer is that the refinements to the core gameplay loop make it better in every respect. You’re still master jewellers, trying to create the most beautiful works for your noble clientele, each one of which enriches your purchases power against future masterpieces. But you’re now picking your raw gems off a board, with placement rules, vying against three different victory conditions, and working with a slew of simple but highly significant special effects to vary your strategies. The result is a fantastic dance of two-player delight, which is ideal over the original if you’re only planning to play with your significant other.
</p><h2>Sea Salt &amp; Paper</h2><div id="200703"><p><h3>Sea Salt &amp; Paper</h3></p></div><p>This is a delightful abstract card game from prolific designer Bruno Cathala which combines several classic gameplay elements in one simple package. You take a card each turn, either randomly off the deck or a face-up one from a discard pile, and your aim is to build sets, which will score you points. Pairs of certain cards can be played for a special effect like taking an extra card or stealing one from an opponent, although that reveals some of your points to the whole table. Why does this matter? Because it's up to the players when the hand ends, and they can gamble they’ve got a winning combo at the potential cost of a lot of their points! While this classic small-box game works with a group, it’s best, fastest and most balanced with a cosy couple and, as a bonus, you can both appreciate its absolutely unique origami artwork, specially commissioned for the game.
</p><h2>Dorfromantik: The Board Game</h2><div id="186796"><p><h3>Dorfromantik: The Board Game</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Age Range: </strong>8+</li><li><strong>Players: </strong>1-6</li><li><strong>Playtime: </strong>30-60 mins</li></ul><p>Dorfromantik the video game gained a deserved reputation as a pleasantly relaxing puzzle in which you could build your own slice of rural utopia hex by hex. This board game adaptation brings the same vibe to one or several players as you work together, taking one tile at a time and trying to complete as many groups of similar terrain features as you can before the pile runs out. It has a trick up its sleeve: a delightfully addictive campaign mode that sees you climbing a tree of different reveals, adding a slow drip of straightforward but highly impactful new content to your game. These come in little boxes that you break open with each reveal, and there’s a particular pleasure in sharing your new discoveries with a partner, so you can coo over your new toys without the excitement getting lost in the crowd, before you move on to your next tile-laying escapade. 
</p><p><em>Matt Thrower is a contributing freelancer for IGN, specializing in tabletop games. He's also been published in The Guardian, Dicebreaker and Senet Magazine as well as being the author and co-author of several books on board games. You can reach him on BlueSky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mattthr.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@mattthr.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Dungeons and Dragons Books in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-dungeons-and-dragons-books</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-dungeons-and-dragons-books-in-2024.873102/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-dungeons-and-dragons-books<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>It’s safe to say that Dungeons &amp; Dragons is enjoying something of a golden age. Between the renewed popularity for the hobby brought on by Stranger Things to the success of the Honor Among Thieves movie, from the explosion of tabletop-focused podcasts and YouTube shows to the massive popularity of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-review">Baldur’s Gate 3</a> last year, there’s seriously never been a better time to start rolling for initiative.</p><p>But navigating the nearly decade-long reign of the Fifth Edition of Dungeons &amp; Dragons (AKA 5E) can be a bit difficult for newcomers to digest, especially owing to the plethora of high quality content being put out by third-party creators. If you’ve recently decided to get into the hobby, but don’t know where to start, here’s our recommendations on the best Dungeons &amp; Dragons books in 2024. You can also check out our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-to-play-dungeons-and-dragons">beginner's guide to D&amp;D</a> for additional tips.</p><h2>First-Party Content</h2><p>A few disclaimers before we dive in! First, this guide will primarily focus on first-party content, since there’s a dizzying amount of third-party content that mostly is geared towards D&amp;D veterans looking to spice up bog standard dungeon crawling. Secondly, we’re going to be excluding the three most essential books: <a href="https://zdcs.link/yN3pw?_ga=2039368431.1689096814" target="_blank"><strong>The</strong> <strong>Player’s Handbook</strong></a>, the <a href="https://zdcs.link/bN5yx?_ga=2039368431.1689096814" target="_blank"><strong>Dungeon Master’s Guide</strong></a>, and the <a href="https://zdcs.link/nJlyx?_ga=2039368431.1689096814" target="_blank"><strong>Monster Manual</strong></a>. While all three of these books are great (and have exciting <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-changes-coming-to-dds-core-rulebooks-overhaul">new versions</a> slated for later this year), it’s probably not particularly helpful to recommend them, since you’ll obviously want those basics before diving deeper. If you don’t have those three core rulebooks, you should get them.</p><p>Here are the best Dungeons &amp; Dragon books worth having in 2024 and beyond:</p><h3>Xanathar’s Guide to Everything (Sourcebook)</h3><div id="189104"><p><h3>Xanathar's Guide to Everything</h3></p></div><p>Quite possibly the most essential sourcebook since it was published in 2017, this expansion focuses on providing additional player options, including over 25 subclasses, 20 racial feats, new spells, and more. It also includes some helpful tools for the game master (like building traps) and some optional rules to flesh out some concepts from the core rulebooks (like playing through downtime).</p><p>Admittedly though, this sourcebook is more useful to players than it is to game masters, but if you want your party to have more options, you’d be hard-pressed to find a better sourcebook than this one. If you want Wizards who can learn War Magic, Paladins who have made an Oath of Redemption, or most importantly, Monks who can master drunken fighting style, you’re going to want to add this sourcebook to your collection immediately.</p><h3>Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything (Sourcebook)</h3><div id="189105"><p><h3>Tasha's Cauldron of Everything</h3></p></div><p>Similar to Xanathar’s Guide to Everything, this sourcebook is all about providing more player options and expanding upon ideas from the core rulebooks. <a href="https://www.wargamer.com/dnd/classes" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Every class</a> gets access to optional class features, there’s a whole host of new spells to peruse, and the game master can look forward to considering new rules for sidekicks, natural hazards, parlaying with monsters, and supernatural environments.</p><p>Again, most of the options in this one are geared towards players, but we consider this an essential part of injecting some class diversity into your milquetoast D&amp;D party.</p><h3>Waterdeep: Dragon Heist (Adventure)</h3><div id="189106"><p><h3>Waterdeep: Dragon Heist</h3></p></div><p>One of the coolest adventures published by Wizards of the Coast, this roleplay-heavy quest is filled with intrigue and deadly feuds. While many D&amp;D adventures are filled with dungeon crawls and loads of monsters to fight, we prefer journeys that are packed with social encounters, political conflict, and subterfuge, and Waterdeep provides just that in one fantastic package.</p><p>The adventure begins when a famous explorer ensnares the party in a bitter conflict between two criminal enterprises, with the promise of great riches that lie hidden somewhere in the city’s shadowy corners. Also, the book offers four possible antagonists, which can be swapped out by the game master depending on their preference – a neat little feature that allows for surprises even if players have played or seen other groups play the adventure before.</p><p>Also, if you like this adventure, there’s a direct follow-up called <a href="https://dnd.wizards.com/products/waterdeep-dungeon-of-the-mad-mage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Waterdeep: Dungeon of the Mad Mage</a>. As the name suggests, it has a significantly different vibe (trading intrigue for dungeons), but it at least provides some options for an extended campaign.</p><h3>Planescape: Adventures in the Multiverse (Sourcebook/Adventure Bundle)</h3><div id="189107"><p><h3>Planescape: Adventures in the Multiverse</h3></p></div><p>Planescape, the multiversal setting that sits at the center of the Forgotten Realms, is one of D&amp;D’s most interesting worlds (not to mention the setting for <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/1999/12/18/planescape-torment"><u>Planescape: Torment, one of the all-time greatest RPGs</u></a>), and this collection of three sourcebooks absolutely knocks it out of the park.</p><p>If you’re concerned that the three-book bundle follows in the disappointing footsteps of <a href="https://dnd.wizards.com/products/spelljammer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spelljammer</a> – fear not – clearly Wizards of the Coast has heard the feedback loud and clear and this expansion doesn’t skimp out on the details. The setting book, Sigil and the Outlands, is bursting with setting details from major landmarks to my personal favorite: factions (complete with extremely troubling philosophies). The setting’s monster manual, Morte’s Planar Parade, provides plenty of options for GMs to throw at their PCs during a campaign in Sigil, and the adventure, Turn of Fortune’s Wheel, goes some really interesting places.</p><p>All-in-All, this sourcebook bundle has really impressed us, and makes great use out of one of D&amp;D’s best settings. We love it and think you will too.</p><h3>Phandelver and Below: The Shattered Obelisk (Adventure)</h3><div id="189108"><p><h3>Phandelver and Below: The Shattered Obelisk</h3></p></div><p>Another recent release is the massive expansion to <a href="https://www.dndbeyond.com/sources/lmop" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Lost Mine of Phandelver</a>, an adventure that was many tabletop players’ first foray into the magical universe of D&amp;D. Phandelver and Below takes players back to the frontier town of Phandalin to dive deeper into the mystery of the magical obelisks found throughout the land. Throughout the course of this lengthy campaign, the party will unravel a conspiracy that’s worse than anything they could have imagined, when mystery becomes cosmic horror.</p><p>Honestly, this adventure is unlike anything Wizards has published in the past, and with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Illithid" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mind Flayers</a> taking a central role in the narrative, hot on the heels of Baldur’s Gate 3, combined with the nostalgia hit of Phandalin, this is one of the best campaigns to run right now.</p><h3>Eberron: Rising from the Last War (Sourcebook/Adventure)</h3><div id="189109"><p><h3>Eberron: Rising from the Last War</h3></p></div><p>This setting sourcebook is set in a war torn world with floating castles, skyscrapers, and airships, and is one of the more unique setting options to consider if you’d like to stray from the basics of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Forgotten_Realms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Forgotten Realms</a>. There’s some really cool stuff packed in this one, including some new species options called Dragonmarks.</p><p>The pulpy post-war vibes in this setting offer lots of opportunities for roleplay-focused groups, but also plenty of swashbuckling goodness as well. The package also includes a campaign that focuses on Mournland, a creepy place that’s rife with not-so-fun magic. We’ll leave it at that, for now….</p><h3>Dragonlance: Shadow of the Dragon Queen (Adventure)</h3><div id="189110"><p><h3>Dragonlance: Shadow of the Dragon Queen</h3></p></div><p>This adventure also introduces a new (at least to 5E) setting, Dragonlance, which was recently incorporated into <a href="https://dnd.wizards.com/products/the-practically-complete-guide-to-dragons" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Practically Complete Guide to Dragons</a> lorebook. If you dream of mass combat encounters featuring lots of enemies warring with one another and dragons laying waste to numerous foes, this is the book for you.</p><p>The adventure is quite lengthy, and focused on the death knight Lord Soth and his frightening army of draconians as the primary antagonist. There’s also some new player options to boot!</p><h3>Curse of Strahd (Adventure)</h3><div id="189111"><p><h3>Curse of Strahd</h3></p></div><p>One of the OG adventures from Advanced Dungeons &amp; Dragons, this classic gothic horror is a remake of a very old adventure from the first edition of the game. It’s got vampires! It’s got blood! It’s got really creepy toys you probably shouldn’t interact with, but probably will! What’s not to like?</p><p>If you enjoy this one, there’s also a supplement to support the setting called <a href="https://zdcs.link/xRNpx" target="_blank"><strong>Van Richten’s Guide to Ravenloft</strong></a>, though honestly, it’s vampires hanging out in castles – you probably get the idea without needing to read a whole book on the matter.</p><h3>The Wild Beyond the Witchlight (Adventure)</h3><div id="189112"><p><h3>The Wild Beyond the Witchlight: A Feywild Adventure</h3></p></div><p>Did we mention we like adventures with lots of roleplaying potential? Because another great option for doing just that is The Wild Beyond the Witchlight, an adventure that takes place in the Feywild setting that’s got a pretty cool carnival going on where nothing untoward is going on – probably. This one’s a lot of fun for parties that like having multiple options for solving a problem, not all of which include physical violence.</p><p>The book also offers two new playable species and some additional backgrounds to go with them. You can even decide to be a carny, meaning your character’s dreams of running away to join the circus can now become a reality – or a background.</p><h2>Third-Party Content</h2><p>Okay, okay – we know we were supposed to keep this thing limited to first-party stuff, since there’s just too much to cover in the third-party space, but we can’t help but name drop just a few quick titles you should consider checking out, including:</p><p><strong></strong><a href="https://shop.mcdmproductions.com/products/strongholds-followers-pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Strongholds and Followers</strong></a>, a sourcebook published by MCDM Productions that adds rules for GMs to give their parties bases and NPC friendlies. This book was so good that Wizards seems to be cribbing from it with their much more player-focused Bastion rules that will debut in next year’s revisions for the core rulebooks.</p><p><strong></strong><a href="https://shop.mcdmproductions.com/collections/flee-mortals-the-mcdm-monster-book" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Flee, Mortals!</strong></a><strong>,</strong> a monster manual published by MCDM Productions that redesigns lots of D&amp;D monsters to be more interesting and adds some new ones to boot. It also has a companion book called <a href="https://shop.mcdmproductions.com/collections/where-evil-lives-the-mcdm-book-of-boss-battles" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Where Evil Lives</a> that provides a single dungeon for groups to enjoy.</p><p><strong></strong><a href="https://koboldpress.com/kpstore/product/creature-codex-for-5th-edition-dnd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Tome of Beasts/Creature Codex</strong></a>, monster manuals published by Kobold Press that add even more monsters to the mix. The three volumes of Tome of Beasts are particularly useful for high-level groups looking for endgame challenges.</p><p><strong></strong><a href="https://ghostfiregaming.com/product-category/game/grim-hollow/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Grim Hollow</strong></a>, a dark fantasy setting created by Ghostfire Gaming that brings players into a much grimmer world of war, dark magic, and plagues. If you want to step out of the basic D&amp;D settings, this is definitely one to consider. Plus, they’ve got plenty of books to support the setting, so you can dive in as deep as you like!</p><p>And there you have it! Those are our top recommendations for the books you should consider buying in 2024. What do you think? Are there any of your favorites that we missed? Sound off in the comments to let us know how wrong we are or take a look at some of our favorite <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dnd-dungeons-dragons-dice">D&amp;D dice sets</a>.</p><div><p><em>Travis Northup is a writer for IGN based in San Francisco. He's been writing about games for over a decade and enjoys everything from strategy games and platformers to shooters and open-world RPGs. He also has an unhealthy relationship with Destiny 2.</em></p></div></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manor Lords moves 2m units | News-in-brief]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/manor-lords-moves-2m-units-news-in-brief</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/manor-lords-moves-2m-units-news-in-brief.873099/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/manor-lords-moves-2m-units-news-in-brief<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p>The resource for people who make and sell games.</p>

  

  <p>GamesIndustry.biz is owned by Gamer Network Limited, a ReedPop company and subsidiary of Reed Exhibitions Limited.</p>
  <p>© 2024 Gamer Network Limited, Gateway House, 28 The Quadrant, Richmond, Surrey, TW9 1DN, United Kingdom, registered under company number 03882481.</p>
  <p>All rights reserved. No part of this website or its content may be reproduced without the copyright owner's permission.</p>


  <nav>
    <ul>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://www.facebook.com/gamesindustry" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="facebook" data-type="facebook" aria-label="Check us out on Facebook">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on Facebook"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://twitter.com/GIBiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="x-twitter" data-type="twitter" aria-label="Check us out on X">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on X"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/gamesindustrybiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="linkedin" data-type="linkedin" aria-label="Check us out on LinkedIn">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on LinkedIn"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/feed" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="rss" data-type="rss" aria-label="Subscribe to our RSS feed" type="application/rss+xml">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Subscribe to our RSS feed"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://mastodon.social/@GIbiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="mastodon" data-type="mastodon" aria-label="Check us out on Mastodon">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on Mastodon"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
    </ul>
  </nav>
      </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Sports College Football 25 Arrives In July, Cover Athletes And Editions Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/05/16/ea-sports-college-football-25-arrives-in-july-cover-athletes-and-editions-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-sports-college-football-25-arrives-in-july-cover-athletes-and-editions-revealed.873096/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/05/16/ea-sports-college-football-25-arrives-in-july-cover-athletes-and-editions-revealed<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>EA Sports College Football finally has a release date, cover stars, and two different editions. The long-awaited return to college football hits PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S on July 19.</p>

<p>Gracing the cover of the game’s Standard edition are Michigan Wolverines’ running back Donovan Edwards, Texas Longhorns quarterback Quinn Ewers, and Colorado Buffaloes wide receiver/defensive back Travis Hunter. Check out the Standard and Deluxe covers in the gallery below.</p>



<p>The cover reveal comes a day before the game's full debut tomorrow. So far, we know that College Football 25 features 134 FBS schools, and it's being developed by Madden developer EA Orlando. The game was <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2021/02/02/ea-sports-announces-return-of-college-football-games">first announced in 2021</a> following a years-long hiatus for college football games due to the 2014 player likeness compensation lawsuit.</p>

<p>Both editions are now available for pre-order. The Standard Edition costs $69.99 and consists of the base game, Alma Mater and Cover Athlete Ultimate Team packs, and Bring Glory Home Ultimate Team Uniform Item.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The $99.99 Deluxe Edition includes three days of early access (July 16-18), 4600 College Football Points, Heisman Hopeful/Alma Mater/Cover Athlete Ultimate Teams packs, and the Bring Glory Home Ultimate Team Uniform Item.</p>

<p>Lastly, a $149.99 MVP Bundle includes the Deluxe editions of EA Sports College Football 25 and the upcoming Madden NFL 25.&nbsp;</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where to find the first pair of switches in Destiny 2 Zero Hour]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/where-to-find-the-first-pair-of-switches-in-destiny-2-zero-hour/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=where-to-find-the-first-pair-of-switches-in-destiny-2-zero-hour</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-to-find-the-first-pair-of-switches-in-destiny-2-zero-hour.873093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/where-to-find-the-first-pair-of-switches-in-destiny-2-zero-hour/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=where-to-find-the-first-pair-of-switches-in-destiny-2-zero-hour<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="391" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/tag/destiny-2/">Destiny 2</a></em> players, myself included, are eager to get their hands on the now-craftable Exotic pulse rifle, Outbreak Perfected. While completing the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/destiny-2-zero-hour-rewards-and-loot/">Zero Hour</a> mission on Normal is enough to receive the weapon, it’s not enough to unlock the craftable perks. Those come from weekly missions where Guardians must hunt down switches. Here is the first set of switches for Outbreak Refined I.</p> <h2 id="h-where-are-the-switches-in-outbreak-refined-i" data-injectable="false">Where are the switches in Outbreak Refined I?</h2> <p data-characters="276" data-current-count="276" data-injectable="false">After going through the Covert Passage into the open space with the ship, there will be a series of vents on your right. Proceed to the row furthest away from you and turn around to face the way you came. You’ll see an opening in the left corner where you can jump down.</p> <figure data-current-count="576" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="387" data-current-count="387" data-injectable="false">Follow the path until you jump down a silo with two crossed catwalks at the bottom. There will be a pair of Fallen Captains below that need to be eliminated. In each corner of this room are switches that will open hatches in the next room. Additionally, there is a switch in the middle of a wall, above a piece of machinery. Remember this switch as you’ll need to press it shortly.</p> <figure data-current-count="687" data-injectable="true"><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/destiny-2-zero-hour-outbreak-refined-002.jpg"></a><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="150" data-current-count="150" data-injectable="false">Kitty corner from that switch will be a passage lined with red pipes on the wall. Go there and activate that switch to open Hatch 03 in the next room.</p> <figure data-current-count="450" data-injectable="true"><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/destiny-2-zero-hour-outbreak-refined-003.jpg"></a><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="324" data-current-count="324" data-injectable="false">After activating the Hatch 03 switch, proceed into the next room. There will be a large gap between you and the next wall. Jump over to the sluice and up it to reach the platform on top where you’ll see the opened Hatch 03. Hop atop the lid of the hatch and use it to reach the vertical strip of platforms in the silo.</p> <figure data-current-count="624" data-injectable="true"><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/destiny-2-zero-hour-outbreak-refined-004.jpg"></a><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="476" data-current-count="476" data-injectable="true">At the top of the silo will be a darkened room with a switch on the wall. This is one of two switches needed, with the other being the first switch I mentioned. You can press them in either order, but I find it’s much quicker to activate this switch first, jump down the silo, and run back to the first switch. Once activated, you’ll see “Catalyst Switch Primed” with a 30-second timer. Reach the second switch within that window to complete this step.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/destiny-2-zero-hour-outbreak-refined-005.jpg"></a><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="301" data-current-count="601" data-injectable="false">The remaining step for Outbreak Refined I is to complete Zero Hour on Legend. Due to the tight time limit, I recommend heading back to orbit and restarting the activity once everyone has completed this first step. To save yourself even more time, check out my <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/destiny-2-zero-hour-fire-puzzle-solutions/">guide on completing the Fire Puzzle room</a>.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New fully automatic M16: Best Warzone loadout]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/new-fully-automatic-m16-best-warzone-loadout/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-fully-automatic-m16-best-warzone-loadout</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-fully-automatic-m16-best-warzone-loadout.873090/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/new-fully-automatic-m16-best-warzone-loadout/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=new-fully-automatic-m16-best-warzone-loadout<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="462" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Remember the burst assault rifle <em>Warzone </em>meta from a few years back? People were using the M16 and AUG like it was nobody’s business. Fortunately, their incredibly high damage output was nerfed into the ground, leaving us with a few fairly useless weapons for a long time. However, a new conversion kit turns the M16 into a fully automatic assault rifle. Here’s how to build the automatic M16 loadout for <em>Warzone</em>, which <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/how-to-build-newly-buffed-m16-loadout-for-warzone/">also received a buff recently</a>.</p> <h2 id="h-how-to-get-the-jak-patriot-conversion-kit-for-the-m16" data-injectable="false">How to get the JAK Patriot conversion kit for the M16</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"></figure> <p data-characters="413" data-current-count="713" data-injectable="true">First and foremost, you’ll need to unlock the JAK Patriot conversion kit for the M16 assault rifle. Without it, the gun isn’t viable in <em>Warzone</em>. The fastest way to unlock it is by focusing on the weekly challenges in multiplayer. However, if you don’t own <em>Modern Warfare 3</em> or just don’t want to play regular multiplayer, there are weekly challenges for <em>Warzone</em> and Zombies game modes too. </p>
 <p data-characters="200" data-current-count="200" data-injectable="false">Simply complete five of the eight available weekly challenges for the current week (6) of Season 3. Once you’ve done that, the JAK Patriot will be available when you go to create an M16 loadout.</p> <h2 id="h-best-fully-automatic-m16-loadout" data-injectable="false">Best fully automatic M16 loadout </h2> <p data-characters="418" data-current-count="618" data-injectable="true">Once you’ve equipped the JAK Patriot, the other attachments are ones you might know by now. Many meta-builds for guns use similar attachments, as they’re significantly better than others. However, the best full-auto M16 class <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/what-is-alternate-ammo-in-call-of-duty-mw3/">uses an alternate ammunition type</a>, which is unusual. You can also swap out the under barrel for an optic if you don’t like the iron sights, as the recoil isn’t too bad.</p>
 <ul data-found-items="5" data-current-count="200" data-injectable="false"> <li><strong>Casus Brake Muzzle</strong></li> <li><strong>5.56 High Velocity Ammunition</strong></li> <li><strong>Bruen Pivot Vertical Grip Under Barrel</strong></li> <li><strong>60 Round Magazine</strong></li> <li><strong>JAK Patriot Conversion Kit</strong></li> </ul> <p data-characters="247" data-current-count="447" data-injectable="false">Community testing has found this version of the M16 to be one of the fastest time-to-kill assault rifles in <em>Warzone</em> right now. The DG-58 LSW is still the absolute meta, but the full-auto M16 is a close competitor for the first time in a long time.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>