<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 19:43:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deus Ex Remastered has been delayed and no longer has a release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/11/deus-ex-remastered-has-been-delayed-and-no-longer-has-a-release-date/</link>
            <guid>1380085</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Aspyr Media have announced that the remaster of<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/deus-ex-remastered/"> Deus Ex </a>will no longer launch on February 5th 2026 and as usual, the delay is because they think the game needs more work.</p>
<p>The full statement reads:</p>


<p><em>Thank you to the community for your feedback following the reveal of Deus Ex Remastered. We’ve listened to what you had to say, and in order to better meet fan expectations and deliver the best possible experience for players, Deus Ex Remastered will no longer launch on Feb. 5, 2026. We look forward to sharing more updates with you when the time comes. All existing preorders will be fully refunded. Thank you again for your patience and support.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Deus Ex Remastered - Announce Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f1RdKezTYNk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The game was only revealed in September this year via a collaboration of Aspyr and Eidos-Montréal. They seemed to be taking the right approach to the game stating The mission: preserve the truth, modernize the tools, and prepare a new generation of agents for what lies ahead.”</p>

<p>“This remaster isn’t just a visual upgrade, but a preservation of Deus Ex’s DNA – carefully modernized without sacrificing the conspiratorial paranoia that made the original game so iconic,” he adds. “Each location has been overhauled with new lighting, dynamic shadows, particle systems, and upscaled textures,” they added.</p>
<p>The title was scheduled for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch. The reception to the trailer was not exactly warm as the remaster adds new textures, upgrades the models and adds new lighting, but the levels are still very empty and sparse.&nbsp; However, the models are not exactly modern and it looks more like someone has put an Instagram filter over the original game.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://twitter.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170679116087572" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitter</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/11/deus-ex-remastered-has-been-delayed-and-no-longer-has-a-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Tips To Know Before Heading Into Pokémon Legends: Z-A’s Grindy New DLC Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-mega-dimension-hyperspace-donuts-tips-2000652670</link>
            <guid>1380076</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-review-switch-2-bugs-performance-2000637719"><i><span>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</span></i><span>’s</span></a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-mega-raichu-evolution-x-y-paid-dlc-2000625371"><i><span>Mega Dimension </span></i><span>expansion</span></a><span> is a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-mega-dimension-research-shiny-charm-2000652209"><span>big ol’ grind</span></a><span>. It’s a fun one, and it paves the way to some really cool reveals and story moments, but it is a lot more time-consuming than fans probably expected. I’ve put about a dozen hours into the DLC’s new roguelike mode, so I’m practically an expert, right? If you’re getting tired of making donuts for the mysterious Pokémon Hoopa and heading into portals to an unknown world when you just want to see one of the new Mega Evolutions, I’ve got a handful of tips to help you make the most of these time-limited expeditions into Hyperspace.&nbsp;</span></p> <h2><b>Keep a flying Pokémon on your team</b></h2> <p><span>Now, I don’t mean you need a flying-type Pokémon on your team; I mean a Pokémon capable of flight or quickly moving through the air. Your biggest asset in </span><i><span>Mega Dimension</span></i><span>’s Hyperspace zones is time, and it’s possible to miss out on an objective by literal seconds if you don’t have a Pokémon that can readily reach an object or target on high ground. This is especially important when you’re trying to reach the floating Poke Balls throughout the zone that you’ll often have to destroy as part of a Hyperspace run. If you’ve only got land-based monsters, it will take them longer to reach these objectives, which means precious seconds lost before you’re pulled back to reality. So keep someone on your belt who can fly to harder-to-reach places.</span></p>

 <h2><b>Find moves that don’t take long to cast</b></h2> <p><span>Speaking of saving time, one thing that will help you accomplish more in a Hyperspace run is to make sure your Pokémon have moves that don’t take long to execute. Moves that have to charge up or have phases might be strong, but you’re going to lose more time casting them than you will with a different attack. I tried using my Raichu, who knows the ground-type move Dig, against a long string of fire-type Pokemon weak to that move, but because it requires the mouse to dig into the ground and then sprout up underneath an opponent, I lost time using it that I could have saved by swapping to another monster who has a ground-type move that doesn’t take as long to use. Be mindful of your movesets before you head into Hyperspace so you can take out enemies more quickly.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000652671" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000652671"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000652671">© The Pokémon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <h2><b>Get to high ground while searching for the Bonus Ball</b></h2> <p><span>After you complete all the missions in a run, a golden Bonus Ball will spawn somewhere on the map. </span><i><span>Mega Dimension </span></i><span>doesn’t give you any guidance as to where, and you’ll have to find it in whatever time you have left before Hoopa pulls you off the stage with a hook. Your best chance at finding this spherical treasure chest is to get to high ground. Sometimes you’ll be able to get to the top of buildings with a Holovator; other times, you might have to climb scaffolding. This isn’t foolproof because the Bonus Ball might be tucked in a corner on the lower levels of a zone, but it’s a quick way to eliminate some possibilities so you’re not wasting time.</span></p>

 <h2><b>PSA: You can fast-travel to the exit if you’re not in battle, and you should</b></h2> <p><span>If you’ve caught every Pokémon you want in a zone, completed every objective, and found the Bonus Ball, keep in mind you can fast-travel back to the Hyperspace entrance, and this will get you out much faster so you can get to the next run. It’s a small thing, but when you’re grinding runs back to back, every second counts.</span></p>

 <h2><b>Don’t worry about being at or too far above the raised level of a zone</b></h2> <p><span>One of the big changes Game Freak harped on in the lead-up to </span><i><span>Mega Dimension</span></i><span>’s release</span> <span>was that the roguelike segments would break the series’ level 100 cap. You meet these superpowered monsters where they’re at by feeding Hoopa berry-filled donuts, which it uses to boost your team’s level in the Hyperspace zones. While I understand the instinct to try and be at or above the projected levels of monsters in a zone, in my experience, even if you’re maybe 20 or so below you can reasonably accomplish what you need to on a run. Don’t be reckless, but don’t feel like you’ve gotta waste all your best berries each time you need to make a donut. Do try and have a team of six that is all at a base level of 100 so they can make the most of the donut-based upgrades, though.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000652672" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000652672"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000652672">© The Pokémon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <h2><b>You don’t get experience from Hyperspace battles, so don’t come here to grind levels</b></h2> <p><span>As cool as the thought of fighting superpowered Pokémon and raking in experience sounds, you will not gain any of that in Hyperspace. The rewards you get for running through the bizarro Lumiose City are often very specific to the </span><i><span>Mega Dimension</span></i><span> content, rather than something you can use to grind for other parts of the game. You’ll get a ton of berries and survey points, but not experience that will raise your monsters’ base levels. You might find Exp. Candies sometimes, which will give you experience, but it’s inconsistent.&nbsp;</span></p> <h2><b>Don’t haphazardly load up Donuts with whatever Berries you’ve got</b></h2> <p><span>Every Donut Hoopa eats is made up of various Berries you’ll come across throughout Lumiose City. You can mix any combination of them, which each will increase your level in a Hyperspace run, but they also have different perks like stat upgrades, resistance to certain attacks, and maybe even an upgraded Shiny spawn chance. As tempting as it is to just load your best Berries into one pastry, this will come back to bite you, especially in the later story segments when you need to create specific Donuts with a list of high-flavor requirements. You’ll wish you hadn’t wasted some of those rare Berries, and you’ll have to go on runs with your fingers crossed hoping they will spawn in Hyperspace. So bake your Donuts responsibly.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-mega-dimension-hyperspace-donuts-tips-2000652670]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TheBurntPeanut Finally Gets an Escape from Tarkov Streamer Item]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/theburntpeanut-tarkov-streamer-item/</link>
            <guid>1380070</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>TheBurntPeanut, one of the most popular content creators in the world right now, has received an exclusive ‘streamer item’ from Battlestate Games for use in Escape from Tarkov. In the last couple of years, the Escape from Tarkov community and platform have been a foundation for TheBurntPeanut on his rise to fame, so this is a very appropriate move by Battlestate Games.</p>



<p>Fans of the energetic, hilarious streamer have been lobbying Battlestate Games for the longest time for an exclusive streamer item, and now it’s here. Check it out below.</p>



<h2 id="h-theburntpeanut-s-tarkov-streamer-item-is-exactly-what-you-d-expect">TheBurntPeanut’s Tarkov Streamer Item is Exactly What You’d Expect</h2>



<p>This isn’t the first new streamer item unveiled by Battlestate Games in recent days. Earlier this week, Nikita Buyanov, the head of the studio at Battlestate Games, revealed <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/first-player-escape-tarkov-streamer-item/">a streamer item for Tigz</a>, the first person in the world to complete the Tarkov campaign in full. He received a special ‘splint’ item just days ago.</p>



<p>TheBurntPeanut has now received the Escape from Tarkov streamer item treatment.</p>



<p>He joins a long line of popular creators who have used Escape from Tarkov to propel their content forward. At this point, there are a couple of dozen streamer items in the game, and they even feed into one of the game’s most aspirational tasks. To unlock the legendary ‘Kappa’ case, players must collect <strong>every streamer item</strong>, amongst other things.</p>



<p>There’s even a special ‘streamer item case’ that users can unlock to store these items in.</p>



<p>TheBurntPeanut’s item is at least practical, surfacing as a balaclava that perfectly resembles TheBurntPeanut’s own visage.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Dmitri Ogorodnikov, the head of PR at Battlestate Games, followed up with a post dubbing the streamer item ‘well deserved’, a sentiment that was echoed by fans of the streamer, who are affectionately named ‘Bungulators’.</p>



<p>Do you think TheBurntPeanut’s streamer item is appropriate? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> what you’re thinking.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lords-of-the-fallen-final-surprise-update-revealed/">surprise final update for Lords of the Fallen</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/theburntpeanut-tarkov-streamer-item/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Plan Your Pokemon Team: Mega Dimensions DLC Added to Planet Pokemon Tool]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/plan-your-pokemon-team-mega-dimensions-dlc-added-to-planet-pokemon-tool</link>
            <guid>1380067</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">With the arrival of the Mega Dimensions DLC for Pokémon Legends: Z-A, <a href="https://planetpokemon.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Planet Pokémon</u></a>, powered by a team-up of Pokémon experts from Maxroll, Eurogamer, and IGN, has delved into Hyperspace to uncover all of the knowledge you need to be fully prepared for this new adventure in Lumiose City.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Our <a href="https://planetpokemon.com/legends-z-a/planner" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Pokémon Planner</u></a> now includes all of the Mega Evolutions and returning Pokémon added to Legends: Z-A in the new DLC. This includes Pokémon base stats and movesets. With this information on hand, you can start experimenting with your team before catching the Pokémon in-game. Don't worry if you haven't used the planner before, our handy <a href="https://planetpokemon.com/news/how-to-use-the-planet-pokemon-planner" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Pokémon Planner guide</u></a> will teach you all the tricks.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/11/screenshot-2025-12-11-at-9-18-31-am-1765473664409.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside this, our <a href="https://planetpokemon.com/legends-z-a/pokedex" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Legends: Z-A Pokédex</u></a> and <a href="https://planetpokemon.com/legends-z-a/items" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Items list</u></a> have also been updated for the DLC. So whether you're checking to see if your favourite Pokémon has returned or if a handy item has been added, you'll find it all here on Planet Pokémon. Here's a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-legends-z-a/Mega_Dimension_DLC">full list of what's been updated in the Mega Dimensions DLC</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-legends-z-a/How_to_Start_the_Mega_Dimension_DLC">Remember, you need to have completed the main campaign in Legends: Z-A to play the Mega Dimensions DLC. </a>When you do, you'll experience a simple task - helping a young girl bake a donut - transform into combating another threat looming over Lumiose City. (I'm starting to wonder why people live there… It's a bit of a danger magnet.) You won't just be fighting Rogue Mega Evolutions this time though. No, you'll be crossing the boundaries of time and space itself thanks to a Hoopa who can open Hyperspace portals after eating a donut. Not the weirdest thing to happen in a Pokémon game, but it's up there.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/11/screenshot-2025-12-11-at-9-17-31-am-1765473664409.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Along the way, you'll team up with old friends, collect new Mega Evolutions like Mega Lucario Z and catch returning Pokémon from past generations, such as Meowth, Mudkip and Mimikyu. There's also a host of new Side Missions for you to complete too! One might even lead you to a Legendary Pokémon… Just be prepared for the Pokémon in Hyperspace to have levels higher than what you're used to. I'm talking over 100! Thankfully, the right donut can make your team just as dangerous.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/11/screenshot-2025-12-11-at-9-18-38-am-1765473664410.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Hope you enjoy the Mega Dimensions DLC and don't forget to check out the updated Pokémon Planner over on Planet Pokémon!</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lottie Lynn is the Guides Editor over at Eurogamer. She covers a wide of games - spanning the latest RPG to farming simulators to an awful lot of Pokémon. Thankfully she's a massive Pokémon fan and lore expert, having started playing back in the Pokémon Yellow days. Though her Pokémon collection actually started before the series even reached UK shores due to her Dad bringing back a Pikachu child alarm from a business trip to Japan. (A purchase he most likely regrets for multiple reasons.)</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/plan-your-pokemon-team-mega-dimensions-dlc-added-to-planet-pokemon-tool]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Celebrate Metroid Prime 4: Beyond with This Samus Aran Figure at IGN Store]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/celebrate-metroid-prime-4-beyond-with-this-samus-aran-figure-at-ign-store</link>
            <guid>1380061</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Pre-order the legendary bounty hunter now.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">After eight long years, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> has officially released as of last week for Nintendo Switch and Nintendo Switch 2. The next chapter in the legendary series sees Samus Aran explore the mysterious planet of Viewros, which offers many secrets to uncover. One of the key new elements of this game is the new psychic powers, allowing Samus to control objects, guide energy beams, and interact with the environment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For a limited time, you can pre-order the official Metroid Prime 4: Beyond CHOGOKIN Samus Aran action figure at IGN Store. This ultimate collector's item is perfect for any new or longtime Metroid fan.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pre-Order the Metroid Prime 4: Beyond - CHOGOKIN Samus Aran - Action Figure at IGN Store</h2><div catalogid="21d1aad9-0e34-40d3-bb6b-8da93d9c57fb" id="233531"><div id="233531" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Metroid Prime 4 Beyond - CHOGOKIN Samus Aran - Action Figure</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Standing at approximately 8.3 inches tall, this figure of Samus Aran perfectly captures her unique new appearance from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metroid-prime-4-beyond">Metroid Prime 4</a>. The iconic barrier suit is fitted with a mysterious purple crystal, allowing Samus to harness the psychic abilities. Speaking of the barrier suit, this figure includes diecast parts for sections of the outer armor and skeleton, giving a realistic weight.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">An LED unit in the arm cannon makes it appear as if Samus is charging a blast, and there are also lights in the chest and helmet for added visual effect. Optional hand parts are also included to allow for many of Samus Aran's most iconic poses to be recreated.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can pose this figure any way you'd like, and the included interchangeable parts make this an excellent choice for any collection. This pre-order is set to end in just over one week, so be sure to lock in your figure before time runs out. Samus Aran will ship in Q3/4 2026.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">About IGN Store</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/ZoyWY?_ga=1194235761.1666047560&amp;content_id=0315af98-1af8-43c6-b8bc-a52bd609c020&amp;pagetype=article&amp;object_uuid=b6d5f5de-b761-4f02-a831-726496a445b8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>IGN Store</u></a> sells high-quality merch, <a href="https://zdcs.link/N6vGY?_ga=1194235761.1666047560&amp;content_id=0315af98-1af8-43c6-b8bc-a52bd609c020&amp;pagetype=article&amp;object_uuid=b6d5f5de-b761-4f02-a831-726496a445b8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">collectibles</a>, and shirts for everything you're into. It's a shop built with fans in mind: for all the geek culture and fandom you love most. Whether you're into comics, movies, <a href="https://zdcs.link/D4mEw?_ga=1194235761.1666047560&amp;content_id=0315af98-1af8-43c6-b8bc-a52bd609c020&amp;pagetype=article&amp;object_uuid=b6d5f5de-b761-4f02-a831-726496a445b8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">anime</a>, games, retro gaming or just want some <a href="https://zdcs.link/drOGK?_ga=1194235761.1666047560&amp;content_id=0315af98-1af8-43c6-b8bc-a52bd609c020&amp;pagetype=article&amp;object_uuid=b6d5f5de-b761-4f02-a831-726496a445b8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">cute plushies</a> (who doesn't?), this store is for you!</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Dec 11, 2025 6:00 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/celebrate-metroid-prime-4-beyond-with-this-samus-aran-figure-at-ign-store]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Developer Rockstar Claims Fired Employees Were Dismissed for Leaking 'Specific Game Features From Upcoming and Unannounced Titles,' Not Because ]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-developer-rockstar-claims-fired-employees-were-dismissed-for-leaking-specific-game-features-from-upcoming-and-unannounced-titles-not-because-they-were-trying-to-unionize</link>
            <guid>1380058</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar has claimed the employees it recently fired were dismissed because they leaked game features for upcoming and unannounced titles in Discord, not because they were trying to unionize.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a statement provided to IGN, a Rockstar Games spokesperson said:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Rockstar Games took action against a small group of individuals, across the UK and internationally, who distributed and discussed confidential information (including specific game features from upcoming and unannounced titles) in a public forum, in breach of company policy and their legal obligations. Claims that these dismissals were linked to union membership or activities are entirely false and misleading.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">34 members of staff at Rockstar were dismissed, 31 in the UK and three in Canada, sparking protests outside the office of GTA 6 developer Rockstar North in Edinburgh, Scotland, and outside parent company Take-Two’s office in London.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Rockstar North and Take-Two Office Protest Photos Nov 2025</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar’s statement comes after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/uk-prime-minister-sir-keir-starmer-says-rockstar-firing-31-gta-6-developers-over-alleged-union-busting-is-deeply-concerning-and-pledges-that-ministers-will-now-investigate">UK Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer called the case “deeply concerning,"</a> and pledged that ministers would investigate.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The layoffs, which took place at the end of October, were raised in the UK's Parliament during this week’s session of Prime Minister's Questions by Rockstar North's local MP Chris Murray.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The video games company Rockstar in my constituency last month fired 31 employees without providing evidence or union representation," Murray told the Prime Minister. "The [Independent Workers Union of Great Britain union] IWGB alleges union busting. Having met Rockstar they failed to reassure me they are following employment law and I share concerns about union busting.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Given this government is responsible for the biggest increase in workers rights in a generation," Murray continued, "does the Prime Minister agree all companies regardless of profit size must follow UK employment law and all workers have the right to join a union?"</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"It's a deeply concerning case," Starmer replied. "Every worker has the right to join a trade union and we're determined to strengthen workers rights and ensure they don't face unfair consequences for being part of a union. Our ministers will look into the particular case that he [Murray] raises and will keep him updated."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has contacted the IWGB for further comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a statement sent to IGN this week, MP Chris Murray shared further, eyebrow-raising detail of his attempts to discuss the matter with Rockstar itself, including a joint meeting alongside fellow Edinburgh MPs Tracy Gilbert and Scott Arthur at Rockstar North's offices which began with a standoff over the need to sign a non-disclosure agreement (NDA).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The meeting began with us as MPs refused entry unless an NDA was signed, a request they eventually withdrew after it being made clear this would not be signed," Murray said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He continued: "The meeting only entrenched my concerns about the process Rockstar used to dismiss so many of their staff members. I was not assured their process paid robust attention to UK employment law, I was not convinced that this course of action was necessary, and alarmingly, I did not leave informed on exactly what these 31 people had done to warrant their immediate dismissal."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Rockstar's now-former staff, the IWGB has formally taken up their case and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/uk-video-game-worker-union-files-legal-claims-against-gta-6-developer-rockstar-alleging-trade-union-victimisation-and-blacklisting">filed legal claims against Rockstar Games</a>, alleging that their dismissal constituted "trade union victimisation and blacklisting." The first step on this legal journey will see the IWGB's claim examined by a tribunal who will determine whether the ex-employees are eligible for any interim relief. IGN recently questioned Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick on the matter, who answered by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-ceo-says-our-culture-is-extraordinary-amid-accusations-of-union-busting-at-gta-6-dev-rockstar-games">defending the company's culture</a> and saying that Take-Two was "incredibly proud of our labor relations."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-developer-rockstar-claims-fired-employees-were-dismissed-for-leaking-specific-game-features-from-upcoming-and-unannounced-titles-not-because-they-were-trying-to-unionize]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deus Ex Remastered Delayed Indefinitely, All Pre-Orders Refunded]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/deus-ex-remastered-delayed-indefinitely-pre-orders-refunded-aspyr-media/</link>
            <guid>1380040</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Aspyr Media has <a href="https://x.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170679116087572">announced</a> that its upcoming Deus Ex Remastered, a remaster of the original June 2000 game, has been delayed indefinitely. It will no longer release on its previously announced February 5, 2026, date, and Aspyr has refunded all pre-orders of the game.</p>



<p>The decision to delay the game came after feedback from Deus Ex fans based on the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/deus-ex-remastered-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc">game's initial reveal this past September</a>, which failed to impress players with its changes to the game's visuals. How a remaster changes the visuals in a retro game is almost always a point of controversy among that game's fan base, and this remaster of Deus Ex is no different.</p>



<p>This time, it seems, that the backlash has been too loud for Aspyr to ignore, as its statement thanks players for their feedback and that this delay is to ensure the studio is able to meet players expectations.</p>



<p>"<em>Thank you to the community for your feedback following the reveal of Deus Ex Remastered,</em>" the statement begins. "<em>We've listened to what you had to say, and in order to better meet fan expectations and deliver the best possible experience for players, Deus Ex Remastered will no longer launch on February 5, 2026. We look forward to sharing more updates with you when the time comes. All existing pre-orders will be fully refunded. Thank you again for your patience and support</em>."</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thank you to the community for your feedback following the reveal of Deus Ex Remastered. We've listened to what you said, and in order to better meet fan expectations and deliver the best possible experience for players, Deus Ex Remastered will no longer launch on Feb. 5, 2026. <a href="https://t.co/NhalyPLm8q">pic.twitter.com/NhalyPLm8q</a></p>— Aspyr (@AspyrMedia) <a href="https://twitter.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170679116087572?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 11, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Unfortunately for Aspyr, this is yet another disappointing result for them after a string of disappointing results. In the last few years, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-battlefront-classic-collection-launch-mess-3-servers/">Star Wars Battlefront Collection was an absolute mess of a release</a>, Aspyr <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-kotor-remake-is-still-being-worked-on-jason-schreier-says-to-have-heard/">was pulled off the Knights of the Old Republic Remake</a>, and now this.</p>



<p>Hopefully, the studio can rally and come back with a version of Deus Ex Remastered that gets fans excited to dive into the stealth game that set the blueprint for so many after it. Deus Ex is one of gaming's more important titles when it comes to how influential it was on everything that came after and the immersive sim genre, so it would be incredibly disappointing for a remaster of the title to be anything less than a complete show of respect and love for the original work.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/deus-ex-remastered-delayed-indefinitely-pre-orders-refunded-aspyr-media/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lords of the Fallen Surprise Final Update Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lords-of-the-fallen-final-surprise-update-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1380037</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Lords of the Fallen debuted in 2023, emerging as a reboot of sorts of the 2014 game of the same name. It was a considerable success, surfacing as a solid entry into the ever-growing lineup of Soulslike games that have dominated the market in recent years.</p>



<p>At Gamescom’s Opening Night Live ceremony, CI Games unveiled Lords of the Fallen II, slated for a 2026 release window. However, the team isn’t <strong>quite finished </strong>with Lords of the Fallen (2023), as a surprise, final update was revealed for the game, featuring stacks of extra content.</p>







<h2 id="h-lords-of-the-fallen-is-still-standing">Lords of the Fallen is Still Standing</h2>



<p>In an unexpected reveal, CI Games uncovered a final update for 2023’s Lords of the Fallen, a world-bending Soulslike title with some incredible combat sequences.</p>



<p>It was back in April 2024 that Lords of the Fallen’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lords-of-the-fallen-final-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘final update’</a> was released, dubbed ‘Master of Fate’, and the team thereafter pivoted to work on Lords of the Fallen II, which was then revealed a year and a half later.</p>



<p><strong>But then</strong>, in April 2025, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-update-friend-pass-co-op-improvements-explained/">‘Lords of the Fallen 2.0’</a> went live, with CI Games introducing several game-changing features such as a ‘Friend Pass’ system, new co-op challenges, and better multiplayer mechanics. It seems that, once again, final didn’t mean final, as <strong>yet another </strong>update has been lined up for Lords of the Fallen.</p>



<p>Now, the team at CI Games has confirmed that Lords of the Fallen ‘2.5’ is being released, including all of the following:</p>



<ul>
<li>Deadlier boss battles</li>



<li>Faster, smarter enemies</li>



<li>All-new Veteran Mode</li>



<li>New boss weapon animations</li>



<li>Veteran of the Veil Armour Set</li>



<li>And more…</li>
</ul>







<p>Did you ever play Lords of the Fallen? Let us know what you think about the game on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tomb-raider-prime-video-amazon-sigourney-weaver-report/">Sigourney Weaver might star in the new Tomb Raider production</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/lords-of-the-fallen-final-surprise-update-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout Is The Franchise That Bethesda Is "Doing The Most In" Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-is-the-franchise-that-bethesda-is-doing-the-most-in-right-now/1100-6536889/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1380034</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536889">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Fallout fans have been understandably curious about the future of the franchise, especially since <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-5-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6522412/" data-ref-id="1100-6522412">Fallout 5</a> isn't expected to arrive before <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6492383/" data-ref-id="1100-6492383">The Elder Scrolls 6</a>, and Bethesda hasn't been very forthcoming about when that game is coming either. For now, Bethesda's Todd Howard is keeping the company's plans close to his vest, but he has indicated there's more happening with Fallout than any other Bethesda property at the moment.</p><p>"We've had a long-term plan for Fallout, and so I wish I could talk about all those today," Howard told <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-chief-todd-howard-says-fallout-is-the-franchise-that-were-doing-the-most-in-right-now-coy-on-potential-return-to-new-vegas-or-a-fallout-3-remaster-while-fans-wait-for-fallout-5?utm_source=bluesky,threads,twitter" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN</a>. "I'll just say this, it's the franchise that we're doing the most in right now."</p><p>Howard also indicated that the success of Prime Video's Fallout TV series hasn't altered those plans or caused Bethesda to move up its timetable.</p><p>"We had a plan for the games we were going to make," said Howard. "The TV show was part obviously of our Fallout plan as far as a franchise. And in a lot of ways, I view it as an entry, as a game entry. Games are one lens into the world, the TV show is another lens into the world."</p><p>The show and the game world recently intersected in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-76-burning-springs-update-adds-new-map-region-and-walton-goggins-the-ghoul/1100-6536654/" data-ref-id="1100-6536654">Fallout 76's Burning Springs update</a>, which added Walton Goggins' The Ghoul as an important character. Howard praised the new update, but refused to directly answer questions about the rumored remaster of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fallout-3/" data-ref-id="5000-19700">Fallout 3</a>. However, he did reiterate how pleased he was with the release of The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion remaster, and hinted that future titles like that may also be given shadow drops.</p><p>Earlier this fall, Bethesda released <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-4-and-fallout-new-vegas-are-getting-anniversary-editions/1100-6535649/" data-ref-id="1100-6535649">Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition</a>, but the rollout has been marred by numerous bugs and other issues that sparked a backlash. Bethesda <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-4-gets-new-update-following-anniversary-edition-backlash/1100-6536446/" data-ref-id="1100-6536446">released an update</a> last month to deal with some of those problems, with a second bug-fix update slated to arrive this month as well.</p><p>Fallout Season 2 will premiere on Prime Video on December 17. In the meantime, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-fallout-pip-boy-controller-is-now-available-to-preorder/1100-6536863/" data-ref-id="1100-6536863">Fallout Pip-Boy Xbox Wireless Controller is now available for preorders</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-is-the-franchise-that-bethesda-is-doing-the-most-in-right-now/1100-6536889/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deus Ex Remastered Delayed To "Better Meet Fan Expectations"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/deus-ex-remastered-delayed-to-better-meet-fan-expectations/1100-6536890/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1380028</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536890">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Developer Aspyr Media announced that Deus Ex Remastered has been delayed (seemingly indefinitely) so the team can "deliver the best possible experience."</p><p>Aspyr <a href="https://x.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170679116087572" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">delivered the news on X</a>, posting that, alongside a commitment to delivering the best possible experience, the team wants to meet the expectations of its fanbase.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170679116087572" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Thank you to the community for your feedback following the reveal of Deus Ex Remastered. We've listened to what you said, and in order to better meet fan expectations and deliver the best possible experience for players, Deus Ex Remastered will no longer launch on Feb. 5, 2026. <a href="https://t.co/NhalyPLm8q" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/NhalyPLm8q</a></p>  — Aspyr (@AspyrMedia) <a href="https://twitter.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170679116087572?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 11, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>As such, the game has been pushed back from its initial February 5, 2026 release date. More updates will be shared "when the time comes," Aspyr said. By delaying the game, <a href="https://x.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170713253564497" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the studio is also refunding all preorders</a> while thanking fans for their continued patience and support.</p><p>Deus Ex Remastered was revealed during Sony's September 24 <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/playstation-state-of-play-september-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements-and-games/2900-7073/" data-ref-id="2900-7073">State of Play livestream</a>. The trailer showed off visual "enhancements," with associate brand manager Matthew Ray <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/09/24/deus-ex-remastered-launches-february-5-on-ps5/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">explaining on the PlayStation Blog</a> that the remaster would introduce overhauled controls, haptic feedback with the DualSense controller, updated lighting, improved shadows, increased particle effects, and enhanced textures.</p><p>Unfortunately, the game was criticized following its reveal. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f1RdKezTYNk" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the comments of the official trailer</a> on PlayStation's YouTube channel, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/everyone-thinks-the-deus-ex-remaster-looks-awful-and-theyre-right-they-really-turned-those-1999-graphics-into-2003-graphics/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">netizens decried the game's new visuals</a>. Others couldn't believe this was coming when no one asked for it. Some simply said it was a shame. Up and down the comments, people were confounded by the supposed visual improvements Aspyr touted.</p><p>This feedback is likely why Aspyr has delayed the game. Now, Deus Ex Remastered doesn't have a firm release date.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/deus-ex-remastered-delayed-to-better-meet-fan-expectations/1100-6536890/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: The Game Awards trailers can cost devs up to $1 million]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/report-the-game-awards-trailers-can-cost-devs-up-to-1-million</link>
            <guid>1380025</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">December 11, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>4 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via The Game Awards</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/game-awards-geoff-keighley-tickets-trailers-clair-obscur-2000652243">Kotaku report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, submitting a trailer to be presented at the Game Awards can reportedly cost developers up to $450,000 for a 60-second trailer, and $1 million for a three-minute-long one.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The first figure comes via two sources familiar with this year's show. Moreover, two separate sources in video game publishing said that while they had not been briefed on this year's rates, these "sounded in line with what they'd expect from previous years," as told to Kotaku.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Game Awards sells coveted spots for reveals, trailers, and previews, as well as sponsorships for specific awards. Some slots are reserved for the "biggest surprises," and organizer Geoff Keighley curates "free slots for what he personally wants to champion." But aside from these exceptions, developers who want to get their games in front of millions of viewers (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/game-awards-2024-viewership-record-1236253334/">154 million in 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, according to The Game Awards) have to pay the aforementioned fees.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Last year, an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/a61006534/summer-game-fest-explained/">Esquire</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> report on Summer Game Fest, an annual showcase that's also organized by Keighley, provided a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-summer-games-fest-trailers-can-cost-devs-up-to-550k">first insight</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> into how much trailers can cost. Back then, prices reportedly ranged from $250,000 for a one-minute trailer, $350,000 for 90 seconds, to $550,00 for two and a half minutes.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">An Esquire source acknowledged those costs may be too much for smaller studios, calling the price structure "an unattainable goal for most indie developers and publishers."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/bekah-saltsman-breaks-down-indie-biz-essentials-gdc-side-quest" target="_self" data-discover="true">Bekah Saltsman breaks down indie marketing essentials - GDC Side Quest</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The 2023 Game Awards had a similar pricing structure but, as noted by </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/summer-game-fest-sgf-prices-trailer-cost-e3-keighley-1851523472">Kotaku,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> some major publishers get "earned editorial placements" during the main show at no cost.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Nominated studios are reportedly offered only two tickets to attend the ceremony">Nominated studios are reportedly offered only two tickets to attend the ceremony</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to multiple developers speaking to Kotaku, from "both smaller indie studios and triple-A monoliths" who wished to remain anonymous, the Game Awards reportedly offers only two tickets to attend the ceremony to studios that get nominated.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The report notes there was at least one instance in which a developer received more than that, and some overall confusion about which studios get preferential treatment (as in, more than two tickets).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A source told Kotaku that Sandfall Interactive, the studio behind this year’s </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, bought a "swath of tickets at face value" (around $300 each) to ensure more members of the team could attend. The game received 12 nominations, setting a record for most nominations in Game Awards history.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A freelance narrative writer who worked on a game nominated this year expressed frustration to Kotaku about the ticketing process of the event. Since they're no longer under contract with the nominated studio, they didn't qualify for an official invite. Attempting to purchase a ticket from resellers didn't prove to be fruitful either.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/dear-game-developers-please-remember-what-on-the-record-actually-means" target="_self" data-discover="true">Dear game developers, please remember what 'on the record' means</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Even if I had wanted to pay the inflated prices for scalper tickets, I couldn't find 2 seats together," the source told Kotaku, with said tickets, according to the source, running between $600 to $1000. "At the very least, TGA should wait to sell general release tickets until after the nominations are announced…or have a separate bucket of tickets for devs who can provide proof that they worked on a nominated game."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The lead-up to this year's Game Awards hasn't been without complications. The developer of breakout indie </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Megabonk</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/megabonk-dev-withdraws-from-the-game-awards-over-unqualified-nomination">withdrew an award nomination</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for 'Best Debut Indie Game,' with the developer saying that he had made games in the past under different studio names, so </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Megabonk</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> didn't actually qualify as a debut game to him.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">More prominent is the case of the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-game-awards-confirms-its-future-class-program-will-remain-on-ice">Game Awards' Future Class</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> program, which served to champion and "represent the bright, bold, and inclusive future of video games." After two years in a row without the organization announcing a new cohort of industry professionals, Future Class organizer Emily Weir confirmed to Game Developer that the Game Awards isn't planning a new Future Class for this year, nor does the organization have "any active programming plans for Future Class."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/book-excerpt-online-community" target="_self" data-discover="true">Book Excerpt: Mastering Community Management: Chaos, Compassion, and Connections in Games</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Game Awards has also removed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://thegameawards.com/future-class">the Future Class page on its website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, eliminating the definitive record of previous honorees. Malek Teffaha, who was recognized by the group in 2022, told Game Developer that the news "honestly hurt."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I, among others, thought that the Future Class program was not just a platform for celebration, but a means to bridge the gap between industry workers and leaders and help shape the future of the game industry."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has contacted the Game Awards for clarification on the matter.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/report-the-game-awards-trailers-can-cost-devs-up-to-1-million]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Comcast cable boxes are getting Amazon Luna cloud gaming]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/842201/amazon-luna-comcast-xfinity-rogers-cable-boxes</link>
            <guid>1380019</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Amazon’s Luna cloud gaming service is coming to cable boxes from Comcast and Rogers. The Luna app is already available via web browsers, Fire TV devices, Fire tablets, and many smart TVs from Samsung and LG, and this new expansion will bring the service to “millions” more devices, <a href="https://www.amazongamestudios.com/en-us/news/articles/amazon-luna-on-xfinity-devices">according to Amazon</a>.</p><p>Starting Thursday, Luna will be available on “eligible” X1 and Xfinity Xumo Stream Box devices in the US and on the Rogers Xfinity Stream Box in Canada, Amazon says.</p><p>The expansion to Comcast’s and Rogers’ cable boxes follows Amazon’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/789658/amazon-luna-cloud-relaunch-gamenight-social-gaming">recent relaunch</a> of the service. A major aspect of the new Luna is “GameNight,” a collection of local multiplayer titles you can play using a smartphone as a controller — including one game from Amazon Game Studios starring an AI-powered <a href="https://luna.amazon.com/game/courtroom-chaos-starring-snoop-dogg/B0FR8SP73R">“Judge Snoop Dogg.”</a></p><p>Shortly after Amazon’s new Luna went live, Amazon announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/807825/amazon-job-layoffs-2025-ai">mass layoffs</a> and “significant” changes to its gaming division, including that it <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/808332/amazon-gaming-layoffs-mmo-aaa-first-party-games">would be ditching MMOs</a>.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/842201/amazon-luna-comcast-xfinity-rogers-cable-boxes]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[That Ugly Deus Ex Remaster Just Got Indefinitely Delayed]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/that-ugly-deus-ex-remaster-just-got-indefinitely-delayed-2000652654</link>
            <guid>1380010</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The previously announced <a href="https://kotaku.com/elon-musks-favorite-game-is-getting-remastered-25-years-later-2000628283"><em>Deus Ex Remastered</em></a> from Aspyr was set to launch in February of next year. It’s now been indefinitely delayed following a flood of complaints that the new version of the classic PC game looked ugly.</p> <p>During <a href="https://kotaku.com/state-of-play-playstation-5-sony-stream-youtube-twitch-2000628258#:~:text=One%20of%20the,on%20February%205.">Sony’s State of Play event in September</a>, Aspyr revealed <em>Deus Ex Remastered</em>, an “improved” and “better” looking version of the original, a beloved sci-fi immersive sim developed by Ion Storm and released in 2000. Almost immediately, the reaction online turned negative. <a href="https://kotaku.com/deus-ex-remastered-trailer-ugly-bad-comparison-ps5-pc-mods-nightdive-2000628799">People, myself included, weren’t happy about all the textures being replaced</a> with newer, higher-resolution assets. These didn’t mesh well with the old models and geometry that was still left in the game, creating a bizarre effect where it looked even worse than the chunky but charming visuals of the original game.</p> <p>Now, the remaster has been delayed, likely in an attempt to improve how it looks. On December 11, Aspyr announced that it wouldn’t move ahead with releasing <em>Deus Ex Remastered</em> in early 2026, <a href="https://x.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170679116087572?">posting on X</a>:</p> <blockquote><p>Thank you to the community for your feedback following the reveal of <em>Deus Ex Remastered. </em>We’ve listened to what you said, and in order to better meet fan expectations and deliver the best possible experience for players,<em> Deus Ex Remastered</em> will no longer launch on Feb. 5, 2026.</p></blockquote> <p>Asypry didn’t provide a new release date or window. The studio behind other remasters, <a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-bounty-hunter-remaster-review-is-it-good-ps5-1851610382">like 2024’s </a><em><a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-bounty-hunter-remaster-review-is-it-good-ps5-1851610382">Star Wars Bounty Hunter</a>,</em> confirmed all pre-orders would be refunded, which seems to imply the delay won’t be a short one.&nbsp; Aspyr says it looks “forward to sharing more updates” with fans “when the time comes.”</p> <p>Based on how many people didn’t like the trailer and were disappointed with <em>Deus Ex Remastered</em>‘s visuals, I think very few people are going to be upset about this delay. Hopefully, when/if <em>Deus Ex Remastered</em> sees the light of day again, it looks more like the original and less like a bad fan-created Unreal demo.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/that-ugly-deus-ex-remaster-just-got-indefinitely-delayed-2000652654]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deus Ex Remastered Has Been Delayed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/deus-ex-remastered-has-been-delayed/</link>
            <guid>1380007</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a recent update, Aspyr has confirmed that the upcoming Deus Ex Remastered has been delayed. Originally scheduled to launch on February 6, 2026, the highly anticipated remaster has now been pushed back indefinitely.</p>



<p>The original <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-new-deus-ex-game-pitched-by-eidos-montreal/">Deus Ex</a>, released in 2000, is widely regarded as an incredibly important title in gaming history. Its blend of action, espionage, and non-linear level design helped define the immersive sim genre—and fans were eager to experience the revamped version. Now, it seems they’ll have to wait a while longer.</p>







<h2 id="h-aspyr-announces-deus-ex-remastered-has-been-delayed">Aspyr Announces Deus Ex Remastered Has Been Delayed</h2>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thank you to the community for your feedback following the reveal of Deus Ex Remastered. We've listened to what you said, and in order to better meet fan expectations and deliver the best possible experience for players, Deus Ex Remastered will no longer launch on Feb. 5, 2026. <a href="https://t.co/NhalyPLm8q">pic.twitter.com/NhalyPLm8q</a></p>— Aspyr (@AspyrMedia) <a href="https://twitter.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170679116087572?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 11, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>In the public statement shown above, Aspyr officially confirmed the delay. According to the studio, the decision was made in response to community feedback, with the team wanting additional time to “better meet fan expectations and deliver the best possible experience for players.”</p>







<p>The announcement didn’t include a revised release date, offering only that the studio will “share more updates when the time comes.” With the original launch only months away, players will be hoping the project isn’t set for an extended setback.</p>



<p>Adding to the uncertainty, though, Aspyr also revealed that all existing preorders will be fully refunded. It’s a move that has left some fans questioning the remaster’s current state, as well as what the long-term future of the project might look like. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/embracer-cancels-deus-ex-game-lays-off-eidos-montreal-staff/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deus Ex as a franchise can’t seem to catch a break</a>, and the misery doesn’t seem to be stopping any time soon.</p>



<p>Were you looking forward to Deus Ex Remastered? Share your thoughts on the delay in the official <a href="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming content, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ai-game-playable-demo-codex-mortis/">world’s first fully-playable, AI-made game</a>, as well as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sandfall-reveals-budget-clair-obscur-expedition-33/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">budget for Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/deus-ex-remastered-has-been-delayed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lords of the Fallen version 2.5 update now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/lords-of-the-fallen-version-2-5-update-now-available</link>
            <guid>1380004</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Deadlier boss battles, "Veteran Mode" difficulty setting, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > CI Games [73 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ci-games">CI Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Hexworks [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ci-games/hexworks">Hexworks</a> have released the version 2.5 update for Soulslike <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,887 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Lords of the Fallen (2023) [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lords-of-the-fallen-2023">Lords of the Fallen</a></em>, which adds deadlier boss battles, a new “Veteran Mode” difficulty setting, and more. <span id="more-1013696"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the update, via CI Games:</p><blockquote><p>Following over 70 post-launch updates shaped by millions of players, <em>Lords of the Fallen</em> version 2.5 delivers the FINAL major update for the dark fantasy action RPG. Available now and free for all owners, version 2.5 adds significantly deadlier boss battles and enemies, an all-new Veteran difficulty mode, new boss weapon animations, a new armor set, and more!</p><ul><li><strong>Deadlier Bosses and Enemies</strong> – Across both Legacy and Veteran modes, bosses, mini-bosses, and regular foes have been reworked with refined combos, improved AI, faster recovery, and increased aggression for a more challenging Soulslike experience.</li><li><strong>Veteran Mode: The Ultimate Challenge</strong> – Face a far deadlier trial designed for players who have mastered Mournstead with the new Veteran Mode difficulty setting. Faster transitions, new attack patterns, and heightened aggression transform familiar encounters into unpredictable battles.</li><li><strong>Boss Weapons Reforged</strong> – Several iconic boss weapons now feature brand-new signature attack animations, adding fresh depth, impact, and identity to these coveted tools of war.</li><li><strong>New Armor Set</strong> – Conquer Veteran Mode to earn the Veteran of the Veil warplate, a high-end armor set featuring a unique passive that boosts item drop rates.</li></ul><p>Version 2.5 stands as the definitive final update for <em>Lords of the Fallen</em>. Forged through community feedback and refined through countless battles, it is our last gift to the crusaders who have walked with us through light and shadow.</p></blockquote><p><em>Lords of the Fallen</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,023 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,429 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,051 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1501750/The_Lords_of_the_Fallen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/lords-of-the-fallen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Version 2.5 Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Lords of the Fallen - VERSION 2.5 (Deadlier Boss Battles, All-New Veteran Mode) | PC, PS5, Xbox X|S" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BUTsB_cuDYA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/lords-of-the-fallen-version-2-5-update-now-available]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hades 2 Dev Shares Adorable GOTY Nominee Artwork Ahead Of The Game Awards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/hades-2-dev-shares-adorable-goty-nominee-artwork-ahead-of-the-game-awards</link>
            <guid>1379968</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Now that's sweet</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="a06dccc32ec29"><a title="The Game Awards - Supergiant GOTY Art" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a06dccc32ec29/the-game-awards-supergiant-goty-art.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/supergiantgames.bsky.social/post/3m7pwj3j26k2k">Supergiant Games</a></em></figcaption></figure><p>We are mere hours away from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/the-game-awards-2025-time-date-and-how-to-watch">The Game Awards 2025</a>, where we'll finally learn which of this year's nominees will walk away with the coveted GOTY trophy.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hades_ii">Hades II</a> is one of the six games up for the grand prize, and before the ceremony can get underway, developer Supergiant Games has shared a heartwarming piece of artwork, congratulating its fellow nominees.</p>
<p>The art depicts the main character from each of the six games (<a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/clair_obscur_expedition_33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hollow_knight_silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>, <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/death_stranding_2_on_the_beach">Death Stranding 2</a>, <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/kingdom_come_deliverance_ii">Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</a> and, of course, Hades II) dressed in their finest award ceremony attire and gracing the red carpet. We're particularly enamoured by the tiny little Hornet sitting on DK's shoulder — just look at those guys!</p><div><figure data-videoid="JmOlmniuSog" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JmOlmniuSog?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytJmOlmniuSog" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JmOlmniuSog?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JmOlmniuSog?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed624b7cqiknrj&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>"We’re deeply honored that HADES II is in the running for Game of the Year and more at #TheGameAwards tonight," the Supergiant message accompanying the art reads, "especially since we’re in the company of such an amazing group of wildly different and beautiful games. Congratulations to all our fellow nominees — we salute you!!"</p>

<p>Clair Obscur is the big favourite to take home the grand prize tonight (and every other award, it seems), but we'd be happy to see just about any finalist walk away with the win. Bananza is also nominated in the Best Family Game category alongside <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>.</p>
<p>You'll find everything you need to know about tonight's ceremony — including how to watch and the full list of nominees — in our <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/the-game-awards-2025-time-date-and-how-to-watch">The Game Awards 2025 guide</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:194739,195142 @ 1765479631 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this cute Hades art? Will you be watching along tonight? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://bsky.app/profile/supergiantgames.bsky.social/post/3m7pwj3j26k2k" rel="noopener" href="https://bsky.app/profile/supergiantgames.bsky.social/post/3m7pwj3j26k2k">bsky.app</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/bb40127fc0ad902c234d5cdff734458b @ 1765481872 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/hades-2-dev-shares-adorable-goty-nominee-artwork-ahead-of-the-game-awards]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aethermancer Early Access Review – When creature collecting goes rogue]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/11/aethermancer-early-access-review-when-creature-collecting-goes-rogue/</link>
            <guid>1379965</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Creature collecting games are becoming more and more common, but while many of them follow a similar format, Aethermancer aims to be a bit different by adding a roguelite element to it. There is no permanent party you can fall back on, with the game built to make you experiment with what is to hand.</p>
<p><iframe title="Aethermancer | Official Early Access Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mw47bWzgjCI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Aethermancer casts you in the role of an aethermancer named Siriux, who has taken it upon himself to dive into the Void, a vast growing disaster that is swallowing the world. Within the Void are different biomes in which various creatures roam, creatures that you can use to help navigate the dangers of this world. In the early access build of Aethermancer there are three biomes to discover, with each one having different paths you can choose to follow and native creatures that you can add to your collection. Within each zone of a biome you will find battles to win, allies that will provide assistance, and various points of interest that can provide boosts and boons at a cost.</p>


<p>Aethermancer’s gameplay has you start a run with one starter creature, and you can gather a maximum of two other creatures to create your battle party. If you lose a creature in battle, that specific creature is gone for that run, and losing if all of your creatures are defeated the run ends. However the start of each zone features a rebirth station where you can bring back the souls of fallen creatures from the dead to help you, letting you change up your party at the same time.&nbsp;What I like about this system is that you are not punished for trying to experiment. A creature that is swapped in is levelled up to match the rest of your party, allowing you to unlock moves and traits that could complement the whole group.</p>


<p>Each creature has moves and traits that can help buff or heal the whole party, or cast debuffs on enemy groups like poisoning or burning them. As you battle, you start figuring out which creature traits work well together, along with moves and items that can be equipped. For example, on one run I managed to create a group that could deal and trigger poison damage each turn while also providing heal and regeneration through each battle round. This party was nigh unstoppable and only fell at the final hurdle of the boss after the end of the third biome.</p>
<p>Aethermancer’s battle system is really fun to experiment with, though I have only tried a few different combos due to which creatures I have had at my disposal. As you make progress through the game you do unlock more, but there is a limit to how often you can swap out creatures or which ones you can use. Earlier I mentioned costs for bonuses and boons. One of those costs can be a monster soul, and if you spend that soul you will not be able to rebirth it on your run to add to your party. You will have no idea which soul has been spent until the next time you choose to change your party. </p>

<p>Finding a great party parity is essential for survival. As you battle and venture through the void, your creatures are at risk of getting Corrupted. The value of Corruption is taken away from a creature’s starting health, so being able to heal that damage at the start of a battle is essential. It seems that Aethermancer will let you build a solid team, but still make sure you do not get too powerful so that there is never a challenge.</p>
<p>When a run ends, you will find yourself in Pilgrim’s Rest which is a location so far untouched by the Void. Here you will find different people that can offer permanent bonuses and upgrades to use on future runs. That can include starting a run with more gold, or soulbonding with a creature so you can use it as a starter. It also a place where you can learn a bit more about the characters you end up rescuing from the Void, and I do wonder what else Pilgrim’s Rest will have to offer when Aethermancer exits early access.</p>

<p>So far, Aethermancer is proving to be a fun roguelike that seems to have a lot of potential depth to it, essentially forcing you to experiment with different party members to find different ways in which they can support each other in battle. I am looking forward to what will come next for the game, and anyone who enjoys roguelikes, creature collecting and battling should be keeping an eye on Aethermancer too.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/11/aethermancer-early-access-review-when-creature-collecting-goes-rogue/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best And Worst Moments In Game Awards History]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/game-awards-oscars-flute-kojima-ninja-muppets-drdisrespect-2000652237</link>
            <guid>1379956</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>As <a href="https://kotaku.com/game-awards-2025-goty-nominees-categories-clair-obscur-2000644825">The Game Awards enters its 12th year</a>, it’s worth looking back on some of the highs and lows from TGAs past. Out of the ashes of the Spike VGAs, creator and host Geoff Keighley created an annual gaming staple that highlights some of the <a href="https://kotaku.com/game-awards-geoff-keighley-tickets-trailers-clair-obscur-2000652243">biggest and best games for millions watching from home</a>. It honors creators and brands, seeking to elevate the craft and art of games while also leaving room for giant walking razor blade sponsorships. Here are 17 of the best and worst Game Awards moments going back to 2014.</p> <h2>“Fuck The Oscars!” – The Game Awards 2017</h2>  <p>Any list of iconic or famous Game Awards moments must legally include what is arguably the show’s most well-known clip: That time <em>Split Ficition</em> and<em> It Takes Two</em> director Josef Fares took control of the show for a few minutes and yelled “Fuck the Oscars!” in front of a visibly confused Geoff. Great stuff. – Zack Zwiezen</p>

 <h2><em>Ark 2</em> starring Vin Diesel is announced – The Game Awards 2020</h2>  <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/vin-diesel-is-fighting-dinosaurs-in-ark-2-1845856293">It was funny when Wildcard Studios announced an <em>Ark</em> sequel</a> despite many fans at the time feeling the original game needed more updates. It was even funnier when Vin Diesel appeared in the trailer. And it’s really, really funny that five years later, the game appears to be vaporware and has yet to launch. <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/survival/almost-5-years-since-its-reveal-ark-2-devs-admit-the-survival-sequel-was-put-on-hold-a-couple-of-years-ago-but-theyre-hopeful-it-could-release-in-early-access-within-the-next-2-years/">But it might finally see the light of day in 2027.</a> – Zack Zwiezen</p>

 <h2>The leaders of the three console companies share a stage – The Game Awards 2018</h2>  <p>The Game Awards foreshadowed the end of the console wars when Nintendo’s Reggie Fils-Aimé, Xbox’s Phil Spencer, and PlayStation’s Shawn Layden took the stage together at the 2018 ceremony to look beyond old marketing rivalries, exclusivity deals, and platform competition and praise gaming as a medium that transcends studio borders and corporate branding. Two of them are now retired and only Spencer remains at his post, currently overseeing the implementation of a similar philosophy as Microsoft goes multiplatform. – Ethan Gach</p>

 <h2>DrDisrespect wins the Trending Gamer award – The Game Awards 2017</h2>  <p>Herschel “Dr Disrespect” Beahm was crowned the biggest gamer of 2017 back when the Game Awards and the traditional gaming industry was still much more intertwined with the growing creator economy on YouTube and Twitch. Little did we all know that this was the same year in which Beahm would later <a href="https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-sexting-twitch-ban-youtube-elden-ring-1851556854">admit to having had</a> “casual, mutual conversations that sometimes leaned too much in the direction of being inappropriate” with a female minor. He was later banned from Twitch over it, even though the full incident wouldn’t come to light until 2024. Presciently, the Game Awards never did another Trending Gamer prize again. – Ethan Gach</p>

 <h2>Ken &amp; Roberta Williams win the first Industry Icons Award – The Game Awards 2014</h2>  <p>The very first Game Awards in 2014 was an overly long and very boring show. But even I had to smile when Ken and Roberta Williams, two very important video game pioneers, were given the Industry Icon award. This show should have tons of these kinds of moments; alas, these segments that truly celebrate creators and games are still far too rare. – Zack Zwiezen</p>

 <h2>Ninja showing up – The Game Awards 2018</h2>  <p>In an attempt to professionalize the category, the Game Awards shifted from 2017’s Trending Gamer to “Content Creator of the Year.” While Richard “Ninja” Blevins would go on to win it in 2018, he also just appeared during the show at the height of his electric-blue-haired popularity for a bit with a Muppet that may have been one of the least funny bits to ever appear during the show’s decade-plus run. Ninja may have had the charisma of a plastic “forkknife” but the writers did him no favors here. – Ethan Gach</p>

 <h2>Flute Guy – The Game Awards 2022</h2>  <p>Live concerts have always been a staple of the Game Awards, but they’ve gotten much better with the move away from <em>Rock Band</em>-like cameos and toward orchestral arrangements of actual video game music. No one embodies that more than Venezuelan flautist Pedro Eustache, who became a viral sensation for his passionate and expressive performances across a variety of different instruments at the 2022 show, especially during the <em>Xenoblade Chronicles 3</em> segment. He’s so good <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4sb27LA2n8w">they keep bringing him back</a>. – Ethan Gach</p> <h2><em>Rock Band VR</em> announcement trailer – The Game Awards 2015</h2>  <p>I’m not sure why <em>Rock Band VR</em> was even created or why it was given such a lengthy spotlight at the Game Awards. And perhaps the worst part is that if you watched the show live or were there in person, you had to look at Palmer Luckey’s feet. The VR wunderkind is now a <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/tech-ceo-shares-how-he-early-supporter-trump-running-president-before-his-2016-campaign">right-wing</a> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/palmer-luckey-ai-powered-autonomous-weapons-future-of-warfare-60-minutes-transcript/">AI weapons dealer</a>, and it makes this already hard-to-watch segment even more unbearable. – Zack Zwiezen</p> <h2>Waldorf and Statler dunk on the event – The Game Awards 2024</h2>  <p>Yes, it’s a bit odd how often Geoff invites Muppets to the Game Awards. But whatever, I don’t care because it means Statler and Waldorf got to occasionally appear and make fun of the show, Geoff, and everything else. It was wonderful. Truly inspired. – Zack Zwiezen</p>

 <h2>Schick Hyrdobot takes it to the next level – The Game Awards 2016</h2>  <p>The early days of the Game Awards are filled with some truly bizarre sponsorship moments and deals. Geoff needed help funding this thing and seemed willing to take any deal he was offered. That is likely how we ended up with Schick Hyrdobot, a horrific razor-robot-man hybrid that appeared periodically throughout the&nbsp; 2016 event. – Zack Zwiezen</p> <h2>Fans boo Konami – The Game Awards 2015</h2>  <p>Number one Keighley best friend Hideo Kojima was not allowed to attend the 2015 show. In an uncharacteristically candid segment, Geoff outlined that Konami’s lawyers were specifically prohibiting the <em>Metal Gear Solid V: The Phantom Pain</em> director from attending despite the game being nominated. “It’s unfathomable to me,” the host said. As the audience booed the publisher, the show commemorated the absence with a special performance of “Quiet Steam” from the game. – Ethan Gach</p>

 <h2>Cutting the GOTY speech short – The Game Awards 2023</h2>  <p>Larian Studios took home the top prize for <em>Baldur’s Gate 3 </em>at the 2023 show but director Swen Vincke only had 60 seconds to speedrun through the team’s acceptance speech. Things were made even worse by a “<a href="https://twitter.com/javierabegazo/status/1732975428237934964?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1732975428237934964%7Ctwgr%5Ef68fd0afd04e064cfcb2ee0dbe53a48fa90d90b0%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fkotaku.com%2Fbaldur-s-gate-3-game-awards-2023-goty-speech-1851099039">wrap it up</a>” sign that happened to flash right when he was mentioning the colleagues that had been lost along the way during development. Fortunately, the studio head shared <a href="https://kotaku.com/baldur-s-gate-3-game-awards-2023-goty-speech-1851099039">his full speech online</a> after the show, and went on to have one of the best monologues at the following year’s show, in which he predicted <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> <a href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-game-awards-goty-larian-1851780699">potentially sweeping this year’s awards</a>. – Ethan Gach</p> <h2>Nintendo’s Reggie Fils-Aime remembers Iwata – The Game Awards 2015</h2>  <p>As mentioned already, it’s rare that the Game Awards takes a moment to truly slow down and let someone be human. That makes this moment in 2015 when Geoff and then-Nintendo of America boss Reggie Fils-Aimé eulogized and honored the recently passed Satuoru Iwata, all the more special. Geoff literally says that for the next few minutes he’s putting away the trailers, the awards, and the marketing, and seems truly affected by Iwata’s death. Turns out you don’t need big flashy trailers to create a memorable moment. Just some heart. – Zack Zwiezen</p> <h2>Michelle Rodriguez and Vin Diesel end the show awkwardly – The Game Awards 2019</h2>  <p>I think the 2019 Game Awards have the worst and strangest ending in the show’s history. It starts with Michelle Rodriguez revealing the last game of the show, a crappy <em>Fast and Furious</em> game that looked terrible, and evolves into an awkward back-and-forth between her and Vin Diesel about the next <em>F&amp;F</em> movie and video games. It’s rough stuff. Worse, the two were then involved in <a href="https://youtu.be/UOmdhofNzDM">handing out the final award of the night to the Game of the Year winner.</a> Yikes! – Zack Zwiezen</p>

 <h2>Christopher Judge wins and gives a nine-minute speech – The Game Awards 2022</h2>  <p>There’s no <em>God of War</em> reboot without Christopher Judge, and the <em>Stargate</em> veteran went on to win “Best Performance” for <em>Ragnarök</em> in 2022. He gave what must be the longest speech in Game Awards history. It was personal, emotional, and so drawn out that Keighley spent the next few years rushing winners off the stage after 30 seconds to stop the show from going too late into the night. But he earned it after punctuating the 2018 show with the best three words anyone spoke onstage that night: “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uxgaD_0LboI">Read it, boy</a>.” – Ethan Gach</p> <h2>Bill Clinton kid crashes the stage – The Game Awards 2022</h2>  <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/game-awards-2022-bill-clinton-infowars-blizzcon-troll-1849877331">Small-time online troll</a> Matan Even snuck on stage at the end of the 2022 ceremony when <em>Elden Ring</em> was crowned Game of the Year. It was confusing and absurd. “I want to nominate this award to my reformed Orthodox Rabbi Bill Clinton,” he said after speeches from the actual developers. The incident’s legacy as the most “this thing is happening live” moment in TGA history was only trumped by just how dumb it turned out to be. Keighley has tightened security in the years since. – Ethan Gach</p> <h2><em>Alan Wake 2</em> dance – The Game Awards 2023</h2>  <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-ii-2-herald-of-darkness-music-video-musical-1851024833">Recreating the best moment from </a><em><a href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-ii-2-herald-of-darkness-music-video-musical-1851024833">Alan Wake 2</a>,</em> one of the best games of 2023, live on stage was such a brilliant and fun idea that I almost believe Geoff wasn’t involved in that meeting. However this came about, I don’t care, because the end result is <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-game-awards-alan-wake-2-herald-of-darkness-1851085691">arguably the most joyful moment in the history of the Game Awards</a>. More of this and honoring creators, and less random celebrities and bad jokes, please! – Zack Zwiezen</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/game-awards-oscars-flute-kojima-ninja-muppets-drdisrespect-2000652237]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prediction Market Gamblers Can’t Believe They Just Lost A $20 Million Bet On A Technicality]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/time-person-of-the-year-ai-musk-altman-kalshi-bet-lost-millions-angry-2000652622</link>
            <guid>1379953</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Time Magazine</em> revealed its Person of the Year for 2025. It wasn’t one person, but many different people who are all at the helm of pushing AI technology. This has caused some prediction market gamblers who had bet on AI itself earning the distinction to start yelling a lot online. It’s very funny, but also a horrible glimpse at our bet-on-everything future.</p> <p>On December 11, <a href="https://time.com/7339685/person-of-the-year-2025-ai-architects/"><em>Time Magazine</em> revealed its annual Person of the Year cover</a>. The long-running magazine, whose readership at this point is made up mostly of bored people in waiting rooms, revealed that there wasn’t just one person of the year in 2025, but seven different individuals. <em>Time Magazine</em> refers to these people as the “Architects of AI,” and they include names like Elon Musk, Nvidia’s Jensen Huang, and OpenAI boss Sam Altman. Normally, I’d think about who <em>Time</em> picked as the Person of the Year for about 10 seconds and then move on with my life. But this time, who they picked, and the <a href="https://time.com/7339703/ai-architects-person-of-the-year-2025/">use of two different covers,</a> have caused chaos among people who love to bet on everything.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">2025 was the year when artificial intelligence’s full potential roared into view, and when it became clear that there will be no turning back.</p> <p>For delivering the age of thinking machines, for wowing and worrying humanity, for transforming the present and transcending the… <a href="https://t.co/mEIKRiZfLo">pic.twitter.com/mEIKRiZfLo</a></p> <p>— TIME (@TIME) <a href="https://twitter.com/TIME/status/1999097617633189955?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 11, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>On the prediction market website Kalshi, <a href="https://kalshi.com/markets/kxtime/times-person-of-the-year/kxtime-25">nearly $20 million worth of betting</a> happened over who would be <em>Time</em>‘s Person of the Year. One popular option that many bet on was AI. So when Kalshi called the bet and listed the specific people the magazine had named as the “Architects of AI” as the winners, but not AI itself, a lot of people were angry. They believed that AI was also the winner as it was named directly. Making things more confusing, <em>Time Magazine</em> ran two covers for the Person of the Year issue this year, one featuring the architects, with the other featuring “AI” in massive letters, though the words “The Architects of AI” are still present in the cover’s corner. Still, this cover is more evidence, according to those who bet on AI, that it, too, should be considered a winning outcome in one of the site’s biggest bets of the year.</p>

 <p>“ITS THE ARCHITECTS OF AI THISNIS LITTERALY THE BET FUCK KALSHI,” <a href="https://kalshi.com/ideas/posts/9914a9da-54dc-4447-b104-825713e9dff4">posted one angry gambler</a> who bet on AI and lost. “This is actually so freaking stupid,” said <a href="https://kalshi.com/ideas/posts/0deb1354-478d-4bca-8538-c6e4ce282413">another user</a>.</p> <p>“This pretty clearly should’ve resolved to yes,” <a href="https://kalshi.com/ideas/posts/601174f7-f82e-484a-8955-e3e68fd75032">said another upset AI better</a>. “If you bought AI, reach out to Kalshi support because ‘AI’ is literally on the cover and in the title, ‘Architects of AI.’ They’re not going to change anything unless they hear from people.”</p>

 <p>“The cover literally says ‘AI” right on the front. This is insane,” <a href="https://kalshi.com/ideas/posts/151a0fb2-e8ef-4964-96ed-5627f7cf1820">said another upset gambler.</a> “fr bro we got screwed,” replied someone else.</p> <p>While I am definitely laughing at how many people lost money betting on <em>Time</em>‘s Person of the Year, I’m also aware that this is our future. This bet-on-everything shit is growing quickly. Sites like Kalshi and Polymarket are letting people gamble on literally anything. And this is just the start. <a href="https://kotaku.com/finance-bro-thinks-it-would-be-cool-to-turn-your-entire-life-into-the-stock-market-2000650201">The CEO of Kalshi recently explained</a> that he wants to “financialize everything and create a tradable asset out of any difference of opinion.” In other words, every part of our humanity<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->what we love, believe in, cherish, hope for, fear, etc.<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->in the near future will be something to bet on. That’s only going to make it easier for the <a href="https://pausebeforeyouplay.org/2025/06/online-gambling-is-likely-on-the-rise-at-a-high-school-near-you/">growing number of young people addicted to online gambling</a> to lose even more money. <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/volodymyr-zelensky-suit-polymarket-rebellion/">And the arbiters of how these bets are settled and who wins will be tech bros</a>.</p> <p>Good luck, everyone. I place our odds of making it through the AI-powered online gambling future ahead of us pretty low. I’m not taking that bet.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/time-person-of-the-year-ai-musk-altman-kalshi-bet-lost-millions-angry-2000652622]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deus Ex Remastered delayed to unannounced date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/deus-ex-remastered-delayed-to-unannounced-date</link>
            <guid>1379947</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>No longer due out on February 5, 2026.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Aspyr [48 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/saber-interactive/aspyr">Aspyr</a> has <a href="https://twitter.com/AspyrMedia/status/1999170679116087572" target="_blank">delayed</a> cyberpunk immersive <a title="Genres > Simulation [898 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> remake <em><a title="Games > Deus Ex Remastered [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/deus-ex-remastered">Deus Ex Remastered</a></em> from its <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/deus-ex-remastered-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc">previously planned</a> February 5, 2026 release date to an unannounced date. It will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,023 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,429 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,094 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,051 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3131640/Deus_Ex_Remastered/" target="_blank">Steam</a> when it launches. <span id="more-1014032"></span></p><p>Here is the full message from Aspyr on the delay:</p><blockquote><p>Thank you to the community for your feedback following the reveal of <em>Deus Ex Remastered</em>.</p><p>We’ve listened to what you had to say, and in order to better meet fan expectations and deliver the best possible experience for players, Deus Ex Remastered will no longer launch on February 5, 2026.</p><p>We look forward to sharing more updates with you when the time comes.</p><p>All existing preorders will be fully refunded. Thank you again for your patience and support.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/deus-ex-remastered-delayed-to-unannounced-date]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Clues May Be Hidden In GTA Online's Big New Update, Fans Think]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-clues-may-be-hidden-in-gta-onlines-big-new-update-fans-think/1100-6536887/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1379944</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536887">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The recent <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-onlines-big-new-update-with-michael-dlc-mission-is-out-now-see-the-full-patch-notes/1100-6536845/" data-ref-id="1100-6536845">A Safehouse in the Hills</a> update for GTA Online may contain clues about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto VI</a>, or at least that's what the franchise's passionate fanbase is theorizing based on some recent discoveries.</p><p>After the big new update went live on December 10, people dug into the game's code in search of anything that might provide clues about GTA 6, and people think they found some. A <a href="https://x.com/GTAVI_Countdown/status/1999140552722280655" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">line of text that was discovered</a> references a voice line for the character Jimmy, the son of main character Michael, that says he is "moving out of state." Another line, from his mother Amanda, says, "Our son is finally moving away from home." People are taking this to suggest that Jimmy may have moved to Leonida, the stand-in for GTA 6's setting of Florida, but that's just conjecture for now.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1997041777" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466571,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;GTA%20Online%3A%20A%20Safehouse%20In%20The%20Hills%20-%20Update%20Launch%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:60,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/gta-online-a-safehouse-in-the-hills-update-launch-trailer\/2300-6466571\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466571\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466571\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466571\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466571&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466571,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536887&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;grand-theft-auto-vi,grand-theft-auto-v&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,playstation-3,xbox-360,playstation-4,xbox-one,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;rockstar-games&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;grand-theft-auto&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;grand-theft-auto&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466571},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466571\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4620329-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/efXur20B.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1765379220,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="efXur20B" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> GTA Online: A Safehouse In The Hills - Update Launch Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Dataminers also discovered that the <a href="https://gta.fandom.com/wiki/KnoWay" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">KnoWay</a> autonomous driving company that was added to GTA Online in the new update was formerly known as <a href="https://gta.fandom.com/wiki/Sahara" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sahara</a>. That is the name of a delivery and logistics company for GTA 6, as seen in previously released GTA 6 screenshots. The dataminer, Tex2, theorized that Rockstar might have at one point planned a Part 2 for the A Safehouse in the Hills expansion to be timed with GTA 6's previous release date of May 2026 prior to the game's delay to November 2026.</p><p>With Rockstar providing so little concrete information about GTA 6, people have been hunting for years for any morsels of possible clues about GTA 6, and this is just the latest example. The game's first trailer was released two years ago this month. A second trailer arrived in May 2025, but the company has said said anything more about the game since then, apart from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-delayed-to-november-2026/1100-6536012/" data-ref-id="1100-6536012">confirming the delay to November 2026 in early November.</a></p><p>Rockstar said it delayed GTA 6 yet again as part of an effort to ensure the game is up to the company's high quality standards.</p><p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/grand-theft-auto-vi-delayed-again" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Game Business</a>, Take-Two boss Strauss Zelnick said, "When we set a date, we really do believe in it. We said when we set the last date, if a game requires more polish to be the best possible version of itself, then we will give that game more time. And that's exactly what happened."</p><p>He added: "We feel really good about this release date. It's in the same fiscal year, it happens to be a great release window, and naturally we're really supportive of Rockstar's approach."</p><p>GTA 6 is coming to market with an enormous amount of hype behind it. One expert has said <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-is-most-important-game-release-in-industrys-history-analyst-says/1100-6521839/" data-ref-id="1100-6521839">GTA 6 is the single most important game release in history.</a> It's the first new entry in the series since 2013's GTA 5 and is predicted to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-5-could-make-3-billion-in-first-year-alone/1100-6528605/" data-ref-id="1100-6528605">sell more than 40 million units in its first year alone.</a></p><p>Another talking point regarding GTA 6 has been what its price point could be. One industry observer has said there is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-costing-as-much-as-100-could-help-video-game-industry-rebound-in-2025-analyst-says/1100-6528832/" data-ref-id="1100-6528832">"hope"</a> from some that GTA 6 would come to market at $100 to help give other publishers a reason to raise prices as well. A GTA 5 actor recently said GTA 6 would be <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-warrants-a-100-price-tag-gta-5-actor-says/1100-6535876/" data-ref-id="1100-6535876">well worth $100 given the game's size and scope.</a></p><p>Developer Rockstar has found itself embroiled in controversy, as the studio recently fired dozens of employees for what it called "gross misconduct." Rockstar said employees were <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-dev-says-it-fired-workers-for-leaking-secrets-not-for-trying-to-unionize/1100-6535987/" data-ref-id="1100-6535987">leaking company secrets</a>, but a labor union says this is baloney and that the affected staffers were fired for attempting to unionize. The UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer has said he will <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/united-kingdoms-ministers-will-look-into-rockstars-dev-firings-says-prime-minister/1100-6536840/" data-ref-id="1100-6536840">"look into" the firings.</a></p><p>For more on GTA Online's new update, you can <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-onlines-big-new-update-with-michael-dlc-mission-is-out-now-see-the-full-patch-notes/1100-6536845/" data-ref-id="1100-6536845">see the full patch notes</a> and read about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-start-the-michael-mission-in-gta-online-safehouse-in-the-hills-update/1100-6536842/" data-ref-id="1100-6536842">how to start the new mission starring Michael.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-clues-may-be-hidden-in-gta-onlines-big-new-update-fans-think/1100-6536887/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket's Upcoming Expansion Shows The OG Starters Some Love]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/pokemon-tcg-pockets-upcoming-expansion-shows-the-og-starters-some-love</link>
            <guid>1379926</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Mega!</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>The next expansion heading for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_trading_card_game_pocket">Pokémon Trading Card Game Pocket</a> has been revealed, and it has some very familiar faces front and centre.</p>
<p>The Crimson Blaze set launches on <strong>17th December</strong>, and sees Mega Charizard Y plastered across the packet cover. Naturally, new cards for Mega Venusaur and Mega Blastoise are included too, alongside new art for the Kanto starters and fresh card covers/backdrops.</p>
<p>The above trailer gives us a pretty good idea of what the set will have in store, but here's a closer look at a handful of the new cards:</p>


<p>The last set to arrive in the app was October's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/pokemon-tcg-pocket-lands-new-expansion-as-app-surpasses-150-million-downloads">Mega Rising expansion</a>, which ushered a new range of risky Mega Evolutions into the card battler. It'll be interesting to see how long these Mega cards stay in play as new sets keep rolling out in 2026.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:193321,188830 @ 1765480600 -->
<p><em>What do you make of the next TCG Pocket expansion? Will you be ripping some virtual packs next week? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/pokemon-tcg-pockets-upcoming-expansion-shows-the-og-starters-some-love]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Awards 2025 everything announced for PC so far – and a few rumours thrown in for good measure]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>1379923</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-game-awards-2025_6Jjp1rO.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-game-awards-2025_6Jjp1rO.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-game-awards-2025_6Jjp1rO.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-game-awards-2025_6Jjp1rO.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-game-awards-2025_6Jjp1rO.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-game-awards-2025_6Jjp1rO.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-game-awards-2025_6Jjp1rO.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-game-awards-2025_6Jjp1rO.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-game-awards-2025_6Jjp1rO.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>The Game Awards</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            
<p>Time is ticking down until Geoff Keighley once again emerges from his fleshy cocoon, brushes the Garibaldi crumbs from his suit, and strides onto the stage to bellow his customary challenge of "Who wants some?". We assume he means games, but one day he will nut a developer in the front row and we won't be able to say he didn't warn us.</p>
<p>We're pulling together a quick rundown of everything announced at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/the-game-awards-2025">The Game Awards 2025</a> so you don't need to risk life and limb by straying too close to Geoff's grasping fingers.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>If you're planning on staying up for the night, then a fine time shall be had by all who pull up a stool at James's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2025-livestream">The Game Awards 2025 liveblog</a>. If, however you'd rather not trade a good night's sleep for an early look at trailers, then head back here tomorrow morning for a full list of everything announced at the show.</p>
<p>For the games we find most intriguing, we will be writing fuller stories which I'll link out to below.</p>
<p>What's that? The Game Awards haven't started yet? You could have fooled me, what with all the…</p>
<h2>Confirmed games at The Game Awards 2025</h2>
<h3>Total War: Mystery</h3>
<p>Those cheeky so and sos over at Creative Assembly held a livestream last week, a right poke in the eye for ol' Geoff. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/creative-assembly-reveal-total-war-medieval-3-while-teasing-a-huge-game-reveal-to-follow">It's where they announced Total War: Medieval 3</a> (while also puncturing the excitement by saying it was still years from release). However, to salve Geoff's bloodshot eye, they also teased a big announcement for The Game Awards.</p><p>There have long been rumours of a Total War take on either Star Wars or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-40000-reveal-likely-after-telltale-words-40k-spotted-in-creative-assembly-video">Warhammer 40k</a>. That could well live up to Creative Assembly's promise that "this title will be Total War's next major release and represents one of the most ambitious projects in the franchise's history, marking the beginning of an exciting new era."</p>
<h3>Resident Evil Requiem</h3>
<p>First revealed at Summer Game Fest in June, Resident Evil Requiem is the ninth main game in the series. Capcom had insisted that it wouldn't star Leon and would instead focus on new character technical analyst Grace Ashcroft. However, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/leon-kennedys-in-resident-evil-requiem-playstation-store-cover-art-leak-confirms">a leaked cover from earlier this week</a> certainly appeared to show everyone's favourite cop-turned-super-soldier, suggesting that Capcom's pants are a-blazing.</p>
<h3>New Tomb Raider</h3>
<p>Like a Roman emperor tossing another prisoner to the lions in the colosseum, <a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/1998093056692895923">on Monday Geoff threw out a tweet teasing "a look at the future" for Tomb Raider</a>. Out in the world with all that hungry attention on it, someone quickly found the box art and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis-is-the-next-tomb-raider-reboot-project-going-by-alleged-trailer-leak">reveal trailer for Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</a>. The trailer was taken down, but reports from those that saw it say it looks like a reboot for the series.</p>
<p>Confirmed game news is all well and good, but what about the more salacious stuff? The grimy things no one wants to stand by ahead of the night? You know what I mean…</p>
<h2>The Game Awards 2025 rumours</h2>
<p>Well, one of the worst-kept secrets in gaming is the Assassin's Creed 4: Black Flag remake. It looks like it may be ready to eagle dive from the crow's nest with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-rated-by-pegi-as-the-siren-song-of-remake-sea-shanties-grows-deafening">a PEGI rating for Assassins's Creed Black Flag Resynced</a> spotted just the other day. Presumably it's too late to rename the project? Something a little less of a mouthful would be lovely.</p><p>Being a Keighley show, Hideo Kojima is often lurking in the wings. With a recent ESRB rating for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/death-stranding-2">Death Stranding 2</a>: On The Beach PC release, tonight could be the moment for an on-stage reveal. Maybe with some added director's cut gubbins thrown in?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> is likely to win big at the awards tonight, so it would also be the perfect time for the team to reveal their next project. Be it details of an expansion of a tease of something more.</p>
<p>Now, finally, as long as I've been a games journalist, I've been hearing rumours of the imminent reveal of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/half-life-3">Half-Life 3</a>. Once again, with the advent of the Steam Machine, Steam Frame, and new Steam Controller, there's been more buzz about Gordon Freeman once again picking up his crowbar. I want it to be true, but I have no reason to believe it is true. Nor that Valve would announce it anywhere other than their own show. That said, I'm not going to say I'll eat my hat if it's announced, because under everything I remain an optimist.</p>
<p>I'll be updating this post throughout the night and, if all goes to plan, when you wake up tomorrow it will be chock full of trailers and game reveals. If not, well, let us salute my attempt.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>