<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 13:52:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RailGods of Hysterra will be available on Steam Early Access from April 23rd]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/railgods-of-hysterra-will-be-available-on-steam-early-access-from-april-23rd/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/railgods-of-hysterra-will-be-available-on-steam-early-access-from-april-23rd.1145151/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/railgods-of-hysterra-will-be-available-on-steam-early-access-from-april-23rd/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Developer Troglobytes Games and publisher Digital Vortex Entertainment have confirmed that the Lovecraftian inspired survival action game RailGods of Hysterra will be available through Steam Early Access on April 23rd.</p>
<p><iframe title="RailGods of Hysterra - Early Access Date Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QlUQj4xMS3E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><em>“We at Troglobytes are thrilled to invite all players to get on board the RailGod and wander through the Lovecraftian world we crafted with so much love and passion! See you all in Hysterra, and remember: Ph’nglui mglw’nafh Cthulhu R’lyeh wgah’nagl fhtagn!”</em> said Saverio Caporusso, CEO and Lead Designer at Troglobytes Games.</p>
<p><em>“To fans of cosmic horror, survival games, and those who just love trains, we’re happy to shout ‘ALL ABOARD!’”</em> said Digital Vortex CEO and Co-Founder Alex Izotov. <em>“This is an adventure we’ve been working on for a long time, and your feedback will be instrumental in shaping RailGods of Hysterra into its final form.”</em></p>
<p>In RailGods of Hysterra players can ride the train, which is infused with a RailGod, solo or team up in groups of four as you explore a world in which the Old Gods have conquered. The train can be customised by adding additional cars that can be used as storage facilities and workbenches. As you venture into this nightmare world you will face monsters and cultists that you beat in battle, or capture them to feed to the RailGod. This is a twisted world after all and the RailGod wants something in return for acting as your transport.</p>

<p>After RailGods of Hysterra releases on Steam Early Access it will eventually make its way to PS5, though a release date is yet to be confirmed.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet Won’t Launch Before 2027, Says Schreier]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-wont-launch-before-2027-says-schreier/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-won%E2%80%99t-launch-before-2027-says-schreier.1145148/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-wont-launch-before-2027-says-schreier/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to Bloomberg's Jason Schreier, Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, the new sci-fi intellectual property in development at Naughty Dog, won't be released before 2027. The comment was prompted by CD Projekt RED's confirmation to investors that The Witcher IV <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-wont-launch-until-2027-says-cd-projekt-red/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wouldn't launch before the end of 2026</a>.</p>
<p>On the ResetEra forum, users recalled that Schreier had talked about both games (which were shown for the first time at The Game Awards 2024 in December) as being quite early in the development phase and relatively far from launch. Schreier himself then chimed in <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-studios-ot45-game-of-the-year-edition.1093518/post-137487981" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with a new post</a>:</p>
<p><em>I'm pretty sure I said they were both going to be very early teases. Neither of those games will be out next year.</em></p>
<p>Truthfully, while we didn't have any dates for Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, Game Director Neil Druckmann recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-is-a-game-about-faith-and-religion-where-players-will-feel-lonely-says-druckmann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hinted</a> that fans would have to wait quite some time:</p>
<p><em>We still have a ways to go, but I'm kind of very excited to see... Again, these things are so complex and big and there's so many people involved. It's like, I still don't know exactly what this thing's gonna look like at the end. It's like, I have a theory, I have an idea, but it's still evolving and changing as we are making it.</em></p>
<p>If Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet launched in 2027, it would be seven years since the launch of Naughty Dog's previous game, The Last of Us Part II. That's a very long time between releases, but it should be noted that Naughty Dog had nearly completed The Last of Us Online before deciding to <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-last-of-us-multiplayer-canceled-naughty-dog-live-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cancel it</a> after they realized (with Bungie's input) that the game's post-launch support would have absorbed much of the studio's efforts for years to come. It is quite likely that if The Last of Us Online was not canceled, Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet would have been postponed even further away.</p>
<p>Interestingly, The Witcher IV will also be the studio's next full game release after Cyberpunk 2077's late 2020 debut. CD Projekt RED did not cancel a game in between, but they were busy improving Cyberpunk 2077 and releasing the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty-shiny-firmware-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">excellent Phantom Liberty expansion</a>. Moreover, the studio has transitioned from its in-house RED Engine <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-next-game-announced-unreal-engine-5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to Unreal Engine 5</a>.</p>
<p>All this is to say there are reasons why these games are taking so long. Nonetheless, it's becoming apparent that the largest triple-A games can now take between five and seven years to complete, which makes it all the more challenging to invest in them, as failure would be catastrophic to a studio after spending so much time and resources.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gran Turismo 7 Update 1.57 Adds a Classic British Car and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gran-turismo-7-update-157</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gran-turismo-7-update-1-57-adds-a-classic-british-car-and-more.1145145/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gran-turismo-7-update-157<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony and Polyphony Digital will release a new update for&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>later today, and as ever, it's adding some new cars, one of which is a certified British classic.</p>

<p>Following on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gran-turismo-7-update-156" rel="nofollow">last month's Update 1.56</a>, the aptly-named Update 1.57's first major addition to&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>is the Aston Martin Vantage '18, which Sony says has been referred to as "the best Aston Martin ever". It's the 2018 version of a car that became its own model line back in 2005.</p>

<p>Your second new car in this update is the&nbsp;Mazda CX-30 X Smart Edition ‘21, a crossover SUV designed to marry the best parts of sports utility vehicles with the convenience and compact nature of regular civvie cars.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mazda-cx-30-x-smart-edition-21-gran-turismo-7-update-1.57.jpg?itok=VPLPHh-2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mazda-cx-30-x-smart-edition-21-gran-turismo-7-update-1.57.jpg?itok=lP86IOP4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>Update 1.57 has some new cars for you to try out.</figcaption></figure><p>Finally, you can also drive the&nbsp;Renault Kangoo 1.4 ‘01 in this update. It's a "popular leisure activity vehicle that started life as a commercial van", according to Sony. It's not a powerful machine, but it should get you from A to B, at least.</p>

<p>This being a&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>update, you can also look forward to new events in the World Circuits mode, as well as new Sophy AI enhancements and more. You can read everything that's new in this update <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/03/26/gran-turismo-7-update-1-57-available-today/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>In case you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7</em>, it's the latest entry in Sony's long-running&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo&nbsp;</em>series of racing games. Like its predecessors, the game is a "simcade" racer, which means it balances realistic simulation with arcade-style accessibility and ease of use.</p>




<p><em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>is also the only&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo&nbsp;</em>game it's currently possible to play without resorting to the second-hand market; last year, Sony delisted the PS4's&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo Sport&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gran-turismo-sport-delisted" rel="nofollow">without warning</a>, although it's still possible to play the offline portions of the game.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/gran-turismo-7/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>. Update 1.57 lands at 10pm Pacific tonight (that's 1am the following morning in Eastern time).</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If There Is No The Last of Us 3, Would Naughty Dog's Neil Druckmann Keep the TV Show Going Past the Games?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/if-there-is-no-the-last-of-us-3-would-naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-keep-the-tv-show-going-past-the-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/if-there-is-no-the-last-of-us-3-would-naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-keep-the-tv-show-going-past-the-games.1145142/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/if-there-is-no-the-last-of-us-3-would-naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-keep-the-tv-show-going-past-the-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"I leave nothing on the line."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Amid question marks about the future of The Last of Us video game series, fans are wondering where the story might go next after the HBO series Season 2 and 3 cover off the second video game. Earlier this month, series creator <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/neil-druckmann-says-dont-bet-on-there-being-a-the-last-of-us-part-3">Neil Druckmann cast doubt on the prospect of The Last of Us 3</a>, saying: “I guess the only thing I would say is don’t bet on there being more of ‘Last of Us.’ This could be it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But if there’s no The Last of Us 3, would Naughty Dog and Druckmann keep the TV show going past the games?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s the question IGN put to Druckmann himself on the red carpet ahead of The Last of Us Season 2 premiere, and he replied to say that while he has an ending of The Last of Us story in mind, because he’s not sure if he’ll get the chance to make The Last of Us 3, he’s leaving nothing on the line.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“I have to have an ending,” Druckmann said. “When I made The Last of Us 1, I didn’t know if there was going to be a sequel, so that had to be a definitive ending. When I worked on Uncharted 4, I don’t know if we’ll ever get to do it again. I need it to be a definitive ending. Last of Us 2, same way. All these things have to line up.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I don’t know how long I’ll keep doing this or whether I’ll be given another opportunity. So I leave nothing on the line.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Right now it’s like, we have an ending in mind. And that ending will be it. That ending will be it for this story.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One question hanging over Druckmann is if he will even have the time to make The Last of Us 3, were it to be green lit for production. That’s because he has his hands full with The Last of Us TV show, which is set to round-out the events of The Last of Us 2 video game with Season 2 and Season 3, and the recently announced PlayStation game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“As far as everything else, and you’re asking me about future games, my time so much is, we have to finish this season,” Druckmann continued. “We’re not quite done. We’re almost there. Knock on wood we get to do it again. Season 3, there’s a lot more story we have to cover, as you know with game two.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And then my hands are pretty full with Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Last of Us Season 2 Character Posters</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In February 2024, Druckmann teased a "concept" for a potential The Last of Us 3 at the end of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SC3C7GMMfDU&amp;ab_channel=NaughtyDog" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Grounded 2: Making The Last of Us Part 2</a>, noting that there's "probably one more chapter to this story."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The first game had such a clean concept of like, the unconditional love a parent feels for their child," he said. "The second one, once we landed on this idea of the pursuit of justice at any cost, justice for the ones you love, we felt like, 'there's a clean concept here and there's a throughline from the first game, about love.' If we never get to do it again, this is a fine ending point. Last bite of the apple, the story's done."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The great thing about working at Naughty Dog is that we don't have to," he added. "It's always like, 'we would love another Last of Us, but if you guys feel you're passionate about something else, we'll support this other thing.' Very privileged position to be in, I never take that for granted. I've been just thinking about it, 'is there a concept there?' And for now years, I haven't been able to find that concept. But recently, that's changed, and I don't have a story, but I do have that concept that to me is as exciting as 1, as exciting as 2, is its own thing, and yet has this throughline for all three. So it does feel like there's probably one more chapter to this story."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Restocks: Amazon Has Surging Sparks Booster Bundles in Stock Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-surging-sparks-booster-bundles-back-in-stock-amazon-spring-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-restocks-amazon-has-surging-sparks-booster-bundles-in-stock-right-now.1145139/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-surging-sparks-booster-bundles-back-in-stock-amazon-spring-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Plus more Pokémon TCG booster sets hanging on during the Spring Sale.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I wasn’t planning to buy more Pokémon cards this week. Then I saw that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-surging-sparks-is-the-best-scarlet-and-violet-set">Scarlet &amp; Violet – Surging Sparks Booster Bundle</a> was somehow <a href="https://zdcs.link/QpXEDw?object_uuid=97f4f848-ef36-4c95-a72e-88d7b7b771c5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">still in stock on Amazon for $45.02</a> following its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-finally-solves-pokemon-tcg-shortage">massive Pokémon TCG restock</a>. The restock has come at a great time, with the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025">Amazon Spring Sale</a> in full swing, there are plenty of hot sets to pick up while stock lasts. Suddenly, my willpower crumbled like a 60 HP Basic tackling a 390-damage Hydreigon ex. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">My favorite? This <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-surging-sparks-is-the-best-scarlet-and-violet-set">Surging Sparks</a> set is chaos in the best way. You’ve got chase cards that deserve to be slabbed, like the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QL5AlX?object_uuid=97f4f848-ef36-4c95-a72e-88d7b7b771c5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$432 Pikachu ex Special Illustration Rare</a>. That’s not a typo. The little electric mouse is putting in work as both a collectible and a monster in battle. Topaz Bolt deletes nearly anything from the board, and Resolute Heart makes it annoyingly hard to knock out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Then there’s the Latias ex and Latios combo, pulling a full-on romance movie moment with matching connected artwork. Latias is the rarer and, apparently, the more expensive twin at over $200. I guess big sibling energy costs more. Meanwhile, Milotic ex is out here channeling its inner supermodel with light and shadow drama, and somehow also counters Tera Pokémon like it moonlights as a meta card.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">My personal favorite? Ceruledge. It’s giving neon fever dreams, and I mean that as a compliment. This is the first time its card has actually been valuable, and I think illustrator Rond deserves a standing ovation. Or at least a coffee. Ceruledge isn’t even a top-tier Pokémon competitively, but with this art, I don’t care.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're a collector, the value potential is real. If you're a player, some of these cards slap on the battlefield. And if you just like shiny things and the thrill of gambling $45 on cardboard, welcome to the club. I already cracked one box and I’m convincing myself I “need” another for science.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The bundle includes six booster packs, so you’re not guaranteed any heavy hitters, but at the rate people are snapping these up, I wouldn't wait too long. Pikachu isn’t going to pull itself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Mar 26, 2025 11:29 am</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Witcher Dev Partners With Pokemon Go Owner For A New Game Based On Its IP]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/witcher-dev-partners-with-pokemon-go-owner-for-a-new-game-based-on-its-ip/1100-6530370/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/witcher-dev-partners-with-pokemon-go-owner-for-a-new-game-based-on-its-ip.1145136/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/witcher-dev-partners-with-pokemon-go-owner-for-a-new-game-based-on-its-ip/1100-6530370/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530370">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>CD Projekt has signed a deal to work with Pokemon Go owner Scopely to make a game based on one of the Polish company's franchises. CD Projekt made the announcement during its latest financial briefing, but didn't elaborate much on the deal.</p><p>Scopely, which is owned by Saudi Arabia's Savvy Games, is primarily a mobile game developer. Management was asked to share more details on this deal with Scopely during the earnings call, but declined to discuss the matter.</p><p>Scopely is one of the biggest mobile game companies on the planet, and recently entered a new stratosphere of success with Monopoly Go.</p><p>In March, Niantic sold its video game division, including Pokemon Go, to Scopely for $3.5 billion--this was the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/top-10-most-expensive-video-game-buyouts-of-all-time/2900-4718/#1" data-ref-id="2900-4718">No. 8 biggest gaming acquisition in history</a>. Before that, Savvy Games bought Scopely in 2023 for $4.9 billion--that was the No. 6 biggest gaming acquisition of all time.</p><p>In 2024, CD Projekt said it was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-and-witcher-mobile-games-could-come-in-the-future-cd-projekt-says/1100-6522276/" data-ref-id="1100-6522276">considering the possibility of making The Witcher and/or Cyberpunk mobile games.</a> The company does have experience with the mobile market, as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/gwent-the-witcher-card-game/" data-ref-id="5000-455324">Gwent: The Witcher Card Game</a> received mobile ports, though support for the title ended in October 2023. Another Witcher mobile game, the Pokemon Go-inspired <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-witcher-monster-slayer/" data-ref-id="5000-517724">The Witcher: Monster Slayer</a>, released in July 2021 but shut down nearly two years later in 2023.</p><p>As for CD Projekt's other upcoming projects, we just learned that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/witcher-4-release-date-is-not-soon-as-dev-discusses-why-it-wont-use-genai/1100-6530369/" data-ref-id="1100-6530369">The Witcher 4 is not going to release until 2027 at the soonest</a>. CD Projekt is also working on a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6526333/" data-ref-id="1100-6526333">Cyberpunk 2077 sequel </a>and a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-witcher-remake-everything-we-know-about-the-open-world-remake-of-the-classic-rpg/1100-6528839/" data-ref-id="1100-6528839">Witcher remake. </a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Of The Biggest Choices We've Agonized Over In Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/video-game-best-choices-decisions-mass-effect-witcher-3-1851772314</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/12-of-the-biggest-choices-weve-agonized-over-in-games.1145112/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/video-game-best-choices-decisions-mass-effect-witcher-3-1851772314<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="c07bf5c09561d259ac52f146256bd6fa" data-recommend-id="image://c07bf5c09561d259ac52f146256bd6fa" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shepard, Ashley, and Kaidan look out a window." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shepard, Ashley, and Kaidan look out a window." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->BioWare / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c07bf5c09561d259ac52f146256bd6fa" data-recommend-id="image://c07bf5c09561d259ac52f146256bd6fa" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shepard, Ashley, and Kaidan look out a window." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>One of the best things video games can do is let us have ownership over the stories we play through. Crafting meaningful, engaging moments of choice and consequence can be difficult for some developers to navigate, but when a game really makes you stop and consider why you’re doing something beyond just a raw desire to extract the maximum amount of content, that’s when you’ve struck gold. Some choices are big, some are meaningless in the grand scheme of things, but if it’s done well, even the most minute decision can stick with you. Here are a few of the choices we’ve agonized over in games.</p></div><div><p>The final choice in the first <em>Life Is Strange </em>game is controversial because it effectively negates everything else you’ve done in the supernatural teen drama while also giving you an impossible moral conundrum. As Max, a time-traveling teenager who has been through more trauma in the past week than most people go through in a lifetime, you’re asked to either sacrifice the entire seaside town of Arcadia Bay to a storm caused by Max’s repeated use of her time manipulation, letting you save your best friend Chloe while many residents die, or go back to the beginning of her story when she first discovered her powers and not use them, letting Chloe die but preserving the town. Developer Don’t Nod created an agonizing and airtight dilemma with no “good” ending that could make everybody happy. It forces you to declare what matters most to you, and a decade later, people are still disputing which was the right choice.</p></div><div><p>You know how it’s weird that we ask high school students to pick a career track and dedicate years of their lives to it in higher education, just hoping it all works out for them down the road? Picking your starter Pokémon is kind of like that. Yeah, you might gravitate toward one little guy or another based on whether or not you think they’re cute or cool, but if you don’t know what their final forms look like or what challenges await you throughout the game, you might have set yourself up for a bad time. What if you don’t like your starter’s final form? How likely is it that your starter will have bad match-ups in the early game and you may struggle to make any real progress for several hours? There are so many unknowns when picking your first friend, and you might not know if you’ll regret it until it’s too late. That’s a lot of pressure to put on a 10-year-old trainer.</p></div><div><p>Fighting games can be overwhelming. There are mechanics to learn, combos to memorize, and match-ups to be prepared for that you really only understand after hours of play. But part of that journey is also deciding on which character or characters you’re going to dedicate your training time to. Some of these games have dozens of fighters to choose from, and you never really know how they handle until you’ve taken them for a test run. Some people spend dozens of hours on a character just to decide they’re not the right fit. But when you find the fighter who fits your playstyle like a glove, there’s nothing like it.</p></div><div><p>Telltale took some pretty big swings with <em>Batman </em>in its episodic adventure game’s two seasons. It inverted the dysfunctional Joker/Harley Quinn relationship, had Bruce Wayne teaming up with the clown throughout, and ended on a pretty profound choice. Alfred, Bruce’s long-time butler and an invaluable support to his crime-fighting efforts, tells Batman that he no longer has the stomach for the work the two have been doing to stop crime in Gotham. He plans to leave for a permanent vacation, and while the player can protest, it ultimately comes down to whether or not Bruce will hang up the cowl or lose his closest friend. It’s a bold choice to give to the player, but it’s also one Telltale had earned over the course of two seasons. <em>The Enemy Within </em>reflects on whether or not Batman’s crusade and methods are worth the result, and at the end, it asks you to decide.</p></div><div><p>Save files are precious keepsakes for most players. Everyone has a devastating story of losing a memory card, or a younger sibling deleting your 40 hours of progress in a game. (People who’ve grown up in the era of cloud saves will never know this pain!) So when <em>Nier Automata </em>asks you in the end to delete your save in order to help someone else playing through PlatinumGames’ action RPG, it’s no small matter. By this point, you’ve put dozens of hours into the game, likely collected a ton of loot, and unraveled plenty of mysteries in the post-apocalyptic world. Giving all that up to help a stranger? What if I still have optional stuff I haven’t finished yet? You can decline and come back later, but once you do it, it’s done. The game makes a big show of it, too, painstakingly erasing your menus and inventory. Most choices you make in video games aren’t final, as you can just save scum your way around them. <em>Nier Automata</em> makes you live with a choice, even if you won’t see any material benefit from it.</p></div><div><p>The <em>Mass Effect </em>trilogy is full of choices that cause ripple effects from one game to the next. One of the most infamous happens in the first game. On the planet Virmire, Commander Shepard is forced to choose between saving only one of their first two crewmates: Kaidan Alenko or Ashley Williams. The decision not only takes an emotional toll on the Normandy’s crew, but it fundamentally changes your party for not one, but two games. Whoever survives Virmire will go on to become a potential rival or party member for the rest of the trilogy, and even within that fixed role, Kaidan and Ashley deviate pretty strongly from one another and can completely change a party dynamic. <em>Mass Effect </em>may not have nailed every instance of choice and consequence carryover across all three games, but the decision the player makes on Virmire starts one of the best-executed threads across all three games.</p></div><div><p>Sure, the decision you make as the President of the United States at the beginning of <em>Saints Row IV</em> doesn’t actually change anything, but it’s about the principle. You’ve only got enough clout to solve one of Earth’s biggest problems: cure cancer or end world hunger. It’s a silly little hypothetical that will be quickly derailed by the game’s inciting incident, but yeah, I still want to know what people choose. Even as I write this I’m wondering which would be more of an immediate good. Probably cure cancer? Maybe? World hunger could be eradicated with some change in policies, but an instant “cure cancer” button? That’s too good to pass up, right? I’m making the right decision, right? Oops, no time to think about it; there’s an alien invasion happening.</p></div><div><p>The <em>Fable </em>series is typically a binary, good vs. evil affair. The series got a bit more gray as it went on, but most of its choices were of the “will you help people or beat them to death with a stick” type shit that was common in the early 2000s. <em>Fable II</em>’s final choice is a bit more complex. You’re given a choice between one of three wishes: revive the citizens of Albion who died over the course of the game, resurrect your family, or suddenly amass a whopping 1 million gold for you to spend as you please. The decision can completely change the world’s perception of you. A hero who revives the citizens will be met with applause and celebration as they travel through the world, whereas someone who chooses wealth will only receive disdain and ridicule wherever they go. If you want to be a truly evil bastard that’s all well and good, but I can’t imagine anyone not choosing to revive their family and loyal canine companion.</p></div><div><p><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> has plenty of big choices, but perhaps the most affecting is in its <em>Phantom Liberty </em>expansion. The spy thriller DLC puts you in the middle of a dispute between a government agent, Solomon Reed, and a terminally ill netrunner, Songbird. Solomon wants to bring her in so she can continue to be a tool of the state, and Songbird wants to be free to seek life-saving medical treatment. Both of them reach out to the player with their respective plans, and it’s up to you to decide who you will betray at a pivotal moment. Making either choice will send you down one of two very different paths with a completely divergent endgame. Neither is entirely satisfying, and you have to play through both to get the full picture, but no one leaves <em>Phantom Liberty </em>unscathed. It’s just a matter of who you’re willing to sell out in order to reach the finish line.</p></div><div><p>Most post-apocalyptic games have some element of supply scarcity—consider, for instance, how you have to scrounge for the limited number of tools you can craft with in <em>The Last of Us</em>—but Telltale’s first season of <em>The Walking Dead</em> may handle this concept more memorably than any other game. In its second episode, protagonist Lee Everett is given food rations to divide between a group of survivors, and it’s made clear to you that there isn’t enough for everyone. There are children, irritable adults, and, of course, yourself to consider. No matter who you choose, someone is going to be left wanting, and desperate people can hold a grudge like no other. Choosing who gets half an apple can sour people on you or others, and you didn’t ask to be put in this position. It was thrust upon you, and now you’ll bear all the responsibility and consequences of your actions. The group will remember this.</p></div><div><p>The <em>Gears of War </em>series isn’t one known for choice and consequence, but <em>Gears 5 </em>throws a gut punch of a decision at you in the end. As Kait Diaz, you’re forced to choose which of your two companions to save. The trio of Kait, Del Walker, and JD Fenix has been together since <em>Gears of War 4</em> and was essentially the “next generation” of COG soldiers after Marcus Fenix’s run in the first three games. Now, no matter what you do, the group is one friend short. To this day, we still don’t know how the <em>Gears of War </em>series will handle this decision because there hasn’t been a sequel to the 2019 shooter yet. The next game is a prequel called <em>Gears of War: E-Day</em>, but JD’s voice actor has hinted that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-6-jd-fenix-actor-reveal-announcement-1851435150&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-6-jd-fenix-actor-reveal-announcement-1851435150">something else might be in the works</a></span>.</p></div><div><p>The reason that <em>The Witcher 3</em>’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-story-behind-the-witcher-3s-bloody-baron-quest-1736090893&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-story-behind-the-witcher-3s-bloody-baron-quest-1736090893">most famous quest</a></span> is such an impactful one is not just because of the choice you have to make but because the twists and turns it contains are dizzying and difficult to swallow. Geralt meets a man known as the Bloody Baron, whose life story is a tragic, sympathetic one full of highs and lows. His “Family Matters” quest line, however, ties many threads from his life together until they all lead to an impossible decision. No matter what Geralt does, the Bloody Baron’s story ends tragically. It’s just a matter of where Geralt directs the most damage. By the time you make the final choice in the quest line, you’ve seen so much misfortune tied to one man that reaching this point with no real solution in sight is painful, but it also exemplifies the best parts of <em>The Witcher 3</em>’s storytelling and quest design.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Adventure Cobra: The Awakening launches August 26]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/space-adventure-cobra-the-awakening-launches-august-26</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/space-adventure-cobra-the-awakening-launches-august-26.1145109/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/space-adventure-cobra-the-awakening-launches-august-26<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Side-scrolling action platformer dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Side-scrolling action <a title="Genres > Platformer [641 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Space Adventure Cobra: The Awakening [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/space-adventure-cobra-the-awakening">Space Adventure Cobra: The Awakening</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,135 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,843 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,873 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,837 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,717 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2878220/Space_Adventure_Cobra__The_Awakening/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a title="Companies > Epic Games [348 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/space_adventure_cobra_the_awakening" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a> on August 26, publisher <a title="Companies > Microids [202 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/microids">Microids</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Magic Pockets [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/magic-pockets">Magic Pockets</a> announced. <span id="more-952573"></span></p><p>The game is based on the manga <em>Cobra</em> created by Buichi Terasawa in 1978, and covers the first 12 episodes of the anime series.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Microids:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Immerse yourself in a thrilling action platform game and harness the unique abilities of an iconic <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,149 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>r.</p><p>Play as Cobra, the space pirate, in an action platformer. Along with Lady Armaroid, your loyal partner, and equipped with your iconic Psychogun, you must solve a mystery that could threaten the entire universe.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Travel from planet to planet to save three enigmatic sisters, whose fate is tied up with a fabulous treasure sought by the dreaded Space Pirate Guild.</p><p>You will need to shrewdly use Cobra’s weapons and gadgets to defeat your enemies and complete the levels filled with obstacles and traps, which won’t be an easy feat for our space rogue.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>An <a title="Genres > Action [2,598 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> and Platform Crossover</strong> – Visit a multitude of exotic planets across levels filled with traps testing your skills to the limit. With Cobra’s superhuman abilities, you will need to relentlessly run, jump and climb, and make sure you use all the means at your disposal to take out your enemies.</li><li><strong>Equipped to the Nines</strong> – <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter Cobra’s iconic weapons, such as the awesome psychogun and the Colt Python 77, to destroy the opponents on your heels, as well as his famous gadgets like the cigar and the grappling hook. You will need all of your arsenal to defeat the powerful bosses standing in your way.</li><li><strong>Solo and <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [468 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a> Modes</strong> – Explore story mode by choosing from the three difficulty levels, allowing veterans of the genre to take on a real test worthy of their skills, while those looking for less of a challenge to enjoy the story. You can also try to escape your enemies in a two-player <a title="Genres > Co-Op [245 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> mode.</li><li><strong>A Thrilling <a title="Genres > Science-Fiction [76 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/science-fiction">Science-Fiction</a> World</strong> – Immerse yourself in this amazing space opera world as you embark on your adventure as a fearsome, charismatic hero. Over the course of this epic journey, you will cross paths with colorful characters like the Royal Sisters and the terrifying Crystal Bowie—Cobra’s nemesis.</li><li><strong>A Faithful Adaptation</strong> – <em>Space Adventure Cobra: The Awakening</em> is the first video-game adaptation of <em>Cobra</em> on modern platforms. It covers the first 12 episodes of the famous anime series, remaining true to its spirit with the moments of bravery and humor that made it so special.</li></ul></blockquote><p>View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/space-adventure-cobra-the-awakening/march-26-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_952575"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Witcher 4 Release Date Is Not Soon, As Dev Discusses Why It Won't Use GenAI]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/witcher-4-release-date-is-not-soon-as-dev-discusses-why-it-wont-use-genai/1100-6530369/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/witcher-4-release-date-is-not-soon-as-dev-discusses-why-it-wont-use-genai.1145106/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/witcher-4-release-date-is-not-soon-as-dev-discusses-why-it-wont-use-genai/1100-6530369/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530369">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>As part of CD Projekt's recent earnings briefing, the Polish company confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-witcher-4-release-date-trailer-news/2900-5228/" data-ref-id="2900-5228">The Witcher 4</a> is not going to release anytime soon and commented on the company's thoughts regarding generative AI.</p><p>Management <a href="https://www.investing.com/news/transcripts/earnings-call-transcript-cd-projekt-q3-2023-sees-strong-sales-and-strategic-growth-93CH-3947581" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said during an earnings call</a> that The Witcher 4 is projected to be released after 2026. The company added that it sees "potential" in releasing "a trilogy within six years." It's been confirmed that The Witcher 4 kicks off a new trilogy, and it seems extremely ambitious for The Witcher 5 and 6 to follow within the space of six years, but that is what management believes could be possible, it seems.</p><p>Michal Nowakowski, the co-CEO of CD Projekt, was asked during the call if he believes it's possible to release the entire trilogy within a six-year window. He said the company does not foresee anything that would make this goal impossible. The new Witcher games are being made using Epic's Unreal Engine technology, which is a major shift from past releases that were built using CD Projekt's own technology.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="113298546" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465564,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;The%20Witcher%20IV%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20Cinematic%20Reveal%20Trailer%20Breakdown&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:492,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/the-witcher-iv-official-cinematic-reveal-trailer-breakdown\/2300-6465564\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465564\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465564\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465564\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465564&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465564,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6530369&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;the-witcher-4&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;cd-projekt-red-studio&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;the-witcher&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;the-witcher&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465564},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465564\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4415349-1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/bJE8LEN3.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1734111900,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="bJE8LEN3" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465564" data-src="/videos/the-witcher-iv-official-cinematic-reveal-trailer-breakdown/2300-6465564/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>The Witcher IV – Official Cinematic Reveal Trailer Breakdown</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>Nowakowski said CD Projekt will work with the Epic team if any issues with the engine arise. GameSpot has followed up with CD Projekt in an attempt to get more insight into the six-year timeframe remark.</p><p>Before this, CD Projekt management said <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/witcher-4-coming-2025-at-the-soonest/1100-6508062/" data-ref-id="1100-6508062">The Witcher 5 and The Witcher 6 would each take about three years to develop.</a> As confirmed previously, the <a href="https://x.com/BigManFanelli/status/1577335568224198657" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">six-year window begins when The Witcher 4 releases</a>.</p><p>Given that The Witcher 4 won't release until 2027 at the soonest, many are wondering if it's possible the game could come to new PlayStation and Xbox consoles. This remains unknown.</p><p>Also during the earnings briefing, Nowakowski discussed why CD Projekt will not use generative AI in the development of The Witcher 4 or other upcoming games. Generative AI is "quite tricky" as it relates to IP rights and legality, the executive said (<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-wont-be-out-until-after-2026-so-could-it-be-a-next-generation-game" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">via Eurogamer</a>), adding, "when it comes to implementation of any gen AI in the actual games, we really have nothing happening when it comes to Witcher 4 or any projects in the near future."</p><p>Nowakowski went on to remind everyone that CD Projekt established an internal team in 2024 tasked with investigating how the company's teams can use AI for its future games, including potentially creating its own customized AI models. "Several" research projects for this are underway, Nowakowski said.</p><p>General AI has been used in game development for decades and is far less controversial than generative AI technologies that are relatively newer and more potentially problematic. Part of the reason why video game voice actors remain on strike is due to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mass-effect-actor-on-why-ai-is-existential-issue-in-ongoing-strike-negotiations/1100-6528710/" data-ref-id="1100-6528710">concerns around AI</a>. As for game developers, there are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-says-ai-will-lead-to-job-losses-invests-80-billion-in-the-tech/1100-6528633/" data-ref-id="1100-6528633">fears that jobs could be lost due to a rise in AI. </a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us season 2 showrunners are changing the way Abby is introduced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-2-showrunners-are-changing-the-way-abby-is-introduced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-season-2-showrunners-are-changing-the-way-abby-is-introduced.1145103/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-2-showrunners-are-changing-the-way-abby-is-introduced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Abby-in-The-Last-of-Us-Part-2-and-Kaitlyn-Dever-as-Abby-in-TLOU-season-two.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Naughty Dog/HBO/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The introduction of Abby Anderson will be a bit different in HBO's The Last of Us TV series than it is in the game. </p>
<p><strong>Please be aware of spoilers for The Last of Us (both games and show) below. </strong></p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Death of Console Exclusives Is Inevitable and I Don't Know How I Feel About It" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ipoW24t90fw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Death of Console Exclusives Is Inevitable and I Don't Know How I Feel About It</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ipoW24t90fw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ipoW24t90fw?autoplay=1" title="The Death of Console Exclusives Is Inevitable and I Don't Know How I Feel About It">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Death of Console Exclusives Is Inevitable and I Don't Know How I Feel About It. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ipoW24t90fw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Just as with the first season, there will be some differences between the game and the TV show due to the nature of each medium, ensuring the story remains satisfying for each audience and spoilers are less likely to occur.</p>
<p>"In the game, you play as Abby, so you immediately form a path to connection with her, because you're surviving as her, you're running through the snow, you're fighting infected, and we can withhold certain things and make it a mystery that will be revealed later in the story," <a href="https://www.goldderby.com/article/2025/the-last-of-us-season-2-abby-introduction/">The Last of Us' Neil Druckmann shared during a press conference</a>.</p>
<p>He noted the showrunners "couldn't do that" in the TV series because, obviously, viewers won't be able to actually play as Abby when season two airs. "So we need other tools, and that context gave us that shortcut," Druckmann explained.</p>
<p>The showrunners ultimately decided to tweak the game's timeline framing a notch, and instead The Last of Us series two will introduce Abby (<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-two-teaser-gives-first-look-at-kaitlyn-dever-as-abby">played by Kaitly Dever</a>) and reveal her connection to Pedro Pascal's Joel and Bella Ramsey's Ellie to the audience from the off.</p>
<p>"Where that revelation happens in the game, if we were to stick to a very similar timeline, viewers would have to wait a very, very long time to get that context," Druckmann reasoned.</p>
<p>"It would probably get spoiled to them between seasons, and we didn't want that, so it felt appropriate for those reasons to move that up and give the viewer that context right off the bat."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Abby-in-The-Last-of-Us-season-2_zWcHRAT.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>HBO</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The second season of The Last of Us will kick off next month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-long-awaited-season-2-finally-gets-a-start-date">on 13th April</a>, and will <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-two-will-be-shorter-so-every-episode-feels-like-a-blockbuster">comprise seven episodes</a>, with one of those episodes being "quite big" in length. Spores have also been confirmed for The Last of Us' second season, with the showrunners <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-two-promises-viewers-a-different-evolution-of-infection-plus-spores-make-a-return">promising viewers "a different evolution" of infection</a>.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-twos-abby-kaitlyn-dever-wants-to-do-this-character-justice-and-make-the-fans-proud">Dever spoke more about her role as The Last of Us' Abby</a>, stating she wants "to do this character justice and make the fans proud" on the second season's debut.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Cutscenes Framerate Cap Can Be Removed With New Version of Special K Mod; 1.0.1 Patch Released to Address “Various” Issues]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-cutscenes-framerate-uncapped-mod/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-cutscenes-framerate-cap-can-be-removed-with-new-version-of-special-k-mod-1-0-1-patch-released-to-address-%E2%80%9Cvarious%E2%80%9D-issues.1145085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-cutscenes-framerate-uncapped-mod/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The new version of the popular Special K mod improves Assassin's Creed Shadows on PC by fixing multiple issues and introducing an option to uncap cutscenes' framerate.</p>
<p>Shortly after the release of the latest entry in the series, Special K creator Kaldaien released <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/3159330/discussions/0/612032512885050246/">a new version of the mod</a>, which includes an option to uncap cutscenes framerate and addresses several issues found in the PC version of the game, which includes NVIDIA DLSS options mysteriously becoming unavailable and broken NVIDIA Reflex integration.</p>
<p>The new version of the Special K mod introducing the fixes highlighted above is also fully compatible with the Assassin's Creed Shadows latest patch, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1jjlifk/ac_shadows_title_update_101_hot_fix_release_notes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">patch 1.0.1</a>, which was released today. Unfortunately, the patch doesn't bring any major changes to the game, as it only fixes some unspecified global issues and a Photo mode issue that could cause a crash when fetching photos to display on the game's world map.</p>
<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows is far from being among the best open-world role-playing games released to date, but it's still a solid entry in the Ubisoft series, bringing back a focus on stealth gameplay without doing away completely with the combat-focused approach seen in Valhalla, as I highlighted in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/assassins-creed-shadows-a-gorgeous-dive-into-feudal-chaos/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows is one of the finest entries in the series, successfully bringing back stealth-oriented gameplay while retaining the RPG mechanics and refined combat mechanics seen in previous entries in the series, seamlessly integrating them with the dual protagonist setup and a well-paced story that doesn't overstay its welcome. While the game still features way more content and gameplay systems than necessary, its rendition of Feudal Japan is among the best ever seen in a video game, and it is well worth experiencing for the vast majority of players.</em></p>
<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Voices Khazan in The First Berserker Khazan? Voice Actor Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/who-voices-khazan-in-the-first-berserker-khazan-voice-actor-explained/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/who-voices-khazan-in-the-first-berserker-khazan-voice-actor-explained.1145082/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/who-voices-khazan-in-the-first-berserker-khazan-voice-actor-explained/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>General Khazan’s story is a morbid and merciless one until his body is inhabited by an ethereal presence. In real life, a voice actor adds the depth and detail to Khazan’s character, so let’s see who gets the credit in The First Berserker Khazan.</p>



<p>The story goes that General Khazan is deemed a traitor guilty of treason. His body is relentlessly tortured and mutilated as a result, to the extent that his arms’ tendons are cut. He’s on the brink, until the Blade Phantom penetrates Khazan’s almost lifeless husk and imbues the character with otherworldly strength.  </p>



<p>Khazan engages with numerous characters throughout the story, and you hang onto his every word. We have one person to thank for being able to do this in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-release-date-platforms-free-demo-editions-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The First Berserker Khazan</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-who-plays-khazan-in-the-first-berserker-khazan">Who Plays Khazan in The First Berserker Khazan?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>You can feel the pain and anguish. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Ben Starr is the voice actor for General Khazan in The First Berserker Khazan.</strong></p>



<p>Starr described the role of Khazan as “terrifyingly sexy” in an interview with Gamespot. He talked about how interesting the game looked and declared, “I really want this” when auditioning.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ben Starr REALLY Wanted This Voice Role | The First Berserker: Khazan" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1ZKM_wIWKBk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-who-is-ben-starr-amp-what-has-he-been-in">Who is Ben Starr &amp; What Has he Been in?</h2>



<p>Ben Starr is now regarded as a breakout star in the games industry after a solid career mixing TV roles and voice-over work in games. His headline-making performance arrived in 2023 when Starr claimed the lead role of Clive Rosfield in Final Fantasy 16.</p>



<p>He would reprise the role in subsequent FF16 DLCs—Echoes of the Fallen Rising Tide—as well as a guest star in Tekken 8.</p>



<p>Since then, Starr has lent his talents to the role of Prometheus in Hades 2. According to his <a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm5471977/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">IMDB page</a>, his schedule is (unsurprisingly) starting to fill up as the actor also has upcoming roles in various games: Warframe 1999, Date Everything, and Clair Obscur Expedition 33.</p>



<p>More hilariously, you might recognize the actor from the Balatro Friends of Jimbo Pack 3 trailer.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Balatro - Friends of Jimbo (Pack 3) | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1r1LVgAGXlE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>If Starr can keep up this level of top-class performances and roles, he has the potential to join Nolan North, Troy Baker, Laura Bailey, and other peers in the upper echelons of voice-acting excellence!</p>



<hr>



<p>I think Ben does an excellent job in the role of Khazan and adds to the story. Do you agree? Is the actor deservedly earning his pips? Who else do you think Ben Starr would be perfect to play the role of in future games? Drop a comment and let us know.</p>



<p>We have other The First Berserker Khazan content for you to browse: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-the-first-berserker-khazan-have-difficulty-settings-easy-mode-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Does The First Berserker Khazan have difficulty settings?</a> and its complete <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-trophy-list-achievements-and-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trophy List</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2 will now launch in October 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-will-now-launch-in-october-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-the-masquerade-%E2%80%93-bloodlines-2-will-now-launch-in-october-2025.1145073/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-will-now-launch-in-october-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2 has been delayed once again, now set to launch in October 2025 after missing the previous target of a first half 2025 release. However, World of Darkness Executive VP Marco Behrmann states that the game is now complete and into the final bug fixing and polishing phase of development.</p>
<p><iframe title="Vampire: the Masquerade - Bloodlines 2 - Game Update" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rzc1Ow18qhY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In the game update video, Behrmann runs through the development progress of the past year or so, which has been covered through dev diaries from developer The Chinese Room. This includes adding more narrative depth, character development and evolving Fabian’s role in the storyline, partly in response to community feedback to earlier announcements and reveals.</p>
<p>In a statement attached to the video, the team say:</p>
<p><em>Hello Kindred,</em></p>

<p><em>We would like to share an update on the development and release window of Vampire: the Masquerade – Bloodlines 2.</em></p>
<p><em>As Marco explained in the video, Bloodlines 2 will not be ready for release in the first half of 2025.</em></p>
<p><em>Paradox Interactive and The Chinese Room are committed to delivering this game, and we believe that ensuring great technical quality is more important than sticking to a specific date.</em></p>
<p><em>The game is currently in a late development stage, and feedback from the community has been taken into account during this time. TCR is working hard on quality assurance to ensure it is stable and free of bugs that could disrupt the player experience.</em></p>
<p><em>Bloodlines 2 will launch in October 2025 when the game meets the technical quality standards that you, our fans, rightfully expect and deserve. Please stay tuned for the game’s exact launch date.</em></p>
<p><em>We want to ensure that the content we share with you is high-quality and showcases exciting game features. With this updated release timeline, we will pause our development diaries so that the team can concentrate on refining the game. However, we will still be available online for questions and comments, and we welcome everyone to join the Bloodlines 2 Discord.</em></p>
<p>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2 has had a very, very long journey through development. First announced back in March 2019 with Seattle-based developer Hardsuit Labs, the game’s development struggled to the extent that <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/02/23/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-delay-release-date-2021-hardsuit-labs-cancelled-developer/">Paradox made the decision to pull the project from Hardsuit Labs</a> and, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/10/14/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-was-nearly-cancelled-instead-of-getting-a-new-developer/">after considering cancelling it outright</a>, brought in The Chinese Room to reboot the game.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/09/04/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-new-developer-is-the-chinese-room-coming-in-2024/">Bloodlines 2 was re-revealed</a> in September 2023, the pitch and overarching story for Bloodlines 2 shifting compared to the originally revealed version of the game. Still set in Seattle, there’s a three-way power struggle for power in the Vampire Court, and in an intriguing shift, with protagonist Phyre cast as an Elder Vampire, capable of tapping into all the fantastical enhancements that each clan offers them. First expected for late 2024, release has slipped multiple times.</p>
<p>The big question is whether October 2025 will actually stick. After all, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/05/the-next-battlefield-is-set-to-release-before-april-2026/">other developers and publishers are preparing to delay their games</a> from the end of this year to avoid the crushing behemoth that is GTA 6, which is doggedly sticking to a late ’25 launch, according to Take-Two. We’ll see how that affects Bloodlines 2.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Monster Hunter Wilds Bug Is Sweet Revenge for Those Stuck at 30 FPS]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/this-monster-hunter-wilds-bug-is-sweet-revenge-for-those-stuck-at-30-fps/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-monster-hunter-wilds-bug-is-sweet-revenge-for-those-stuck-at-30-fps.1145070/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/this-monster-hunter-wilds-bug-is-sweet-revenge-for-those-stuck-at-30-fps/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Monster Hunter Wilds has some<a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gpu-streaming-issues-barely-60-fps-rtx-5080/"> widely reported technical issues</a> that impact the game's performance considerably, but you should consider yourself lucky if you cannot run the game at a high framerate thanks to a bug that actually increases damage dealt by multi-hit attacks the lower the framerate is.</p>
<p>A video shared on YouTube by<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Antawoo" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Anta</a> a few days ago showcases how multi-hit moves in the latest entry in the series actually deal more damage under certain conditions when the game runs at 30 FPS, the lower possible framerate cap available on PC. This is caused by framerate tied to game logic, which isn't something new for the series, as Monster Hunter Rise, for example, was also affected by <a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-rise-challenging-high-framerates/">a similar issue</a> that made the game harder when running at higher than 30 FPS, which really seems to be the ideal framerate for the series' developers.</p>
<p><iframe title="[Monster Hunter Wilds] This bug is stealing your damage - Here's how to fix it" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zB3e1zYpuqE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>After watching the video above, I launched Monster Hunter Wilds and did a quick test using a Great Sword and the Training Area dummy, which confirmed the bug described by Anta occurs very frequently. The Total Damage seen in the screenshot below was dealt with the game running with a 30 FPS cap, while the Previous Total with a 120 FPS cap. While there are ways to mitigate the issue, as highlighted in the video, they are far from ideal, so hopefully, the issue will be addressed with a future update.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/20250326123227_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Monster Hunter Wilds' first major update will launch next week on all formats, introducing new features to the game as well as High Rank Zoh Shia and returning monster Mizustune. You can learn more about the update <a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-adds-new-challenges-and-more-on-april-4/">here.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 4 won't come out before 2027, so chill out would you]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-witcher-4-wont-come-out-before-2027-so-chill-out-would-you</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-4-wont-come-out-before-2027-so-chill-out-would-you.1145067/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-witcher-4-wont-come-out-before-2027-so-chill-out-would-you<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-witcher-4-release-date-not-until-2027-at-least-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>CD Projekt Red</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a> may have entered its <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-witcher-4-has-entered-the-most-intensive-phase-of-development-say-cd-projekt">"most intensive" production phase</a> but it won't be gracing your whirring machinery any time in the next year or two. During a financial call for people in suits with lots of money, the developer said they were hoping to give shareholders value for money, "even though we do not plan to release The Witcher 4 by the end of 2026." Basically confirming what you probably could've guessed anyway: there's no plan to bring the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> sequel out before 2027.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/DY-Q-Wd3Hz4">earnings call</a> was mostly a slew of graphs and tables with lots of numbers. Horrifying stuff. But there were some comments from executives which eliminated the possibility of an early release for the anticipated open world RPG, as spotted by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/the-witcher-4-wont-be-out-until-sometime-in-2027-at-the-soonest-cd-projekt-says/">PC Gamer</a>. </p>
<p>"We are not going to announce the precise launch date for the game yet," said CD Projekt Red's chief financial officer Piotr Nielubowicz when asked about plans for the release during a Q&amp;A session. "All we could share now to give more visibility to investors is that the game will not be launched within the time frame of the first target for the incentive program, which ends December 31, 2026."</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the call, the studio also asserted that they won't be using generative AI to help with development, mostly because of the legal problems it could cause in regards to copyright and such. </p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_Jc1JhcH.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"Gen AI, to be honest, is quite tricky when it comes to legal IP ownership and so on, and many other aspects," said joint CEO Michał Nowakowski when asked about it. "So when it comes to implementation of any gen AI in the actual games, we really have nothing happening when it comes to Witcher 4 or any projects in the near future."</p>
<p>Although that doesn't rule out the company using the technology in the future, as even Nowakowski admits the studio has been "investigating the potential use of AI solutions in our future products, including development of our own customized AI models."</p>
<p>The recent <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-witcher-4-trailer-is-here-and-ciri-is-the-star">Witcher 4 trailer</a> confirmed that Ciri, not Geralt, would be the star of the next adventure. It saw her doing battle with an ancient spidery evil and suffering an unheroic outcome typical to The Witcher games. Placing Ciri at the centre of the story will <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/having-ciri-as-the-witcher-4-lead-will-help-the-game-explore-the-witcher-worlds-sexism-say-cd-projekt">let the game explore sexism within the fantasy world</a>, say CD Projekt. Which could be an interesting angle if done intelligently. You may also be glad to know that the in-universe card game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gwent-returns-in-the-witcher-4-according-to-cd-projekts-heavy-hints">Gwent will be making a return</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision user research workers are unionizing 'to create an industry that works for them']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/activision-user-research-workers-are-unionizing-to-create-an-industry-that-works-for-them-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-user-research-workers-are-unionizing-to-create-an-industry-that-works-for-them.1145061/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/activision-user-research-workers-are-unionizing-to-create-an-industry-that-works-for-them-<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A supermajority of user research workers at Activision have voted to unionize under the Communications Workers of America (CWA) banner.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://cwa-union.org/news/releases/activision-user-research-workers-overwhelmingly-vote-form-union-cwa">The CWA confirmed the news in a press release</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and explained those workers will become members of CWA Local 9400. Microsoft has recognized the union, which has named itself Activision User Research Union-CWA.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Activision User Research Union-CWA is hoping to secure higher wages, job security and protections amid rampant layoffs, and transparency around promotions and career advancement.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It has become the first union formed by video game user researchers—but joins a number of others that have emerged at Microsoft after the company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-signs-labor-neutrality-agreement-with-cwa-ahead-of-activision-blizzard-deal">signed a labor neutrality agreement with the CWA</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We are excited to join our fellow game makers across the video game industry to show what’s possible when workers can freely build solidarity in the workplace," said organizing committee member and quantitative user researcher Nicolaas VanMeerten. "Many of us were mobilized to do something about the layoffs in 2023 and 2024, and now we can look out for each other with a union."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">CWA Local 9400 president Maurice Washington said it's critical that workers in the game industry have a "protected voice" to ensure they can fight for their fair share.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/-we-need-to-define-what-it-means-to-be-safe-as-gamers-around-the-world-a-code-of-ethics-in-gaming" target="_self" data-discover="true">'We need to define what it means to be safe as [players] around the world:' a code of ethics in gaming</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We are proud to welcome these workers to CWA and are looking forward to meeting Microsoft at the bargaining table to secure a fair union contract," they added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The news caps a remarkable few days for unionizing workers in the game industry. United Videogame Workers-CWA (UVW-CWA) </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/game-workers-in-the-us-and-canada-launch-industry-wide-union-to-fight-for-dignity-and-respect-">broke cover at GDC 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/game-workers-in-the-us-and-canada-launch-industry-wide-union-to-fight-for-dignity-and-respect-">last week</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to fight for "dignity and respect."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The union </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/industry-wide-union-uvw-cwa-has-already-welcomed-over-100-new-members">attracted 100 new members</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> within hours of launching and has now welcomed over 350 due-paying members into its ranks.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As a direct-join union, UVW-CWA is open to contractors, freelancers, and developers directly impacted by layoffs. It's a setup the union hopes will enable industry-wide reform by uniting swathes of developers across the U.S. and Canada.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Industry bosses have shown time and time again that they will choose the siren call of profit over uplifting workers or doing what’s right," said UVW-CWA last week. "Now is the time to stand with your peers, and fight for the dignity and respect you deserve."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 4 won't be out until after 2026, so could it be a next generation game?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-wont-be-out-until-after-2026-so-could-it-be-a-next-generation-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-4-wont-be-out-until-after-2026-so-could-it-be-a-next-generation-game.1145058/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-wont-be-out-until-after-2026-so-could-it-be-a-next-generation-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>CDPR confirms it's not using generative AI.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Witcher-4-%E2%80%93-Cinematic-Reveal-Trailer-%E2%80%93-Behind-the-scenes-1-6-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>CD Projekt Red</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>CD Projekt Red doesn't plan to release <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a> by the end of 2026, perhaps hinting it could be a next generation game.</p>
<p>In its latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DY-Q-Wd3Hz4&amp;t=1175s">financial call</a>, the company discussed its profit forecast for the next few years up to 2028, for which it expects a significant increase.</p>
<p>"Even though we do not plan to release The Witcher 4 by the end of 2026, we are still driven by this financial goal," the company said.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Witcher 4 – Cinematic Reveal Trailer – Behind the scenes" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pGJ-B7v5tYI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Witcher 4 – Cinematic Reveal Trailer – Behind the scenes</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pGJ-B7v5tYI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pGJ-B7v5tYI?autoplay=1" title="The Witcher 4 – Cinematic Reveal Trailer – Behind the scenes">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Witcher 4 – Cinematic Reveal Trailer – Behind the scenes<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pGJ-B7v5tYI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Witcher 4 was first revealed at last year's The Game Awards, though no release window was provided leaving fans to speculate. Though 2025 was very unlikely, some had hoped for a 2026 release. Now we know it will be 2027 at the earliest.</p>
<p>This is also in-line with journalist Jason Schreier, who <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-studios-ot45-game-of-the-year-edition.1093518/page-284#post-137487981">responded on ResetEra</a> that both The Witcher 4 and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a>'s Intergalactic won't be out next year.</p>
<p>Does this mean The Witcher 4 will be a next generation game? Sony is no doubt already planning its PlayStation 6 console, while <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-next-gen-console-reportedly-targeting-2027-with-handheld-device-due-this-year">Xbox is reportedly targeting 2027 for its next console</a>.</p>
<p>Or perhaps the game could be a cross-generation release, though that didn't work out well for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a>.</p>
<p>Eurogamer previously spoke with CDPR's vice president of technology, Charles Tremblay, about a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/technical-ambition-optimism-and-timeframes-what-we-learned-about-the-witcher-4-from-speaking-to-cd-projekt-red">potential PC-only launch for The Witcher 4</a>, with consoles following.</p>
<p>"It's something we discussed, actually," he said, "but we're not 100 percent sure. Maybe - so it's hard to say if we want to go this way at this stage. I would assume that as long as I understand, like, the strategy we want to do - I'm just trying not to say too much, bear with me - most likely, the launch, we will not have a PC-only launch, for example. I don't think this is a strategy we want to adopt right now. That being said, will it mean that we will have - let's say there were 20 platforms available - we'll have 20 at launch? Maybe not. But at least PC only, and then scattered, it's not necessarily the approach we want to go forward, for sure."</p>
<p>From the same financial call, joint CEO Michał Nowakowski discussed not using generative AI in The Witcher 4 due to the legalities of ownership.</p>
<p>"I think we mentioned before that last year, we set up a team that's investigating the potential use of AI solutions in our future products, including development of our own customised AI models," he said. "And we have several research projects underway. However, they are really not necessarily focusing on generative AI.</p>
<p>"Gen AI, to be honest, is quite tricky when it comes to legal IP ownership and so on, and many other aspects. So when it comes to implementation of any gen AI in the actual games, we really have nothing happening when it comes to Witcher 4 or any projects in the near future."</p>
<p>CD Projekt Red also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cd-projekt-shares-witcher-and-cyberpunk-project-updates-announces-partnership-with-mobile-developer-scopely">confirmed a partnership with Saudi-backed mobile developer Scopely</a> to create a game within one of CDPR's franchises.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Fortnite x The Walking Dead collab lets you create your own zombie-filled islands]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/new-fortnite-x-the-walking-dead-collab-lets-you-create-your-own-zombie-filled-islands/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-fortnite-x-the-walking-dead-collab-lets-you-create-your-own-zombie-filled-islands.1145043/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/new-fortnite-x-the-walking-dead-collab-lets-you-create-your-own-zombie-filled-islands/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The Walking Dead is coming back to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/fortnite">Fortnite</a> in a new and creative way, with a bunch of assets and content from <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/the-walking-dead">The Walking Dead Universe</a> added to Unreal Editor for Fortnite (UEFN) and Fortnite Creative. This means you’ll be able to drop into the editing tools and quickly cook up a Zombie-filled TWD-themed island of your own.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Walking Dead Universe Lurches into UEFN and Fortnite Creative" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_sB3hyiahKE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>There’s a bunch of different elements that you’ll be able to draw upon for your creations. It starts with the Walker NPC template for UEFN, a slow and shambling enemy that just wants to chomp on people, giving damage-over-time and eventual death. They can be grouped into hordes and can also smash through breakable environmental props.</p>
<p>This collaboration will also add Negan to Fortnite, both as a playable character for purchase from 4th April, and as an NPC with an update on 8th April. The Shiva Shotgun and Negan’s iconic spiked bat, Lucille, are also available.</p>
<p>JAHBSKD</p>

<p>But you don’t want to just drop these into basic Fortnite levels. The Prison Starter Island Template gives a basic prison layout to then populate and customise, and there’s also eight prison-themed Prefabs that can be placed in worlds. It can all be made to look extra TWD-like with a Heavy Linework shader to get that graphic novel feel.</p>
<p>Alongside all the other tools available in UEFN, you can create whatever kind of experience you want with this. Epic suggest survival RPGs, prison escapes and FFA shoot ’em ups, but I reckon a zombie baseball game would be a good shout.</p>
<p>Any creations can be published from 16th May via the Creator Portal, and can then potentially be found in the TWDU section of Discover, which will be present for a limited time.</p>
<p><a href="https://create.fortnite.com/news/the-walking-dead-universe-lurches-into-uefn-and-fortnite-creative?team=personal">Head to the announcement blog post</a> for more details.</p>
<p>In other Fortnite-ly news, people that want to relive the early days of Fortnite BR can continue to do so with Fortnite OG, which has now moved on to <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-og-makes-a-lucky-landing-into-season-3">Chapter 1 Season 3</a>. This brings back Lucky Landing and features a meteor on a collision course with the original island.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Event That Started It All - Fortnite OG Season 3 Launches March 25" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cvuJtEhV4Nc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>A bit like rewatching a favourite TV show, we all know what happens next, but it’s nice to revisit, isn’t it? The huge Team Deathmath mode OG 50v50 is also coming back for a limited time, so get into that while you can.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Games Are Apparently Very Enticing for PlayStation Users as Indiana Jones and FH5 Top Pre-Order Charts]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-games-are-apparently-very-enticing-for-playstation-users-as-indiana-jones-and-fh5-top-pre-order-charts/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-games-are-apparently-very-enticing-for-playstation-users-as-indiana-jones-and-fh5-top-pre-order-charts.1145040/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/microsoft-games-are-apparently-very-enticing-for-playstation-users-as-indiana-jones-and-fh5-top-pre-order-charts/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It looks like Microsoft's big decision to switch to a multiplatform policy could start paying dividends soon if the PlayStation Store pre-order charts are to be believed. As <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-is-topping-the-pre-order-charts-on-the-playstation-store-with-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-and-forza-horizon-5.1144932/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spotted</a> by ResetEra user Red Kong XIX, two games that are due to launch in April, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle and Forza Horizon 5, are taking the top spots across various countries with their various editions.</p>
<p><em><strong>United States</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: #1, #2</em><br>
<em>Forza Horizon 5: #3, #4, #14</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Canada</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: #1, #2</em><br>
<em>Forza Horizon 5: #3, #4, #12</em></p>
<p><em><strong>United Kingdom</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: #1, #2</em><br>
<em>Forza Horizon 5: #3, #5, #12</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Germany</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: #1, #2</em><br>
<em>Forza Horizon 5: #3, #4, #17</em></p>
<p><em><strong>France</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: #3, #4</em><br>
<em>Forza Horizon 5: #1, #2, #11</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Italy</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: #1, #3</em><br>
<em>Forza Horizon 5: #2, #5, #22</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Spain</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: #2, #4</em><br>
<em>Forza Horizon 5: #1, #3, #13</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Portugal</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: #1, #4</em><br>
<em>Forza Horizon 5: #2, #3, #11</em></p>
<p>It seems like PlayStation users are eager to get their hands on two of the best Microsoft games released in the past few years. Forza Horizon 5 might be the most surprising since it's now nearly four years old. Still, it's arguably the finest open world racing game ever made, having won several Game of the Year awards in 2021. Here on Wccftech, the game earned a 9.5/10 score in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/forza-horizon-5-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chris Wray's review</a>:</p>
<p><em>Let's keep it simple. Forza Horizon 5 is a fantastic game. It's outstanding, and I can unashamedly say that if it's not my favorite, it's in my top five games of the year. I recommend it for anybody and everybody.</em></p>
<p>When the game launches on PS5 on April 29, all users in the <a href="https://wccftech.com/forza-horizon-5-40-million/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">40-million-strong community</a> will be able to access the new Horizon Realms update that allows drivers to relive the post-launch Evolving World updates at their leisure.</p>
<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will debut twelve days earlier despite being much more recent. Still, it's just every bit as great as Forza Horizon 5 in its own genre, as I outlined in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-indiana-at-his-finest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">my 9/10 review of the PC version</a>:</p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is an excellent adventure/action game that features one of the best Indiana Jones stories, great level design that rewards exploration, and awesome ray traced visuals. This might just be the best game dedicated to Dr. Henry Walton we've ever seen.</em></p>
<p>It is perhaps a bit ironic that both games will be played best on consoles on Sony's PlayStation 5 Pro, but that's entirely on Microsoft for choosing not to make another mid-generation console refresh like they did with the Xbox One X.</p>
<p>Anyway, as The Verge's Tom Warren <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-playstation-5-more-xbox-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reiterated</a>, this is just the beginning for PlayStation and Nintendo Switch users. Microsoft-owned studios are expected to release many more titles on 'rival' consoles throughout the year, including <a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-starfield-playstation-5-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">possibly Bethesda's Starfield</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/avowed-surprisingly-meaty-unsurprisingly-deep/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Obsidian's Avowed</a>, and more.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeoGuessr is coming to Steam after 12 years in your browser]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/636201/geoguessr-steam-browser-game-early-access</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geoguessr-is-coming-to-steam-after-12-years-in-your-browser.1145037/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/636201/geoguessr-steam-browser-game-early-access<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/dominic-preston">Dominic Preston</a> <span>is a news editor with over a decade’s experience in journalism. He previously worked at <em>Android Police</em> and <em>Tech Advisor</em>.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>12-year-old browser game GeoGuessr is getting a belated port to PC, with a new listing for the game now in the Steam Store. Despite its age, GeoGuessr will launch in Early Access when it goes on sale some time in April 2025.</p><p>GeoGuessr <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/5/12/4323978/geoguessr-map-game-google-street-view-exploration">first launched in 2013</a>, and tasks players with figuring out their coordinates after being dropped into a random Google Street View location. Over the years it’s developed an <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22846869/geoguessr-competitive-esport-reddit-geowizard-google-street-view">unlikely competitive esports scene</a>, which the Steam edition looks to capitalize on, with a focus on competitive modes and ranked play.</p><p>The <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F3478870%2FGeoGuessr_Steam_Edition%2F" rel="sponsored">Steam listing</a> explains that the game will remain in Early Access “for at least six months,” while the developers add “new game modes, maps, and competitive features.” At launch it will support ranked Solo Duels and unranked Team Duels, including <a href="https://x.com/geoguessr/status/1904516547806150715">cross-play with the browser version</a>.</p><p>What we don’t know is exactly when in April GeoGuessr will launch on Steam, or how much it will cost. While the game’s browser version was initially free, it now only allows you to make three guesses per day before requiring a <a href="https://www.geoguessr.com/pro">paid subscription</a>, starting from $2.49 per month. GeoGuessr’s iOS and Android apps are locked behind the $2.99 Pro Unlimited plan, but the Steam app will require a new account that will not be synced with existing Geoguessr accounts, so may have its own pricing structure.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet the Minecraft Movie’s Cast in the Game Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/meet-the-minecraft-movies-cast-in-the-game-right-now/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/meet-the-minecraft-movie%E2%80%99s-cast-in-the-game-right-now.1145034/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/meet-the-minecraft-movies-cast-in-the-game-right-now/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Minecraft’s ‘A Minecraft Movie’ live event has arrived, and players can hang out with cast members like Steve, Garrett, Henry, Natalie and Dawn in the game today.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-when-does-a-minecraft-movie-live-event-start-and-end">When Does A Minecraft Movie Live Event Start and End?</h2>



<p>A Minecraft Movie live event was released on March 25 at 2:30 PM PT and will last until April 7 at 2 PM PT. Players can find the live event through the main menu of Minecraft: Bedrock Edition. If it is not visible, you need to update to the latest version of the game. When you load up the limited-time event, will Steve be waiting to take you on your new adventure?&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-a-minecraft-movie-live-event-mini-games">A Minecraft Movie Live Event Mini-Games</h2>



<p>A Minecraft Movie live event features three mini-games where players interact with a different cast member for each new activity. Like the movie, players will fight against the Piglins and defend the Midport Village.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-mining-with-henry">Mining With Henry</h3>



<p>Henry will require the players’ help with some good old mining for resources to build defences and weapons. Players will meet Henry at the Mineshaft and must dig for resources while defending themselves from the pesky Pilgins.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-protecting-the-payloads-with-natalie-and-dawn">Protecting the Payloads with Natalie and Dawn</h3>



<p>In this Minecraft Movie live event, mini-game players will help Natalie and Dawn protect their resources from waves of Pilgins while escorting transport carriages.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-defending-the-walls-with-garrett-nbsp">Defending the Walls with Garrett&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Three huge Nether portals have opened at the outskirts of the village, and hordes of Pilgins are rushing in to wreak destruction. Garrett and the players must take these Pilgins head-on while showcasing their archery skills. However, you are not the only one shooting projectiles.&nbsp;</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<h2 id="h-a-minecraft-movie-s-midport-village">A Minecraft Movie’s Midport Village</h2>



<p>The event also includes a new settlement, the Midport Village, which features shops, unique structures, adorable mobs, and hidden items. Thus, players have much more to do than fight in this Minecraft movie live event.&nbsp;Some of these items will be helpful when faced against the Pilgins. </p>



<figure></figure>



<h3 id="h-minecraft-yearn-cape">Minecraft Yearn Cape</h3>



<p>During the battle for Midport Village, players will receive six challenges, and after completing them, they will be rewarded with the Yearn cape. The Yearn cape features the “stunning art of a mineshaft inspired by Steve’s longing for the mines.”&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-minecraft-home-and-menace-capes">Minecraft Home and Menace Capes</h3>



<p>On the other hand, the Home and Menace Capes can be claimed by “watching a Minecraft creator for at least 3 minutes on Twitch and TikTok, respectively.” Players will receive a 5×5 redemption code for two capes, one inspired by Steve’s love for the mines and the other by Nether portal’s aura of danger.</p>



<p>All three capes will also be available in Bedrock and Java Edition, provided players use the same account on both editions.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In other news, Minecraft will <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-wont-be-going-free-to-play-mojang-says/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">not be going free-to-play</a>. Also, this year, the game receives <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-happy-ghasts-vibrant-visuals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘Vibrant Visuals’ and Happy Ghasts</a>. What are your thoughts on a Minecraft Movie live event? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-will-not-release-earlier-than-2027/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Witcher 4 not releasing before 2027</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does The First Berserker Khazan Have Difficulty Settings? Easy Mode Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/does-the-first-berserker-khazan-have-difficulty-settings-easy-mode-explained/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/does-the-first-berserker-khazan-have-difficulty-settings-easy-mode-explained.1145031/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/does-the-first-berserker-khazan-have-difficulty-settings-easy-mode-explained/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The First Berserker Khazan is a Soulslike, which means it’s difficult. Powerful mobs, even more deadly bosses, respawning enemies, and limited health. The genre isn’t for everyone, and despite the incredible aesthetic of Khazan, people want to know how difficult Neople’s Souslike is.</p>



<p>It took a long time for the Souls genre to win me over. I owned Demon’s Souls on day one, and hated it—now I love it. The unrelenting difficulty and intensity of boss fights aren’t for everyone. But darn it if <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-release-date-platforms-free-demo-editions-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The First Berserker Khazan</a> isn’t worth it for its aesthetic alone!</p>



<p>If you need comfort more than classy visuals, here’s everything you need to know about The First Berserker Khazan’s difficulty.</p>



<h2 id="h-are-there-difficulty-settings-in-the-first-berserker-khazan">Are There Difficulty Settings in The First Berserker Khazan?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A welcome inclusion. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Yes, The First Berserker Khazan has difficulty settings, allowing players to choose between Easy mode and Normal.</strong></p>



<p>After my first death to <a href="https://khazan.nexon.com/en/main" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Khazan</a>‘s first major boss fight, I was presented with the screenshot above (I’m not sure if it’s the same for everyone). You can see two different settings laid out with easy-to-read descriptions, which you can check out here:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Easy: </strong>“This difficulty is intended for players who are unfamiliar with action games.”</li>



<li><strong>Normal:</strong> “This difficulty is intended for players who are familiar with action games and enjoy the challenge and sense of achievement that the genre is known for.”</li>
</ul>



<p>For the longest time, Soulslikes have avoided optional difficulty settings like the plague. I don’t know if it’s a pride thing or if it’s the notion of toughness that comes with the territory of playing a Souls title. But companies are starting to ease up on the “it’s this or nothing” approach.</p>



<p>2024’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-shift-up-record-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stellar Blade</a> is a recent example of a Soulslike having distinct difficulty settings. Thankfully, The First Berserker Khazan has followed suit with its <strong>Easy </strong>and <strong>Normal </strong>options.</p>



<h2 id="h-which-difficulty-should-you-play-on-in-the-first-beserker-khazan">Which Difficulty Should You Play on in The First Beserker Khazan?</h2>



<p><strong>Your The First Berserker Khazan difficulty decision rests on whether you want to enjoy the story or relish the challenge of combat.</strong></p>



<p>The First Berserker’s premise is fascinating, so it makes sense if you’re in it for Khazan’s journey. If constantly dying frustrates you and you want to progress the narrative, <strong>I recommend picking Easy</strong>.</p>



<p>However, if you enjoy combat, are happy to keep dying to bosses and learn their movesets in the hope of overcoming the imperious foe, <strong>stick with Normal</strong>. I play on Normal, I enjoy seeing the game over screen constantly, but I also live for the feeling of satisfaction when I finally beat a boss on my 153rd attempt.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Khazan content, check out the game’s whopping <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-trophy-list-achievements-and-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trophy List</a>. It could easily go down as the best Souslike of the year, but what do you think? Are better titles set to arrive in 2025? Let us know.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG: Destined Rivals Launch Ran Into the Same Old Issues, With Scalpers, Shortages, and Outages]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-destined-rivals-launch-ran-into-the-same-old-issues-with-scalpers-shortages-and-outages</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-destined-rivals-launch-ran-into-the-same-old-issues-with-scalpers-shortages-and-outages.1145028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-destined-rivals-launch-ran-into-the-same-old-issues-with-scalpers-shortages-and-outages<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop">Pokémon TCG</a> set, Destined Rivals, has been fully unveiled and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-destined-rivals-preorder-guide-2025">the first pre-orders are already underway</a>. If you've been collecting for a while, it might not surprise you that it's been a fairly chaotic launch window though, with scalpers and store issues already reportedly plaguing the new set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fully unveiled on March 24, Scarlet &amp; Violet - Destined Rivals is set to launch starting on May 30, 2025. A few factors make this a particularly sought-after set. First, it marks the return of Trainer's Pokémon cards. Those old enough to remember <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PokemonTCG/comments/1jjbcba/mom_says_we_have_destined_rivals_at_home/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">vintage Trainer's Pokémon cards</a>, like Brock's Sandslash or Rocket's Mewtwo, should take a moment to stretch their back and adjust their posture before expressing excitement for this returning archetype.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">They're popular ways of tying beloved Trainers into the actual Pokémon cards in cool ways. Additionally, Destined Rivals is also centered around Team Rocket, the bad-team faction of Pokémon's first generation. Suffice to say, much like Prismatic Evolutions and its Eevee-lutions earlier this year, Destined Rivals has the makings of a very popular set.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet - Destined Rivals Pokémon Center Elite Trainer Box Images</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So, when the pre-orders went live, it should be little surprise that frustration quickly ensued. People trying to get into the Pokémon Center website to buy an Elite Trainer Box, a themed box of packs and other niceties that's a common pick-up for people looking to crack into a set, were <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PokemonTCG/comments/1jiwtc5/mood/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">left staring in from the outside</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And, still unsurprisingly, scalpers immediately hit online auctions like eBay with their ETB pre-orders. Listings of several hundred dollars for the typically $54.99 box were <a href="https://x.com/TCGDannyP/status/1904219026391499227" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">seen hitting the site</a>. Again, this is for a confirmed pre-order of the Pokémon Center-specific ETB. Serebii's Joe Merrick summed it up well, <a href="https://x.com/JoeMerrick/status/1904215887965511861" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">outlining his own experience</a> waiting for hours in queue to get a Destined Rivals ETB.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I truly hate this," Merrick wrote. "The way almost all Pokemon TCG content has shifted to financial. The way that people just treat it as investment. The way people just want to flip it. It's disgusting. Shame on all involved."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This is, sadly, par for the course. The aforementioned <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-company-breaks-silence-on-prismatic-evolution-shortage">Prismatic Evolutions set had shortages</a>, and the Blooming Waters 151 box also came and went fast. It's not uncommon to see notifications and signal-boosts of sets <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-paradox-rift-etbs-in-stock-now-on-amazon-live-new">restocking on various retailers</a>. Already, TPC has said in a FAQ online (<a href="https://www.pokebeach.com/2025/03/pokemon-center-says-more-destined-rivals-product-coming" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">per PokéBeach</a>) that more inventory of the Destined Rivals ETB will become available later this year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even on top of scalper issues, some purchases are <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/pokemon-destined-rivals-elite-trainer-box-pre-orders-are-being-cancelled/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reporting that their ETB orders are being cancelled</a>. Demand and popularity for the Pokémon TCG seem to be through the roof, but sadly, it also seems to be marring the actual hobby for most trying to just crack some packs or play some matches.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-tcg-pocket">Pokémon TCG Pocket</a> offers virtual solutions for the woes of physical scarcity, it's an understandable frustration for those who'd like to simply partake in the hobby. A stroll down your local store's card aisle will, more than likely, paint a clear picture of what it's like trying to pick up some packs right now. It's doubly frustrating when these drops have been exciting ones to see. Hopefully we see some remedies soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Metaphor: ReFantazio's UI escaped the shadow of Persona]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/how-metaphor-refantazios-ui-escaped-the-shadow-of-persona</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-metaphor-refantazios-ui-escaped-the-shadow-of-persona.1145022/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/how-metaphor-refantazios-ui-escaped-the-shadow-of-persona<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Function and style convey a timeless sense of cool.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Metaphor_-ReFantazio-%E2%80%94-AWAKEN-_-Xbox-Series-X_S%2C-Windows-PC-0-41-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Atlus</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>RPG maker Atlus has become celebrated for the unique UI designs in its games, from the Persona series to the more recent fantasy epic <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metaphor-refantazio">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a>.</p>
<p>I spoke with Metaphor's UI designer Koji Ise at this year's Game Developers Conference (GDC) to discuss the creation of the game's UI and how it conveys a sense of "cool".</p>
<p>"There are various ways of interpreting cool," said Ise. "But if we're simply looking at the aesthetics, it should be pretty simple and easy for designers to create that. The important part is to tie [the UI] in with the tone of the game and weave that into the game narrative. Being able to tie all that together with the game itself is what I consider to be something that's cool.</p>
<p>"I think a game that achieves that is a game that has designs that are just unique to that title alone, something that other titles cannot achieve," he added. "I think that sort of design is what I would consider to be cool."</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Metaphor: ReFantazio Review<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ct98clbQw5k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>UI is hugely important in setting the tone of a game as it appears across a game during gameplay, in menus, and more. "I think it is a powerful tool to control the overall kind of impression that the game gives off," said Ise.</p>
<p>He continued: "UI has the power to become the face of a game as well as move the player's emotions. That's why we as a team put in so much cost, resources and passion to create all these fleshed out UIs."</p>
<p>A big challenge with Metaphor in particular, though, was standing out from the shadow of the Persona games, which very much established the stylish UI designs of Atlus's games.</p>
<p>"I first started out by really trying to identify what Metaphor as a game was trying to convey and what specific unique traits the game had," said Ise. "And by really honing into those elements and being creative in how to express that through the UI, I believe we were able to pull the appeal of Metaphor to the forefront…[and] create something that was uniquely Metaphor."</p>
<p>Ise added the team was "very conscious of Persona" during development. "It was an established and big presence for us and it felt like we were in its shadows. But the director at one point pulled me aside and told me 'hey, don't focus on that too much, focus on what you want to do on this title alone'. And that really gave me [a chance to] step back and look at Metaphor as it is and focus on what expressions we want to make for this game specifically."</p>
<p>One of those elements was the use of Da Vinci's classic Vitruvian Man for the menu of the game's class system, known as Archetypes.</p>
<p>"That's actually a representation of a formula for the ideal king," said Ise, referencing the game's core plot. "Because the game adopts medieval painting styles, we were looking at various artwork from that era, which is when we found the Vitruvian Man, which we thought fit that theme because it has the ideal proportions of a human being."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/IMG_6209.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>The Archetype Tree uses the Vitruvian Man for its design | <span>Image credit: <cite>Atlus / Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>At Atlus, UI is a core part of the development process from the very beginning and this allowed the design to morph and evolve from the early conceptualisation stage to its final form along with the game as a whole.</p>
<p>As such, Ise showed me some early UI designs to represent the winding road of its development.</p>
<p>The earliest design focused on the game's fantasy setting, using parchment paper and other elements to represent the travel motif. "This was a design that was created when the theme of the journey itself with your companions was at the forefront, so that's why that's clearly expressed in this design," said Ise.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GDC_Metaphor_Parchment-Concept.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>The travel motif is reflected in the fantasy items | <span>Image credit: <cite>Atlus</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The next design was more retro, with minimalist white borders around menu elements but rearranged in a modern style. This was to tie back to the roots of RPGs for a classic feel.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GDC_Metaphor_Retro-Game-Concept.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>The white boxes here reflect classic RPGs | <span>Image credit: <cite>Atlus</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The third design was focused on the theme of anxiety and depicted the face of the protagonist falling downwards into his emotions. "This was created when one of the ideas of anxiety came into the picture," said Ise. "This is an emotion that people in the fantasy world and also in the real world share, it's mutual between those two worlds."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GDC_Metaphor_Anxiety-Concept.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>The falling character in this design represents anxiety | <span>Image credit: <cite>Atlus</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>To me, the blend of medieval fantasy and modern style lends the UI a timeless feel. "Yes that was very intentional and was something we were aiming for because the game is in a fantasy setting and we were referencing a lot of medieval designs," said Ise, though he felt this alone was too old fashioned and "wouldn't be catchy for the modern player".</p>
<p>He was then inspired by a poster in an art museum promoting medieval artwork but with pop art fonts and designs. "It felt like they were talking directly to us as modern people," he said, ultimately influencing that blend of a painterly style enveloped in modern animation and typography.</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GDC_Metaphor_Colorful-%26-Stylish-Concept.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GDC_Metaphor_Ink-Concept.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption>Two further concepts for the UI design | <span>Image credit: <cite>Atlus</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A key element of any UI, though, is balancing style with usability and clarity. "Striking that balance was, to be honest, the most difficult part of creating the UI for this game," Ise admitted.</p>
<p>"If we lean too much into the visuals, then it's difficult to use. But if we lean too much into the functional or usability side, then we start to lose the Atlus touch. So we put in a lot of effort and thought to make sure that we were taking both and making sure that it is a great balance to meet the needs of both."</p>
<p>"Persona veteran Atlus flexes its expertise with a fresh take on high fantasy," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metaphor-refantazio-review">Metaphor: ReFantazio review</a>. "What it lacks in subtlety, it makes up for in grandeur and heart."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI Limit Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/ai-limit-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ai-limit-review.1145016/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/ai-limit-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>AI Limit is, strangely enough, a game that’s all about mud. Your player character, Arrisa, is formed from mud. When you die – which you will a lot – Arrisa is respawned from mud. Most foes you encounter are made from mud, heck, you can even eat mud balls to regain health. Also, when you meander down the umpteenth dingey dull brown subterranean tunnel as you make your way through a level, you’ll be thinking the environment looks darn muddy too. AI Limit’s predilection with the goopy brown stuff is a little bit odd…</p>
<p><iframe title="AI Limit - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I9AckdXyWGs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It’s not the only odd thing about AI Limit, as the story is, quite frankly, bonkers. An assembly of random proper nouns haphazardly glued together – probably with mud – proceedings are overly complicated, make little sense, and are likely best ignored. Suffice to say, Arrisa is an immortal Blader, tasked with traversing a post-apocalyptic landscape to protect the last city of Havenswell. She’ll do this by slaying numerous beasties in a third person action adventure Soulslike.</p>
<p>Unlike a Souls game however, the levels here are almost completely linear. There are some shortcuts to be found, but you’ll generally be traipsing through the exact same level, along the exact same route, again and again. What is initially fun soon becomes a chore, as the identical hidden cultist ambushes you as they always tediously too, like some confused inhabitant of Punxsutawney, Pennsylvania. Finally, you’ll open a shortcut and get to avoid the hidden cultist, but AI Limit will push your patience in the wait to do so.</p>


<p>Combat is decent if unremarkable, a selection of light and chargeable hard attacks are available, though light attacks are much more effective, so you’re unlikely to do much charging. Rapid and capable of staggering most foes, light attacks prove so potent that hammering their button proves a more winning strategy than all the dodging, parrying, and special abilities combined. Particularly when the controls are a little bit off, as they are here. Inputs are regularly laggy and the targeting fussy, often leading to death as Arrisa insists on not looking at the demon about to kill her.</p>
<p>The Sync Rate mechanic is a neat addition, though. The more you hit opponents the more powerful your attacks become, but being hit or using abilities lowers your Sync Rate and thus your attack power. The risk and reward balance is intriguing but poorly implemented and under-explored; when light attacks are by far your best option and can quickly boost your Sync Rate, why bother troubling yourself doing anything else? As a result, combat is perfunctory and soon becomes rather dull, a significant issue when hitting stuff forms the majority of the game.</p>

<p>Boss encounters are fine, with some memorable behemoths to take down, but they are resolutely cheap in their tactics. Relying on insta-kill attacks to make the game difficult, rather than increasingly dangerous and varied attack patterns to fend off before finding your opening to strike back. Again, decide to stick with it, hammer light attack and force Arrisa to look in the right direction, and you’ll eventually defeat the boss, I’m just not sure how much fun you’ll be having in the process.</p>
<p>Visually, despite the dull as dish-water environments, the characters and enemies are well-designed and fluidly animated, with a lovely anime aesthetic that serves to make the game look more interesting. But don’t be fooled; this is a paint-by-numbers Soulslike offering little of note to differentiate it from the multitude of other games in the genre.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows – How to Change Seasons]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/assassins-creed-shadows-how-to-change-seasons/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-%E2%80%93-how-to-change-seasons.1145013/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/assassins-creed-shadows-how-to-change-seasons/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows enhances the open-world formula seen in previous entries in the series by introducing some dynamic elements that make the world feel more alive than ever. Some of these elements also have a considerable impact on the gameplay, such as Seasons. Depending on the current one, Naoe and Yasuke will have to deal with different weather and environmental conditions that can make certain quests easier or harder to complete. Other mechanics, such as the<a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/assassins-creed-shadows-how-to-refill-scouts/"> Scouts mechanics</a>, are also tied to the cycle of Seasons, so knowing how they change is extremely important to take full advantage of all the mechanics tied to them.</p>
<p>The changing of Seasons in Assassin's Creed Shadows depends on the<strong> actual passage of time</strong>. <strong>Spring, Summer and Autumn last 140 minutes</strong>, while <strong>Winter 180 minutes</strong>. No matter which activity you complete in the game, <strong>there's no way to speed up the changing of Seasons</strong>, altough there are ways to prevent a Season from changing automatically, or initiate a change manually when the time is up.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/20250326114317_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>To learn when a Season will end, all you need to do is open the main menu and access the World tab. In the upper right corner of the map, you will find<strong> a compass</strong> with a circulation progression bar. Once it is filled with the passage of time, <strong>the Season will change if you either fast travel, complete a mission or hold the right directional button while in the World menu</strong>. The same will happen if you do any of the things above when the progression bar is halfway full. In this case, you will trigger a mid-season refresh that won't change the Season, but will refresh locations, local factions and alerts.</p>
<p>Even if the Season has ended, if you do not fast travel, complete a mission or trigger the change manually via the main menu, <strong>it will not change</strong>, so you can use this to your advantage. During Spring, for example, you will find additional vegetation all over the world, which you can use to better conceal yourself if needed. During Fall, to make another example, weather will change more often, and you can use a heavy downpour at night to have an easier time sneaking inside enemy strongholds or camps. Being able to change the Season at wish might have been better for some, but this new Assassin's Creed Shadows system, if used correctly, can still be a strong tool to help Naoe and Yasuke in their quest.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 owners really want to play Xbox games, as Microsoft tops Sony’s preorder charts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/636178/microsoft-playstation-store-ps5-xbox-games-preorder-chart</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-owners-really-want-to-play-xbox-games-as-microsoft-tops-sony%E2%80%99s-preorder-charts.1145010/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/636178/microsoft-playstation-store-ps5-xbox-games-preorder-chart<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/tom-warren">Tom Warren</a> <span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>If you’re looking for some solid evidence that Microsoft’s strategy to bring Xbox games to PS5 is seeing some early success, look no further than Sony’s own PlayStation Store today. The top preordered games in the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">US PlayStation Store</a> are <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> and <em>Forza Horizon 5</em>, with the $99.99 premium versions of both games proving the most popular.</p><p><a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-is-topping-the-pre-order-charts-on-the-playstation-store-with-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-and-forza-horizon-5.1144932/">Resetera</a> posters have noticed it’s the same story in the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-ca/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">Canadian</a> PlayStation Store and across a variety of European stores, including <a href="https://store.playstation.com/fr-fr/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">France</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/de-de/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">Germany</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/it-it/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">Italy</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/es-es/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">Spain</a>, and the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/category/3bf499d7-7acf-4931-97dd-2667494ee2c9/1">UK</a>. Microsoft-owned Bethesda <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/610817/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date">announced earlier this week</a> that <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> will debut on PS5 on April 17th, with the premium version providing two days of early access starting April 15th. <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/620993/forzas-on-ps5s-horizon">Forza Horizon 5</a></em> is also coming to Sony’s rival console on April 29th.</p><p>Microsoft may have timed these two games perfectly for the PS5, amid a slow point for Sony’s own game studios, but the software maker has seen success with its earlier Xbox titles on PS5, too. <em>Sea of Thieves</em> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/21/24079090/hi-fi-rush-ps5-xbox-release-date">debuted on PS5</a> in April last year and <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/13/playstation-store-may-2024s-top-downloads/">Sony revealed</a> it was the top seller across the US, Canada, and EU markets a month later. It remained in Sony’s top downloads list for nearly six months.</p><p>Microsoft’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/12/24067370/microsoft-xbox-playstation-switch-games-future-hardware">Xbox everywhere strategy</a> — which I’ve been covering closely in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter">my <em>Notepad </em>newsletter</a> over the past year — is clearly doing well on PS5, and I’d expect to see more titles land on Sony’s console throughout 2025 and beyond. Microsoft is also preparing a similar list of Xbox games for Nintendo’s Switch 2, with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-launch-plans/">reports suggesting</a> the next-gen console will launch in June with third-party games to follow later this year.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[InCARceration is a free minigame "carlike experience" for parole breakers everywhere]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/incarceration-is-a-free-minigame-carlike-experience-for-parole-breakers-everywhere</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/incarceration-is-a-free-minigame-carlike-experience-for-parole-breakers-everywhere.1145007/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/incarceration-is-a-free-minigame-carlike-experience-for-parole-breakers-everywhere<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_EQ2Y7BQ.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Crayon / kit bloodgutters / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Soberly breaking down the plot, mechanics and presentation of InCARceration would be like trying to cook a meal, win a spelling bee or perform a sneak-attack after being welded inside a car. So I will say only that this is an amusing bizarro take on WarioWare that makes me yearn for other, bizarro takes on WarioWare.</p>
<p>You may find it cathartic if you've had any dealings with obtuse legal systems lately. A Kafkar sim, perhaps. Yeah, that'll do. <a href="https://crayonmelon.itch.io/incar">Play it in a browser here</a>. If you've already tried it, there was an update this week that (possibly?) adds a new ending and does away with some unintended quantum physics.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
The dignity of journalism requires that I drag this news piece kicking and screaming past the 300 word mark, so let me add that the release of InCARceration continues <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/my-summer-car-review-a-sordid-sim-of-piss-and-pistons-that-wont-hold-your-disgusting-little-hand">a promising year for unhallowed "carlike" experiences</a>. It was created for this February's automobile-fixated TFR Gamejam, which harbours a few other roadsters of note - the comparatively sheeny <a href="https://mabalobo.itch.io/redshift">RedShift</a>, in which your debt increases when you crash, and the gloomy pizza delivery sim <a href="https://eirye.itch.io/high-road">High Road</a>, of which we may jovially and unforgiveably say "<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/paratopic">Paratopic</a>-esque, is it? Paratoppings, more like!" You can find the jam on <a href="https://itch.io/jam/tfrjam-001/rate/3262838">Itch.io</a>.
</p>
<p>
Question for the thread: what makes a minigame collection more than a minigame collection? Decent variety between minigames?  Not actually being called a "minigame collection"? An overarching theme to stop it feeling like you're pointlessly fishing different shapes and colours of marshmallow from a bowl of Lucky Charms? Some actual craft, so that the component games are more like exquisite snowflakes than soggy cereal pieces endorsed by racist leprechaun imagery? Or alternatively, a full embrace of the disposability of minigames? Let the players have their fill of politically incorrect breakfast comestibles. They deserve nothing better.</p>
<p>It turns out RPS has some Background Reading to share. Here's Brendy on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-7-most-needless-minigames">the seven most needless minigames</a>, and here's Alec Meer (RPS in peace) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/worst-hacking-minigames-ever">sticking it to rancid hacking games</a> in particular.
</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher IV Won’t Launch Until 2027, Says CD Projekt RED]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-wont-launch-until-2027-says-cd-projekt-red/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-iv-won%E2%80%99t-launch-until-2027-says-cd-projekt-red.1144998/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-wont-launch-until-2027-says-cd-projekt-red/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>After the <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-gets-first-trailer-showing-off-cirilla/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stunning reveal trailer</a> for The Witcher IV at The Game Awards 2024, fans might have hoped to see the game in the not-too-distant future. However, CD Projekt RED has now confirmed that there's still a long wait ahead.</p>
<p>During yesterday's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/DY-Q-Wd3Hz4?t=1175s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fiscal year 2024 earnings conference</a>, they announced that the game won't be launched until at least 2027. Here's the full quote:</p>
<p><em>Regarding the expected release date for The Witcher IV, we are not going to announce the precise launch date for the game yet. All we could share for now to give more visibility to investors is that the game will not be launched within the timeframe of the first target for the incentive program, which ends on 31 December 2026.</em></p>
<p>It isn't inconceivable, then, that the two most anticipated fantasy open world roleplaying games, The Elder Scrolls VI and The Witcher IV, might be launched in the same year or at least in relative proximity. Bethesda's game might also debut in late 2027, given that Starfield <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/starfield-the-elder-space-scrolls/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched in September 2023</a>, and there is usually a four-year timeframe between their titles.</p>
<p>Following the aforementioned reveal of The Witcher IV, the Polish studio provided some info on the first installment in the new saga:</p>
<ul>
<li>As most fans had surmised following the end of the previous chapter, Cirilla Fiona Riannon will be the protagonist. The previous actress (Jo Wyatt) has been <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-ivs-ciri-has-a-new-voice-actress/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">replaced</a> by Ciara Berkeley. Having Ciri leading the game also allows the development team to <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-devs-comment-on-ciri-as-the-new-protagonist-explain-that-player-agency-will-be-at-the-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">increase player agency</a> since she's just starting her journey as a Witcher, as opposed to Geralt, who had a lot of experience on the job.</li>
<li>There will be 'super compelling, very meaningful' <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-has-super-compelling-very-meaningful-romances-in-store-for-ciri/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">romances</a> in store for her throughout the game.</li>
<li>Gwent <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-dev-confirms-gwent-talks-about-ciris-new-powers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">is in the game</a>.</li>
<li>The Witcher IV will be <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-will-be-around-the-same-size-of-wild-hunt-devs-aim-for-quality-over-quantity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">around the same size as The Witcher III: Wild Hunt</a>, although the team aims for quality rather than quantity.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the financial report, CD Projekt RED revealed that 2024 was a solid year despite the lack of new releases. The studio almost reached $260 million in revenue, and the net profit line was the third-best in the group's history. CD Projekt RED also announced that it will soon become the owner of 100% of shares of <a href="https://wccftech.com/cd-projekt-acquires-drake-hollow-developer-the-molasses-flood/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Molasses Flood</a>, the Boston-based developer that's working on The Witcher spin-off called Project Sirius. As you might remember, the game was <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-project-sirius-molasses-flood-rebooted-new-framework-cd-project-red/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rebooted</a> a couple of years ago. Following the total control of the shares, The Molasses Flood will be fully merged into CD Projekt RED.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 4 Will Not Release Earlier than 2027]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-will-not-release-earlier-than-2027/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-4-will-not-release-earlier-than-2027.1144995/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-will-not-release-earlier-than-2027/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>CD Projekt Red’s recent statements indicate that The Witcher 4 could target next-gen PlayStation and Xbox consoles, as its release window has been pushed past 2026.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/the-witcher-4-wont-be-out-until-sometime-in-2027-at-the-soonest-cd-projekt-says/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PCGamer</a>, CD Projekt Red discussed The Witcher 4’s release window during their latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/DY-Q-Wd3Hz4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">earnings call</a>. During their presentation, the developers explicitly stated that the game would not arrive in 2026 twice, leading players to believe that the developers are targeting a 2027 release window and possibly next-gen consoles, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During the segment about CD Projekt Group’s incentive program B, it was stated, “Even though we do not plan to release The Witcher 4 by the end of 2026, we are still driven by this financial goal.” Then, during the Q&amp;A section, CD Projekt Red’s chief financial officer, Piotr Nielubowicz, stated, “We are not going to announce the precise launch date for the game yet.”</p>



<p>Nielubowicz added that right now, all they can share for “more visibility to investors” is that The Witcher 4 will not be released “within the time frame of the first target for the incentive program, which ends December 31, 2026.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Currently, CD Projekt Red has four different The Witcher projects in the works. The Witcher 4 is in the production stage, Project Sirius is in pre-production, and The Witcher Remake is in the concept phase. Cyberpunk’s Project Orion is also in the concept phase, and their new IP, Project Hadar, is in the IP concept phase.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Witcher 4 — Cinematic Reveal Trailer | The Game Awards 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/54dabgZJ5YA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, CD Project Red has hired <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cd-projekt-red-hires-50-new-devs-to-work-on-witcher-4-and-other-projects/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more than 50 new devs</a> to work on The Witcher 4 and other projects. Also, The Witcher 4’s Map size is<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4s-map-size-and-quests-are-more-or-less-the-same-as-previous-title/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> ‘more or less’ the same</a> as the previous game. What are your thoughts on The Witcher 4 not releasing earlier than 2027? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/moonshot-games-reveals-online-multiplayer-game-wildgate/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Moonshot Games’ new online multiplayer game</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pirates Outlaws 2: Heritage drops a brand new demo ahead of its release later this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/pirates-outlaws-2-heritage-drops-a-brand-new-demo-ahead-of-its-release-later-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pirates-outlaws-2-heritage-drops-a-brand-new-demo-ahead-of-its-release-later-this-year.1144992/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/26/pirates-outlaws-2-heritage-drops-a-brand-new-demo-ahead-of-its-release-later-this-year/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>While big blockbuster games like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows/">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a> and Call of Duty pull in huge audience numbers, there are games that quietly ramp up the player numbers without entering the global consciousness. That’s definitely the case for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1046300/Pirates_Outlaws/">Pirates Outlaws</a>, a game which racked up an astounding 3 million downloads, while accruing over 30,000 positive reviews on Android. Fans will be happy to find that not only will the sequel, Pirate Outlaws 2: Heritage, be sailing to iOS, Android and PC later in 2025, but they can already test out its roguelike deckbuilding charms via the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3025160/Pirates_Outlaws_2_Heritage/">brand new demo that’s just dropped on Steam</a>.</p>
<p><iframe title="Pirates Outlaws 2: Heritage - Official Teaser Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BGQCWKTN994?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Pirates Outlaws 2: Heritage is a swashbuckling roguelike deckbuilder. Collect &amp; fuse cards, gather powerful relics and adapt your strategy during each run. Become a reputed pirate, loot the Sea Masters, challenge giant creatures and triumph in the great Arena! In this sequel to Pirates Outlaws, a new era begins at New Elysia. Enter your mansion, pick a character, class ability and starting deck, and embark on a daring expedition!</p>
<p>Every character has several classes, and each one comes with a pre-made starter deck and one unique ability card. At the Alchemy shop, drinking elixirs alters each hero’s abilities, pre-made deck, and appearance. Also new is that you can recruit an animal companion and add their unique cards to your starter deck. It’s your job to discover the many possible strategies created by this combination!</p>


<p>The team describe the game’s key features as being:</p>
<ul>
<li>Combine Heroes, Classes and Companions – Each hero has multiple unique cards and abilities that can be combined with companion cards.</li>
<li>Customise your deck – Improve your deck along the way and try to build overpowered strategies</li>
<li>Enhanced turn-based combat – Each card you play affects a “countdown” towards the enemy’s actions.</li>
<li>Freely explore the map – Navigate between battles, revisit islands, stop by taverns, or trade at markets. Enjoy more freedom than ever before!</li>
<li>New card evolution tree – Collect three identical cards to level them up and choose how they evolve, adding new layers of strategy to your deck</li>
<li>Find relics that provide powerful outfit bonuses – When you complete an outfit, you receive its associated bonus.</li>
</ul>
<p>Pirate Outlaws 2: Heritage will release in Q3 2025, for iOS, Android and PC.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Full Three-Volume Hardcover Skyrim Library Is On Sale for Just $49.99]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/skyrim-library-on-sale-amazon-spring-sale-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-full-three-volume-hardcover-skyrim-library-is-on-sale-for-just-49-99.1144986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/skyrim-library-on-sale-amazon-spring-sale-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">This is stunning.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Even 14 years after its launch, The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim is still one of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-rpgs">finest RPGs</a> to date, with tons of deep lore to enjoy. That's The Skyrim Library, a three-volume collection of texts detailing its massive world and history, a must-buy for any avid fan. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now that you can <a href="https://zdcs.link/akRE73?object_uuid=0640381f-e18b-4c6b-a81a-7daa706490e0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">buy this collection for just $49.99</a> in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025">Amazon’s Big Spring Sale</a>, your bookshelves can become even more spectacular at a bargain. Just clip the coupon on the product listing for that additional savings.</p><div catalogid="1ade7db2-e22a-4f7a-a075-d9f688f9b8dd" id="217501"><p data-cy="paragraph">Originally released in 2017 at $110.00, this The Skyrim Library brings together gorgeous volumes— I: The Histories, II: Man, Mer &amp; Beast, and III: The Arcane— into a deluxe slipcase that can either be displayed on its own or fit neatly into your larger home assortment of tomes at home.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With each of its 232 pages thoughtfully written in impeccable detail and artistically illustrated, each book promises to immerse you in Skyrim’s history, its people, creatures, and the depths of its magical roots, almost as much as the iconic 2011 game had.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Going into some of the video reviews on its Amazon page, the whole package looks especially impressive. The outer slip case carries a distinct stone aesthetic and folds out to show a very well-done illustration of what appears to be Alduin.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The books themselves look just as high-quality, with embellished and raised text over the durable hardback cover—giving you that luxury feel every time you want to open one up and peek into the Skyrim universe without jumping into the game itself or checking your phone. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Written by Elder Scrolls developer Bethesda Softworks themselves, such a superb set comes as no surprise. Although their games aren’t short of imperfections with bugs, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/all-bethesda-games-in-order">Bethesda</a> always seems to go the extra mile when it comes to books based on their worlds.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re in the UK, <a href="https://zdcs.link/9YOgdl?object_uuid=0640381f-e18b-4c6b-a81a-7daa706490e0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">The Skyrim Library is also on offer for just £58.30 at Amazon UK</a>—a 35% price drop at the site's equivalent sale, Spring Deal Days. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Deals in Amazon's Spring Sale</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ben Williams</strong> – IGN freelance contributor with over 10 years of experience covering gaming, tech, film, TV, and anime. Follow him on Twitter/X <a href="https://x.com/BenLevelTen" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BenLevelTen</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Mar 26, 2025 8:16 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ark: Aquatica developer shifts blame for disastrous AI trailer onto marketing team]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ark-aquatica-developer-shifts-blame-for-disastrous-ai-trailer-onto-marketing-team</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ark-aquatica-developer-shifts-blame-for-disastrous-ai-trailer-onto-marketing-team.1144983/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ark-aquatica-developer-shifts-blame-for-disastrous-ai-trailer-onto-marketing-team<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>You may still be thinking about the recent trailer for Snail Games' Ark: Aquatica expansion, but not because it was so impressive it left a long lasting impression of wonder and awe. Rather, you probably still think about it because it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ark-aquatica-dlc-trailer-slammed-for-its-blatant-use-of-ai-slop">was so <em>unimpressive</em> with its heavy handed use of AI slop</a>.</p>
<p>"This is disgusting and you should be ashamed of yourselves," reads one comment on the trailer's YouTube page.
</p>
<p>But, who was to blame for the trailer, which at the time of writing has amassed over 480k views, but only 1.7k upvotes on YouTube?</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" title="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaSpf-70nc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"That [trailer] was done by our marketing department," lead game designer Matt Kohl told <a href="https://aftermath.site/ark-aquatica-ai-trailer-snail-games-studio-wildcard-youtube">Aftermath</a>. "They took our assets and then ran them through an AI to animate them. That was marketing."</p>
<p>Kohl reiterated that the development team "did not do that" adding "there has been no AI use in development of Aquatica". The designer said he didn't "have any knowledge" as to why the marketing team decided to use AI for Ark: Aquatica's trailer, which was revealed at GDC.</p>
<p>Kohl said we would all hear more closer to launch, but did highlight a brief gameplay trailer for Aquatica released by the developer, which you can see below. At the time of writing, Snail's marketing team is yet to comment on last week's trailer.</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ARK/comments/1jej5yh/trailer_with_actual_gameplay_from_snail_games/">Trailer with actual gameplay from Snail Game's ARK:Aquatica.</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/RathinaAtor/">u/RathinaAtor</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ARK/">ARK</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>As for Ark more broadly, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ark-2">Ark 2</a>, which was first announced all the way back in 2020, with a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ark-2-revealed-with-preposterous-van-diesel-starring-trailer">CGI trailer starring Vin Diesel</a>, is yet to materialise. Last week, developer Studio Wildcard said it was still "dedicated to the production" of both Ark 2 and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ark-survival-ascended">Ark: Survival Ascended</a>.</p>
<p>Additionally, we have <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ark-2-developer-acknowledges-missing-in-action-sequel">had a trailer for Ark expansion Lost Colony</a>, which featured the character played by Michelle Yeoh from <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ark-the-animated-series-surprise-releases-in-us-and-canada-ahead-of-april-debut-elsewhere">the Ark animated series</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>