<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 21:29:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Reveals New Details For Season 2: Hellfire Gala, Introduces Emma Frost]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-reveals-new-details-for-season-2-hellfire-gala-introduces-emma-frost/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-reveals-new-details-for-season-2-hellfire-gala-introduces-emma-frost.1154784/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-reveals-new-details-for-season-2-hellfire-gala-introduces-emma-frost/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/netease-releases-statement-on-western-marvel-rivals-team-layoffs/">Marvel Rivals</a> developer NetEase Games has just revealed new details about the upcoming Season 2: Hellfire Gala update that will go live next week on April 11, 2025. The new season adds X-Men Emma Frost to the lineup, and Ultron, who spoils the gala Frost is hosting in the Mutant nation of Krakoa.</p>
<p><span>This is also the setting of the new maps that'll be added with Season 2, which, according to a press release, will feature "<em>dreamy botanical landscapes and beautiful fireworks</em>."</span></p>
<p><iframe title="Season 2: Hellfire Gala Official Trailer | Krakoa Welcomes You April 11! | Marvel Rivals" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/thyG51IdChc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Weekly missions will also be added with Season 2 on top of the already included daily missions, just to give players a little more to do during the three-month-long season.</p>
<p>Speaking of season length, NetEase also revealed that beginning with Season 3, a season in Marvel Rivals will only be two months long, with a new playable character introduced each month.</p>
<p>For Season 2, the first half will introduce Emma Frost as a new Vanguard character, with Ultron, and details about his character type, still to come in the second half of the season. Season 2 will also feature the first time NetEase adjusts or removes certain team-up abilities, which means the game is about to undergo some of its first major changes.</p>
<p>Marvel Rivals launched at the end of 2024, and has so far accomplished what many big publishers have tried and failed to do, which is carving out a slice of the live service pie for itself. NetEase boasts that the game has grown to beyond <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-surpassed-40-million-players-tomorrows-patch-adds-nvidia-dlss-4-and-amd-anti-lag-2/">40 million players</a> since its launch, and it doesn't show any signs of slowing down. Marvel Rivals definitely has an advantage over games like Sony's failed <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-ceo-shares-learnings-from-concord-failure-reckons-psn-requirement-will-keep-pc-games-safe/">Concord</a>, which was also attempting to establish a new set of characters and a new world for players to enjoy, but as we saw in <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-avengers-shutting-down-soon-2023-content-canceled/">Marvel's Avengers,</a> a big IP backing up your game doesn't mean it'll be a smash-hit.</p>
<p><iframe title="Season 2 Hellfire Gala | Dev Vision Vol. 05 | Marvel Rivals" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LOuv0tO_aLI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>NetEase even admits in its developer vision presentation that the studio understands the pressure it is under to sustain the success Marvel Rivals has enjoyed so far. These changes coming in Season 2, which are still to be laid bare in the full patch notes still to come, could prove to be the beginning of a turning point for the game, with the next check coming with the arrival of shorter seasons in Season 3. This was a move made specifically to try to keep players engaged and not let the game stay too stale.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Virtual Game Cards Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/nintendo-virtual-game-cards-explained</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-virtual-game-cards-explained.1154781/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/nintendo-virtual-game-cards-explained<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In what may be the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-march-2025-all-news-and-announcements" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">last Nintendo Switch 1-dedicated Nintendo Direct</a>, the gaming company revealed Virtual Game Cards, a solution to moving digital purchases between Switch consoles and even lending them to family members who are part of your Nintendo Switch Online family account.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But how exactly does loading, ejecting, and sharing games work on Nintendo Switch and upcoming Nintendo Switch 2 systems?&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Loading &amp; Ejecting Nintendo Switch Virtual Cards&nbsp;</h2>

<p>For many of us who own multiple Nintendo Switch consoles and buy games digitally, the process of ensuring those games are actually playable is pretty daunting, since an internet connection can be required to load the game. Many players have solved this problem by designating a Switch Lite or OLED as their primary Switch and the console they use at home as a secondary Switch.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Virtual Game Cards are supposed to make this process simpler by allowing you to view your Virtual Game Cards on a designated menu and simply load or eject them between two consoles. The idea is to be able to play your digital purchase on either console without the need for an internet check, but being online is still necessary.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The fine print on the Nintendo Virtual Game Card page reads: "An internet connection is required the first time you start a game that you have loaded to your system. An internet connection is also required each time a loaded title is ejected."</p>

<p>So even though only a local area connection is required to change the games between systems, you'll need to be connected to the internet to actually launch the game. The two Switch consoles must be linked to the same Nintendo Account, and any user on that account has access to that game.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Virtual Game Cards management system in the Direct also indicated a simple drag-and-drop method of loading and ejecting cards between two systems. It will be interesting to see if the real thing is as seamless as they make it to be, but it makes sense with the upcoming Nintendo Switch 2 release that they want users to more easily share digital games between Switch 1 and Switch 2 consoles.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It's currently unclear if you'd be able to load a digital game onto a family member's primary Switch console if your account is on there as a secondary user, but you can at least lend games to other NSO members on your family plan.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Lending a Nintendo Switch Digital Game to a Family Member</h2>

<p>Up until now, letting family members play digital games you own has been a cumbersome process that usually involves setting your Nintendo Account as the primary user for the console they'll be using.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With this system, users can lend a Nintendo Virtual Game Card to people on the same Nintendo Switch Online family account. However, only one game can be lent per person at a time, and you can't lend the same game to multiple people at the same time. I suppose this is primarily to prevent one person buying&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/splatoon-3" rel="nofollow">Splatoon 3</a></em> and making it possible to squad up with three other people with just one copy of the game.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There's also an expiration: the Virtual Game Card will be loaded onto the second user's Switch for 14 days before it's automatically returned. Nintendo didn't clarify if the lender will be able to also play the game during this lending period, but seeing as Virtual Game Cards are supposed to be the digital variation of a physical game cart, it's likely not.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With that in mind, if lending Virtual Game Cards is supposed to be as convenient as lending a physical cart, it's extremely weird to have the 14-day limit. It would make sense for the person lending to have the ability to pull the card back at any time, but the idea of lending a game like <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/legend-of-zelda-breath-of-wild" rel="nofollow">Breath of the Wild</a></em> or <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-kingdom" rel="nofollow">Tears of the Kingdom</a></em> for only 14 days is absurd.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It's implied the lender should be able to lend the same game out again immediately after the 14 days expire, but this wasn't explicitly stated. For these reasons, those wanting to freely lend their games out with no restrictions may want to stick to physical media for the foreseeable future.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>What Are the Nintendo Virtual Game Card Limitations?&nbsp;</h2>

<p>As covered above, the main Nintendo Virtual Game card limitations include:</p>

<ul><li>Only being able to load and eject Nintendo Switch and Nintendo Switch 2 games between two consoles.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Only lend out one game at a time per person through the NSO family plan.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Games can only be lent out for 14 days at a time before automatically being returned to the owner.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>It does not appear like the owner will have the ability to play the game they lend out during this period.</li>
</ul><p>The Virtual Game Card is a solution to a problem that Nintendo created by not allowing digital games to be easily played and shared between different users. A platform like Steam has a much better game-sharing system, and I don't see a reason why Nintendo wouldn't adopt something like this to make their games be more easily enjoyed by more people, apart from the fact that they're Nintendo.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Are Virtual Game Cards going to be an easy and convenient way to swap digital purchases between consoles or just a cumbersome step that could potentially feed into an algorithmic marketing machine to better gauge gaming interests from a young age? Only time will tell.</p>

<p>Those concerns aside though, we did get a cool reveal in the fine print of the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/gaming-systems/virtual-game-cards/?srsltid=AfmBOoqItjD-H0JptkV-v6kE_8IJi01rkN1RUf-4Z3As7MmIE3FgGSh3" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Virtual Game Card webpage</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Did Nintendo Just Confirm Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Games?&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Yes. Yes they did, and in a disclaimer no less.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On the Nintendo Virtual Game Card webpage, they have the following disclaimer:&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Compatible systems must be linked to a Nintendo Account to use virtual game cards. Nintendo Switch 2 exclusive games and Nintendo Switch 2 Edition games can only be loaded on a Nintendo Switch 2 system."</p>

<p>There has been discussion for months now about if the Nintendo Switch 2 would ship Switch 2-editions of Switch 1 games, most notably <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/metroid-prime-4" rel="nofollow">Metroid Prime 4</a></em> and <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/pokemon-legends-arceus" rel="nofollow">Pokemon Legends</a> ZA</em>. This disclaimer looks to confirm that Switch 1 titles have the potential to also get a Nintendo Switch 2 version.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This falls in line with what we've seen from other companies – Sony and Microsoft continued releasing cross-gen games for a few years into the current console cycle. Though Nintendo has a history of making their consoles backwards-compatible (which we know Switch 2 will be), it usually reserves cross-gen games for special launch titles (<em>Twilight Princess, Breath of the Wild</em>).&nbsp;</p>

<p>Read More: <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/best-legend-of-zelda-games" rel="nofollow">The Best <em>Legend of Zelda</em> Games</a></p>



<h2>Virtual Game Cards in Spring 2025&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Available as an update in late April 2025, Nintendo Account users can start experimenting with Virtual Game Cards. As for the digital titles we already own, will those transfer and become a Virtual Game Card? I don't think we'll know for sure until the update actually drops.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nintendo Virtual Game Cards were a cool reveal, but I think in practice they're going to be much more cumbersome than they're worth.</p>

<p>Maybe this will be a fun feature for families with lots of kids who want to load and eject Virtual Game Cards frequently, but for a company that still sells a significant number of physical games, it feels like a half-step solution that won't be worth the trouble.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That being said, I'm looking forward to checking this out for myself in April when it launches and see if it's measurably better than the current system for digital purchases.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Dan is a Boston-based writer who has been with TechRaptor since the end of 2020. He has been working in the online writing, editing and SEO space for nearly… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/dan-rockwood">More about Dan</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How the Nintendo Switch 2 stacks up to the Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/642866/nintendo-switch-2-steam-deck-lcd-oled-comparison-specs-price</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-the-nintendo-switch-2-stacks-up-to-the-steam-deck.1154778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/tech/642866/nintendo-switch-2-steam-deck-lcd-oled-comparison-specs-price<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The biggest threat to the Steam Deck in 2025 won’t be the arrival of other Windows-based handheld gaming PCs. Instead, it’ll likely be the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/638604/nintendo-switch-2-direct-news-trailers-stream">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, which arrives on June 5 for $449.99 — smack dab between the cost of the $399 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23513517/steam-deck-long-term-test-valve">Steam Deck LCD</a> and the $549 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23951655/steam-deck-oled-review">Steam Deck OLED</a>. </p><p>Ironically, the Steam Deck is also the Switch 2’s biggest threat. While Nintendo’s new console may have Valve’s beat on screen resolution, refresh rate, and a custom Nvidia processor capable of DLSS and ray tracing, Steam trumps it in value, particularly with game prices.</p><p>I get it, I get it. They’re totally different devices. So even though comparing Nintendo and Valve’s hardware and software philosophies is an apples versus oranges exercise, the two devices — and companies — are more aligned than you might think. And that’s especially true when consumers, whether because of tariffs or other economic reasons, need to choose between one or the other.</p><p>You’ve come to the right place, as we’ll break down all of the specs worth caring about to show how they stack up.</p><div><p id="pricing-and-availability"><h2>Pricing and availability</h2></p></div><p>As mentioned, the Switch 2 and the Steam Deck have somewhat similar prices. The Switch 2 will launch on June 5 for $449.99 to start, though there will be a $499.99 bundle available for a limited time that includes <em>Mario Kart World</em>. Preorders go live on Wednesday, April 9th for the console, its accessories, and launch titles.</p><p>Valve’s Steam Deck doesn’t come with various game bundles, although there are two models to choose from: the $399 Steam Deck LCD (also known simply as Steam Deck) and the Steam Deck OLED, which starts at $549. Several specs, as well as storage amounts, differentiate the two. The Verge’s Sean Hollister has a review of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23951655/steam-deck-oled-review">Steam Deck OLED</a> that neatly sums up their differences. In the US, the Steam Deck is only available through Steam, Valve’s online game storefront. Internationally, it’s available through various stores.</p><div><p id="display-technology"><h2>Display technology</h2></p></div><p>This is where things get really interesting. The Switch 2 took many by surprise by featuring a 7.9-inch 1080p LCD touchscreen with a 120Hz refresh rate. Not only that, it supports VRR and HDR10. Compared to the launch Switch and Switch Lite, both of which had 720p LCDs of varying sizes (6.2 inches in the Switch, 5.5 inches in the Switch Lite), it’s a big difference in terms of added size, features, more clarity, and smoothness in how games appear onscreen. The same could be said for the Switch 2’s screen improvements over the Steam Deck LCD, which has a 7-inch 60Hz LCD touchscreen (with chunky bezels) without VRR or HDR support.</p><p>The Switch OLED’s 7-inch 720p OLED screen may be better than the Switch 2’s screen in terms of contrast and viewing angles, but the Switch 2’s is faster and better in every other metric.</p><p>The Switch 2 meets its match in the Steam Deck OLED. Many hoped that Nintendo would come out of the gates with an OLED display, but that still makes Valve’s $549 handheld special. The Steam Deck OLED has a smaller 800p touchscreen than the Switch 2 at 7.4 inches (but without the chunky bezels of the Deck LCD), but adds 90Hz refresh rate and HDR into the mix. </p><p>It’s a gorgeous screen, with stellar viewing angles and brilliant color reproduction, making 800p games somehow look higher resolution. Some may prefer the higher refresh rate and VRR in the Switch 2, which will allow the screen to quickly adapt to a fluctuating frame rate without tearing. The VRR difference is something you have to experience yourself, and it’s great to have in the Switch 2 as not many handhelds support it, save for the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/617613/lenovo-legion-go-s-review-feels-good-plays-bad">Lenovo Legion Go S</a> and select others.</p><div><p id="performance-and-battery-life"><h2>Performance and battery life</h2></p></div><p>There is sure to be more to come in terms of comparing performance between the Switch 2 and the Steam Deck. Hands-on time with the Switch 2 has been limited to a few games coming at launch, so you should expect more on how games available for both compare in terms of visuals and frame rate.</p><p>We can make some comparisons based on specs. Both the Steam Deck models use a custom AMD APU (bundling the Zen 2 CPU and RDNA 2 GPU) that plays a swath of PC games relatively smoothly at good-to-great visual quality with surprisingly good battery life. Not every game can take full advantage of the Steam Deck OLED’s 90Hz refresh rate, but that’s not a claim Valve makes. Some AMD’s FSR graphical upscaling technology is available in select games to reduce the render resolution of the image and upscale it using AI. In many cases, it makes supported games run better on Steam Deck, but with a major hit to visual quality.</p><p>On the other hand, I think Nintendo’s Switch 2 is more of a spec powerhouse than anyone expected. It uses a custom Nvidia processor, though almost no details about its power have been unveiled at the time of publishing. Nintendo is publicly targeting up to 120 frames per second in some games in handheld mode, with a 60 frames per second cap at 4K when docked, indicating that there’s quite a bit of potential in the Switch 2. Nintendo Switch 2 hardware engineers claim the console utilizes DLSS and ray tracing — key features offered by Nvidia graphics cards. It’s unclear how these features will be used in titles across the board, and if there are any downsides to its implementation.</p><p>Switching over to battery life, the Steam Deck has the Switch 2 beat, though for both handhelds it’s important to note that battery longevity varies wildly depending on the games you play. <em>Balatro</em>, for instance, is less taxing on hardware than <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>. The Switch 2 has an expected battery life between 2 and 6.5 hours. Valve’s Steam Deck LCD (which has a 40Wh battery) can last between 2 and 8 hours, while the Steam Deck OLED, thanks to its more efficient display and jump from 40Wh to 50Wh, lasts between 3 and 12 hours.</p><div><p id="storage-dock-and-more"><h2>Storage, dock, and more</h2></p></div><p>By default, the Switch 2 contains 256GB of speedy UFS storage that presumably cannot be upgraded by the end user. However, it can be expanded upon with microSD cards — but not just any will do. It’s one of the first devices to support microSD Express, which are classified as PCIe 3.0 NVMe SSDs, but are just as tiny as other microSD cards. The console supports up to 2TB capacities, though we’ve only seen up to 1TB models hit shelves so far (more will certainly show up in time for the Switch 2’s June 5th launch).</p><p>The Steam Deck offers more versatility. For one, all models come with M.2 2230-sized SSDs that can be upgraded by opening the system. Doing so doesn’t void the warranty, but you’ll want to be careful. Once inside, you can replace the SSD with something bigger. It’s unclear currently whether the Steam Deck’s built-in SSD is faster or on a par with the Switch 2’s internal storage.</p><p>If you want to supplement the SSD with more user-friendly expandable storage, each Deck also supports UHS-1 microSD cards. Those are slower than the Switch 2’s microSD Express cards, but they do the trick.</p><div><p><cite>Photo by Owen Grove / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>Both handhelds can be used as hybrids, either in handheld mode or docked to a TV. Speaking of their handheld use case first, the Switch 2 includes a versatile kickstand, while the Steam Deck doesn’t. </p><p>Placing either on a dock grants you more ports to connect to the console. The Switch 2 dock, which comes with each console, includes an HDMI port, USB-C for power, plus an Ethernet port for wired internet. The Steam Deck docking station is a separate $79 accessory that includes more ports, such as HDMI, DisplayPort, three USB-A ports, Ethernet, and a USB-C port for power.</p><p>The Steam Deck and Nintendo Switch 2 have USB-C ports that send video out to your display. However, only the Switch 2 features a second USB-C port, located on its top, which can be used to plug in peripherals, such as a camera for GameChat, or numerous other accessories to be released in the future. This Switch 2’s secondary USB-C port doesn’t support video out. In the case of the Switch 2, its dock unlocks more power capabilities, whereas the Steam Deck’s dock <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fsteamdeckdock%23%3A~%3Atext%3DWill%2520using%2520Docking%2520Station%2520increase%2520the%2520performance%2520of%2520Steam%2520Deck%253F" rel="sponsored">doesn’t increase its power</a>. </p><div><p id="games-and-software"><h2>Games and software</h2></p></div><p>The Steam Deck puts your Steam library at your fingertips. You’ll be able to play most of them on the Steam Deck, but how each game performs — including whether you can launch it at all, due to anti-cheat or other incompatibility reasons — varies depending on the game. Valve attempts to make it easy to know whether a game will work well on Steam Deck. If it’s “<a href="https://www.steamdeck.com/en/verified">Verified</a>,” that means you’ll probably have a good experience. If it’s “Playable,” there might be some controller-based difficulties that might negatively impact and otherwise good experience. “Unsupported” games are simply that — they either won’t work if you boot them, or Valve hasn’t tested them and doesn’t know what kind of time you’re in for. One defining feature of Steam is that the store hosts many sales, and Steam games can be legally acquired through third-party sites at big discounts. Games are often significantly more affordable by comparison to the Switch and other gaming consoles.</p><p>The Switch 2 supports almost all original Switch games, though <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nintendo.com%2Fus%2Fgaming-systems%2Fswitch-2%2Ftransfer-guide%2Fcompatible-games%2F%3Fsrsltid%3DAfmBOopHuS4GsXqD2aRPJwfKf5_kU7odM1BiStkhrlQBjoFQSVOAqSzR" rel="sponsored">there are some titles that have issues</a>. It supports them through a method “somewhere in between a software emulator and hardware compatibility,” according to <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nintendo.com%2Fus%2Fwhatsnew%2Fask-the-developer-vol-16-nintendo-switch-2-part-4%2F" rel="sponsored">Switch 2 developer Takuhiro Dohta</a>. This sounds somewhat similar to Valve’s Proton, a compatibility layer that allows Windows games to run on the Steam Deck’s fork of Linux.</p><p>Continuing on the Switch 2, there are “Switch 2 Edition” upgrades to select Switch titles that add flourishes allowed by the more powerful hardware, ranging from faster frames per second and higher resolution (<em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</em> and <em>Tears of the Kingdom</em>), as well as other Switch 2-only features, like GameChat functionality (<em>Super Mario Party: Jamboree - Switch 2 Edition</em>), or mouse controls (Metroid Prime 4: Beyond - Switch 2 Edition). Then, there will be Switch 2-exclusive games, like Mario Kart World, that can only be played on new hardware.</p><p>Games aside, let’s speak about the underlying software. The Switch 2, much like its predecessor, is focused almost exclusively on gaming. We don’t yet know whether video streaming services will be available. However, on the Steam Deck, you have the option to switch from gaming to “desktop mode,” essentially turning it into a Linux desktop. From there, you can install apps of your choosing, run a browser, connect Google accounts to it to type documents — anything that comes to mind.</p><div><p id="by-the-numbers"><h2>By the numbers</h2></p></div><div><table><thead><tr><th><h3>Specification</h3></th><th><h3>Nintendo Switch 2</h3></th><th><h3>Steam Deck OLED</h3></th><th><h3>Steam Deck LCD</h3></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Processor</td><td>Custom Nvidia chipset (details TBD)</td><td>Custom AMD APU</td><td>Custom AMD APU</td></tr><tr><td>Screen type</td><td>7.9-inch LCD</td><td>7.4-inch OLED</td><td>7-inch LCD</td></tr><tr><td>Resolution (handheld)</td><td>1,920 x 1080, up to 120Hz, VRR, HDR</td><td>1,280 x 800, up to 90Hz, HDR</td><td>1,280 x 800, up to 60Hz</td></tr><tr><td>Resolution (docked)</td><td>3,840 x 2,160 at 60Hz, or 1440p/1080p at up to 120Hz</td><td>7680 x 4320 at 60Hz, or 3840 x 2160 at 120Hz</td><td>7680 x 4320 at 60Hz, or 3840 x 2160 at 120Hz</td></tr><tr><td>HDR10 support?</td><td>Yes</td><td>No</td><td>No</td></tr><tr><td>Internal storage</td><td>256GB</td><td>512GB</td><td>256GB</td></tr><tr><td>Expandable storage</td><td>microSD Express (up to 2TB)</td><td>microSD (up to 2TB)</td><td>microSD (up to 2TB)</td></tr><tr><td>Sensors</td><td>Accelerometer / gyroscope, mouse / brightness (in console)</td><td>Accelerometer / gyroscope / ambient light sensor</td><td>Accelerometer / gyroscope / ambient light sensor</td></tr><tr><td>Ports (handheld)</td><td>2x USB-C / 3.5mm</td><td>USB-C / 3.5mm</td><td>USB-C / 3.5mm</td></tr><tr><td>Ports (dock)</td><td>2x USB-C / HDMI / ethernet</td><td>3x USB 2.0 / 2x USB-A / USB-C (power adapter) / HDMI / DisplayPort / Ethernet (dock not included)</td><td>3x USB 2.0 / 2x USB-A / USB-C (power adapter) / HDMI / DisplayPort / Ethernet (dock not included)</td></tr><tr><td>Wireless connectivity</td><td>Wi-Fi 6 / Bluetooth / NFC</td><td>Wi-Fi 6E / Bluetooth 5.3</td><td>Dual-band Wi-Fi / Bluetooth 5</td></tr><tr><td>Wired connectivity</td><td>Ethernet (docked mode)</td><td>Ethernet via optional dock</td><td>Ethernet via optional dock</td></tr><tr><td>Built-in mic?</td><td>Yes</td><td>Yes</td><td>Yes</td></tr><tr><td>Speakers</td><td>Stereo speakers</td><td>Stereo speakers</td><td>Stereo speakers</td></tr><tr><td>Battery capacity</td><td>5,220mAh lithium-ion</td><td>50Wh battery</td><td>40Wh battery</td></tr><tr><td>Battery life (est.)</td><td>2 to 6.5 hours</td><td>3 to 12 hours</td><td>2 to 8 hours</td></tr><tr><td>Charging time</td><td>About 3 hours 30 minutes</td><td>Not advertised</td><td>Not advertised</td></tr><tr><td>Game card slot</td><td>Switch 2 and Switch cartridges</td><td>N/A, uses microSD card (plus internal SSD)</td><td>N/A, uses microSD card (plus internal SSD)</td></tr><tr><td>Weight (grams)</td><td>399.16g (or 535.24g with Joy-Con 2 controllers attached)</td><td>640 grams</td><td>669 grams</td></tr><tr><td>Dimensions</td><td>4.5 x 10.7 x .55 inches</td><td>4.6 x 11.7 x 1.92 inches</td><td>4.6 x 11.7 x 1.92 inches</td></tr><tr><td>Starting price</td><td>$449.99</td><td>$549.99</td><td>$399.99</td></tr><tr><td>Available</td><td>June 5th, 2025</td><td>Now</td><td>Now</td></tr></tbody></table></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arkane's founder is open to the idea of making Dishonored 3, just don't place any bets on it actually happening]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arkanes-founder-is-open-to-the-idea-of-making-dishonored-3-just-dont-place-any-bets-on-it-actually-happening</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arkanes-founder-is-open-to-the-idea-of-making-dishonored-3-just-dont-place-any-bets-on-it-actually-happening.1154775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arkanes-founder-is-open-to-the-idea-of-making-dishonored-3-just-dont-place-any-bets-on-it-actually-happening<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content" data-component="article-header">
  

        <p>"We're talking about science fiction at this point"</p>

    </div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Much like many of you, I suspect, I too would love a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dishonored-2">Dishonored</a> 3, but I'm not entirely confident it will ever happen. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-are-shutting-down-the-studios-that-made-redfall-and-hi-fi-rush">Arkane Austin was obviously shut down last year</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arkanes-deathloop-team-are-making-a-marvel-blade-game">Arkane Lyon are making a Blade game</a>, which leaves little room for a <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dishonored">Dishonored</a> sequel. But is there any possibility of one happening all the same? Well, still no, probably, but Arkane Studios founder and Dishonored co-creator Raphaël Colantonio did recently say that he could at the very least see himself working on a follow-up.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
While on an episode of the Quad Damage Podcast (thanks for the heads-up, co-host Robert Yapp), Colantonio was asked if he'd have any interested in bringing back working on Humanhead Studio’s version of a <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/prey-2">Prey 2</a>. The developer expressed disinterest in working on someone else's games (don't forget Arkane's Prey just uses the name), but he did say this about a potential Dishonored 3: "I'd love to - I mean, we're talking totally hypothetically at this point - I could see myself working on Dishonored 3 right now because it's been so long that, you know, why not?"
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Quad Damage Podcast - Discover Raphaël Colantonio, the Genius Behind Arkane Studios' Success" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f_VP86VvwDk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Quad Damage Podcast - Discover Raphaël Colantonio, the Genius Behind Arkane Studios' Success</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f_VP86VvwDk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/f_VP86VvwDk?autoplay=1" title="Quad Damage Podcast - Discover Raphaël Colantonio, the Genius Behind Arkane Studios' Success">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_VP86VvwDk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Like all glimmers of hope, there was a caveat, as he noted "after Dishonored 1, the last thing I wanted to do for the next four years of my life was Dishonored 2. In general I like to create new stuff." 
</p>
<p>
None of this exactly screams Dishonored 3, but Colantonio did also say that both he, fellow Dishonored creator Harvey Smith, and current Arkane head and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/deathloop">Deathloop</a> director Dinga Bakaba all have their own documents about their own ideas for a sequel. "I don't think it would make sense to talk about it," Colantonio continued. "Which of those three versions will ever see the day, now we're talking about science fiction at this point. So many of the people [that worked on the series] are scattered around, and Harvey is not at Arkane any more. I'm not at Arkane, and Dinga is working on Blade."
</p>
<p>
So, there you have it. All the people formerly in charge of and currently in charge of Arkane all have ways they could take Dishonored 3, except none of them really have the ability to do it at this point in time. It's a shame Arkane likely won't be working on an original game any time soon, even if Blade looks cool, but I'll still keep my fingers crossed that something fresh - or even a Dishonored sequel - makes its way out eventually.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prime Gaming is Offering 23 Free Games in April 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/prime-gaming-is-offering-23-free-games-in-april-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/prime-gaming-is-offering-23-free-games-in-april-2025.1154772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/prime-gaming-is-offering-23-free-games-in-april-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Prime Gaming has returned with its free offerings for the month, and in April 2025, we will see the addition of Mafia III: Definitive Edition, Minecraft Legends, and more than 20 free games to the service.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-all-free-games-on-prime-in-april">All Free Games on Prime in April</h2>



<p>The 23 free games for April on Prime Gaming will be released in phases. The first phase, including this month’s highlights, Mafia III: Definitive Edition and Minecraft Legends, is available today. The following collection arrives on April 10, the third phase will be released on April 17, and the fourth and final set of games will be released on April 24. These games will be available through GOG Code, Epic Games Store Code, Microsoft Store Code, Amazon Games App, and Legacy Games Code.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Check out the entire list of 23 free games through Prime Gaming in April and their platforms below:&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-available-today">Available Today</h3>



<ul>
<li>Mafia III: Definitive Edition: GOG Code</li>



<li>Minecraft Legends: Xbox and PC via Microsoft Store Code</li>



<li>Gravity Circuit: Amazon Games App</li>



<li>Paleo Pines: Amazon Games App</li>



<li>Clouds &amp; Sheep 2: Amazon Games App</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-april-10">April 10</h3>



<ul>
<li>DreadOut 2: Amazon Games App</li>



<li>Endless Space – Definitive Edition: Amazon Games App</li>



<li>God’s Trigger: GOG Code</li>



<li>New York Mysteries: Power of Art Collector’s Edition: Legacy Games Code</li>



<li>Projection: First Light: Amazon Games App</li>



<li>Faraway: Director’s Cut: Amazon Games App</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-april-17">April 17</h3>



<ul>
<li>Gloomhaven: Epic Games Store</li>



<li>The Last Spell: GOG Code</li>



<li>Fashion Police Squad: Epic Games Store</li>



<li>Genesis Noir: Amazon Games App</li>



<li>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain: GOG Code</li>



<li>Berserk Boy: GOG Code</li>



<li>The Last Show of Mr. Chardish: Epic Games Store</li>



<li>Wild Country: GOG Code</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-april-24">April 24</h3>



<ul>
<li>Thief Gold: GOG Code</li>



<li>Troublemaker: Epic Games Store</li>



<li>Kraken Academy!!: Amazon Games App</li>



<li>Priest Simulator: Vampire Show: Epic Games Store</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-amazon-luna-games-for-april-2025">Amazon Luna Games for April 2025</h2>



<p>Apart from Prime Gaming titles, there are some Amazon Luna games to look forward to this month, too. Amazon Luna is a cloud gaming service that lets you play on devices players already own, such as a Fire TV. The service is only available in the US, UK, Canada, Germany, France, Italy, Spain, Austria, the Netherlands, and Poland. Interestingly, a multi-year agreement with Electronic Arts has brought Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order, Star Wars Jedi: Survivor, and Dead Space. Check out the current lineup for Amazon Luna games:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>SpongeBob: Battle for Bikini Bottom – Rehydrated</li>



<li>Hot Wheels Unleased</li>



<li>Bee Simulator</li>



<li>Thymesia</li>



<li>The Jackbox Party Pack 6</li>
</ul>



<figure></figure>



<p>In addition to the new games, Amazon Luna subscribers can continue playing Fortnite OG, Fortnite Ballistic, LEGO Fortnite Brick Life, Fortnite Battle Royale, Fortnite Festival, LEGO Fortnite Odyssey, Rocket Racing, Fortnite, Trackmania Starter Access, Fallout New Vegas: Ultimate Edition and Fallout 3: Game of the Year Edition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Amazon has offered to acquire the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazon-big-acquire-tiktok-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">entire TikTok platform</a>. Which of these Prime Gaming titles will you be playing in April? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-news-being-teased-by-bungie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marathon news being teased by Bungie</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Dev Says It's Feeling Social Media Pressure to 'Keep the Game as Exciting as It Has Been Since December,' Announced Big Season 3 Shake-U]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-dev-says-its-feeling-social-media-pressure-to-keep-the-game-as-exciting-as-it-has-been-since-december-announced-big-season-3-shake-up</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-dev-says-its-feeling-social-media-pressure-to-keep-the-game-as-exciting-as-it-has-been-since-december-announced-big-season-3-shake-u.1154769/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-dev-says-its-feeling-social-media-pressure-to-keep-the-game-as-exciting-as-it-has-been-since-december-announced-big-season-3-shake-up<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">NetEase Games is fundamentally changing its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvel-rivals"><u>Marvel Rivals</u></a> post-launch roadmap to shorten its seasons and deliver at least one new hero every month as it battles to maintain live service momentum with its players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a major update to the existing content release schedule that was teased during the new <a href="https://www.marvelrivals.com/devdiaries/20250402/40954_1224468.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Marvel Rivals Season 2 Dev Vision Vol. 5 video</u></a>. Included in the 15-minute upload were details about how Season 2 will introduce its new Vanguard, Emma Frost, at launch April 11, as well as Ultron, whose class will be revealed closer to his mid-season launch. Both promise to keep Marvel Rivals fans on their toes with new abilities, but the real changes to how playable heroes will impact matches truly begin in Season 3.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In Marvel Rivals Season 3, which is currently without a release date, NetEase will shift season lengths from being three months long to just two months. It means major content updates will progress rapidly without changing <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-dev-promises-a-new-hero-every-month-and-a-half">the team’s initial promise to drop at least one new hero every half-season</a>. So, while you’ll have to wait a month and a half to play as Ultron after Emma Frost launches next week, that wait will be cut down significantly after the hero after that drops.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Since the launch of Season 1, we’ve been deeply contemplating how Marvel Rivals can continuously deliver fun and engaging experience for you all,” Marvel Rivals creative director Guangyun Chen explained in the Dev Vision video. “During this time, several discussions on social media have certainly added some pressure on us to keep the game as exciting as it has been since December. To a certain extent, we agree.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>With our goal of keeping the audience’s excitement alive just like our opening months, the real adventure with Marvel Rivals is just beginning.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Chen went on to explain that NetEase wants Marvel Rivals “to fulfill everyone’s fantasies about Marvel Super Heroes,” and that means exploring new modes and flooding the scene with a dense roster of varied characters. Following what he called “extensive internal discussions and thorough evaluations,” NetEase will adjust its systems to account for the increased flow of content. More information on how this will affect players will be revealed before the launch of Season 3.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“With our goal of keeping the audience’s excitement alive just like our opening months, the real adventure with Marvel Rivals is just beginning,” Chen added.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">NetEase <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-season-2-ushers-in-the-age-of-ultron-with-hellfire-gala-theme-and-emma-frost"><u>pulled back the curtain on Marvel Rivals Season 2</u></a> just hours ago, revealing that it will soon swap out its vampire takeover theme in favor of a new storyline that focuses on the Hellfire Gala. That means new fancy outfits, maps, and characters are on the way, with more information primed to be revealed in the coming weeks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marvel Rivals was a smash hit when it launched in December, securing 10 million players in three days. NetEase’s free-to-play superhero team-based PvP shooter launched on December 6 across PC via Steam and the Epic Games Store, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S. On Steam the launch was particularly huge, with 480,990 concurrent players. January's Season 1 then drew an incredible 644,269 concurrent players, making Marvel Rivals the 15th most-played game ever on Valve's platform.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But those concurrents have been on a downward slide ever since, which may have sparked the drastic roadmap change from NetEase. Still, Marvel Rivals remains hugely popular, and is one of Steam's most-played games. The launch of Season 2 will no-doubt prove a shot in the arm, and again with Season 3.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more on Marvel Rivals, be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-update-20250327-patch-notes-reveal-new-galactas-quest-easter-egg-and-hero-fixes-coming-this-week"><u>the patch notes for update version 20250327</u></a> as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/there-was-once-an-idea-for-a-marvel-gaming-universe-that-would-tie-all-the-video-games-together-like-the-mcu-but-it-didnt-get-funded"><u>why Disney decided to scrap an idea for a Marvel Gaming Universe</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prime Gaming members get 22 more games in April]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/prime-gaming-members-get-22-more-games-in-april</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/prime-gaming-members-get-22-more-games-in-april.1154766/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/prime-gaming-members-get-22-more-games-in-april<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Mafia 3! Minecraft Legends! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prime-gaming-april-25.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Amazon</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
April's upon us, meaning it's time to toss March's Prime Gaming offerings aside and ready ourselves with open arms for a brand-new batch - with this month <a href="https://primegaming.blog/prime-gaming-april-content-update-mafia-iii-definitive-edition-gravity-circuit-minecraft-19475b4ff9d3">bringing 22 more titles</a> to Prime Gaming members, including <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mafia-iii">Mafia 3</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/minecraft-legends">Minecraft Legends</a>, Thief Gold, and Genesis Noir.
</p>
<p>
April offerings - as is Prime Gaming's way - arrive across four scheduled content drops, with Amazon's first five titles available right now. This initial bunch brings Mafia 3's open-world crime capering, Minecraft Legends' colourful real-time strategy action, Mega-Man-inspired platforming with Gravity Circuit, dino-themed farming in Paleo Pines, and more.
</p>
<p>
Then, looking further ahead into April, Prime Gaming subscribers can brace themselves for Endless Space's 4X sci-fi strategy, Genesis Noir's wonderfully moody cosmic adventuring, acclaimed digital board game adaptation Gloomhaven, dark fantasy action-adventure <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/blood-omen-legacy-kain">Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain</a>, and Looking Glass Studios' retro stealth classic Thief.
</p>
<p>
You'll find the full list of April's titles (plus the digital stores they can be grabbed from) below.
</p>
<h3>Available now:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Mafia 3: Definitive Edition [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Minecraft Legends [Xbox and PC via Microsoft Store Code]</li>
<li>Gravity Circuit [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>Paleo Pines [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>Clouds &amp; Sheep 2 [Amazon Games App] </li>
</ul>
<h3>10th April</h3>
<ul>
<li>DreadOut 2 [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>Endless Space — Definitive Edition [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>God's Trigger [GOG Code]</li>
<li>New York Mysteries: Power of Art Collector’s Edition [Legacy Games Code]</li>
<li>Projection: First Light [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>Faraway: Director’s Cut [Amazon Games App] </li>
</ul>
<h3>17th April</h3>
<ul>
<li>Gloomhaven [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>The Last Spell [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Genesis Noir [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Berserk Boy [GOG Code]</li>
<li>The Last Show of Mr. Chardish [Epic Games Store] </li>
<li>Wild Country [GOG Code] </li>
</ul>
<h3>24th April</h3>
<ul>
<li>Thief Gold [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Troublemaker [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Kraken Academy!! [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>Priest Simulator: Vampire Show [Epic Games Store]</li>
</ul>
<p>
Alongside all the above, Prime Gaming subscribers in the UK, US, Canada, Germany, France, Italy, Spain, Austria, the Netherlands, and Poland get access to a rotating selection of titles via Amazon's cloud gaming service, Luna. This month, these include SpongeBob: Battle for Bikini Bottom — Rehydrated, Hot Wheels Unleashed, Bee Simulator, Thymesia, and The Jackbox Party Pack 6. That's in addition to Luna regulars <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-new-vegas">Fallout New Vegas</a>: Ultimate Edition, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-3-game-year-edition">Fallout 3: Game of the Year Edition</a>, Fortnite, and Trackmania.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Season 2: All Changes and Updates Coming Next Season]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-2-all-changes-and-updates-coming-next-season/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-season-2-all-changes-and-updates-coming-next-season.1154733/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-2-all-changes-and-updates-coming-next-season/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Marvel Rivals Season 2 is set to launch on April 11th, bringing a plethora of new changes to the wildly popular multiplayer title. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netease-promises-a-new-hero-each-month-in-marvel-rivals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Seasons will be shortened down from three months to two months starting with Season 3</a>, but there will still be plenty of new content to explore over the next few months.</p>



<p>Here’s the full breakdown of the changes coming to Marvel Rivals in Season 2, including the new heroes, new features, and gameplay changes.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-heroes-emma-frost-and-ultron">New Heroes: Emma Frost and Ultron</h2>



<p>When Season 2 launches, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-2-confirms-emma-frost-and-ultron/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Emma Frost will join the roster of heroes</a> in the Vanguard role. Emma Frost will be able to “adeptly utilize her telepathic and diamond abilities” while “standing at the fore front to shield her allies and obliterate her foes.”</p>



<p>Ultron will join a month and a half after the launch of Season 2, during the Season 2.5 update. Details about Ultron have not been released yet, but he will most likely join the roster as either a Vanguard or Duelist.</p>



<h2 id="h-costume-colors-and-costume-sharing">Costume Colors and Costume Sharing</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>New color options for some of the “more popular costumes” are being added in Season 2. Psylocke’s Vengeance costume and Luna Snow’s Mirae 2099 costume are just two examples of costumes that will have new color options. </p>



<p>A new feature that allows players to gift costumes and bundles to their friends is also going live with Season 2. When at the checkout screen for a costume bundle, players can select the “Gift” option instead of buying it for themselves. It appears that players will be limited to sending only five gifts a day.</p>



<h2 id="h-team-up-ability-and-hero-balance-changes">Team-Up Ability and Hero Balance Changes</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>For the first time since the game’s release, Team-Up Abilities are being either altered or removed. Since Marvel Rivals launched, Team-Up Abilities have only been added to compliment new hero arrivals. Here are the changes coming to Team-Up Abilities in Season 2:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>New</strong>: Emma Frost can team up with Psylocke and/or Magneto to form Mental Projection. Emma creates illusory clones of Psylocke and Magneto.</li>



<li><strong>New:</strong> Doctor Strange can share his arcane magic with Scarlet Witch to form Arcane Order, which transforms her right-click into a rapid-fire, long-range projectile that doesn’t consume energy.</li>



<li><strong>New: </strong>Captain America and Winter Soldier (finally) can team up with Stars Aligned. Winter Soldier can pounce forward and deal a shockwave pulse. He and Captain can pounce together to cause more damage and debuff nearby enemies.</li>



<li>Metallic Chaos (Scarlet Witch and Magneto) has been removed.</li>



<li>Voltaic Union (Storm, Captain America, and Thor) has been removed.</li>



<li>Psylocke has been removed from Dimensional Shortcut (Black Panther and Magik).</li>



<li>Winter Soldier has been removed from Ammo Overload (The Punisher and Rocket Raccoon).</li>



<li>Namor has been removed from Chilling Charisma (Luna Snow and Jeff).</li>



<li>Doctor Strange has been replaced with Namor in Gamma Charge (Iron Man and Hulk).</li>
</ul>



<p>Without giving specific details yet, the Marvel Rivals team also provided some information on who’s getting buffed or nerf in the next balance update. Here are the changes players can expect to hero balance in Season 2:</p>



<ul>
<li>Peni Parker, Scarlet Witch, Mister Fantastic, Black Widow, Rocket Raccoon, Jeff the Land Shark, Captain America, Winter Soldier, Moon Knight will receive buffs, either via increases to their power or through Team-Up Abilities.</li>



<li>Doctor Strange will get a nerf to his offensive power, but a buff to his survivability (health).</li>



<li>Loki and Adam Warlock are getting nerfs to their area-of-effect healing abilities.</li>
</ul>



<p>A deeper dive in the balance changes coming to Season 2 will be coming soon.</p>



<h2 id="h-changes-to-missions-competitive">Changes to Missions, Competitive</h2>



<p>Starting in Season 2, Marvel Rivals will implement weekly missions alongside the existing daily missions and challenges. Players won’t be able to earn more Chrono Tokens, instead those will be rebalanced across all three mission types. </p>



<p>On the Competitive side, some players might be disappointed to learn that ranked players will drop nine divisions at the start of Season 2. For example, a player that ends Season 1.5 at Diamond 1 will start Season 2 at Silver 1. The new map, Hellfire Gala: Krakoa, will enter the competitive pool, while Yggsgard: Royal Palace and Tokyo 2099: Shin-Shibuya will be “retired” from competitive play. </p>



<p>The minimum level requirement for competitive play is being increased from level 10 to level 15. The hero pick and ban system will also be implemented starting at Gold 3. Only duo queueing will be allowed when a team includes players that are Eternity or One Above All. And finally, the rank rating players receive will now be more weighed by individual performance.</p>



<p>The full Dev Vision video can be viewed <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=thyG51IdChc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>, and full patch notes will release closer to the April 11th launch date for Season 2 of Marvel Rivals.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-hits-highest-peak-viewer-count-since-2022/">Warzone’s hit its highers viewer count in three years</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia confirms the Switch 2 supports DLSS, G-Sync, and ray-tracing]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/04/nvidia-confirms-the-switch-2-supports-dlss-g-sync-and-ray-tracing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-confirms-the-switch-2-supports-dlss-g-sync-and-ray-tracing.1154730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/04/nvidia-confirms-the-switch-2-supports-dlss-g-sync-and-ray-tracing/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          <p>In the wake of the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/04/nintendo-offers-new-details-on-switch-2-hardware-software/">Switch 2 reveal</a>, neither Nintendo nor Nvidia has gone into any detail at all about the exact chip inside the upcoming handheld—technically, we are still not sure what Arm CPU architecture or what GPU architecture it uses, how much RAM we can expect it to have, how fast that memory will be, or exactly how many graphics cores we're looking at.</p>
<p>But interviews with Nintendo executives and <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/nintendo-switch-2-leveled-up-with-nvidia-ai-powered-dlss-and-4k-gaming/">a blog post from Nvidia</a> did at least confirm several of the new chip's capabilities. The "custom Nvidia processor" has a GPU "with dedicated [Ray-Tracing] Cores and Tensor Cores for stunning visuals and AI-driven enhancements," writes Nvidia Software Engineering VP Muni Anda.</p>
<p>This means that, as rumored, the Switch 2 will support Nvidia's Deep Learning Super Sampling (DLSS) upscaling technology, which helps to upscale a lower-resolution image into a higher-resolution image with less of a performance impact than native rendering and less loss of quality than traditional upscaling methods. For the Switch games that can render at 4K or at 120 FPS 1080p, DLSS will likely be responsible for making it possible.</p>
<p>The other major Nvidia technology supported by the new Switch is G-Sync, which prevents screen tearing when games are running at variable frame rates. Nvidia notes that G-Sync is only supported in handheld mode and not in docked mode, which could be a limitation of the Switch dock's HDMI port.</p>

          
                      
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty Just Hit A 2025 Record On Steam Following Verdansk's Return To Warzone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-just-hit-a-2025-record-on-steam-following-verdansks-return-to-warzone/1100-6530610/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-just-hit-a-2025-record-on-steam-following-verdansks-return-to-warzone.1154724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-just-hit-a-2025-record-on-steam-following-verdansks-return-to-warzone/1100-6530610/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530610">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The return of Call of Duty: Warzone's original map, Verdansk, appears to be doing its job of driving players back to the game, on Steam at least. On Steam, Warzone and Black Ops 6 are packaged together inside the overarching "Call of Duty" launcher--and player numbers are spiking.</p><p>Call of Duty <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">surged past 114,000 concurrent players</a> on Steam today, April 3, following the re-introduction of Verdansk to Warzone for the first time since December 2021. This is the <a href="https://x.com/charlieINTEL/status/1907864893702733843" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">highest player count for Call of Duty in 2025 so far</a>. It's still well below the all-time peak of <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1938090/charts/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">491,670 players</a> from November 2022, however. At 114,000+ concurrent players, Call of Duty is the No. 8 most popular game on Steam at press time.</p><p>Warzone itself is a free-to-play game, but it's not listed as such on Steam because it's part of the Call of Duty launcher that includes paid titles like Black Ops 6. It's not clear how many of the 110,000+ people playing Call of Duty on Steam are playing Warzone. Also unknown is how Warzone is performing on Xbox and PlayStation since the reintroduction of Verdansk.</p><p>Beyond the return of Verdansk, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-season-3-patch-notes-black-ops-6-and-warzone-update-adds-major-movement-changes-camo-hub/2900-6387/" data-ref-id="2900-6387">Black Ops 6's new Season 3 update</a> is live now with lots of new content, including more weapons, maps, and modes.</p><p>Call of Duty seems to be banking on nostalgia to revive Warzone's player count. A recent report said if the arrival of Verdansk fails to retain existing players and/or bring back lapsed players, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2026-could-drop-last-gen-systems-and-make-other-big-changes-report/1100-6529841/" data-ref-id="1100-6529841">there will be no "Warzone 3."</a> (For what it's worth, the current version of Warzone is a renamed version of Warzone 2.0). It's not clear what this means, though, or how Activision may measure success.</p><p>Beyond Warzone, a new Call of Duty game is expected to release in 2025, and it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/" data-ref-id="1100-6529073">could be a Black Ops 2 sequel</a>. It'll face stiff competition in the market, as Rockstar's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> is coming this fall. For context, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/2024s-best-selling-games-in-the-us/2900-5106/" data-ref-id="2900-5106">Black Ops 6 was 2024's best-selling game in the US. </a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Manufacturers Association Opposes New Trade Tariffs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/game-manufacturers-association-opposes-new-trade-tariffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-manufacturers-association-opposes-new-trade-tariffs.1154706/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/game-manufacturers-association-opposes-new-trade-tariffs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Game Manufacturers Association has made an official announcement regarding the recent United States trade tariffs. The organization has declared that they oppose the US' 54% tariff on Chinese Goods, stating that they will severely impact the entire US tabletop industry.</p>



<p>In an official press release, the Game Manufacturers Association explains its stance on opposing the newly implemented US trade tariffs. It states that the United States' 54% tariff on Chinese products imposed by the Trump Administration is dire news for the tabletop industry. This is because the vast majority of tabletop game manufacturing depends on producing the product overseas and then importing it to the US.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tabletop-dice-image.jpg?itok=DLvlC4wZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tabletop-dice-image.jpg?itok=LSqVOLdi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This will have devastating consequences on the tabletop industry. First is the obvious: trade tariffs are essentially taxes on the consumer. not the countries being affected. This is because, while the tariffs only affect import cost, publishers will pass this extra cost on to consumers. At best, this means prices for imported products will skyrocket. At worst, it will cause smaller companies to cease operations altogether.</p>

<p>The Game Manufacturers Association is not alone in this assessment. The <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/esa-trump-tariffs-comments" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">ESA</a> (Entertainment Software Association) has stated these trade tariffs would cause "significant harm to everyday Americans" and to the videogame industry itself.</p>

<p>The Game Manufacturers Association's statement adds further economic context. Nearly one-third of all US consumer goods are imported. This includes food, clothing, certain appliances and cars, and entertainment electronics like videogame consoles. Think the new <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-launch-lineup" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch 2</a> has a hefty price point? It may be a sign of what is to come. To quote the release,</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Not only will game prices rise, but everything will become more expensive, reducing discretionary income for entertainment items like games. This one-two punch is likely to put many of our members out of business or force them to downsize and lay off employees to survive. This will have ripple effects across all segments of the industry.</p>

<p>The US lacks the production capacity to quickly ramp up and create replacement products at affordable prices, contrary to the administration's beliefs. This policy is not well thought out and is doomed to fail. It will have major repercussions throughout the US economy and could lead to a recession.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In response to how these trade tariffs will impact the tabletop industry the Game Manufacturers Association will continue to oppose them publicly alongside calling on the US Congress to, "avoid wrecking the US economy in a misguided tariff war that is neither necessary nor needed."</p>

<p>The presser ends with a call to action for all US citizens to call upon their own local representatives and senators</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Title Update 1 Patch Notes: Mizutsune And New Skills]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-patch-notes-mizutsune-and-new-skills/1100-6530611/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-patch-notes-mizutsune-and-new-skills.1154700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-patch-notes-mizutsune-and-new-skills/1100-6530611/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530611">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Capcom released the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds/">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> Title Update 1 patch notes ahead of the patch's release, outlining what to expect from the action game's first big, free update. Title Update 1 comes just a few days after Capcom announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-hits-a-massive-milestone-free-item-pack-coming-to-celebrate/1100-6530490/" data-ref-id="1100-6530490">Monster Hunter Wilds sold 10 million copies</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Title Update 1 goes live on April 3, 2025, at 8 PM PT/11 PM ET, and you'll need a bit of extra space to fit it in.</p><ul><li dir="ltr">PS5 file size: 10 GB</li><li dir="ltr">Xbox Series X|S file size: 10 GB</li><li dir="ltr">PC file size: Six GB or, with high-resolution pack, 16 GB</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Capcom is adding a new monster mission and bringing back an old one in Title Update 1. After reaching Hunter Rank 21, players can take on an assignment to hunt a Mizutsune, a Leviathan-class monster, and unlock an additional, optional assignment to hunt more after completing the initial quest. Speak to Kanya in the Scarlet Forest base camp to start.</p><p dir="ltr">Once players reach Hunter Rank 41, Alma, the handler, will present them with a quest to hunt a Tempered Mizutsune. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-tempered-monsters-artian-weapons/1100-6529749/" data-ref-id="1100-6529749">Tempered monsters</a> are more powerful than their normal variants, so you might want to make use of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/does-monster-hunter-wilds-have-cross-play-and-cross-save/1100-6529521/" data-ref-id="1100-6529521">Monster Hunter Wilds' multiplayer features</a> to call in some help.</p><p dir="ltr">The update will also add a quest to hunt Zoa Shia, the monster players face at the end of Wilds' story campaign in chapter three. The Zoa Shia quest unlocks at Hunter Rank 50.</p><p dir="ltr">Capcom added new weapon and armor sets for both monsters, along with new skills, though the patch notes don't hint at what the skills do. There's no word yet on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-is-getting-layered-weapons-eventually/1100-6530504/" data-ref-id="1100-6530504">layered weapons</a>, though Capcom still has plans to add them in the future.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1382568133" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465712,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Monster%20Hunter%20Wilds%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:0,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/monster-hunter-wilds-review\/2300-6465712\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465712\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465712\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465712\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465712&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4448843-mhw_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/uADhnvZY.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1740409200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="uADhnvZY" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465712" data-src="/videos/monster-hunter-wilds-review/2300-6465712/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Monster Hunter Wilds Review</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">Title Update 1 adds the Grand Hub, a social area that functions similar to the village in Monster Hunter Rise and the Gathering Hub in Monster Hunter Worlds. In the Grand Hub, players can play minigames together, listen to The Diva perform at night, manage squads, forge equipment, and eat <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-recipes-and-cooking-guide/1100-6529743/" data-ref-id="1100-6529743">new meals</a> at the hub's canteen. The Grand Hub is where you'll go to start future event and seasonal quests, such as the upcoming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-festival-of-accord-blossomdance-event-overhauls-new-grand-hub-area/1100-6530345/" data-ref-id="1100-6530345">Festival of Accord</a>, and to pick up Wilds' new Arena and Challenge quests.</p><p dir="ltr">Arena quests are timed challenges to see who can defeat a specific monster the fastest. Challenge quests are limited-time fights against a specific monster where you have to meet specific equipment requirements to take part. There's also a Free Challenge variation, which is essentially the same thing, only without equipment restrictions. Completing both types will earn you pendants. Unlike decorations, pendants are just <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-seikret-customization-guide/1100-6529798/" data-ref-id="1100-6529798">cosmetics for you and your Seikret</a> and have no influence over your hunter's performance in battle.</p><p dir="ltr">That's in addition to a slew of balance changes--including an adjustment that makes Wyverian Melding cost more points--and bug fixes to issues such as input lag when you're pressing buttons during a conversation.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Monster Hunter Wilds Title Update 1 patch notes</h2><p dir="ltr">The full set of notes is below.</p><h3 dir="ltr">Major additions and changes</h3><ul><li dir="ltr">New monsters can now be hunted after meeting certain in-game conditions.</li><li dir="ltr">Mizutsune has been added. Reach HR 21 to unlock an extra mission that can be started by speaking to Kanya in the Scarlet Forest Base Camp. Complete the mission to unlock Mizutsune.</li><li dir="ltr">Tempered Mizutsune has been added and will appear when you are HR 41+ after completing the Mizutsune extra mission.</li><li dir="ltr">Zoh Shia has been added as a high-rank monster. Reach HR 50 to unlock a story mission that unlocks Zoh Shia.</li><li dir="ltr">New story, extra, and side missions have been added.</li><li dir="ltr">New weapons, armor, and skills have been added.</li><li dir="ltr">The upgrade limit has been increased for armor of rarity 5 and above.</li><li dir="ltr">The Grand Hub has been added. It can be unlocked by completing a tutorial mission that appears from HR 16.</li><li dir="ltr">The following features have been added to the Grand Hub: Barrel Bowling; the Diva; Arena Quest Counter; the Canteen; the Arm Wrestling Barrel.</li><li dir="ltr">The Expedition Record Board has been added to the Grand Hub, along with rankings for time attack quests.</li><li dir="ltr">Arena Quests have been added.</li><li dir="ltr">Challenge Quests and Free Challenge Quests (Challenge Quests with no equipment restrictions) have been added and will be made available at a later date.</li><li dir="ltr">New status ailments have been added.</li><li dir="ltr">New voice lines for Alma (the Handler) have been added.</li><li dir="ltr">An arena log page has been added to hunter profiles.</li><li dir="ltr">The Change Appearance menu in the camp now has an option to change Alma's outfit.</li><li dir="ltr">New pop-up camp gear options have been added.</li><li dir="ltr">New limited bounty categories have been added.</li><li dir="ltr">New voice lines, pose sets, and gestures have been added.</li><li dir="ltr">Preparations have been made for the Festival of Accord, planned to run from April 23 to May 6.</li><li dir="ltr">The following features will be temporarily modified during the Festival of Accord: the Handler's Outfit; Seikret decoration; the Diva's song list; the Grand Hub decorations; the Canteen's menu.</li></ul><h3 dir="ltr">Bug fixes and balance adjustments</h3><p dir="ltr"><strong>Based and facilities</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">After unlocking the Grand Hub, the Squad Information Counter will move from the Windward Plains Base Camp to the Grand Hub.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where consecutive uses of the BBQ Grill inside a tent could cause game controls to stop functioning.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue with the BBQ Grill where ingredients would be used but meal effects wouldn't trigger when a meal is canceled, such as when an Environment Link is disbanded.</li><li dir="ltr">Improved the response time for controls in all dialogue scenes, such as facility conversations.</li><li dir="ltr">The "Rest" command now requires 500 guild points, and investigations reward 10% more guild points than before.</li><li dir="ltr">Increased the amount of points required for "Wyverian Melding" and "Meld Decorations" at the Melding Pot.</li><li dir="ltr">Increased the amount of melding points obtained from some items and rare decorations when using them as melding materials.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where meal invitations would sometimes be announced or show up in the Environment Overview at times when the invitation could not actually be accepted.</li><li dir="ltr">The "Transfer Items" option has been added to the Provisions Stockpile menu, allowing you to restock items outside of the tent.</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Missions</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where some side missions which required specific item turn-ins could not be completed correctly.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue that prevented the completion of side mission conditions during event quests.</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Monsters and endemic life</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where some monsters would stop moving in certain situations.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where some monster wounds would disappear unintentionally after performing certain actions.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where the game might crash after blocking a Gravios's attack.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where the introductory cinematic camera (used for newly discovered monsters) would trigger on monsters you've already discovered.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where the Smokeshroud Gekko endemic life would not appear in the Windward Plains.</li><li dir="ltr">Adjusted the behavior of some monster actions.</li><li dir="ltr">The distance between the monster and camera has been increased for certain monsters, such as Gore Magala.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where Jin Dahaad would unintentionally disappear from the locale.</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Player </strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where the hunter profile could not be edited properly.</li><li dir="ltr">Added a feature that lets you reset hunter profile edits.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where sneak attacks could not be canceled when using light bowgun, heavy bowgun, or bow.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where weapon pendants could appear in scenes where weapons are not displayed.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an unintended issue where large falling boulders could be blocked.</li><li dir="ltr">Lance: Made it easier to land thrust attack finishers after a focus strike in which the first hit causes large knockback.</li><li dir="ltr">Hammer: Fixed an issue where Focus Strikes could not be used quickly after coming to a stop after moving during a charge.</li><li dir="ltr">Light Bowgun: Fixed an issue that caused Wyvernblast to react to Palico attacks.</li><li dir="ltr">Palico: Fixed an issue that prevented stun and exhaust values from increasing when a Palico attacks a monster with a blunt weapon.</li><li dir="ltr">Hunting Horn: Fixed an issue where certain actions that required simultaneous inputs were not behaving correctly.</li><li dir="ltr">Heavy bowgun and light bowgun ranged attack capabilities have been adjusted when riding a Seikret.</li><li dir="ltr">The effects of the Corrupted Mantle have been adjusted.</li><li dir="ltr">The Rocksteady Mantle's damage mitigation has been increased.</li><li dir="ltr">Mending Mantle and Evasion Mantle durations have been increased.</li><li dir="ltr">Bow: Dragon Piercer damage has been decreased.</li><li dir="ltr">Bow: Power Volley elemental values have been increased.</li><li dir="ltr">Bow: Thousand Dragons damage has been increased. This includes when using Close-range Coating and Power Coating.</li><li dir="ltr">Bow: Power Shot and Power Volley are now affected by the skill Charge Master.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where Opening Shot did not work with special ammo.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue that caused Support Hunters to be unable to reach certain areas.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue that prevented guest players from receiving the effects of Rosso's Demon Ammo, Armor Ammo, and Recover Ammo.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue that resulted in guest players not seeing any visual change when a Support Hunter would equip a mantle.</li><li dir="ltr">Adjusted the rate at which Support Hunters use certain items.</li><li dir="ltr">Adjusted the distance that the Handler keeps from the monster during hunts.</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miscellaneous</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">There will now be login bonus days that include a free meal voucher (one out of the different types).</li><li dir="ltr">Login bonuses now include at least one Barrel Bowling Voucher every day.</li><li dir="ltr">Improvements were made to VRAM usage, and the DirectStorage version has been upgraded.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue that prevented pigment information from being included in shared loadouts.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue with some display settings on the character models on the title screen and save data selection screen.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where the model display toggle for pendants would not function properly when previewing armor.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue with the visual effects of the Hope Charm.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue so that other Link Members are now properly prioritized to be displayed in Base Camps and other shared locations.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue that made communication errors more likely to occur when firing an SOS Flare right after the start of a quest.</li><li dir="ltr">Background color has been changed to black for areas outside of the game's rendering range.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where a squad leader leaving a squad would not correctly transfer leader rights to the sub-leader.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue that made it impossible in some instances to obtain the Powercharm or Armorcharm even after fulfilling the requirements to do so. If you have fulfilled the requirements and have not obtained the items, they can be re-obtained after proceeding through another Quest Results screen.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where some NPC dialogue would be cut off when completing certain story assignments by capturing the target.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where accepting an Investigation but failing to depart (due to a communication error or similar) would still reduce the number of times you can accept that Investigation.</li><li dir="ltr">Failing to join another quest while already in the middle of a quest will now forcibly end the current quest and take you back to base.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue that would prevent game progress after departing on a quest while performing platform-related invitations.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where quest party size limits would not work as intended when performing certain actions.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where a quest would not appear in an SOS Flare Quests search if the quest host fires the SOS Flare but then leaves the quest.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where the stated number of Pop-up Camps and their locations would not match up with their actual data in some situations.</li><li dir="ltr">Adjusted the placement of some ore deposits to make them easier to gather while riding the Seikret.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed an issue where some voice lines would not trigger properly.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed various text issues.</li><li dir="ltr">Fixed other miscellaneous issues.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Says The eShop Is Better On Switch 2, But Offers Vague Answer About Stick Drift]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-stick-drift-joy-con-eshop-fix-better-nintendo-1851774614</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-says-the-eshop-is-better-on-switch-2-but-offers-vague-answer-about-stick-drift.1154664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/switch-2-stick-drift-joy-con-eshop-fix-better-nintendo-1851774614<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo claims that it has built better, nicer controllers to help avoid <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/joy-con-drift-is-becoming-a-real-problem-on-the-switch-1836417809&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/joy-con-drift-is-becoming-a-real-problem-on-the-switch-1836417809">stick drift</a></span> on the Switch 2, and that it’s made the new console’s eShop snappier and easier to use. But the company’s answers haven’t fully convinced me that we shouldn’t be worried as we approach the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502">Switch 2's launch on June 5.</a></span></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195670" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="184" data-playlist="195670,196181,196230" data-current="195670"><div><p>This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21167.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>In a roundtable interview with press about the upcoming console, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502">Nintendo Switch 2</a></span> producer Kouichi Kawamoto was asked about the console’s eShop and he made it clear that using the digital storefront should be a great experience, like it was back on the Wii. </p><p> “Maybe this is a little bit controversial, but in terms of applications on the Wii, I probably booted the Wii shopping channel the most out of any application,” said Kawamoto, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamesradar.com/games/switch-2s-producer-made-requests-in-great-detail-and-great-amounts-to-make-sure-the-eshop-is-as-good-as-the-wii-shop-channel/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/switch-2s-producer-made-requests-in-great-detail-and-great-amounts-to-make-sure-the-eshop-is-as-good-as-the-wii-shop-channel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">as reported by <em>Eurogamer</em></a></span> who attended the roundtable event. <em>Kotaku</em> wasn’t invited. </p><p> “So when it comes to the eShop, I wanted to make sure that it was a smooth experience, that the scrolling of the list doesn’t stop, that it’s very smooth, pages load fast. These are all requests that I made to the team in great detail and great amounts.” </p><p>Switch 2 technical director Tetsuya Sasaki says that the team worked really hard to “make Mr. Kawamoto happy,” including the various people who worked on the console’s network service, server apps, software, and more.</p><p>This sounds great, and is a much-needed improvement over the old Switch. Trying to navigate that console’s eShop is about as fun as pulling teeth. Things take forever to load, menus are unresponsive, and the shop is filled with garbage. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248">And while it sounds like you’ll still have to navigate through awful slop</a></span> to buy games you care about, at least you can speed by the crap you don’t care about faster on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-backwards-compatibility-list-start-up-issues-1851774297&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-backwards-compatibility-list-start-up-issues-1851774297">Switch 2</a></span>. Lovely. </p><p>Of course, the topic of stick drift also came up during the roundtable. Since basically day one, the Switch has suffered from Joy-Con sticks drifting and becoming hard to use as a result.<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-joy-con-drift-fix-repair-center-replace-1848828886&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-joy-con-drift-fix-repair-center-replace-1848828886"> This has led to a lot of costly repairs for Nintendo</a></span> and damaged the console’s reputation. So I was really hoping for a better answer when Nintendo was asked about this big problem and if the Switch 2 would avoid it. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-addresses-joy-con-drift-in-switch-2-says-new-console-will-have-better-wireless-connectivity&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-addresses-joy-con-drift-in-switch-2-says-new-console-will-have-better-wireless-connectivity" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">That’s not what we got.</a></span></p><p>“As you may have witnessed and felt, the new Joy-Con 2 controllers for the Nintendo Switch 2 have been really designed from the ground up from scratch, and they have been designed to have bigger movement and smoother movement,” said Switch 2 hardware design lead Tetsuya Sasaki.</p><p>So the controllers are better and totally new. That’s nice. But it doesn’t answer the question. You’d like to think, after all the headaches Nintendo dealt with during the Switch’s lifespan, that stick drift would be a big priority for the company on its next console. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-release-date-joycon-drift-repair-1850825084?_gl=1*d5lrqg*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MzY5OTc4NC41OC4wLjE3NDM2OTk3ODQuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-release-date-joycon-drift-repair-1850825084?_gl=1*d5lrqg*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MzY5OTc4NC41OC4wLjE3NDM2OTk3ODQuNjAuMC4w">And this answer, along with some patents, seems to indicate that it is working to make sure the issue doesn’t return for Switch 2.</a></span> But for now, we’ll have to wait until Switch 2 arrives in June to see if the new and improved Joy-Cons avoid the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/valve-hopes-to-avoid-thumbstick-drift-on-the-steam-deck-1847313237&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/valve-hopes-to-avoid-thumbstick-drift-on-the-steam-deck-1847313237">dreaded drift</a></span>. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last of Us Part 2 on PC Struggles To Beat PS4 Performance in Some Ways]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/last-of-us-part-2-on-pc-struggles-beat-ps4/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/last-of-us-part-2-on-pc-struggles-to-beat-ps4-performance-in-some-ways.1154661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/last-of-us-part-2-on-pc-struggles-beat-ps4/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Digital Foundry has published an in-depth technical review for The Last of Us Part II Remastered on PC, which was released earlier today. While it has been regarded as an improvement over the woeful release of The Last of Us Part I on PC, it’s still <strong>not as good as it could be</strong>.</p>



<p>In some aspects, The Last of Us Part II on PC performs worse – or not as well as you’d expect comparatively – than the base PlayStation 4, which was released in 2013. For instance, Digital Foundry found that a GPU with more than three times the compute power of the base PS4 wasn’t able to consistently double the performance of The Last of Us Part II on PlayStation 4.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-in-the-weeds">In The Weeds</h2>



<p>Digital Foundry’s comprehensive technical review of The Last of Us Part II Remastered on PC is pretty insane. It’s fifteen minutes long, and it takes the time to dive into absolutely every aspect of the game, from frame rates and load speeds, and from texture clarity to settings optimisation.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Last of Us Part 2 PC Review - We're Disappointed - Analysis + Optimised Settings" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z0IoZxiv1i0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>The team mentioned that the game’s usage of GPU resources is ‘a bit inordinate’, comparing the figures between a base PS4 and an RTX 3060 GPU. The PC GPU should be able to walk rings around the PlayStation 4’s tech, but that’s not what’s happening with this game, as DF explains:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We should be looking at a GPU that is around 3.5 times <strong>more </strong>performant in compute, even at a non-boosted clock. Yet the RTX 3060 cannot fully double the PS4’s performance in this game at the closest equivalent settings.</p>



<p>This is a very large outlier in our history of examining PC ports.</p>



<p>Whether or not that’s justified is up to the jury, but that means you as a user will have to adjust your expectations accordingly. You really don’t want to drop below those PS4 settings, as I see it, as you’re getting a visual experience worse than a 12-year-old console at that point.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>DF also revealed that stuttering and framerate drops were fairly common, and at one point, they reveal that the game would lock up without any prior warning before leaping back into life a few seconds later. They also detected issues with shadows popping in at odd times – even on maxed-out settings. </p>



<p>These issues weren’t present on the PS4 Pro backwards-compatible version of the game on PS5.</p>



<p>Have you played The Last of Us Part II Remastered on PC yet? Let me know if you’re having issues in the comments or on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-hits-highest-peak-viewer-count-since-2022/">Warzone’s viewer count is soaring</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto 5 Enhanced Comes to Xbox Game Pass for PC in 2 Weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-comes-to-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-in-2-weeks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-comes-to-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-in-2-weeks.1154655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-comes-to-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-in-2-weeks<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A triumphant return to Microsoft's gaming service.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft will bring Rockstar Games’ <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">Grand Theft Auto 5</a> to Xbox Game Pass and GTA 5 Enhanced to Game Pass for PC on April 15.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This striking addition to the Wave 1 April 2025 lineup was announced in an <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/04/03/grand-theft-auto-v-game-pass-gtav-enhanced-april-15/?ocid=Announce_soc_omc_xbo_tw_Photo_lrn_4.3.1" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Xbox Wire post</u></a>, revealing that the service’s biggest new title of the month is only a few weeks away from dropping. It’s an especially enticing reveal, as the PC Game Pass version of GTA 5 comes with that all-new Enhanced update Rockstar dropped in early March.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“No matter what version you’re playing, everyone will have access to <em>Oscar Guzman Flies Again</em>, the latest update where you can take to the skies — taking control of the McKenzie Field Hanger in Grapeseed,” an official description from Xbox explained. “Play new arms trafficking missions, fly new aircraft, and more.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Its arrival in two Tuesdays will mark a triumphant return to Game Pass after Rockstar’s open-world masterpiece was previously removed from the service. However, while the addition will mark the title's first time on PC Game Pass, it’s not all sunshine and rainbows as far as many die-hard GTA fans are concerned.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-online-on-pc-is-finally-catching-up-with-console-versions"><u>GTA 5 Enhanced arrived on PC March 4</u></a> as a free update, bringing access to all the latest vehicles, performance upgrades in Hao’s Special Works, animal encounters, and visual bumps. It was a promising addition that also resulted in GTA 5 becoming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstars-grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-now-the-worst-user-reviewed-gta-on-steam"><u>Rockstar’s worst-reviewed title on Steam</u></a> as players latched onto account migration issues that kept them from bringing their GTA Online profiles over to the new version.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re a newcomer to Los Santos, then you likely won’t have much to worry about. If you’re returning to the world of GTA 5 Online and looking to migrate your account over to that shiny new Enhanced upgrade, you might find yourself out of luck. For now, it appears the issues with account migration are still ongoing.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every Celebrity in GTA 5 and GTA Online</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, we’re still waiting for any news about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi"><u>Grand Theft Auto 6</u></a>. Our last GTA 6 update ensured that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-release-date-still-set-for-fall-2025-take-two-ceo-insists-we-feel-really-good-about-it"><u>Rockstar intended to deliver its next open-world trend-setter sometime this fall</u></a>, though we’re <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/when-will-gta-6-trailer-2-come-out-take-two-boss-says-its-better-to-provide-marketing-materials-relatively-close-to-the-release-window"><u>still waiting on that elusive release date</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Rockstar works out the kinks ahead of GTA 5’s return to Game Pass, you can read up on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-reveals-xbox-game-pass-april-2025-wave-1-lineup"><u>the rest of the Wave 1 April 2025 titles coming to Xbox Game Pass</u></a>. You can also read up on how Rockstar is supporting the modding community by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstar-owned-modding-team-working-on-official-grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-conversion-tool"><u>granting them access to official tools</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom Are Getting Achievements on Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-are-getting-achievements-on-nintendo-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-are-getting-achievements-on-nintendo-switch-2.1154652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-are-getting-achievements-on-nintendo-switch-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Build the legend all over again.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Both The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom are getting Nintendo Switch 2 versions for the new console. Alongside the in-game upgrades, Nintendo's adding a number of additional features through the new Zelda Notes option in its Nintendo Switch App, including achievements.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch App (formerly known as the Nintendo Switch Online App) will get an update adding Zelda Notes, a game-specific service exclusive to the Nintendo Switch 2 versions of both Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This app was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-nintendo-switch-2-will-improve-switch-1-games">shown off in the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct</a>, allowing players to use GPS-style navigation to reach landmarks in the Zelda games. For achievements, the app will track your play data and allow players to earn in-app medals based on their records. These account for opening chests, earning rupees, and more.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In the Achievements section, Nintendo lists categories such as "Quests and Adventures Cleared," "Shrines of Light Cleared," "Locations Visited," "Lightroots Unlocked," and others. Alongside tracking those numbers, the app will also let you see how you match up with other players on a global scale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the achievements seem geared towards completion, it's interesting to see Nintendo experiment with these options. Granted, they exist in a phone app rather than on the Switch 2 console by itself, but I am curious to see whether other games get similar treatments in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other features of the Zelda Notes app include a Daily Bonus option for helpful resources, a Voice Memories section which adds more story and lore to the world as you explore, and an Autobuild Sharing tool. These do seem like handy tools, and especially geared towards people playing through this Zelda duology for the second time on their Nintendo Switch 2.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch 2 has a launch date set for June 5, 2025. Both Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom will have Switch 2 editions at launch, alongside a slew of other games both new and refreshed. Previews dropped this morning for some of the launch window games for the Nintendo Switch 2, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-for-nintendo-switch-2-first-hands-on-preview">Mario Kart World</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-first-hands-on-preview">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-played-nintendo-switch-2-first-hands-on-preview">general hands-on impressions of the console</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking for everything announced at the Direct for this upcoming console, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-direct-everything-announced">be sure to check out our recap of all the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct news here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World Video Suggests There Are 84 Characters, Including Costume Variants]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-world-video-suggests-there-are-84-characters-including-costume-variants/1100-6530608/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-video-suggests-there-are-84-characters-including-costume-variants.1154646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-world-video-suggests-there-are-84-characters-including-costume-variants/1100-6530608/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530608">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Following the announcement of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/" data-ref-id="1100-6528874">Mario Kart World</a> this week for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Switch 2</a>, Nintendo showed off even more gameplay footage during a Treehouse Live event, and more information about the game has come to light.</p><p>Social media user BearUNLV clipped a segment from the broadcast that shows the Mario Kart World character-select screen. There are three rows of four characters on one page for a total of 12, with seven tabs shown at the bottom of the screen. If each tab has 12 characters, this suggests there are a whopping <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-mario-kart-9-racer/2900-6141/" data-ref-id="2900-6141">84 characters in Mario Kart World</a>.</p><p>A <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@ign/video/7488860529600285998?_r=1&amp;_t=ZT-8vEQLcI9xSV" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">subsequent video from IGN runs through</a> the characters and costumes, featuring 60 in all, including costume variants like Gondolier Luigi and Yakuta Peach. The IGN video features five tabs as opposed to seven tabs in the official Nintendo video.</p><p>For comparison, Mario Kart 8 Deluxe for Switch had 36 characters, including those featured in the base game and through DLC. It hasn't been explicitly confirmed as of yet if Mario Kart World does indeed have 84 characters; since we haven't seen the full roster, it's unknown. But Mario Kart World appears to be aiming to be a bigger Mario Kart game overall, so a larger character roster wouldn't be a surprise.</p><p>The new Mario Kart World video also suggests the game will have at least 28 tracks spread across seven Cups, along with 24 vehicles. Interestingly, it looks like Mario Kart World has fully formed vehicles; players seemingly no longer select individual parts to assemble a car.</p><p>One major lingering question that remains unanswered for Mario Kart World is if the game will have DLC characters and courses like Mario Kart 8 Deluxe did.</p><p>Another video from the event showed the stage DK Spaceport, which includes a segment at the end that recreates the classic 1981 arcade game Donkey Kong. As you can see in the video below, racers have to dodge barrels that a giant DK is tossing down at them right at the race's finish. With up to 24 players competing at a time--the most ever for the Mario Kart series--things may get pretty chaotic.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/Stealth40k/status/1907857457340448811" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">At the end of the DK Spaceport stage in Mario Kart World, they've recreated the arcade classic. <br>A very cool ending to a track, especially when you have that many racers at once trying to dodge barrels. <a href="https://t.co/WSf0z52RO4" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/WSf0z52RO4</a></p>  — Stealth (@Stealth40k) <a href="https://twitter.com/Stealth40k/status/1907857457340448811?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 3, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Mario Kart World appears to be a larger-scale Mario Kart game with a price tag to follow--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-game-prices-reach-staggering-80/1100-6530563/" data-ref-id="1100-6530563">it will cost $80</a>. That's $10-$20 more than the current going-rate for AAA games. Price increases are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/will-tariffs-increase-switch-2s-price-why-the-console-and-games-are-so-expensive/1100-6530591/" data-ref-id="1100-6530591">necessary for the overall sustainability of the video game industry</a>, one retailer has said.</p><p>For more on Mario Kart World, which is a launch title for the Switch 2, be sure to check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-world-hands-on-the-conservative-switch-2-gets-a-bold-sequel/1100-6530583/" data-ref-id="1100-6530583">GameSpot's hands-on preview of Mario Kart World.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2's C Button Was A "Very Last-Minute Request"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-c-button-was-a-very-last-minute-request/1100-6530609/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2s-c-button-was-a-very-last-minute-request.1154643/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-c-button-was-a-very-last-minute-request/1100-6530609/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530609">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Nintendo Switch 2's</a> C button was a late addition, with a new interview stating it was added following a "very last-minute request."</p><p dir="ltr">The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-quietly-confirmed-the-switch-2s-c-button-in-nintendo-today-promo/1100-6530447/" data-ref-id="1100-6530447">Nintendo Switch 2 Joy-Con 2's mysterious C button</a> sparked debate ahead of the Switch 2 Nintendo Direct, where it was revealed to be a dedicated button for the console's Discord-like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2s-c-button-is-all-about-video-and-voice-chat/1100-6530539/" data-ref-id="1100-6530539">GameChat feature</a>. In a series of developer <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-17-gamechat-part-1/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interviews</a> posted on Nintendo's website diving into various aspects of the Switch 2's creation, Sumikazu Ono, a member of Nintendo's entertainment planning and development department, said the C button came as a result of making sure the GameChat feature was easy to use.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1408948724" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465857,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20System%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:330,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-official-system-overview-trailer\/2300-6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465857&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6530609&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465857\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4469338-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/P7d0cUEb.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1743603600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="P7d0cUEb" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch 2 – Official System Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">He said he thought the idea of having to pause the game and go to the home screen, find the right menu, make a chat room, and then return to the game (the way basically every other modern video game console does it) was "bothersome." That resulted in the idea of the C button.</p><p dir="ltr">"So we asked for a special button to be added while the hardware design was in progress," Ono said. "It was a very last-minute request, just before the controller molds were about to be made."</p><p dir="ltr">Ono said he thinks GameChat's ease of use, as well as the fact that the Switch 2 comes with a built-in microphone, will result in more players trying voice chat for the first time.</p><p dir="ltr">"We knew a lot of players would eventually stop using this feature if it wasn't easy to understand, so we worked hard to ensure it could be used easily to play with friends and family without any fuss," he said.</p><p dir="ltr">In the interview, Ono described GameChat as one of the Switch 2's "defining features," and that its origins came from trying to capture the vibe of a "student lounge" where people can gather not just to play games but also hang out.</p><p dir="ltr">"Until now, online play for Nintendo games has meant everyone coming together to play the same game," Ono said. "But more than anything, we wanted to create a space where people would naturally gather, whether it's to play the same game together, or different games, or even just to watch."</p><p dir="ltr">GameChat will technically require a Nintendo Online subscription to use, but can be accessed for free until March 2026, around nine months after the Switch 2 releases in June 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">In a previous developer interview, Nintendo said the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-could-have-had-magnetic-joy-cons-like-switch-2/1100-6530577/" data-ref-id="1100-6530577">Switch 2's magnetic Joy-Con 2's were originally an idea for the first Switch</a>, but the idea was shelved following a meeting with late Nintendo President Satoru Iwata where he gave feedback on the prototype.</p><p dir="ltr">The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-launches-june-5/1100-6530537/" data-ref-id="1100-6530537">Nintendo Switch 2 will launch on June 5 for $450</a>, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">preorders, including a Switch 2 bundle with Mario Kart World, going live April 9</a>. Nintendo announced a number of new first-party games coming exclusively to Switch 2, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-hands-on-red-faction-gorilla/1100-6530581/" data-ref-id="1100-6530581">Donkey Kong Bonanza</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-upgrades-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-revealed/1100-6530550/" data-ref-id="1100-6530550">Switch 2 versions of games like Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age creator's Stray Gods studio unveils demonic deckbuilder Malys]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-creators-stray-gods-studio-unveils-demonic-deckbuilder-malys</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-creators-stray-gods-studio-unveils-demonic-deckbuilder-malys.1154640/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-creators-stray-gods-studio-unveils-demonic-deckbuilder-malys<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Kickstarter campaign coming soon.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/malys-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Summerfall Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
If you found yourself bopping along in admiration to 2023's Stray Gods: The Roleplaying Musical, you might be interested to hear Dragon Age creator David Gaider's Summerfall Studios has announced its follow-up game. It's a "demonic roguelite deckbuilder" called Malys, and a Kickstarter campaign is coming soon.
</p>
<p>
Malys casts players a Noah, a former-priest-turned-demon-hunter, who's on a mission of vengeance to exorcise the infernal forces running rampant in a festering night-time city. "Expose, endure, and expel evil from the innocent possessed," teases Summerfall. "Confront your past, forge precarious alliances, and uncover the truth."
</p>
<p>
At the centre of all this demonic mayhem is the titular Malys, a being of "extraordinary cunning and power" and Noah's primary target. As players hunt the demon down, they'll deploy their deck of arcane tricks, finding unique combinations and strategies to withstand the city's horrors and expose the rot within. And if death wins out, they can always try, and try again.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" title="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eurogamer goes hands-on with Switch 2.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9CF8nQGolWY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Malys is written by Gaider - perhaps best known as the lead writer on BioWare's original Dragon Age trilogy - and it's promising to deliver a "unique take on a familiar genre, pushing the boundaries of roguelite storytelling and delivering a satisfyingly moody experience".
</p>
<p>
And that's pretty much all we know so far. <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/summerfallstudios/malys-exorcise-demons-on-your-hunt-for-an-ancient-evil?ref=t828fa">Malys' crowdfunding campaign</a> starts later this month, and Summerfall says the Kickstarter will enable it to "work closely" with backers to "ensure Malys is the best game it can be". The game itself is planned to release on PC this year.
</p>
<p>
Eurogamer's Ed Nightingale called Summerfall's Stray Gods "fascinating but flawed" in his <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stray-gods-a-roleplaying-musical-review-greek-melodrama-fails-to-reach-lofty-expectations">three star review</a>, but it was interesting enough that Malys should be worth keeping an eye on.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Report Reveals The ESA Expects Trump’s Tariffs To Have A “Detrimental Impact On The Video Game Industry”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-report-reveals-the-esa-expects-trumps-tariffs-to-have-a-detrimental-impact-on-the-video-game-industry/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-report-reveals-the-esa-expects-trump%E2%80%99s-tariffs-to-have-a-%E2%80%9Cdetrimental-impact-on-the-video-game-industry%E2%80%9D.1154610/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-report-reveals-the-esa-expects-trumps-tariffs-to-have-a-detrimental-impact-on-the-video-game-industry/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Immediately after Donald Trump announced his proposed tariffs that will go into effect this coming Saturday, April 5, and then a second wave on Wednesday, April 9, there was speculation across the video game industry as to how this would impact games.</p>
<p>So far, the sentiment is that these tariffs will have a huge impact on the video game industry, and the latest report from <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/esa-trump-tariffs">Game File</a> reveals that the Entertainment Software Association (ESA) expects the tariffs to have "<em>a real and detrimental impact on the video game industry.</em>"</p>
<p>Game File spoke to Aubrey Quinn, senior vice president at the ESA, who said that gaming hardware, for example, will be hit on multiple fronts, not just from the tariffs levied against countries like Vietnam, China, and Cambodia.</p>
<p>"<em>Any one product that a consumer would buy is likely to be subject to many of the tariffs announced, all compounded on top of one another,</em>" said Quinn.</p>
<p>It was already speculated that the tariffs on Vietnam and Cambodia, in particular, could potentially impact the pricing of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2s-price-could-go-even-higher-due-to-trumps-tariffs/">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, but Quinn's point is that there's more to gaming hardware that comes from other countries beyond Vietnam and Cambodia, which means that the base 10% tariff levied against all imports to the United States will only add on to the already high tariffs on specific countries.</p>
<p>Quinn did add, though, that the ESA remains "<em>optimistic that there will be a solution that doesn’t damage U.S. industries, ours included, and doesn’t hurt U.S. consumers</em>."</p>
<p>As we previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-is-selling-a-cheaper-region-locked-nintendo-switch-2-in-japan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a>, Niko Partners analyst Daniel Ahmad believes that Nintendo won't raise the price of its new console anytime soon, at least on the specific question of the pricing for the Nintendo Switch 2.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, we could still see things shift with these tariffs for the better, with the potential still remaining for a deal to be reached with exemptions for certain products, a lower tariff, or no tariffs at all being levied. Those deals, however, will take some time to set up with each impacted country, and in the meantime, we could still see the video game industry take a serious hit.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genki has a magnetic battery for the Switch 2 and a better Joy-Con charging dock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/642869/genki-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-cases-shells-magnetic-battery</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genki-has-a-magnetic-battery-for-the-switch-2-and-a-better-joy-con-charging-dock.1154607/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/642869/genki-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-cases-shells-magnetic-battery<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-liszewski">Andrew Liszewski</a> <span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2011, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>With every new portable console comes a mountain of new third-party accessories. We’ve already seen <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/642514/nintendo-switch-2-usb-c-camera-hori-piranha-plant-privacy">Hori’s Piranha Plant alternative</a> to the Switch 2’s USB-C camera, but Genki has announced a larger lineup of accessories designed to help protect the portable console while you’re playing away from home, plus some clever ways to keep it and its Joy-Con controllers charged.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/joy-station-pre-order">$49.99 Genki Joy-Station</a> looks like a sleek way to avoid the annoying juggling act of keeping more than two Joy-Cons charged, with some additional, well thought-out functionality. The Joy-Cons attach to two delta-shaped grips turning each pair into standalone controllers. Two Joy-Cons can be simultaneously charged using a USB-C cable while attached to the grips – useful for those times when you want to play and the Joy-Cons are nearly dead – but they also charge when the grips are reattached to the charging base.</p><p>Thanks in part to a larger screen, the Switch 2’s battery life is estimated to be between two and 6.5 hours per charge. You can extend that using <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/energy-pack-pre-order">Genki’s $69.99 Energy Pack</a> which is designed to conveniently magnetically attach to the back of the console and charge it at up to 30W speeds. The 10,000mAh Energy Pack is Qi2 compatible so you can also use it to wirelessly charge your phone, but the Switch 2 isn’t, so the battery instead connects to the console’s top USB-C port using a short included cable.</p><p>For gamers wanting added protection while they’re playing the Switch 2, <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/attack-vector-pre-order?variant=42025271623754">Genki’s Attack Vector is a $49.99 three-piece dock-compatible protective shell</a> that can be upgraded with a screen cover for an extra $10. Its most compelling feature is that it comes with three different sizes of sweat-resistant grips including a slim option designed for travel and a chunky option for maximum grip.</p><p>The $29.99 (or $39.99 with an optional screen cover) <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/force-field-2-pre-order?variant=42025278701642">Force Field 2 shell</a> is a cheaper alternative to the Attack Vector featuring a swing open design so you can detach and reattach the Switch 2’s Joy-Cons without having to fully remove it. It’s also dock-compatible, and allows for full use of the Switch 2’s folding stand.</p><p>If you’re simply looking for a way to keep the Switch 2 safe from dirt and scratches while it’s stuffed in a bag, <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/sleeper-case">Genki’s $42.99 Sleeper Case</a> features a hidden zipper and a soft wool finish inside and out wrapped around a sturdy shell the company describes as both “crushproof” and “virtually indestructible.”</p><p>Genki has also introduced a $19.99 Switch 2 screen protector called the <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/aegis-shield-pre-order">Aegis Shield</a>, and the <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/mimic-chest-pre-order">Mimic Chest</a>: a $19.99 plastic case sold in three-packs that each hold 12 game cartridges. All of the accessories are available for preorder now and expected to ship sometime in May or June 2025. If you want them all, <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/pre-order-genki-accessory-pack-for-switch-2?variant=42025332637770">Genki also sells the collection as a bundle</a> with either the Force Field 2 shell for $184.99 or the Attack Vector for $199.99.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon News Being Teased By Bungie]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-news-being-teased-by-bungie/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marathon-news-being-teased-by-bungie.1154601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-news-being-teased-by-bungie/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>More details and news about Bungie’s upcoming extraction shooter Marathon could be coming sooner rather than later. </p>



<p>On Thursday afternoon, the official Marathon Twitter <a href="https://x.com/MarathonTheGame/status/1907840558544072722" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">account posted</a> a “glitching” teaser video while updating its header image. Not long after that, the official PlayStation account also updated its header image to something Marathon related. </p>



<p>Other aspects of the game’s online presence such as its Steam page, Facebook, and YouTube were also updated. Lastly, a MIDA profile had been created on Twitter as well.</p>







<p>That has led to plenty of speculation that fans are only days away from getting more information of the relatively unknown reboot of the classic Bungie franchise.</p>



<p>To add fuel to the fire, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/why-bungies-marathon-wasnt-at-state-of-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jeff Grubb reported</a> back in February that Marathon wasn’t a part of that month’s PlayStation State of Play because PlayStation was planning a standalone event for the game. At the time, he said that April was the target for such a showing.</p>







<p>“I think April [is] when we probably hear from them about Marathon,” he said. “And it would be its own thing separate from a State of Play.”</p>



<p>As of publishing, neither PlayStation nor Bungie have officially confirmed anything regarding when more Marathon news will be announced. Based on the teases, however, it should be only a matter of time.</p>



<p>When do you think Bungie will give the next look at Marathon? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official Insider Gaming forums.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/with-verdansk-return-call-of-dutys-player-count-jumps-200/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">player count boost Call of Duty is receiving</a> with the return of Verdansk in Season 3. &nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warzone Hits Highest Peak Viewer Count Since 2022]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-hits-highest-peak-viewer-count-since-2022/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warzone-hits-highest-peak-viewer-count-since-2022.1154595/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-hits-highest-peak-viewer-count-since-2022/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Call of Duty Warzone is back at the top of the streaming charts as Verdansk comes storming into the game once again. In 2021, Verdansk was removed rather unceremoniously from Warzone, being replaced with Caldera – a decision that many fans were disappointed with.</p>



<p>Even if it’s a flash in the pan, the return of Verdansk has proven the power of nostalgia – at the time of writing, more than 336,000 people were watching Call of Duty Warzone on Twitch. The last time the game had numbers that high was in <strong>November 2022</strong> when Warzone 2.0 was released.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-up-the-charts">Up the Charts</h2>



<p>Warzone is currently the most popular game on Twitch, which is a position it hasn’t occupied for many years. It was in 2022 that the previous peak was set, as 615,000 people tuned in to see what was new in Warzone 2.0, the release that came with Modern Warfare II.</p>



<p>Presently, more than 336,000 <a href="https://twitchtracker.com/games/512710" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">are watching Warzone on Twitch</a> – and the number is growing. Before this, Warzone had struggled to push beyond the 280,000 mark, even during groundbreaking events and new map releases.</p>



<p>As I write this, 11,000 channels are streaming Warzone gameplay, which is <strong>almost </strong>hitting that November 2022 peak. It seems everyone wants a piece of the Verdansk pie on streaming platforms – and this is before we even start talking about YouTube. On <strong>that </strong>platform, streamers like TimTheTatman are currently broadcasting to as many as 40,000 viewers.</p>



<p>It’s safe to say that, all in all, across the suite of streaming platforms, a good 500,000 – 750,000 people are watching Warzone gameplay in some way, shape, or form.</p>



<p>Many doubted that Verdansk would herald a return to form for Warzone, but if streaming figures are anything to go by, it’s looking <strong>very </strong>good for the battle royale title.</p>



<p>Are you playing in Verdansk? Let me know what you think of the map’s return on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-falcons-roster-priestahh-arcitys/">the Vegas Falcons have finalised their new roster</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Verdansk Return Leads To Call of Duty’s Player Count Rising 200%]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/with-verdansk-return-call-of-dutys-player-count-jumps-200/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/verdansk-return-leads-to-call-of-duty%E2%80%99s-player-count-rising-200.1154592/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/with-verdansk-return-call-of-dutys-player-count-jumps-200/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It seems that people are just a little bit excited for the start of Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Season 3 and the return of Verdansk in Warzone. After just the first few hours since the start of the season, player count for Call of Duty on Steam has risen over 200%.</p>



<p>As of writing, Call of Duty currently sits with 111,377 players <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1938090/charts/#3m" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">on Steam</a>. That represents a 207.8% increase from its numbers prior to the start of the season. It also marks the first time Call of Duty has been over 100,000 concurrent players on Steam since early February when 102,000 players were on at once on February 2.</p>







<p>While not the be all, end all for numbers, Steam’s player counts are often a solid indication of the performance for a game. With numbers rising as high as they have on the platform, it could be safe to assumed that early numbers on console are just as strong, if not stronger.</p>



<p>The question then becomes whether these numbers will continue, or if players will tune out again after seeing what the return of Verdansk has to offer. Either way, the game has a ways to go to match the 160,000+ average player count it saw in its first month after release. Since then, the average count has dropped by double digits each month as of the end of March.</p>



<p>Do you think Call of Duty’s player count will stay elevated with Season 3? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1812/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the change coming to the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/change-made-to-madden-26-broadcast-team/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA Sports Madden NFL 26 broadcast team</a>&nbsp;when the game launches later this year. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo’s Switch 2 era comes at a price]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/642868/nintendo-switch-2-price-console-games-accessories</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo%E2%80%99s-switch-2-era-comes-at-a-price.1154574/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/642868/nintendo-switch-2-price-console-games-accessories<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Just about everything with the Nintendo Switch 2 is more expensive than the original Switch. </p><p>It’s perhaps not unexpected that the console itself costs more money than the first Switch. That device launched more than eight years ago, after all. But following yesterday’s big Switch 2 Direct, there has been a lot of sticker shock as people have seen just how much Nintendo is charging for the console and its games, including multiple titles with a price tag of just under $80. (And some of those games are just improved versions of years-old Switch titles.)</p><p>Based on hands-on reports from my colleagues, the Switch 2 seems like another <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/642420/nintendo-switch-2-hands-on-preview">excellent device</a>, with upgrades like an improved <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/642793/nintendo-switch-2-dlss-support-nvidia-ray-tracing">Nvidia processor</a> and a bigger screen with support for HDR and 120fps framerates. Nintendo games like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/642432/mario-kart-world-hands-on-nintendo-switch-2"><em>Mario Kart World</em></a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/642699/donkey-kong-bananza-hands-on-preview-switch-2"><em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em></a> seem like they’re shaping up well, too.</p><p>But if you’re looking to buy a Switch 2 for yourself – pre-orders in the US start <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/24342715/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-price-release-date-availability-how-to-buy">on April 9th</a> – you’re going to have to pay up. (And, depending on the impact of President Trump’s newly-announced tariffs, the Switch 2 could cost <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/642459/switch-2-price-donald-trump-tariffs-china-vietnam-cambodia">even more</a>.)</p><p>Here are some comparisons of console, accessory, and game costs between the Switch and Switch 2. </p><div><p id="console"><h4><strong>Console</strong></h4></p></div><div><ul><li><span>Switch:</span><ul><li><span>Switch Lite: $199</span></li><li><span>Switch: $299</span></li><li><span>Switch OLED: $349</span></li></ul></li><li><span>Switch 2:</span><ul><li><span>Switch 2: $449.99</span></li><li><span>Switch 2 + <em>Mario Kart World</em> bundle: $499.99 (which is available for a limited time through fall 2025)</span></li></ul></li></ul></div><div><p id="games"><h4>Games</h4></p></div><div><ul><li><span>Switch (typically): $59.99</span></li><li><span>Switch 2: seems to be between $69.99 and $79.99</span><ul><li><span>Nintendo’s suggested retail price for <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em> is $69.99, while <em>Mario Kart World</em>’s is $79.99.</span></li><li><span>Wal-Mart lists <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fbrowse%2Fswitch-2-hardware-and-software%2F0%2F0%3F_refineresult%3Dtrue%26_be_shelf_id%3D7433688%26search_sort%3D100%26facet%3Dshelf_id%253A7433688%26povid%3Dets_switch2_pov%26nrtv_cid%3Dq6408wp3nhonf%26clickid%3DQTFXQTy2wxyKT9I2Qh2KvSx-Uksyj3SByXfazY0%26irgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_QTFXQTy2wxyKT9I2Qh2KvSx-Uksyj3SByXfazY0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_376373%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383%26sharedid%3D" rel="sponsored">various prices</a> for Nintendo’s Switch 2 games, including:</span><ul><li><span><em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em>: $69.00</span></li><li><span><em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition:</em> $79.00</span></li><li><span><em>Kirby and The Forgotten Land - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Star Crossed World:</em> $79.00</span></li><li><span><em>Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</em>: $79.99</span></li></ul></li></ul></li></ul></div><div><p id="accessories"><h4>Accessories</h4></p></div><div><ul><li><span>Switch:</span><ul><li><span>Joy-Con: $79.99</span></li><li><span>Pro Controller: $69.99</span></li></ul></li><li><span>Switch 2:</span><ul><li><span>Joy-Con 2: $89.99</span></li><li><span>Pro Controller: $79.99</span></li><li><span>Camera: $49.99</span></li></ul></li></ul></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>