<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 19:57:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Sure Sounds Like Assassin's Creed Shadows Is Coming To Switch 2 This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-switch-2-port-release-date-1851786749</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-sure-sounds-like-assassins-creed-shadows-is-coming-to-switch-2-this-year.1250340/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="055b9f11550af1f2111c71c567166a9a" data-recommend-id="image://055b9f11550af1f2111c71c567166a9a" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Yasuke crawls next to a cat. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Yasuke crawls next to a cat. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Ubisoft</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="055b9f11550af1f2111c71c567166a9a" data-recommend-id="image://055b9f11550af1f2111c71c567166a9a" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Yasuke crawls next to a cat. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The Switch 2 seemingly has the capacity to be <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-ports-cyberpunk-2077-ps4-ps5-xbox-dlss-outlaws-1851782817&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-ports-cyberpunk-2077-ps4-ps5-xbox-dlss-outlaws-1851782817">a perfect port machine</a></span> for recent blockbusters. Will <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> be one of them? Reading between the lines of a recent Ubisoft earnings call, it certainly sounds like that’s what the French publisher has planned.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196470" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Reignited Rivalries And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="123" data-playlist="196470,195922,196345" data-current="196470"><div><p>The Week In Games: Reignited Rivalries And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22020.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>As first noted by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/stephentotilo.bsky.social/post/3lukzk2ls4k2c&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://bsky.app/profile/stephentotilo.bsky.social/post/3lukzk2ls4k2c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Game File</em>’s Stephen Totilo</a></span>, the company told analysts during a Q&amp;A today that it had some unannounced games coming later this year, including one for the Switch 2. “Beyond the announced releases we will have a couple of other titles to announce but what we can just say is it’s going to be paid content of strong quality and we also have a game that will be launched on the Switch 2,” Ubisoft Chief Financial Officer Frederick Duguet said during the call. </p><p>CEO Yves Guillemot gave some additional color, as the analysts like to call it, on the company’s fall 2025 release calendar, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-rpg-1851770647?_gl=1*18u9gh*_ga*MTk5MTE1MDYyMi4xNzIyNjAzODYw*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTMyMDk0OTgkbzgzMCRnMSR0MTc1MzIxMDQxNCRqNjAkbDAkaDA.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-rpg-1851770647?_gl=1*18u9gh*_ga*MTk5MTE1MDYyMi4xNzIyNjAzODYw*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTMyMDk0OTgkbzgzMCRnMSR0MTc1MzIxMDQxNCRqNjAkbDAkaDA.">specifically with regard to <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em></a></span>. “We have lots of things that are going to come soon we have an expansion that’s coming before the end of the quarter and we have some new versions that will come on other machines,” he said. The DLC in question is Claws of Awaji, which is supposed to be a new 10-hour island adventure coming to the game. </p><p>While the company declined to confirm a Switch 2 version later in the call, I would be willing to bet the vineyard that the port being referenced is indeed for Nintendo’s new handheld hybrid, the only other “machine” with a dedicated gaming platform on the market. Unless <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows </em>is somehow coming to iPhone or Mac. I don’t suspect the sales from either would account for Ubisoft’s expected revenue in the second half of the year. </p><p>There is one big Ubisoft port that’s already been confirmed. <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em> is coming to Switch 2 on September 4. To keep some breathing room between them, I could see the Switch 2 version of <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> arriving in November. If that ends up being the case, it’s going to be one of the biggest <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-bundle-pokemon-legends-za-preorder-cheap-1851786686&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-bundle-pokemon-legends-za-preorder-cheap-1851786686">holiday lineups a Nintendo console has had</a></span> in quite some time. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-switch-2-port-release-date-1851786749]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Gets Switch 2 Launch Date]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/22/borderlands-4-gets-switch-2-launch-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-gets-switch-2-launch-date.1250334/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text" typeof="schema:Article"><p>Borderlands 4’s launch date on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC has been set <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/29/borderlands-4s-release-date-moved-forward-state-of-play-announced-for-tomorrow">since April</a>, but Switch 2 owners finally know when they’ll get their hands on the upcoming looter shooter. That date will be October 3.</p><p>The news comes straight from Gearbox CEO Randy Pitchford via a <a href="https://x.com/duvalmagic/status/1947702377185763768">video on Twitter </a>in which he reveals the date. Borderlands 4 arrives on Switch 2 just shy of a month after its initial launch on September 12.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MOwGXe3ZSpU"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MOwGXe3ZSpU" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Borderlands 4 graced <em>Game Informer's</em> magazine cover last month, and we have a month’s worth of in-depth features. You can read our articles covering the game’s<a href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2025/07/04/crafting-a-compelling-villain-in-the-timekeeper"> main antagonist</a>, its <a href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2025/07/11/everything-we-know-about-dominion-the-timekeepers-late-game-city">late-game city</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2025/07/07/creative-director-discusses-designing-the-very-ambitious-endgame-content">endgame content</a>, and more on the game’s <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/borderlands-4">main hub page</a>.&nbsp;If you're wondering what else is launching on Switch 2 in 2025, check out our <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/29/2025-nintendo-switch-2-game-release-schedule">dedicated release calendar</a> for the platform.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/22/borderlands-4-gets-switch-2-launch-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of The Night Is The Sensual Coming Of Age Anime I Craved As A Teen]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/coming-of-age-anime-call-of-the-night-vampires</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-the-night-is-the-sensual-coming-of-age-anime-i-craved-as-a-teen.1250331/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Anime, like video games, offers a unique way of<a href="https://aftermath.site/1000x-resist-anniversary" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> providing guidance</a> when life feels particularly aimless. For kids my age, that wisdom was kept secret. Anime wasn’t mainstream at school or welcomed at home, so the lessons I learned about facing life's hardships felt like smuggling contraband with existential subtext from the odd books I’d beg my mom to buy every Sunday at church. Still, I had a Goldilocks problem: the anime I found didn’t match my in-between space of adolescence and adulthood; it was either too salacious or too focused on spectacle, losing the nuance. I yearned for something honest and reflective, without having to dig through its mass appeal to find something truly meaningful—something that sparked wonder or didn’t leave me emotionally drained. Nothing ever seemed like the perfect analogy for my teenage-to-adult years, which were neither purely sensible nor purely salacious.&nbsp;</p><p>Ahead of its second season debut on HIDIVE, I finally watched an anime called <a href="https://yofukashi-no-uta.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Call</em> <em>Of The</em> <em>Night</em></a>, and discovered it’s the kind of coming-of-age supernatural story I wish I had growing up.&nbsp;</p><p>On the surface, <em>Call Of The Night</em>, created by <a href="https://x.com/cot_510" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kotoyama</a> and animated by <a href="https://lidenfilms.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Liden Films</a>, plays with familiar genre conventions where a budding romance develops between a human and a vampire. However, it’s how the show <a href="https://aftermath.site/lets-plays-sleep-youtube" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">explores insomnia</a>, intimacy, and late-night wanderlust in its tepid romance that drew me in. The series centers on Ko Yamori, a middle school student who struggles with going to school, falling asleep, and understanding love. To cope with his first problem, he starts skipping school and breaking curfew to roam around town at night, experiencing that euphoric feeling of being alive while the rest of the city sleeps or buzzes with nighttime energy.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>So light spoilers for that.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>One night, he meets a girl named Nazuna Nanakusa, who tells him she believes that people who can’t sleep like him do so because they aren’t satisfied with how they spent their day and can’t find rest until they let go of their inhibitions. After pretending to sleep when she offers to help him by inviting him to her place and sleeping on her futon, he discovers she’s a vampire. Mind you, he doesn’t figure out her vampiric nature through clues or detective work, but because she bites his neck and begins feeding on him. When he asks why he didn’t turn into a vampire, she reveals that the show’s take on vampirism isn’t that simple.&nbsp;</p><p>In this universe, for a human to become a vampire, they have to be bitten by a vampire they genuinely love. Instead of running away after learning too much about vampires to keep himself safe, Ko channels <a href="https://gizmodo.com/what-we-do-in-the-shadows-guillermo-de-la-cruz-badass-1849401674" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Guillermo from <em>What We Do in the Shadows</em>,</a> seeing it as a perfect chance to solve all three of his problems at once. His new goal is to fall in love with Nazuna and become a vampire.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Call of the Night | HIDIVE" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Gy9f_fTfVY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><em>Call Of The Night</em> isn’t my first rodeo with vampiric romance anime. I’ve served my time with formative manga like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rosario_%2B_Vampire" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Rosario + Vampire</em></a>, which the <em>Call Of The Night</em>’s premiere hews close enough to with its protag inexplicably having the tastiest blood, making its resident vampire go steady with him on that principle alone before it drifts into ecchi harem territory with an encyclopedia of equally down-bad heroines.&nbsp;</p><p>What made <em>Call Of The Night</em> engaging for me was its genuine portrayal of how there’s no magical age when you fully understand everything as a teenager (or as an immortal vampire). Throughout the show, Ko's rebellious rejection of societal norms in his quest to become an adult ultimately leads him to face the same limitations that trap the adults who have surrendered to a structured life. For starters, falling in love isn’t easy even when you truly want to.&nbsp;</p><p>Each episode of <em>Call Of The Night</em> unfolds like a slice of nocturnal life. Ko and Nazuna drift through late-night dates that feel both normal and electric. One scene where Ko encourages Nazuna to feed off him humorously illustrates the long road ahead. Hoping to get turned early in season one after feeling a tug on his heartstrings, Ko realizes nothing has changed. It turns out that her feeding connects Nazuna to Ko’s emotional state, leading her to reveal that his newfound attraction isn’t love; it’s just lust.</p><figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><span><figure><figcaption>That's rough, buddy. </figcaption></figure></span></figure><p>From there, <em>Call Of The Night</em> takes the time to actually interrogate what it means to be young and in love. Nazuna is an abrasive, guarded tsundere, and while Ko meets other vampires that are easier to get close to, he still wants Nazuna. Their romance is a slow-burning tug of war. While Nazuna doesn’t necessarily fall first, she’s fallen harder for Ko. Instead of leaning into it, she masks her feelings behind teasing and dirty jokes to get a rise out of Ko or ducking behind videogames whenever things get too tender.</p><p>Beneath it all, Nazuna is not just scared of vulnerability, but of being responsible for Ko losing the spark that drew him to the night in the first place. Throughout the series, Nazuna plays up the façade that her nocturnal life is endlessly freeing, even as it threatens to calcify into something depressive and hollow. The show later reveals that she fears that Ko will see through the mysticism of vampirism and will regret his decision to become one, and also for falling for her.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="ＴＶアニメ「よふかしのうた」振り返り特番" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j9Gk1VacWoo?start=64&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>After finishing Season One, <em>Call Of</em> <em>The Night</em> didn’t just become an anime I wish I had watched growing up; it earned its place among the essential shows I recommend to others right now. For better or worse, my coming-of-age anime diet mainly consisted of <em>Neon Genesis</em> <em>Evangelion</em> and <em>FLCL</em>. Both are brilliant in their own fractured ways, but neither really provided a blueprint for growing up in a healthy environment beyond horny teenage angst and manic pixie dream girls, all tailored to the protagonist’s psychological projections (and mommy issues), whether they piloted mecha or drove a Vespa. Still, they are both shows that portrayed the pursuit of getting laid as a fundamental part of growing up, with little scrutiny into that idea. <em>Call Of The Night</em>, by contrast, leans into the complicated emotions you first start to discover as a teenager, when pursuing romance and sex is all brand new.&nbsp;</p><p>As a coming-of-age anime, <em>Call Of The Night</em> stands out as a quietly introspective, emotionally sincere, and unapologetically strange series that doesn’t try to shout for attention to seem deep. It offers plenty of space to breathe, wonder, and maybe even heal—and that’s true for its vampire ensemble as well—and I find that outstanding.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/tyler-the-creator-dont-tap-the-glass-hip-hop-rap-kendrick"><h3>We Should All Outgrow Our Heroes Like Tyler, The Creator</h3></a><p>Turns out all it takes to shake hip-hop’s foundations was “Don’t Tap The Glass” daring its rap listeners to put the keyboard down and dance
</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/warframe-old-peace-world-war-one-interview-tennocon"><h3>Warframe, Still A Space Ninja Game (Technically), Is Now Drawing Inspiration From World War I</h3></a><p>"I liken it to the moment in World War I where you have soldiers playing football on Christmas day across the trenches"</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/polygon-valnet-off-the-grid-gunzilla-rip-this-sucks"><h3>🙃 [Update: 🤔]</h3></a><p>Cool, cool, cool</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/coming-of-age-anime-call-of-the-night-vampires]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Scores Nintendo Switch 2 Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/borderlands-4-scores-nintendo-switch-2-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-scores-nintendo-switch-2-release-date.1250304/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>And it's not long after other versions</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Borderlands 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/c34c895667b32/borderlands-4.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: 2K Games</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a>, announced for Switch 2 back in the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct in April, finally has a release date on the newest Nintendo console.</p>
<p>We've known about the game's release date on PC, PS5, and Xbox for a while now, but in a video posted on social media, Randy Pitchford has confirmed that the Switch 2 version will follow shortly afterwards — on <strong>3rd October 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>Pitchford manages to draw out the reveal in the video posted on X earlier today, but eventually alleviates fans' concerns about the game's portable port.</p>

<p>So, we'll have to wait just an extra three weeks to get our hands on this one. Not bad at all!</p>
<p>Thankfully this was much better news than what has previously been circling Gearbox founder and CEO Pitchford previously. The industry icon <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/05/randy-pitchford-defends-borderlands-4-pricing-comment">was forced to defend a statement</a> he made about game prices where he said "if you're a real fan, you'll find a way", in response to a potential $80 price tag.</p>
<p><em>Let us know if you'll be checking Borderlands 4 out on Switch 2 in the comments below</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:182715,182308 @ 1753213742 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://x.com/DuvalMagic/status/1947702377185763768" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/DuvalMagic/status/1947702377185763768">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/0eb520756ca12e6e0c6437f560db6bba @ 1753211119 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/borderlands-4-scores-nintendo-switch-2-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1047 Games Announces it Will Re-Launch Splitgate 2 in 2026 After Overhauling the Game, Amid Layoffs and OG Splitgate Servers Getting Shutdown]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/splitgate-2-back-to-beta-re-launch-2026-og-splitgate-servers-shutdown-1047-games-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/1047-games-announces-it-will-re-launch-splitgate-2-in-2026-after-overhauling-the-game-amid-layoffs-and-og-splitgate-servers-getting-shutdown.1250301/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/splitgate-dev-would-like-to-add-a-map-editor-a-single-player-experience-and-more/">1047 Games</a>, the studio behind Splitgate and Splitgate 2, whose co-founder boldly proclaimed from the Summer Game Fest 2025 stage that Splitgate 2 will <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/splitgate-2-director-refuses-to-apologize-for-make-fps-great-again-hat-then-apologizes-anyway">"<em>make FPS great again</em>,"</a> admitted that they have <a href="https://www.splitgate.com/news/building-the-splitgate-you-deserve">launched Splitgate 2 "<em>too early</em>,"</a> and have announced that the studio will undergo a massive overhaul of the game before re-launching sometime in early 2026. Alongside this announcement was the reveal that the studio is laying off more members of the development team, and the servers for the original Splitgate are getting shutdown next month.</p>



<p>Splitgate 2 officially launched on June 6, 2025, on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S, and though it'll still be playable for the foreseeable future and will still get the upcoming Chapter 3 update, 1047 Games has effectively announced that it has 'unlaunched' the game, and is bringing it back to a beta state. </p>



<p>"<em>We've heard your feedback, and we agree with you,</em>" the studio writes in its statement, which was published on its website and to the game's official account on X and attributed to co-founders Ian Proulx and Nicholas Bagamian. "<em>We launched too early. We had ambitious goals with Splitgate 2, and in our excitement to share it with you, we bit off more than we could chew. We rushed certain features, made some boneheaded mistakes, and most importantly, we didn't give you the polished, portal-filled mayhem you fell in love with. So we're going back to beta. We'll be heads down until early next year, rebuilding major parts of the game to capture the spirit of what made Splitgate special.</em>"</p>



<p>"<em>That means reworking progression from the ground up, adding more portals to our maps, simplifying monetization, refocusing on classic game modes you've been asking for, and more, which we'll share soon</em>."</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>To the Splitgate community,</p><p>We believe in Splitgate 2. This game means everything to us – it's been our life for almost 10 years, starting in our dorm room, and we're more committed than ever to delivering the incredible experience you deserve.</p><p>We’ve heard your feedback, and we…</p></div>— Splitgate 2 (@Splitgate) <a href="https://twitter.com/Splitgate/status/1947717804364353641?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 22, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>The statement goes on to confirm that the studio is laying off more staff, with 45 people <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/splitgate-2-will-go-back-to-beta-to-undergo-a-massive-rework-amid-more-layoffs-and-splitgate-1-shutdown?utm_source=threads,twitter">reportedly</a> losing their jobs at 1047 Games, and so that the cuts don't impact the team too heavily, OG-Splitgate is getting its servers shut down "<em>in a month.</em>" </p>



<p>1047 Games says that though it would love to keep those servers online, "<em>it's cost us hundreds of thousands of dollars over the past couple of years, and we have to prioritize our team.</em>" It is however "<em>exploring the possibility</em>" of creating an offline mode and/or peer-to-peer matches, so that dedicated fans of the first Splitgate game can still play it beyond the shutdown.</p>



<p>The studio also promises to have "<em>a dedicated experience in Splitgate 2 that delivers on the promise of the original,</em>" when Splitgate 2 re-launches in 2026. </p>



<p>"<em>We've faced a lot of dark days and have made many mistakes,</em>" the statement reads as it begins to conclude. "<em>But we've learned a lot and</em> <em>are as determined as ever to make Splitgate as great as possible. Splitgate has been our life for 10 years, and we wouldn't have it any other way. We've got work to do, but we aren't giving up. We love this game and we love this community too much to ever quit. So we won't</em>."</p>



<p>After 1047 Games launched with all the confidence in the world, it's clear that it was sorely misguided when Splitgate 2 officially launched last month, which players knew without the studios' co-founders having to admit it. There are still plenty of questions regarding what the changes will be exactly, how the game will still be playable, whether it will now appear as 'Splitgate 2 - Open Beta' on consoles and PC, and when exactly the OG-Splitgate servers will be taken offline.</p>



<p>It's all together not at all what 1047 Games envisioned when they were looking ahead at Splitgate 2's launch earlier this year. By the time the studio is ready to re-launch the game next year, it'll be interesting to see if anyone is still waiting around for 1047 to "<em>make FPS great again</em>," and if anyone will even care that it's back after what's been a mixed bag of a first launch, to say the least.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/splitgate-2-back-to-beta-re-launch-2026-og-splitgate-servers-shutdown-1047-games-layoffs/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Week at Remap]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-79/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-week-at-remap.1250298/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<div>
					
					
					

					<article>
	
	<div>
		<p>I had a moment last night where it became clear that without intervention, I would not stop playing <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em>. This intervention came in the form of imagining the personal shaming that would be directed my way if I did not beat <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 </em>before leaving for Europe, as I'd promised Janet. The zingers she would send me way if I broke that covenant? I dread it. So I put down a game I was <em>reallyreally </em>enjoying and started another game I am <em>reallyreally </em>enjoying. That said, the endgame of <em>Clair Obscur</em> is a mess, something I hope to get deeper into during a spoiler podcast that we'll record when I return from that trip. BTW, Rob is on the mend but doing better and should be present in some stuff this week. Send him all the vibes!</p><p>-pk, who will likely play a lot of <em>Bananza</em> on his flight to London</p><hr><figure></figure><ul><li><strong>PODCAST: </strong><em>Remap Interview: Mystical</em> – Well, this was a delight. When we logged on for the interview, it became clear it would be deeply silly of me to not conduct the interview in my own frog costume. It's not quite a Vtuber setup, but it as pretty close. You don't have to care about <em>Hopshot</em>, btw, to enjoy this interview. We do talk a fair bit about the platformer, but it's a broader convo.</li><li><strong>STREAM:</strong> <em>Rematch</em> – Me, Janet, and Cado are going to head onto "the pitch" and try to "win." I'm sure it'll turn out fine.</li><li><strong>STREAM: </strong><em>TBD</em> – Rob wants to do a stream, but we're going to put in on the schedule for Friday to provide maximum flexibility and rest to make it happen.</li><li><strong>PODCAST: </strong><em>Remap Radio</em> – [Two hours of Patrick trying to tell everyone how interesting <em>Bananza</em> is, but how it gives him great concern about how far Nintendo, as a company, has distanced itself from traditional platformers]</li><li><strong>ARTICLE:</strong> <em>Letter Series</em> – Topic TBD!</li></ul><p><em>If you have any support issues, send details to </em><a href="https://remapradio.com/r/53613e2c?m=c2a53baa-518b-4385-90e8-62545232c3f6"><em><u>support@remapradio.com</u></em></a></p>
		<p><em>Patrick Klepek (he/him) is an editor at Remap. In another life, he worked on horror movie sets, but instead, he also runs&nbsp;<a href="https://crossplay.news/?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Crossplay</em></a>, a newsletter about parenting and video games. You can follow him on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.twitter.com/patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.threads.net/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Threads</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://mastodon.social/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Mastodon</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/patrickklepek.bsky.social?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a>.</em></p>
			</div>
</article>

				</div>
			<div id="notifications">
	<p>You’ve successfully subscribed to Remap</p>
	<p>Welcome back! You’ve successfully signed in.</p>
	<p>Great! You’ve successfully signed up.</p>
	<p>Success! Your email is updated.</p>
	<p>Your link has expired</p>
	<p>Success! Check your email for magic link to sign-in.</p>
</div>
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-79/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate 2 Fails To 'Make FPS Great Again,' Shuttering Before Relaunching Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/splitgate-2-maga-refunds-reboot-beta-season-3-servers-1851786742</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/splitgate-2-fails-to-make-fps-great-again-shuttering-before-relaunching-next-year.1250292/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Things have gone from bad to worse for <em>Splitgate 2</em>. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/splitgate-2-preview-impressions-1851624294&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/splitgate-2-preview-impressions-1851624294">The portal-based sci-fi multiplayer shooter</a></span> has been bleeding players and continues to face negative Steam reviews, as fans clamor for basic features like leaderboards and balk at <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/splitgate-2-skin-bundle-prices-call-duty-maga-hat-1851784073&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/splitgate-2-skin-bundle-prices-call-duty-maga-hat-1851784073">the free-to-play live service’s microtransaction prices</a></span>. As a result, 1047 Games CEO Ian Proulx announced on Tuesday that the team is taking a step back to hopefully relaunch a better version of <em>Splitgate 2</em> in 2026 and making some tough choices in the meantime. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195670" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="184" data-playlist="195670,197550,196055" data-current="195670"><div><p>This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21167.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p> “It’s brutal, but we’re not going away,” he <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/splitgate-2-will-go-back-to-beta-to-undergo-a-massive-rework-amid-more-layoffs-and-splitgate-1-shutdown&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/splitgate-2-will-go-back-to-beta-to-undergo-a-massive-rework-amid-more-layoffs-and-splitgate-1-shutdown" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told<em> IGN</em></a></span>. “We’re not quitting. We absolutely love this. We love every single part about it, the good and the bad. And we’ve been here before and we’ve come out the other end, and we’re going to just keep doing what we can to stay alive.” That means suspending new content plans for the game after season 3 while the team works on overhauling core parts of the design, killing the servers for <em>Splitgate 1</em>, and laying off more staff. </p><p>The major pivot comes <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Splitgate/comments/1lzfv20/if_youve_stopped_playing_tell_me_why/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Splitgate/comments/1lzfv20/if_youve_stopped_playing_tell_me_why/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a week after a thread on the game’s subreddit</a></span> asked fans to do some soul searching about why they’ve stopped playing<em> Splitgate 2</em> and what could one day bring them back. Some players complained about basic stuff like not being able to pick game modes when they queue. Others were more turned off by the sequel’s departure from the arena-shooter roots of the original. “I found <em>Splitgate 1</em> more fun. It scratched the <em>Halo</em> itch for me. <em>Splitgate 2</em> no longer does that because it has heroes, loadouts and attachments,” one wrote. </p><p>From the variety of responses and preferences, it’s clear there’s not one or two obvious things that can turn the shooter’s fortunes around, which is why Proulx says the studio is going to work on a soft reboot instead, similar to how it did with the original <em>Splitgate</em>. “I think there’s a lot of things <em>Splitgate 2</em> does extremely well,” he <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.polygon.com/news/614738/splitgate-2-unlaunch-announcement-1047-games-layoffs&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.polygon.com/news/614738/splitgate-2-unlaunch-announcement-1047-games-layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told <em>Polygon</em></a></span>. “I think we have a very polished actual core experience in terms of gun gunplay movements, graphics, et cetera. But I do feel like we bit off more than we could chew, and we have three games in one between Arena and Battle Royale and our own Map Creator.”</p><p>One big area of criticism at launch as <em>Splitgate 2</em>'s microtransactions, which many players felt were overreaching and too expensive, even after some prices were brought down. Anyone who did already spend money on the game won’t be getting a refund either. All of those cosmetics will continue to be available throughout this year and presumably once the game relaunches in 2026, but anyone who’s already sunk a good chunk of change into <em>Splitgate 2</em> at launch might feel a bit burned. The likely alternative, however, could mean the game and studio shutting down entirely. </p><p>That will be the case for <em>Splitgate 1 </em>at least, whose roughly 100 concurrent players on Steam will soon be heading into their final matches. 1047 also wouldn’t confirm the number of new layoffs to <em>Polygon</em>, but confirmed more are on the way following a small round in June. And then there’s the dumb “Make FPS Great Again” MAGA hat  Proulx wore to kick things off when announcing <em>Splitgate 2</em>'s battle royale mode during Summer Game Fest Live while ICE protests were going on elsewhere in LA. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/splitgate-2-apology-video-maga-hat-ranked-battle-royale-1851784272&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/splitgate-2-apology-video-maga-hat-ranked-battle-royale-1851784272">He initially defended it</a></span> and said he wouldn’t apologize. He later did walk it back but pointed to <em>Death Stranding 2</em> director Hideo Kojima wearing a similar one at some point and not getting any flack for it. “Yes, I definitely would’ve done things differently,” he <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/splitgate-2-will-go-back-to-beta-to-undergo-a-massive-rework-amid-more-layoffs-and-splitgate-1-shutdown&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/splitgate-2-will-go-back-to-beta-to-undergo-a-massive-rework-amid-more-layoffs-and-splitgate-1-shutdown" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told<em> IGN</em></a></span>. “I will say I think we would be in the position we’re in regardless of any of that stuff. Obviously, I don’t think that stuff helped us, and I don’t plan on doing any more stunts like that, but I think the reality is if this was a 10 out of 10 game, people would still be playing it and happily spending money and grinding and telling their friends, and that’s my feeling. And so I think the past is the past, and we’ve made a lot of mistakes.”<br></p><p>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/splitgate-2-maga-refunds-reboot-beta-season-3-servers-1851786742]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donkey Kong Fan Paints Their Bananza Cartridge Yellow, Pain Inevitably Follows]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/donkey-kong-fan-paints-their-bananza-cartridge-yellow-pain-inevitably-follows/1100-6533352/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/donkey-kong-fan-paints-their-bananza-cartridge-yellow-pain-inevitably-follows.1250283/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533352">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Who doesn't love a little DIY arts and crafts project? They're fun, they get you doing something, and most of the time, you'll come out of it with something special, or at least a fun story. Unfortunately, this is the story of one fan's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/donkey-kong-bananza/" data-ref-id="5000-671287">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> project gone horribly wrong, and while it can't be fun for the poor guy at the center of it, watching it unfold sure has been pretty funny.</p><p>Recently, a TikTok user (<a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-donkey-kong-bananza-yellow-spray-paint-cart-1851786727?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=SocialMarketing&amp;utm_campaign=dlvrit&amp;utm_content=kotaku" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">via Kotaku</a>) by the name of <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@gardnerhartung?lang=en" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Gardner</a> shared that they wanted to paint their Switch 2 cartridge of the critically acclaimed 3D platformer yellow. The rationale behind the move is a simple one rooted in nostalgia: Nintendo has previously released Donkey Kong games with banana-yellow cartridges, like Donkey Kong 64, which Gardner flashes on camera as a reference point in the first of two videos.</p><p>I can already hear everyone groaning and screaming at their screens. I was there too, but it's worth it to enjoy the rest of this cringe-inducing ride.</p><p>Gardner then proceeds to crudely pry apart the crimson red Switch 2 cartridge, showing multiple failed approaches before it is finally cracked open. Once it is, they remove the card with the game files on it and take the spray paint can to each half of the cartridge casing. The first video ends as they piece it back together and insert the game in the console only to find it gets stuck about halfway through and can't actually fit back into the slot.</p><p>One comment on the first video reads, "Seems like the paint might melt and stick in the system when it heats up. This feels like a bad idea." If only that commenter knew how right they'd be within just 24 hours.</p><p>To make matters worse, Gardner returned with a second video a day later showing that despite the system's resistance to the painted-over case, they insistently jammed the game in anyways, where it is now irretrievably stuck. They even take a pair of pliers to the system but simply cannot pull it out, instead chipping the yellow paint and even breaking the cartridge. Eventually Gardner relents, hilariously saying, "Without tagging Nintendo, somebody let me know what I should do to get it out of my system. Again, I'm chilling because I'm going to play the game for a while but I'd love your suggestions."</p><p>As you might expect, Gardner's ridiculous journey for a yellow Bananza cartridge has already gone viral. Some chimed in with what they believed to be advice, like multiple comments suggesting they should've just 3D printed a yellow case and reprinted the game's art, but many of the commenters are also just poking fun at Gardner's dedication and misfortune.</p><p>One comment simply reads, "It's NOT THAT SERIOUS," alongside a crying emoji. Another jokes, "Guy buys a Switch 2 with Donkey Kong built in!!!" The most devastating of the bunch simply says, "Is now a bad time to mention it isn't even the right shade of yellow?" Ouch.</p><p>I guess the big takeaway here is that the next time you want to undertake a DIY project with your expensive gaming system, please just ask around the internet before doing a very costly amount of damage. I hope they're really enjoying Donkey Kong Bananza, because that seems to be the only thing that Switch 2 is going to be playing for the foreseeable future.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/donkey-kong-fan-paints-their-bananza-cartridge-yellow-pain-inevitably-follows/1100-6533352/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mobile subscriptions are shedding unique indie games in search of a bigger audience]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/analysis/711575/netflix-games-apple-arcade-mobile-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mobile-subscriptions-are-shedding-unique-indie-games-in-search-of-a-bigger-audience.1250256/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>For the last few years, subscription gaming services like Apple Arcade and Netflix have offered mobile game developers something of a haven for high-quality, premium mobile games: a type of game that had become vanishingly rare following the rise of the microtransaction-stuffed free-to-play model. But as these services’ once enviable lineup of indie games dwindles, that haven appears to be shrinking.</p><p>In 2021, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759628/netflix-games-global-rollout-mobile-android-devices">Netflix announced a new gaming initiative</a>, offering users a chance to play games through the streaming service’s mobile app. Apple launched a similar program <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/25/18280589/apple-arcade-gaming-subscription-release-date-pricing-features">with Apple Arcade</a> just two years before that. Both services offered an interesting value proposition: Pay a monthly subscription fee to get access to a library of premium games, with some of those games available as mobile exclusives. Those games would have no ads or in-app purchases, and the money paid to studios would ostensibly be used to fund the development of more games.</p><div><p>The games themselves covered an interesting range of genres and topics, from <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/29/23378549/netflix-desta-the-memories-mobile-ustwo-games">strategy games featuring depression and dodgeball</a> to finding one’s place by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24206836/arranger-puzzle-game-review-netflix-summer-game-fest">literally rearranging the space around you</a>. Netflix funding something like <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24190846/harmonium-the-musical-developer-interview-deaf-culture-experience">Harmonium: The Musical</a></em>, a game about a Deaf girl’s love of music, signaled that the platform was taking its gaming initiative seriously, bringing titles from off the beaten path to the platform. But now that game <a href="https://www.whats-on-netflix.com/news/netflix-games/harmonium-the-musical-no-longer-set-to-release-on-netflix-games/">appears to have been pulled</a> from Netflix’s lineup.</p></div><p>In addition to serving as a publisher, Netflix took the additional step of outright purchasing game studios like <em>Oxenfree</em> developer Night School Studio and <em>Cozy Grove</em> studio Spry Fox to make bespoke games for the service. But late last year, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/22/24276700/netflix-gaming-studio-closure-blue">Netflix closed down the studio</a> it spun up to produce what was going to be the service’s first blockbuster AAA game. Then, just this month, it announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/692227/netflix-games-delisting-hades-braid-gaming-strategy">it was going to delist some of its most notable third-party titles</a>, including indie darlings like <em>Hades</em> and the <em>Monument Valley</em> series.</p><div><p>Netflix is increasingly focused on games tied to its own content. In its most recent quarterly earnings report, <a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/2025/q2/FINAL-Q2-25-Shareholder-Letter.pdf">the platform briefly extolled its continued investment</a> in titles like <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/20/24325810/squid-game-unleashed-netflix-mobile-game">Squid Game: Unleashed</a></em> and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/645952/black-mirror-game-thronglets-season-7-netflix">Thronglets</a></em> — games tied to Netflix-produced<em> Squid Game</em> and <em>Black Mirror</em>, respectively.</p></div><p>This focus, though, seems to come at the expense of adding existing original games from independent developers. It’s easy to understand this shift. While these services don’t share much about hard numbers, third-party reporting suggested that the majority of Netflix users <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/8/8/23296545/netflix-games-1-percent-subscribers">never engaged with the platform’s gaming offerings</a>. And the games they were playing, in however limited amounts, were familiar titles. It’s no surprise that <em>GTA</em> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/23/24048412/gta-is-netflixs-biggest-gaming-launch-so-far">had Netflix’s biggest game launch</a>.</p><div><p><figcaption><em>The </em>GTA series<em> are some of the most-played games on Netflix.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>At GDC 2025, Netflix’s president of games, Alain Tascan, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/633481/netflix-gaming-strategy-alain-tascan-interview">spoke to <em>The Verge</em> about the platform refocusing its gaming efforts</a>, saying of indie games, “We will continue supporting some of them, but I feel that indie gamers are not really coming to Netflix to find indie games.”</p><div><p>So far Apple has only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/675241/apple-game-center-app-replace-rac7-sneaky-sasquatch-acquisition">purchased a single game studio</a> to make content for Apple Arcade, though its retreat to more casual offerings follows a similar pattern as Netflix. Original or indie games appear less frequently in favor of those attached to big, family-friendly IP like <em>Uno</em>, <em>Angry Birds</em>, and <em>Bluey</em>, <a href="https://www.apple.com/ca/newsroom/2025/06/apple-arcade-welcomes-nine-new-games/">all three of which are featured in Apple Arcade’s July update</a>. <a href="https://mobilegamer.biz/inside-apple-arcade-axed-games-declining-payouts-disillusioned-studios-and-an-uncertain-future/">Payouts from Apple Arcade have reportedly been shrinking</a> while developers have complained that it’s hard to get their games noticed on the platform.</p></div><p>The free-to-play model has conditioned users that spending money for gaming content can be optional. Casual games like <em>Monopoly Go</em> make money through in-game advertisements or opt-in consumer spending on microtransactions, and few traditional paid games outside of <em>Minecraft</em> are now able to break through that mindset.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/1/20893691/apple-arcade-subscription-gaming-price-premium-games-zach-gage-noodlecake-snowman">Subscription services were viewed as a kind of equalizer</a>. With investment from Apple and Netflix and elsewhere, quality games could be brought to a platform not generally associated with quality gaming experiences. Developers could fund their vision and not have to worry about monetization, while consumers could access those games with a monthly subscription and no added costs.</p><p>But a few years in, the aim of these services has been adjusted, and casual games designed to keep eyeballs on an app for as long as possible, or promote the latest streaming series, have won out. Despite strong lineups of indie games, neither Netflix nor Apple could really cut through the noise, and their offerings are no longer unique. Worse still, the unique games they did have now have fewer places to go.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTAy"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Ash Parrish</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/analysis/711575/netflix-games-apple-arcade-mobile-games]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate 2 goes back into beta, original Splitgate servers going offline, staff cut]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/22/splitgate-2-goes-back-into-beta-original-splitgate-servers-going-offline-staff-cut/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/splitgate-2-goes-back-into-beta-original-splitgate-servers-going-offline-staff-cut.1250241/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>1047 Games has made some major announcements today regarding Splitgate 2, the original Splitgate, and changes at the studio. First, and most importantly, staff are being let go from 1047 games as the studio reassesses its resources to work on Splitgate 2. Splitgate 2 will be going back into beta though will remain available to play, and the original Splitgate servers will be going offline next month due to the costs associated with keeping it running.</p>
<p><iframe title="Splitgate: Battle Royale Official Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ob8fNw6a8O0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In its statement, 1047 Games stated it was shutting the servers of the original game to minimise job losses at the studio. As the rebuild for Splitgate 2 gets underway, 1047 Games has said that it will be carrying out more playtests and player surveys, so feedback shapes the way the game evolves to meet player expectations. You can read the full statement from 1047 Games below.</p>
<p><em>“We believe in Splitgate 2. This game means everything to us – it’s been our life for almost 10 years, starting in our dorm room, and we’re more committed than ever to delivering the incredible experience you deserve.&nbsp;<wbr></em><em>We’ve heard your feedback and we agree with you:&nbsp;we launched too early. We had ambitious goals with Splitgate 2, and in our excitement to share it with you, we bit off more than we could chew. We rushed certain features, made some boneheaded mistakes, and most importantly – we didn’t give you the polished, portal-filled mayhem you fell in love with.<wbr></em></p>
<p><em>So we’re going back to beta.&nbsp;We’ll be heads down until early next year, rebuilding major parts of the game to capture the spirit of what made Splitgate special. That means reworking progression from the ground up, adding more portals to our maps, simplifying monetization, refocusing on classic game modes you’ve been asking for, and more, which we’ll share soon.<wbr></em></p>

<p><em>Now more than ever, we need your help.&nbsp;We’re returning not just to our roots in what we build, but in how we build it – with you. That means more playtests, more surveys, more listening, and truly being community first. Our goal is to combine the DNA of the first game with the best improvements from the second.<wbr></em></p>
<p><em>Rebuilding the core experience isn’t a quick fix; it’s a long-term commitment. To give ourselves the time to build the Splitgate you deserve, we’ve made the incredibly difficult decision to reduce certain roles and shift our resources to focus on this rework. This is heartbreaking. These are our teammates and our friends, and they helped build what we have today. They’re receiving severance and job placement support, and we’re committed to doing everything we can to help them through this transition. We hope to bring them back when we can.<wbr></em></p>
<p><em>In an effort to retain as many team members as possible, we’re also going to be shutting down OG Splitgate servers in a month. While we’d love to keep servers online indefinitely, it’s cost us hundreds of thousands of dollars over the past couple of years, and we have to prioritize our team. Like us, we know this game means a lot to so many of you, so we are exploring the possibility of supporting offline or peer-to-peer matches. And when we return, we plan to have a dedicated experience in Splitgate 2 that delivers on the promise of the original.<wbr></em></p>
<p><em>In the meantime, Splitgate 2 will remain playable,</em> and we’ll still be shipping Chapter 3, as well as fixes and high-priority changes. We hope you will continue to play and support the game. As always, please keep the feedback coming. <wbr><em>We’ve faced a lot of dark days and have made many mistakes, but we’ve learned a lot and are as determined as ever to make Splitgate as great as possible. Splitgate has been our life for 10 years, and we wouldn’t have it any other way. We’ve got work to do, but we aren’t giving up. <wbr>We love this game and we love this community too much to ever quit. So we won’t.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2918300/view/510712444576860070?l=english">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/22/splitgate-2-goes-back-into-beta-original-splitgate-servers-going-offline-staff-cut/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Will Arrive on Nintendo Switch 2 in October, a Little Less Than a Month After PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-nintendo-switch-2-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-will-arrive-on-nintendo-switch-2-in-october-a-little-less-than-a-month-after-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-and-pc.1250238/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/borderlands-4-everything-we-know-return-og-looter-shooter/">Borderlands 4</a> is coming to PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC on <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-release-date-moved-forward/">September 12, 2025</a>, but that's not the date that it'll be arriving on Nintendo Switch 2. Gearbox needs a little bit more time with that version of the game, and today, Gearbox president, Randy Pitchford, announced the separate release date in a video posted to X.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Though he hams it up as if the Nintendo Switch 2 version won't make it in 2025, the actual launch date for Borderlands 4 on the Switch 2 is October 3, 2025, making its release arrive a week and change less than a month from its arrival on other platforms.</p>



<p>"<em>Look, I know we promised that the game would come inside of 2025,"</em> Pitchford began<em>. "We promised that it would come before the end of the year, and...game development is very hard.</em> <em>But I do have an update for you, we do have a date now. We have a date for the Nintendo Switch 2 version, of Borderlands 4</em>. <em>You guys, that date...that date is...October 3! It's October 3 you guys! It's not next year, it's not even the holiday, it's so much before Christmas, it's so much before Thanksgiving, it's October 3 you guys, wooo! *horn noise.* I'm psyched, I'm psyched. Get it!</em>"</p>



<p>Compared to the rest of the platforms, it'll be interesting to see how Borderlands 4 performs on the Switch 2, and though it's perhaps a bit upsetting for Switch 2 owners that they'll have to wait nearly a month after everyone else can get their hands on Borderlands 4 to play it themselves, they'll at least be able to see the beginnings of whether Gearbox is able to deliver on its promise that the endgame in Borderlands 4 is the<a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-series-best-endgame-yet-gearbox/"> "<em>best endgame</em>"</a> in the series so far.</p>



<p>Especially if the Switch 2 version is somehow more expensive than the other versions of the game. That's not likely to happen, but with all the <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-wont-cost-80/">issues that Borderlands 4 has had around pricing</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/randy-pitchford-apologizes-for-the-misunderstanding-caused-by-saying-a-real-fan-would-find-a-way-to-buy-borderlands-4-at-80/">Pitchford having to apologize</a> for telling fans that even if it had ended up being $80, they should have found a way to pay it, the last thing this game needs is another pricing controversy.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-nintendo-switch-2-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate 2 Is Reverting To Beta, OG Servers Shutting Down]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/splitgate-2-is-reverting-to-beta-og-servers-shutting-down/1100-6533350/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/splitgate-2-is-reverting-to-beta-og-servers-shutting-down.1250217/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533350">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Developer 1047 Games has made some drastic announcements about the Splitgate series, confirming today that Splitgate 2 is reverting to beta and the servers for the original Splitgate are going offline.</p><p>In a <a href="https://x.com/Splitgate/status/1947717804364353641" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">statement</a>, the developer's co-founders said they agree with the sentiment from many fans that the game was released into a 1.0 state too soon. "We've heard your feedback, and we agree with you: We launched too early. We had ambitious goals with Splitgate 2, and in our excitement to share it with you, we bit off more than we could chew."</p><p>The studio went on to admit that some features were "rushed" and that the team made some "boneheaded mistakes," which could be a reference to the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Splitgate/comments/1l8yux9/comment/mx8l8fe/?context=3" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">overpriced microtransactions</a> or an executive's decision to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/splitgate-dev-lays-off-staff-co-founders-forgoing-salaries/1100-6532622/" data-ref-id="1100-6532622">wear a certain hat on stage at Summer Game Fest. </a></p><p>"So we're going back to beta. We'll be heads down until early next year, rebuilding major parts of the game to capture the spirit of what made Splitgate special," the developer said.</p><p>Splitgate 2's progression system will be reworked "from he ground up," while maps will get more portals, the monetization systems will be simplified, and the game overall will be refocused on "classic game modes."</p><p>1047 Games said it will conduct playtests, issue surveys, and listen to fan feedback as it seeks to grow and improve on Splitgate 2. "Our goal is to combine the DNA of the first game with the best improvements from the second. Rebuilding the core experience isn't a quick fix; it's a long-term commitment," the developer said.</p><p>Despite what sounds like a major development effort from the part of 1047 Games, the studio is cutting roles. "To give ourselves the time to build the Splitgate you deserve, we've made the incredibly difficult decision to reduce certain roles and shift our resources to focus on this rework," the studio said.</p><p>"This is heartbreaking. These are our teammates and our friends, and they helped build what we have today. They're receiving severance and job placement support, and we're committed to doing everything we can to help them through this transition," the studio added. "We hope to bring them back when we can."</p><p>Additionally, the servers for the original Splitgate are closing as part of an "effort to retain as many team members as possible."</p><p>"While we'd love to keep servers online indefinitely, it's cost us hundreds of thousands of dollars over the past couple of years, and we have to prioritize our team," the company explained. "Like us, we know this game means a lot to so many of you, so we are exploring the possibility of supporting offline or peer-to-peer matches. And when we return, we plan to have a dedicated experience in Splitgate 2 that delivers on the promise of the original."</p><p>Splitgate 2 will remain playable through the rework, and the planned Chapter 3 update is still coming, along with the scheduled fixes and changes.</p><p>"We've faced a lot of dark days and have made many mistakes, but we've learned a lot and are as determined as ever to make Splitgate as great as possible," the developer said. Splitgate has been our life for 10 years, and we wouldn't have it any other way. We've got work to do, but we aren't giving up. We love this game, and we love this community too much to ever quit. So we won't."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/splitgate-2-is-reverting-to-beta-og-servers-shutting-down/1100-6533350/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty Season 4 Outro Teases Avalon, But It's Probably Not What Players Think]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-season-4-outro-teases-avalon-but-its-probably-not-what-players-think/1100-6533349/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-season-4-outro-teases-avalon-but-its-probably-not-what-players-think.1250211/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533349">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-5-release-date-and-details/1100-6533306/">Call of Duty Season 5</a> arrives to Black Ops 6 and Warzone next month, and the new Season 4 outro cutscene teases future story implications for the Black Ops team. The clip is also themed heavily around the location of Avalon, leading players to once again speculate that it could be the location of Warzone's next map.</p><p dir="ltr">As seen in the video below, the Season 4's outro shows Woods and Adler preparing to leave Avalon. Pantheon has collapsed, and the team is fully pardoned and ready to go home. Woods is on a call with Sev, who says she's not leaving with them. She's going to stay in Avalon and guide local factions now that Pantheon is gone.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/Treyarch/status/1947688085824934141" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">"I thought you were done working from the shadows..."<br>With the codenames finally cracked, Pantheon has collapsed. Woods and his team are coming home to finish the job... with one exception. The future of Avalon is unwritten. <a href="https://t.co/3jrEhKDBbh" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/3jrEhKDBbh</a></p>  — Treyarch (@Treyarch) <a href="https://twitter.com/Treyarch/status/1947688085824934141?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 22, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">Call of Duty's seasonal outro cutscenes usually tease a continuation of post-launch story for the next season, so some players are suggesting this could be a teaser to confirm the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-players-think-theyve-discovered-the-next-warzone-map/1100-6527488/">long-rumored Avalon map</a> for Season 5 of Warzone.</p><p dir="ltr">Avalon is a fictional city featured in the Black Ops 6 campaign, and it's also been teased in post-launch content. It's possible the developer has a surprise up its sleeve for Warzone, but most likely the Season 4 story outro is teasing a continuation of Black Op 6's post-launch narrative that is meant to tie into Black Ops 7 and build hype for the new game. This could just be a tease that we'll see some of Sev's impact on Avalon in the Black Ops 7 campaign.</p><p dir="ltr">Activision has confirmed that part of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-podcast-confirms-black-ops-7-is-boots-on-the-ground/1100-6532517/">Black Ops 7's campaign takes place in Avalon</a>, which was discussed on a recent Call of Duty podcast episode and shut down speculation that the Black Ops 7 reveal trailer was teasing Avalon as the next Warzone map. The clip in question showed a scene with a squad flying down onto Avalon with wingsuits, mimicking a drop into a match of battle royale. According to the podcast host, the scene is part of Black Ops 7's co-op campaign set on Avalon, which will support up to four players.</p><p dir="ltr">Of course, they also didn't outright confirm the Avalon content wasn't also developed for Warzone, and it's worth noting that Call of Duty battle royale maps often include campaign and multiplayer locations. This means Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 could potentially still feature the rumored Warzone map at some point, but it's unlikely to launch at the end of Black Ops 6's cycle.</p><p dir="ltr">Warzone's Verdansk was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-devs-shows-off-faithful-recreation-of-verdansk/1100-6530323/" data-ref-id="1100-6530323">rebuilt from the ground up</a> as a collaboration between several Call of Duty studios, so a lot of time and resources went into bringing this map back, making it unlikely to have such a brief return. Data miners have also found new information in the game files to suggest <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-5-release-date-and-details/1100-6533306/">Verdansk's Stadium POI will be updated</a> in Season 5 to open up as a playable area, much like the map's original update in 2020.</p><p dir="ltr">We'll learn more about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-reveal-set-for-gamescom-in-august/1100-6533147/">Black Ops 7 with the full game reveal</a> scheduled for Gamescom Opening Night Live next month. It's possible the Black Ops 7 reveal will also include details about the future of Warzone.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-season-4-outro-teases-avalon-but-its-probably-not-what-players-think/1100-6533349/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Finally Know Who Voices The New Princess Peach In Mario Kart World]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/we-finally-know-who-voices-the-new-princess-peach-in-mario-kart-world/1100-6533348/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we-finally-know-who-voices-the-new-princess-peach-in-mario-kart-world.1250208/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533348">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>After being the voice of Nintendo's Princess Peach and Toad for the past 18 years, Samantha Kelly suddenly found herself not part of Mario Kart World. She was only informed when the game was announced and released without her name attached. So after almost two decades, the roles of the beloved princess and the friendly fungus were to be recast, and we finally know who is behind the voices.</p><p>Laila Berzins and Courtney Lin announced they have now assumed the roles of Toad and Princess Peach--as well as Baby Peach, respectively--for Mario Kart World. Berzins has also lent her vocals to the likes of Hades and Genshin Impact, while Lin's previous credits include Neon White and the Monster High series.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/thecourtneylin/status/1947399822946013624" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">I can finally say… I’m the voice of 👑🍑 Princess Peach and Baby Peach in Mario Kart World! Eternally grateful for <a href="https://twitter.com/Nintendo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Nintendo</a> , for trusting me to help carry the legacy of this icon. (Continued🔽) <a href="https://t.co/7HOGTsFtCz" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/7HOGTsFtCz</a></p>  — Courtney Lin 🦇🖤 DRACULAURA MONSTER HIGH (@thecourtneylin) <a href="https://twitter.com/thecourtneylin/status/1947399822946013624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>"These characters are so much bigger than ourselves," Lin posted on her <a href="https://x.com/thecourtneylin/status/1947399822946013624" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">social media</a>. "I am so honored and honestly can still hardly believe it. I have so much respect for all of the Peaches that came before me, especially the one I grew up with. I will do my best with every opportunity I am given, and I hope you all have been enjoying the game!"</p><p>Berzino added that she's living a childhood dream and wanted to pay respects to the VAs before her. "I am so inspired by the magnificent Toads before me, Jen Taylor and Samantha Kelly. The gaming community owes them a huge debt of gratitude for the years they've spent bringing these characters to life," Berzino <a href="https://x.com/lberzins_voices/status/1947688353002111161" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">posted</a>. "I hope to do this little mushroom proud! He’s a fun guy! Get it? Fungi? Anyway…immensely grateful to Nintendo and Cup of Tea studios. Here we go!"</p><p>These are the most recent Nintendo recasts, with the most famous being the recasting of Mario, Luigi, and Wario voice actor Charles Martinet after three decades. Following Martinet's departure, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-new-voice-actor-may-have-been-revealed-thanks-to-a-hacked-demo/1100-6518372/" data-ref-id="1100-6518372">Kevin Afghani announced he'd taken over the role</a> shortly before the release of Super Mario Bros. Wonder.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/we-finally-know-who-voices-the-new-princess-peach-in-mario-kart-world/1100-6533348/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Finally Converted Kevin Feige’s Son to the Big M]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-converted-kevin-feiges-son/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-finally-converted-kevin-feige%E2%80%99s-son-to-the-big-m.1250190/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NetEase's Marvel Rivals accomplished the seemingly impossible by 'converting' none other than the son of Kevin Feige, president of Marvel Studios and head creative of the incredibly lucrative Marvel Cinematic Universe, to the Big M. </p>



<p><a href="https://www.thewrap.com/kevin-feige-marvel-rival/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Speaking to The Wrap</a>, Feige said that his son only 'feigned interest in a supportive way' in the movies and TV series and comics until he got his hands on the free-to-play hero shooter game. Afterward, he became interested in learning more about all those characters.</p>



<p><em>Suddenly, he was asking me to tell him more about Hela. Tell him more about The Punisher and these other characters. And then he started seeking them out in the shows.</em></p>



<p>Feige used this as an example of Marvel's struggles when winning over the newer generation. The president of Marvel Studios also underlined the success of the Disney Junior preschool TV series Spidey and His Amazing Friends, which also succeeded in bringing new fans to the superhero universe.</p>



<p>Kevin Feige's son is certainly not the only one whose attention was caught by Marvel Rivals. In February 2025, just two months after its debut, the game had already <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-surpassed-40-million-players-tomorrows-patch-adds-nvidia-dlss-4-and-amd-anti-lag-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reached</a> over 40 million players globally across the various platforms. The game recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-season-3-gets-release-date-and-first-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">kicked off its third season</a>, featuring Phoenix and Blade as new playable characters.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Get groovy and suit up with your team featuring the costumes inspired by Marvel Studios' The Fantastic Four: First Steps! </p><p>🔬 "Today we are your defenders. The four of us will face the danger and we will protect you."<br>🦸‍♀️ "Family is about connecting to something bigger than… <a href="https://t.co/EKCgWht05R">pic.twitter.com/EKCgWht05R</a></p></div>— Marvel Rivals (@MarvelRivals) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarvelRivals/status/1947695635916067128?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 22, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>With the imminent theatrical debut of The Fantastic Four: First Steps, Marvel Rivals is well-positioned to gain even greater interest. The Fantastic Four were already introduced in the game back in the first season, but NetEase is now adding new movie-inspired costumes, and even a brand new team-up ability featuring Human Torch (Johnny Storm) and The Thing (Ben Grimm), as shown below.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Things are heating up!</p><p>Introducing a brand-new Team-Up Ability: Human Torch &amp; The Thing!</p><p>Lift, slam, and disable with "First Steps" - launching July 24 UTC! </p><p>Buckle up, hot shot. Time to take flight... and land with impact. 💥 <a href="https://t.co/sLzRozr5pZ">pic.twitter.com/sLzRozr5pZ</a></p></div>— Marvel Rivals (@MarvelRivals) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarvelRivals/status/1947710733904724396?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 22, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-converted-kevin-feiges-son/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OneXSugar: Playing with the first dual-screen transforming handheld]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/report/711116/onexsugar-sugar-1-hands-on-preview-transforming-dual-screen</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/onexsugar-playing-with-the-first-dual-screen-transforming-handheld.1250187/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>I can’t believe they’re actually making these</em>, was my very first thought, as I powered on a working prototype of the OneXSugar Sugar 1.</p><p>This week, One-Netbook <a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/onexsugar-1st-dual-screen-transformable-handheld">is crowdfunding a gaming handheld on Indiegogo</a> like none I’ve ever touched before. It’s got two OLED touchscreens, two power buttons, two sets of volume controls, and two <em>hinged rotating</em> gamepads that let it transform into entirely different modes.</p><p>Folded down, it’s like a Nintendo Switch, with a single 6-inch screen flanked by half-gamepads. Pop open the 3.92-inch secondary screen and rotate the gamepads, and it’s like a Nintendo DS with one screen on top of the other! Whichever mode you pick, the main controls instantly and automatically remap themselves to their new orientation.</p><p>And that’s just the start. Check out my video below for an extended look:</p><p>This is a handheld that can emulate Wii, GameCube, and play the most demanding Android games like <em>Genshin Impact</em> on high settings — and, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DLRKYoReFI0">according to <em>RetroGameCorps</em></a>, its flagship Qualcomm Snapdragon G3 Gen 3 and 16GB of RAM can even play original Nintendo Switch games smoothly with <a href="https://github.com/K11MCH1/AdrenoToolsDrivers/releases/tag/v25.2.0-rc.14">the right drivers</a>.</p><p>But there’s only so much I can show you in a two-minute video, so I expect you’re wondering: just how competent is this handheld? How does it actually feel? Do you think it’ll be a worthy product by its planned September ship date? Will it be worth the $599 early bird price, let alone its now-revealed $799 MSRP?</p><p>I can’t say for sure — it’s a prototype, after all — but so far, the fun is outweighing the frustrations.</p><p>First, because I know you’ll ask: yes, the multitasking is real. I’ve played with dual-screen phones where the manufacturer artificially limits what you can do with the second screen, but that’s not happening here. You can send <em>any</em> app to either screen, even press a virtual button to swap which screen is “primary” as far as Android is concerned. You can turn off either screen to save battery, too, and use whichever you need. As I show in my video, there are all sorts of fun possibilities!</p><p>Second, I didn’t have to baby this prototype’s hinges, despite some worrying flex. I just flip them around and enjoy the loud <em>thock</em> as the pads magnetically snap into place. OneXSugar tells me the final hinges are SK7 tool steel and screwed directly into the aluminum alloy underframe, and will have more screws than the prototype. Still, I’m surprised the final hinge pins will still only attach to one half of the handheld’s frame rather than being sandwiched between top and bottom for more strength.</p><p>I’m continually surprised at how pleasant the Sugar 1 is to hold. The drift-resistant Hall effect joysticks and the microswitch buttons both feel smooth and responsive, and the grips feel quite sufficient in DS mode — with the secondary screen flipped out of the main body, it leaves a comfortable gap to place my fingers. The one notable caveat is there’s no real D-pad. OneXSugar includes a strong magnetic one that floats atop four face buttons of your choice, but I’m having trouble with accidental extra button presses that way; the buttons are better by themselves.</p><p>It’s not the mechanics that worry me most, despite many comments I’ve read about how unnecessarily fragile a multi-hinge device will be. What gives me pause is the software, which feels quite unfinished just over a month before it’s supposed to ship.</p><p>One-Netbook has been building miniature Windows laptops, tablets and handhelds for years now, but its first Android device will ship with the last-gen Android 14, with no promise of future upgrades for future game compatibility, and only a single “Sugar Console” app to make the OS gaming-handheld friendly.</p><p>Often, it works fine! But while I can generally just flip the controllers up or down and largely have gaming buttons instantly work the way my muscle memory expects, that’s not true of every button: the Start button, Android’s back button and the button that summons OneXSugar’s overlay are hard-coded for now, and I’ve had quite a few apps accidentally open or pause because I pressed the wrong button at the wrong time.</p><p>And since you can only swipe out of apps from the designated “primary” screen, I often try to close apps only to find it’s not working because I’m doing it the wrong way.</p><p>I’ve also had occasional issues charging the Sugar 1 reliably, or stretching some Android apps across both screens at the same time. Both are getting fixed in software, according to the company.</p><p>Though the Sugar 1’s primary selling point is the flexibility of its twin OLED screens, I was surprised to find OneXSugar doesn’t yet have a way to resize your games to use those screens optimally — it only offers the equivalent of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mat_(picture_framing)">picture frame matting</a> to minimize the black borders you see. In order to play Nintendo DS and SNES games at their proper aspect ratios on the Sugar 1, I was at the mercy of the resizing, window dragging, and arranging tools each emulator offers.</p><p>Some of the Android games I was able to download didn’t run properly quite yet, as they apparently haven’t yet whitelisted Qualcomm’s new handheld chip; <em>Fortnite</em> refused to run entirely, and <em>Genshin Impact</em> complained about overloading the processor as I ramped up the settings, even as the game seemed to run smoothly.</p><p>I wasn’t able to download a lot of native Android titles to begin with: prototypes went out to reviewers without any Google apps or the Google Play Store. That drastically limited what I was able to test, as many top English-language Android games require Google components, and many top Chinese-language games require Chinese logins. The company confirms to <em>The Verge</em> that final units will ship with Google Play, though.</p><p>Lastly, I suspect you’re curious about the battery life from its 21.5Wh pack, I won’t be able to give you a good idea yet because my tool was clearly misreporting the battery drain. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DLRKYoReFI0">Over at <em>Retro</em> <em>Game Corps</em></a>, Russ seems to be seeing anywhere from 1 to 12 hours depending on the title.</p><p>I’ve seen lots of zany and droolworthy gaming prototypes in my 15-plus years covering gadgets, but transforming ones like this typically never ship because they’re too complicated and too niche to be worth a manufacturer’s trouble. But One-Netbook, a brand that’s built a reputation <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24161887/onexplayer-x1-mini-handheld-gaming-pc-ssd">for modular portable computers,</a> sees this as an opportunity to make a splash in the crowded Android market, VP Jason Zeng tells <em>The Verge</em>.</p><p>He says the goal was to “create something different,” and that his company actually wants to release more such splashy products in the future. For now, its gaming handheld efforts are indeed niche: the 200-person company has only sold around 100,000 pieces, Zeng estimates on a call, with 60 percent of those sales in China. But he says the US is One Netbook’s fastest growing market, and the company sees Android devices as a more affordable way to access a larger population of customers than it’s done with Windows handhelds so far.</p><p>One-Netbook has no plans for Windows on ARM yet, Zeng tells us, but would like to connect with Valve. He says the company would find it “very interesting” to discuss a potential SteamOS handheld.</p><div><div><p id="onexsugar-sugar-1-specs"><h2>OneXSugar Sugar 1 specs</h2></p></div><div><ul><li><span>6.01-inch 1080 x 2160 60Hz 450-nit OLED primary screen (18:9)</span></li><li><span>3.92-inch 1080 x 1240 60Hz 450-nit OLED secondary screen (8:7)</span></li><li><span>Qualcomm Snapdragon G3 Gen 3 8-core (1+5+2) w/ Adreno A32 GPU</span></li><li><span>16GB RAM (8533MHz), 512GB storage (UFS 4.0)</span></li><li><span>MicroSD expansion up to 1TB (UHS-I)</span></li><li><span>21.5Wh battery (5600mAh), bundled 45W charger</span></li><li><span>Hall effect joysticks</span></li><li><span>Microswitches for face, shoulder, and trigger buttons</span></li><li><span>Wi-Fi 7 and Bluetooth 5.3</span></li><li><span>USB-C x1 10Gbps w/ 1080p60 DP output and USB-OTG mode</span></li><li><span>Aluminum internal frame overmolded with PC+ABS plastic composite; SK7 steel hinges</span></li><li><span>Stereo speakers, single microphone</span></li><li><span>1.07 lbs (486.3g)</span></li><li><span>Android 14</span></li></ul></div></div><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MzQz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Sean Hollister</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/report/711116/onexsugar-sugar-1-hands-on-preview-transforming-dual-screen]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SSR Wives is a sparky throwback survival horror with romantic intentions and iMacs for save points]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ssr-wives-is-a-sparky-throwback-survival-horror-with-romantic-intentions-and-imacs-for-save-points</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ssr-wives-is-a-sparky-throwback-survival-horror-with-romantic-intentions-and-imacs-for-save-points.1250184/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Liminal labyrinths" await, tank controls encouraged</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hen Studios / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>SSR Wives: The Murder Of My Winter Crush is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/silent-hill-3">Silent Hill 3</a> for people who like the chibi proportions of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/final-fantasy-ix">Final Fantasy 9</a> and also, people who hoot in adoration when they see a low-poly model of an iMac. I am both of these people. Created by Hen Studios with a demo on Steam, it's a sour and sugary blend of survival horror and romantic visual novel. You play one of several anime characters with names such as Tradgirl and Chudboy, all trapped in The Town That Time Forgot.</p>
<p>Those mouth-wateringly chubby iMacs? They are save points, the local equivalent for Resident Evil's typewriters. Excellent work, game. You have reminded me of my advancing age in a way I actually enjoy.</p> <!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="SSR Wives: The Murder Of My Winter Crush Official Trailer #2" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hv87xZ8RMIE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>SSR Wives: The Murder Of My Winter Crush Official Trailer #2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hv87xZ8RMIE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/hv87xZ8RMIE?autoplay=1" title="SSR Wives: The Murder Of My Winter Crush Official Trailer #2">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hv87xZ8RMIE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>The Town That Time Forgot probably should have been named The Town That Time Deliberately Crossed Off The Xmas Card List Because It's An Absolute Shithole. Here you will find "liminal labyrinths", an abandoned missile silo, and a "clown carnival". Also an "antiquated bakery", but I wouldn't touch the bread. It's doubtless liminal bread, with always angries up my guts. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2880000/SSR_Wives_The_Murder_Of_My_Winter_Crush/">The Steam demo</a> offers up a bunch of rusty tunnels and toilets where you will encounter hungry giant rats. Later, there are gnashing pumpkin monsters and assorted mutant clogboggoes with guillotine arms.</p>
<p>Where does the romance component fit in? Well, if you get to know and carry out quests for the locals you might be able to date them, presumably paving the way for one of multiple endings. Beware, however, that the town's residents are "inflicted with disorder", that the game's terrors are projections of their sins, and that you must "balance their emotional connections with the need to survive". To which end, SSR Wives harbours a sizeable assortment of shiny, real-world guns, which look almost cute in each character's mitts until you fire one and turn a rodent into a casserole.</p>
<p>I worry SSR Wives might be throwback to the point of being obnoxious. This is a game that describes non-tank controls as for "cowards", which I would deem "feisty" if the controls worked perfectly: instead, I got chewed apart by a rat because my character refused to strike downward. The Steam page lists "classic door scene transitions" as a feature, which feels like pandering and makes the game sound like a jigsaw of references.</p>
<p>Still, this is a potent demo, and perhaps not as straightforwardly "retro" as billed: there's something going on here with the intersection of fourth-wall-nibbling anime puppetry and cathode-ray Konami squalor I'm still deciphering. The full game is out this year.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ssr-wives-is-a-sparky-throwback-survival-horror-with-romantic-intentions-and-imacs-for-save-points]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where to Buy Magic: The Gathering x Sonic the Hedgehog Secret Lair Now WOTC Has Sold Out]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-magic-the-gathering-sonic-the-hedgehog-secret-lair</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-to-buy-magic-the-gathering-x-sonic-the-hedgehog-secret-lair-now-wotc-has-sold-out.1250172/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Buuut, you'll be paying inflated prices for everything.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-the-hedgehog-magic-the-gathering-crossover-spoilers-secret-lair"><u>Magic: The Gathering x Sonic The Hedgehog</u></a> is finally here, but it’s also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-scalpers-are-already-selling-the-sonic-secret-lair-at-a-mark-up">gone in a flash</a>, just like its namesake. At the time of writing, the “Sonic Superdrop” is down to low stock across the board, with items selling out pretty swiftly. Boo!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, they do join a long line of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/secret-lair-release-full-release-schedule-2025"><u>Secret Lair drops</u></a> that can be found on the secondary market, just like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-secret-lair"><u>Final Fantasy before it</u></a>. Still, you can expect to pay a significant markup, so keep that in mind before you decide to empty that bag of gold rings for these cards.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At the time of writing, only the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QObWW7?object_uuid=de26033d-6cf1-46af-aeb5-e6a3f81a0212&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Friends and Foes set is available from Wizards of the Coast</a>, meaning you've not got long to claim either the Foil or <a href="https://zdcs.link/a5wNN8?object_uuid=de26033d-6cf1-46af-aeb5-e6a3f81a0212&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Non-Foil variant</a> at $49.99 or $39.99, respectively.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Every Sonic x Secret Lair Drop and Where to Buy Them</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As we’ve already mentioned, you can expect to pay <em>a lot </em>more for any of these sets compared to buying directly via Wizards of the Coast<strong> (standard $30-40 nonfoil, $40-50 rainbow foil</strong>), with most being listed anywhere between <a href="https://zdcs.link/aAgje4?object_uuid=de26033d-6cf1-46af-aeb5-e6a3f81a0212&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>$70-$150 or above</strong></a> right now. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Magic: The Gathering – Secret Lair x Sonic: Turbo Gear</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s sadly just part of the supply and demand of sellers offering limited-time bundles right after WOTC has sold out. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Will the prices drop in the coming weeks? It’s hard to say, but we've always found <a href="https://zdcs.link/aRn3lV?object_uuid=de26033d-6cf1-46af-aeb5-e6a3f81a0212&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">TCGPlayer</a>, while still eBay-owned, to be the most secure and trustworthy way to nab Secret Lair drops post-release.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Not only are they secure and trustworthy, but their sellers do tend to adjust to the market, whereas some stores will still be charging markups for months and maybe years to come.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are three sets of Sonic x Secret Lair cards, with Foil variants of each, but you can also buy a ‘Sonic 100% Complete Bundle’ that includes everything.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That comes in <a href="https://zdcs.link/a5wNVV?object_uuid=de26033d-6cf1-46af-aeb5-e6a3f81a0212&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Foil</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QObWNE?object_uuid=de26033d-6cf1-46af-aeb5-e6a3f81a0212&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Non-Foil</a> versions, too.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Friends and Foes:</h3><div catalogid="c0296d94-8570-404e-a49a-2b6bb3fbefce" id="225559"><div id="225559" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Sonic Friends and Foes Secret Lair</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This set includes our favorite heroes and villains (sorry, Big the Cat), including Sonic, Tails, Eggman and more.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Sonic the Hedgehog</li><li>Knuckles the Echidna</li><li>Miles "Tails" Prower</li><li>Shadow the Hedgehog</li><li>Amy Rose</li><li>Dr. Eggman</li><li>Super State</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Chasing Adventure</h3></div><div catalogid="c0296d94-8570-404e-a49a-2b6bb3fbefce" id="225561"><div id="225561" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Sonic Chasing Adventure Secret Lair</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Swapping out classic Magic spells with Sonic-specific artwork, this collection of Instants, Sorceries, and a Sol Ring Artifact also includes a Ring as a Treasure Token.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Generous Gift</li><li>Open the Armory</li><li>Fabricate</li><li>Deadly Dispute</li><li>Unexpected Windfall</li><li>Sol Ring</li><li>Treasure Token</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Turbo Gear</h3></div><div catalogid="c0296d94-8570-404e-a49a-2b6bb3fbefce" id="225563"><div id="225563" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Sonic Turbo Gear Secret Lair</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, this set is all about equipment, but each has a new name. For example, The Reaver Cleaver has become Knuckles’s Gloves. The original, in-universe Magic: The Gathering card name is in brackets.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Tornado, Sonic's Biplane (Weatherlight)</li><li>Knuckles's Gloves (The Reaver Cleaver)</li><li>Piko Piko Hammer (Hammer of Nazahn)</li><li>Power Sneakers (Lightning Greaves)</li><li>Egg Hammer (Myr Battlesphere)</li><li>Air Shoes (Swiftfoot Boots)</li><li>Egg Pawn (Myr Token)</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Sonic Secret Lair Singles</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 22, 2025 4:00 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-magic-the-gathering-sonic-the-hedgehog-secret-lair]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>