<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 14:06:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 Remake Wikipedia Page Locked to Prevent Review Edit Trolling]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-to-prevent-review-edit-trolling.1002522/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Wikipedia has locked down the&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>remake's page in order to stop trolls from editing the review section to make it look like the game is performing much worse than it actually is.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-after-salty-fans-try-to-rewrite-its-critically-acclaimed-reception" rel="noopener" target="_blank">reported by Eurogamer</a>, the page was repeatedly vandalized over the weekend by editors whose motives are unclear, although some are <a href="https://x.com/airbagged/status/1842644442433700020" rel="noopener" target="_blank">speculating</a> that the page has become yet another theater in the tiresome culture war surrounding "wokeness", as arguably meaningless as that word has become.</p>
<p>Whatever the goal of the editors in question, however, the&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>Wikipedia&nbsp;page was being edited to change the review scores of publications like Eurogamer itself, as well as IGN, Digital Trends, and others, to laughably low scores.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/silent-hill-2-wikipedia-lock-street.jpg?itok=zHmGOtLc 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/silent-hill-2-wikipedia-lock-street.jpg?itok=7nr1lgqy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>remake is getting pretty good reviews, and for some reason, some people aren't happy about that.</figcaption></figure><p>A quick glance at the reception section of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silent_Hill_2_(2024_video_game)" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Wikipedia page</a> as it currently stands shows that&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>is getting some pretty solid reviews; there are lots of four-star and five-star reviews, so it's clear the game is resonating with critics.</p>
<p>What's more, the <a href="https://opencritic.com/game/16791/silent-hill-2" rel="noopener" target="_blank">OpenCritic</a> and <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/silent-hill-2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Metacritic</a> pages for the game show high scores across the board, so I'm not sure what the aforementioned Wikipedia editors think they were achieving here. It's not like it's hard to disprove their edits.</p>
<p>In case you're wondering, the&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>remake launches tomorrow around the world. It's a hotly-anticipated remake of a 2001 survival horror classic, and if you want, you can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/konami-silent-hill-2-remake-music">listen to around 100 minutes of music from the game</a> right now.</p>

<p>The remake is being handled by&nbsp;<em>The Medium&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Layers of Fear&nbsp;</em>studio Bloober Team, and enterprising fans have already discovered that it contains a rather amusing reference to the original.</p>
<p>As documented by <a href="https://x.com/GmanLives/status/1843114248958066831" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GmanLives on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, the infamous "Silent Hill Ranch" sign, which was written in Comic Sans in&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill HD Collection&nbsp;</em>for some reason, can be found in the remake as well, although you've got to jump through a couple of hoops to see it.</p>
<p><em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>launches tomorrow on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2124490/SILENT_HILL_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/silent-hill-2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft's Troubles Continue as Data Policy Lawsuit Looms]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-lawsuit-data-policy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisofts-troubles-continue-as-data-policy-lawsuit-looms.1002519/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-lawsuit-data-policy<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Another plate has been added to the ones Ubisoft is already spinning, as the studio is now facing a lawsuit from disgruntled plaintiffs who claim that it shared their data with Facebook without their knowledge.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/ubisoft-facing-lawsuit-over-allegations-online-store-ubisoft-shared-customer-info-with-meta" rel="noopener" target="_blank">MP1st</a> (which cites a <a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/privacy-and-data-security/ubisoft-shared-gaming-data-with-meta-wiretap-lawsuit-claims?" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Bloomberg Law article</a> that requires a subscription), California resident Trevor Lakes and West Virginia resident Alex Rajjoub are suing the French studio over claims that it shared their info to Facebook via parent company Meta's <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/docs/meta-pixel/support/pixel-helper/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">pixel tracker</a>.</p>
<p>The two plaintiffs claim that while signed up to the Ubisoft+ subscription service, they "downloaded one game while they were logged into Facebook", in MP1st's words, and Ubisoft then gathered info from that download and shared it with Facebook.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ubisoft-lawsuit-valhalla.jpg?itok=bMRc0VUe 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ubisoft-lawsuit-valhalla.jpg?itok=ydt2l_nH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ubisoft is in trouble for allegedly collecting users' data without their consent.</figcaption></figure><p>Lakes and Rajjoub contend that they weren't aware their data was being shared to Facebook. Presumably, because they weren't aware, they therefore also couldn't give consent.</p>
<p>As MP1st points out, the pixel tracker has also been the subject of <a href="https://www.bipc.com/meta-pixel-a-new-target-for-privacy-litigation" rel="noopener" target="_blank">several other class action lawsuits</a>, so it's not just Lakes and Rajjoub that are upset with its use.</p>
<p>To reiterate, though, it's specifically Ubisoft in the firing line here; as the original Bloomberg Law article points out, Ubisoft is being accused of sharing the data it collected with Meta, with the class action lawsuit alleging "wiretapping and other privacy violations" on the studio's part.</p>
<p>This lawsuit comes at what is probably one of the worst times it could possibly have arrived for Ubisoft, as the company is dealing with several other challenges at the moment.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-outlaws-ubisoft.jpg?itok=9loBHSr- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-outlaws-ubisoft.jpg?itok=YnMFZz00 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ubisoft is already dealing with several other problems, including the underperformance of&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Back in September, upcoming RPG&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-february">delayed until next year</a>, and alongside that delay, Ubisoft also revealed that open-world action-adventure game&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a>&nbsp;</em>had underperformed.</p>
<p>The company is also dealing with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/activist-ubisoft-investor-open-letter-change">challenges</a> from some of its investors, as well as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-strike-investor-letter">a three-day strike</a> that's expected to take place later this month over return-to-work policy and low salaries.</p>
<p>Amidst this turmoil, Ubisoft bosses the Guillemots, alongside investor Tencent, are <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-bosses-tencent-private-buyout-report">reportedly considering taking the company private</a>, although nothing has been announced by the studio itself yet. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Disneyfication Of Fortnite Won't Let You Take Mickey Mouse On A Killing Spree]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-fortnite-project-mickey-mouse-1851666530</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-disneyfication-of-fortnite-wont-let-you-take-mickey-mouse-on-a-killing-spree.1002516/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-fortnite-project-mickey-mouse-1851666530<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Back in February, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-games-15-billion-fortnite-1851236865?_gl=1*1j8dzbm*_ga*MTM1ODc4MTMxOS4xNzIxMzEwNzc3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODA1NTA2Mi44Mi4xLjE3MjgwNTc0MzcuNTMuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-games-15-billion-fortnite-1851236865?_gl=1*1j8dzbm*_ga*MTM1ODc4MTMxOS4xNzIxMzEwNzc3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODA1NTA2Mi44Mi4xLjE3MjgwNTc0MzcuNTMuMC4w">we learned that Disney had invested an astonishing $1.5 billion in game developer Epic</a></span>, as the two companies set out to create what they called “a new persistent universe.” Little more was known how this integration would work, but now an interview with Epic management <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/4/24261555/epic-disney-fortnite-unreal-fest&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/4/24261555/epic-disney-fortnite-unreal-fest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by <em>The Verge</em></a></span> has made things a teeny bit more clear.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196395" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="80" data-playlist="196395,194440,195386" data-current="196395"><div><p>The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21945.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Obviously, Disney is already heavily interwoven with <em>Fortnite</em>. Just this last Saturday saw some 5.6 million people show up simultaneously—numbers not even the biggest games on Steam could dream of—to battle a colossal Doctor Doom, who appeared on the island following weeks of the battle royale foreshadowing Marvel-based storylines. That came a week after skins for Pixar’s <em>The Incredibles </em>characters were added to the game, alongside cosmetics for Deadpool and Wolverine. Let alone the years of <em>Star Wars</em>-related inclusions in the massive game.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-games-15-billion-fortnite-1851236865&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-games-15-billion-fortnite-1851236865">Disney Will Develop A ‘New Persistent Universe’ With Epic Games</a></span></p><p>However, what the two mega-corps have planned is something that builds on all of this, but in an overlapping space. <em>The Verge</em> spoke to Epic’s executive vice president, Saxs Persson, who told them, “Disney wants a persistent place where all things Disney can be there, but they want to be part of an ecosystem we’ve built.” The idea being, you can discover the Disney-focused aspect of this future project via <em>Fortnite</em>, or you can come into it through other portals, but it’ll all somehow integrate together.</p><p> “We see the power of ecosystems interoperating as being really the magic here, continued Persson. “From a player perspective, you want to be able to flow between a <em>Fortnite</em> experience, a Disney experience, or any experience really.” So all the skins and characters you may have collected in <em>Fortnite</em>, or in similarly overlapping survival crafting game, <em>Lego Fortnite</em>, or perhaps even <em>Rocket League</em>, will transfer to this Disney space. However, it’s looking unlikely this will be an entirely  two-way street.</p><p> “Not every outfit will be able to do everything,” Persson told <em>The Verge</em>. “A minifig doesn’t hold a gun...Some IPs are not teen IPs or mature IPs. They are E for everyone IPs.” Which is to say, there’s obviously no desire with Disney to see its beloved children’s characters making headshots with a bolt-action sniper rifle, and as such, devastatingly, we’re still a long way off getting to see Donald Duck finally take his rightful revenge against that smug, dumb-voiced mouse via the means of rapid fire SMG.</p><p>What Disney’s own space will entail is still under wraps, but my money would be on something adjacent to the enormously popular <em>Disney Dreamlight Valley</em>, but with more emphasis on multiplayer events and interaction. Then you’ll be able to bring in all your Disney IP-based <em>Fortnite-</em>accrued skins and items, albeit without their arsenal of weapons, in a festival of corporate joy.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Come True now available for Xbox One]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/death-come-true-now-available-for-xbox-one</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-come-true-now-available-for-xbox-one.1002510/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/death-come-true-now-available-for-xbox-one<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Kazutaka Kodaka's full-motion video game adds another platform.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > IzanagiGames [96 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/izanagigames">IzanagiGames</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Too Kyo Games [66 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/too-kyo-games">Too Kyo Games</a> have released and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,547 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> version of <a title="Genres > FMV [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/fmv">full-motion video game</a> <em><a title="Games > Death Come True [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/death-come-true">Death Come True</a></em> via <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/death-come-true/9nn8j5bfpz6k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> for $15.99. The PC version is also now available via Microsoft Store. <span id="more-919809"></span></p><p><em>Death Come True</em> first launched for Switch, iOS, and Android on June 25, 2020, followed by PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1321070/Death_Come_True/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 17, 2020, PlayStation 4 on October 15, 2020, and PlayStation 5 on September 19, 2024. A physical edition is also available for PlayStation 4 in Japan.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>“A new wave interactive movie game” where your <a title="Genres > Action [2,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s, and the ending of the story, are determined by your choices.</p><p>A completely new science fiction mystery, in full-length live-action movie format, from genius creator of the <em><a title="Series > Danganronpa [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/danganronpa">Danganronpa</a></em> series, Kazutaka Kodaka.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Player controls are simple and straightforward: just swipe to look around and tap to make a selection. Even if you are a beginner, you can enjoy the game as if you were watching a movie.</p><p>The protagonist acts as you make choices in each scene, moving the story forward. What ending awaits you after you’ve made your choices?</p><p><strong>Cast</strong></p><ul><li>Kanata Hongo as Makoto Karaki</li><li>Chiaki Kuriyama as <a title="Games > Aka [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/aka">Aka</a>ne Sachimura</li><li>Win Morisaki as Nozomu Kuji</li><li>Yuki Kaji as the Concierge</li><li>Chihiro Yamamoto as Nene Kurushima</li><li>Jiro Sato as Kenichi Mino</li></ul><p><strong>Theme Song</strong></p><p>“Inner Circle” by Kami-sama, I have noticed (Warner Music Japan)</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>In a hotel room, there is a man lying on the bed.</p><p>He wakes up to the piercing sound of the phone ringing.</p><p>Picking up the phone, he hears a message from the hotel concierge,</p><p>“If you have any trouble, please visit the front desk.”</p><p>He doesn’t even know why he is in the hotel.</p><p>In fact, he doesn’t remember anything at all.</p><p>As he begins to look around, he suddenly finds a woman tied up and unconscious.</p><p>The evening news on the TV shows the man himself, allegedly wanted as a serial killer.</p><p>Then comes the sound of knocking on the door.</p><p><strong>Collect “Death Medals”</strong></p><p>Each time the protagonist experiences a new “death,” you can collect “Death Medals” based on the way he died. Depending on the number of the medals you collect, special movies called “DeathTube” will become available. Try and collect them all!</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GreedFall 2: The Dying World Preview – A Dated Feel]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/greedfall-2-the-dying-world/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/greedfall-2-the-dying-world-preview-%E2%80%93-a-dated-feel.1002489/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/greedfall-2-the-dying-world/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Admittedly, GreedFall II: The Dying World was my first experience with <a href="https://wccftech.com/greedfall-2-the-dying-world-hands-on-preview-swapping-places-with-dragon-age/">the franchise</a>, and it really wasn't a good one. Even though the game is in Early Access, I don't think it's even ready for that. Within the first 30 minutes of the game, I was immediately aware of how janky this game was and how dated it felt despite being developed and released for a modern audience. Admittedly, after seeing the main menu, I was hopeful and thought that the game had a lot of potential, as it's very aesthetically pleasing. However, my feelings were in the wrong place.</p>
<p>I got into the opening cutscene, which then took me into character creation, and I was hugely disappointed. The character creation was severely lacking- with the only options that 'mattered' to change being the hair. The several face presets that were available didn't offer much variation, and most of them had no 'attractive' qualities. There was only one face preset that I found remotely tolerable with the wild, untamed curls I used. It has been confirmed that face sliders will be added in the future, which is at least an upcoming benefit to making pretty characters in the game. Overall, the character creation is severely lacking, and the physics of the hair reminded me of that from The Sims 3. It had a chunky choppiness to it and didn't really provide much realism.</p>
<p>GreedFall 2: The Dying World is my first introduction to this franchise, and I immediately struggled to get to grips with it. Perhaps if I had used a controller, I would not have struggled as much, but this was really tricky. While there were tutorials given to you, it didn't really feel as if they were beneficial in any way whatsoever. As someone who had never played a game with this kind of combat system, I immediately found myself struggling. I read the tutorials, but they did not really provide enough information about them. However, once the combat clicked, it really clicked. It became much easier to deal with battles once I understood the system. In the early stages, the combat is very samey, as you don't have many skills to use at this point. Once you get into the later game, there's more variety to it, and you can choose to use abilities or just auto-attack, depending on how many action slots you have.</p>
<p>Navigation can be a little bit tricky to get used to, especially when you're in the starting area and trying to navigate yourself out of the weaving city. To make matters worse, running is a toggle. While I'm very much used to pressing Shift for running, most games I've played typically have you holding the button down. Every time my character stopped moving to look around, I had to toggle it, and sometimes it would toggle by itself, and my character would walk instead of run. The animation of running and walking is very stop-and-start and could do with a bit of buffering.</p>
<p>However, one feature I did really like about GreedFall 2: The Dying World was exploring the environment. A lot of the areas were very aesthetically pleasing to look at, especially with large flora and fauna in the overworld. The sun shining through the leaves was a great touch, and it helped provide an element of realism to the game. it reminded me of a lot of other games I've played with Celtic influence.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/GreedFall2_Screenshot_07-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Questing is quite fun, but sometimes they take longer than they need to because of the markers on the map. If you are asked to look for something, the game sometimes highlights the area on the map and minimap to show you where you should be looking. However, when asked to look for clues near the river to find out what was poisoning people, the item I was looking for was way out of the area specified. I ended up scanning the area multiple times and searching absolutely everything, just for it to be nowhere near the river.</p>
<p>While exploration is a lot of fun, and there are items to be grabbed along the way, the transition between opening a door and stepping into a new area needs some work. Of course, at this point, I am fully aware the game is at the beginning of its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1997660/GreedFall_II_The_Dying_World/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Early Access</a>, and the team is already working diligently on adding fixes and making the game a smoother experience for all. Still, I couldn't help but laugh, noticing how doors would lose all graphical fidelity when opening them, and you and your party would clip through the doors into a blinding light if you stepped outside.</p>
<p>Overall, I had a lot of fun with GreedFall 2: The Dying World, and I'm eager to see what improvements are made during the Early Access period. However, in its current state, I don't think I'll be playing it much more - it needs a lot of improvements.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I really hope turn-based horror RPG Lurks Within Walls gets combat worthy of its lovely claustrophobia]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-really-hope-turn-based-horror-rpg-lurks-within-walls-gets-combat-worthy-of-its-lovely-claustrophobia</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-really-hope-turn-based-horror-rpg-lurks-within-walls-gets-combat-worthy-of-its-lovely-claustrophobia.1002486/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-really-hope-turn-based-horror-rpg-lurks-within-walls-gets-combat-worthy-of-its-lovely-claustrophobia<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Try the demo, beware the ball</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20241006193032_1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>2 Wedges</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
My default movement mode in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a> games that actually scare me is: meandering. I seek to approach without approaching, scooting back and forth across the path like a stray hamster, worrying at the corners and avoiding clear perspectives of the route ahead, while keeping the route behind me in my peripheral vision. I have been trained to do this especially by Amnesia, where tilting your gaze too decisively at anything nasty drives your character nuts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/lurks-within-walls">Lurks Within Walls</a> has no time for my hamstery antics. Developed by Here Be Monsters, it's a grid- and turn-based first-person dungeon crawler - a long-lost cousin of Etrian Odyssey that has wound up in an asylum jammed with internet cryptids, reminiscent in cinematic texture of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fear">F.E.A.R.</a> In keeping with other grid-based dungeon crawlers, it only lets you turn the view by 90 degree angles and travel in straight lines. Going by the demo, it's a promising restraint for a horror game, though they really do need to expand on the combat, which is currently a slight waste of some terrific creature art. 
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="LURKS WITHIN WALLS | Official Annoucement Teaser" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VZTGC7kFWcc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>LURKS WITHIN WALLS | Official Annoucement Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VZTGC7kFWcc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VZTGC7kFWcc?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VZTGC7kFWcc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
In the demo, you wake up on a gurney in a curtained room full of boxes containing weapons and items, plus a medical report or two alluding to hellish goings-on in the recent past. You know the stuff: "Subject X should be kept under visual observation at all times. Do not feed Subject Y prune juice after midnight. Do not ask Subject Z about her exciting web3 start-up." The visuals are dingy and fish-eyed and creased by static. The found doc writing is terse and fairly evocative. Setting off down the corridor, you spy a huge, spinning ball of godflesh trapped inside a cage of spotlights.
</p><p>
The game's monsters are the work of Trevor Henderson, a Canadian artist of some repute, who has a lifelong passion for creepypasta photography. They're an unpleasant bunch, for sure, but what really gets me going about Lurks Within Walls is being confined to 90 degree turns while roaming a small maze of lock-and-key puzzles, awash with glitchy lighting and frankly unreasonable quantities of negative space. Every sharp turn is an opportunity for a scare - it's as though you were viewing one of those slidereel shows 80s horror movies love, waiting for the one that has the spook. </p>
<p>It is also pleasantly unpleasant to glimpse or hear something to your right or left, and not know whether it's sensible to pivot toward or away from it. This being a turn-based game, you can spend an eternity inside that feeling of uncertainty. I would expect the novelty of the format to wear off eventually, but perhaps the developers can keep the suspense up by doing creative things with the audio or monster behaviour.
</p>
<p>
Hopefully, they'll also pamper the combat a bit. Part of the problem is that the options on show in the demo aren't that extensive or imaginative - you pick a weapon, then pick a body part to target based on your hit percentage, chugging health consumables where necessary. The other part of problem is that while the monsters look great in screens, they are purposefully devoid of animations and effects, to preserve that looming creepypasta aesthetic. I'm not sure what to suggest, but the game as it stands squanders all terror during battle. It just feels like you're rolling dice to punch an imageboard post from 2007.
</p>
<p>
Here's a rundown of key features, from <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3197890/LURKS_WITHIN_WALLS/">the Steam page</a>:
</p>
<blockquote><p>
Survival Horror meets Modern Dungeon Crawling: Experience a unique blend of survival horror and dungeon-crawling RPG elements, where every decision could be your last.
</p>
<p>
Fast-Paced Turn-Based Combat: Engage in intense, tactical battles against a range of nightmarish creatures. Gather weapons and items, and confront threats that demand strategy and resource management.
</p>
<p>
Creatures by Trevor Henderson: Explore accursed buildings and haunted settings, encountering terrifying creatures brought to life by the distinctive style of Trevor Henderson, known for his iconic horror art such as Siren Head, Long Horse, Bridge Worm, and many others.
</p>
<p>
Choose your Path: Choose to play as surviving residents, armed with pipes and makeshift weapons, or police officers, striving to eliminate threats and save remaining survivors. Will you seek to escape or search for your lost loved ones?
</p>
<p>
Inspired by Horror Classics: Revive the atmosphere of legendary titles like Resident Evil, Parasite Eve, and Shin Megami Tensei, blending exploration with strategic combat and storytelling.
</p></blockquote>
<p>
And here's a release date: BOO, JUMPSCARE, there isn't one yet. Just the ominous refrain "coming soon". You can also find the demo on <a href="https://herebemonstersx.itch.io/lurks-within">Itch.io</a>, if you consider Steam the greatest horror of all.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Undisputed Review – Redefining The Boxing Game Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/undisputed-review-redefining-the-boxing-game-experience/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/undisputed-review-%E2%80%93-redefining-the-boxing-game-experience.1002474/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/undisputed-review-redefining-the-boxing-game-experience/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The bell rings, and I find myself standing across from Canelo Álvarez, one of the best to ever put on a pair of gloves. The excitement rises and my heart rate increases, but not because of nerves, it’s because Undisputed truly brings the tension of a real title fight to life.</p>



<p>As Canelo moves in, with movement similar to what you’d see on a Saturday night, I quickly realize this isn’t just another arcade boxing game. Every step I make, jab I throw, and punch I take feels calculated, like I’m really squaring off against Álvarez.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s been over 13 years since the last major simulation boxing game, and as I cover up and look for an opening to counter, it becomes clear that Undisputed isn’t just a game trying to fill a void. They’re trying to redefine the entire boxing game experience.</p>



<h2 id="h-undisputed-boxing-review">Undisputed Boxing Review</h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Undisputed Review - Redefining The Boxing Game Experience" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4le6_cyLNH8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h3 id="h-game-modes-a-deep-roster-and-career-options"><strong>Game Modes – A Deep Roster and Career Options</strong></h3>



<p>Undisputed offers a variety of modes that give players plenty of ways to step into the ring. From Career Mode – where you can guide either a real boxer or your fully customized creation – to Prize Fights offering unique conditions to quick offline or online fights, there’s no shortage of options.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The create-a-fighter feature is deep in areas while weak in others. It allows for fine manipulation of a boxer’s face and body. However, I wish there were more customization options, particularly in terms of tattoos and gear. Also, the ability to share and download created fighters from others would’ve added another layer of fun and community engagement.</p>



<p>One of the highlights is the huge roster of over 70 past and present boxers, including Tyson Fury, Terrance Crawford, Mohammed Ali, Oleksandr Usyk, and more. It’s the deepest we’ve seen in a boxing game, and the variety helps keep things fresh. There’s no open-weight option for exhibition fights, but a number of boxers do appear across multiple weight classes.</p>



<h6>RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/interview-undisputed-boxing-with-steel-city-interactive/">INTERVIEW – Undisputed Boxing With Steel City Interactive</a></h6>



<p>The main mode for most is the Career Mode. As said, you take either a custom or real fighter through the ranks to become an undisputed champion. Get it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>While you could expect a system of just pick a fight, fight, repeat, there’s a bit more depth here with the mode. Throughout your career, you’re able to negotiate fights with specific demands, including payout, rematch clauses, and training time. Once you have a fight signed, managing weight, energy, and readiness adds pressure to make smart decisions, especially early in your career when it’s tough to make up for shortcomings. The deeper you go, the tougher the opponents get, making those early wins crucial to rising up the ranks. Those early wins also help prevent you from being in a rut facing the same few boxers over and over again.</p>



<p>The mode can drag a bit once you reach the top, but the overall journey remains engaging. And there’s no real narrative here, forcing you to use your imagination to create one. While that’s something I personally love, I can see some being bored by it.</p>



<p>One thing I would’ve liked to see is the option to change weight classes, which would have added even more longevity. Hopefully, this is something that can get introduced in a future update</p>



<hr>



<figure></figure>



<h3 id="h-gameplay-fluid-and-responsive-boxing-action"><strong>Gameplay – Fluid and Responsive Boxing Action</strong></h3>



<p>Undisputed shines in its moment-to-moment gameplay. Movement is smooth, and punches feel fluid, though there are occasional visual issues, like punches clipping through arms or connecting when they visually don’t appear to. These minor hiccups, however, don’t detract much from the experience.</p>



<p>The beauty of Undisputed is its adaptability. Whether you prefer a tactical, measured fight or want to throw haymakers from the start, the game accommodates various playstyles through difficulty settings and modifiers. This flexibility makes the game accessible while still offering a challenge for those who seek it.</p>



<p>After months of fine-tuning and, in some instances, even overhauling before the full release, the gameplay has become one of the most enjoyable boxing experiences I’ve ever played. Real frustration never came from the game’s design but rather from my own skill – or lack thereof – inside the ring. </p>



<p>There’s also a major difference depending on the overall and skill of your fighters. Not&nbsp; every fighter will feel the same. You’ll notice in things like stamina and punch speed just how low-level you are if you try and take your 60-something overall fighter up against someone in the 80s or 90s. Speaking of how fighters feel, not every fighter will match their persona in the ring. Some boxers definitely feel more studio developed than others, but it doesn’t take away too much from the feeling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do have a couple concerns with how body uppercuts connect and how the AI acts strange in the ring. Whether it’s a bug or something intentional I don’t know, but, sometimes, my opponent would stay in a blocking stance for far too long. It’s one thing to be a defensive fighter, but when a fighter stays blocking for nearly a whole round, that’s when it becomes kind of ridiculous. It’s enough to break the immersion at times.</p>



<p>Speaking of immersion, the knockdown minigame is nice, having to use the triggers to line up within the right and left meter. I just don’t like how, no matter where or how someone is knocked down, they are always back in the middle of the ring for the minigame.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<figure></figure>



<h3 id="h-presentation-a-broadcast-worthy-experience-with-room-for-improvement"><strong>Presentation – A Broadcast-Worthy Experience with Room for Improvement</strong></h3>



<p>Visually, Undisputed captures the essence of a televised boxing event. In the ring, the fighters look stellar. Álvarez, Fury, Usyk, and Ali all look as realistic as you’d expect a current-gen boxing game to look. Even the way some punches land just look incredible, especially hard body shots that make your opponents stomach and chest ripple.</p>



<p>The pre-fight atmosphere and fighter entrances are broadcast-like, making big fights feel like grand occasions. However, a few areas could be improved. The crowd could be more reactive during intense moments, and the game sorely needs a replay suite to capture those amazing fight highlights.</p>



<p>That said, the variety of venues, including small gyms and major arenas (with 18 unique locations plus 2 nighttime variants), adds to the authenticity. It’s clear that Steel City Interactive put a lot of thought into making the game’s presentation match the grandeur of real-life boxing, and, for the most part, it pays off.</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-undisputed-boxing-review-verdict"><strong>Undisputed Boxing Review Verdict</strong></h3>



<p>Undisputed isn’t just a boxing game – it’s a full boxing experience that fans haven’t had in years. With a deep roster, fluid gameplay, and solid modes, it hits all the right notes for fans of the sport. Minor visual issues and a few missing features and gameplay hiccups, like the ability to change weight classes or a replay suite, are easily overlooked when compared to the sheer joy of stepping into the ring.</p>



<p>Whether you’re a casual player or a die-hard boxing fan, Undisputed is the game we’ve been waiting for, and, when it’s all said and done, could wind up as one of the best boxing titles we’ve ever seen.</p>



<figure><a href="https://playundisputed.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"></a></figure>



<hr>



<p><em>Undisputed was&nbsp;<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1451190/Undisputed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reviewed on PC</a>&nbsp;with a code provided by the publisher. For more on Insider Gaming’s reviews, view our full&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/review-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">review policy</a>. Let us know what you think of Undisputed and Insider Gaming’s review in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums</a>. </em></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Director of Original Silent Hill 2 ‘Not Satisfied’ With Limited Camera From 23 Years Ago, Much Prefers the Remake’s Modern Perspective]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/director-of-original-silent-hill-2-not-satisfied-with-limited-camera-from-23-years-ago-much-prefers-the-remakes-modern-perspective</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/director-of-original-silent-hill-2-%E2%80%98not-satisfied%E2%80%99-with-limited-camera-from-23-years-ago-much-prefers-the-remake%E2%80%99s-modern-perspective.1002471/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/director-of-original-silent-hill-2-not-satisfied-with-limited-camera-from-23-years-ago-much-prefers-the-remakes-modern-perspective<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Games and technology are constantly evolving…"</h2></div><section><p>Now Bloober’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/silent-hill-2-remake">Silent Hill 2 Remake</a> is out in the wild, the director of the original Silent Hill from 2001 has offered his thoughts on this reimagining of his work, and he’s full of praise.</p><p>In <a href="https://x.com/tsuboyama2024/status/1842185991496614263" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a series of tweets</a>, Silent Hill 2 director Masashi Tsuboyama began by saying he is “very happy” about the remake and how a new generation will get to play the horror classic. “It's been 23 years,” he said. “Even if you don't know the original, you can just enjoy the remake as it is. Whether it's good or bad doesn't affect the original.”</p><p>Tsuboyama went on to discuss the change in camera perspective from the original’s limited camera to the remake’s modern over-the-shoulder camera perspective. This change — debated by fans in the context of the original tank controls’ crucial role in Silent Hill 2’s famously oppressive atmosphere — has a “significant impact” on everything from combat to level design, and even art creation. “While the impact on the story may be relatively small, it brings a big change to the playfeel of the game,” he added.</p><p>It sounds like Tsuboyama has come down in favor of the switch, saying: “The over-the-shoulder view definitely adds to the sense of realism. In other words, it makes me want to try playing the even more immersive remake of Silent Hill 2.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Silent Hill 2 (2024) Review Screens</h3></div></output><p>Tsuboyama, as he has done before, said he isn’t happy with the original game’s camera, but this time added some context as to why it had to be as constrained as it ended up being back in 2001 on the PS2.</p><p>“Games and technology are constantly evolving, resulting in significant differences in constraints and levels of expression,” he explained. “This is a common issue with media arts in general, but it is not easy to maintain and appreciate the environment of the time.</p><p>“To be honest, I'm not satisfied with the playable camera from 23 years ago. Depth and angle were limited by the processing load,” he said. “It was a continuous process of hard work that was not rewarded. But that was the limit.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>To be honest, I'm not satisfied with the playable camera from 23 years ago.</p></div><p>One aspect of Silent Hill 2 Remake Tsuboyama doesn’t sound thrilled about is Konami’s marketing for the game. He says “it seems like they're [Konami] not doing enough to convey the appeal of the work to the generation that doesn't know Silent Hill,” while pointing to the inclusion of the Mira the Dog Mask and the PS5 exclusive Robbie the Rabbit Mask DLC pre-order bonuses.</p><p>The original Silent Hill 2 had plenty of goofiness in among its horror, so Tsuboyama may be upset at the idea of players running around the game wearing the DLC masks during their first playthrough, rather than their second or third.</p><p>Either way, the Silent Hill 2 Remake is going down well with fans and critics, with IGN’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-2024-review">Silent Hill 2 Remake review</a> returning an 8/10. Unfortunately, trolls are trying to ruin the fun — <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-down-after-persistent-disruptive-editing-lowers-review-scores"><u>the Silent Hill 2 Remake Wikipedia page had to be locked down after its list of review scores from the press was edited to make them lower</u></a>. Check out the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-global-release-times-confirmed"><u>Silent Hill 2 Remake’s global release times</u></a> to find out when it’s playable in your region, and while you wait, check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-fans-are-loving-this-amazing-hd-collection-easter-egg">the remake's awesome Silent Hill 2 HD Collection Easter egg</a>.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ShadPS4 PlayStation 4 Emulator Is About to Make Gravity Rush Remastered Fully Playable on PC]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/shadps4-playstation-4-emulator-exclusive-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadps4-playstation-4-emulator-is-about-to-make-gravity-rush-remastered-fully-playable-on-pc.1002453/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/shadps4-playstation-4-emulator-exclusive-pc/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The ShadPS4 PlayStation 4 emulator is finally bringing Bloodborne on PC, also making fan-made remasters possible, but there's another console exclusive that will eventually be made playable on PC before Sony will bother porting it.</p>
<p>As showcased in a recent video shared on YouTube by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@JohnGodGamesEmus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John GodGames Emus</a>, Gravity Rush Remastered emulation has been improved in the emulator's <a href="https://github.com/shadps4-emu/shadPS4/commit/2fd4861d3e32aa337663e2536393cb5fb97f6bf9">0.3.1</a>. By adding the libSceFontFt.sprx and libSceFreeTypeOt.sprx sys modules, the game running on the emulator properly displays text, solving one of the biggest issues that made the game pretty much unplayable. Hopefully, future versions of the emulator will address the remaining issues that prevent the game from being a flawless experience on PC, such as some shadows visual glitches and random crashing issues.</p>
<p><iframe title="Gravity Rush Remastered - PS4 Emulator Gameplay / 60 fps / Text Visible (Shadps4 v0.3.1 WIP)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jgF8j4uoYZ4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The ShadPS4 emulator has been making amazing progress for the past few months, going from barely being able to boot Bloodborne to running it at a high resolution and framerate. Well-known FromSoftware modder fromsoftserve is also working on an unofficial remaster that aims to vastly improve the game's visuals. The modder is detailing the remastering process with some in-depth videos that highlight the <a href="https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-remaster-video/">high amount of care</a> the modder is putting into the project.</p>
<p>More information on the ShadPS4 emulator can be found on its <a href="https://shadps4.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official website.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tavern Keeper Delayed to 2025 to Iron Out Bugs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tavern-keeper-delayed-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tavern-keeper-delayed-to-2025-to-iron-out-bugs.1002450/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tavern-keeper-delayed-2025<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Upcoming tavern management sim&nbsp;<em>Tavern Keeper&nbsp;</em>has been delayed to an unspecified point in 2025 so that developer and publisher Greenheart Games can work on ironing out bugs and performance issues.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/436780/view/4700159105840202578" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a post on Steam</a>, Greenheart says that&nbsp;<em>Tavern Keeper&nbsp;</em>is "actually in a good state"; it's content complete, all of its gameplay mechanics have been implemented, and it's got a full English voiceover, with translations due "within the week".</p>
<p>However, Greenheart says it's only currently possible to have a "great time" playing&nbsp;<em>Tavern Keeper&nbsp;</em>"if you know how to avoid a number of existing pitfalls".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tavern-keeper-delayed-pub.jpg?itok=gAj0F-Ph 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tavern-keeper-delayed-pub.jpg?itok=ZuNWtCPS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Tavern Keeper&nbsp;</em>isn't coming out in November as previously intended.</figcaption></figure><p>Greenheart points to a number of existing issues, including tavern staff getting "stuck forever", mechanics interacting with one another "in ways that make them hard to control", and confusing UI and mechanical elements.</p>
<p>Additionally, the studio says it's encountered performance issues and errors "that interrupt or halt gameplay". As such, Greenheart has determined that the chance you'll get frustrated while playing&nbsp;<em>Tavern Keeper&nbsp;</em>in its current form is "a little too high for a great first experience".</p>
<p>It would, Greenheart says, have technically been possible to have all of these issues solved by the originally-intended November release date, but that would have burned out the development team and prevented the devs from responding to player feedback quickly.</p>
<p>As such,&nbsp;<em>Tavern Keeper&nbsp;</em>has been delayed to an unspecified point in 2025, and Greenheart says it will announce a new release window "next year, when we are ready".</p>

<p><em>Tavern Keeper&nbsp;</em>is, as you've probably guessed from the name, a "charming fantasy business sim" in which you can manage and develop your very own fantasy tavern.</p>
<p>Originally <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/greenheart-games-announces-tavern-keeper">announced all the way back in 2016</a>,&nbsp;<em>Tavern Keeper&nbsp;</em>has been in development for over ten years, so it's been a long time coming. With that in mind, this delay doesn't seem quite so devastating.</p>
<p>You'll be able to check out&nbsp;<em>Tavern Keeper&nbsp;</em>when it launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/436780/Tavern_Keeper/https://store.steampowered.com/app/436780/Tavern_Keeper/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC via Steam Early Access</a> sometime next year.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo Franchise Switches to Unreal Engine 5, Multiple New Games in the Works]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/halo-unreal-engine-5-new-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo-franchise-switches-to-unreal-engine-5-multiple-new-games-in-the-works.1002447/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/halo-unreal-engine-5-new-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>343 Industries - or, to give it its new name, Halo Studios - has revealed a new outline for what the future of the&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>franchise looks like, and it includes a switch to Unreal Engine 5, internal development process changes, and more.</p>
<p>In an <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/10/06/halo-studios-unreal-engine-interview/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox Wire news post</a>, the studio announces its name change, as well as revealing that Unreal Engine 5 will be used for all future&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>projects. Not only that, but the studio has revealed that "multiple new games" in the&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>series are currently in development.</p>
<p>Studio lead Pierre Hintze describes the advent of Halo Studios and the switch to Unreal Engine 5 as "a new chapter" in the studio's history, pledging to "improve the efficiency of development" and "change the recipe of how we make&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>games".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/halo-new-engine-studio-changes-fight.jpg?itok=vhDHKdxl 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/halo-new-engine-studio-changes-fight.jpg?itok=V0Ce8fRU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Halo Studios (formerly 343 Industries) wants Unreal Engine 5 to do big things for&nbsp;<em>Halo</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>When it comes to the engine change, COO Elizabeth van Wyck says it's part of wanting the Halo Studios team to "focus on making games" rather than "making the tools and the engines". As a reminder,&nbsp;<em>Halo Infinite</em>, the <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/halo-infinite">most recent</a>&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>game, is built on a proprietary engine called Slipspace.</p>
<p>Art director Chris Matthews points out that "some components of Slipspace are almost 25 years old", and Van Wyck says using Unreal Engine 5 for future&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>projects will help Halo Studios to onboard new employees more effectively.</p>
<p>The first&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>project to be built in Unreal Engine 5 is something called Project Foundry, which Matthews says is not a tech demo; rather, it's a sort of tool to help train staff to understand what kind of assets&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>should have when it's built in Unreal Engine 5.</p>
<p>Although the team is adamant Project Foundry isn't a tech demo, it does do a good job of showing off what Unreal tech can achieve when it comes to&nbsp;<em>Halo</em>. You can see it in action below.</p>

<p>So, what's next for the&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>franchise? Well, Halo Studios is remaining tight-lipped about what the "multiple"&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>games in development might be, but the studio does say that it's "at the beginning" of its new chapter and that a new&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>game "isn't imminent".</p>
<p><em>Halo Infinite</em>, as it stands, won't be switching to Unreal Engine 5 either; it'll remain on Slipspace, and it'll still be supported through more Operations and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/343-industries-explains-how-halo-infinite-forge-ai-toolkit-could-be-revolutionary">Forge</a> updates.</p>
<p>Hintze closes by saying that the team now wants "a singular focus", namely "to make the best possible <i>Halo&nbsp;</i>games". We'll have to wait and see whether this change in direction helps them achieve that goal or not.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Acknowledges Recent Buyout Reports]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-buyouts-reports/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-acknowledges-recent-buyout-reports.1002444/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-buyouts-reports/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ubisoft has acknowledged the recent buyout reports, saying it “regularly reviews options.”</p>



<p>Last week, a new report from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-10-04/tencent-guillemot-family-are-said-to-consider-buyout-of-ubisoft?cmpid=socialflow-twitter-business&amp;utm_campaign=socialflow-organic&amp;utm_content=business&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Bloomberg</a> revealed that the Guiellmot family is considering a buyout from Tencent. The news came following the company’s stocks <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-stock-prices-falls-to-11-year-low-after-assassins-creed-delay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">falling to a 11-year low</a> as games like&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-outlaws-sales-1-million/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Star Wars Outlaws have struggled meet the company’s expectations</a>, and its biggest launch of the year, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-context-around-the-assassins-creed-shadows-delay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Shadows was delayed</a>&nbsp;into 2025.</p>



<div><p>In a statement shared with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-acknowledges-buyout-reports-stating-it-regularly-reviews-options" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>, Ubisoft said, </p><p>“Ubisoft has noted recent press speculation regarding potential interests around the Company. It regularly reviews all its strategic options in the interest of its stakeholders and will inform the market if and when appropriate.”</p></div>



<p>The statement continues, “The company reiterates that management is currently focused on executing its strategy, centered on two core verticals – open world adventures and GaaS [Games as a Service]-native experiences.”</p>



<p>Last week, Ubisoft’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-stock-prices-rise-30-amid-buyout-reports/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stock increased by over 30% due to recent rumors</a> of a potential buyout. </p>



<p>As for if the buyout happens and whether it will improve Ubisoft’s standing in the games industry remains to be seen, but developers who spoke to Insider Gaming are understandably nervous about the future.</p>



<p>What do you think of the recent rumors that Ubisoft could go private? Let us know in the comments, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums.</a> And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Assassin’s Creed content, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-assassins-creed-shadows-co-op-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Shadows will have a coop most post-launch</a>!</p>








    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neva adds PS4, Mac versions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/neva-adds-ps4-mac-versions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neva-adds-ps4-mac-versions.1002441/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/neva-adds-ps4-mac-versions<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Side-scrolling puzzle <a title="Genres > Platformer [551 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,799 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Neva [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/neva">Neva</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,296 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> and Mac alongside its <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/neva-launches-october-15">previously announced</a> PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, Switch, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,406 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2420660/Neva/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>) versions on October 15, publisher <a title="Companies > Devolver Digital [379 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/devolver-digital">Devolver Digital</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Nomada Studio [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nomada-studio">Nomada Studio</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/nomadastudiobcn/status/1843244512463987109" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-919796"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Devolver Digital:</p><blockquote><p><em>Neva</em> depicts the moving tale of a young woman, Alba, and her lifelong bond with a magnificent wolf as they embark on a thrilling adventure through a dying world.</p><p>Following a traumatic encounter with dark forces, Alba finds herself bound to a curious, mischievous wolf cub. Working together, the pair will help each other overcome increasingly dangerous situations.</p><p>The wolf will grow and mature over time—as will Alba’s relationship with it as they traverse this cursed, decaying world.</p><p>Building on what Nomada Studio achieved with <em><a title="Games > GRIS [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gris">GRIS</a></em>, <em>Neva</em> will feature platforming, puzzles, and combat against monstrous enemies, with a minimal user interface, delicate art, high quality traditional animation, and haunting music.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Venus Vacation PRISM: DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme adds Fiona]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme-adds-fiona</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme-adds-fiona.1002438/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme-adds-fiona<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Four characters still to be announced.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Fiona will join Misaki as one of the six romanceable characters in “immersive <a title="Genres > Romance Visual Novel [59 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel/romance-visual-novel">romance adventure game</a>” <em><a title="Games > Venus Vacation PRISM: DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme">Venus Vacation PRISM: DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme</a></em>, publisher <a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,022 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Team NINJA [634 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/team-ninja">Team NINJA</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Venus_Vacation/status/1843214696519794924" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. Four characters are still to be announced. <span id="more-919795"></span></p><p><em>Venus Vacation PRISM: DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,121 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,296 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,406 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3155730/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a title="Companies > DMM Games [74 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dmm-games">DMM Games</a> Player in early 2025 in Japan and Asia with English language support. Read more about the game <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme-announced-for-ps5-ps4-and-pc">here</a>.</p><p>Watch the Fiona teaser trailer below.</p><h2><span>Fiona Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="ティザー映像「フィオナ」#VVP #VVプリズム" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4NG_OIaxqqA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Multiple New Halo Games In The Works, As Series Moves To Unreal And 343 Gets A New Name]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/multiple-new-halo-games-in-the-works-as-series-moves-to-unreal-and-343-gets-a-new-name/1100-6526938/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiple-new-halo-games-in-the-works-as-series-moves-to-unreal-and-343-gets-a-new-name.1002432/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/multiple-new-halo-games-in-the-works-as-series-moves-to-unreal-and-343-gets-a-new-name/1100-6526938/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526938">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It's a new era for Halo, as developer 343 Industries announced at the conclusion of the 2024 Halo World Championships that not only are multiple new Halo projects in the works, but they will be developed (as long rumored) with Unreal Engine 5 instead of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/halo-infinite/" data-ref-id="5000-483351">Halo Infinite's</a> Slipstream Engine. 343 Industries itself is also undergoing a major change, rebranding as Halo Studios.</p><p dir="ltr">Those multiple new Halo games aren't coming anytime soon. An <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/10/06/halo-studios-unreal-engine-interview/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox blog</a> on the subject makes clear this announcement marks "the beginning of this new chapter, not the final stages." But Halo Studios is being restructured in a way to make it so multiple projects can be in the works simultaneously, instead of the entire studio being focused on a single project like in the past.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FDgR1FRJnF8" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FDgR1FRJnF8" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">That's not to say Halo Studios didn't have anything to show as part of its big announcement. To highlight what the move to Unreal Engine 5 will look like, Halo Studios has been working on a non-game called Project Foundry. Footage and images from Project Foundry show numerous Halo-esque locales, from the Pacific Northwest-inspired vistas that have become synonymous with Halo to a Flood infested world, all meant to show the power of the engine and what will be possible. It wouldn't be a glimpse at the future of Halo without a look at the man in green himself, and Halo Studios showed that off too, with a highly-detailed look at a Halo: Combat Evolved-era Master Chief battling against an Elite made in Unreal Engine 5.</p><p dir="ltr">In the Xbox blog, Halo Studios art director Chris Matthews said Project Foundry isn't a new game, but also isn't just a tech demo. Instead, it's being built "to the standards" of what would be needed for future Halo games, with content created for the project having the potential to actually be used for projects.</p><p dir="ltr">"Everything we've made is built to the kind of standards that we need to build for the future of our games," Matthews said. "We were very intentional about not stepping into tech demo territory. We built things that we truly believe in, and the content that we've built--or at least a good percentage of it--could travel anywhere inside our games in the future if we so desire it."</p><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379661-foundryue5-05-7c79dec4eedb7c205729.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379662-foundryue5-06-4d494c4dd4c8471278b0.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379663-foundryue5-02-b7f89138d9296126d1eb.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379664-foundryue5-03-0c171ee2a8f31ef7d0e3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379665-foundryue5-04-bcfe4b071b194fd07ba6.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4379661,1300-4379662,1300-4379663,1300-4379664,1300-4379665" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1647/16470614/4379661-foundryue5-05-7c79dec4eedb7c205729.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1647/16470614/4379662-foundryue5-06-4d494c4dd4c8471278b0.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1647/16470614/4379663-foundryue5-02-b7f89138d9296126d1eb.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1647/16470614/4379664-foundryue5-03-0c171ee2a8f31ef7d0e3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1647/16470614/4379665-foundryue5-04-bcfe4b071b194fd07ba6.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379661-foundryue5-05-7c79dec4eedb7c205729.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379662-foundryue5-06-4d494c4dd4c8471278b0.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379663-foundryue5-02-b7f89138d9296126d1eb.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379664-foundryue5-03-0c171ee2a8f31ef7d0e3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4379665-foundryue5-04-bcfe4b071b194fd07ba6.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Part of the reason behind the shift to Unreal Engine 5 is to better meet player demand. Halo Studios head Pierre Hintze said in the past, a significant portion of the studio was required to simply develop and upkeep the engines its Halo games ran on. That made 343 less able to deliver content at the pace players wanted. The move to Unreal will not only mean freeing up more of the studio to work on things unrelated to the engine itself, but also make the actual development pipeline faster, according to Halo Studios COO Elizabeth Van Wyck.</p><p dir="ltr">"It's not just about how long it takes to bring a game to market, but how long it takes for us to update the game, bring new content to players, adapt to what we're seeing our players want," Van Wyck said. "Part of that is [in how we build the game], but another part is the recruiting. How long does it take to ramp somebody up to be able to actually create assets that show up in your game?"</p><p dir="ltr">While much of the talk about the move to Unreal Engine 5 and Project Foundry is the visuals, Halo Studios makes clear in the Xbox blog that it knows there is far more to Halo than what the games look like (though that is a big part of it too).</p><p dir="ltr">"The spirit of Halo is more than just the visuals," Matthews said. "It's the lore. It's the physics. Playing as the Chief, you're this huge tank of a soldier--it's the way that he moves, feels. We're all really obsessed about what our players love about Halo. We're constantly listening to this feedback--and that's at the core of any initiative like Foundry, or any intention that the studio has about how we move forwards."</p><p dir="ltr">Halo Infinite, meanwhile, will still be maintained on its existing Slipspace Engine, with Halo Studios confirming that more Operations and updates to the game's Forge mode are in the works. Even if a new Halo video game is likely still years away, there is technically a new Halo game on the horizon. A Halo tabletop wargame, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-halo-tabletop-wargame-is-up-for-preorder-at-amazon-releases-this-month/1100-6526901/" data-ref-id="1100-6526901">Halo: Flashpoint, is available for preorder</a> and releases October 25.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parcel Corps Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/parcel-corps-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/parcel-corps-review.1002420/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/parcel-corps-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/parcel-corps-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Parcel Corps Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Jim Hargreaves">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-10-07">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-10-07">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p><a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/parcel-corps">Parcel Corps</a> transforms the thankless graft of an urban courier into an extreme sport with a flair of <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/crazy-taxi">Crazy Taxi</a> and a streak of satirical British humour. Battling against the clock, players are tasked with whisking all kinds of cargo across maze-like urban sandboxes, interacting with a colourful cast of clients looking to pedal their wares.</p>
<p><iframe title="Parcel Corps - Release Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ogtlwy0OYUY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Oh yes, there’s plenty of pedalling in Parcel Corps. The game’s stand-out feature is its use of bicycles as the only mode of transport which instantly makes travel more dynamic. Not only can players weave through the traffic and backstreets, they can also perform a simple yet effective repertoire of tricks such as grinds, wall-rides, slides, and wheelies. In this respect, the game takes on a <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/tony-hawks-pro-skater">Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater</a> dimension that seamlessly complements its beat-the-clock arcade action.</p>


<p>With that said, I wasn’t all too enthused by the opening half an hour. Parcel Corps wants to ease you in with a step-by-step tutorial that has you performing basic manoeuvres around traffic cones before the training wheels can come off. Those first few deliveries can also feel sluggish as you get to grips with not just the bicycle handling, but also juggling a mobile phone.</p>
<p>However, after exploring the game’s first of several open-world locations and signing up a handful of clients, everything starts to click into place. With mastery, the bike handling will go from feeling slow and clumsy to fast and fluid as you chain together parkour-like stunts to access shortcuts while generally getting a feel for your surroundings.</p>


<p>Delivery Rush events are where your skills are put to the test. This is where Parcel Corps is at its most Crazy Taxi-like, challenging players to complete as many deliveries as the clock counts down, giving them freedom to choose which jobs to complete. It can often feel like the entire game was constructed around this core game mode – your performance in Delivery Rush will impact your story progress and how quickly you move onto the next map.</p>
<p>Speaking of story, developer Billy Goat Entertainment uses live action cutscenes and comical caricatures to poke fun at real world issues such as corporate greed and the exploitative gig economy in the UK. There’s also an anti-authoritian streak throughout. As a courier, you can align with mask-wearing anarchists by vandalising surveillance equipment which, in turn, comes with its own rewards by unlocking handy shortcuts.</p>
<p>Repetition is another antagonist you’ll need to face off against. As you progress from zone to zone, a predictable pattern emerges in which players must sign up a handful of clients and then grind out Delivery Rush XP, repeating the process until your boss is happy for you to move on, only to go through the same loop again.</p>

<p>Finicky controls present another bugbear, particularly when trying to use the in-game phone. You can essentially multitask while riding, though the button inputs and map feature can be frustrating to use even if the concept is innovative. There are other parts of the game that don’t feel well executed. All that hard earned money you amass can only be spent purchasing cosmetic upgrades and although there is online multiplayer, it feels superfluous with launch day matchmaking times being a true test of patience.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Parcel Corps is easily one of the best attempts at revitalising a highly addictive subgenre of arcade game. Pulling off gnarly trick combos and thrashing those bike pedals feels great - even if things get repetitive after a while, saddling up for short bursts of play is incredibly fun. The world-building will also keep players engaged between delivery jobs with enough referential humour and satire to warrant the occasional hearty chuckle.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Fun arcade gameplay that mashes together Crazy Taxi and THPS</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Delivery Rush is highly replayable</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Genuinely funny in places</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Vibrant, playful cell-shaded art style</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Repetitive story progression</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Finicky controls </li>
														
								<li><i></i>Limited upgrade options</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phoenix Springs reimagines the point-and-click adventure as weird noir]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24262101/phoenix-springs-review-point-and-click-adventure</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phoenix-springs-reimagines-the-point-and-click-adventure-as-weird-noir.1002417/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24262101/phoenix-springs-review-point-and-click-adventure<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In <em>Phoenix Springs</em>, it’s not so much the ravishing hand-drawn visuals that first grab the attention, but the voice of narrator and protagonist Iris. Befitting her name, she behaves like a roving eye, investigating and describing her surroundings with a clinical, almost robotic detachment. Yet Iris is no blank slate: you quickly come to learn that she is a snob with little regard for the homeless. She even appears to have short shrift for the player, delivering a withering putdown when you make a connection she deems just a little <em>too</em> obvious.</p><p>Iris, a tech journalist by trade, is the perfect protagonist for a point-and-click adventure, a genre whose mechanics often begin with the simple act of looking. Eventually, in classics like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/1/27/7877417/grim-fandango-remastered"><em>Grim Fandango</em></a> and the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23360869/return-to-monkey-island-review-nintendo-switch-pc"><em>Monkey Island</em></a><em> </em>series, you advance the narrative by combining objects in increasingly esoteric ways. But in <em>Phoenix Springs</em>, it’s not objects you’re combining but ideas; it’s not an inventory you’re delving into but a sprawling mindmap. There are shades of <em>Disco Elysium’s</em> <a href="https://youtu.be/9X0-W5erEXw">Thought Cabinet</a> here. In Studio Zaum’s 2019 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22412485/disco-elysium-the-final-cut-review-ps4-ps5-mac-pc">detective classic</a>, the mechanic played a supporting role. In <em>Phoenix Springs</em>, it carries the whole game.&nbsp;</p><p>Ideas-as-inventory is an elegant revision of point-and-click mechanics, transforming what can often feel like an opaque and sometimes clunky genre into something more supple, streamlined, and modern. These ideas aren’t just reminders of the plot but tools to wield in the game and thematic anchors to mull over while playing it. They also function as red herrings in a narrative that moves quickly: Iris’ brother, an esteemed bioethicist called Leo Dormer, has gone missing, and she is trying to find him.</p><p>In one early scene, Iris travels to his university, which has recently been destroyed by student protests. Amid its ruins, ravers are hosting a multiday sleep deprivation party (without the aid of chemicals, they stress), soundtracked by murky, pulsating techno. Iris doesn’t “get it,” nor does she seem to understand anything vaguely countercultural. The mystery deepens. In this near-future scenario, censorship is the norm; the privileged sleep in stasis pods. What is going on, and where in the world is Leo Dormer?</p><p>Like <em>Disco Elysium</em>, there is a peculiarity to <em>Phoenix Springs</em> whose world is inspired by our own, features many of the same objects and similar kinds of locations, yet diverges in enough unsettling ways to feel deeply confounding. You come across a gigantic ladder in the desert at the top of which sits a rocking chair and a solar-powered radio. There is an oasis in the middle of said desert populated by a community whose residents seem condemned to speak in strange, elliptical phrases. Rotting fruit is strewn about the place. The mood is never less than uncanny.</p><p>The visuals — bold, hyper-stylized illustrations set against rough, painterly textures — add to the sense of unease. <em>Phoenix Springs</em> is a game of abundant negative space with large parts of the screen blocked out by slabs of shimmering color and darkened shadow. As Iris traipses through eerie, empty buildings and unnaturally lush ruins, she has a tendency to almost disappear into the environment, as if her very physical being is compromised. The negative space extends to characters whose innermost feelings and motivations remain obscure throughout. The plot is never less than cryptic, even as you are seemingly able to unravel it.&nbsp;</p><p>The beguiling spell that <em>Phoenix Springs</em> casts is only intermittently broken by its sometimes obtuse puzzles. In the university, having completed much of the ostensibly more challenging sleuthing, my progress was halted by simply overlooking a key object. But getting stumped is never a dealbreaker. Pausing the game brings up a list of tips: there is even a button that whisks you away to an external webpage featuring a guide for the entire game. Does offering a walkthrough betray a lack of confidence, or perhaps conviction, in the game’s puzzles? I don’t think so. The makers of <em>Phoenix Springs</em>, a three-person <a href="https://www.calligramstudio.com/">art collective</a> spread across the UK and France, don’t care if you “git gud”; they just want to tell you a bizarre, unsettling story.&nbsp;</p><p>The weirdness is precisely the point. Nods to bioethics, toxic fungi, and the “green crater in the heart of the desert” evoke the weird fiction of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/17/15799902/jeff-vandermeer-borne-climate-change-science-fiction-book-review">Jeff VanderMeer</a> (as popularized in the author’s <em>Southern Reach</em> series of novels). <em>Phoenix Springs</em> is also a compelling neo-noir, albeit one that, for a large part, takes place in the blindingly bright sunlight. That is a little weird, too.&nbsp;</p><p>Yet even as the game mutates into an odder metaphysical shape than its detective premise seemed to initially suggest, it does not sag or lose any potency. On the contrary, the game becomes more powerful as it becomes clear just how far Iris is willing to go in order to follow her little brother and restore their connection. Throughout it all, Leo Dormer remains at the center of her mind map; he remains the one constant in Iris’ thoughts. </p><p><small>Phoenix Springs <em>launches October 7th on PC.</em></small></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 Remake Fans Are Loving This Amazing HD Collection Easter Egg]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-fans-are-loving-this-amazing-hd-collection-easter-egg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-fans-are-loving-this-amazing-hd-collection-easter-egg.1002411/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-fans-are-loving-this-amazing-hd-collection-easter-egg<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>2012’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/silent-hill-hd-collection">Silent Hill HD Collection</a> is perhaps best known by fans for inexplicably changing the Silent Hill Ranch sign font to Comic Sans. It was a tweak to the beloved original that baffled Silent Hill fans and has become infamous in the 12 years since the HD Collection’s release.</p><p>Fans had wondered which font Bloober would go with for its remake ahead of release, and so now with early access available it has come as some relief to discover the developers did indeed ditch the HD Collection’s Comic Sans sign in favor of the original's. X/Twitter user <a href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1842785611029057840" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Wario64</a> showed off this new/old look.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">not comic sans :( <a href="https://t.co/K6ZAmpG5dg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/K6ZAmpG5dg</a></p>— Wario64 (@Wario64) <a href="https://twitter.com/Wario64/status/1842785611029057840?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>However, Silent Hill 2 Remake players have discovered that if you clip through or go out of bounds in the PC version when at Silent Hill Ranch, you can find the HD Collection’s Comic Sans sign among other discarded rubbish in an abandoned warehouse (right where fans will say it belongs).</p><p><a href="https://x.com/GmanLives/status/1843114248958066831" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter/X user @GmanLives</a> surfaced the change, since verified by other users, declaring Silent Hill 2 Remake GOTY for this awesome nod to Silent Hill HD Collection.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">So if you clip through the ranch at the start of the Silent Hill 2 remake you can find the comic sans font sign hidden away inside. GOTY. <a href="https://t.co/J855Vtk8am" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/J855Vtk8am</a></p>— GmanLives (@GmanLives) <a href="https://twitter.com/GmanLives/status/1843114248958066831?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 7, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>The apparent Easter egg is certainly going down well with Silent Hill fans. “... Bloober Team and Konami are genuinely amazing for that,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/silenthill/comments/1fxyf5o/comic_sans_silent_hill_ranch_is_cannon_now/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said NONAMEDREDDITER</a>. “... Bloober are officially god tier,” added Low-Positive5888. “Bloober, my heart grows bigger and bigger for you every day,” said stinkyratboiii. “Suck it HD Collection!” declared cyb0rganna.</p><p>Generally, Bloober’s Silent Hill 2 Remake is going down well with fans and it’s certainly a hit with critics. However, trolls are trying to ruin the fun — <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-down-after-persistent-disruptive-editing-lowers-review-scores">the Silent Hill 2 Remake Wikipedia page had to be locked down after its list of review scores from the press was edited to make them lower</a>. Check out the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-global-release-times-confirmed">Silent Hill 2 Remake’s global release times</a> to find out when it’s playable in your region.</p><p><em>Image credit: </em><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/silenthill/comments/1fxyf5o/comment/lqq8me9/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>xRudeAwakening / reddit</em></a></p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Halo on Unreal Engine 5 means for PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/what-halo-on-unreal-engine-5-means-for-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-halo-on-unreal-engine-5-means-for-ps5.1002408/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/what-halo-on-unreal-engine-5-means-for-ps5<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>We asked Digital Foundry.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/halo-unreal-engine-5.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Halo Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Today's announcements by the newly-rebranded <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/halo">Halo</a> Studios - formerly <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/343-industries">343 Industries</a> - that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/halo-developer-343-industries-rebrands-confirms-multiple-new-games">multiple new Halo games are in development</a> has excited fans of Microsoft's flagship Xbox franchise. But is there cause for celebration for PlayStation 5 owners too?
</p>
<p>
Halo Studios has said it will now develop all future Halo projects using Unreal Engine 5, the Epic Games-made toolkit for game development that's used widely across the industry. It's set to power the next Witcher and Tomb Raider installments, and can be seen in action this week within the highly-acclaimed <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-2">Silent Hill 2</a> remake. 
</p>
<p>
Discussing the move to Unreal Engine, Halo Studios said the change means faster, smoother development and iteration is now possible, while it will also allow for an easier onboarding of  new team members who know the toolkit already. On top of this, though, it potentially means easier multiplatform development is now possible - should Microsoft look to extend its cross-platform release program and launch Halo on other consoles. 
</p>
<p>
"From a multi-platform game development perspective, moving to Unreal Engine 5 would certainly be easier for the developer than porting across the existing Slipspace engine," Digital Foundry boss Rich Leadbeatter told me this morning. 
</p>
<p>
"It stands to reason that an engine designed for deployment across multiple platforms would be easier to work with than existing technology built for Xbox and PC."
</p>
<p>
Xbox is yet to release games from any of its biggest franchises - Halo, Forza, Gears of War - on PlayStation or Switch hardware, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gears-of-war-reportedly-also-being-considered-for-playstation-release">multiple reports have suggested</a> Microsoft is at least <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-mulls-major-xbox-exclusives-starfield-indiana-jones-for-playstation-5-reports">seriously considering the option for future installments of its biggest brands</a>, and the direction of trend seems clear. 
</p><p>
The writing had been on the wall for Halo's previous Slipspace engine for some time, following the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/343-industries-reflects-on-one-year-of-halo-infinite">mixed performance of Halo Infinite</a>, the cancellation of plans to further develop the game's campaign, and the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/halo-developer-343-reportedly-loses-engine-lead">loss of the studio's lead developer of Slipspace at the end of 2022</a>. The past few years have seen other departures, too, including then-343 Industries boss <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/halo-studio-boss-bonnie-ross-announces-departure-from-microsoft">Bonnie Ross</a>, director <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-halo-infinite-creative-head-joseph-staten-joins-netflix-games">Joseph Staten</a>, multiplayer creative director <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/halo-infinites-multiplayer-creative-director-parts-ways-with-343-industries">Tom French</a>, and Halo franchise director <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/halos-franchise-director-frank-oconnor-may-have-left-microsoft">Frank O'Connor</a>. 
</p>
<p>
Could Slipspace be ported to PS5? Well, yes, Digital Foundry says. But it would require an extra layer of porting work that using Unreal Engine simply skips over.
</p>
<p>
"Moving Slipspace to PS5 would be similar to the kind of work many other developers - including those with bespoke game tech - have successfully achieved and I don't see much in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/halo-infinite">Halo Infinite</a> that couldn't be achieved on PS5," Leadbetter tells me. 
</p>
<p>
But clearly this - with the move to UE5 instead - is no longer a going concern. Perhaps the biggest obstacle now would be the optics of launching Xbox's flagship franchise on rival hardware, though today's Xbox Wire blog post makes it clear that none of Halo Studios' fresh projects are set to arrive any time soon. 
</p><p>
There's plenty of time, then, for other Microsoft franchises to take the plunge first, following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/four-xbox-exclusive-games-heading-to-ps5-and-switch-according-to-phil-spencer">the arrival on PlayStation of four Xbox games earlier this year</a>, and the upcoming <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-confirmed-for-playstation-5">PS5 launch of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle in early 2025</a>. It will be by no means the last.
</p>
<p>
Perhaps the biggest clue to how Microsoft may treat Halo in the future can be seen in its motives for bringing <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-review">Sea of Thieves</a>' to PS5 - and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-published-sea-of-thieves-reportedly-surpasses-1m-sales-on-playstation-5">the success it has seen as a result</a>. Ahead of its launch on Sony hardware, Microsoft said it wanted to use Sea of Thieves' PS5 version to further grow the live-service pirate game's online audience - benefiting players on PC and Xbox, too. This indeed seems to have occurred. 
</p>
<p>
"This is complete conjecture," Leadbetter closed, "but Halo Infinite has evolved into the kind of live-service game that would benefit from a multiplatform release, just as Sea of Thieves has."
</p>
<p>
Back in August, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-boss-phil-spencer-addresses-indiana-jones-ps5-launch-news-by-saying-xbox-is-a-business">Xbox boss Phil Spencer addressed the continued launch of its games on other console platforms</a> and stated that "Xbox is a business". 
</p>
<p>"We said we'd watch... I might have said, from our learning, we're gonna do more," Spencer said. "What I see when I look is: our franchises are getting stronger. Our Xbox console players are as high this year as they've ever been. I look at it, and I say, okay: our player numbers are going up for the console platform. Our franchises are as strong as they've ever been. And we run a business.
</p><p>"There's a lot of pressure on the industry," he concluded. "It's been growing for a long time, and now people are looking for ways to grow. I think us - as fans, as players of games - we just have to anticipate there's going be more change, and how some of the traditional ways that games are built and distributed - that's gonna change. That's gonna change for all of us. But the end result has to be better games that more people can play. If we're not focused on that, I think we're focused on the wrong things."</p>
<p>Time will tell if this change includes Halo on PS5 - or Switch 2. But with the franchise's future being built on Unreal Engine 5, there's one less barrier to making it happen.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 Remake Supports AMD FSR 3 Frame Generation, NVIDIA DLSS Ray Reconstruction Via Settings File Tweaks; New Mod Improves Cutscenes]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-2-remake-fsr-3-frame-generation-nvidia-dlss-ray-reconstruction-mod/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-supports-amd-fsr-3-frame-generation-nvidia-dlss-ray-reconstruction-via-settings-file-tweaks-new-mod-improves-cutscenes.1002399/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-2-remake-fsr-3-frame-generation-nvidia-dlss-ray-reconstruction-mod/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Though they are not officially supported, both AMD FSR 3 frame generation and NVIDIA DLSS 3.5 Ray Reconstruction can be easily enabled in the Silent Hill 2 remake by Bloober Team, which is now available in early access for those who pre-ordered the game's Deluxe Edition.</p>
<p>As reported by Deck Wizard, to enable AMD FSR 3 frame generation in the game, users need only add the r.FidelityFX.FI.Enabled=1 line under [SystemSettings] in the game's engine.ini file. While it shows some ghosting issues, frame generation can definitely make the game feel smoother, especially for those who are playing on an underpowered system or on Steam Deck.</p>
<p><iframe title="How To Enable FSR 3 Frame Generation In Silent Hill 2 Remake On Steam Deck" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JIQYatT9jxA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Those with an RTX 4000 series card can also enable NVIDIA DLSS 3.5 Ray Reconstruction in the Silent Hill 2 remake using a similar method to enhance the quality of ray tracing. All that needs to be done is adding the following lines to the game's engine.ini file under [SystemSettings], as reported by Aren on <a href="https://x.com/Aren2ouioui">X.</a></p>
<blockquote><p><em>r.NGX.DLSS.denoisermode=1 </em></p>
<p><em>r.Lumen.Reflections.BilateralFilter=0 </em></p>
<p><em>r.Lumen.Reflections.ScreenSpaceReconstruction=0 </em></p>
<p><em>r.lumen.Reflections.Temporal=0 </em></p>
<p><em>r.Shadow.Denoiser=0</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Further improvements to the game are provided by a new mod that enhances cutscenes by removing the black bars that display in any aspect ratio beyond 16:9 and the 30 FPS cap. This mod can be downloaded <a href="https://github.com/RoseTheFlower/UltrawideIndex/releases/tag/silenthill2remake">here.</a></p>
<p>Even in its vanilla state, the Silent Hill 2 remake is more than worthy of any fan's time. Bloober Team not only managed to remake the iconic original in the best possible way but also created its best game to date, as Chris highlighted in his <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/silent-hill-2-restless-dreams-town/">review.</a></p>
<p>The Silent Hill 2 remake launches for everyone tomorrow, October 8th, on PC and PlayStation 5.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic detail plans for Unreal Engine 6 and share vision of a metaverse spanning "Roblox, Minecraft, and Fortnite"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-detail-plans-for-unreal-engine-6-and-share-vision-of-a-metaverse-spanning-roblox-minecraft-and-fortnite</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-detail-plans-for-unreal-engine-6-and-share-vision-of-a-metaverse-spanning-roblox-minecraft-and-fortnite.1002396/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-detail-plans-for-unreal-engine-6-and-share-vision-of-a-metaverse-spanning-roblox-minecraft-and-fortnite<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>"Let the best ecosystem win"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fortnite-tacos.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Epic Games <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-lay-off-830-people-thanks-to-unrealistic-metaverse-ambitions">laid off over 800 people a year ago</a>, following what CEO Tim Sweeney confessed was an "unrealistic" period of investment designed to "grow Fortnite as a metaverse-inspired ecosystem for creators". Now, it's time to start talking about brighter, metaversal tomorrows and hopefully, not do the whole thing all over again. Epic have detailed early plans for Unreal Engine 6, which Sweeney says will combine Unreal Engine with Fortnite's easy-to-use Unreal Editor to create a gigantic, "interoperable" metaverse platform that lets developers sell stuff that can seamlessly be transferred to other games, whether they run on Unreal Engine or not. Stealth blockchain post? Genuinely, I can neither confirm nor deny.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
All this comes from <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/5/24262376/epic-unreal-engine-6-fortnite-metaverse-plans">a new Verge interview</a> with Sweeney and Epic executive vice-president Saxs Persson, which follows this year's Unreal Fest conference in Seattle. Regarding the layoffs, Sweeney told the site that Epic are now financially stable. 
</p>
<p>
"Last year, before Unreal Fest, we were spending about a billion dollars a year more than we were making," he said. "Now, we're spending a bit more than we're making." 
</p>
<p>
Epic "have a very robust amount of funding relative to pretty much any company in the industry and are making forward investments really judiciously that we could throttle up or down as our fortunes change," Sweeney went on. "We feel we're in a perfect position to execute for the rest of this decade and achieve all of our plans at our size."
</p><p>
Foremost among those grand plans is the blueprint for Unreal Engine 6, which will take several years to arrive, and is built around the philosophy of "interoperable content" that can be transferred between any game running on the engine. Epic's principal testcase for this idea is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disney-buy-15-billion-stake-in-fortnite-publisher-epic-announce-new-games-and-entertainment-universe">the Manhattan-Project-ish "games and entertainment universe" they're making for Disney</a>, which will smoosh together the Disney and Fortnite communities to produce a hellish, hybrid race of monsters I call "Disnites", who raid our dwellings by the light of the full moon aboard flying, bus-shaped princesses. I mean, it will supposedly let devs and players move and ferry their digital belongings easily between Fortnite and Unreal Engine worlds based on Disney properties. A battle royale map based on Disneyland seems like an easy win, tbh.
</p>
<p>
In the meantime, Epic are about to open the Fab digital assets marketplace, which will apparently host assets that can work even in non-Unreal-Engine games like Minecraft and Roblox, and is the first step on the road towards a scenario in which Fab creators sell exactly "one logical asset that has different file formats that work in different contexts", meaning you won't have to buy it separately for any other game that supports "interoperability". Sweeney's example in the Verge piece is "a forest mesh set that has different content optimized for Unreal Engine, Unity, Roblox, and Minecraft". 
</p>
<p>
Sweeney's view is that "having seamless movement of content from place to place is going to be one of the critical things that makes the metaverse work without duplication." 
</p>
<p>
I have a couple of fairly predictable comments in response to all this. Firstly: what exactly is "the metaverse" these days? Is it still a loose buzzword for a bunch of ostensibly transformative technologies like VR, and if so, does it still include dodgy prospects like the blockchain and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/if-nfts-are-worthless-how-come-i-have-written-a-third-novel-about-nfts-saving-the-future">NFTs</a>, which promise a similar "interoperability" of materials between games?
</p><p>
Secondly: why would Microsoft want Epic selling stuff that people can bring into Minecraft, rather than just selling those things themselves, as they currently do? Sweeney conceded to the Verge that Epic haven't had any "discussions" about interoperability with other publishers beyond Disney yet, "but we will, over time". He basically thinks companies should set up a revenue sharing scheme, so that all can prosper from 'the same' asset being sold for use in several games.
</p>
<p>
Persson, meanwhile, noted that "people are not dogmatic about where they play," and as such, "there's no reason why we couldn't have a federated way to flow between Roblox, Minecraft, and Fortnite." He added: "From our perspective, that would be amazing, because it keeps people together and lets the best ecosystem win."
</p>
<p>
"Let the best ecosystem win" is possibly a poor choice of words here, inasmuch as it suggests that, goodness gracious, some partners might actually <em>lose out</em> on "interoperability" with Epic's platform. As The Verge notes, Sweeney's vision of "interoperability" between worlds, whether Unreal or no, makes perfect sense for Epic - it means they can pump a little indirect revenue from the increasingly besieged group of games that refuse to use Unreal Engine. But other companies might wish to avoid a scenario in which all their artists are, strictly speaking, making stuff for the Unreal Engine marketplace, rather than the games they're supposed to be working on.
</p>
<p>
I don't know. I'm an idiot non-businessy know-nothing: feel free to give me an education in the comments. Epic are being pretty militant about increasing their returns from third-party platforms at present. In other news, they're still <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-launches-major-new-lawsuit-in-app-store-fight-this-time-against-samsung-and-google">picking legal fights with the likes of Google</a> over how easily players can access Fortnite on their phones.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 Remake Global Release Times Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-global-release-times-confirmed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-global-release-times-confirmed.1002393/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-global-release-times-confirmed<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Konami has revealed the global release times for the <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/silent-hill-2-remake">Silent Hill 2 Remake</a> across PlayStation 5 and PC via Steam.</p><p>The publisher shared launch times for each region in an X/Twitter post, below, across its October 8 release date, confirming exactly when survival horror fans can get their hands on the highly anticipated remake.</p><p>It sees players take on the role of protagonist James Sunderland as he follows a mysterious letter from his late wife to the terrifying town of Silent Hill, which teems with nightmarish monsters out for blood. "Silent Hill 2 is a great way to visit (or revisit) one of the most dread-inducing destinations in the history of survival horror," <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-2024-review">IGN said in our 8/10 review</a>.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here are the global launch times of SILENT HILL 2 for October 8th! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SILENTHILL?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#SILENTHILL</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KONAMI?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#KONAMI</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlooberTeam?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#BlooberTeam</a> <a href="https://t.co/noFaYGnSfQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/noFaYGnSfQ</a></p>— Bloober Team (@BlooberTeam) <a href="https://twitter.com/BlooberTeam/status/1841812001464455336?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 3, 2024</a></blockquote> <h2>Silent Hill 2 Remake PS5 Release Times</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Los Angeles - 9pm PDT (on October 7)</li><li>New York - 0am EDT</li><li>São Paulo - 0am GMT-3</li><li>London - 0am BST</li><li>Paris - 0am CEST</li><li>Warsaw - 0am CEST</li><li>Istanbul - 0am GMT+3</li><li>Riyadh - 0am GMT+3</li><li>Hong Kong - 0am HKT</li><li>Tokyo - 0am JST</li><li>Sydney - 0am AEST</li></ul><h2>Silent Hill 2 Remake PC via Steam Release Times</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Los Angeles - 9pm PDT (on October 7)</li><li>New York - 0am EDT</li><li>São Paulo - 1am GMT-3</li><li>London - 5am BST</li><li>Paris - 6am CEST</li><li>Warsaw - 6am CEST</li><li>Istanbul - 7am GMT+3</li><li>Riyadh - 7am GMT+3</li><li>Hong Kong - 12pm HKT</li><li>Tokyo - 1pm JST</li><li>Sydney - 3pm AEST</li></ul><p>Those on Xbox will have to wait a tad longer, as Sony itself has confirmed <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-console-exclusive-to-ps5-for-1-year">Silent Hill 2 is a PS5 console exclusive for one year</a>. And some fans seemingly upset with the remake's release <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-down-after-persistent-disruptive-editing-lowers-review-scores">took to Wikipedia to falsify lower review scores than Silent Hill 2 actually received</a>, to the point where the website itself had to lock down the page.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 Remake Wikipedia Page Locked Down After ‘Persistent Disruptive Editing’ Lowers Review Scores]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-down-after-persistent-disruptive-editing-lowers-review-scores</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-down-after-%E2%80%98persistent-disruptive-editing%E2%80%99-lowers-review-scores.1002390/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-down-after-persistent-disruptive-editing-lowers-review-scores<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The Silent Hill 2 Remake Wikipedia page was locked down after its list of review scores from the press was edited to make them lower.</p><p>Silent Hill 2 is Bloober Team’s well-received remake of Konami’s classic 2001 psychological horror game for PC and PS5 (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-console-exclusive-to-ps5-for-1-year">it’s console exclusive to PS5 for one year, Sony has confirmed</a>). It sees protagonist James Sunderland following a mysterious letter from his late wife, Mary, and a search for clues in the terrifying namesake town, which is teeming with nightmarish monsters.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-after-salty-fans-try-to-rewrite-its-critically-acclaimed-reception" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eurogamer</a>, admins were forced to make <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silent_Hill_2_(2024_video_game)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wikipedia’s Silent Hill 2 Remake page</a> ‘semi-protected’ after what was called “persistent disruptive editing.”</p><p>Wikipedia’s rules state that semi-protection is sometimes necessary “to prevent vandalism” to popular pages, and that’s exactly what happened here, with admins issuing a number of updates that changelog entries said were “to fix trolling.”</p><p>IGN’s was among the review scores tampered with. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-2024-review">IGN’s Silent Hill 2 Remake review</a> returned an 8/10, but it was lowered to 6/10. Eurogamer’s score dropped down to 0/5 after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-review" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">awarding the game a five-star review</a>. At the time of this article’s publication, the review scores were accurate.</p><p>Why did this happen? Eurogamer speculates it may be driven by trolls who are upset about changes made to the character’s faces and clothes.</p><p>Silent Hill 2 Remake is having a better time of it over on Steam, where it currently enjoys an ‘overwhelmingly positive’ user review rating from over 3,000 reviews. (Silent Hill 2 Remake’s global release date is October 8, but advanced access is available now.)</p><p>Wikipedia’s Silent Hill 2 Remake page protection is set to expire on October 9, although admins may need to keep an eye on it in the near-term at least.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 HD Collection's Comic Sans ranch sign is in the Remake… but not in the way you might think it is]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-hd-collections-comic-sans-ranch-sign-is-in-the-remake-but-not-in-the-way-you-might-think-it-is</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-hd-collections-comic-sans-ranch-sign-is-in-the-remake%E2%80%A6-but-not-in-the-way-you-might-think-it-is.1002387/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-hd-collections-comic-sans-ranch-sign-is-in-the-remake-but-not-in-the-way-you-might-think-it-is<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-10-07-at-11.13.57.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Gmanlives / Konami</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>A nod to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-2">Silent Hill 2</a>'s disastrous HD Collection remake is hidden away in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-2-remake">Silent Hill 2 Remake</a>: the infamous Silent Hill Ranch sign.</p>
<p>Along with <a href="https://www.neogaf.com/threads/silent-hill-hd-collection-ot-programmed-in-smoke-signals.464801/page-45#post-36489999">Maria's nightmare-fuel orthodontic rearrangement</a>, one of the most egregious things to come out of the 2012 version for some was the tragically comical Silent Hill Ranch sign, which <a href="https://x.com/dark1x/status/1779975148818362787">was written in Comic Sans</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Silent Hill 2 Review" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vOv1JTfPnuQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Silent Hill 2 Review</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vOv1JTfPnuQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vOv1JTfPnuQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Silent Hill 2 Review.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vOv1JTfPnuQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>No one's entirely sure if it was an intentional change or merely leftover placeholder text, but it became emblematic of the HD Collection's wider quality and performance issues.</p>
<p>Whilst <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/bloober-team">Bloober Team</a> has addressed many of these problems with its outstanding Remake, it seems the team was keen to honour the game's legacy in more ways than one… including by keeping this silly sign in the new game.</p>
<p>It'll take a little work to see it, though:</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>"So if you clip through the ranch at the start of the Silent Hill 2 remake you can find the Comic Sans font sign hidden away inside. GOTY," GmanLives posted on X/Twitter.</p>
<p>"I'm waiting for someone to make a mod that replaces the Silent Hill Ranch sign with Comic Sans version," <a href="https://x.com/moleslaw_/status/1842984765039022476">quipped</a> one commenter.</p>
<p>Yesterday, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-after-salty-fans-try-to-rewrite-its-critically-acclaimed-reception">Wikipedia had to lock down the Silent Hill 2 Remake page after repeated vandalism</a> from editors who refuse to accept that the remake of Konami's seminal horror game released to critical acclaim last week.</p>
<p>Outright lies around the games reception and metacritic score - including one edit that said the game had "received the worst reviews imaginable" - means the page has now been put into a semi-protected state to stop unregistered users from making wild, unsubstantiated claims.</p><p>"It doesn't matter if you've never played Silent Hill 2 before. It also doesn't matter if you have. Silent Hill 2 Remake's heady blend of old and new delivers the best horror I've played for years, and I suspect that will hold true even for those meeting James for the first time," I wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-review">Eurogamer's Silent Hill 2 Remake review</a>, awarding it 5 out of 5 stars.</p>
<p>Silent Hill 2 Remake releases on PC and PS5 tomorrow, Tuesday 8th October.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dino Crisis Unreal Engine 5 Fan-made Remake Demo Is Now Available for Download]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dino-crisis-unreal-engine-5-remake-download/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dino-crisis-unreal-engine-5-fan-made-remake-demo-is-now-available-for-download.1002378/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dino-crisis-unreal-engine-5-remake-download/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A Dino Crisis remake powered by Unreal Engine 5 is in development by a fan, and a playable demo is now available for download, allowing fans to try out this remake themselves.</p>
<p>The Project Crisis remake is currently being developed by a single developer, Stefano Cagnani, so we shouldn't expect the same level of quality as other fan-made projects with multiple people working on them. Still, the demo is still an interesting way to see how the classic survival horror game would look and play using more modern technology. The demo can be downloaded <a href="https://stefano-cagnani-3.itch.io/dino-crisis-rebirth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p><iframe title="DINO CRISIS Rebirth (Project: Crisis) - NEW GAMEPLAY Trailer (Unreal Engine)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x-KDYOZyYCs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Despite being a beloved classic, CAPCOM hasn't shown much interest in remaking the first entry in the Dino Crisis to date.&nbsp;<span>Back in&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/shinji-mikami-says-no-need-for-dino-crisis-to-exist-when-monster-hunter-is-so-successful/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">August</a>, producer and director of the original game, Shinji Mikami, talked about the franchise, saying that the success of the Monster Hunter series reduced the need for a new entry in the series, a weird statement considering the two franchises have nothing in common.</span>&nbsp;Still, as CAPCOM did bring back one of its beloved series that hadn't seen a new entry in the while, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-coming-back-to-life/">Dead Rising</a>, there's still hope for a remake of the original Dino Crisis in a similar fashion.</p>
<p>While waiting for CAPCOM to bring back the series, PlayStation 5 owners will soon be able to enjoy the original Dino Crisis on their system, as the game will be added to the PlayStation Plus Classics lineup this month, together with another beloved classic, Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Silent Hill 2 Remake’s Wikipedia page briefly got transformed into a phantasmagorical reflection of the psyches of idiots unable to accept reality]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-silent-hill-2-remakes-wikipedia-page-briefly-got-transformed-into-a-phantasmagorical-reflection-of-the-psyches-of-idiots-unable-to-accept-reality</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-silent-hill-2-remake%E2%80%99s-wikipedia-page-briefly-got-transformed-into-a-phantasmagorical-reflection-of-the-psyches-of-idiots-unable-to-accept-reality.1002375/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-silent-hill-2-remakes-wikipedia-page-briefly-got-transformed-into-a-phantasmagorical-reflection-of-the-psyches-of-idiots-unable-to-accept-reality<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>If you’ve been keeping up with the positive review scores for the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/silent-hill-2-remake">Silent Hill 2 Remake</a>, you may have been surprised to read the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silent_Hill_2_(2024_video_game)">Wikipedia</a> page over the weekend, only to learn that the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror game</a> had "received the worst reviews imaginable." As spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-after-salty-fans-try-to-rewrite-its-critically-acclaimed-reception">Eurogamer</a>, the page has now been locked following some deranged edits that altered review scores to appear much lower than they actually were.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Silent Hill 2 - Official Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M_WNxWctGsk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Silent Hill 2 - Official Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M_WNxWctGsk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/M_WNxWctGsk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M_WNxWctGsk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>These salty edits were apparently the work of the usual suspects. You know, the sort of silly sausages that love games so much they spend every waking hour not playing them so they’ve got more time to harass voice actors - although there’s also some speculation it might have been series diehards sceptical about the positive reception. The edits have been attributed to both <a href="https://x.com/airbagged/status/1842644442433700020">“anti-woke dorks”</a> and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/silenthill/comments/1fwvmqb/seriously_trolls_cant_handle_sh2rs_success_so">“trolls”</a>, although I’ve also seen the words “Asmongold Subreddit” floating about.</p>
<p>There was also some highly ignorable twattery around Maria’s new character design not being suitably jorkable doing the rounds, which is very funny if you know where the story goes. The nonsense has even found it’s way to series artist Masahiro Ito, <a href="https://x.com/adsk4/status/1843210691492422049">who Xeetered</a> “This is NOT the account to take it out on. I decided to block all of them who did it to me IMMEDIATELY from now on,” presumably in response to general trolling.</p>
<p>I did briefly check Wikipedia just to see how easy it was to edit a page, since I’d never done it before. Turns out, yep, it takes mere seconds. Don't worry, I changed it back. </p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deep-rock-2.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Wikipedia/Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Silent Hill 2 Remake itself has been available to play for a few days now, but only for fans that purchased the Digital Deluxe edition. I will call "premium access" out as bullshit whenever I see it, but those early players are at least having a good time - it’s currently sitting at a 96% ‘Overwhelmingly Positive’ on Steam. None of this means anything until our man-in-the-fog Brendy unleashes his own verdict, of course, so do check back for that soon.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>