<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 20:19:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drive Rally Preview – Arcade thrills meet sim rally spills]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/21/drive-rally-preview-arcade-thrills-meet-sim-rally-spills/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/drive-rally-preview-%E2%80%93-arcade-thrills-meet-sim-rally-spills.960195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/21/drive-rally-preview-arcade-thrills-meet-sim-rally-spills/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>For people who worship at the glorious squelch of mud and the reassuring spray of dirt from a rear wheel, rally games are the pinnacle of the racing genre. Rather than your Forza Motorsports and your Gran’s Turismo, fans have enjoyed games like the iconic Sega Rally, Colin McCrae, and WRC series from a variety of developers, with the rally game becoming a grubby staple of our racing heritage. It’s fair to say though that it’s all got very serious, shifting away from arcade thrills to pure sim racing.</p>
<p>Drive Rally looks to forge a point between those two extremes, bringing chunky, retro-styled visuals together with a thoughtful, but not overly exacting, handling model. It’s doing something that no one else is right now – come on Sega, we’re waiting! – and in our early hands-on, it’s doing it very well indeed.</p>
<p><iframe title="#DRIVE Rally | Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0hhmI6MoImo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Drive Rally doesn’t feature any licensed cars, but it does feature cars that bear striking (but legally distinct) resemblances to iconic rallying legends of the past. There’s the Celestia doing it’s very best Toyota Celica impression, as well as a very Audi Quattro-esque little number called Das Sandstorm. Meanwhile, Das Bretzel is totally not a BMW. Definitely not.</p>
<p>While they’re not quite the real thing, they’re all very characterful, and you can upgrade their bodykit and various parts, adding increasingly outlandish spoilers, headlights and tyre mounts. Each car handles differently, with that profile changing as you alter its spec and upgrade, and while we only had a small selection to choose from, there’s going to be at least 27 different cars in the final version.</p>

<p>Much of Drive Rally’s attraction lies in its art-style, with a landscape that focuses on the key elements, and presents them in the same retro-infused 3D as the cars. It’s fun returning to a world where every tree isn’t a million polygons, and it allows you to concentrate on staying on the track, which, as you’d expect with a rally game, is not a foregone conclusion.</p>

<p>Drive Rally straddles the line between exacting precision and arcade-y floatiness, and once you get used to what it’s asking of you you’ll have the same edge-of-seat experience you’ll find in the best rally games. Hurtling along, waiting for a corner to leer out at you is tempered by one of the three enigmatic co-drivers and their relatively accurate pace notes. There is a strange drop-off in traction when you brake at the moment, and cars feel a little too sluggish to get going again once you’ve slowed, but I like the handling overall.</p>
<p>In true old-school fashion, there’s two options here, either a Quick Race or the Championship series. Each manufacturer has their own set of tracks within the championship, and you can unlock new car parts and new cars as you progress through the in-game scrapbook. It’s beautifully laid out, showcasing your times, rewards and a few other bits and pieces, though it could do with being a bit clearer about the race you’ve just completed. While there’s no online multiplayer, there are online leaderboards so you can compare yourself to the other Drive Ralliers out there.</p>

<p>There’s so much to like about Drive Rally. I love the visual style, and there’s a sense of fun that’s often lacking in modern racers. I like how focused it is too, and while there are some elements of the cars handling that that need a little tuning up, it’s in a great place as it heads towards an Early Access launch.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Games Workshop Imposes Golden Demon AI Ban, Preventing Its Use In Miniature Painting Competition]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/games-workshop-imposes-golden-demon-ai-ban-preventing-its-use-in-miniature-painting</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/games-workshop-imposes-golden-demon-ai-ban-preventing-its-use-in-miniature-painting-competition.960192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/games-workshop-imposes-golden-demon-ai-ban-preventing-its-use-in-miniature-painting<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Back in January, Games Workshop released details for this year's <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/games-workshop-reveals-golden-demon-2024-details" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Golden Demon</a> competition. It is one of the largest miniature painting competitions in the world, accepting submissions from all <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/warhammer-40000" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Warhammer</em></a> properties and the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/middle-earth-strategy-battle-game-second-edition-updates-war-for-ring" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Middle-earth Strategy Battle Game</em></a>. Now, GW has updated its guidelines, and implemented a Golden Demon AI ban.</p>

<p>The Golden Demon AI Ban can be found in the <a href="https://citadelcolour.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/rIUY6MVHgkR2J1Vj.pdf">official 2024</a> category list and entry guidelines. The change can be found in the FAQ section. Question 8 asks "Am I allowed to use Artificial Intelligence to generate any part of my entry?" The answer is a simple "No."</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/golden-demon-2023-exodite-neil-hollis-image.jpg?itok=ix9Bc_Ag 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/golden-demon-2023-exodite-neil-hollis-image.jpg?itok=dqUTV_th 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This is an important decision given the controversial use of AI in creative fields. All AI-generated artwork is, by design, stolen from other artists and cobbled together into a derivative work. To pass off such derivative work as your own is plagiarism. It is a fact many tech companies are contending with <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/nvidia-sued-for-scraping-youtube-videos-for-ai-training/">in court right now</a>.</p>
<p>Games Workshop enforcing this Golden Demon AI ban has precedent from last year. Neil Hollis, a 12-time Golden Demon winner, took home the gold in 2023's <em>Warhammer 40,000: Single Miniature</em> competition for his <a href="https://thegoldendemoncompendium.com/entry?id=mkNYh9HTQB">Exodite miniature</a>. The miniature and paint were all made from approved materials, but the backdrop was AI-generated.</p>
<p>Hollis spoke openly about the controversy in a video interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ouFUPIA9bug">The Painting Phase</a>. Hollis mentioned the contention around his entry, including waves of hostility and support from parts of the community.</p>
<p>In the video, Hollis expressed the convenience of AI tools and acknowledged using them to generate his backdrop was a risk. Not due to the ethical implications of the technology, but on the basis that the backdrop was printed and not painted.</p>
<p>Regardless, if Hollis plans on winning any awards at this year's Golden Demon, he will have to do so without AI tools.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shattered Space's Irresistible Horror Vibes Have Me Ready To Reinstall Starfield]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/starfield-dlc-shattered-space-bethesda-horror-1851628323</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shattered-spaces-irresistible-horror-vibes-have-me-ready-to-reinstall-starfield.960189/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/starfield-dlc-shattered-space-bethesda-horror-1851628323<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Shattered Space</em>, the upcoming first major expansion to <em>Starfield</em>, feels like Bethesda returning to an old, comfy chair. Albeit a horror-driven, combat-intensive chair set in a half-destroyed capital city that’s the victim of a tear in space-time. But rather than another galaxy-wide sprawling set of adventures like the base game, this is a tale told on one planet, a confined and controlled narrative that is far more reminiscent of the old <em>Elder Scrolls</em> approach.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196742" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="254" data-playlist="196742,196163,195150" data-current="196742"><div><p>What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22297.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>During Bethesda’s behind-closed-doors showing of the game, Va’ruun’kai was shown to be a planet distinct from the rest of the explorable galaxy. Its capital city has been rent asunder by a tear in the fabric of space-time, a place described as somewhere humanity’s search for knowledge—that otherwise drives the overarching narrative of <em>Starfield</em>—has “gone too far.” Whatever its scientists were up to, and it was something to do with “grav-drive technology,” it’s had devastating effects, and you’re now exploring the remains as various factions fight for control in the void of leadership.<br></p><p>The <em>Shattered Space</em> demo footage shown at this week’s Gamescom began with a brutal scene of floating dead bodies in dank, metallic corridors, a vibe that immediately spoke far more of horror than <em>Starfield</em>’s more familiar science fiction cleanliness. This is a planet with a more <em>alien</em> feel, its landscape much more peculiar, featuring gravitational anomalies among the many things going wrong for the locals.<br></p><p>What followed in the demo was a lengthy series of events taking place in the aftermath of the Va’ruun people’s recent disaster, which is so much worse when you learn those rifts in space are now letting in some gruesome monsters from another reality. The immediate vibe was <em>FEAR</em>— it very strikingly reminded me of Monolith’s classic spook-shooters, as the player character crept around abandoned sci-fi corridors, plagued by the grim beasts incessantly leaping at them.<br></p><p>Bethesda’s Brian Chaplin described Va’ruun’kai as a “secluded, hand-crafted location,” featuring an “isolated faction” who had been living on the planet separate from outside communication. Their culture had therefore developed independently of what has previously been explored in <em>Starfield</em>, which of course gives carte blanche for the team to make something that feels other, distinct, and not shackled by the perhaps less than-adored nature of the rest of the game. If anything, it seems to have given them freedom to return to their roots.<br></p><p>So following this recent crisis, with vast amounts of the capital city destroyed, and before any rebuilding has begun, you show up. The remainder of the citadel, where the power structure of the area was based, is now contained within some peculiar energy field, and the leader is missing, meaning there’s a power vacuum. This is pursued by “minor houses,” the area’s factions—the Zealots, Spacers and Crimson Fleet—looking to fill the political void. And that of course means all sorts of factional rivalry.<br></p><p>To match the different location, Bethesda is looking to see the game played differently too. While most people have approached <em>Starfield</em> as a remote shooter, keeping your distance and sniping from afar, in <em>Shattered Space</em>, there’s a push to force people to get far more up close and impersonal, with ambushes, close quarters combat, and a great deal more panic.<br></p><p>“We wanted to lean in on the mystery and horror aspects,” said Bethesda. “Space is scary, and part of getting that across is tapping into the chaos of combat.” It’s all very much part of what is a horror-first expansion.<br></p><p>While you can leave the planet any time you wish, given <em>Starfield</em>’s open nature, the plot here is entirely self-contained, and exploration of the planet and the city will lead to uncovering exactly what happened here, and, we’re told, becoming “entangled in the political feud between the minor houses.” You, of course, will be a part of deciding the fate of the city, and which faction eventually takes control.<br></p><p>This refocusing of how <em>Starfield</em> is played and experienced could be a boon for the ailing project. While Bethesda describes it as “one of our biggest games,” the publisher could well be including the likes of <em>Rogue Warrior </em>and <em>Wet</em> in that list, and <em>Starfield</em> has certainly not retained its audience. At the time of writing, it’s sporting a desultory 6,000 players on Steam, compared to 2015’s <em>Fallout 4</em> with a casual 17,000. So releasing something that seems so deliberately different, both in terms of its vibe and its nature, could be a well-timed decision.<br></p><p>The idea that there’s a complete, detailed story to play through, all taking place in one confined location, alongside its <em>FEAR</em>-like atmosphere, has me wanting to return to the game for the first time since its launch week. Presumably Bethesda is hoping this will be a desire shared by the hundreds of thousands who were playing back in July.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[#DRIVE Rally launches in Early Access for PC on September 25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/drive-rally-launches-in-early-access-for-pc-on-september-25</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/drive-rally-launches-in-early-access-for-pc-on-september-25.960183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/drive-rally-launches-in-early-access-for-pc-on-september-25<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Early Access version includes four locations, 12 cars, Championship mode, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>#DRIVE Rally</em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,017 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> and Mac via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2494780/DRIVE_Rally/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/drive-rally-d500ef" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/game/drive_rally" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOG</a> on September 25 for $19.99, followed by a full launch across PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, Switch, and PC in 2025, developer <a title="Companies > Pixel Perfect Dude [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pixel-perfect-dude">Pixel Perfect Dude</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2494780/view/4203624569927583283" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>. <span id="more-907073"></span></p><p>The Early Access version of the game will include:</p><ul><li>Four unique locations, each with up to 24 stages that can be driven in standard or reversed modes.</li><li>Championship mode, featuring a selection of four fully voiced co-drivers.</li><li>A selection of 12 cars with unique performance stats, plus three different classes per car, amounting to 36 unique variations.</li><li>Fixes, quality-of-life improvements, and community-driven updates based on feedback from <em>#DRIVE Rally</em>‘s community.</li></ul><p>Additional locations, co-drivers, championships, cars, car livery customization, and more will be added throughout the Early Access period.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Pixel Perfect Dude:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>#DRIVE Rally</em> isn’t just a trip down memory lane; it’s an <a title="Genres > Arcade [59 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a>-inspired rally-driving experience set in the golden <a title="Genres > Racing [197 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> era of the ’90s. From the lush, evergreen forests of Holzberg in Germany, to the twisty, arid roads of the American southwest, <em>#DRIVE Rally</em> offers a variety of iconic tracks and legendary rally cars that players can tune and customize. Whether you’re a newcomer or a seasoned pro, the game ensures that every race is challenging and rewarding. Plus, co-drivers aren’t just there for the ride—they bring personality to the journey with their unique brand of humour and insightful driving directions!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em>#DRIVE</em> All Over the World</strong> – From the sunny landscapes of Dry Crumbs, through the whispering woods of Holzberg, to the chilly wilderness of Revontuli, each track offers unique features and asks drivers to go the distance.</li><li><strong>Legendary Cars</strong> – Jump behind the wheel of legendary rally cars, including Das Holzwagen, The Doggo, The Bobond, and many more from the studio’s previous title #DRIVE. New from the ‘90s era are Das Sandsturm and Celestia, just for a start!</li><li><strong>Passionate Co-Drivers</strong> – For better or worse, your co-driver is with you to the end! There to help and lend some humourous jabs, they’re your trusty navigator—and your worst critic.</li><li><strong><em>#DRIVE</em> Design</strong> – It’s your way and the highway, baby! From tires to tailpipe, build your car to your liking. Add your special touches with paintwork, decals, and decorations. Take a picture in Photo Mode—it’ll last longer.</li><li><strong><em>#DRIVE</em> Like it’s 1999</strong> – Pumped up with 90’s Easter Eggs and references in an adoring homage to the thunderous days of rally racing circa 1990s, this game feels like a finely-tuned arcade experience, with no coins needed.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="#DRIVE Rally | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0hhmI6MoImo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drill Core launches in Early Access on September 12]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/drill-core-launches-in-early-access-on-september-12</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/drill-core-launches-in-early-access-on-september-12.960180/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/drill-core-launches-in-early-access-on-september-12<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Corporate greed meets strategic planet mining.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>“Strategic mining game” <em><a title="Games > Drill Core [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/drill-core">Drill Core</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,017 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2821800/Drill_Core/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on September 12, publisher <a title="Companies > tinyBuild [121 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tinybuild">tinyBuild</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Hungry Couch [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hungry-couch">Hungry Couch</a> announced. <span id="more-908719"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via tinyBuild:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Drill Core</em> is a strategic mining game. Dig to the center of the planet, find rare materials, and defend yourself from alien attack as you build your mining platform base and plan the best way to strike it rich.</p><p>Boss others into doing the hard work for you as you manage your own mining crew to descend deeper into the planet’s core. Deep dive and drill down on those deliverables by investing in a mix of barracks, factories and new tech during the day to keep your colony strong and reach the planet’s core. Make important corporate decisions like building up your platform’s defenses with turrets and guards to keep everyone safe, or pushing on for glory and greater rewards by focusing on the dig. Be mindful though, as when night falls aliens will attack from both above and below and endanger your precious revenue.</p><p>Each mission is unique, with procedurally generated planets, monsters, and conditions to test your strategy prowess. Will you move the needle and disrupt your approach or is it all above your paygrade? Collect valuable resources as you mine downwards to spend on upgrading your rig and employing new workers to optimize your dig. Each successful mission will unlock new upgrades for your platform so be sure to plan carefully and pick the right tools for the job. How deep will you get on your next run?</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Drill down to the planet’s core and earn mineral riches.</li><li>Lead your crew to boost your revenue.</li><li>Build factories, barracks and tech to grow your base.</li><li>Defend your colony from hordes of aliens.</li><li>Customize your platform and plan your dig for the most rewards.</li><li>Every mission is unique with randomized enemies and dig conditions.</li><li>Nostalgic pixel art style.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Drill Core - Release Date Trailer | Awesome Indies | Gamescom 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_7hoS-UeZ5I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Won't Have Gender Locked Armor, A Series First]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-wont-have-gender-locked-armor-a-series-first/1100-6526033/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-wont-have-gender-locked-armor-a-series-first.960177/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-wont-have-gender-locked-armor-a-series-first/1100-6526033/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526033">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2024-08-21T13:00:50-0800">August 21, 2024 at 1:00PM PDT</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" data-ref-id="5000-612214">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> will allow players to mix and match armor pieces from both genders, regardless of the character they create. Revealed during the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/__dNDhhJzQo?si=7dIv5Ol72pO8107i&amp;t=1769">Monster Hunter Wilds developer livestream</a> during Gamescom, Capcom showed a character equipping both male and female armor pieces from the same armor set, where they confirmed the feature would be in the new entry.</p><p dir="ltr">While this might not sound like a big deal, this is the first time in the Monster Hunter series that armor isn't locked to your created character's gender. In previous entries, there were different designs for each armor set: one for male characters and one for female. While the two different sets will still be present in Monster Hunter Wilds, you will no longer be forced into one set or the other. Instead, you can choose which version of the armor set you want for each individual piece.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1126342976" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464921,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;We%20Played%20Monster%20Hunter%20Wilds%20And%20It%20Rules%20Hands%20On%20Preview&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:760,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/we-played-monster-hunter-wilds-and-it-rules-hands-on-preview\/2300-6464921\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464921\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464921\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464921\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464921&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464921,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526033&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;monster-hunter-wilds&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;collection&quot;:&quot;gamescom&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;capcom&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;monster-hunter&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;monster-hunter&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464921},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464921\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1352\/13527689\/4354166-preview_monsterhunterwilds_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/GJGmNtdH.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724238000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="GJGmNtdH" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> We Played Monster Hunter Wilds And It Rules Hands On Preview</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Not only does this double the number of cosmetic options for armor, but Monster Hunter has previously had restrictions when it came to editing your character's appearance. In <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/582010/Monster_Hunter_World/" rel="nofollow ">Monster Hunter World</a>, Capcom offered a single character-edit voucher for free to claim as DLC, but getting more vouchers cost real money. If you didn't want to pay, you would have to make a new character to change your appearance or gender, making it difficult to switch if you preferred the other look for an armor set. It also gives players who prefer to build their armor sets based on visual appearance even more freedom when it comes to making their outfits.</p><p dir="ltr">Monster Hunter Wilds is set to release in 2025 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. Monster Hunter Wilds also got a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/monster-hunter-wilds-trailer-gamescom-2024/2300-6464907/" data-ref-id="2300-6464907">new story trailer</a> during Gamescom Opening Night Live, highlighting new monsters and some of the companions.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525928&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/buy-two-get-one-free-nintendo-switch-games-and-preorders-my-best-buy-members\/1100-6525928\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525217&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-start-time-how-to-watch\/1100-6525217\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525985&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/persona-5s-joker-is-coming-to-persona-3-reload-as-an-enemy\/1100-6525985\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525905&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-myth-wukong-gets-special-edition-8bitdo-wireless-controller-available-now-for-35\/1100-6525905\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525901&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/last-chance-to-get-lego-super-mario-64-question-block-before-its-gone-for-good\/1100-6525901\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525915&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-criterion-collections-40-film-box-set-costs-more-than-the-ps5-you-watch-blu-rays-on\/1100-6525915\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525948&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-cancels-star-wars-the-acolyte-after-a-single-season\/1100-6525948\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525916&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/rockstar-classic-bully-launches-on-new-platforms-via-gta-this-week\/1100-6525916\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525861&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/transformers-blu-ray-box-set-amazon-preorder\/1100-6525861\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525900&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hollow-knight-silksong-will-not-be-shown-at-gamescom-opening-night-live\/1100-6525900\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525971&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-preorder-guide-pc-ps5-xbox-series-x-nintendo-switch\/1100-6525971\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525999&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fortnites-op-marvel-weapons-have-been-nerfed-thankfully\/1100-6525999\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525898&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-myth-wukong-guides-hub\/1100-6525898\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525906&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2-finishes-filming-see-photos-from-the-wrap-party\/1100-6525906\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525903&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/attack-on-titan-final-season-final-chapters-blu-ray-preorder-amazon\/1100-6525903\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525946&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-reportedly-coming-to-playstation-5\/1100-6525946\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525993&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/this-new-game-dumps-free-to-play-model-changes-to-40-premium-release\/1100-6525993\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Robert Downey Jr. Explains How He Was Convinced To Return To The MCU]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/robert-donwey-jr-rdj-doctor-doom-avengers-mcu-1851628220</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robert-downey-jr-explains-how-he-was-convinced-to-return-to-the-mcu.960144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/robert-donwey-jr-rdj-doctor-doom-avengers-mcu-1851628220<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Robert Downey Jr. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/robert-downey-jr-rdj-doctor-doom-avengers-marvel-sdcc-1851607689&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/robert-downey-jr-rdj-doctor-doom-avengers-marvel-sdcc-1851607689">shocked, energized, and dismayed</a></span> various comic book fans earlier this summer when it was revealed he would return to the Marvel Cinematic Universe as Doctor Doom in 2026's <em>Avengers: Doomsday</em>. More recently, he shared a bit more detail on how he found himself back in line for another massive Hollywood payday. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197209" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Boys Star Karen Fukuhara On Kimiko’s Character Arc, Karate, And More" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="319" data-playlist="197209,196923,196922" data-current="197209"><div><p>The Boys Star Karen Fukuhara On Kimiko’s Character Arc, Karate, And More</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22759.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Speaking on the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/robert-downey-jr-dr-doom-the-sympathizer-broadway-debut-1235979275/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/robert-downey-jr-dr-doom-the-sympathizer-broadway-debut-1235979275/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">latest episode</a></span> of<em> The Hollywood Reporter</em>’s Awards Chatter podcast, the occasional singer and <em>Ally McBeal </em>season 4 star outlined in broad strokes how he was enlisted to return to the most lucrative, and perhaps played out, franchise in movie history. Despite leaving the <em>Avengers </em>behind after dying in 2019's<em> Endgame</em>, RDJ said he still keeps in touch with directors Anthony and Joe Russo, as well as Marvel Studios president Kevin Feige.</p><p>He was set up to meet with Feige in 2023 to discuss reprising his Iron Man role for performances tied to certain Disney theme park attractions when the executive ambushed him with a much bigger proposal. “He said, ‘It just keeps occurring to me, if you were to come back…,’ and Susan [his wife] was like, ‘Wait, wait, come back as what?,’” Downey <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/robert-downey-jr-kevin-feige-doctor-doom-1235979584/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/robert-downey-jr-kevin-feige-doctor-doom-1235979584/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said on the podcast</a></span>, thinking back to the fateful encounter.</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doctor-doom-mcu-robert-downey-jr-rdj-recommended-comics-1851609329&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doctor-doom-mcu-robert-downey-jr-rdj-recommended-comics-1851609329">7 Great Doctor Doom Comics You Should Go Read Right Now</a></span></p><p>Feige apparently kept talking about all the problems with bringing RDJ back before pivoting to his pitch for Doom. “‘How can we not go backwards? How can we not disappoint expectations? How can we continue to beat expectations?’” Downey said, describing the concerns. “And he brought up Victor Von Doom. I looked into this character. Later on, he goes, ‘Let’s get Victor Von Doom right.’”</p><p>The seed planted, the actor said he later met with Disney CEO Bob Iger to survey what was being worked on for the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.dailynews.com/2024/08/20/fly-like-iron-man-on-stark-flight-lab-ride-coming-to-disneyland/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.dailynews.com/2024/08/20/fly-like-iron-man-on-stark-flight-lab-ride-coming-to-disneyland/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Iron Man-themed Stark Flight Lab ride</a></span> and other parts of the Disneyland MCU attraction <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/disneylands-avengers-attraction-is-officially-called-avengers-infinity-defense-d23-2024&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/disneylands-avengers-attraction-is-officially-called-avengers-infinity-defense-d23-2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">called “Avengers Infinity Defense.</a></span>” “So then I said to Kevin, ‘Can I go talk to Bob Iger?’” Downey said. “He goes, ‘About?’ I go, ‘About everything. I’d gone to Bob’s house and I don’t know how to describe that experience. I’ve had a lot of really cool experiences, but I go to Iger’s pad, we sit down and he goes, ‘I like it.’ I was like, ‘He likes it.’ </p><p>Downey later said that the Avengers-based Disney rides being worked were mind-blowing, but didn’t spill any more details about why the same might be said for how he’ll being returning to the MCU as Doom. He also left out the part where <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/robert-downey-jr-dr-doom-mcu-pay-controversy-1851609881&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/robert-downey-jr-dr-doom-mcu-pay-controversy-1851609881">he’s apparently getting $80 million</a></span> and lots of other exclusive perks in order to come back and try to revive the currently faltering transmedia comic book hero industrial complex. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sea Of Thieves Sold Over 1 Million Copies On PS5, Report Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sea-of-thieves-sold-over-1-million-copies-on-ps5-report-claims/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sea-of-thieves-sold-over-1-million-copies-on-ps5-report-claims.960141/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sea-of-thieves-sold-over-1-million-copies-on-ps5-report-claims/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-54046">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Sea of Thieves continues to be a massive success for Xbox and PlayStation. According to a new report, Sea of Thieves has sold more than 1 million copies on PlayStation 5 (PS5).</p>



<p>“[T]rusted sources have indicated to me that Sea of Thieves has crossed a million sales on PlayStation since its launch over there, and is most likely higher still since this information came to me,” Jez Corden of <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/phil-spencer-we-have-more-xbox-console-players-than-ever-as-fans-question-microsofts-multi-platform-strategy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Windows Central reports</a>.</p>







<p>If the numbers are accurate, Microsoft is looking at an extra $40 million-plus in revenue that it wouldn’t have had if they kept the game exclusive. As Corden astutely states, however, the actual revenue is likely higher due to in-game purchases that can also be made.</p>



<p>The game launched on PS5 on April 30. The game has been available on PC and Xbox since March 2018.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Microsoft and PlayStation for comment on the rumored sales numbers. Should a response be received, this article will be updated accordingly.</p>



<hr>



<p>Have you played Sea of Thieves on PS5 since it launched? For more Insider Gaming, check out exclusive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-the-beast-exclusive-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details surrounding Dying Light: The Beast</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-new-details-anti-cheat-esports/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-new-details-anti-cheat-esports/">Splitgate 2: New Details on Anti-Cheat, Esports, and Updates</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>We sat down with the co-founder and CEO of 1047 Games, Ian Proulx, to learn about the development of Splitgate 2.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dune-awakening-gets-25-minutes-of-new-gameplay/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dune-awakening-gets-25-minutes-of-new-gameplay/">Dune: Awakening Gets 25 Minutes Of New Gameplay</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>During its appearance at Gamescom 2024, developer Funcom released a walkthrough with over 25 minutes of new gameplay for Dune: Awakening.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-on-why-indiana-jones-is-coming-to-ps5/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-on-why-indiana-jones-is-coming-to-ps5/">Phil Spencer On Why Indiana Jones Is Coming To PS5</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>During a Microsoft Gamescom Q&amp;A, Xbox head Phil Spencer talked about why Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is coming to PS5.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-hands-on-another-indie-must-buy/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-hands-on-another-indie-must-buy/">Squirrel With a Gun Hands On – Another Indie Must Buy</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Squirrel With A Gun is shaping up to be another indie success, and left us wanting more after a short hands-on with the game.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond Galaxyland launches September 24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/beyond-galaxyland-launches-september-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beyond-galaxyland-launches-september-24.960138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/beyond-galaxyland-launches-september-24<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>2.5D <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,691 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> <a title="Genres > RPG [16,538 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Beyond Galaxyland [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/beyond-galaxyland">Beyond Galaxyland</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,757 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,948 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,417 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,818 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, adn <a title="Platforms > PC [21,017 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1543710/Beyond_Galaxyland/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/beyond-galaxyland-521b75" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on September 24, publisher <a title="Companies > United Label [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ci-games/united-label">United Label</a> Games and developer <a title="Companies > Sam Enright [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sam-enright">Sam Enright</a>. <span id="more-908714"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via United Label Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Inspired by classic sci-fi movies, <em>Beyond Galaxyland</em> is an intergalactic, 2.5D adventure RPG set among the stars. Step into the sneakers of high-schooler Doug, as he’s whisked away to “Galaxyland”—a zoo-like solar system of planets—on an epic quest to save Earth itself.</p><p>An all-new take on the beloved RPG adventures of old, prepare for a journey like no other, skyrocketing through teeming jungles, neon-lit cities, and cybernetic casinos, with each new planet brimming with intriguing characters, fiendish adversaries, and many other surprises.</p><p>Accompanied by Doug’s pet guinea pig—the pistol-wielding Boom Boom—and a sentient robot called MartyBot, together you must defend the world against an all-powerful entity known only as “The End,” before it conquers the Universe itself…</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>No pressure.</p><p><strong>A Bold New Take on the Classic <a title="Genres > Science-Fiction [65 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/science-fiction">Science-Fiction</a> Caper!</strong></p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> firsthand all the thrills and spills of a retro science-fiction adventure, in an all-new take on the fish-out-of-water tale that sticks you right in the center of the <a title="Genres > Action [2,105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>! Laughter, loss, peril and friendship, <em>Beyond Galaxyland</em> has it all and then some, dipped in a dazzling layer of neon-tastic pixels.</p><p><strong>Explore a Solar System of Extraordinary Worlds</strong></p><p>From the blizzard-swept planes of <a title="Games > Arco [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/arco">Arco</a>s to the tropical jungle ravines of Erros, the neon-buzzing cities of Neo to the arid sand dunes of Xalm, explore a cosmic cluster of unique worlds, each with its own quests, environmental puzzles, and out-of-this-world characters.</p><p><strong>Overcome Cosmic Foes in Tactical Turn-Based Combat</strong></p><p>Engage in strategic turn-based battles against a vast range of galactic nemeses, with time-responsive defensive gameplay to minimize damage. Each party member has a range of unique abilities at their disposal, but for an additional tactical advantage, sneakily scan your enemy pre-battle to discover their strengths and weaknesses.</p><p><strong>Experience Epic Boss Battles</strong></p><p>Each planet boasts its own distinct perils, but none more so than the epic bosses you’ll encounter throughout your extraterrestrial travels, including colossal space dragons, flesh eating flowers, and the all-knowing bionic behemoth that is Nexus Mind.</p><p><strong>Capture Enemies to Use in Battle</strong></p><p><a title="Companies > SUCCESS Corporation [89 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/success-corporation">Success</a>fully capture the many weird and wonderful creatures you encounter, to later unleash them in battle, with each possessing a number of exclusive abilities. Will you acquire every last one?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Explore the many extraordinary worlds of Galaxyland in an adventure to save the Earth.</li><li>Experience a thrilling story that pays homage to your favorite retro science-fiction movies.</li><li>Form a party of diverse companions to overcome foes in tactical turn-based combat.</li><li>Capture enemies in combat to later unleash as allies or buffs during future battles.</li><li>Craft new armors and consumables to aid Doug and his pals on their journey.</li><li>Engage in over 25 epic boss battles with the Universe’s most-feared adversaries.</li><li>A truly unique soundtrack unlike anything you’ve heard (at least on this planet) with over 50 diverse tracks spanning a myriad of genres from electronic to hip-hop to piano-heavy blues.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Beyond Galaxyland – Release Date Trailer – Nintendo Switch" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GXDbIVeAibM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virtuos acquires co-developer Third Kind Studios]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/virtuos-acquires-co-developer-third-kind-studios</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/virtuos-acquires-co-developer-third-kind-studios.960132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/virtuos-acquires-co-developer-third-kind-studios<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Omeda Studios/Third Kind.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><div data-testid="content-paragraph"><p><span data-testid="content-text">External development partner Virtuos has just announced its acquisition of Third Kind Studios, a move that they say will, "bolster Virtuos’ AAA co-development capabilities" in the years to come. </span></p><p><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://thirdkindgames.com/news/TKG-joins-Virtuos/">In an announcement on its website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the company revealed that the studio will continue to be led by its original co-founders and that it seeks to double its headcount in the coming years in response to growing client demand.</span></p></div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Founded in 2016, Third Kind has co-developed several triple-A games in recent years. Many of them come from Xbox (like the new </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fable </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sea of Thieves</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">), and also include </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Predecessor, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Omeda's revival of Epic Games' once-defunct MOBA </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/epic-is-closing-down-i-paragon-i-and-offering-refunds-to-players">Paragon</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Per CTO Ray Tharanee, this is the first UK venture for its new parent company. On the studio's end, this will allow it to take on "new and exciting triple-A projects" and continue its own growth, including doubling its staff over the next two years.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We're proud to play a pivotal role in expanding [Viruos'] global footprint, and we look forward to pushing the boundaries of what's possible in gaming together," he wrote.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Over the past year, Virtuos has opened studios in international cities such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/virtuos-opens-tokyo-studio-to-strengthen-relationship-with-japanese-developers">Tokyo</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/virtuos-expands-engineering-capabilities-with-new-prague-studio">Prague</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Beyond offering co-developer and engineering services, it still has an apparent desire to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/virtuos-is-now-making-but-not-publishing-original-games">make</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (but not publish) original games of its own.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong’s Anti-‘Feminist Propaganda’ Streaming Restrictions Are Unusual, But Not Unprecedented]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/black-myth-wukong-feminist-propaganda-politics-twitch-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong%E2%80%99s-anti-%E2%80%98feminist-propaganda%E2%80%99-streaming-restrictions-are-unusual-but-not-unprecedented.960126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/black-myth-wukong-feminist-propaganda-politics-twitch-steam<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Chinese action-RPG <em>Black Myth: Wukong </em>is officially a hit, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/black-myth-wukong-breaks-steams-concurrent-single-player-record-within-hours-of-launch-184559634.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAM6-oR4EjeU4eldsTz-da3U4XHqeuTAXHL9o-5A4_mejqOrmOxNfBj2gE4YS_YLaZaQVS8hmSzHnzyf4BLT_29P_WboaMSq6XbXu1igYyAfz8RBXaSRqQTfHYMTqFbPMfb6jmxty3nz2Gn-cpIkYci5mKyKcLM1JfS5mgBVAkDzP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">breaking Steam’s concurrent single-player record</a> within hours of release. It’s also embroiled in a culture war that, unlike a great deal of others, is not <em>entirely </em>contrived. Following <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-black-myth-wukong-developers-history-of-sexism-is-complicating-its-journey-to-the-west" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reports of sexism</a> at developer Game Science last year, the studio sent pre-release code to content creators last week with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-marketing-team-offers-content-creators-a-steam-key-but-bans-feminist-propaganda-and-all-talk-of-covid" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a series of stipulations</a>, one of which barred “politics, violence, nudity, feminist propaganda, fetishization, and other content that instigates negative discourse,” as well as mentions of covid and “content related to China's game industry policies.” These are extreme restrictions. They are, however, not that far afield from what content creators sometimes encounter during dealings involving game code.</p><p>It’s important to situate <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> in the broader context of content creation not to minimize the overbearing directive issued by marketers at Game Science collaborator Hero Games, but to understand the forces that can inform creators’ thinking – even slightly – as well as the ways companies try to control the messaging around their games.&nbsp;</p><p>In <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>’s case, the <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/u/0/d/1aKlZvxWxbPOzldSUdc6CaHmoy80Fl7W_wQt-Ex-vl0k/mobilebasic?pli=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">list of do’s and don’ts</a> was only issued to content creators, not reviewers at websites and other more traditional publications (who received a different set of guidelines with restrictions largely centered around spoilers). It was also not tied to any sort of contract or sponsored content. As Aftermath understands the situation, Hero Games sent out code with what essentially amounted to a gentle – albeit forcefully worded – suggestion. Aside from denying opportunities in the future, there’s not much the company can do to actually enforce these rules.&nbsp;</p><p>That part immediately struck creators to whom Aftermath spoke as strange. Typically, you don’t encounter rules this specific until you’re in the fine print of a contract for a sponsored stream or video – aka, one in which a company is directly paying a content creator to play a game.&nbsp;</p><p>“The normal language of 'No politics, please don't talk about current events (covid), etc' have always been part of contracts,” longtime Twitch streamer <a href="https://x.com/CohhCarnage" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ben “Cohh Carnage” Cassell</a> told Aftermath. “That's totally normal and has been in there for years. Even the vulgar language stuff, although I've never seen it enforced. ... I do many sponsored streams, and I've never seen anything about ‘feminist’ anything in any of them. That is new. And definitely very strange."</p><p>"It's only in sponsored, actually-paid stuff when we're signing a contract and agreeing to certain things [that] I ever see 'Don't bring up politics. Don't bring up this. Don't bring up that,'" pirate-themed streamer <a href="https://x.com/0BurkeBlack0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Burke Black</a> told Aftermath.</p><p>"The vast majority [of creator emails about game keys] I’ve seen don't require behavioral restrictions," <a href="https://x.com/shannonplante" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shannon Plante</a>, director of business operations for popular Twitch streamer <a href="https://x.com/Sacriel" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sacriel</a>, told Aftermath. "Those are usually kept to paid activations, which makes sense [because] they’re paying you. … Typically restrictions would be normal stuff like refraining from abusive conduct, hate speech, [and] sometimes too much swearing depending on the game and brand.”</p><p>A creator who was granted anonymity so as not to lose out on future opportunities shared several such documents with Aftermath. One, for <em>Alan Wake 2</em>, included mandatory streaming language, but only around <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/business-guidance/resources/disclosures-101-social-media-influencers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FTC disclosures</a> (“Thank you to Epic Games for sponsoring this video” at the beginning of the stream and again every 30 minutes). Another, for <em>Shin Megami Tensei V: Vengeance</em>, included talking points to help advertise the game (“Talk about what makes <em>SMTV: V</em> so interesting to you – the ominous atmosphere, the metal music, demons, etc”) as well as a request that streamers include spoiler tags in their titles. </p><p>A third, for Meta-published VR game <em>Asgard’s Wrath 2</em> was a little stricter, with a list of do’s and don’ts that forbade third-party IP in creators’ content (logos, etc), alcohol consumption, and derogatory, sexual, or explicit comments. The streamer who received it told Aftermath that they nonetheless made “plenty” of sexual comments during the stream and were not penalized.&nbsp;</p><p>In general, while language can at times be restrictive, enforcement is rare.&nbsp;</p><p>"I’ve never experienced a situation where a brand hasn’t paid, but technically I guess if you violate those things it could result in them withholding," said Plante. "It would have to be proven, though, I’m guessing, [because] talent management firms would go after the brand for denial of pay otherwise."</p><p>"I’ve broken the ‘no swearing’ rule by accident a handful of times before and have never seen any enforcement, nor even any negative feedback,” noted Aftermath subscriber (and content creator and writer and actor) <a href="https://x.com/Charalanahzard" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Alanah Pearce</a> told Aftermath. “Generally if a brand wants to sponsor a creator, they know who that creator is and know their audience [and] can tell when they aren’t being authentic; if you talk about politics or you swear, they wouldn’t want you to stop doing that to the extent that it goes against your established brand."</p><p>But not all companies are created equal in this regard. In May, <a href="https://x.com/JeffHoogland" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jeff Hoogland</a>, a <em>Marvel Snap</em> streamer, was invited to join the creator program for upcoming <em>Overwatch</em>-alike <em>Marvel Rivals</em>, which, like<em> Black Myth: Wukong</em>, is being published by a Chinese company, NetEase. The program would not have paid Hoogland any money. Despite this, he was sent a “commitment letter,” which Aftermath has viewed. Among other things, it required a signature and included language like "I pledge not to disseminate any content associated with misinformation, hate speech, discrimination, politics, pornography, or other objectionable subjects" and "not to publish any illegal content, distorting game facts with malicious intent or insult to others." Hoogland objected to the “politics” restriction and asked a company representative if that language could be removed. The rep, Hoogland said, ended up ghosting him.</p><p>“Effectively policing what I post on social media in general just to be a part of a creator program is a huge overreach,” Hoogland said. “Code of conduct for no hate speech and hostile stuff is typical [for these sorts of creator programs]. Blanket no 'politics' as an incredibly vague catch-all is a first for me.”</p><p>Game Science and Hero Games have yet to publicly comment on <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>’s content creation restrictions. They’ve also <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/action/black-myth-wukong-sexism-controversy-interview-no-comment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">remained tight lipped about other, similar subjects</a>. Aftermath asked the PR firm representing the game on the press side of things, One PR, for more details, but did not receive a response. Given the outcry around <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>’s approach, however, other companies employing heavy-handed tactics might want to reconsider.</p><p>"Simply put, what that studio is requiring just for a key is absolutely insane," said Plante, "and they should get called out for it."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revenge of the Savage Planet revealed and it is coming in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/21/revenge-of-the-savage-planet-revealed-and-it-is-coming-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/revenge-of-the-savage-planet-revealed-and-it-is-coming-in-2025.960117/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/21/revenge-of-the-savage-planet-revealed-and-it-is-coming-in-2025/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>A sequel to Journey to the Savage Planet has been revealed by Raccoon Logic, and the new game is Revenge of the Savage Planet. Revenge of the Savage Planet is due to release in early 2025 for PC, PS5 and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<p><iframe title="Revenge of the Savage Planet | Official Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mVjBRZqajYY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><em>“We’re beyond excited to welcome budding explorers back to the Savage Planet universe. A lot has happened since we launched the original title – both in-game and life, with the whole studio being shuttered during a global pandemic. On the back of this, Raccoon Logic was born, and with it Revenge of the Savage Planet, which may or may not incorporate an element of the journey we all went through. The XBOX showcase today is the tip of the asteroid, and we can’t wait to show everyone the world we’ve created next year.”, </em>said Alex Hutchinson, Creative Director at Raccoon Logic.</p>
<p>Revenge of the Savage Planet will be playable solo and in co-op, including local split screen, and it will have four planets for players to explore. You’ll be tasked with cataloguing the plants and animals of each planet, and you can even capture the animals too. Not every venture will be easy and you will have to fight some dangers out on the planet surfaces. Exploration will net you rewards with all sorts of gear scattered around the place.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/01/27/journey-to-the-savage-planet-review/">Journey to the Savage Planet Review</a></h2>
<p>In our Journey To The Savage Planet review, Dom wrote,&nbsp;<em>“Few games generate enough excitement, intrigue, or fun to have you hoovering up all the collectibles in order to bag all the trophies and achievements, but Journey to the Savage Planet will have you searching every nook and cranny, leaping seemingly impossible gaps and scanning every last rock, simply because you’ll want to. A rollicking space adventure, Journey to the Savage Planet has the smarts to make you laugh out loud while taking shots at consumerism and big business.”</em></p>

<p>Journey to the Savage Planet was released in 2020 for PC, PS4, and Xbox. Then in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/01/24/journey-to-the-savage-planet-lands-on-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs-in-february/">February 2023</a>, a PS5 and Xbox Series X|S version was released, and included the DLC, 4K visuals, performance options, and improved photo mode.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Dice Tower's Mike DiLiso Starts Board Game Company Massive Asterisk, First Project Coming To Kickstarter]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dice-towers-mike-diliso-starts-board-game-company-massive-asterisk-first-project</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-dice-towers-mike-diliso-starts-board-game-company-massive-asterisk-first-project-coming-to-kickstarter.960114/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dice-towers-mike-diliso-starts-board-game-company-massive-asterisk-first-project<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new board game company is making its debut. The company is called Massive Asterisk, created by Mike DiLiso. DiLiso is a content creator for the tabletop-focused website The Dice Tower. The first game it will publish is coming to Kickstarter this Fall, and it is packed with 90s nostalgia.</p>

<p>According to Massive Asterisk's <a href="https://massiveasterisk.com/">official website</a>, they are a company dedicated to creating strong theme-driven games with a passion and commitment to quality.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/massive-asterisk-i-made-you-a-mixtape-card-artwork.jpg?itok=shlPIHcv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/massive-asterisk-i-made-you-a-mixtape-card-artwork.jpg?itok=yj6mpUD8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Massive Asterisk's debut board game is titled <em>I Made You A Mixtape</em>. It is a board game set in the 1990s where you try to make an awesome mixtape for the coolest kid in the neighborhood as they leave for college. Whoever makes the best tape gets the grand prize: a <em>Quantum Leap</em> poster signed by Scott Bakula.</p>
<p><em>I Made You A Mixtape</em> was created by both Mike DiLiso and Dan Hughes. It is an easy-to-learn, quick-to-teach drafting game utilizing an 'I cut, you choose' system.</p>
<p>Players slowly create a mixtape of songs on the cards. Players earn points based on how well the tracks flow, their genre consistency, and if both the A-side and B-side of the cassette are balanced in length.</p>
<p>It is designed for 1-4 players and a single game can be finished in 30 minutes. Overall, it is a novel take on a card game with a strong nostalgic appeal to an older Millennial audience.</p>
<p>Mike DiLiso is a content creator and video editor for The Dice Tower. The Dice Tower is a website dedicated to videos, reviews, and podcasts discussing interesting or acclaimed board games across multiple categories. DeLiso is also the co-host of the "Sporadically Board With Mike and Dan" podcast.</p>
<p>The Kickstarter campaign for <em>I Made You A Mixtape</em> will launch this November.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pick Up The Entire Mafia Series In This Offer You Can’t Refuse]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mafia-series-2-3-sale-hangar-13-new-game-1851628204</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pick-up-the-entire-mafia-series-in-this-offer-you-can%E2%80%99t-refuse.960108/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mafia-series-2-3-sale-hangar-13-new-game-1851628204<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>2K <em>finally </em>announced what Hangar 13 has been working on at Gamescom Opening Night Live, and unsurprisingly, it’s the prequel to the <em>Mafia </em>games that we <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-release-date-hangar-13-haden-blackman-lucasarts-1848883555&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-release-date-hangar-13-haden-blackman-lucasarts-1848883555">previously reported on back in 2022</a></span>. After <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;http://v&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://v/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">years of tumult</a></span>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-the-old-country-trailer-gamescom-hangar-13-2k-1851627259&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-the-old-country-trailer-gamescom-hangar-13-2k-1851627259"><em>Mafia: The Old Country</em></a></span><em> </em>has finally emerged and it’s set to take us to the origins of the mafia in 1900s Sicily when it releases next year. That gives you all just enough time to play through the existing <em>Mafia </em>trilogy, which just happens to be remarkably cheap right now. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196394" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="97" data-playlist="196394,196470,196299" data-current="196394"><div><p>The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21942.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><strong>On Steam, </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fmafia-trilogy%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fmafia-trilogy%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody"><strong>Humble Bundle</strong></a></span><strong> and </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/mafia-trilogy/9NKG0X1MGQTX&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/mafia-trilogy/9NKG0X1MGQTX" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Xbox</strong></a></span><strong>, you can currently cop the entirety of the <em>Mafia Trilogy</em>—a compilation that gathers the definitive editions of the first three titles— for $15. </strong>That includes a remake of the first game, a remaster of the second (with all of its DLC included), as well as <em>Mafia 3</em> and all of its DLC. I guess you could say that 2K Games is making you an offer you can’t refuse. You can also snag each one of the games individually on Steam.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mafia-definitive-edition-is-a-great-remake-of-a-clunky-1845182811&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mafia-definitive-edition-is-a-great-remake-of-a-clunky-1845182811"><em><strong>Mafia: Definitive Edition</strong></em></a></span>&nbsp;<strong>will run you $8 on Steam, </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fmafia-definitive-edition%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fmafia-definitive-edition%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Humble Bundle</strong></a></span><strong>  and Xbox, but it’s also available on Game Pass for both systems, as well as the PS Plus catalog. </strong>Notoriously a bit of a slow burn, I recall the original game being incredibly moody, and a more direct parallel to its cinematic influences than other games around it at the time. It wasn’t at all what I expected out of an open-world crime game, though my experience was pretty limited to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tag/grand-theft-auto&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tag/grand-theft-auto"><em>Grand Theft Auto</em></a></span><em> </em>back then, and I think these days I’d really find a lot to love about it and its atmosphere.<strong> Hell, if you want to stick to that classic feeling, the original version of </strong><em><strong>Mafia </strong></em><strong>is also on sale  right now for just about $5.</strong></p><p><em>Mafia 2 </em>came about a decade later in 2010, and though it got knocked for its linearity—even if in my opinion, it means it doesn’t suffer from open-world bloat— it’s still probably my favorite. I remember being wowed by its production values, a staple which carried over from the original game, and its attention to detail. While other open-world games were certainly upping their fidelity and the sizes of their worlds, <em>Mafia </em>was always a series more interested in the minute details, which always led to interesting wrinkles and systems that flew under the radar despite the franchise’s clear success and longevity.</p><p>In <em>Mafia 2</em>, one of those systems was the ability to interact with certain objects in one of two ways: either neutrally, or in a more violent manner. It was a subtle system that might not have meant much to too many people back in the day, but as far as roleplaying tools that help build immersive worlds and characters, this was absolutely wonderful.</p><p><em>Mafia 2 </em>was also just a tried-and-true mobster story, filled with the kind of deplorable characters and tragic twists one might expect from their favorite mob movie. <strong>Yeah, I’m a </strong><em><strong>Mafia 2 </strong></em><strong>apologist, and you can be too once you pick it up as part of the </strong><em><strong>Mafia Trilogy </strong></em><strong>or on Steam where it’s going for $7.49 right now.</strong></p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mafia-iii-the-kotaku-review-1787722761&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mafia-iii-the-kotaku-review-1787722761"><em><strong>Mafia 3</strong></em></a></span>&nbsp;<strong>is the most recent entry, releasing back in 2016, and it and its DLC are now compiled into a </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fmafia-iii-definitive-edition%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fmafia-iii-definitive-edition%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>definitive edition</strong></a></span><strong> that you can pick up for $7.49.&nbsp;</strong>I admittedly haven’t played this game, but it’s at the top of my to-do list due to its main character, Lincoln Clay. A Black veteran of the Vietnam War, he returns from overseas only to be plunged into a life of crime in the deep South, where he still feels the effects of racism and segregation as he rises through the ranks. Games that are frank in their tackling of subject matter such as institutional racism in America aren’t exactly a dime a dozen, and though <em>Mafia 3 </em>sounds like it has trouble clearing some technical hurdles, I’m more than happy to hear it out.</p><p>Altogether, the <em>Mafia </em>series is one of the more interesting open-world crime franchises, departing from the do-anything zaniness of its closest competitors with more somber, linear stories and some unique systems. Everywhere they could (and maybe <em>should</em>) have zigged, the developers stewarding the series have zagged. I think that makes the series bolder and more unique than a dozen other <em>GTA </em>clones that have come and gone. And after all of this, the <em>Mafia </em>series is still standing, and even has a fresh new game on the horizon, so these games clearly stand the test of time.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fruitbus for PC launches October 28]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/fruitbus-for-pc-launches-october-28</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fruitbus-for-pc-launches-october-28.960105/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/fruitbus-for-pc-launches-october-28<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Console versions due out at a later date.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > PC [21,017 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> version of culinary <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,691 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Fruitbus [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fruitbus">Fruitbus</a></em> will launch via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2484130/Fruitbus/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on October 28, developer <a title="Companies > Krillbite Studio [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/krillbite-studio">Krillbite Studio</a> announced. Console versions will follow at a later date. <span id="more-908705"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Krillbite Studio:</p><blockquote><p>An open world bursting with flavor and possibility is waiting for you! ​Follow in Grandma’s footsteps and take your fully customizable Fruitbus out on the road, explore the wilderness of the Gustum archipelago, forage for new ingredients and unlock new menu options to craft yummy meals for your customers.</p><p>But Grandma has left you more than her beloved Fruitbus; tasked with uniting friends and loved ones for one last feast, forge strong connections with local customers and right some of Grandma’s wrongs by creating dishes that stir emotions and evoke long-forgotten memories. ​Use the power of food to fuel the community, experiment with new recipes or master the art of local specialties to make meals that will make someone’s day—and allow Grandma’s legacy to thrive!</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PC Relese Date Trailer</span></h2><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="Fruitbus | Steam Release Date Trailer 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/su_dmobOeb0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wilmot’s Warehouse sequel Wilmot Works It Out announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/wilmots-warehouse-sequel-wilmot-works-it-out-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wilmot%E2%80%99s-warehouse-sequel-wilmot-works-it-out-announced-for-pc.960102/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/wilmots-warehouse-sequel-wilmot-works-it-out-announced-for-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Puzzle building game due out on October 23.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Finji [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/finji">Finji</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Hollow Ponds [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hollow-ponds">Hollow Ponds</a> and <a title="Companies > Richard Hogg [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/richard-hogg">Richard Hogg</a> have announced <em>Wilmot’s Warehouse</em> sequel <em><a title="Games > Wilmot Works It Out" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wilmot-works-it-out">Wilmot Works It Out</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,017 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> and Mac. It will launch via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2060590/Wilmot_Works_It_Out/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on October 23. <span id="more-908695"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2060590/Wilmot_Works_It_Out/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Wilmot Works It Out</em> is a puzzle building game about completing beautiful images and hanging them in your house.</p><p>You play as Wilmot, who likes to unwind from sorting out a warehouse by sorting out puzzle pieces. Yesterday’s puzzle was a snake wearing a hat, but today’s looks like it might be an octopus?… or maybe that’s a hamburger?</p><p>Once complete, you decide where to hang it. Then the mail person delivers a brand new puzzle! Oh dear, this one has a few extra pieces – I hope there wasn’t a mix-up at the puzzle delivery service!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Complete a series of puzzles to unlock new customisation options for your house, including colours, wallpapers, bookcases, and cats. This house is going to feel like a home in no time at all!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Assemble more than 60 original puzzles by Richard Hogg (<em><a title="Games > Hohokum [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hohokum">Hohokum</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Flock [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/flock">Flock</a></em>).</li><li>Unlock new rooms and customisation items to decorate with!</li><li>A gentle and slightly jazzy electronic soundtrack to listen to as you ponder and solve, brought to you by composer and sound artist Eli Rainsberry (<em>Wilmot’s Warehouse</em>, <em>Flock</em>).</li><li>Sequel to beloved organization game <em>Wilmot’s Warehouse</em>.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. Visit the official website <a href="https://wilmotworksitout.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Wilmot Works It Out | Wishlist today on Steam!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YARyZ2peq3U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8BitDo Launches Official Xbox And PC Accessibility Controller With Unique Design And Friendly Price]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/8bitdo-lite-se-official-xbox-accessibility-controller/1100-6526020/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/8bitdo-launches-official-xbox-and-pc-accessibility-controller-with-unique-design-and-friendly-price.960099/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/8bitdo-lite-se-official-xbox-accessibility-controller/1100-6526020/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526020">

            
            
    


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Gamescom has already brought us plenty of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-5715/" data-ref-id="2900-5715">big game reveals</a>, but Microsoft also spent time highlighting its accessibility initiatives, which include four new products. One of the best third-party controller manufacturers, 8BitDo, partnered with Microsoft to create a brand-new wireless Xbox and PC controller. Available now at Amazon, the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7P5M1Q3?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo Lite SE</a></strong> features 12 low-resistance face buttons and oversized, detachable Dual Super Buttons--the same ones found with <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0CYSQWYZP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo's stellar retro keyboards</a>. easy to press in the heat of battle. Like all 8BitDo controllers, the price of the Lite SE is on the budget side at just $60.</p><div title="6526020 - 8BitDo Lite SE Wireless Controller" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2607" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6526020 - 8BitDo Lite SE Wireless Controller" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7P5M1Q3?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0D7P5M1Q3?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7P5M1Q3?tag=gamespot-promos-20">8BitDo Lite SE 2.4G Wireless Controller</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7P5M1Q3?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0D7P5M1Q3?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D7P5M1Q3?tag=gamespot-promos-20">$60</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>Officially licensed by Xbox and compatible with Xbox Series X, Xbox One, and PC, the 8BitDo Lite SE is built from the ground up for accessibility.</p><p>Its buttons have lower resistance than traditional gamepads and the sticks are "highly sensitive," meaning users don't have to apply as much pressure for inputs to register.</p><p>The Lite SE moves the bumpers and triggers next to the ABXY face buttons and D-pad (with individual buttons).</p><p>As mentioned, the Dual Super Buttons are the same as the ones bundled with <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0CYSQWYZP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo's mechanical keyboards</a>, and their large size and programmable nature should make them great for a wide range of inputs. As a nice bonus, the Super Buttons are compatible with the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851399501288220571%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2F8bitdo-lite-se-official-xbox-accessibility-controller%2F1100-6526020%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Adaptive Controller</a>, giving owners of Microsoft's first-party accessibility controller another module option.</p><p>With support for 8BitDo's Ultimate Software X software, users can adjust stick sensitivity and remap inputs. The Lite SE can save up to three custom profiles that can be cycled through on the fly. It connects wirelessly to Xbox and PC vis the included 2.4GHz dongle. Wired connection is supported with the included USB-C charging cable.</p></div>                      </div><p>Microsoft also showed off the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/accessories/controllers/xbox-adaptive-joystick" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Adaptive Joystick</a>, which is built as a singular joystick that works alongside the Xbox Adaptive Controller. It's expected to release in early 2025 for $30. Then there's the <a href="https://www.byowave.com/product/proteus-controller" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Proteus Controller</a>, which is a premium, $299 gadget that's highly modular and supports over 100 million custom configurations.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4354632-8bitdolitese.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4354632" data-ratio="0.667" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4354632-8bitdolitese.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4354632"></a><figcaption>8BitDo Lite SE Accessibility Controller for Xbox and PC</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4354632-8bitdolitese.jpg"></figure><p>8BitDo is no stranger to officially licensed Xbox products, as the company recently released the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ultimate-Controller-Joysticks-Triggers-Gaming-Console/dp/B0D1VHT3S6?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Ultimate 3-Mode Controller for Xbox</a>. It includes its own charging dock, Hall Effect joysticks and triggers, and works as wired controller on Xbox and wirelessly on PC and mobile. If you're a Prime member, you can now snag it for $55 (was $70).</p><p>If you're not interested in picking up a new gamepad but want to bring more accessibility features to your game room, take a look at the new 3D printable adaptive thumbstick toppers announced by Xbox. These can be found at the <a href="https://xboxdesignlab.xbox.com/accessories/adaptive-thumbstick-toppers-for-xbox-controllers" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Design Lab</a> and work with the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Microsoft-Xbox-WL-Controller-Gaming-Console/dp/B08K4HLCPR?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Wireless Controller</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMicrosoft-Xbox-Elite-Series-2-Wireless-Controller-Black%2F784834522%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2F8bitdo-lite-se-official-xbox-accessibility-controller%2F1100-6526020%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Elite Series 2</a>, and Adaptive Joystick.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wkXO8MeX7vA" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wkXO8MeX7vA" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/buy-two-get-one-free-nintendo-switch-games-and-preorders-my-best-buy-members/1100-6525928/">B2G1 Free All Nintendo Switch Games - Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom, Mario &amp; Luigi, And More Preorders</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-preorder-guide/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition Preorders Live Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-anthology-preorders-quakecon-2024/1100-6525656/">Doom Anthology Preorders Are Live - Comes With 6 Games, Steelbook Case, And Replica BFG</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retrorealms-halloween-ash-vs-evil-dead-retro-game-preorder-guide/1100-6525752/">Halloween And Ash Vs. Evil Dead Retro Games Revealed - Collector's Bundle Preorders Live</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/amiibo-nintendo-switch-restocks-reprints-2024/2900-5671/">Rare Nintendo Amiibo Figures Restocked - Ness, Mr. Game &amp; Watch, ROB, Charizard, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-i-vi-pixel-remaster-collection-north-america-release/1100-6525641/">Final Fantasy Pixel Remaster Collection Anniversary Edition Preorders Live At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retro-pokemon-brick-sets-in-stock-at-target-pixel-art-mew-pikachu-charmander-and-more/1100-6525719/">Retro Pokemon Brick Sets In Stock At Target - Pixel Art Mew, Pikachu, Charmander, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-deals-games-controllers-nintendo-consoles/1100-6525715/">Best Nintendo Switch Game Deals This Week - Zelda And Mario Games For Big Discounts</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          

                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525905&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-myth-wukong-gets-special-edition-8bitdo-wireless-controller-available-now-for-35\/1100-6525905\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525989&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/game-pass-standard-launches-today-wont-get-microsofts-new-releases-for-a-while\/1100-6525989\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525946&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-reportedly-coming-to-playstation-5\/1100-6525946\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526011&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/phil-spencer-discusses-bringing-indiana-jones-to-ps5-we-run-a-business\/1100-6526011\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525971&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-preorder-guide-pc-ps5-xbox-series-x-nintendo-switch\/1100-6525971\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525869&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/preorder-fortnite-xbox-wireless-controller-special-edition\/1100-6525869\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525953&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvel-rivals-release-date-announced-at-gamescom-with-new-trailer\/1100-6525953\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526019&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/forza-horizon-5-adding-hide-and-seek-mode\/1100-6526019\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526017&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/excited-for-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-pass-the-time-with-these-discounted-lego-sets\/1100-6526017\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525735&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-make-arrows-in-minecraft\/1100-6525735\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525733&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-make-a-bow-in-minecraft\/1100-6525733\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525815&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/oscar-winner-michelle-yeoh-not-in-avatar-3-will-debut-in-4\/1100-6525815\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525817&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/theres-now-an-800-meta-quest-3-gaming-chair-thatll-rumble-your-bum\/1100-6525817\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525818&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-lord-of-the-rings-games-being-prototyped-right-now\/1100-6525818\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525819&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/halle-berry-was-never-asked-to-cameo-as-storm-in-deadpool-wolverine\/1100-6525819\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525813&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/silent-hill-goes-cyberpunk-in-this-horror-game-coming-next-month\/1100-6525813\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6476419&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/free-games-epic-games-store\/1100-6476419\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525479&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/who-is-maya-sundaresh-in-destiny-2\/1100-6525479\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525808&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/scrubs-creator-says-reunion-is-possible-but-not-a-priority\/1100-6525808\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525824&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-wont-require-2k-launcher-on-pc\/1100-6525824\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Survey: Spotty preservation efforts risk 'significant loss' for Australian game industry]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/survey-australian-game-industry-significant-loss-preservation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/survey-spotty-preservation-efforts-risk-significant-loss-for-australian-game-industry.960093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/survey-australian-game-industry-significant-loss-preservation<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Australia's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nfsa.gov.au/about/corporate-information/media-release/international-video-games-survey-points-threat-collection-and-preservation">National Film &amp; Sound Archive</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> recently conducted a survey on international game preservation. The results show how dire the efforts to preserve games are worldwide and how they will hit local industry the hardest.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the NFSA's survey (conducted in 2023), respondents cited key roadblocks such as legal and technical access, a lack of dedicated staffing, and funds. Its summary further notes most groups treat preservation as part of a larger operation rather than a key focus.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Like last year's survey from the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/study-finds-nearly-every-pre-2010-video-game-is-unavailable">Video Game History Foundation</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the NFSA said the industry is facing a "significant loss of heritage," particularly as it pertains to the Australian game industry.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nfsa.gov.au/collection/curated/international-video-games-preservation">website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> reveals over 96 percent of classic Australian games are "critically endangered," substantially worse than the US's 87 percent of pre-2010 games. And while the US has support from the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-library-of-congress-just-made-game-preservation-a-little-bit-easier">Library of Congress,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> preservation is not a priority for every country.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Even more recent games are said to be at risk, as organizations have them saved as digital titles rather than physical releases, of which they're "almost twice as likely to have."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One respondent candidly said the industry needs to prioritize preservation over playability and "make choices about how 'original' to keep artifacts."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Collecting and preserving [games] is a still-developing&nbsp;field growing beyond today’s institutions," said NFSA CEO Patrick McIntyre. Citing the loss of pre-1929 films, he said the survey proves games need an international preservation effort to avoid a similar outcome."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Those surveyed noted collaboration networks like the Software Preservation Network and the Digital Preservation Coalition. But more structured interational partnerships are needed, as are "standardized cataloging systems."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The NFSA's full findings on the country's game preservation issues can be read </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nfsa.gov.au/collection/curated/international-video-games-preservation">here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Overwatch 2 Patch Makes It Easier To Kill Some Of Its Peskiest Heroes]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/new-overwatch-2-patch-makes-it-easier-to-kill-some-of-i-1851628143</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-overwatch-2-patch-makes-it-easier-to-kill-some-of-its-peskiest-heroes.960048/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/new-overwatch-2-patch-makes-it-easier-to-kill-some-of-i-1851628143<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Overwatch 2</em> has begun its 12th season and alongside the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-kiriko-mercy-venture-reaper-season-12-skins-1851626893&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-kiriko-mercy-venture-reaper-season-12-skins-1851626893">Egyptian-themed battle pass</a></span> and new support hero <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-juno-support-trial-period-space-ranger-1851599766&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-juno-support-trial-period-space-ranger-1851599766">Juno</a></span>, Blizzard has released a balance patch. The tweaks have addressed some longstanding issues with heroes like Lifeweaver, while also giving a few tweaks to tanks after <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-season-11-midseason-worst-patch-mauga-tanks-1851584869&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-season-11-midseason-worst-patch-mauga-tanks-1851584869">supercharging them</a></span> last season to mixed reception. There’s also a new mode added to the rotation, so the patch has a lot to unpack.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195460" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="195460,196880,192616" data-current="195460"><div><p>Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20938.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Juno is obviously the star of the season, and she’s received a few tweaks since her test period back in July. Nearly every ability in the Martian medic’s kit has been balanced in some way. Her primary fire has been reduced to 28 shots per second from its original 34, her lock-on torpedoes that damage enemies and heal teammates have become more powerful, and her speed-boosting Hyper Ring ability has an increased deploy range alongside a shorter cooldown. So while her healing and damage output has been lowered, her abilities have been made more efficient. Those are the kinds of minimal changes you’d expect as Blizzard is still figuring out a new hero, so we’ll see if farther-reaching changes are on the horizon. The team also included several quality-of-life adjustments to how Juno’s abilities are communicated, which you can read about in the patch notes below.</p><figure id="" data-id="0eb76ad65e2cdad6ca8914687bb8c464" data-recommend-id="image://0eb76ad65e2cdad6ca8914687bb8c464" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Juno stands in Midtown." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Juno stands in Midtown." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0eb76ad65e2cdad6ca8914687bb8c464" data-recommend-id="image://0eb76ad65e2cdad6ca8914687bb8c464" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Juno stands in Midtown." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Lifeweaver, who Blizzard has had trouble balancing since he launched last year, is getting some pretty notable quality-of-life improvements that will make his kit less punishing to those using the support hero. His primary Healing Blossom that heals teammates now passively charges, allowing you to fire a fully-charged flower across the battlefield instantly. This passive charge is slower than the manual one you can do by holding down the RT/R2/Left click, but it stays charged when you swap between Healing Blossom and his offensive secondary fire. This way you’re not punished for swapping between modes of fire, allowing you to switch to an offensive attack and quickly return to healing if need be. The Petal Platform, which elevates any hero (friend or foe) who stands on it, also got a much-needed update. Now, if someone steps off the platform, rather than remaining in the air and becoming functionally useless, it will return to the ground to lift a player to high ground once more. There have been plenty of times I’ve thrown a platform down as Lifeweaver just for someone to fall off of it almost immediately, so this is a welcome change.<br></p><figure id="" data-id="2f43baafa42ffe13c2815d11179d2837" data-recommend-id="image://2f43baafa42ffe13c2815d11179d2837" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Lifeweaver tosses a Healing Blossom." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Lifeweaver tosses a Healing Blossom." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2f43baafa42ffe13c2815d11179d2837" data-recommend-id="image://2f43baafa42ffe13c2815d11179d2837" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Lifeweaver tosses a Healing Blossom." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>One balance change that affects multiple heroes is a health nerf that cuts a lot of squishy characters’ health down to 225. <em>Overwatch 2</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-season-9-balance-patch-passive-healing-hp-1851235801&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-season-9-balance-patch-passive-healing-hp-1851235801">increased most characters’ health</a></span> in February after <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-season-9-self-healing-passive-tank-damage-1851163814&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-season-9-self-healing-passive-tank-damage-1851163814">adding passive health regeneration</a></span> in season 9. Blizzard is tweaking health pools for mobile heroes that can get away from a scrap, so the hope here is that this will make it easier to take out the heroes who often harass a backline and get away just before a killing shot. Heroes affected by this nerf include flight-based characters Echo, Juno, and Mercy (Pharah is notably absent), as well as those who can escape a fight easily like Lucio, Sombra, Kiriko, and Moira. Hanzo, meanwhile, has also had his health nerfed, which Blizzard says is to balance the fact that he can one-shot a lot of these heroes now that they have 225 HP.<br></p><p>Beyond hero changes, Season 12 also adds the new mode Clash, which is a King of the Hill-style mode that feels like a reason for Blizzard to bring back old maps without revisiting the maligned two-point capture mode that was phased out in <em>Overwatch 2</em>. Both the Hanaoka and Throne of Anubis maps are based on fan-favorite maps from the original <em>Overwatch</em> Hanamura and Temple of Anubis, respectively. We’ll see how the community reacts to the mode in the coming weeks.</p><p>The full patch notes are as follows:</p><h4 id="h3748"><a id=""></a><strong><em>GENERAL UPDATES</em></strong></h4><p><strong><em>Avoid As Teammate</em></strong></p><p><em>The Avoid List has been updated with the following new features:</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Players now have 15 avoid slots divided into 3 Pinned slots and 12 Recent slots.</em></li><li><em>Pinned Avoid slots guarantee that these players will never be in your matches and unlike our old Avoid slots, they never time out.</em></li><li><em>The new Recent Avoid slots do time out after 7 days like the old Avoid slots, and they only prioritize constructing teams without these players on them.</em></li><li><em>The player with the lowest time remaining in the Recent list is removed from the list if a new player is avoided when the list is full.</em></li><li><em>Time Remaining for an avoided player in the Recent list can be refreshed by using the Reset Avoid Expiration feature.</em></li><li><em>The Avoid List is now its own tab in the Social menu (which still only appears when at least 1 player is avoided).</em></li><li><em>Any players that were avoided when Season 11 ended will be removed from the avoided list due to the aforementioned updates to the system.</em></li></ul><p><em>Developer Comments: Avoiding other players has been a great way to curate your experience since the system was added, but with these changes we wanted to explore giving players best ways to manage their avoid slots.</em></p><p><strong><em>Spawn System Changes</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Group Respawn is replaced by Wave Respawn for all non-Competitive modes.</em></li><li><em>Wave Respawn is added to Competitive Play.</em></li><li><em>Default respawn time increased from 10 to 12 seconds.</em></li><li><em>Overtime respawn time increased from 13 to 14 seconds.</em></li><li><em>Wave Respawn is disabled in Overtime.</em></li><li><em>Overtime respawn time is not increased in Flashpoint.</em></li><li><em>Wave Respawn is disabled when the Payload is near the end of the track in Escort and Hybrid game modes (the same time the existing Anti-Stall system activates).</em></li><li><em>When the first hero on a team dies, they start a new Wave for their team.</em></li><li><em>Any hero that dies within 6 seconds of a Wave starting automatically joins that Wave.</em></li><li><em>A hero joining a Wave will respawn at the exact same time as the hero that started the Wave. This means that the respawn time of heroes joining the wave can be as long as 12 seconds if they died at the same time as the first hero or as short as 6 seconds if they catch the end of the Wave.</em></li><li><em>If a hero starts a Wave and no other hero joins the Wave they will respawn 2 seconds faster. This hero will respawn in 10 seconds (the default respawn time before Season 12).</em></li></ul><p><em>Developer Comments: These changes are designed to reduce the number of one-sided matches. For an in-depth analysis of our thought process behind the changes to respawning, read the latest Director’s Take on PlayOverwatch.com.</em></p><p><strong><em>Shop Updates</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>You can now try out all skins in the practice range from the Hero Gallery or the Premium Shop.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3749"><a id=""></a><strong><em>COMPETITIVE PLAY UPDATES</em></strong></h4><p><strong><em>Mid-Year Rank Reset</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Competitive skill ranks for all players have been reset for Season 12.</em></li><li><em>Players will need to complete ten placement matches for each role to be ranked and start climbing on the leaderboard.</em></li></ul><p><em>Developer Comments: Our plan is to reset ranks every 6 months alongside larger updates that shake up the metagame including significant hero balance changes, new heroes like Juno, new game modes like Clash, and changes to core systems like the respawning changes mentioned above.</em></p><p><strong><em>Predicted Rank</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>The Predicted Rank that was displayed to players in Placements at the end of each match is now displayed in all locations that rank is displayed for individual players.</em></li><li><em>Predicted Rank is only displayed to players viewing their own Rank (other players can’t see this information).</em></li><li><em>Predicted Rank is now used to determine whether a group is Wide or Narrow, meaning that Placements are no longer automatically considered Wide.</em></li><li><em>This will allow players to get much faster queues in many scenarios after their Rank has been reset.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3750"><a id=""></a><strong><em>HERO UPDATES</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comments: Our recent 2.11.1 patch (which adjusted all the Tank heroes), saw a significant gain in interest for the role and had a positive lasting effect in queue times for Damage and Support as well. There are a few additional tuning changes in this update for Tanks but this patch is largely focused on adjusting many of the more mobile heroes in the Damage and Support roles.</em></p><p><em>Mobility is very powerful and we would like for there to be more of a tradeoff for the flexibility that it brings, especially as we add speed boosting abilities by welcoming Juno to the game. We’re moving a handful of heroes to a 225 HP maximum and in some cases increasing potency elsewhere in their kit.</em></p><h4 id="h3751"><a id=""></a><strong><em>TANK</em></strong></h4><h4 id="h3752"><a id=""></a><strong><em>D.VA</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: The increase in Defense Matrix availability didn’t help D.Va’s overall performance that much compared to the amount of frustration it is causing players on the opposing team, so we’re reverting it to the previous duration.</em></p><p><strong><em>Defense Matrix</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Maximum duration reduced from 3.5 to 3 seconds.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3753"><a id=""></a><strong><em>ORISA</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: Orisa is still underperforming so we’re increasing the impact damage of Energy Javelin to better reward accuracy with the ability.</em></p><p><strong><em>Energy Javelin</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Impact damage increased from 60 to 80.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3754"><a id=""></a><strong><em>ZARYA</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: Zarya’s secondary fire didn’t benefit much from the projectile size changes in Season 9 since it’s mostly aimed at the ground. We’re increasing its damage to keep it feeling effective relative to her primary fire beam.</em></p><p><strong><em>Particle Cannon</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Secondary fire minimum damage increased from 47 to 55.</em></li><li><em>Secondary fire maximum damage increased from 95 to 110.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3755"><a id=""></a><strong><em>DAMAGE</em></strong></h4><h4 id="h3756"><a id=""></a><strong><em>ECHO</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: No additional adjustments to support the reduced health pool as, like Pharah, Echo was one of the top performing Damage heroes recently.</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Base health reduced from 250 to 225.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3757"><a id=""></a><strong><em>HANZO</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: Hanzo doesn’t quite fit the category of being as highly mobile as the other heroes we’re moving to 225 HP, but like Widowmaker, has the potential long-range lethality merits, as he is now able to one-shot the 225 HP heroes. It’s also nice for the Hanzo mirror match to be more decisive as well.</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Base health reduced from 250 to 225.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3758"><a id=""></a><strong><em>JUNKRAT</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: This is mostly a reversion back to how Junkrat’s grenades used to ricochet in early Overwatch, which enables more control over the angle of the bounce and helps the weapon better control spaces with some tricky shots, but the projectile size is now reduced after a couple of bounces so there will be fewer random feeling direct impacts near the end of the projectiles lifetime.</em></p><p><strong><em>Frag Launcher</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Projectile size is now reduced by half after the second ricochet.</em></li><li><em>Projectiles preserve slightly more velocity on ricochet.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3759"><a id=""></a><strong><em>SOJOURN</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: After reducing the maximum damage of the Railgun’s secondary fire, we’re continuing to look at the effectiveness of Sojourn’s primary fire. These changes are to make it more accurate and better reward accuracy by increasing the energy gained from headshots.</em></p><p><strong><em>Railgun</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Primary fire weapon spread reduced from 2 to 1.6 degrees.</em></li><li><em>Critical hits now grant 10 energy.</em></li><li><em>Energy degeneration rate reduced from 33 to 15 per second after 7 seconds.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3760"><a id=""></a><strong><em>SOMBRA</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: The increased movement speed while in stealth will better enable Sombra to get into advantageous positions or be slightly more evasive with the new lower health.</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Base health reduced from 250 to 225.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Virus</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Impact damage increased from 25 to 35.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Stealth</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Bonus movement speed increased from 45 to 60%.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3761"><a id=""></a><strong><em>TORBJÖRN</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: This shift in armor health for Torbjorn is to increase survivability against the heroes which are most affected by armor’s damage reduction, such as Tracer.</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Base health reduced from 250 to 225.</em></li><li><em>Base armor increased from 50 to 75.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3762"><a id=""></a><strong><em>SUPPORT</em></strong></h4><h4 id="h3763"><a id=""></a><strong><em>ILLARI</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: Illari can deal a lot of damage over the course of a game but may have too much ammo, given that her projectiles are easier to land hits due to their increased projectile size. We’re also removing the extra environment collision size on her Captive Sun projectile so that it doesn’t accidentally detonate early when firing at nearby walls and such. There is a similar fix to prevent her secondary fire beam from impacting a wall instead of allies near it.</em></p><p><strong><em>Solar Rifle</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Maximum ammo reduced from 16 to 14.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Captive Sun</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Projectile environment collision size reduced from 0.15 to 0 meters.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3764"><a id=""></a><strong><em>JUNO</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: Community feedback on Juno’s trial was split between over and underpowered. On the stat side, she performed strongly in most every categories but particularly overperformed in healing output over the course of a game. These changes are improving her utility while pulling back lightly on healing throughput, since we’d still like her to launch in a strong state as players grow accustomed to her playstyle. There were also quite a few quality-of-life improvements that are listed elsewhere in the patch notes.</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Juno has been added to the lineup.</em></li><li><em>Juno is now eligible for Competitive Play.</em></li><li><em>Base health reduced from 250 to 225.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Mediblaster</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Burst projectile volley rate of fire reduced from 34 to 28 shots per second.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Pulsar Torpedoes</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Damage and Healing impact increased from 75 to 85.</em></li><li><em>Heal-over-time reduced from 60 to 50 health.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Hyper Ring</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Deploy range increased by 3.5 meters.</em></li><li><em>Cooldown reduced from 16 to 14 seconds.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Orbital Ray</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Beam travel speed increased from 1.9 to 2.25 meters per second.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3765"><a id=""></a><strong><em>KIRIKO</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: Despite the perception of how powerful Kiriko feels to play against, she is a hero that consistently underperforms when it comes to winning games. However, she is a highly evasive hero that makes a lot of sense to be in the 225 health bracket. To help counterbalance the loss of health, we’re smoothing out her damage dealing consistency by increasing the Kunai weapon’s base damage and removing the enhanced critical multiplier.</em></p><p><em>Base health reduced from 250 to 225.</em></p><p><strong><em>Kunai</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Critical multiplier reduced from 2.5 to 2x.</em></li><li><em>Damage increased from 45 to 60.</em></li><li><em>Recovery time increased from 0.5 to 0.55 seconds.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3766"><a id=""></a><strong><em>LIFEWEAVER</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: The Petal Platform was too easy to waste if a player accidentally ran over it without intending to make use of it. Now it resets back to the ground if no one is standing on it. We’re also reducing its health so that it’s more reasonable counterplay to destroy the platform. Healing Blossom will now passively charge at a slower rate to enable players to swap between weapons without the fear of falling too far behind when swapping back to healing.</em></p><p><strong><em>Healing Blossom</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Healing progress can now charge passively at a reduced rate.</em></li><li><em>No longer reduces movement speed when holding a full charge.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Petal Platform</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Duration only counts down while the platform is raised.</em></li><li><em>Platform now resets if no one is standing on it for 2 seconds.</em></li><li><em>Duration increased from 10 to 12 seconds.</em></li><li><em>Health reduced from 400 to 300.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Rejuvenating Dash</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Healing reduced from 60 to 45.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3767"><a id=""></a><strong><em>MERCY</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: Mercy’s Guardian Angel movement enables her to be highly evasive and difficult to engage with for many heroes, but is also one of the most fun parts of her ability kit so we’d like to keep that strength, so we’re moving her to 225 HP and increasing the output of her Caduceus Staff beams.</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Base health reduced from 250 to 225.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Caduceus Staff</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Primary fire healing increased from 55 to 60 health per second.</em></li><li><em>Secondary fire damage boost increased from 25% to 30%.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3768"><a id=""></a><strong><em>MOIRA</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: Moira can be difficult to take down between the low cooldown on her Fade ability and self-healing with the Biotic Orb, so now she has 225 HP and slightly higher damage output to keep an edge to her offensive potential.</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Base health reduced from 250 to 225.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Biotic Grasp</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Secondary fire damage increased from 60 to 65 damage per second.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3769"><a id=""></a><strong><em>LÚCIO</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comment: Lucio is one of the most mobile heroes and makes his allies faster as well, so we’re moving him into the 225 HP hero category. His playstyle tends to get into closer ranges more often than other heroes in this category, so we’re turning up his Primary fire damage output to increase his effectiveness at range before diving in.</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Base health reduced from 250 to 225.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Sonic Amplifier</em></strong></p><p><em>Primary fire damage increased from 18 to 22.</em></p><h4 id="h3770"><a id=""></a><strong><em>HERO QUALITY OF LIFE UPDATES</em></strong></h4><p><em>Developer Comments: Alongside balance changes that should make Juno a strong and viable choice in the Support Role, we also heard community feedback to apply several small changes to make the experience of playing with or against Juno a lot more enjoyable. Thank you for your detailed feedback during Juno’s Hero Trial.</em></p><h4 id="h3771"><a id=""></a><strong><em>SUPPORT</em></strong></h4><h4 id="h3772"><a id=""></a><strong><em>JUNO</em></strong></h4><p><strong><em>Mediblaster</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>The weapon model visuals and firing sounds were updated to indicate when the weapon is at low ammo.</em></li><li><em>The heal sounds that play locally to the Juno player were updated to be more noticeable when healing allies closer to full health.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Pulsar Torpedoes</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>The cooldown when the ability is canceled after no successful lock-ons has been reduced from 5 seconds to 2 seconds.</em></li><li><em>Line of Sight checks were improved to better find targets with hitboxes in view.</em></li><li><em>Added range forgiveness of an extra 5 meters on current targets that might move beyond the max 40 meters range.</em></li><li><em>The local cancel sound was increased in volume to be more noticeable for the Juno player.</em></li><li><em>The ally and enemy impact sounds were updated to be more noticeable for the Juno player.</em></li><li><em>Healing torpedoes have new impact visuals when hitting enemy barriers and when clipping near walls.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Glide Boost</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Now adjusts Juno better when she hits level architecture such as doorways.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Hyper Ring</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Juno players will now hear the initial Hyper Ring apply sound when entering their own ring for the first time.</em></li><li><em>The sound when re-entering the Hyper Ring was updated to be more noticeable.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Orbital Ray</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>The Ultimate enemy voice line was updated in tone to better contrast the ally version.</em></li><li><em>The enemy version of the ray’s start sound was updated to be more noticeable.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3773"><a id=""></a><strong><em>MAP UPDATES</em></strong></h4><p><em>Flashpoint</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Passing through the spawn door barrier of your own spawn will apply a temporary speed boost to get to the capture point faster.</em></li><li><em>The speed boost is removed when taking or dealing damage.</em></li><li><em>The speed boost is applied by both the default and forward spawns.</em></li><li><em>The speed boost counts toward the existing movement speed bonus cap of 75%.</em></li></ul><p><em>Push</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>The Push bot collision has been updated so players cannot contest from certain high ground positions.</em></li></ul><p><em>General map &amp; Mode updates</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Updates to our map recency system to increase the frequency of new maps and modes at the start of each season.</em></li><li><em>Capture point outlines can now be seen through walls on Clash and Flashpoint when the capture point is unlocked.</em></li><li><em>Lighting scenarios are now randomized in Quick Play and Competitive Game Mode.</em></li></ul><h4 id="h3774"><a id=""></a><strong><em>BUG FIXES</em></strong></h4><p><strong><em>General</em></strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Fixed a bug where the Gotcha achievement was not awarding properly.</em></li><li><em>Fixed a bug where weapon skins were not showing in the weapon variant menu.</em></li><li><em>Fixed a bug where first-time users could not skirmish which waiting for a game.</em></li></ul><p><strong><em>Heroes</em></strong></p><p><em>Ashe</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Fixed a bug where some of the effects would not trigger with the Ashe mythic skin equipped on Steam.</em></li></ul><p><em>Illari</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Fixed a bug with Illari’s Solar Rifle secondary fire healing beam impacting the environment instead of players when aiming near edges of collision.</em></li></ul><p><em>Juno</em></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Cleaned up some of the effects of Juno’s Pulsars torpedoes when they landed as D.Va was re-entering her mech.</em></li></ul></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7 Features Another Game Of Thrones Veteran As In-Game Narrator]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-features-another-game-of-thrones-veteran-as-in-game-narrator/1100-6526028/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-7-features-another-game-of-thrones-veteran-as-in-game-narrator.960045/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-features-another-game-of-thrones-veteran-as-in-game-narrator/1100-6526028/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526028">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Civilization VII's in-game narrator has been revealed, and it's none other than Game of Thrones and Star Wars actor Gwendoline Christie. Christie is just the latest Game of Thrones alum to be the narrator for a Civilization game, following <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-of-thrones-actor-sean-bean-narrates-civilizat/1100-6442342/" data-ref-id="1100-6442342">Sean Bean in Civilization VI.</a></p><p>"Now it's your turn to reimagine civilization, and build something you believe in," Christie says in the trailer announcing her involvement. Another famous person who has lent their voice to the Civilization series is Star Trek's Leonard Nimoy (Civilization IV)</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qw6H7r8S_Wk" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Qw6H7r8S_Wk" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Christie is perhaps best known for playing Brienne of Tarth in Game of Thrones and Captain Phasma in the Star Wars series. She joins the cast for Apple's Severance Season 2, which is coming in 2025.</p><p>Civilization VII launches in February 2025 for PC, Xbox, PlayStation, and Switch. The game features a new Ages system that splits the flow into three distinct eras, with their own playable civilizations, resources, and gameplay systems. Unlocking milestones within each Age will let you carry advantages into the next era. As you progress into new Ages, you'll select new civilizations with their own perks, as determined by your accomplishments in the previous Age. As always, you'll choose a leader, but for the first time in series history, you can choose your leader separately from your civilization.</p><p dir="ltr">Multiplayer will take advantage of the new Ages system by allowing you to choose between multi-Age campaigns or taking on opponents in a single Age. Plus it will support cross-play between PC and consoles.</p><p>Civilization VII has multiple editions to choose from, and if you're curious, you can check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-preorder-guide-pc-ps5-xbox-series-x-nintendo-switch/1100-6525971/" data-ref-id="1100-6525971">Civilization VII preorder guide.</a> You can also check out GameSpot's preview below:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-civilization-7-rethinks-the-series-structure/1100-6525957/" data-ref-id="1100-6525957">How Civilization 7 Rethinks The Series' Structure</a></li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds Finally Launched, Bringing In Housing Mechanism, New Raids & Much More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-finally-launched-bringing-in-housing-mechanism-new-raids-much-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-finally-launched-bringing-in-housing-mechanism-new-raids-much-more.960012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-finally-launched-bringing-in-housing-mechanism-new-raids-much-more/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>ArenaNet has finally released <a href="https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-expansion-is-out-august-20-adds-new-raid-player-housing-and-land-spears/">Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds</a>, marking the <a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fifth expansion</a> for the renowned MMORPG title, originally released back in 2012.</p>
<p>The hype surrounding Janthir Wilds in the industry is at its all-time peak, given that initially, we saw ArenaNet disclosing to us about the actual expansion almost three months ago, and now the time has finally arrived when players will have the opportunity to experience the new in-game content that arrives alongside the expansion update. Janthir Wilds brings mechanisms to housing the game, allowing players to create their own "Homesteads." Along with this, the update features a new World Boss event and much more, which we'll discuss next.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Starting with Homestead, the game apparently grants players a patch of land where they can build their own housing space, with plenty of customization options. These include different props, objects, and decorations, which can be placed in the housing area through tools. It's an area where you can socialize with in-game comrades and is set to "provide a new way to express personal identity in the world of Tyria."</p>
<p>Apart from Homestead being the big thing, Janthir Wilds also brings in access to a new weapon type, particularly a spear. The Kodan Spear Mastery will teach players a bevy of new abilities in order to face the wild beasts of Janthir, ultimately taking the combat experience to new levels. Along with this, the new expansion brings in an enhanced Warclaw Mount, along with the dedicated World Boss Event, which is described as below:</p>
<p><em><strong>Warclaw Mount Update:&nbsp;</strong>previously occupying a niche for World-vs.-World competitive game modes, the newly updated warclaw mount provides additional opportunities for exploration in the open world via a new mastery track. Once fully trained, this large cat doesn’t take fall damage, can leap multiple times in the air, uses its sharp nose to sniff for treasure, and employs its chain pull skill in combat against enemies while also allowing its rider to throw lances from the saddle.</em></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><em><strong>New World Boss Event:&nbsp;</strong>the primordial energies of Janthir have drawn massive entities known as titans to its rocky shores. This dual threat encounter will challenge upwards of 50 players to put all their new skills to use in the kind of massive, signature epic showdown that&nbsp;Guild Wars 2&nbsp;is known for.</em></p>
<p>Josh Davis, Guild Wars 2 Game Director, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>Janthir Wilds is a promise fulfilled. When we announced we were moving to yearly expansion cycles, this is what we had in mind: new content every few months full of compelling content and new gameplay features so that the game always feels fresh when you log in</em></p>
<p>Interestingly, ArenaNet's Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds will require users to pay a $25 fee to access the new content, but given the in-game additions we have seen, it's certainly worth it, especially for the franchise's fans.</p>
<p><iframe title="Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gZFsrO_BqCk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Reveals Adorable Little Mario Kart Sets Coming In 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-8-lego-nintendo-switch-release-date-1851628089</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-reveals-adorable-little-mario-kart-sets-coming-in-2025.960006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-8-lego-nintendo-switch-release-date-1851628089<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="60f053e0992b212049dc4c5ee28b9c2a" data-recommend-id="image://60f053e0992b212049dc4c5ee28b9c2a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2272" data-height="1279" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario racers appear as Lego creations. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario racers appear as Lego creations. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Lego / Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="60f053e0992b212049dc4c5ee28b9c2a" data-recommend-id="image://60f053e0992b212049dc4c5ee28b9c2a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2272" data-height="1279" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario racers appear as Lego creations. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-8-10-year-anniversary-1851507678&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-8-10-year-anniversary-1851507678">the most popular game on Nintendo Switch</a></span>, is getting a proper Lego tribute starting next year. The toy brick company announced a line of Super Mario: Mario Kart Lego sets coming in 2025 that will include characters, cars, garages, and more. </p><p>With over 62 million copies sold on Nintendo’s handheld hybrid console, <em>Mario Kart 8</em> remains a monthly best-seller. Kart-related shenanigans also featured heavily in the <em>Super Mario Bros. Movie</em> last year, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/instead-of-announcing-mario-kart-9-nintendo-reveals-mor-1848510647&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/instead-of-announcing-mario-kart-9-nintendo-reveals-mor-1848510647"><em>Mario Kart 9</em></a></span>, whenever it eventually arrives, is likely to be one of the biggest Nintendo launches ever. So it’s not surprising to see that <em>Mario Kart</em> is the latest frontier for Nintendo’s ongoing collaboration with Lego. </p><p>So far, the company has revealed six <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/3-2-1-go-the-lego-group-reveals-first-ever-lego-super-mario-mario-kart-sets/?srsltid=AfmBOop1zWyuU1YoqkUBgQSqPV61yyHn9p7JPOUREUrTRQRM5shtzrNa&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/3-2-1-go-the-lego-group-reveals-first-ever-lego-super-mario-mario-kart-sets/?srsltid=AfmBOop1zWyuU1YoqkUBgQSqPV61yyHn9p7JPOUREUrTRQRM5shtzrNa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Super Mario: Mario Kart Lego</a></span> sets launching January 1, 2025:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>72031 – Yoshi Bike – $15<br></li><li>72032 – Standard Kart – $20<br></li><li>72033 – Donkey Kong &amp; DK Jumbo – $35<br></li><li>72034 – Baby Mario vs. Baby Luigi – $30<br></li><li>72035 – Toad’s Garage – $40<br></li><li>72036 – Baby Peach &amp; Grand Prix Set – $80<br></li></ul></blockquote><p>They are all fairly cheap and small, with the entire batch of sets currently running $220 and around 2,200 pieces. Instead of individual character figures, each racer, from Princess Peach to Baby Luigi, is constructed out of individual blocks. With over 40 characters in <em>Mario Kart 8</em> alone, there are plenty of additional racers for Lego to eventually sell. Bowser is an obvious missing icon from this initial reveal, though I’m personally hoping for Petey Piranha.</p><p>Lego has been <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/horizon-lego-adventures-hands-on-ps5-nintendo-switch-1851535713&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/horizon-lego-adventures-hands-on-ps5-nintendo-switch-1851535713">branching out into video game franchises</a></span> more and more lately, especially Nintendo ones. That includes <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/looks-like-legos-making-a-brick-built-nes-that-plays-ma-1844361085&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/looks-like-legos-making-a-brick-built-nes-that-plays-ma-1844361085">nostalgia-fueled replicas</a></span> as well as more traditional sets <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-lego-legend-zelda-great-deku-tree-set-price-1851503670&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-lego-legend-zelda-great-deku-tree-set-price-1851503670">like a $300 Deku Tree</a></span> from <em>The Legend of Zelda</em>. If Nintendo’s thought of it, Lego is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-price-pieces-date-1850861326&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-price-pieces-date-1850861326">willing to make it out of bricks</a></span>. Maybe we’ll even get a Lego guy or gal in <em>Super Smash Bros.</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-nintendo-console-tech-release-date-1851200648&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-nintendo-console-tech-release-date-1851200648">for the Switch 2</a></span>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate 2: New Details on Anti-Cheat, Esports, and Updates]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-new-details-anti-cheat-esports/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/splitgate-2-new-details-on-anti-cheat-esports-and-updates.960003/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-new-details-anti-cheat-esports/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Earlier today, we sat down with Ian Proulx, co-founder and CEO at 1047 Games, the developer behind Splitgate 2. Eager to find out more about this developing and intense shooter, we probed into the game’s development and the outlook on the title from a competitive perspective.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-first-and-foremost">First and Foremost</h2>



<p>Sitting down with Ian Proulx, we received key insights into the ongoing development of Splitgate 2, which is being tweaked at present following a recent playtest. One of our first and most important questions was about the integration of a solid anti-cheat system, which is paramount to success for an FPS title in this day and age.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>It has been our top priority – a couple of years ago, we acquired an anti-cheat company called EQU8. We decided to bring these guys in-house, partly to put more resources into our anti-cheat. You kind of have two options –  you can either make an anticheat that does a mediocre job of defending against all sorts of games, or you can make an anticheat that does a really good job of defending one game, and for us, we only care about one game. </p>



<p>As a third-party, that was their focus, they needed to make something that caters to lots of different clients, but now they’re in-house, they only have to cater for Splitgate 2.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Bringing the anti-cheat solution in-house means that the team doesn’t need to rely on regularly cracked solutions like BattleEye and Easy Anti-Cheat.</p>



<h2 id="h-getting-competitive">Getting Competitive</h2>



<figure></figure>







<p>If you’ve seen the gameplay of Splitgate 2, you’ll have noticed how much it seems to feel like an <strong>esports-ready </strong>game. It takes place in an arena, like a spectator sport, and it boasts a system that lends itself to players assuming roles and competing as a team.</p>



<p>However, talking to Ian Proulx about this, that isn’t too high on the team’s agenda:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Our art style and our lore is that this is a sport and not a war. We’re not trying to say ‘this is esports’, we’re trying to say ‘this is the world of Splitgate 2’, it’s the sport of the future. If you look at the branding, it’s very inspired by Formula 1, NBA, NFL, and so on.</p>



<p>In terms of esports specifically, obviously we’ve made a game that we say is easy to learn but difficult to master, and I think we’ve hit that balance a lot better this time around. Do I think that this game would be a great esport? Absolutely. I’m not really having tonnes of conversations about that yet.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Proulx did admit that if the game is ‘sticky’ and people enjoy it, then esports with naturally follow.</p>



<h2 id="h-building-something-memorable">Building Something Memorable</h2>



<figure></figure>







<p>Throughout the conversation with Ian Proulx, he remained on-point with the driving message that this is a shooter that is being developed with the community in mind. He used the term ‘community-first development’, talking about forming relationships with streamers and kicking off activations to generate hype, but it always comes back to supporting that community. </p>



<p>Talking about the most recent tweaks to the game, Proulx walked through adjustments and balancing measures to portals and how they work, some quality-of-life changes in button mapping, and some sizeable tweaks to the game, such as the creative decision to remove EMP grenades.</p>



<p>Movement has been ramped up, and Proulx is particularly proud of the game’s sliding mechanic, which is the result of months of painstaking work.</p>



<p>Ultimately, everything that we were shown about Splitgate 2 fills us with a sense of encouragement about the ongoing development of this title. It’s sure to be a hit, just as the first game was, but this time around, there’s more meat on the bones to keep it going post-launch. It’s a free-to-play shooter (with cosmetic MTX) and it has been built with the player in mind and nothing but passion from the developers.</p>



<p>What more could you ask for?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dune-awakening-gets-25-minutes-of-new-gameplay/">Dune: Awakening has a new gameplay video</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light: The Beast Literally Brings Out the Big Guns for a Shooting-Heavy Spin-Off | gamescom 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dying-light-the-beast-literally-brings-out-the-big-guns-for-a-shooting-heavy-spin-off-gamescom-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-the-beast-literally-brings-out-the-big-guns-for-a-shooting-heavy-spin-off-gamescom-2024.960000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dying-light-the-beast-literally-brings-out-the-big-guns-for-a-shooting-heavy-spin-off-gamescom-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The original Dying Light’s story ended with protagonist Kyle Crane suffering a miserable fate; either blasted to atoms by a nuclear bomb or twisted into an infected. But that, it turns out, wasn’t the end of his story. Techland’s new entry in the series, Dying Light: The Beast, appears to lock in the latter of those endings as canon, revealing Crane was held captive for 13 years, subjected to experiments by a villain known only as The Baron. Now free, Crane seeks revenge for the trials and tortures that have turned him into the titular beast. But, if what I’ve seen of this new Dying Light is representative of the entire game, it’s not the beast powers that change the game – it’s the guns.  </p><p>Dying Light: The Beast began life as DLC for Dying Light 2, but developer Techland changed course after some of its work was leaked. The project bloomed into a full, standalone game (although if you did buy Dying Light 2’s ultimate edition you get The Beast for free - Techland promised DLC and intends to fulfil that promise). Perhaps because of this origin, The Beast feels very familiar. Much of what I saw in the 45-minute hands-off demo was very much a continuation of the 2022 zombie smasher, from the robust parkour, to the world design, to the ‘follow the yellow cable’ puzzles that activate UV-protected safe houses. This certainly doesn’t seem like a ‘full’ sequel, but there does appear to be enough fresh ideas to justify its transition to a standalone game.  </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The new map is more rural, with something of a ‘village’ feel. Yes, there are still buildings and rooftops to leap and vault across, but these are surrounded by dense woodland. The demo showed Kyle creeping through tall grass in an effort to avoid nighttime horrors (which, once again, are much stronger than the zombies that appear during the day). Kyle notably doesn’t seem to suffer from the same infection Adien did in DL2 - there’s no immunity gauge ticking down on the HUD – so he can seemingly stay out in the dark as long as he wants. His own mutations mean he can see the illuminated skeletons of approaching foes, Batman: Arkham detective vision-style, which should aid with stealth encounters. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>In beast mode Kyle can perform a ground pound that sends damaging ripples through the concrete.</p></div><p>The most significant new idea, though, is a more prominent use of guns. If you’ve played Dying Light 2 with its recent Firearms update then you already know a little of what to expect – the pistol, shotgun, and assault rifle featured in this demo were all the same as those added to DL2 earlier this year. But they seem key to the experience here, not just a powerful accessory. The Baron’s henchmen are all paramilitary types with body armour and rifles of their own. That means combat encounters with them are very, very different from the melee scraps with zombies and raiders that Dying Light has previously almost exclusively survived on. The Techland employee playing the demo for us used grenades to flush out entrenched gunmen and flanking tactics to snipe others. These encounters were lengthy, too; Kyle seems able to carry more than enough ammunition to chew through multiple squadrons. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/21/dying-light-the-beast-guns-1724258832233.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Techland’s franchise director, Tymon Smektala, emphasised that Dying Light hasn’t been turned into a shooter. But I’d estimate nearly half the demo <em>was</em> played as an FPS. I don’t think that’s a bad thing, though, provided the combat encounters, associated level design,  and weapon feedback all prove successful. It’s a smart way to provide a new spin on Dying Light’s otherwise largely unchanged formula. Not being able to play myself means I can’t say how good all this actually is, but it at least looked like a competent shooter – hardly Call of Duty, but solid enough.  </p><p>The search for The Baron led Kyle into an underground lab where some kind of huge creature had torn its way out of a cage. A scientist there revealed it could be lured by a special gas, and so a cylinder of it was loaded onto a flatbed truck and driven to a junkyard. Yes, driving returns from Dying Light: The Following, although the truck doesn’t look quite as fun as the expansion’s buggy. Still, being able to hit and run zombies looks as enjoyable as ever, as their undead bodies burst and splatter against the headlights. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/21/dying-light-the-beast-zombie-1724258868823.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Releasing the gas in the junkyard summoned the Behemoth, a hulk-like freak with an inflated health bar and the strength to hurl cars. Firearms were effective at whittling that HP down, but when ammunition ran dry it quickly became clear that melee weapons wouldn’t cut it. And so, with just a few minutes of the demo left, Kyle let the titular beast out of its cage.   </p><p>In beast mode Kyle becomes stronger and faster. He can pick up stone blocks and hurl them at enemies, as well as perform a ground pound that sends damaging ripples through the concrete, Hulk style. Easily tearing through the Behemoth’s remaining health, the battle concluded with Kyle ripping the monster’s head from its shoulders in a gory victory move. Safe to say beast mode looks very powerful, but also quite similar to the infected powers Aiden had in Dying Light 2. Unlike Aiden, though, it seems like Kyle can transform into the beast freely rather than only at specific story moments. </p><p>I’m surprised that Techland left the titular power to the very end of the demo. It meant there was little room to properly explore why the beast is so central to the game, so much so that I do wonder if it actually is as important as the title suggests. Instead, I left more interested in how guns and soldier enemies will change the overall rhythm of Dying Light. Hopefully they’ve been smartly woven into the campaign and feel fully integrated rather than awkwardly tacked on. If so, The Beast could well prove a worthy standalone game rather than just a respectable DLC sold separately. </p><p><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Senior Features Editor. </em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>