<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 21:16:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bushido Consequences Cycle Deck Exclusive Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/previews/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-exclusive-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-exclusive-preview.1335010/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Just like the seasons, everything changes in the Jwar Isles. These developments are reflected in the Cycle Decks, and we've been given a first look at some of the cards in the next. In this article, we'll exclusively reveal 5 new cards from the <em>Bushido</em> Consequences Cycle Deck, which is available to preorder now.</p>

<p>We've been covering <em>Bushido&nbsp;</em>for years, so if you'd like to learn more about the game, check out <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/guides/bushido-risen-sun-guide" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">our guide to <em>Bushido Risen Sun</em></a>, our <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/bushido-two-player-starter-set-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">review of the <em>Bushido Risen Sun</em>&nbsp;2-player starter set</a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/start-collecting-bushido-risen-sun-part-1-introduction-and-developer-interview" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">our "Start Collecting" guide to <em>Bushido</em></a>, which includes an interview with the game's developer. You can also check out our review of the last Cycle Deck <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/bushido-weeping-sky-cycle-deck-review" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p>

<h2>Seasonal Changes</h2>

<p>Cycle Decks in <em>Bushido</em> are a way for GCT to easily incorporate new cards, rather than packaging them with specific miniature releases. Players can pick up the Cycle Deck, and the cards will also be available for free in the <em>Bushido</em> App.</p>

<p>The Concequences Cycle Deck, like the Weeping Sky Cycle Deck before it, contains 54 cards for a mixture of factions and card types, including:</p>

<ul><li>Events, usually actions that can be played during the game</li>
	<li>Terrain, which can be deployed onto the battlefield for specific effects</li>
	<li>Enhancements, are attached to units to offer effects and abilities</li>
	<li>Themes, offer new abilities if the warband construction restrictions are followed</li>
</ul><p>We don't know the full breakdown yet, but there are usually a few faction-specific cards, along with Ronin cards that can be used by all. GCT has stated that the newest factions, such as Awoken, will receive dedicated cards in upcoming releases like Kuna, rather than in this cycle deck. This allows them to focus on fully developing these factions, however, Awoken players can still incorporate Ronin cycle cards into their warbands.</p>

<p>Below we reveal 5 cards from the new cycle deck, with comments on their design and lore from the GCT Studios team ahead of our own thoughts.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-2.jpg?itok=SqoK0GN5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-2.jpg?itok=4GLiMHap 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>New Eagle Army</h2>

<blockquote>
<p>Amidst the mystical upheaval in the celestial realm, it's vital to anchor the narrative through the eyes of the Jwar Isles' people. The Shiho Clan has been quietly rebuilding its power base since Hiroto's return. Though they lack the resources to field a standing army like the Prefecture of Ryu, they’ve uncovered pockets of Ashigaru veterans, disciplined fighters whose loyalty, training and battlefield organisation remain intact. These seasoned warriors are well-suited to open combat, a necessity if the Shiho are to reclaim their former influence.</p>

<p>Theme cards play a pivotal role in shaping a faction’s identity, unlocking fresh warband configurations and tactical possibilities. The New Eagle Army theme exemplifies this. Reflecting the elite band of Shiho Ashigaru, once the envy of the land, these soldiers gain powerful advantages when managing Virtue Tokens, making them reliable in both melee and ranged engagements.</p>

<p>Strategically, the Theme enhances warband efficiency by offering free Warband Terrain &nbsp;and / or Enhancements, along with cost reductions for Ashigaru profiles. While the Theme forges the Shiho’s hallmark flanking warfare, it introduces a compelling “take and hold” playstyle, rich with nuanced micro-movements that the faction is celebrated for.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>As a Shiho player, I'm looking forward to trying this out. Even as a Wolf player, it reduces the cost of the Wolf Ryoshi and Spears, and adds in the free Terrain and Enhancements. It might just pull me away from my Open Rebellion theme!</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-3.jpg?itok=B-E4Hiz3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-3.jpg?itok=Tbxf8TtV 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Consequences of Kiyohara</h2>

<blockquote>
<p>Sojobo’s machinations continue to unfold, and the stakes have never been higher. Having already fractured an Asura, the act that drew the gaze and anger of Rajin, he has now unleashed the Awoken to keep the heavens turning, but at what cost? One thing is clear: desperate times demand desperate measures.</p>

<p>From a gameplay perspective, Sojobo has fallen out of favour with the Kami and is now relentlessly struck by lightning, a punishment few could endure. Even a king, it seems, is not immune to the consequences of his actions.</p>

<p>So why include the card in your warband? Despite the divine backlash, Sojobo's card offers a substantial cost discount, making him a compelling choice. This allows players to field a high-value defender at a low cost, unlocking new possibilities for list-building and tactical flexibility. It’s a risky play, but one that could pay off handsomely for those bold enough to use it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Sojobo is a 24-cost Ronin that can join&nbsp;Shiho Clan, Temple of Ro-Kan, and The Descension warbands and is a very effective fighter who can make it harder for ranged attacks across the entire battlefield, and also push units away from them. As the team says above, reducing their cost to 19 at the risk of them taking damage each turn could really pay off.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-4.jpg?itok=dxs-AL5j 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-4.jpg?itok=VY_9KwqU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Yokai Corruption</h2>

<blockquote>
<p>After the great Tsunami, rising waters forced the spiders from their hidden lairs into human settlements and forests, spreading dread wherever they crept. Once again, the common folk came to fear the spider’s presence and so Grandmother, and her corrupted followers, took on this form, one that mirrors her essence and the spirit of her death-bringing cycle.</p>

<p>Now, Sojobo must confront the embodiment of the returned Thirteenth Cycle. If he is to fulfill his mission, he cannot avoid this malevolent force. With such powers unleashed, even the Yokai are being reshaped and twisted into new forms that reflect the corruption of nature itself. The Cult of Yueri stands as a chilling benefactor to this transformation.</p>

<p>This card presents a true conundrum. Your Yokai will blaze with additional Ki Tokens, surging with unnatural energy throughout the game. But this power comes at a price: the stolen energies will eventually consume them. It’s a classic twist on risk-reward mechanics, and one that many Yueri players will find irresistible, offering bold new strategies for those willing to gamble with fate.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Adding this to a Yokai unit with a high Ki empowers them more and means they'll survive longer, but each time they use a Ki feat, they'll drop by 1, which means they might not be as effective late game, but if you want to storm them into combat, and watch them burn out taking down enemies, then this Enhancement for the Cult of Yurei is glorious.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-5.jpg?itok=AbsS3xME 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-5.jpg?itok=s6QsY1bx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Bleeding Moon’s Influence</h2>

<blockquote>
<p>Each cycle is marked by a celestial Asura, a divine embodiment of that cycle’s spirit and nature. For generations, it was believed there were only twelve cycles, but ancient calendars and forgotten dates revealed a hidden truth: a missing cycle, long obscured, whose absence caused the Heavenly misalignment that Sojobo now seeks to correct.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With the return of the Thirteenth Cycle, a much older cosmic order begins to reassert itself. At this pivotal moment, Master Bat’s influence surges, and as the heavens realign with his domain, his growing power manifests through this event card.</p>

<p>Mechanically, this event disrupts many effects that would normally remove Bleeding Markers, including Heal. As a result, any model with the Bleed Trait becomes significantly more lethal, its damage lingering. Ideal for warbands that lean into damage-over-time mechanics.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>With the recent release of the Master Bat Ronin unit (who gives Bleed tokens on their attacks) and Nagato, who opened up the House Bleeding Moon Shadow Wind Clan theme, this Event means that those Bleed tokens are definitely going to be there in the end turn to do damage.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-6.jpg?itok=_fyRFbIG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-6.jpg?itok=xQ5exTGY 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Weeping Sky’s Influence</h2>

<blockquote>
<p>The skies themselves are said to weep, mourning the faltering celestial order. As the heavens tremble, the consequences ripple through both the mortal realm and the spiritual plane, reshaping the balance of power across the Jwar Isles.</p>

<p>At the heart of this upheaval stands Lord Toad, master of the previous cycle and a divine force whose influence endures. Even King Sojobo, no stranger to ambition, offers him respect. Lord Toad is far from finished. He revels in the bounty his cycle has unleashed, and the signs of his lingering power are unmistakable.</p>

<p>From the quagmire and shadowed tunnels, the lifeless legions of the Imperial Court have begun to rise. Their emergence is no coincidence, it is a reaction to Lord Toad’s enduring will for change.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This card offers a powerful early-game advantage: it prevents long-range attacks during Turn One, shielding your warband from opportunistic enemy volleys before formations are set. Whether you're protecting fragile units or setting up a bold advance, this effect can dramatically shift the tempo of the opening round.</p>

<p>The battlefield even becomes a quagmire, Lord Toad, ever the opportunist, thrives in this environment. The movement boost granted by the Quagmire effect plays perfectly into his slippery tactics, allowing him to reposition with ease.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Lord Toad was a recent Ronin release that can be used across all 14 factions. While in a quagmire, Lord Toad's movement is boosted by 2 to 6 and ignores all terrain and other models for the purposes of movement, rushing them ahead to make use of their Swallow Up ki feat to remove an enemy unit from the battlefield for a turn.</p>

<h2>Future&nbsp;Consequences</h2>

<p>Have any of the above cards piqued your interest? Or what are you hoping for out of the other 49 cards in the&nbsp;Consequences Cycle Deck? Let us know in the comments below.</p>

<p>The Bushido&nbsp;Consequences Cycle Deck is available to preorder along with 13 miniatures in the latest of a huge wave of releases <a href="https://gctstudios.com/catalog/new-specials" rel="nofollow">from GCT</a>. I'm picking up Somabo and Kizo from this wave, for an awesome bird invasion of the Jwar Isles!</p>

<hr><p>The preview cards for the&nbsp;<strong>Bushido Consequences Cycle Deck</strong>&nbsp;<em>used to produce this preview were provided by GCT Studios.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/previews/bushido-consequences-cycle-deck-exclusive-preview]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Steam Player Count Spikes With New Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-steam-player-count-spike-pve-mode-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-steam-player-count-spikes-with-new-mode.1335004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new mode for Marvel Rivals has caused a major player spike on Steam, its highest in a while.</p>



<p>Released in December 2024, the free-to-play multiplayer superhero shooter has been going steady. With the release of Season 4, which added <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-showcases-daredevils-duelist-moves-in-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Daredevil</a> and Angela, the game has seen a decent, stable player base. While not as high as when its first season dropped, touting a 644,269 player count, it still ranks as one of the most popular games on Steam. In any case, earlier this week, the numbers rose quite a bit, heading into numbers only seen for the beginning of a season. Well, a new mode, one fans have been asking for for quite a while, has been added.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-pve-marvel-zombies-mode-almost-doubles-marvel-rivals-usual-player-count">New PvE Marvel Zombies Mode Almost Doubles Marvel Rivals’ Usual Player Count</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>According to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2767030/charts/#1w" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>, earlier this week, Marvel Rivals kept at a usual 75k-80k player count, decreasing from the start of Season 4.5 with Daredevil. However, on October 23rd, the game spiked into the high 120k, almost double what it was the previous day. It continued into yesterday and today. The reason? The addition of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-pve-zombies-mode-arrives-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel Zombies PvE mode</a> lets players fight against AI enemies. Based on the comic and new animated series, the limited-time Halloween-based mode brings it to life with droves of zombies and perilous fights with friends. </p>



<p>A quick look at Reddit supports the rise quite well, as many fans have praised the mode a ton. Some, like <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/rivals/comments/1oeqvfe/holy_fucking_shit_is_the_marvel_zombies_game_mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Living-Ad102</a>, want it to be a permanent addition to the game. Given that PvE has been asked for since the game’s release, the massive spike isn’t too surprising. If anything, it’s clear that NetEase may want to do more of these events. Either way, if you want in on the fun, best to do it before mid-November while Marvel Zombies lasts. </p>



<p>Have you played the Marvel Zombies mode in Marvel Rivals yet? If so, how is it? Would you like to see PvE added permanently to the base game? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Marvel Rivals, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-cross-progression-season-5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the upcoming cross-progression addition</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-does-marvel-rivals-season-5-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 5 details</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-steam-player-count-spike-pve-mode-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Old School RuneScape is getting its first new skill since it launched, and so the XP grind begins anew]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/old-school-runescape-is-getting-its-first-new-skill-since-it-launched-and-so-the-xp-grind-begins-anew</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/old-school-runescape-is-getting-its-first-new-skill-since-it-launched-and-so-the-xp-grind-begins-anew.1334986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/old-school-runescape-sailing.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/old-school-runescape-sailing.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/old-school-runescape-sailing.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/old-school-runescape-sailing.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/old-school-runescape-sailing.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/old-school-runescape-sailing.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/old-school-runescape-sailing.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/old-school-runescape-sailing.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/old-school-runescape-sailing.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Jagex</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
A thing I find a lot of joy in is the fact that despite there's technically a new, shinier, perhaps by some people's standards better version of it, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/old-school-runescape">Old School RuneScape</a> is still kicking around. Before the Old School was tagged on the front end of it, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/runescape">RuneScape</a> was an MMO I put many hours into (and found little success in) as a youth with too much free time, so the fact practically two decades later it's introducing a brand new skill into the game simultaneously impresses me and strikes existential fear into my heart because of how old this game actually is.
</p>
<p>
Moving on swiftly, sailing! That's the new skill coming to Old School RuneScape, the first new one since its launch. According to a <a href="https://secure.runescape.com/m=news/sailing-launches-on-november-19th?oldschool=1">blog post</a>, sailing is quite the undertaking, described as "bigger and more expansive than any content that's come before it," and a skill that "touches almost every aspect of the game." With this new skill, you can own up to five boats at any time. These boats are upgradable, and there's three sizes to choose from: the raft, small boat, and large boat.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Sailing - Old School RuneScape’s NEW SKILL | Official Release Date Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EktZVWpY9nw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Sailing - Old School RuneScape’s NEW SKILL | Official Release Date Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EktZVWpY9nw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EktZVWpY9nw?autoplay=1" title="Sailing - Old School RuneScape’s NEW SKILL | Official Release Date Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EktZVWpY9nw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
There's ship combat, which apparently mostly works the same as land combat, and you can also take a few different NPCs with you out on the sea - or your real friends too! Levelling up requires, technically, just one thing, which is, well, sailing. This includes "interacting with facilities on your boat" like trimming your sails, an action that nets you some XP as well as a speed boost.
</p><p>
On top of all that, you can salvage shipwrecks, chart the oceans you travel across, do some deep sea trawling, complete new quests, gather new resources, and while this one's a bit more secretive, there's new areas to explore too, including 30 new islands, some of which have some new dungeons.
</p>
<p>
The sailing update is coming to Old School RuneScape pretty soon too, as it's currently planned to launch in just under a month's time on November 19th.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/old-school-runescape-is-getting-its-first-new-skill-since-it-launched-and-so-the-xp-grind-begins-anew]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#868)—Clues and Answers for Sunday, October 26]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-october-26-868/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nyt-connections-hints-today-868-%E2%80%94clues-and-answers-for-sunday-october-26.1334977/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s a sleepy Sunday, but it’s also time to wrap up your week with another round of NYT Connections hints and solutions. Today’s puzzle will be easy for some, including <strong>boxing fans</strong>, but I’ve still provided the best hints around so that you can get things finished as fast as possible, then get on with the rest of your weekend.</p>



<p>Read on to get the full scope of today’s NYT Connections hints.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-october-26">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (October 26)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will spur your brain into action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #868:</p>



<ul>
<li>BEE</li>



<li>BUTTERFLY</li>



<li>FLOAT</li>



<li>STING</li>



<li>BRASS</li>



<li>PERCUSSION</li>



<li>STRING</li>



<li>WIND</li>



<li>BEAUTY</li>



<li>POPULARITY</li>



<li>STARING</li>



<li>TALENT</li>



<li>DOGGY</li>



<li>DROPLET</li>



<li>KITCHENETTE</li>



<li>STARLING</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>Think orchestra sections! These are categories of musical instruments</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em>These all describe creatures or actions associated with light movement or flight</em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>These words relate to qualities often judged or admired in people or performances</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>This group plays with diminutives or cozy-sounding words</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, October 26.</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-for-today-october-26-868">NYT Connections Answers for Today, October 26 (#868)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– BRASS, PERCUSSION, STRING, WIND</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – BEE, BUTTERFLY, FLOAT, STING</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – BEAUTY, POPULARITY, STARING, TALENT</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – DOGGY, DROPLET, KITCHENETTE, STARLING</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-october-26-868/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 Elden Ring Tarnished Edition delayed to 2026 to "allow time for performance adjustments"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-elden-ring-tarnished-edition-delayed-to-2026-to-allow-time-for-performance-adjustments</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-elden-ring-tarnished-edition-delayed-to-2026-to-allow-time-for-performance-adjustments.1334959/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eldenring-switch2.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eldenring-switch2.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eldenring-switch2.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eldenring-switch2.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eldenring-switch2.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eldenring-switch2.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eldenring-switch2.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eldenring-switch2.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eldenring-switch2.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>FromSoftware / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>FromSoftware has pushed back the release of the highly anticipated <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-nintendo-switch-2-the-digital-foundry-hardware-review">Nintendo Switch 2</a> port of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-walkthrough-8042">Elden Ring</a> to "allow time for performance adjustments".</p>
<p>In a brief statement, the developer apologised for the delay, but said it was "wholeheartedly [working] toward release", which is now expected sometime in 2026. Sadly, a firmer release window has not been provided.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ELDEN RING is coming to Nintendo Switch 2" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EGAaGwQIDoU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ELDEN RING is coming to Nintendo Switch 2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EGAaGwQIDoU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EGAaGwQIDoU?autoplay=1" title="ELDEN RING is coming to Nintendo Switch 2">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Elden Ring is coming to Nintendo Switch 2.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EGAaGwQIDoU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-is-coming-to-switch-2">Elden Ring's Switch 2 port, Tarnished Edition, was announced at a Nintendo Direct presentation back in April</a>. It's slated to include the base game and its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-tips-and-tricks">Shadow of the Erdtree</a> DLC, as well as new armour and a new Torrent appearance customisation feature.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>While development on <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ELDENRING?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ELDENRING</a> Tarnished Edition continues wholeheartedly toward release, we have decided to move the launch to 2026 to allow time for performance adjustments. </p><p>We apologize to players looking forward to the game and thank you for your patience and support. <a href="https://t.co/TsLrhAWIGc">pic.twitter.com/TsLrhAWIGc</a></p></div>— ELDEN RING (@ELDENRING) <a href="https://twitter.com/ELDENRING/status/1981360180580217143?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 23, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>FromSoft hadn't given a firm release date for the Switch 2 Tarnished Edition in 2025, but it was initially expected to release before the end of the year.</p>
<p>"We apologise to players looking forward to the game and thank you for your patience and support," the team said.</p>
<p>As for FromSoftware's Elden Ring spin-off, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>? <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fromsoftware-unveils-elden-ring-nightreigns-new-mode-ahead-of-release-tomorrow">New mode Deep of Night mode is now live</a>, adding extra challenge to the multiplayer spin-off game. The world of Limveld will be full of deadlier enemies, and Nightlords won't be selectable, as in the main game, but instead players can traverse multiple depths, with escalating difficulty and challenges.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  <div>
      <p>
        <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/elden-ring">Elden Ring</a>
      </p>

      <p>
            <span>PS4</span>, 
            <span>PS5</span>, 
            <span>Xbox One</span>, 
            <span>Xbox Series X/S</span>, 
            <span>PC</span>
      </p>





</div>

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-elden-ring-tarnished-edition-delayed-to-2026-to-allow-time-for-performance-adjustments]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Warzone's focus on the year ahead is Battle Royale, Resurgence, and "the future of the game"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-warzones-focus-on-the-year-ahead-is-battle-royale-resurgence-and-the-future-of-the-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-warzones-focus-on-the-year-ahead-is-battle-royale-resurgence-and-the-future-of-the-game.1334950/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"Battle Royale is the foundation upon which we've built every new mode, feature, and memorable moment."</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_16631d200714fb6b043775853498c3c3d78294f4-1442854558.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_16631d200714fb6b043775853498c3c3d78294f4-1442854558.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_16631d200714fb6b043775853498c3c3d78294f4-1442854558.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_16631d200714fb6b043775853498c3c3d78294f4-1442854558.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_16631d200714fb6b043775853498c3c3d78294f4-1442854558.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_16631d200714fb6b043775853498c3c3d78294f4-1442854558.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_16631d200714fb6b043775853498c3c3d78294f4-1442854558.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_16631d200714fb6b043775853498c3c3d78294f4-1442854558.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_16631d200714fb6b043775853498c3c3d78294f4-1442854558.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Raven Software / Activision</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Raven Software says its focus for the year ahead and Call of Duty: Warzone comes down to three pillars: "Battle Royale, Resurgence, and the future of the game".</p>
<p>In a new <a href="https://x.com/RavenSoftware/status/1981852213581381882">update</a> posted earlier today, the developer said the team was "incredibly excited and there is much more to come", including a "first look" at some of the updates on the way, but insisted "Battle Royale is the foundation upon which we've built every new mode, feature, and memorable moment".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="New Warzone Map - Haven's Hollow Flythrough | Call of Duty: Warzone" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QSLfZ0GiNs8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>New Warzone Map - Haven's Hollow Flythrough | Call of Duty: Warzone</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QSLfZ0GiNs8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QSLfZ0GiNs8?autoplay=1" title="New Warzone Map - Haven's Hollow Flythrough | Call of Duty: Warzone">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>New Warzone Map - Haven's Hollow Flythrough | Call of Duty: Warzone.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QSLfZ0GiNs8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"While we continue to innovate across the entire game, we feel it's important that Battle Royale remains a cornerstone of what we do," the developer stated. "That's why we're expanding Battle Royale to include support for multiple large maps via map rotation. While it wasn't previously realistic for us to host multiple large maps, we've since taken the steps necessary to support it. This won't be a launch feature with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7">Black Ops 7</a>, but it's a key addition slated for early next year."</p><p>Though it previously insisted it would "approach change more deliberately to preserve the original Warzone launch experience" after re-releasing Verdansk last spring, Raven confirmed it's going to "increase how often we release updates and refine the way we surface new features to you".</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>"The goal is balance: keep things moving without forgetting about seasonal support and quality-of-life improvements," the team explained.</p>
<p>As part of that, Raven says it's heard you "loud and clear" about Rebirth Island and the broader Resurgence experience, admitting it has "started to feel a bit stale".</p>
<p>"So, to start, we're delivering a full refresh to Rebirth Island in Season 02, which includes new POI updates, a cosmetic pass, and several other upgrades that improve flow," Raven explained. "The launch of the new Haven's Hollow map in Season 01 will be another step in spicing up Resurgence. These past months, we've made changes based on feedback received during early previews of Haven's Hollow.</p><p>"Shortly after launch, we'll be bringing back map rotation to Resurgence, which will swap between Rebirth Island and Haven's Hollow," the statement added. "We are also exploring opportunities to bring back past maps in future seasons: an improved version of Fortune's Keep is underway as we speak. Our goal is to ensure that each map has room to shine without sidelining the ones that you love most."</p>
<p>Moving forward, the developer says it will continue to make "significant, meaningful improvements on multiple fronts", and intends to "deliver a higher frequency of updates, with a larger emphasis on balance changes no less than twice per season".</p>
<p>"Our approach to weapon and attachment balance is fundamentally shifting, which means redefined roles at launch followed by multiple balance passes per season with adjustments entirely unique to Warzone," Raven explained. "Regular updates will extend beyond weapons to include shifts in ground loot, perks, equipment, contracts, and much more throughout the year."</p>
<p>Players can expect a seasonal roadmap next month, and more Ranked Play camos in Season 2, as well as "the arrival of our new Blackout experience on Avalon during Season 2".</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6s-battle-royale-battlefield-redsec-could-shadowdrop-as-soon-as-next-week-dataminers-claim">Battlefield 6's battle royale mode, rumoured to be called Battlefield: RedSec</a>, could be shadowdropped as soon as next week, according to dataminers.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-warzones-focus-on-the-year-ahead-is-battle-royale-resurgence-and-the-future-of-the-game]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nivalis catches yet another delay, this time into 2026, but it sounds like it's for fair reasons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nivalis-catches-yet-another-delay-this-time-into-2026-but-it-sounds-like-its-for-fair-reasons</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nivalis-catches-yet-another-delay-this-time-into-2026-but-it-sounds-like-its-for-fair-reasons.1334941/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>This is the game's second delay</p>

    </div>


  

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
There are two sides to every game delay coin. On the one hand, it's a shame when you're looking forward to a thing only to have to wait even longer for said thing. On the other, there's too many damn video games these days and, oh, gods, don't we all just have a laundry list of things to attend to right now? So make of it what you will that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nivalis">Nivalis</a>, the cyberpunk restaurant <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-simulation-games">sim</a> set in the world of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cloudpunk">Cloudpunk</a>, has been delayed.
</p>
<p>
Word of said delay (<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/glittering-cyberpunk-life-sim-nivalis-has-been-delayed-until-2025">its second one</a>) comes in the form of a recent <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1488490/view/536616765394782627?l=english">Steam news post</a>, which took the time to highlight just how big this technically small indie game actually is: "Right now, we’re deeply focused on the voice over: we’ve just completed the casting process for over 100 new voice roles after our first casting of 32 roles for our demo 2 years ago," the post explains. "In Nivalis, there will be around 135 primary and secondary fully voiced characters, for a total of about 200,000 words."
</p>
<p>
That, to be clear, is genuinely very impressive. We all know how even the biggest of RPGs reuse voice actors for multiple characters and NPCs. With that, the post notes that amongst all of this voice acting stuff, "releasing the game in 2025 would risk compromising its quality." So the game will now be releasing in 2026, though an exact release day or even month hasn't been revealed just yet (apparently the devs are working on this with their publisher, and confirmation of a release date will hopefully be coming before the year is out).
</p>
<p>
Nivalis, for those that haven't heard of it, conceptually feels like quite an open game. You can manage a restaurant or a night club, buy or grow your own ingredients for your establishment, go fishing, purchase a home, and most importantly meet people. It's the meeting people that almost seems to be the key thing here, and the thing I'm most curious about.
</p><p>
The game's Steam page does note that Nivalis is not an easy city to live in, with gangs hoping to harvest your organs, Corps fining you just for breathing, and "the whole time, the ground under your feet is crumbling." So in a world like this, what are its people like? With as many voice lines as the devs claim the game has, hopefully these people are varied and strongly defined, but I also want them to be people with believable problems, wants, and needs.
</p>
<p>
Like many of us in this world I worked in hospitality for many years, and met all sorts of folks, which sometimes was even quite a nice thing to do. It was also often not a nice thing to do, a dichotomy I hope is represented in Nivalis, whenever it launches next year. You can wishlist it on Steam <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1488490/Nivalis/">here</a>.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nivalis-catches-yet-another-delay-this-time-into-2026-but-it-sounds-like-its-for-fair-reasons]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Paranormal Activity games gets a slightly new name and a scarily underwhelming first gameplay trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-paranormal-activity-games-gets-a-slightly-new-name-and-a-scarily-underwhelming-first-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-paranormal-activity-games-gets-a-slightly-new-name-and-a-scarily-underwhelming-first-gameplay-trailer.1334914/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Might wanna pause that recording</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/paranormal-activity-threshold.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/paranormal-activity-threshold.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/paranormal-activity-threshold.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/paranormal-activity-threshold.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/paranormal-activity-threshold.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/paranormal-activity-threshold.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/paranormal-activity-threshold.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/paranormal-activity-threshold.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/paranormal-activity-threshold.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>DarkStone Digital</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
You know, with the original Paranormal Activity steadily approaching two decades of existence, it's becoming harder and harder to recognise what it actually was and is as opposed to the cultural consensus around it. First and foremost you probably think of it as a cheap, jump-scare-filled kind of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a> movie, when in actuality the first entry in the series is a slow, tense window into the world of gaslighting and, obviously, the paranormal. Being as removed as we are from this means one thing: IP expansion, which we're viewing today in the form of the first proper trailer for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/paranormal-activity-found-footage">Paranormal Activity: Threshold</a>, the video game adaptation from the developer behind <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-mortuary-assistant">The Mortuary Assistant</a>.
</p>
<p>
Let's set the scene, with some assistance from the game's description on Steam. Paranormal Activity: <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/threshold">Threshold</a> focuses on Daniel and Jessica Stewart, who've just decided to remodel their first home. We're introduced to said home by Daniel, showing a fairly sized if sparsely decorated building that he describes as the only one they could afford. Sure thing Daniel!
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Paranormal Activity | IHS 2025 Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_WZkOt9EaBI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Paranormal Activity | IHS 2025 Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_WZkOt9EaBI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_WZkOt9EaBI?autoplay=1" title="Paranormal Activity | IHS 2025 Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_WZkOt9EaBI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
The rest of the trailer shows a variety of hauntings and happenings like a shadow moving across the room, a stool sliding along the floor, a door suddenly shutting. There's some kind of vaguely satanic-looking puzzle you can do, but aside from that it doesn't really show much of the broader activities you'll be participating in.
</p><p>
Returning to Steam again, there's an explanation that you can "play in multiple timelines," "hunt and communicate with entities," and "perform demonic rituals to alter your fate." There's apparently multiple endings, and the game's "Paranormal Engine makes every playthrough unique." My guess is that different playthroughs can have different hauntings as I described above take place randomly, which if I'm right, sounds quite similar to the hauntings you can experience in Silent Hill 4's pseudo-hub area.
</p>
<p>
I'll admit that I feel quite apprehensive about Paranormal Activity getting a game adaptation. I can count the number of good entries in the film series on one hand, but there's two hands worth of films to count, distorting what it could be if done well. How might a game adaptation deal with such a framework? Is a game even capable of capturing that tactile feel an actual tape presents like in the first film, having you question what's real and what isn't? I'm not sure that there's enough filters in the world to convey such a feeling.
</p>
<p>
In any case, there's no release date for Paranormal Activity: Threshold, but you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3394030/Paranormal_Activity_Threshold/">wishlist it on Steam</a> in the meantime.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-paranormal-activity-games-gets-a-slightly-new-name-and-a-scarily-underwhelming-first-gameplay-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: NBA 2K26, Logitech PC Gaming Accessories, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-october-25-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-nba-2k26-logitech-pc-gaming-accessories-and-more.1334905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Make every day game day.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">We've rounded up the best deals for Saturday, October 25, below, so don't miss out on these limited-time offers.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">NBA 2K26 for $49.94</h2><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229883"><div id="229883" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>NBA 2K26 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">NBA 2K26 is on sale this weekend for $49.94, just in time for the start of the NBA season. Play kicked off this week with the OKC Thunder and Houston Rockets, and if you haven't yet picked up 2K26, this deal can make every day game day. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nba-2k26-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, “Ball Over Everything” is a fitting description for NBA 2K26. The smooth on-court action is better than ever and MyCareer’s excellent started-from-the-bottom journey to the pros story make it so the imperfections are easier to ignore."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save on Xbox Ally X</h2></div><div catalogid="8d82a57c-a009-4132-a2ac-784cb66e516e" id="229852"><div id="229852" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Open Box, Excellent Condition</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>ROG Xbox Ally X</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Best Buy has open box models of the ROG Xbox Ally X already on sale, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-xbox-ally-x-drops-in-price-for-the-first-time-when-you-buy-slightly-used">allowing you to save</a> on this brand new device. The Xbox Ally X is an excellent choice if you're looking to take your Xbox experience with you wherever you go, as you can instantly access your library and Xbox Game Pass with the press of a button.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Madden NFL 26 for $49.94</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229884"><div id="229884" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Madden NFL 26 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">PlayStation 5 copies of Madden NFL 26 are available for $49.94 this weekend at Amazon. This latest entry brings new updates that make a noticeable difference, particularly when compared to entries of the last few years. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/madden-nfl-26-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, "There’s always room for improvement, but it’s hard to overstate what a leap Madden NFL 26 feels like both on and off the field."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Apple AirTag 4-Pack for $64.99</h2></div><div catalogid="07bae54a-386a-4ab0-8871-973d4758734d" id="229431"><div id="229431" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Apple AirTag 4 Pack</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Apple AirTags are some of the best products out there for numerous reasons. While they aren't necessarily exciting, AirTags can make your life so much easier. Throw one in your luggage, backpack, or even Nintendo Switch 2 case for easy tracking.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Logitech G502 Gaming Mouse for $37.99</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229885"><div id="229885" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Logitech G502 HERO High Performance Wired Gaming Mouse</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Logitech G502 Gaming Mouse has been around for a long while, but it's still one my <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-gaming-mouse">favorite gaming mice</a> on the market. Some of its best features include a Hero 25K sensor, an adjustable weight system, mechanical switch button tensioning, and a total of 11 customizable buttons. This is an amazing mouse for competitive games, single player games, and even just daily web browsing.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save 50% Off the Anker SOLIX C1000 Gen 2 Power Station</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229887"><div id="229887" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Anker SOLIX C1000 Gen 2 Portable Power Station</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">There is nothing worse than losing power due to a storm or outage at a critical moment. A full backup generator can be very expensive to install, but Anker has a portable solution on sale this weekend for $397.99. The SOLIX C1000 Gen 2 Power Station has a 2,000W power output, which is perfect to set up as a UPS. With 100% battery available in under one hour of charging, this can be a game-changing device to your home.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Logitech G515 Lightspeed Gaming Keyboard for $109.99</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229886"><div id="229886" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Logitech G515 Lightspeed TKL Low Profile Wireless Gaming Keyboard</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This weekend, you can score the Logitech G515 Lightspeed Gaming Keyboard for $109.99 - that's 31% off the MSRP! This TKL keyboard is quite slim, making it fit into any setup with ease. The Red Linear switches with double-shot PBT caps offer durability and performance, with a 1.3mm actuation distance.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 25, 2025 3:00 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-october-25-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6's battle royale "Battlefield: RedSec" could shadowdrop as soon as next week, dataminers claim]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6s-battle-royale-battlefield-redsec-could-shadowdrop-as-soon-as-next-week-dataminers-claim</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6s-battle-royale-battlefield-redsec-could-shadowdrop-as-soon-as-next-week-dataminers-claim.1334902/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>The content is reportedly codenamed "Granite" and is separate from the known Season One content dropping next week.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-best-guns-hero.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA / Battlefield Studios.</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a>'s battle royale mode could release as soon as next week.</p>
<p>Parts of Battlefield 6's Battle Royale map - complete with all its points of interest (POIs), big and small - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-leaks-keep-on-coming-this-time-its-the-battle-royale-map">leaked over the summer</a>, but now a new content drop discovered by dataminers is also set to shadowdrop alongside Season One on 28th October. According to the leak, this content is codenamed "Granite" and "is NOT Season One" content we already know about.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Battlefield 6 Season 1 Official Gameplay Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Umw-SKuh0LY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Battlefield 6 Season 1 Official Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Umw-SKuh0LY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Umw-SKuh0LY?autoplay=1" title="Battlefield 6 Season 1 Official Gameplay Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption> Check out the Battlefield 6 season 1 trailer here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Umw-SKuh0LY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Neither EA nor Battlefield Studios has yet committed to a release date for the highly anticipated mode, but the teams did previously say that preparation for the shooter's seasonal content would be "starting" with "an exciting new Battlefield take on Battle Royale", suggesting we'll get it sooner rather than later.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Battlefield and Call of Duty X/Twitter account ModernWarzone shared the news on social media, saying: "Think it’s safe to say this is the BF6 Battle Royale."</p>
<p>The datamined code itself isn't quite convincing everyone, but the dataminers are certain this will be a "full on shadowdrop", even believing they've discovered the name for it: Battlefield: RedSec.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>EXCLUSIVE: The F2P Battlefield 6 battle royale is officially named “Battlefield: RedSec”.</p><p>Releasing October 28th as previously reported, however it looks like there won’t be any trailers or official announcements until the 28th itself instead of a day before.</p><p>Full on shadowdrop <a href="https://t.co/blP6NQR3jW">pic.twitter.com/blP6NQR3jW</a></p></div>— ModernWarzone (@ModernWarzone) <a href="https://twitter.com/ModernWarzone/status/1981741907387523203?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 24, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-finally-has-its-season-one-trailer-showing-new-weapons-maps-and-a-tactical-game-mode">Season One of Battlefield 6 is set to go live on 28th October</a>. EA and Battlefield Studios recently released a trailer for the first season of post-launch content, including a peek at the massive Blackwell Fields map and new game mode, Strikepoint. It's split into three stages in total, the first being dubbed "Rogue Ops" which we'll experience next Tuesday.</p><p>This marks the first major update for Battlefield 6, following a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/missing-shots-in-battlefield-6-well-you-might-not-be-bad-a-bug-might-be-throwing-your-shots-off">series of smaller bug fixes</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-developers-u-turn-on-a-multiplayer-adjustment-following-community-feedback">balance adjustments</a>. The game has proven exceptionally popular, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-confirms-battlefield-6-is-best-selling-entry-in-the-series-7m-copies-sold-172m-online-matches">selling over seven million copies in less than a week and quickly breaking series records</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6s-battle-royale-battlefield-redsec-could-shadowdrop-as-soon-as-next-week-dataminers-claim]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fire Emblem Shadows Gets A Free Update Adding New Story, Map And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/fire-emblem-shadows-gets-a-free-update-adding-new-story-map-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fire-emblem-shadows-gets-a-free-update-adding-new-story-map-and-more.1334887/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Play through 'Book 2 episodes 1-4' today</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>In case you missed it, Nintendo shadow-dropped the new mobile game <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/fire_emblem_shadows">Fire Emblem Shadows</a> in September. If you haven't given this free-to-play title a go just yet, now might be the time to take a look.</p>
<p>A new story "and more" has been added in a free update. Book 2 - Wolf Brother adds episodes 1-4. You can unlock the chapters by collecting Story Fragments earned as battle rewards. You'll also need to complete Book 1 before you can dive into this new content featuring the character Joachim.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Unsettling footsteps approach a small, impoverished village quietly tucked away deep in the mountains…A kind boy from a cold village in the northern mountains who rarely seeks conflict. He's a descendant of wolves from the bloodline of Fenris. You can unlock him by battling and collecting Book 2 Story Fragments."</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<figure data-uuid="14fdc36e8f140"><a title="Fire Emblem Shadows" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/14fdc36e8f140/fire-emblem-shadows.large.png"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Along with this, there's also a new labyrinth map, and new weapons and skills have been added as treasure rewards.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The feature rewards this time are Soul items for Lyn: Plain Wind. Collect 12 of these to recruit Lyn as one of your disciples."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Additionally, the current Season Pass will end on 27th October. You can find out more about this <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/surprise-a-new-free-to-start-fire-emblem-game-is-out-on-mobile-devices-today">in our previous story</a>. And if you want to know more about this strategy and social deduction title, check out our full review here on Nintendo Life:</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-mobile/related-articles:188387,188374 @ 1761424337 -->
<p>Have you tried out this game on your mobile device yet? How are you finding it so far? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/the-fire-emblem-shadows-story-continues-in-a-free-update-with-book-2/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/the-fire-emblem-shadows-story-continues-in-a-free-update-with-book-2/">nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-mobile/related-info/3d5b551bd4887cefd1fc80b96c48a61e @ 1761426273 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/fire-emblem-shadows-gets-a-free-update-adding-new-story-map-and-more]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After EA's buyout and creator exodus, The Sims team wants you to know their "values and commitment remain the same"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/after-eas-buyout-and-creator-exodus-the-sims-team-wants-you-to-know-their-values-and-commitment-remain-the-same</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-eas-buyout-and-creator-exodus-the-sims-team-wants-you-to-know-their-values-and-commitment-remain-the-same.1334884/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"The Sims will always be a space where you can express your authentic self."</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-4-modern-luxe-kit.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-4-modern-luxe-kit.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-4-modern-luxe-kit.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-4-modern-luxe-kit.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-4-modern-luxe-kit.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-4-modern-luxe-kit.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-4-modern-luxe-kit.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-4-modern-luxe-kit.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-4-modern-luxe-kit.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA Maxis</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Last month, something a bit surprising, and perhaps concerning, took place in the games industry: a deal was made which saw that a mixture of Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund, equity firm Silver Lake, and Donald Trump's son-in-law Jared Kushner's Affinity Partners had privately acquired EA. There's a whole host of reasons why this is worrisome, but one reason in particular is the way that it might affect <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-sims-4">The Sims</a>.
</p>
<p>
While it isn't exactly a paragon of identity politics, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/video-game-franchises/the-sims">The Sims</a> has by and large been a game that welcomes and encourages people of all creeds, notably LGBTQIA+ folks. It is probably safe to assume that these new owners, however, will not be so welcoming. In fact, concern has been so great over this acquisition that the biggest Sims YouTuber around lilsimsie has <a href="http://youtube.com/post/UgkxPVv5K6a9ZXkFzbLrta3DlHckpC8A9OF6?si=sglHvJEekR-fr1md">left EA's Creator Network</a>, having been joined by other big Sims YouTubers like <a href="http://youtube.com/post/Ugkxe7pZtIiCBZpCErpuc1fqI3k41pAsna53?si=OTATMfwD8usqaILA">Plumbella</a> and <a href="http://youtube.com/post/UgkxGxA76frKUAO6anFj84Ijhqkc4m-jlznc?si=4KaoEumB9X0jgD7u">James Turner</a>.
</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
In turn, a message has now been shared by The Sims team on its official Dwitter account seemingly attempting to assuage some of the above concerns, though it has been delivered in a bit of a vague tone. "We're continually inspired by our incredible players and creators; by your imagination, creativity, and the joy you bring to The Sims every day," reads the statement.
</p>
<p>
"We deeply respect that everyone experiences The Sims in their own way and will make choices that are right for them. However you choose to play, create, or share, we’re grateful to be part of your journey. Our mission, values, and commitment remain the same. The Sims will always be a space where you can express your authentic self."
</p><p>
The statement carries on with an even vaguer bit about how everyone's "passion and voices" have affected bits to come in 2026, and that on November 4th there'll be a new update coming to The Sims with "150+ fixes and fresh freebies." Notably, this update is "the first of ongoing updates that address the things that matter most to you," though personally this feels slightly disconnected from the main message and is more addressed at those who are frustrated with how broken the game often can be.
</p>
<p>
This is all well and good for now, it's just still a bit too early to tell what kind of effects this acquisition will have. For now let's all just cross our fingers for the future of any staff members currently working at EA.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/after-eas-buyout-and-creator-exodus-the-sims-team-wants-you-to-know-their-values-and-commitment-remain-the-same]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long-time Microsoft-exclusive Halo is coming to PS5 for the very first time: "This is Halo for everyone"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-mascot-and-long-time-microsoft-exclusive-halo-is-coming-to-ps5-for-the-very-first-time-this-is-halo-for-everyone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/long-time-microsoft-exclusive-halo-is-coming-to-ps5-for-the-very-first-time-this-is-halo-for-everyone.1334878/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HaloCE_Wallpaper_Desktop-4K_3840x2160_RGB-d4e38f6e57db5ab9a7e2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HaloCE_Wallpaper_Desktop-4K_3840x2160_RGB-d4e38f6e57db5ab9a7e2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HaloCE_Wallpaper_Desktop-4K_3840x2160_RGB-d4e38f6e57db5ab9a7e2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HaloCE_Wallpaper_Desktop-4K_3840x2160_RGB-d4e38f6e57db5ab9a7e2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HaloCE_Wallpaper_Desktop-4K_3840x2160_RGB-d4e38f6e57db5ab9a7e2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HaloCE_Wallpaper_Desktop-4K_3840x2160_RGB-d4e38f6e57db5ab9a7e2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HaloCE_Wallpaper_Desktop-4K_3840x2160_RGB-d4e38f6e57db5ab9a7e2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HaloCE_Wallpaper_Desktop-4K_3840x2160_RGB-d4e38f6e57db5ab9a7e2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HaloCE_Wallpaper_Desktop-4K_3840x2160_RGB-d4e38f6e57db5ab9a7e2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Microsoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The Halo series is coming to PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>In a new demo debuted at the Halo World Championship, Microsoft has revealed Halo: Campaign Evolved – described as "a faithful yet modernised remake of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/halo-combat-evolved">Halo: Combat Evolved</a>'s campaign" – is coming to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S next year.</p>
<p>The remake has been "rebuilt from the ground up" on Unreal Engine 5, and will include high-definition visuals, refined controls, two-player splitscreen co-op on console, up to four-player online co-op on console and PC, three new missions, an expanded arsenal of weapons, vehicles, new enemies, and more. It will be playable "day one" with Game Pass.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Halo: Campaign Evolved | The Silent Cartographer – 13 Minute Gameplay Demo" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hSjbIM0iegY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Halo: Campaign Evolved | The Silent Cartographer – 13 Minute Gameplay Demo</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hSjbIM0iegY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/hSjbIM0iegY?autoplay=1" title="Halo: Campaign Evolved | The Silent Cartographer – 13 Minute Gameplay Demo">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption> Halo: Campaign Evolved | The Silent Cartographer – 13 Minute Gameplay Demo.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hSjbIM0iegY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>For those unfamiliar with the seminal shooter, the Halo story kicks off after the Master Chief crash-lands on a mysterious ringworld known as Halo, working alongside remaining humans to help humanity survive against overwhelming Covenant forces. Alongside his AI companion Cortana, he uncovers Halo’s dark secrets and fights to avert the annihilation of all life in the galaxy.</p><p>"We wanted to start where it all began, with the original campaign that defined Halo," executive producer Damon Conn <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/10/24/halo-campaign-evolved-answering-the-big-questions/">said</a>. "Starting here means people that have never played the game before will be able to understand the story from the very beginning, and that can help us chart a course forward with new Halo stories."</p>
<p>"Focusing on the campaign experience means we can concentrate fully on really capturing the atmosphere, tone - the emotional impact of what made the first campaign so special and iconic."</p>
<p>In Halo: Campaign Evolved, you'll be able to wield nine additional "iconic" weapons from across the Halo series inside the Halo: Combat Evolved campaign, including the Energy Sword, Battle Rifle and Needle Rifle, as well as hijack vehicles and even pilot the Covenant Wraith tank – two firsts for the Halo campaign.</p>
<p>That's not the only big change, either.</p>
<p>"We learned from Halo: Combat Evolved Anniversary that there was still an appetite for things like better wayfinding, navigation, and diversity in enemy encounters," director Max Szlagor added. "In The Library specifically, which features several Flood encounters, we wanted to reevaluate the pacing and enhance the environmental storytelling. We've added new lines to Guilty Spark, which guide players through the level, and there's new dialogue that gives more insight into the narrative as it plays out."</p><p>"We're so excited about bringing Halo to those who may not have had chance to play it in the past," Conn added. "At its heart, Halo is about connection, we're thrilled to meet a new generation of players on their platforms of choice to fall in love with Halo the same way we did. We're not trying to rewrite Halo's legacy - we're trying to immerse you in it like never before.</p>
<p>"This is Halo for everyone."</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-mascot-and-long-time-microsoft-exclusive-halo-is-coming-to-ps5-for-the-very-first-time-this-is-halo-for-everyone]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What does nearly $6,000 of gaming laptop get you?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/806052/msi-titan-18-ai-rtx-5090-gaming-laptop-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-does-nearly-6-000-of-gaming-laptop-get-you.1334872/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>It’s easy to get into the weeds on a hobby, especially if you’re into PC gaming and dreaming of the highest levels of graphical performance. But how much is too much for hardware? Spending top dollar on graphics power, processing, RAM, storage, etc. — like many things — eventually leads to diminishing returns. When it comes to gaming laptops, MSI’s $5,699.99 Titan 18 is well beyond that inflection point. But it’s also like nothing else.</p><p>It’s not very logical to spend that much when other excellent gaming laptops are nearly as powerful but cost almost half as much. While the Titan is an absolutely reckless purchase, it’s also a joyous one that goes all out for specs and wide-eyed coolness factor.</p><div data-product-filter="" id="product-card-dmcyOnByb2R1Y3Q6ODA2MDc3"><p><span>$<!-- -->4800</span></p><div><div><h4>The Good</h4><ul><li>Top-tier gaming performance in a laptop</li><li>Massive, bright 4K Mini LED screen</li><li>Loud but satisfying mechanical keyboard</li></ul></div><div><h4>The Bad</h4><ul><li>As good as it is, it doesn’t blow away a much cheaper 5080 laptop</li><li>Astronomically expensive</li><li>Battery drains after just a couple hours of everyday tasks</li><li>120Hz refresh is half the speed of cheaper laptops with 2.5K OLEDs</li></ul></div></div></div><p>The Titan goes hard on just about everything, though execution is a mixed bag. The 18-inch Mini LED 4K HDR display has a resolution of 3840 x 2400 and a variable refresh rate up to 120Hz. It looks fantastic. It’s not as contrast-y as an OLED, but it has a colorful punch with enough brightness to be easily visible in even a sun-drenched room. SteelSeries made its mechanical keyboard with Cherry low-profile switches, and it’s one of the most tactile and <em>loudest </em>laptop keyboards I’ve ever touched. It’s got a ping-y metallic undertone in its key presses, which I normally don’t want in a mechanical keyboard, but for some reason I love it in the Titan.</p><div><div><p id="component-report-card"><h2>Component report card</h2></p></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>Screen:</strong> A</span></li><li><span><strong>Webcam:</strong> C</span></li><li><span><strong>Mic:</strong> C</span></li><li><span><strong>Keyboard:</strong> B</span></li><li><span><strong>Trackpad:</strong> C</span></li><li><span><strong>Port selection:</strong> A</span></li><li><span><strong>Speakers:</strong> C</span></li><li><span><strong>Number of ugly stickers to remove:</strong> 4 (one underneath)</span></li></ul></div></div><p>The seamless trackpad is edge-to-edge illuminated by customizable RGB lighting instead of being invisible like on a Dell, and its haptic feedback has a satisfyingly hefty knock that’s unlike any other. But like the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/611176/dell-xps-13-laptop-review-9350-intel-lunar-lake">Dell XPS 13</a> I tested earlier this year, it’s not the most reliable at detecting finger clicks. If it had this feedback combined with the reliability of a MacBook’s trackpad, it would be my all-time favorite. And the Titan is flush with ports and expandability, including two super-fast Thunderbolt 5 ports, three USB-A, two user-accessible RAM slots, and <em>four </em>M.2 SSD slots. Cap off the Titan’s specs with its top-tier Nvidia RTX 5090 laptop GPU, Intel Core Ultra 9 285HX CPU, 64GB of RAM, and 6TB of SSD storage, and the lofty $5,700 price starts making more sense.</p><p>The Titan 18 is unapologetic about its status as a desktop replacement. It’s 7.94 pounds / 3.6kg of “you paid out the nose for me to sit in one spot and crush AAA games or churn through processing-heavy tasks, and that’s what I’ll do.” And with its massive 400W power adapter, the whole package weighs 10.5 pounds / 4.76kg. I lugged it with me on a road trip, and having a machine this powerful when visiting family was awesome — even if traveling with it wasn’t so fun, since it didn’t fit in any of my bags. While it’s easier than moving a full desktop PC and monitor, you’ll feel just as tethered to a wall plug. The Titan’s 99Whr battery can barely eke out 2.5 hours of basic Chrome, Slack, Google Docs, and chat app usage before it’s drained — and that’s in Eco mode with Windows Energy Saver turned on the whole time. While playing a game on battery, even with Nvidia’s BatteryBoost optimizations enabled and targeting just 30fps, it dies in about an hour or less.</p><div id=":R4gbcrij96:"><div><div><p><figcaption><em>The Titan is maximum gaming laptop, from the design to the light-up dragon.</em></figcaption></p></div><div><p><figcaption><em>Ports on the rear include a proprietary power connector, HDMI 2.1, and ethernet.</em></figcaption></p></div></div><div><div><p><figcaption><em>On the right, two Thunderbolt 5, one USB-A, and a 3.5mm audio jack.</em></figcaption></p></div><div><p><figcaption><em>And on the left, two more USB-A and a speedy SD card slot.</em></figcaption></p></div></div></div><p>But when you’re plugged in and going full-tilt on a visually demanding game, the Titan is a joy to use. It can play <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> at Ultra settings in 4K with ray tracing and DLSS 4 turned on at around 60 frames per second (or higher with frame generation). Turn ray tracing off or some settings down, and you can comfortably play at well over 60fps. Early levels of the <em>Battlefield 6</em> campaign ran confidently at 60–75fps on the Ultra graphics preset and at the panel’s native 4K resolution. There were infrequent dips into the mid-to-high 50s during chaotic moments in larger areas, but everything remained smooth and snappy. If you want to push frame rates to the Titan’s max 120Hz refresh or even slightly higher, you can bump the resolution down to 2560 x 1600, and it still looks adequately crisp. But keeping the game in 4K Ultra and turning on DLSS 4 Quality yielded a happy medium of 90 to 100fps, while adding single-frame generation comfortably boosted it to 120 to 140fps.</p><div><table><thead><tr><th><h3>System</h3></th><th><h3>MSI Titan 18 / RTX 5090 / Core Ultra 9 285HX / 64GB / 6TB</h3></th><th><h3>Asus ROG Strix Scar 16 / RTX 5080 / Core Ultra 9 275HX / 32GB / 2TB</h3></th><th><h3>Razer Blade 16 (2025) / RTX 5090 / Ryzen AI 9 HX 370 / 32GB / 2TB</h3></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Geekbench 6 CPU Single</td><td>3054</td><td>3113</td><td>2968</td></tr><tr><td>Geekbench 6 CPU Multi</td><td>21957</td><td>19709</td><td>15922</td></tr><tr><td>Geekbench 6 GPU (OpenCL)</td><td>234632</td><td>200189</td><td>213016</td></tr><tr><td>Cinebench 2024 Single</td><td>133</td><td>137</td><td>119</td></tr><tr><td>Cinebench 2024 Multi</td><td>2173</td><td>1965</td><td>1287</td></tr><tr><td>PugetBench for Photoshop</td><td>8037</td><td>8482</td><td>8679</td></tr><tr><td>Sustained SSD reads (MB/s)</td><td>14516.67</td><td>6832.06</td><td>6726.25</td></tr><tr><td>Sustained SSD writes (MB/s)</td><td>9194.8</td><td>6550.21</td><td>4931.41</td></tr><tr><td>3DMark Time Spy</td><td>24897</td><td>20977</td><td>22498</td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>Fan noise, while loud, isn’t as bad as some <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/658137/gigabyte-aorus-master-16-gaming-laptop-rtx-5080-review">16-inch gaming laptops I’ve tested</a>. The Titan’s large chassis allows for more effective cooling under load, pumping out lots of hot air from its flanks. The keyboard deck near the laptop’s hinge gets incredibly hot to the touch, but thankfully, your fingers on the WASD keys are spared. The width of the chassis also means the six-speaker sound system can help a tiny bit in identifying directional game sounds like gunfire. Though the speakers are sadly just okay for movies and music, lacking depth and much low-end.</p><section tabindex="-1" aria-label="carousel"><p><strong>1<!-- -->/<!-- -->7</strong><span><figcaption><em>The illuminated trackpad is especially fun, though unfortunately underwhelming in performance.</em></figcaption></span></p></section><p>There are two elephants in the room with the Titan: the looming temptation of a proper desktop gaming PC and the class of 16- and 18-inch gaming laptops with RTX 5080 GPUs that sit below it. You can get a much more powerful desktop PC for half the Titan’s price, add a 240Hz QD-OLED monitor, and <em>still</em> have enough money left over for an M5 MacBook Pro or even an Asus ROG Zephyrus G14. But let’s be honest, if you’re considering an 18-inch, 8-pound gaming laptop, you’re probably moving it around enough that this combo won’t work. But in that case, you could save around $2,400 on a gaming laptop with a 5080 like the <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fshop.asus.com%2Fus%2F90nr0ld1-m005n0-rog-strix-scar-16-2025.html" rel="sponsored">Asus ROG Strix Scar 16</a> and get, on average, within 7 to 10fps of the Titan’s performance.</p><p>Running benchmarks on the Titan’s RTX 5090, which runs at its full wattage, I was struck by how close 5080 laptops were nipping at its heels. For $2,100 to $2,400 more than an Asus ROG Strix Scar 16 or Lenovo Legion Pro 7i, the Titan only yields an extra 7fps on average in 4K or about 9fps more in 2.5K. The screens on those laptops are a little smaller and lower-res than the Titan, but they have lovely 240Hz OLED displays with deeper blacks, bolder colors, and a stronger contrast. As much as I love the size and brightness of the Titan’s Mini LED, I prefer the look of those OLEDs. Even the 5090-equipped Razer Blade 16 and 18, pricey machines in their own right, cost $1,000 less than the Titan. The half-inch-thinner, 3-pound-lighter <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/649577/razer-blade-16-2025-rtx-5090-review">Blade 16</a> is much more versatile and travel-friendly, and its performance is mostly on par with the Titan. Though the Titan has a higher-end CPU (with twice as many cores), greater cooling (for quieter fans), user-accessible RAM slots (though <a href="https://youtu.be/z2c_oGk-eIU?si=ptk1zSNzTl3xwNT6&amp;t=681">not <em>easily </em>accessible</a>), faster Thunderbolt 5 ports, and two more M.2 SSD slots.</p><div><p><figcaption><em>In case you were wondering, the Titan 18 is gargantuan enough to eat smaller gaming laptops like the Asus ROG Zephyrus G14.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>The sickos who pony up for the Titan are still getting a machine that isn’t quite like anything else. It’s an illogical purchase, far from any semblance of pragmatism or value-for-dollar shopping — even if you’re aiming for a little futureproofing. But despite its shortcomings and super high price, it’s still a beastly laptop with its own boisterous charm.</p><div><div><p id="SFV5mq"><h2>2025 MSI Titan 18 HX AI A2XWJG specs (as reviewed)</h2></p></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>Display: </strong>18-inch (3840 x 2400) 120Hz Mini LED</span></li><li><span><strong>CPU:</strong> Intel Core Ultra 9 285HX</span></li><li><span><strong>GPU:</strong> Nvidia GeForce RTX 5090 Laptop GPU</span></li><li><span><strong>RAM:</strong> 64GB DDR5 6400MHz (user-replaceable)</span></li><li><span><strong>Storage:</strong> 6TB across 3x SSDs in RAID 0; 1x PCIe Gen 5 NVMe and 3x Gen 4 slots (one slot is empty)</span></li><li><span><strong>Webcam:</strong> 1080p 30fps, Windows Hello</span></li><li><span><strong>Connectivity:</strong> Wi-Fi 7, Bluetooth 5.4</span></li><li><span><strong>Ports:</strong> 2x Thunderbolt 5 USB-C (DisplayPort / Power Delivery 3.1), 3x USB-A 3.2 Gen 2, HDMI 2.1, RJ-45 ethernet, full-size SD Express card slot, 3.5mm combo audio jack, reversible DC power</span></li><li><span><strong>Weight:</strong> 7.94 pounds / 3.6kg</span></li><li><span><strong>Dimensions:</strong> 15.91 x 12.11 x 0.94 - 1.26 inches / 404 x 307.5 x 24 - 32.05mm</span></li><li><span><strong>Battery:</strong> 99Wh</span></li><li><span><strong>Price:</strong> $5,699.99</span></li></ul></div></div><p><em>Photography by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</em></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6NDQ2"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/806052/msi-titan-18-ai-rtx-5090-gaming-laptop-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Book Review: Metroid Prime 1-3: A Visual Retrospective - Stunning Art, Though Lacking Context]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/book-review-metroid-prime-1-3-a-visual-retrospective-stunning-art-though-lacking-context</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/book-review-metroid-prime-1-3-a-visual-retrospective-stunning-art-though-lacking-context.1334860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="352fea995ebc8"><a title="Metroid Prime Art Book 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/352fea995ebc8/metroid-prime-art-book-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Ollie Reynolds / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>It often feels like <strong>Metroid</strong> fans are starved for new goodies these days; doubly so for fans of Retro Studios’ Prime series. Yet just over a month before the highly anticipated fourth mainline entry for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_4_beyond">Switch</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Switch 2</a>, you can get your hands on an absolutely <em>stunning</em> hardback art book from Piggyback covering the first three Metroid Prime games – plus a little extra for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_remastered">Prime Remastered</a>.</p>
<p>Ripping the shrink wrap off the book, it’s immediately clear just how premium <strong>Metroid Prime 1-3: A Visual Retrospective</strong> really is. Clocking in at 212 pages, the minimal black fabric cover displays little more than an outline of Samus on the front, the main Metroid logo on the back, and the book’s title on the spine. These elements shine red when angled in the light and it looks very elegant in person.</p><div><figure data-videoid="FsuAt4uVyTk" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FsuAt4uVyTk?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FsuAt4uVyTk?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FsuAt4uVyTk?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed4022bdxqojnr&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>837k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>My only concern with the cover is that it does pick up minor marks and smudges when handled for longer periods. They rub away easily enough, but it’s something to keep in mind.</p>

<p>Diving into the book itself, it starts off with a relatively short foreword from series producer Kensuke Tanabe going over his introduction to Retro Studios and how the team leveraged its talent to create such incredible games. Every title is then covered in release order with an introductory write-up from Retro Studios for each (though which specific individual, exactly, is undisclosed).</p>
<p>Peppered throughout are further remarks from Tanabe; short anecdotes on how he and Retro Studios worked together on specific mechanics and designs. A lot of it is pretty well-known, but there are definitely a few little tidbits that came as a surprise. Did you know that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/metroid-prime-remastered-almost-had-completely-new-cutscenes">Prime Remastered almost had completely brand new cutscenes</a>, for example? Well, now you do.</p>
<p>In addition to Tanabe’s writing, other breakout boxes essentially replicate text from the in-game Scan Visor logs, and as someone who knows the Prime games inside out, I felt somewhat disappointed that Nintendo and Piggyback went in this direction. These kinds of write-ups work fine in the game itself, but I don’t need to read about how Sheegoth has a vulnerable underbelly (wink-wink, use the Morph Ball Bomb) in an art book. Tell me about the design process!</p>

<p>This is a pretty glaring issue throughout the entire book. While I certainly appreciated Tanabe’s insights, I feel a lot more could have been provided by Retro Studios itself. What was the initial approach in creating <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/metroid_prime_2_echoes">Prime 2</a>'s Luminoth? Why go with <em>this</em> design instead of <em>that</em> one? What kind of challenges were overcome?</p>
<p>As I gazed in wonder at the incredible concept art, multiple questions arose in my mind about the development process involved; unfortunately, most simply went unanswered. It’s important to acknowledge that many devs who worked on the trilogy — including art director Todd Keller — are no longer at Retro, so I can understand why they weren’t directly involved.</p>
<p>As for the artwork itself, well, it's outstanding. This is an extensive dive into the Metroid Prime Trilogy and showcases almost every major aspect of the games, including Samus’ suits, her ship, enemies, bosses, environments, and more.</p>
<p>It’s a <em>lot</em>, and it’s a real treat for fans of the series. I particularly enjoyed looking at some of the alternative designs for the Space Pirate enemies, which seemingly took on a more emaciated appearance compared to the final in-game models.</p>

<p>Naturally, without <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/metroid_prime_hunters">Metroid Prime: Hunters</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/metroid_prime_pinball">Pinball</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/metroid_prime_federation_force">Federation Force</a>, you could argue that this isn't quite as 'complete' as some would like. Indeed, one of the most obvious omissions is <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/metroid-prime-4-beyond-who-is-sylux">Sylux</a>, the shadowy antagonist who really only appears properly in Hunters and Federation Force. Their ship, however, <em>does</em> crop up at the end of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/metroid_prime_3_corruption">Metroid Prime 3: Corruption</a>, but even this isn't present here. It's an odd choice given the character's prominent presence in the marketing for Metroid Prime 4: Beyond.</p>
<p>Speaking of Beyond, I had hoped that there might be a small nod to the upcoming sequel in the book, and while there are hints toward it in Tanabe's notes (<em>"Retro and our team at Nintendo will keep working together to the best of our ability to bring new stories for fans to enjoy!"</em>), there are no visual references. This was perhaps a bit optimistic on my part, and my hope is that there might be another book in the future dedicated to the long, storied development of Prime 4.</p>
<p>Despite my concerns and disappointments, Metroid Prime 1-3: A Visual Retrospective is a lovely book that Prime fans will absolutely devour – I sure did. It's the kind of visual feast you'll want to just dive into again and again at a moment's notice, so you can bet it will take pride a place on my coffee table for the foreseeable future.</p>
<figure data-uuid="1032fcc67f8e4"><a title="Metroid Prime Art Book 11" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1032fcc67f8e4/metroid-prime-art-book-11.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Ollie Reynolds / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<hr>
<p><em>Thanks to Nintendo of America and Piggyback for sending the sample used in this review. The book launches on <strong>28th October 2025</strong> for <strong>£39.99 / $49.99</strong>.</em></p>
<p>Please note that some external links on this page are affiliate links, which means if you click them and make a purchase we may receive a small percentage of the sale. Please read our <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/advertising">FTC Disclosure</a> for more information.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/metroid/related-articles:192794,192886 @ 1761426150 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/book-review-metroid-prime-1-3-a-visual-retrospective-stunning-art-though-lacking-context]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twitch CEO admits it "failed" after TwitchCon streamer assault, "both in allowing it to occur, and in our response"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/twitch-ceo-admits-it-failed-after-twitchcon-streamer-assault-both-in-allowing-it-to-occur-and-in-our-response</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/twitch-ceo-admits-it-failed-after-twitchcon-streamer-assault-both-in-allowing-it-to-occur-and-in-our-response.1334854/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content" data-component="article-header">
        

        <p>"We mismanaged our communications about the incident, and that includes the comments I made."</p>

    </div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/twitch">Twitch</a> CEO Dan Clancy has admitted the company "failed" by both allowing streamer Emiru to be physically assaulted at TwitchCon last weekend, and "in our response following".</p>
<p>Last weekend, streamer<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/streamer-assaulted-at-twitchcon-slams-event-security-i-think-other-creators-should-seriously-consider-not-attending-in-the-future"> Emiru was assaulted at a TwitchCon Meet and Greet after a man crossed multiple barriers to grab her face and try to kiss her</a>. A viral video that caught the incident suggests TwitchCon's own staff did not prevent the incident from occurring, nor "came to ask what happened or if I was okay" in the immediate aftermath.</p>
<p>In Twitch's initial response, it said "the safety and security of all those attending TwitchCon is our highest priority", and called the behaviour of the man who pushed past the queue to grab Emiru and kiss her "completely unacceptable and deeply upsetting". It then revealed it had "blocked this individual from returning to the TwitchCon premises, and they are banned indefinitely from Twitch, both online and in-person events".</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>hello everyone, I am okay and thank you for all of the kind messages, sorry I cannot respond to them all 🩷</p><p>Yesterday, the man who assaulted me was allowed to cross multiple barriers at twitchcon and even in front of another creators meet and greet to grab me and my face and try…</p></div>— emi ⭐️ (@emiru) <a href="https://twitter.com/emiru/status/1979602519967060414?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 18, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Emiru disputed this version of events, however, saying, "Twitch's statement they said that the guy was immediately caught and detained [was] a blatant lie".</p>
<p>"He was allowed to walk away from my Meet and Greet, and I didn't hear he was caught until hours after he attacked me, and it felt like this only happened because of my manager pressing for it, not because TwitchCon staff present thought it was a big deal," she added, later confirming she was pressing charges.</p>
<p>In the days following the incident, Clancy was criticised for a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/twitch-ceo-dan-clancy-responds-to-emiru-twitchcon-assault-says-its-a-challenge-in-todays-society-and-not-limited-to-twitc">video interview</a> in which he said, "the challenge we face is a challenge in today’s society. It’s not limited to Twitch, it extends throughout our society.</p>
<p>"Now, what happened yesterday, obviously, was something that we care deeply about securing this environment. We're looking very closely at everything that happened there, and I care deeply about Emi," he added. "She's a friend of mine, and so I want to see how we can support her. This is just something we have to keep working on. I think everyone identifies our tools in terms of trust and safety as the leaders in the industry about helping creators, but that means there's always more work to be done, because that's the world we live in now."</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">First, I want to be upfront and take accountability for the security incident that occurred during Emiru’s Meet and Greet. It shouldn’t have happened and we take that very seriously. We failed, both in allowing it to occur, and in our response following. We mismanaged our…</p>— Twitch (@Twitch) <a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch/status/1981825064904667169?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 24, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Now, in a fresh statement, Clancy said he "want[s] to be upfront and take accountability for the security incident that occurred during Emiru's Meet and Greet", saying, "it shouldn't have happened and we take that very seriously".</p>
<p>"We failed, both in allowing it to occur, and in our response following. We mismanaged our communications about the incident, and that includes the comments I made. I apologise to Emiru for all that took place."</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Twitch is now investigating "everything" about how they run Meet and Greets, "from sign-ups to the layout to increased security controls". This includes a review of its teams, production and venue staff, so it is "better equipped" for future events".</p><p>"We're also doing a comprehensive review of overall event safety and security, and will be making updates for future TwitchCons," he added. "While we won't be sharing all security updates for privacy and safety reasons, we will keep our community informed about changes that directly impact attendees.</p>
<p>"You put a lot of trust in us by attending TwitchCon, and we take our responsibility to keep you safe seriously," the statement concludes. "We know that TwitchCon means a lot to a lot of people, and it means a lot to us. Be on the lookout for more updates, and thanks for being a part of Twitch."</p>
<p>Clancy said the company has also "hard concerns about IRL" streaming, and though he didn't expand on what those concerns were, added that the IRL category was now "a part of Twitch" and "TwitchCon [should ensure it] meets the needs of a variety of participants". More will be revealed "soon".</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/twitch-ceo-admits-it-failed-after-twitchcon-streamer-assault-both-in-allowing-it-to-occur-and-in-our-response]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ball x Pit is a deep, delightful rabbit hole]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/805022/ball-x-pit-review-pc-nintendo-switch-ps5-xbox-series-x-s</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ball-x-pit-is-a-deep-delightful-rabbit-hole.1334830/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>It took me a while to get into <em>Ball x Pit</em>. The new roguelike blends elements from games like <em>Breakout</em>, <em>Vampire Survivors</em>, and even city builders, creating a complex mix of ideas. But as is the case with many roguelikes, once I figured everything out well enough to get a taste of my first win, delving back into the pit for another round was all I could think about.</p><p><em>Ball x Pit</em> barely has a story — it’s more like a setup. The initial moments of the game show a multi-tiered Gondor-like city called “Ballbylon” being struck by a giant, glowing rock (ball?), and all that remains is a giant pit that “treasure seekers” aim to explore. Then, you’re dropped into the action. Initially, as a knight-like character called “The Warrior,” you move around a narrow playing field, shooting balls up toward steadily advancing hordes of enemies. Your character fires automatically and you have infinite ammo, letting you focus on aiming your shots for optimal bounces and picking up gems and other goodies dropped by defeated bad guys.</p><p>Like in <em>Vampire Survivors</em>, when you pick up enough gems, you’ll gain a level, which improves your stats and gives you the chance to choose some kind of upgrade, like special balls that can poison enemies or activate lasers. Occasionally, enemies will drop little rainbow spirals that can level up a bunch of your upgrades at once, let you fuse balls together to combine their powers, or evolve two balls into a special new one. With the right combination of upgrades, you can get extremely powerful, with balls and effects flying around the screen as you wipe out the enemies and bosses. When you finish a run, win or lose, your character gets experience that carries over so they’re more powerful in future runs.</p><p>After a run, you can choose to visit “New Ballbylon” for the <em>other</em> part of <em>Ball x Pit</em>, which involves base-building. During this phase, you can set up things like plots of wheat and forests for resources or buildings that open up new characters and permanent stat boosts. To harvest resources or build things, you’ll have to send out your characters to bounce against the plots and structures by aiming them like you do in the main part of the game. You can also upgrade structures so they offer better perks, and you’ll eventually be able to make buildings that will auto-harvest resources for you.</p><p>Initially, I didn’t like the base-building; I just wanted to keep doing the main runs. But once I had a good engine for resources and understood how upgrading buildings worked, I was spending a lot longer than I expected optimizing my base, which had the added benefit of making things easier when I jumped back into a level.</p><p>Some buildings unlock new characters, and they’re nearly always worth the effort: the characters have wildly varying playstyles that keep things fresh. One character gets 5 percent more damage for each bounce, so I’d try to shoot balls into tight corners where they’d ping wildly and potentially rack up serious damage. One character makes the game turn-based. Another character automatically picks their own upgrades, and one of the last characters that you can unlock plays the game <em>entirely on their own</em>, which I found very useful while trying to grind some late-game levels and upgrades.</p><p>By the end of my time with <em>Ball x Pit</em>, I will admit that I started to feel a bit of the emptiness I do when I play <em>Vampire Survivors</em> now. Once winning became more routine, I started to focus on maximizing things in a way that felt more obsessive rather than fun. I’m even ashamed to say that I let the auto-play character handle a bunch of runs on the last level while I went and did other things.</p><p>But when you’re in the zone on a good run, the game is a delightful, colorful, and chaotic experience that feels like a hyper-extreme version of the classic <em>Breakout</em>. With so many characters to play and ways to improve your base, <em>Ball x Pit</em> goes deep.</p><p><sup>Ball x Pit<em> is out now on Nintendo Switch, PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X / S, and is coming to Nintendo Switch 2 <a href="https://x.com/devolverdigital/status/1981737834819014867">on October 28th.</a></em></sup></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/805022/ball-x-pit-review-pc-nintendo-switch-ps5-xbox-series-x-s]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Wordle #1590: Hints And Answer For October 26, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1590-hints-answer-october-26-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/today%E2%80%99s-wordle-1590-hints-and-answer-for-october-26-2025.1334824/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Get ready for an easier Wordle answer than the past few days. Wordle challenges players to guess a fresh five-letter word each day in six tries or fewer. Whether you’re a beginner or a daily player, today’s tips and strategies can help you solve it faster and maintain your streak—if you’re open to a little extra help. So, if you’ve found yourself stuck with today’s Wordle, don’t worry, you’ll find some <strong>helpful hints and even the answer for Wordle Game #1590 for October 26, 2025</strong>.</p>



<p>To play today’s Wordle, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/games/wordle/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">head to the game’s website.</a> If you want to go right to today’s answer without any tips or tricks, you <strong><a href="#h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1590-on-october-26-2025">can click right here</a>.</strong> If you’ve missed any days, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wordle-archive-every-past-wordle-answer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wordle Answer Archive</a> for every past answer.</p>



<p><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong> The following information includes spoilers on today’s</em> and yesterday’s editions<em> of Wordle. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<figure></figure>



<h2>How To Play Wordle</h2>



<p>Wordle is a simple but addictive word puzzle. Each day, players have to <strong>guess a five-letter word answer</strong> in no more than six attempts. After each guess:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Green letters</strong> are correct and in the right position.</li>



<li><strong>Yellow letters</strong> are correct, but in the wrong position.</li>



<li><strong>Gray letters</strong> are not in the word at all.</li>
</ul>



<p>The goal is to guess the word in as few tries as possible. Daily puzzles keep players coming back for more, making it a fun brain exercise and a popular online trend.</p>



<p>Wordle can only be played on the New York Times website. There is currently no app for you to download the official game.</p>



<h2 id="h-wordle-hints-for-today-october-26-2025">Wordle Hints For Today, October 26, 2025</h2>



<p>The Wordle answer for game #1590 keeps things exactly the same as Saturday’s puzzle. According to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/25/crosswords/wordle-review-1590.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NY Times Wordle</a> review, today’s answer takes an average of 4.2 guesses out of 6 to get. That means it’s the same as the 4.2-guess average on October 25.</p>



<h3 id="h-general-wordle-hints-for-october-26">General Wordle Hints For October 26</h3>



<p>Without giving today’s Wordle answer completely away, here are a few helpful hints for today to get you started:</p>



<ul>
<li>LUMPY</li>



<li>PLUTO</li>



<li>PLUMB</li>
</ul>



<p>Use these clues to narrow down your guesses and increase your chances of solving <strong>Wordle #1590 for October 26, 2025</strong></p>



<h3 id="h-starter-words-for-october-26-2025">Starter Words For October 26, 2025</h3>



<p>If you want help getting started without having today’s Wordle answer given to you, there are a few starter words worth trying that will help you figure out some included letters. A few starter words that may help are:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong> The word contains <strong>only one vowel</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> It <strong>starts with P</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong> It can describe something <strong>pleasantly full or slightly rounded</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 4:</strong> The same consonant <strong>appears at the beginning and the end</strong>.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1590-on-october-26-2025">Today’s Wordle Answer For Game #1590 On October 26, 2025</h2>



<p>If you’ve tried everything, including using the above hints, and are still stuck, you can find the answer to today’s Wordle below.</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> PLUMP</p>



<p>If you solved today’s Wordle without our answer, congratulations! If not, take note of the best tips above for tomorrow’s puzzle, and check back daily for more hints.</p>



<h2 id="h-yesterday-s-wordle-answer">Yesterday’s Wordle Answer</h2>



<p>If you missed the previous game, here’s yesterday’s Wordle answer for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1589-hints-answer-october-25-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game #1589 on October 25, 2025</a>:</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> GAUGE</p>



<p>While not always the case, looking at previous words can sometimes give you insight into common patterns or letter usage in Wordle puzzles. Reminder, you can check out every past Wordle answer <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wordle-archive-every-past-wordle-answer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in our official archive</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-wordle-game-after-1590">When Is The Next Wordle Game After #1590?</h2>



<p>Wordle games are <strong>updated daily at 12 am or Midnight in your respective time zone</strong>. Information about the next game is often available in the hours before to give players a heads up. The game on <strong>October 27</strong> will be <strong>Wordle Game #1591</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-wordle">What Is Wordle?</h2>



<p>Wordle is a daily word puzzle created by Josh Wardle. Initially developed as a prototype in 2013, it wasn’t fully released until 2021. The game tasks players with guessing a five-letter word in six tries or fewer, using hints from each attempt to narrow down the answer. Its straightforward concept, accessibility, and the thrill of solving a new puzzle each day helped it surge in popularity by late 2021. The success of Wordle inspired numerous spin-offs and social media challenges, leading to its acquisition by The New York Times in early 2022.</p>



<hr>



<p>Need more help with other daily games? Let us know what games you’d like tips and clues for in the comments below, and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1590-hints-answer-october-26-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mega Man Legends 2 Still Suffers From A 25-Year-Old Cliffhanger]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mega-man-legends-2-still-suffers-from-a-25-year-old-cliffhanger/1100-6535697/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mega-man-legends-2-still-suffers-from-a-25-year-old-cliffhanger.1334806/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535697">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><em>Mega Man Legends 2 is celebrating its 25-year anniversary today, October 25, 2025. Below, we look back at how its unresolved cliffhanger ending still overshadows its memory.</em></p><p dir="ltr">Mega Man Legends 2 is an unfinished promise. The anime-inspired adventure series was beloved by fans of the blue bomber for its inventive, Zelda-like spin on the classic formula. It was filled with lovable characters who have endured long past the series itself, like Tron Bonne, the Servbots, and the hero, Mega Man Volnutt. But like a serialized cartoon series, the second game in the series ended with a whopper of a cliffhanger--and then never returned to it. The legacy of Legends for the last 25 years has been fans waiting for a resolution that never came.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Spoilers for the Mega Man Legends series follow</strong></p><p dir="ltr">For those unfamiliar with the Mega Man Legends series, it's unusually story-rich for a Mega Man game. Set in the distant future, in a world almost completely covered with water, Mega Man Volnutt and his adoptive family, Barrel and Roll Caskett, dig for treasure in ruins guarded by ancient technology called Reaverbots. All the while, they're alternatively pursued and occasionally aided by sky pirates called the Bonnes: Teisel, Tron, and big baby Bon Bonne. Each of the main characters in the colorful world is fully voiced, aiding in the presentation as a Saturday-morning cartoon come to life.</p><p dir="ltr">The first game explores Mega Man investigating ruins to avert a prophesized disaster, but inadvertently awakening it in the process. Another being, called Mega Man Juno, reveals to Volnutt that his original name is Mega Man Trigger. Trigger was designed as a "Purifier Unit" whose purpose was to eliminate the Carbons--aka the artificial humans who live in this world. Needless to say, he does the right thing and protects humanity instead.</p><p dir="ltr">The second game treads familiar ground but expands upon it with multiple new characters and a larger scope. This time a unit called Sera tasks Mega Man to find four keys that will unlock the Mother Lode, a rich energy source that would usher in utopia and end the constant scrapping for resources. But Sera's counterpart, Yuna, later informs Mega Man that the keys would not save humanity but rather doom it, by eliminating the Carbons and replacing them with the ancient, non-artificial humans. In the end, the three come to an understanding and stop the Master Program from initializing the wipe, but in the process, the three are left stranded on the moon of Elysium, separated from their home on the planet Terra. To make matters worse, Yuna explains that the shutdown of the Master system will trigger a failsafe by reactivating an even older Elder system, activating machines across the ruins of Terra. Mega Man Legends 2 ends with Roll attempting to build a rocket to save her stranded sibling, but we never see if it's successful.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_VcNbjdMCvY" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_VcNbjdMCvY" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">This is the canonical, chronological end of the Mega Man series. Several of the individual Mega Man series--from the classic 8-bit platformers, through Mega Man X, Mega Man Zero, and Mega Man ZX, and finally Mega Man Legends--form one continuous (though loosely connected and often ret-conned) story. Legends is the last, which means that its unresolved ending is the last thing we see happening in a story that has been changing and evolving since the 1980s. The last in a long line of heroes called Mega Man is stranded, with a clock ticking toward the destruction of all society. It's unsatisfying enough on its own, but even more so as the bookend for an entire franchise that spans dozens of games.</p><p dir="ltr">Making matters worse is the unfulfilled promise of Mega Man Legends 3. The anticipated sequel was teased by Capcom in 2010, closely coinciding with the departure of series co-creator Keiji Inafune. Capcom's plans for Legends 3 included an ambitious idea to invite fans into the development process, soliciting feedback from the community. The company announced it would release a "Prototype Version" on the 3DS eShop, to act as a prologue. This was remarkable for the time, as early access was not yet an industry standard.</p><p dir="ltr">But as the months went on and no Prototype Version released, fans began to suspect that the project had been canceled. Capcom confirmed this in July 2011, announcing that there would be no Mega Man Legends 3 or even Prototype Version released at all, despite <a href="https://www.siliconera.com/adapt-japanese-game-english-voiceovers/" rel="nofollow ">later reports</a> that the demo was nearly completed. And in a PR misstep that would live in infamy for Mega Man fans, Capcom's UK Twitter account <a href="https://x.com/CapcomEurope/status/93558391309471744" rel="nofollow ">appeared to blame the cancellation</a> on a lack of fan involvement. A later tweet <a href="https://x.com/CapcomEurope/status/93940828984193024" rel="nofollow ">clarified</a> that it meant to refer to a lack of interaction in the online "Development Rooms" Capcom had made, not fan support more broadly. Inafune, for his part, <a href="https://www.siliconera.com/keiji-inafune-still-like-make-mega-man-legends-3/" rel="nofollow ">expressed interest in making the game</a>, as an outside contractor with his own studio, as late as 2014.</p><p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, Mega Man Legends exists now mostly in memory. Capcom has gladly capitalized in its history of Mega Man games with compilations of almost every series. The Legacy Collections have now compiled the classic, Mega Man X, Mega Man Zero and Mega Man ZX, and Mega Man Battle Network series, with a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mega-man-star-force-legacy-collection-coming-in-2026/1100-6534729/">Mega Man Star Force collection</a> coming in 2026. Once that releases, every Mega Man series will be readily accessible on modern platforms--except Mega Man Legends. Those games, first released on PlayStation, have remained stuck in that generation, aside from a PSP port.</p><p dir="ltr">And so Mega Man Legends has become a symbol of unfulfilled potential. The series charted a new path forward for the classic character, reinventing him as an anime-styled adventurer with deep lore and a wide cast of lovable, memorable characters. But for all of its promise, it's also the Mega Man series that has received the least games: two in the main series and the quirky minigame spin-off The Misadventures of Tron Bonne. It's become a sore spot for Mega Man fans, even as the series has received new entries like the well-received Mega Man 11. For fans of Mega Man Legends, we're all up there with Volnutt, Yuna, and Sera: waiting for a rescue, and a resolution, that will never come.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mega-man-legends-2-still-suffers-from-a-25-year-old-cliffhanger/1100-6535697/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>