<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:18:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SteamWorld Heist II Preview - Time to Plunder]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/steamworld-heist-ii-preview-time-to-plunder</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steamworld-heist-ii-preview-time-to-plunder.911748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/steamworld-heist-ii-preview-time-to-plunder<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>SteamWorld</em> is host to a myriad of titles spanning across multiple genres. You have the base-building sim <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/steamworld-build"><em>SteamWorld Build</em></a>, or even the turn-based RPG <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/steamworld-quest"><em>SteamWorld Quest</em></a>. As a tactics fan, my personal favorite of the ever-expanding series is <em>SteamWorld</em> <em>Heist</em>, and to see that it's getting an upcoming sequel? I'm all in.</p>
<p>We got a chance to check out <em>SteamWorld Heist II </em>during Summer Game Fest, as well as some extra hands-on time after the show. The early portion of <em>SteamWorld Heist II</em> should serve as a great sequel for fans of the first game, but also a fantastic starting point for anyone that likes tactics or pirates.</p>

<h2>A Pirates Life for <em>SteamWorld Heist II</em></h2>
<p><em>SteamWorld Heist II</em> trades the science fiction, space pirate theme from the first game in for a high seas adventure. Rather than boarding space vessels and seizing loot, you have your very own submarine, the method by which you'll attack ships, plunder booty, and infiltrate strongholds and pirate dens.</p>
<p>The setting is a somewhat jarring departure from the first game, though the core gameplay loop should still be familiar for fans of the first game. <em>SteamWorld Heist II</em> is a tactical strategy game at its core, and maneuvering units and planning ahead is all part of the fun.</p>
<p>Missions usually task players with achieving a certain objective, like seizing all the loot at an outpost. To do so, you'll add members of your crew to missions and go forth. In <em>SteamWorld Heist II</em>, units have their own class, weapon types, and more. Those can later be mixed and matched to make optimal builds, so there's already some depth to the mechanics outside of combat.</p>

<p>One of the ways in which this particular series has set itself apart is with the aiming system -- you're primarily using weapons to dispatch naval robots. The bullet ricochet system is back again, so you can defy physics by having bullets bounce in wild ways to hit enemies that <em>might</em> appear out of reach, but in fact are vulnerable to your guns.</p>
<p>It's been nearly 8 years since I played the original, but combat feels relatively unchanged. That's a good thing, since the core gameplay was very addicting and simple to get the hang of. Of course, pulling off insane shots with the ricochets never grew dull, and you'll find that's the case in <em>SteamWorld Heist II </em>as well.</p>

<h2>Pilot Your Own Ship</h2>
<p>Outside of combat, the most immediate difference between this and the original is the submarine. Players commandeer their own ship and use it to explore a rather vast open world. The world, comprising mostly water and islands scattered throughout, are infested with outposts and enemy vessels you can loot.</p>
<p>It's a simple vehicle to control, but very addicting to use. The submarine is equipped with various weapons like turrets and torpedoes. These weapons fire automatically in fixed directions, but you need to position your ship often when an armament needs to be reloaded.</p>

<p>You're able to collect any loot from these ships and use it to buy upgrades for a wide variety of things. There's also a system in place where players accrue bounty points based on what they achieve in a day. Those bounties can be exchanged for rewards at the end of the day, so you're constantly getting rewarded.</p>
<p>The whole overworld is seamless, and as I mentioned, the combat retains its old charm. <em>SteamWorld</em>'s been a hallmark for quality indie games for over a decade now, and it's encouraging to see that <em>SteamWorld Heist II </em>is upholding that legacy thus far.</p>
<hr><p><strong>Steam<em>World Heist II </em></strong><em>was previewed after about 30 minutes of gameplay at Summer Game Fest, and 4 hours with a key provided by the publisher - all screenshots were taken during the preview process.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring’s DLC Just Got Easier]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-dlc-patch-realm-blessings-1851561110</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring%E2%80%99s-dlc-just-got-easier.911745/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-dlc-patch-realm-blessings-1851561110<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Elden Ring</em>’s newly released <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-expansion-review-1851545505&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-expansion-review-1851545505"><em>Shadow of the Erdtree </em>DLC</a></span> is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-difficulty-vigor-dying-1851553144&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-difficulty-vigor-dying-1851553144">notoriously difficult</a></span>, even for the most seasoned veterans of FromSoftware’s RPG. It’s so divisive among players that some have taken to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-steam-reviews-1851557175&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-steam-reviews-1851557175">review bombing the DLC</a></span> to express their dissatisfaction. But now, FromSoftware is releasing a patch that will tip the scales in players’ favor a bit—we’ll see if it makes the expansion easier.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195624" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: August 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="279" data-playlist="195624,196773,195502" data-current="195624"><div><p>The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: August 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21125.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.bandainamcoent.com/news/elden-ring-patch-notes-version-1-12-2&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.bandainamcoent.com/news/elden-ring-patch-notes-version-1-12-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">patch notes</a></span> aren’t very long, but they outline changes being made to the Shadow Realm Blessings, a. new mechanic introduced in the <em>Shadow of the Erdtree </em>DLC that lets you buff your character’s attack and defense after finding special items within the new map. Scadutree Blessings (which affect attack and defense stars) are found at Miquella’s crosses, while Revered Spirit Ash Blessings (which bolster your Spirit summons) are placed on Miquella statues. Both are required to level up these stats at Sites of Grace, and much of the DLC is scaled to Blessings. As such, FromSoftware is bumping up the stat increases for the first half of the maximum amount in order to give players an edge in the opening hours. They will then level out as you go, so if you’re already deep into the DLC, it’s unlikely you’ll notice any tan3gible difference.</p><p>The patch notes also mention a bug on the PC version that automatically enabled raytracing if you load saved data from previous versions of the game from old patches, with instructions on how to fix it in-game. The full patch notes read as follows:</p><h2 id="h1385"><a id=""></a>Calibration Update 1.12.2 change list</h2><p>Attack and damage negation curve scaling of the <strong>Shadow Realm Blessings</strong> has been revised.</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>The attack and damage negation has been increased for the first half of the maximum amount of <strong>Blessing enhancements</strong>, and the second half will now be more gradual.</li><li>The attack and damage negation granted by the final level of Blessing enhancements has been slightly increased.</li></ul><p>The calibration update can be applied by logging into the multiplayer server.</p><p>If the Calibration Ver. listed at the bottom right of the title menu is not “1.12.2", then select LOGIN and apply the latest regulations before enjoying the game.</p><h2 id="h1386"><a id=""></a>About graphics settings (PC version only)</h2><p>We have confirmed a bug where the raytracing settings are automatically enabled if you have previously loaded saved data from previous game versions.</p><p>If your framerate is unstable, please check in the ‘SYSTEM’ &gt; ‘Graphics Settings’ &gt; ‘Raytracing Quality’ settings from the title menu or in-game menu to check if it has been unintentionally set to ‘ON’. Once set to ‘OFF’, Ray Tracing will no longer be automatically enabled.</p><p>Other balance adjustments as well as bug fixes are also planned for a future patch.</p><p>Hopefully that will help folks who have having trouble with the opening hours of <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>. If you’re having trouble with specific sections or bosses, be sure to check out our <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/game-tips&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/game-tips">Tips &amp; Guides section</a></span> where we’ve got a ton of guides to help you through FromSoftware’s latest. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AAA Games Are Bombing in iOS Port Sales, Estimates Claim]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ios-games-sales-bombing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/aaa-games-are-bombing-in-ios-port-sales-estimates-claim.911742/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ios-games-sales-bombing/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>When the iPhone 15 (and the higher-tier models) was revealed last year, it was promised that a slew of AAA games would wind up on the super-capable device and the topmost iPad models. To that end, Death Stranding, Resident Evil Village, and – most recently – Assassin’s Creed Mirage all landed on the iOS App Store, but recent estimations have suggested that they’re simply not selling and might not be worth the developers’ investment.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-too-niche">Too Niche</h2>



<p>It’s worth stressing that these AAA games can only be played on the most expensive, high-spec iPhones and iPads on the market, but even so, the estimated sales figures are woeful. In a report published by Appfigures (and <a href="https://mobilegamer.biz/those-assassins-creed-resident-evil-and-death-stranding-ports-have-bombed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">shared by MobileGamer</a>), it was suggested that fewer than 3,000 people have paid to unlock the full version of Assassin’s Creed Mirage since it was released a few weeks ago. </p>



<p>Assassin’s Creed Mirage offers users a brief free trial to test out the game on their iPhone or iPad device, but after that, there’s a $49.99 paywall blocking off the rest of the game. That’s where most users are getting to before ultimately giving up, because it has been downloaded approximately 123,000 times, according to Appfigures. That has led Ubisoft to net just $138,000 in revenue, which hardly makes the venture worthwhile.</p>



<p>Elsewhere, it was estimated that while Resident Evil 4 has been downloaded around 350,000 times, only 7,000 consumers have converted to the fully-priced, premium product. The data also shows rapid drop-offs in interest post-launch. </p>



<p>Many have theorised that the leading cause of this lack of interest can be attributed to none of the games being made-for-mobile – and then there’s the fact that they boast premium price tags. In a world dominated by free-to-play games, who wants to pay $49.99 to play a game on a mobile device?</p>



<hr>



<p>&nbsp;For more Insider Gaming, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/surgeon-simulator-series-bought-by-ataris-infogrames/">Infogrames has bought the Surgeon Simulator label</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive content.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cattle Country Aims to Mix Stardew Valley With a Dash of Red Dead Redemption]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cattle-country-aims-to-mix-stardew-valley-with-a-dash-of-red-dead-redemption</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cattle-country-aims-to-mix-stardew-valley-with-a-dash-of-red-dead-redemption.911739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/cattle-country-aims-to-mix-stardew-valley-with-a-dash-of-red-dead-redemption<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Developer Castle Pixel and publisher Playtonic Friends have announced Cattle Country, a new "cozy cowboy life-sim adventure" in the works for PC (via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2818150/Cattle_Country/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a>). It promises pixel-art graphics, 18 romanceable characters, cattle to raise, bandits to fend off, and buried treasure to dig up, among other gameplay elements. Watch the announcement trailer above or check out the first screenshots in the gallery below.</p><p>Fishing, hunting, and farming will make up the core of the gameplay in what Castle Pixel and Playtonic Friends bill as a game that aims to be "Red Dead Redemption meets Stardew Valley." </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Cattle Country - First Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Playtonic Friends is the publishing arm of Yooka-Laylee developer Playtonic, while Castle Pixel previously developed Blossom Tales and Rex Rocket. </p><p><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alkahest Is a New First-Person Medieval Fantasy Action-RPG that Looks Stunning]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/alkahest-is-a-new-first-person-medieval-fantasy-action-rpg-that-looks-stunning</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alkahest-is-a-new-first-person-medieval-fantasy-action-rpg-that-looks-stunning.911736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/alkahest-is-a-new-first-person-medieval-fantasy-action-rpg-that-looks-stunning<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">If the final game plays anything like this trailer, then we should all be in for a treat.</h2></div><section><p>Alkahest is a new first-person fantasy action-adventure RPG from developer Push On that bills itself as a spiritual successor to Dark Messiah of Might &amp; Magic while also citing Dishonored and Kingdom Come: Deliverance as its influences. In it, you'll engage in close-quarters combat, explore realistic medieval locations, learn alchemy, and more. Check out the fantastic announcement trailer above and the first screenshots in the gallery below.</p><p>Alkahest is set in the kingdom of Kadanor, where you're the youngest son of a petty lord. The region's balance of power is tenous at best as three houses vie for control. You'll explore castles, villages, forests, and other settings befitting of the medieval fantasy setting.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Alkahest - First Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Perhaps even more interestingly, Alkahest promises "dynamic combat with a focus on interactive environment." Meaning, you'll build combos with both your attacks and the environment. One example Play On gives: "Drop a tree on [an enemy's] head, kick them off a cliff, set them on fire." That fire part comes from Alkahest's alchemy system, which augments the up-close melee combat in lieu of a magic system. You'll follow recipes or concoct your own throwables, drinkables, weapon oils, and enemy traps. Stealth and brute-force melee combat are both supported and encouraged.</p><p>Alkahest is in development for PC and we'll have more on it as development progresses.</p><p><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition – First Impressions of the Remixed Classics]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-first-impressions-of-the-remixed-classics</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-%E2%80%93-first-impressions-of-the-remixed-classics.911733/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-first-impressions-of-the-remixed-classics<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The 1989 movie The Wizard had a profound effect on me as a kid. In it, young Fred Savage’s character makes his way to the Nintendo World Championships in, heck, I don’t even remember what city, but it was somewhere far away, in order to put his video game skills to the test. Anyway, once he gets there, a big twist in the event is that he competes in the then-unreleased Super Mario Bros. 3. And boy oh boy did that product placement work to perfection – I <em>had </em>to have Super Mario Bros. 3 the moment it came out after that, and God bless my mom, she bought it for me. Her taking it out of that white plastic K-Mart grocery bag and just handing it to me – it wasn’t even my birthday or anything! – is a core memory for me.</p><p>That is what I think of when I think about the Nintendo World Championships, but for others, the real-life competition was far more about just that: a real-life competition. Now, Nintendo is putting a creative twist on the nostalgia for its own history in a way that only they seem to be really good at: by turning into a local and online multiplayer game for the Nintendo Switch that’s played in increments ranging from under two seconds (this is not a joke) to about a minute at most. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition - June 2024 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition includes 13 games: Super Mario Bros. 1-3, Super Mario Bros. 2: The Lost Levels, Zelda 1 and 2, Metroid, Kid Icarus, Donkey Kong, Ballon Fight, Excitebike, Ice Climber, and Kirby’s Adventure. I ended up dabbling in each of them during a 90-minute hands-on session across both solo modes and the local Party Mode. I certainly knew what I was walking into – a collection of classic NES games from my childhood turned into competitive challenges – but I didn’t expect the format to be so much <em>fun</em>.</p><p>Of these games, Kirby’s Adventure was the only one I’d flat-out never played as a kid, and sure enough it was the Kirby challenges that tripped me up the most. But outside of that, I had an absolute blast trying to earn S rankings on the myriad challenges on offer for each game. They get progressively more difficult as you go, naturally, and you have to unlock the tougher ones with coins you earn by getting good rankings on the challenges you do have access to. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>As an example, the first challenge from The Legend of Zelda is so simple it probably sounds stupid: you start from the beginning of the game and have to walk into the cave that’s on the very first screen and acquire the sword. And yet, I found myself replaying it multiple times to try and shave tenths of a second off of my time and get that pride-inflating S ranking. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The first challenge from The Legend of Zelda is so simple it probably sounds stupid. And yet, I found myself replaying it multiple times to try and shave tenths of a second off of my time and get that pride-inflating S ranking.&nbsp;</p></div><p>Party Mode is where it really got fun, though. IGN’s Rebekah Valentine and I competed in a series of challenges in Party Mode against Nintendo reps. We sped through World 1-1 of Super Mario Bros. 3. We got the first energy ball in Metroid. We climbed to the top of the first stage in Donkey Kong, we took a lap around the track in Excitebike, and more. Is it the perfect re-creation of an in-person competition with hundreds if not thousands of people cheering you on? Certainly not. But it is a delightfully simple party game that truly anyone can pick up and play. Will it help if you already have a nostalgic connection to these games? No doubt. But is that experience required? Absolutely not; in 2024, any of these 1980’s classics can be picked up and played by anyone pretty easily, as there are only two buttons to worry about.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Although speaking of buttons, my one genuine complaint about Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition involves them. See, when four of you are competing, all four of you have to press the A button to ready up before an event starts. The problem is, <em>so many </em>of the games use the B button as a turbo or run button that you naturally want to be holding it as soon as the countdown timer hits zero. But if any one of the four of you hasn’t readied up yet and anyone else starts laying on the B button in anticipation of the start of the event, it backs everyone out to the previous menu. This happened over and over during my 90-minute hands-on session, and I wasn’t the only one accidentally doing this. It seems like a UI design flaw that there must be a solution for.</p><p>I have one other nitpick, though this one is far less serious: the slowdown in Kirby’s Adventure (and perhaps in parts of other games that I didn’t see enough of to rule out). The versions of the 13 games included here are the original iterations, but during a couple of the Kirby challenges, the slowdown kicked in and felt disruptive to the action – as framerate hitches do in any game, modern or classic. I can see the argument for preserving each of the games as-is, but for the sake of the competition that’s at the heart of the gameplay in Nintendo World Championships, I’d prefer that it have been smoothed out. You may disagree, and that’s OK!</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Meanwhile, I didn’t play the Online World Championships mode since, of course, the game isn’t out yet and there’s no one online to play with. But expect weekly rankings there, with the ability to watch the replays of the top players – a handy tool for improving your own skills and strategies. </p><p>Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition feels priced right to be at $30 for the digital version, and again I was surprised at how engaged I was with the seemingly simple challenges it puts forth (at least in the early rounds). I hope this does well, because the name of this implies that we might get a SNES Edition, Nintendo 64 Edition, and dare I say even a GameCube Edition if this one is a hit. </p><p><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Medieval first-person action adventure RPG Alkahest announced for consoles, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/medieval-first-person-action-adventure-rpg-alkahest-announced-for-consoles-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/medieval-first-person-action-adventure-rpg-alkahest-announced-for-consoles-pc.911730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/medieval-first-person-action-adventure-rpg-alkahest-announced-for-consoles-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>From Cyprus-based studio Push On.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Push On" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/push-on">Push On</a>, a Cyprus-based studio of 40-plus veteran developers who have previously worked on AAA and independent games, has announced <em><a title="Games > Alkahest" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/alkahest">Alkahest</a></em>, a medieval first-person <a title="Genres > Action [1,965 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> adventure <a title="Genres > RPG [16,379 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> with <a title="Genres > Simulation [510 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation</a> elements coming to unspecified consoles and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,544 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3016620/Alkahest/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date was not announced. It will support English, French, Italian, German, Spanish, Portuguese, Polish, Russian, Ukrainian, Japanese, Korean, and Simplified Chinese language options. <span id="more-895082"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Push On:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Alkahest</em> is an action adventure RPG set in a murky medieval world. Where satisfying melee combat with highly interactive environments takes center stage. Explore realistic locations, learn alchemy and make a name for your family.</p><p><strong><a title="Games > Grounded [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/grounded">Grounded</a> Fantasy <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a></strong></p><p>When the sun rises over the kingdom of Kadanor, it casts long shadows. Explore a world mired in feodal turmoil, where the balance of power between the three major houses is fragile.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>As the youngest son of a petty lord, you’re no hero. And to become someone, you’ll have to prove your worth through sweat and blood. Investigating unusual goblin raids on the county border may be the chance you’ve been waiting for.</p><p>Explore castles, forests, villages and other realistic settings, while meeting its residents<br>and making interesting decisions on your journey.</p><p><strong>Dynamic Combat With a Focus on Interactive Environment</strong></p><p>Build your combo and execute it against enemies. Drop a tree on their head, kick them off a cliff, set them on fire. In <em>Alkahest</em>, fast-paced close combat within a richly interactive environment takes center stage.</p><p>Unlike games where stealth is the “right” way to play, we encourage a balanced approach. Players can opt for stealth, scouting the area for an effective strategy, or boldly confront enemies head-on. Enemies adapt dynamically; if overwhelmed, they may flee, regroup, and set up ambushes, keeping gameplay challenging and engaging.</p><p>Use all advantages—alchemical potions, daggers, relics, and more! Even a rope can become a deadly weapon in skillful hands.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_895088"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Master the Craft of Alchemy</strong></p><p>Instead of magic, <em>Alkahest</em> will feature alchemy, a complex and important game system. Follow a recipe or mix gathered ingredients at your own discretion. Use the substance as a throwable, a weapon oil, plant it into an NPC’s pocket or even drink it yourself. In each scenario, outcomes can be unpredictable.</p><p>Sticky death or heady encouragement—what are you brewing next?</p><p><strong>Immerse Yourself in the Journey</strong></p><p>We are players ourselves and believe in quality over quantity. So a big no to a bloated map and dull filler quests.</p><p>We strive to create a highly interactive and believable world with semi <a title="Genres > Open-World [435 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> locations, packed with secrets and adventure. With branching gameplay options, inspired by Dishonored, Dark Messiah of Might and Magic, <a title="Games > Kingdom Come: Deliverance [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance">Kingdom Come: Deliverance</a> and other genre-defining games.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Creative melee combat with extensive use of physics and highly interactive environments. Kick enemies off a cliff, drop a tree on their heads, and much more.</li><li>Alchemy instead of magic. Follow a recipe or mix gathered ingredients at your own discretion. Use the substance as a throwable, a weapon oil, plant it into an NPC’s pocket or even drink it yourself. In each scenario, outcomes can be unpredictable.</li><li>First-person adventure, balanced between scripted gameplay sections and free exploration of semi-open locations.</li><li>Grounded setting focused on realism and believability, muddy Middle Ages with a fantasy spin.</li><li>Story involving personal drama, politics, interesting factions and characters.</li><li>Immersive sim elements: aggressive <a title="Genres > Stealth [64 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a>, non-linearity in addressing gameplay tasks, multiple gadgets and unobvious combinations of mechanics.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/alkahest/june-26-2024/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://alkahestgame.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Alkahest - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ceMcXz9czCI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40k: Rogue Trader Gets "Biggest Update So Far"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40k-rogue-trader-update-biggest-yet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-rogue-trader-gets-biggest-update-so-far.911715/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40k-rogue-trader-update-biggest-yet<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Owlcat has released a new&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Rogue Trader&nbsp;</em>update, and it's the game's biggest yet, bringing over 2500 changes to the grimdark CRPG.</p>
<p>The studio estimates that the new update, catchily named 1.2.0.25, is around 30% bigger than its 1.1 patch, and it brings big balance updates, improvements to locations and the UI, and much, much more.</p>
<p>There's arguably no one big centerpiece for this update; rather, it revolves around a litany of smaller tweaks and improvements that should all add up to create a patchwork that significantly boosts your&nbsp;<em>Rogue Trader&nbsp;</em>play experience.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-40k-rogue-trader-update-combat.jpg?itok=9GlAPzQ9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-40k-rogue-trader-update-combat.jpg?itok=sKQZ9-iG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The latest&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Rogue Trader&nbsp;</em>update has tons of improvements in store.</figcaption></figure><p>First up, the game is getting major balancing changes including a "deep rebalance" for out-of-sequence turns, as well as late-game scaling tuning, buffs to Sanctioned Psykers and Pyromancy, and more.</p>
<p>You can also look forward to a bevy of quality-of-life changes like quests appearing on star systems, improved tooltips, and a better level-up screen, as well as an improved combat log.</p>
<p>The update adds "various improvements for locations across the game", too, including improved NPC variety and better pathing, and several companions have had new dialogue introduced so you can get to know them better.</p>
<p>Rumor zones are now highlighted on&nbsp;<em>Rogue Trader</em>'s map, and co-operative play has been improved too, so if you're investigating those rumors alongside a friend, your experience should be a lot smoother.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-40k-rogue-trader-update-necrons.jpg?itok=PQSU1gQ9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-40k-rogue-trader-update-necrons.jpg?itok=uRizcdMu 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Want to take on&nbsp;<em>Rogue Trader&nbsp;</em>alongside a friend? You're in luck with the game's latest update.</figcaption></figure><p>The full list of changes for&nbsp;this&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Rogue Trader&nbsp;</em>update is absolutely massive. You can read <a href="https://roguetrader.owlcat.games/news/en/38" rel="noopener" target="_blank">the full patch notes here</a> if you wish. Just make sure you've set some time aside!</p>
<p><em>Warhammer 40k: Rogue Trader&nbsp;</em>is a turn-based CRPG set in the&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k&nbsp;</em>universe. Developed <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-reveals-new-rpg-in-rogue-trader">by&nbsp;<em>Pathfinder: Wrath of the Righteous&nbsp;</em>studio Owlcat</a>, the game casts you as one of the titular rogue traders as you explore the barely-charted Koronus Expanse in search of new opportunities.</p>
<p>Like other CRPGs,&nbsp;<em>Rogue Trader&nbsp;</em>features a number of companions you can get to know, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40k-rogue-trader-introduces-its-companions-their-romantic-preferences-with">some of whom you can even romance</a>, but if love in the&nbsp;<em>40k&nbsp;</em>universe gives you the ick, don't worry; there's plenty of turn-based combat and exploration to go around as well.</p>
<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Rogue Trader&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2186680/Warhammer_40000_Rogue_Trader/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10008102/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/warhammer-40000-rogue-trader/9p30bfhz1bkn" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grab 22 of Capcom’s greatest fighting games on sale right now for under $20]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/deals/2024/6/26/24186002/capcom-fighting-game-bundle-deal-sale-street-fighter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grab-22-of-capcom%E2%80%99s-greatest-fighting-games-on-sale-right-now-for-under-20.911712/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/deals/2024/6/26/24186002/capcom-fighting-game-bundle-deal-sale-street-fighter<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="uqL62d">If you’re looking to revisit fighting game history in all its glory, Capcom is offering Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 4, and PlayStation 5 owners a chance to do so for under $20. Now through early July, you can pick up the Capcom Fighting Bundle — which includes <em>Capcom Fighting Collection</em> and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/4/16/22376607/everything-you-ever-wanted-to-know-about-street-fighter-history"><em>Street Fighter 30th Anniversary</em></a> —<strong> </strong>for about 66% off. That’s 22 Capcom classics for about 90 cents each!</p>
<p id="KbCBK6">I’m not even sure why I’m writing other words here, I’m just gonna list all the games instead. From Capcom Fighting Collection:</p>
<ul>
<li id="B07Rw3"><em>Darkstalkers: The Night Warriors</em></li>
<li id="a4qceI"><em>Night Warriors: Darkstalkers’ Revenge</em></li>
<li id="czsxO5"><em>Vampire Savior: The Lord of Vampire</em></li>
<li id="5QUrRT"><em>Vampire Hunter 2: Darkstalkers’ Revenge</em></li>
<li id="AQbSqs"><em>Vampire Savior 2: The Lord of Vampire</em></li>
<li id="FKs2xY"><em>Hyper Street Fighter II: The Anniversary Edition</em></li>
<li id="v4CVv1"><em>Super Puzzle Fighter II Turbo</em></li>
<li id="5Yqow4"><em>Super Gem Fighter Mini Mix</em></li>
<li id="C9Lt2t"><em>Cyberbots: Full Metal Madness</em></li>
<li id="wb8pZN"><em>Red Earth</em></li>
</ul>
<p id="gYphu0">From Street Fighter 30th Anniversary Collection:</p>
<ul>
<li id="ajvjXZ"><em>Street Fighter</em></li>
<li id="IDlvM7"><em>Street Fighter II</em></li>
<li id="cpOdRD"><em>Street Fighter II: Champion Edition</em></li>
<li id="CiAg45"><em>Street Fighter II Turbo: Hyper Fighting</em></li>
<li id="RXyrvU"><em>Super Street Fighter II: The New Challengers</em></li>
<li id="a3NpCK"><em>Super Street Fighter II Turbo</em></li>
<li id="PxK8ds"><em>Street Fighter Alpha</em></li>
<li id="shhy19"><em>Street Fighter Alpha 2</em></li>
<li id="Nz66RG"><em>Street Fighter Alpha 3</em></li>
<li id="ujXUoa"><em>Street Fighter III: New Generation</em></li>
<li id="IjBvu1"><em>Street Fighter III: 2nd Impact</em></li>
<li id="RSMzya"><em>Street Fighter III: 3rd Strike</em></li>
</ul>
<div id="pWuRhM">
  <div>
      
      <p>This bundle includes Capcom Fighting Collection and Street Fighter 30th Anniversary Collection, for a total of 22 games in all. Nintendo Switch and PlayStation 4 / PS5 owners can currently get everything for around $20—less than a dollar per game.</p>
    </div>
  <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Nintendo         $20         (67% off)" has-subtag="" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/capcom-fighting-bundle-switch/">
              
                <span>
                  $20
                </span>
              
            <span>
                at Nintendo
            </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="PlayStation         $20         (68% off)" has-subtag="" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0102-CUSA31205_00-CFCBUNDLE0000001">
              
                <span>
                  $20
                </span>
              
            <span>
                at PlayStation
            </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
  </ul>
</div>
<p id="MSxYud">So much <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/4/16/22376607/everything-you-ever-wanted-to-know-about-street-fighter-history">Street Fighter history</a>: one <em>Street Fighter</em>, five <em>Street Fighter IIs</em>, three <em>Street Fighter Alphas</em>, and three <em>Street Fighter IIIs, </em>which I’m pretty sure you’re supposed to multiply out to get 23 SF units in all. Pretty sure that’s how it works. Probably.</p>
<p id="U7OHCG">Even if just a few of those games pique your interest, it’s still a great value, and we <strong>—</strong> that is, the royal, collective Polygon hivemind — have at least a dozen favorites among the list, chief among them <em>Super Puzzle Fighter II Turbo</em>.</p>
<p id="nOg9yG">The Capcom Fighting Bundle deal runs until July 4 on the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0102-CUSA31205_00-CFCBUNDLE0000001">PlayStation store</a> and July 8 on the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/capcom-fighting-bundle-switch/">Nintendo store</a>. As of this writing we haven’t been able to find comparable deals for <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1516586&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fcapcom-fighting-bundle%2F9pmzw2080cnb&amp;referrer=polygon.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.polygon.com%2Fdeals%2F2024%2F6%2F26%2F24186002%2Fcapcom-fighting-game-bundle-deal-sale-street-fighter" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://go.redirectingat.com?xcust=___pl__p_23950043__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026id=66960X1516586\u0026xs=1\u0026url=https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/capcom-fighting-bundle/9pmzw2080cnb\u0026referrer=polygon.com\u0026sref=https://www.polygon.com/deals/2024/6/26/24186002/capcom-fighting-game-bundle-deal-sale-street-fighter&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:50,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;xcust&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;xcust&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23950043__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;66960X1516586&quot;,&quot;xs&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/capcom-fighting-bundle/9pmzw2080cnb&quot;,&quot;referrer&quot;:&quot;polygon.com&quot;,&quot;sref&quot;:&quot;https://www.polygon.com/deals/2024/6/26/24186002/capcom-fighting-game-bundle-deal-sale-street-fighter&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">Xbox</a> or <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sub/709779/">Steam</a> <strong>— </strong>both of those currently cost around $60 for the bundle <strong>— </strong>but we’ll keep an eye on things and update if that changes.</p>
<p id="9uhS6E">So... what should you do with all those savings? We’d like to recommend a <a href="https://www.polygon.com/features/2014/3/10/5451014/street-fighter-the-movie-what-went-wrong">certain Raul Julia classic</a>, which assuredly will <a href="https://www.threads.net/@wario64/post/C8mZkuyqpzy">keep Capcom talking about it</a> at shareholder meetings for a long time to come.</p>

  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation’s New Patent Reveals a New Controller Concept That Uses Conductive Ink]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-new-patent-reveals-a-controller-concept-with-conductive-ink/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation%E2%80%99s-new-patent-reveals-a-new-controller-concept-that-uses-conductive-ink.911706/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-new-patent-reveals-a-controller-concept-with-conductive-ink/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>PlayStation has filed for a new patent for a new controller concept. The standout feature of this controller is its use of electric ink, allowing players to craft a custom layout that suits their unique play style. This patent could revolutionize the way we interact with games. Dive into the details of PlayStation’s patent for a “user customized flat computer simulation controller field below.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://exputer.com/news/playstation/sony-controller-customize-shape/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Exputer</a>, PlayStation’s latest patent talks about a controller that gives players a new level of freedom towards customization. This concept will work on a flat surface, and the user will have to personally draw the layout for the computer simulation buttons that fit their needs perfectly. Players would need a regular first, however, to link the hand-drawn controls to the actual buttons on the standard controller.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, there will be an “anti-fatigue” key, a feature designed to enhance button functionality. In some instances, players will press buttons a single time, repeatedly, or keep them pressed. This anti-fatigue key will ensure that players can enjoy a higher level of customization for their button presses, providing a smoother and more enjoyable gaming experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PlayStation’s newest controller patent can be seen as a highly advanced version of the accessibility controller. This new concept provides players with an even higher range of options, particularly in terms of customization. The patent aims to create a personalized layout that best suits their needs by allowing players to draw custom buttons. </p>



<p>However, it’s important to note that this technology is currently just a patent, and its future is uncertain. Nevertheless, the research and development of this technology could potentially open up more options for future accessibility controllers, further enhancing the gaming experience for all players.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-making-cuts-to-playstation-vr-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rumours</a> of PlayStation scaling back on VR development have emerged while Bluepoint continues to work on an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstations-bluepoint-games-is-still-working-on-an-original-title/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">original title</a>. We’re eager to hear your thoughts on PlayStation’s controller patent. Share your views in the comments below.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-5-ps3-emulation/">PlayStation is working on PS3 emulation for PS5</a>, and sign up to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">receive our newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shadow of the Erdtree Receives First Balancing Patch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-receives-first-balancing-patch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadow-of-the-erdtree-receives-first-balancing-patch.911700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-receives-first-balancing-patch/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>The highly anticipated Shadow of the Erdtree expansion for FromSoftware’s critically acclaimed open-world action RPG has finally arrived. As players embark on their new journey into the Realm of Shadows, they’ve encountered some challenges. </p>



<p>The battles, in particular, have proven to be more demanding than expected, leading to some player frustration. However, the developers have just released a Shadow of the Erdtree balancing patch in response to player feedback, a move that should reassure players that their concerns are being heard and addressed.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Elden Ring <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/news/elden-ring-calibration-update-1122" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Calibration Updat</a>e 1.12.2 is now live, bringing balancing changes and adjustments to PC graphics settings. Regarding balancing, the devs have revised the attack and damage negation curve scaling of the Scadutree Blessing. Now, the attack and damage negation will be “increased for the first half of the maximum amount of Blessing enhancements”, and the second half has been made more gradual. Moreover, there is also a slight increase towards “attack and damage negation granted by the final level of Blessing enhancements“.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The developers noticed a bug in the graphics settings. The ray tracing settings were automatically enabled due to previously loaded save data, which caused unexpected changes in the game’s visual quality and performance. </p>



<p>Players can now check the Ray Tracing Quality settings through the Settings and Graphics Settings options in the title or in-game menu. From this menu, players can set Automatic Ray Tracing Off or On. Lastly, FromSoftware will introduce more balancing updates and bug fixes through upcoming patches.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="ELDEN RING Shadow of the Erdtree | Official Launch Trailer" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M-Xh4vbs6go?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, check out the Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-boss-order/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">boss order</a> and learn whether the expansion has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-shadow-of-the-erdtree-have-achievements-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">achievements</a>. In the comments below, let us know your thoughts on Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree’s latest balancing patch.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-streamer-brainwaves/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how a streamer defeated Shadow of the Erdtree bosses using only brainwaves</a>, and sign up to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">receive our newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Casting of Frank Stone Release Date Possibly Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-casting-of-frank-stone-release-date-possibly-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-casting-of-frank-stone-release-date-possibly-leaked.911697/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-casting-of-frank-stone-release-date-possibly-leaked/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>It looks like the release date of The Casting of Frank Stone has possibly been leaked online. According to a post on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LeaksDBD/comments/1doae9w/the_casting_of_frank_stone_release_date_ingame/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">leaksDBD</a> subreddit, the game is currently scheduled to release on Tuesday, September 3.  </p>



<p>In addition to the game’s release date, there will also be an in-game promotion within Dead by Daylight to hype up it’s release. The leaked release date also featured a QR code that takes you to a “Buy Now” page for the game that currently is offline.</p>



<p>“Step out of The Fog and experience a never-before-seen side of Dead by Daylight with The Casting of Frank Stone, available September 3,” the promotional message reads in the leak. “Decide the fate of four friends in the summer of 1980, and guide their shoot of Murder Mill, a soon-to-be cult classic with an insidious influence.”</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Behaviour Interactive and Supermassive Games regarding the validity of the leaked release date. Should a response be received, this article will be updated accordingly.</p>



<hr>



<p>Do you think the leaked release date for The Casting of Frank Stone is legitimate? For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mortal-kombat-1-dlc-characters/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the new Mortal Kombat 1 DLC characters</a> that have been leaked, and &nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Strange Scaffold announces dark incremental narrative game CLICKOLDING for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/strange-scaffold-announces-dark-incremental-narrative-game-clickolding-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/strange-scaffold-announces-dark-incremental-narrative-game-clickolding-for-pc.911694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/strange-scaffold-announces-dark-incremental-narrative-game-clickolding-for-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher and developer <a title="Companies > Strange Scaffold [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/strange-scaffold">Strange Scaffold</a>, and publisher <a title="Companies > Outersloth [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/innersloth/outersloth">Outersloth</a>, have announced dark incremental narrative game <em><a title="Games > CLICKOLDING" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/clickolding">CLICKOLDING</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,544 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3011440/CLICKOLDING/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch on July 16. <span id="more-895073"></span></p><p>“We exist in a time where it’s hard for a game to be allowed to exist if it doesn’t fit into a clear genre or audience demographic,” said Strange Scaffold studio head Xalavier Nelson Jr. in a press release. “With the support of Outersloth, and a track record for delivering games that don’t take the easy joke but instead use any topic as an opportunity to deliver a deeper experience, I want to make another project that challenges this environment. Another project that says video games should still step into new, uncomfortable, and undeniably compelling spaces.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Strange Scaffold:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>CLICKOLDING</em> is a dark, first-person incremental narrative game that revolves around thumbing a tally counter to satisfy the distressing masked man sitting in the corner of your hotel room. If you leave, you don’t get the money, and you can’t come back. If you stay…</p><p>You won’t be the same. And neither will he.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>With the self-contained mystery of titles like <em><a title="Games > Inscryption [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/inscryption">Inscryption</a></em>, and an emphasis on thoughtfully bringing an uncomfortable and shifting atmosphere to life, <em>CLICKOLDING</em> players will unravel a peculiar story one click at a time. Clicking, solving simple environmental puzzles, and managing a tenuous and uncertain relationship with an uncanny host are the subtle ingredients that make <em>CLICKOLDING</em> more than a suggestive pun.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Lovingly detailed 3D tally counter.</li><li>Polished, mature, one-sitting storytelling from the developers behind <em>Life Eater</em> and <em><a title="Games > El Paso, Elsewhere [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/el-paso-elsewhere">El Paso, Elsewhere</a></em>.</li><li>A surreal encounter with the Original Clickold in a land beyond space and thought.</li><li>Weird jazz from award-winning composer RJ <a title="Games > Lake [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lake">Lake</a> (<em>Space Warlord Organ Trading Simulator</em>, <em>Unbeatable</em>).</li><li>A locked bathroom door.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="CLICKOLDING - ANNOUNCEMENT TRAILER" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6j9Ns3K0OkE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cowboy life simulation game Cattle Country announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/cowboy-life-simulation-game-cattle-country-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cowboy-life-simulation-game-cattle-country-announced-for-pc.911691/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/cowboy-life-simulation-game-cattle-country-announced-for-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>From Blossom Tale series developer Castle Pixel.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Playtonic Friends [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playtonic-games/playtonic-friends">Playtonic Friends</a> and <em>Blossom Tale</em> series developer <a title="Companies > Castle Pixel [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/castle-pixel">Castle Pixel</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Cattle Country" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/cattle-country">Cattle Country</a></em>, a cowboy life <a title="Genres > Simulation [510 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> coming to <a title="Platforms > PC [20,544 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2818150/Cattle_Country/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date was not announced. <span id="more-895052"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2818150/Cattle_Country/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Cattle Country</em> straddles the saddle of cozy wholesome gaming and action adventure. Serving up hours of the slice-of-life you’d expect on the frontier—including mining, fishing, crafting, and farming—along with deep-rooted Wild West Quests delivering stories of romance, cattle drives, bandits, and robberies.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_895051"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Ranchin’ and Handcraftin’</strong> – Making your home on the range is a modern departure. From sunup to sundown, you’ll be rollin’ up your sleeves and gettin’ your hands dirty working the land and raising your cattle. Building and <a title="Genres > Crafting [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> as you go to make your own little slice of heaven under the blues skies of <em>Cattle Country</em>.</li><li><strong>Swappin’ Stories and Settlin’ in With Your Neighbors</strong> – Get to know the townsfolk, hear their stories, help them out. The people here are a hardy bunch- you’ve got be to survive here. But they have hearts as warm as a hearth in the wintertime if you make the effort to stoke the flames.</li><li><strong>Beware of Bandits</strong> – Not everyone in <em>Cattle Country</em> is the warm and <a title="Companies > fuzz" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fuzz">fuzz</a>y type, so watch out for nefarious plots and shady characters. Protect your homestead and your community.</li><li><strong>Rodeos to Romance</strong> – Making friends is a must in the Wilderness, relying on each other through the thick and the thin. But maybe you’ve got a yearnin’ for more? With 18 romanceable characters, take a chance and grab love by the reigns.</li><li><strong>Buried <a title="Companies > Treasure [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/treasure">Treasure</a></strong> – Did yer hear? There’s treasure in the mines, for those who are brave enough to look for it. From precious metals and minerals to bandit stashes. Grab your pickaxe and venture out into the thrill of prospecting.</li><li><strong>Trackin’ Game in the Wild</strong> – From bunnies to bovine, there’s many a critter waiting in the woodlands for a keen <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>r. Hunting to eat or venturing out just to see all of nature’s wonders, it’s your call.</li></ul><p>This is just a taste of the adventures on offer, so throw down roots and work the land. Become part of a story that’s as old as these hills and a part of this small community of settlers. Welcome to <em>Cattle Country</em>!</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/cattle-country/june-26-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Saddle up for Cattle Country! | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-GV3QQnqGZo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Payday 3 Is Getting An "Offline" Mode That Still Requires An Online Connection, For Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-3-is-getting-an-offline-mode-that-still-requires-an-online-connection-for-now/1100-6524507/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/payday-3-is-getting-an-offline-mode-that-still-requires-an-online-connection-for-now.911688/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-3-is-getting-an-offline-mode-that-still-requires-an-online-connection-for-now/1100-6524507/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524507">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Payday 3 has had a rough launch, with its online-only gameplay coming under fire when the game's servers went offline multiple times in its first week of release. Developer Starbreeze said it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-3-dev-apologizes-profusely-for-poor-launch-discusses-potential-offline-mode/1100-6517973/" data-ref-id="1100-6517973">might add an offline mode</a> further down the track, and this week the first iteration of that mode is coming to the game--though it will still require an internet connection for now.</p><p>The new Solo Mode (<a href="https://www.vg247.com/payday-3-offline-solo-mode-beta-boys-in-blue-update" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">via VG247</a>) is launching in beta in Payday 3's next major patch, which arrives on June 27. While players will be able to play most of it offline, they will still need an internet connection to load into Solo Mode, and to upload their progress at the end of a session. In a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r26hIijRoRo" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dev update video</a>, Starbreeze head of community Almir Listo also warned that players will see a drop in performance "since the parts normally front loaded by our servers will now have to be run on your own hardware."</p><p>The developers are aware that it's far from a perfect solution, and have said that this version of Solo Mode is just the first iteration, with a more polished, fully offline option coming later down the track. "This is a stepping stone for a feature to come, not something we're releasing and calling done," Listo added.</p><p>Because the mode is releasing in beta, Starbreeze are also asking players to report any issues they experience while playing. The studio also has plans to improve the mode in future, hoping to add popular features like hosted co-op in future updates.</p><p>Payday 3 has struggled since it came out, facing server issues and low player numbers, and has even seen <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-ceo-is-gone-after-games-bad-start-and-low-player-numbers/1100-6521797/" data-ref-id="1100-6521797">Starbreeze's CEO replaced</a> after the messy launch. The studio plans to continue to patch up the troubled game in an effort titled <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-3-will-add-solo-mode-and-lots-more-in-a-series-of-patches/1100-6521545/" data-ref-id="1100-6521545">Operation Medic Bag</a>, which the addition of Solo Mode is just a small part of. The ongoing updates plan to add new features, fix up existing ones, and add more content to the game.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Movie? There Is "Interest," Dev Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-movie-there-is-interest-dev-says/1100-6524511/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-movie-there-is-interest-dev-says.911685/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-movie-there-is-interest-dev-says/1100-6524511/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524511">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Elden Ring is a huge hit with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-passes-25-million-players-ahead-of-shadow-of-the-erdtree-expansion-launch/1100-6524201/" data-ref-id="1100-6524201">25 million copies sold</a> and fantastic reviews for the base game and its recently released Shadow of the Erdtree expansion. Naturally, many are wondering if Bandai Namco might expand the franchise beyond games to other forms of entertainment, like a potential film. From Software president Hidetaka Miyazaki told <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2022/sep/20/sign-up-for-the-pushing-buttons-newsletter-our-free-video-games-email" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Guardian</a> (<a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/from-software-says-theres-interest-in-an-elden-ring-adaptation/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">via VGC</a>) that the studio isn't ruling anything out.</p><p>"I don't see any reason to deny another interpretation or adaptation of Elden Ring, a movie for example," he said. "But I don't think myself, or From Software, have the knowledge or ability to produce something in a different medium. So that's where a very strong partner would come into play."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1802925818" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464459,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Shadow%20of%20the%20Erdtree%20-%20First%2020%20Minutes%20w%2F%20Commentary&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:1222,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/shadow-of-the-erdtree-first-20-minutes-w-commentary\/2300-6464459\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464459\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464459\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464459\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464459&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464459,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6524511&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;elden-ring&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-one,pc,playstation-4,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;bandai-namco-games,from-software&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464459},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464459\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4322524-gameplayeldlcfirst20_thumb1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/lvonKfW0.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1718920800,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="lvonKfW0" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Shadow of the Erdtree - First 20 Minutes w/ Commentary</p>
      </div>
<p>Miyazaki went on to say that From Software would need to "build a lot of trust and agreement" with a potential partner for an Elden Ring movie. "But there's interest, for sure," he said, though he didn't clarify if the interest is from within From Software or if the company has already been approached for a movie deal, or both.</p><p>Back in 2021, Bandai Namco said Elden Ring was already being developed for a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-is-not-just-a-game-bandai-namco-says/1100-6492709/" data-ref-id="1100-6492709">"variety of other areas,"</a> and many took this to mean some kind of film or TV adaptation. Nothing has materialized as of yet, however.</p><p>There are more than 30 video game film projects in various stages of development right now, and you can see a rundown of them in the gallery below.</p><p>Elden Ring's Shadow of the Erdtree expansion is out now. Here at GameSpot, we scored the expansion a 10/10 in our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-review-kill-them-with-kindness/1900-6418243/" data-ref-id="1900-6418243">Shadow of the Erdtree review</a>. If you're just getting started with the expansion, be sure to check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-guides-hub-classes-summons-and-more/1100-6501032/" data-ref-id="1100-6501032">Shadow of the Erdtree guides hub. </a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition is a retro speedrunning paradise]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/26/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-is-a-retro-speedrunning-paradise/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-is-a-retro-speedrunning-paradise.911664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/26/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-is-a-retro-speedrunning-paradise/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>While online gaming really thrown esports and competitive gaming into the spotlight over the past 15 years, the battle to be the very best gamer in the room goes back much, much further. Ardent gamers have been at it since the “Intergalactic Spacewar Olympics” were held by Stanford University students in 1972, but there’s been the rise and fall of countless gaming competitions in the decades since. While far from being a part of the yearly gaming landscape like Evo or QuakeCon, there’s still a special place in gaming lore for the Nintendo World Championships. And now you can bring that competitive spirit home with Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition.</p>
<p><iframe title="Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition – Survival Mode &amp; Legend Challenge – Nintendo Switch" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GBhA0XdNb94?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It’s actually a little surprising that there’s only been three Nintendo World Championships, with a 25 year wait from the 1990 inaugural event to the anniversary to its anniversary revival in 2015, and then another entry two years later just as the Nintendo Switch was coming to the fore. It’s similarly surprising that it’s taken Nintendo seven years to decide to release a branded tie-in game, but it’s better late than never, right?</p>


<p>Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition, much like Nintendo World Championships Remix on the Wii U and the original Nintendo World Championships 1990 Game Pak that went before it, is all about taking classic NES games and breaking them down into mini stages and tasks for you to try and speed run your way through. That factor alone adds a huge compulsive urge to play, replay, better yourself and best the other names on leaderboard, or rivals who are closer to home.</p>
<p>It starts with 1-1, and a challenge that’s barely 5 or 6 seconds long (if you’re doing things right), to go left to right, hop over a Goomba, hit the second question block, and grab the mushroom that emerges. Seriously, I could play this time and time and time again trying to master it, and getting an S rank is going to require pixel precise jumping. There’s similarly miniscule, but addictive challenges to get you started in The Legend of Zelda, Balloon Fight, Donkey Kong, Metroid, Kirby’s Adventure, Excitebike and all of the 13 games featured here, before building up into longer slices of levels and more varied challenges to test yourself against.</p>


<p>The UI wrapped around this is pretty neat in the Speedrun mode. You always get to see a preview of the task you have before you, to get your eye in, and then you have your current attempt on the left side of the screen and your previous best on the right, and showing your button inputs on screen. Arguably it’s not that important for a six second level, but when you get to a longer challenge, this will let you see how you’re stacking up as you chase down a better time and ranking.</p>
<p>It all builds up to the Legend Challenges, which will really put your skills to the test through minutes, not seconds. These could be clearing the first three Donkey Kong levels, racing through the whole of Super Mario Bros. (using Warp Pipes), or doing the most ridiculous thing imaginable: speedrunning a Kirby level. Legend Challenges come with ‘Classified Information’ pages, styled after classic game guides as they give you a rundown of all the specific tips and tricks that you’ll need to beat the challenge.</p>

<p>Putting a different spin on things are things like Survival Mode, where you face off against ghost data plucked from the internet. It’s a small three round knockout format that drops you in against seven other players and then ditches the bottom half after each level. The three levels are known in advance, with a Silver and Gold ranked competition to enter, but they can appear in a varying order that potentially gives you a better chance of coming out on top. While you have just a single shot for success on each attempt, you can play these over and over, just like pretty much everything else in the game.</p>
<p>And then there’s the Party Mode for local multiplayer with up to eight players, in which you can take on individual levels or curated sequences set to different difficulty levels, with each round awarding points for your finishing position. It’s another fun competitive twist to play side-by-side, especially with some of the game crutches like an automatic rewind meaning that less skilled players can still compete despite the odd mistake. Another nice tweak is that, in addition to the video preview before a challenge, you can also dive into a full practice session to get everyone up to speed.</p>

<p>It’s a bit of a mystery why Nintendo hasn’t made the Nintendo World Championships a more regular event, but it’s neat to see them bringing it back to the living room with Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition, filled with around 150 challenges and a bunch of different ways to play them.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naraka: Bladepoint Is Getting Witcher and Tomb Raider Crossovers]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/naraka-bladepoint-witcher-tomb-raider-crossovers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/naraka-bladepoint-is-getting-witcher-and-tomb-raider-crossovers.911661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/naraka-bladepoint-witcher-tomb-raider-crossovers<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>24 Entertainment and publisher NetEase have announced that&nbsp;<em>Naraka: Bladepoint&nbsp;</em>is getting three new high-profile collaborations to celebrate its third anniversary, as well as a new map, a new weapon type, and more.</p>
<p>In an anniversary livestream, it was revealed that the worlds of&nbsp;<em>The Witcher&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Tomb Raider&nbsp;</em>will be joining&nbsp;<em>Naraka: Bladepoint&nbsp;</em>soon, and the game is also getting a crossover with Chinese novel series&nbsp;<em>Daomu Biji</em>, also known as&nbsp;<em>Time Raider&nbsp;</em>in its movie form.</p>
<p>The&nbsp;<em>Tomb Raider&nbsp;</em>collab is coming this summer and will add a new outfit inspired by heroine Lara Croft. First&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dead-by-daylight-tomb-raider-crossover">Dead by Daylight</a>&nbsp;</em>and now this? She really is a true globetrotter. This summer will also see&nbsp;<em>Daomu Biji&nbsp;</em>hero Kylin Zhang joining the cast of&nbsp;<em>Naraka: Bladepoint&nbsp;</em>as a playable hero.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tomb-raider-naraka-bladepoint.jpg?itok=jspPQ2t1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tomb-raider-naraka-bladepoint.jpg?itok=l8voMeRd 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Lara Croft will soon join the world of&nbsp;<em>Naraka: Bladepoint</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>The second collaboration is with&nbsp;<em>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</em>, whose hero, Geralt, will be appearing in&nbsp;<em>Naraka: Bladepoint&nbsp;</em>later this year. It's not exactly clear what form the collaboration will take; it could see Geralt join as a hero, or it could simply involve new outfits to collect. We'll have to wait and see.</p>
<p>That's not all&nbsp;<em>Naraka: Bladepoint&nbsp;</em>is getting for its birthday, though. A new map, Perdoria, will be introduced "after the July 2nd update", and it will take you into a subterranean city with platform areas designed for combat.</p>
<p>You can also look forward to the Fistblades, a new hand-to-hand combat weapon. It's not quite the "hands" the game <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/april-fools-day-2024-gaming-roundup">promised on April Fools' Day</a>, but it's as close as you're going to get.</p>
<p>Tantalizingly, 24 Entertainment also promises an Easter egg to discover in the new Perdoria map, and it's designed to "provide players with a more immersive adventure experience". Exciting! I wonder what it could be?</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Naraka: Bladepoint</em>, it's a melee combat-focused battle royale game in which up to 60 players duke it out while playing as a variety of colorful heroes.</p>
<p>Since the game's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/naraka-bladepoint-release-date-announced">launch in 2021</a>, it's been updated with a variety of new <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/naraka-bladepoint-new-hero-skill-changes">heroes</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/naraka-bladepoint-heng-sword-season-11">weapons</a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/naraka-bladepoint-anniversary-celebrations-adds-new-campaign-mode">game modes</a>, and it's also enjoyed crossovers with the likes of&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-wo-long-naraka-crossover">Wo Long: Fallen Dynasty</a>&nbsp;</em>and the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/naraka-bladepoint-nier-crossover"><em>NieR&nbsp;</em>franchise</a>.</p>
<p>You can play&nbsp;<em>Naraka: Bladepoint&nbsp;</em>for free right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1203220/NARAKA_BLADEPOINT/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10004405/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/naraka-bladepoint/9p8sqqj5t94b" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox</a>.&nbsp;</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Original Resident Evil available now on GOG, 2 and 3 on their way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/original-resident-evil-available-now-on-gog-2-and-3-on-their-way</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/original-resident-evil-available-now-on-gog-2-and-3-on-their-way.911655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/original-resident-evil-available-now-on-gog-2-and-3-on-their-way<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>PC-playing survival horror fans, I have good news for you. The original version of Resident Evil is now available to purchase via GOG, with "even more blood, graphic violence and gory scenes than the worldwide monster hit version on PlayStation".</p>
<p>This PC release is fully compatible with Windows 10 and Windows 11, and promises new rendering options as well as other Quality of Life improvements, such as improved cutscene timing, an improved game video player and "issue-free" game exit.</p>
<p>At present, Steam only has the HD remake of Resident Evil, rather than this original release.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: For Xbox, could this year finally be the one where it all pays off?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mPVhT_7O0iE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition, GOG's Resident Evil port supports modern controllers.</p>
<p>"Your Special Tactics and Rescue Squad has been choppered to a remote mansion to investigate a biotechnical experiment gone hideously wrong. Before you can say 'mass murder', you're plunged straight into a deathtrap writhing with man-eating freaks, swarming crows and rabid dogs," reads the official blurb.</p>
<p>"Arm yourself with knives and flame-throwers scavenged from dead teammates. Solve puzzles, disarm traps and unearth mysteries. But beware: every move you make draws you deeper into the deadly embrace of Resident Evil."</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Following this release, both Resident Evil 2 and Resident Evil 3 will also be coming to the platform "soon", GOG announced earlier today. These two games will include similar improvements across the board.</p>
<p>According to the Resident Evil 2 <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/resident_evil_2">sales page</a>, this particular release will come with both the original US and the original Japanese version. 4th Survivor and Tofu modes will also be enabled from the very beginning, the page states.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/resident_evil_3">Resident Evil 3</a>, meanwhile, will arrive with Mercenaries Mode included.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>If you are interested, you can scoop up the Resident Evil series' first outing for <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/resident_evil">£8.99</a>, or you can buy the bundle - which will also give purchasers access to both Resident Evil 2 and Resident Evil 3 on their eventual release - for <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/resident_evil_Bundle">£20.99</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Descendant Summer Game Fest Impressions – Let the (Loot) Rain Fall on Me]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-first-descendant-summer-game-fest-impressions-let-the-loot-rain-fall-on-me/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-descendant-summer-game-fest-impressions-%E2%80%93-let-the-loot-rain-fall-on-me.911652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-first-descendant-summer-game-fest-impressions-let-the-loot-rain-fall-on-me/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A good free-to-play action shooter is always on my radar, even if I'm reviewing a dozen other titles at a given time. However, when you're as much of a looker as The First Descendant, then you really have my attention. Showcasing the power of Unreal Engine 5, Nexon Games' upcoming third-person looter shooter has a lot to show for itself in <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-first-descendant-qa-on-the-game-ue5-implementation-and-future-dlss-3-support/">The First Descendant</a>.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/First-Descendant-Assault-Rifle-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Rather than starting from scratch and having to sit through tutorial after tutorial, Nexon Games' opened our session with a brief pitch deck on the general systems and overall vibe of The First Descendant before letting us run free in the open environments. With a wide list of characters unlocked to play through, I opted for the Ultimate variant of one of the fourteen available characters: Ultimate Bunny. With a thigh gap that even the Evergreen could pass through and more skin than Metal Gear Solid V's Quiet, I went with the most photogenic character on the roster. The fact that she came with chain lightning abilities and multiple sniper weapons was just the icing on the peach cake.</p>
<p>In talking with one of my colleagues that also demo'd The First Descendant, they didn't quite understand where to go after being set free in the demo. Truth be told, in the span of 30 minutes, I didn't really have the freedom to explore the hub city and get my bearings straight. Instead, I popped out to the minimap, got a good look at the nine available regions, and then jumped straight into some Void Intercept Battles. Here, instead of learning about the game through tutorial after tutorial, I took my level 40 Ultimate Bunny and challenged a level 34 Executioner Colossus. If I had the foresight, I probably would have picked an enemy that didn't have electric attribute resistance, but it was still a good place to grasp the combat.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/The-FIrst-Descendant-Ultimate-Bunny-Hop.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The First Descendant is a very mobile type of third-person shooter. Staying grounded in one spot and even strafing from side to side won't prevent players from catching a stray bullet to the face. Instead, adding in jumps and a sleek grappling hook helps the player bounce around the battlefield and circle to the backside of an oversized boss and escape attacks coming their way. Having the grappling hook set to the middle mouse button took some getting used to, but with a very short cooldown and a generous range, I could unload a full clip into the boss' weak point, grapple onto a nearby pillar, and hide behind it as cover while I reload. The first Void Intercept battle lasted barely more than a minute even as a first-time player but it certainly helped that I had a sniper rifle that could hit for over 250k damage and killed the boss before I even needed to reload the five-round magazine. All character abilities are cooldown-driven, so there are no extra resources to juggle beyond just having enough bullets on hand. Fodder enemies will occasionally show up in combat, acting as loot pinatas that burst open with recovery items and spare ammo.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Gunplay is quick and snappy in The First Descendant and would be the main draw as a casual non-IAP, or truly free-to-play, player. Nexon granted us level 100 gear that would far exceed what the common player would have access to for hours in the game and the power difference was quite noticeable as the second Void Intercept, a level 54 Devourer, took a bit longer (almost three minutes) to down but without having to break a sweat or even retreat to recover health and shields. That fight took longer simply for the shield mechanics on the boss where I had to seek down these green bubble-covered nodes and destroy them to remove the boss' shielding. I do enjoy when bosses implement new mechanics beyond simply being a bullet sponge and at least this was a challenge to break away from the DPS phase and do something different in the fight. My third Void Intercept was against a level 118 Swamp Walker which kept summoning a bunch of adds and despite my best attempts, couldn't even break its shielding before the 10-minute quest timer elapsed.</p>
<p>For the second portion of my gameplay session, I picked one of the playable regions at random and delved into the arctic region, thinking it to be a good change of pace from the boss arenas although my bunny girl was quite underdressed for the occasion. I had just enough time to eke out a zone recon mission and jump into a few shootouts for loot and glory before my session came to an end. One thing that I'll have to give Nexon praise for is continuing the trend of implementing Korean vocal tracks into your open world exploration. It's a thing I thoroughly enjoyed in Stellar Blade, and I earnestly want the trend to continue.</p>
<p>The First Descendant has had its share of beta test phases and hands-on opportunities but this was one of the last events that Nexon will be showing off the title ahead of its launch next month. Officially launching on July 2nd, 2024, The First Descendant will be available across PlayStation 4/5, Xbox One, Xbox Series S|X, and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2074920/The_First_Descendant/">PC (Steam)</a>.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Descendant Preview - Nexon's Answer to Destiny]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/first-descendant-preview-nexons-answer-to-destiny</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-descendant-preview-nexons-answer-to-destiny.911649/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/first-descendant-preview-nexons-answer-to-destiny<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I'm always on the search for the next "podcast game," as I like to call them. You know the type of game you can just have going on one screen, with videos, music, or podcasts rolling in the background? It might be terrible for the attention span, but <em>The First Descendant</em> fits that criteria to a tee.</p>
<p>Developed in-house by <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/nexon">Nexon</a> is the soon-to-launch <em>The First Descendant</em>, which we saw a fancy new trailer for at Summer Game Fest. I also had the chance to test it out in LA a few short weeks ago, and further access to a pre-launch build was also granted to me. Needless to say, I've already put several hours into <em>The First Descendant</em>, and I might just be hooked.</p>

<h2>Becoming a Descendant</h2>
<p><em>The First Descendant</em> is a massive game, and Nexon is going all gas, no breaks to make it their next hit. Using Unreal Engine 5 to power this beast, <em>The First Descendant</em> boasts top-of-the-line visuals and the polish. It's a looter shooter that has to contend with the likes of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/destiny-2-final-shape-end-to-light-and-darkness"><em>Destiny</em> <em>2</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/tom-clancys-division-2"><em>The Division 2</em></a>, so those are big shoes to fill.</p>
<p>During my play session at Summer Game Fest, I had unrestricted access to pretty much every item, character, and upgrade in the game; likewise, I was able to test this out more in depth using a preview build. There's also a mode that started me fresh, so I got a taste of both the beginning of the game, and end-game.</p>

<p>The beginning of <em>The First Descendant</em> tasks me with choosing a hero, dubbed Descendant, to control -- these are pre-made characters that have a unique set of abilities. I went with Ajax, a tank/bruiser-type hero that specializes in shielding and disrupting foes.</p>
<p>I'm taken through a linear beginner mission to get acquainted with the gameplay of <em>The First Descendant</em>. Here, I learn about my abilities as Ajax and I get familiar with the gunplay and traversal system. Every Descendant is equipped with a grappling hook (because every game needs one, duh), but I can't complain because it's really fun to use.</p>

<h2>Lootin' and Shootin' in <em>The First Descendant</em></h2>
<p>Like any live service game, you're hit with a deluge of information explaining the various systems at play. Don't get too stressed by <em>The First Descendant</em> -- it might not necessarily <em>ease</em> you into things, but you're able to intuit most of the mechanics even if some aren't explained all that well.</p>
<p>You have open-world missions you can partake in these hub areas, as well as more linear dungeon experiences. These can be tackled with friends or others online, so there's a communal element to <em>The First Descendant</em>.</p>
<p>Of course, what I gravitate towards the most is loot and progression, of which there is a <em>lot</em> in this game. First, you level up your descendants and gain more power as you do so, all the while gaining new abilities and looting new weapons and modules to upgrade them with.</p>

<p>Loot is actually my biggest gripe with <em>The First Descendant</em>. There's a decent amount of weapon types, approximately a dozen or so. Weapons within each type feel almost if not exactly the same as the last. The only difference is, you'll have modifiers that make a gun more powerful, but it's not like <em>Borderlands</em> where guns can vary wildly.</p>
<p>Even the modules, which you use to upgrade the stats of your guns, are bland. You get percent increases like increased damage or fire rate, but it's hard to notice a difference. Even modules like "Electric Enhancement," which makes your guns shoot electric-based attacks, doesn't seem to look or feel individualized.</p>
<p>When I tried out a late-game, fully equipped character with the very best weapons and upgrades, I felt more powerful, sure, but weapons behaved the same as they did at lower levels. Looter shooters are so fun because of this unknown element of what the next gun might be, but I'm not really feeling it here.</p>
<p>That said, the guns do feel punchy and enemies go down relatively easy, so you feel powerful. Combine the gunplay with some Descendant abilities, and combat is just enticing enough to keep me engaged. Moving forward, though, I hope for more weapon types and variation in gunplay.</p>

<h2>Will <em>The First Descendant </em>Keep You Hooked?</h2>
<p><em>The First Descendant</em> plays it very by the books, which means it's a safe bet for a fun time, but I do fear for its longevity. Is it unique enough to distinguish itself from others on the market? How long will it take for me to get bored of it?</p>
<p>Because my progress was fast-tracked in the demo, I'm not sure how progression will be, but I hope that core gameplay loop of going out on missions, grabbing materials, and upgrading my descendant is enough to justify playing a game that demands a lot of time.</p>
<p>For now, I'm pretty impressed by the overall package. It's polished, runs decently well (and the implementation of DLSS is appreciated), and I like how individualized the Descendants are with their abilities. We won't have to wait very long to see the final product, which will be available on July 4, 2024.</p>
<hr><p><strong>The First Descendant</strong> <em>was previewed after about 40 minutes of gameplay at Summer Game Fest, and 5 hours with a key provided by the publisher - all screenshots were taken during the preview process.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Riven remake transforms a tricky classic into a modern masterpiece]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/reviews/24185656/riven-review-remake-remaster-pc-steam-vr</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-riven-remake-transforms-a-tricky-classic-into-a-modern-masterpiece.911646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/reviews/24185656/riven-review-remake-remaster-pc-steam-vr<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="sdPJyZ">Back in the early 1990s, the creators of <em>Myst</em> had a problem with their testers. Players would wander around the initial island, poking at the rocket ship, flipping the levers on the podiums up and down, and watching as none of it did anything. The quantity of puzzles was overwhelming, the solutions inaccessible. They’d get bored, and then get frustrated, and then too many of them would give up. </p>

<p id="gKFQRF">The solution was to add a hologram, near the starting point of the game, which contained a recorded message from <em>Myst</em>’s guiding figure, Atrus. And if players missed that room, there was a piece of paper — a piece of paper, <em>loose on the ground — </em>with a note on it that told players — with, like, <em>words</em>! — to go check that room.</p>
<p id="bSsnXa">Today, this would be fixed by making the message room more obvious. Or by starting with the player <em>facing</em> the door, or by putting the room in a privileged position. In the genre of puzzle games in which you explore a series of freaky li’l rooms, environmental storytelling is king. Except the phrase “<a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/environmental-storytelling-creating-immersive-3d-worlds-using-lessons-learned-from-the-theme-park-industry">environmental storytelling</a>” wouldn’t be coined until years after the release of <em>Myst</em> and its expectation-shattering sequel, <em>Riven</em>. </p>
<p id="888JHj">To unpack the legacy of those two games would take another article on its own, but suffice it to say, the genre that developer Cyan Worlds put on the map has done some significant evolving in the 30 years since <em>Myst</em> and <em>Riven</em> were first released. Which is exactly why it’s so fascinating to play this week’s 3D remake of <em>Riven</em>, in which Rand Miller and the rest of the folks at Cyan return to a masterpiece with three decades of environmental puzzle games at their backs. </p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719407789_6347_6411" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25506112,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nCJfbl3iJpROPfEXMcEXAsMTUaw=/0x0:1920x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HT-qmlOJA24d5PuMzo9O0P0tlpI=/0x0:1920x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FmLPMdMStyaRrln2v-LARk3g1DA=/0x0:1920x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_D9cfq554FP0pvVfsxa9SK7FyN0=/0x0:1920x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tT8-G0Os29vkwARjacfEl6ahC1w=/0x0:1920x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QN9illfPByy7v53vg4O4SXEg7vU=/0x0:1920x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8uXcUQdlhOU0_A2cYpqZAqZE8E8=/0x0:1920x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cwsq6wYfcjnzK1xH4fqho8B0rHo=/0x0:1920x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cvhb21kYpsRivpdeBwG0weSusqA=/0x0:1920x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506112/Screenshot__18_.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Cyan Worlds via Polygon</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="BWCTgr"><em>Riven </em>(2024) is a compelling work of preservation. The game’s earliest life began as <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23432662/riven-remake-myst-sequel-cyan-worlds-release-date">the Starry Expanse Project</a>, a fan-run effort to faithfully convert the three hours of video and nearly 5000 images that make up the original <em>Riven</em> into a traversable 3D environment. The final result, after Cyan officially absorbed the Project’s assets and even hired some of its contributors, is — in a word — gorgeous. </p>
<p id="HbVXwe"><em>Riven</em>, after all, is a game of stone, metal, and wood, textures that the Unreal Engine can simulate with its eyes closed, and there are vistas in the remake that, so long as you don’t move your view, you could <em>almost</em> convince yourself are photographs. The other good news for the pleasure centers of fans’ brains is that the original game’s sound design is intact. The meaty thunk-griiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiind-LATCH of Temple Island’s rotating room, the keening screech of metal as a maglev car turns around, the bone-vibrating slam of a fire marble turning over — all are just as you remember them. </p>
<p id="nTNXjF">Also familiar: The loading screens take forever. But for a game that originally prompted you to insert one of five different CD-ROMs every time you moved from one island to another — a core, frequent, and intended part of the gameplay — sitting through a gently disguised loading screen, however long, is a palpable advancement. </p>
<p id="CTh1ZQ">Other parts will <em>not</em> be familiar.</p>
<p id="kbgWAA">Some solutions that remained the same from playthrough to playthrough in the original are now randomized for each save, so cheeky players can’t just look up the answers. The full-motion video actors have been replaced with animated figures, synced to both original and re-recorded dialogue, from necessity. Those 30-year-old recordings simply don’t scale up to modern screens. </p>
<p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719407789_5196_6412" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25506117,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NEGbKKdGZc94dRmvkUCAHnY6yvQ=/0x0:1920x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2_9jFmqjNhiyP5wXq05Wj2lsP20=/0x0:1920x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7HJ8ioq1KxIT5CkRPiSoLtpm_N0=/0x0:1920x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uWnRGOjpFaRaogvhBkkG2qDaJ5E=/0x0:1920x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J1CEV11xR90MvHZwjWv_SqOP0u0=/0x0:1920x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CDB-RbJPSl4ZVMfoEa4vtBV4mIU=/0x0:1920x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vKbb682LJJFqy24ka_QyqwF3JxI=/0x0:1920x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HKzgtMiOwZcw5k1hRfKIltp4d8E=/0x0:1920x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-yjlK0B3pJhBPdLl5lgkhBxS7qw=/0x0:1920x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506117/_03__Riven___PC_Screenshot_3.png 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Cyan Worlds</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719407789_6346_6413" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25506116,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VvNjge4pECov5WX7E9JwF9SkU0c=/0x0:1920x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B43vpiOsGAlL1bffXD9NSow1XmE=/0x0:1920x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lt8ENRO9MoFy3YDlKG8bd44dovc=/0x0:1920x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ib__kBZFtDrtTgBrGqCKRPEZrNI=/0x0:1920x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h9sN_xDTv5IWivB8gGkEzj6FMco=/0x0:1920x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7lRmQ8XsopT7zflnj6ZLGv-HMXU=/0x0:1920x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PFSrSb9EeT7a1HimlLK-mRhXYCY=/0x0:1920x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aok3tGTDonC7E3Xh1PO019if000=/0x0:1920x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IHcpYayNXJUo2Ffbotl7JLIDPLk=/0x0:1920x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25506116/_02__Riven___PC_Screenshot_2.png 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Cyan Worlds</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>



</p>
<p id="ZdTX49">The transition from static images with no need for consistency of euclidean space to a full 3D environment has had a myriad of effects. Some rooms aren’t where they used to be; some modes of travel simply turned out not to work in 3D space. But some tweaks seem fully considered on the part of the developers — and well-chosen. </p>
<p id="rmVuI2">The <em>Riven</em> remake gently gates areas of the game that were originally fully accessible to a new player, yet unsolvable until much later in their playthrough, so as to prevent exactly the kind of overwhelmed frustration that early <em>Myst</em> playtesters experienced. Two of the game’s most involved puzzles have also been completely reworked in ways that were simply not technologically possible in 1997.</p>
<p id="7axwuY">These are not small changes, and I expect some of them may tweak at the nostalgia of longtime fans. But on the other hand, <em>Riven</em>’s most finicky, tedious, time-consuming stumper is here converted into something visually jaw-dropping and engaging to manipulate. </p>
<p id="3zOXlU">If you’re a <em>Riven</em> fan, you simply must play this version. If you’ve never played <em>Riven</em>, there’s no better opportunity. Escaping into another world is not just the external promise of the Myst games, but the actual premise, and <em>Riven</em>’s update brings those two things closer than ever before. </p>
<p id="wQ6rNL"><small>Riven</small><small><em> was released June 25 on Meta Quest VR and Windows PC. The game was reviewed on PC using a pre-release download code provided by Cyan Worlds, Inc. Vox Media has affiliate partnerships. These do not influence editorial content, though Vox Media may earn commissions for products purchased via affiliate links. You can find </em></small><a href="https://www.polygon.com/pages/ethics-statement"><small><em>additional information about Polygon’s ethics policy here</em></small></a><small><em>.</em></small></p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex Destiny and Halo Producer Says Live Service Is 'Better for Developers and Players']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ex-destiny-and-halo-producer-says-live-service-is-better-for-developers-and-players</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ex-destiny-and-halo-producer-says-live-service-is-better-for-developers-and-players.911643/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ex-destiny-and-halo-producer-says-live-service-is-better-for-developers-and-players<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"The games as a service model is so much better."</h2></div><section><p>A former Halo and Destiny executive producer at Bungie has said the live service model is "so much better for developers and players" than the one-off $60 or $70 purchase model.</p><p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/battle-royale/former-halo-and-destiny-producer-says-live-service-model-is-much-better-for-developers-and-players-than-the-dollar60-boxed-product-model/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PC Gamer</a>, Theorycraft Games CEO and former <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2010/09/12/halo-reach-review">Halo: Reach</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2014/09/03/destiny-review">Destiny</a> executive producer Joe Tung said the traditional method of buying video games, meaning to make a single payment of around $60 or $70, causes developers to make decisions which were not "in the best interest" of players.</p><p>"I always felt like, in the $60 boxed product model, I was having to make decisions that were not in the best interest of players," Tung said.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The games as a service model is so much better for developers and players.</p></div><p>"It was in the best interest of: 'How do we sell as many copies in the first 48 hours as we can?' One of the huge strengths of the games as a service model is you can be long term, you can think long term in terms of what is best for the player, and how does that overlap with what is best for the company. I think it allows you to make much, much, much better decisions overall."</p><p>Tung referenced <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/e3-is-dead-for-good">the now defunct E3</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-responds-to-report-about-fake-e3-demo-and-development-issues">the trailers and gameplay clips which premiered there</a>, promising what he called "bulls**t vaporware" that players would never actually get to experience, because all developers had to do was convince them to spend $60.</p><p>"I would wager that any developer who has ever worked in the $60 box product model, up until the point where E3 was cancelled, has a story about the E3 build," he said. "It's like, let's jam as much bulls**t vaporware into the build as we can in the next three months because we have to have a huge showing at E3, because it's our one opportunity to talk to our audience before we launch the game."</p><p>"I would have to wager that some hugely significant percentage of those E3 efforts ended up on the cutting room floor because they were half-baked and caused people to crunch and really make huge sacrifices to get it in," Tung added. "That's my favorite example of hugely impactful decisions that were not about what is best for the player."</p><p>Live service, on the other hand, allows developers to continue working on games after launch, communicate with their audience to see what players actually want, and so on. Tung therefore believes "the games as a service model is so much better for developers and players."</p><p>The topic has proved controversial amongst gamers, with many frustrated that even single player games now have microtransactions, preorder bonuses, early access periods, and so on, and as a result the $60 purchase, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-70-dollar-price-point-aaa-games">which is more commonly $70 in 2024</a>, no longer grants everything a game has to offer.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-responds-to-star-wars-outlaws-season-pass-backlash-insists-jabba-the-hutt-is-part-of-the-experience-for-all-players">Ubisoft titles Star Wars: Outlaws and Assassin's Creed Shadows have both faced criticism for this</a> recently, as both have <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-has-day-one-missions-only-available-through-season-pass-or-by-preordering">missions locked behind more expensive editions</a> and can't be played on their true launch date unless players spend upwards of $100.</p><p>Some developers have seemingly managed to thread the needle between one-off purchase and live service, however, with PlayStation and PC hit Helldivers 2 being the best recent example of a successful game balancing both models.</p><p>It launched for a lesser $40 and still features microtransactions, but its live service components feature incredible depth as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2s-latest-major-order-presents-players-with-a-moral-dilemma-save-sick-kids-or-unlock-a-new-stratagem">the game's story is weaved around them and changes depending on what players can and can't accomplish</a> in timed events.</p><p>This combination appears to have worked as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-review">Helldivers 2 wasn't just received well by critics</a> but <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-playstations-fastest-selling-game-of-all-time-with-over-12-million-sold-in-12-weeks">had sold more than 12 million copies by May 14, 2024</a>.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Between Realism and Abstraction - The Boundaries of Playability]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/between-realism-and-abstraction-the-boundaries-of-playability</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/between-realism-and-abstraction-the-boundaries-of-playability.911640/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/between-realism-and-abstraction-the-boundaries-of-playability<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the world of computer games, developers constantly balance between striving for realism and maintaining playability. Realism in computer games is a powerful tool that can enhance immersion and player engagement. However, an excessive focus on detail and faithful representation of reality can lead to complications that not only affect gameplay fluidity and overall enjoyment but also pose legal and socio-cultural challenges.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In this article, I would like to examine how, during my nearly seven years of employment at </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://jujubee.pl/">Jujubee</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, we faced these challenges, what compromises we had to make, and how they influenced the final reception of our games by the gaming community. I will also explore the lessons that can be learned from these experiences and how they might impact the future of developing computer games that aspire to be realistic.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Jujubee’s approach to Realism"><span>Jujubee’s approach to Realism</span></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Jujubee is a Polish studio that has been active in the computer game market for over a decade. Several years ago, the studio decided to create socially responsible games that address real-world issues. Wanting to develop games with a message, Jujubee consolidated these efforts under the brand Games Beyond, which focuses on games that not only provide entertainment but also have strong reflections of reality.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="KURSK">KURSK</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The first production by Jujubee under the Games Beyond brand was the documentary game "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/860620/KURSK/">KURSK</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">." This game focused on recreating real events from the recent past—the Russian naval maneuvers and the catastrophic sinking of the eponymous submarine Kursk during those exercises. The developers, aside from the historical backdrop, decided to realistically depict the interior of the submarine and other locations. To achieve this, they relied on the few available photographs taken on sister submarines. The situation was complicated by the fact that most of the materials were available exclusively in Russian, making access to sources significantly more difficult. At this stage, one can identify the first problem of creating realistic games—the insufficiency of materials, sources, and information.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The true causes of the disaster and its sequence of events are also unknown, so this gap had to be filled with an abstract scenario. In a situation where a significant portion of individuals who experienced the event, either directly or indirectly, are still alive, crafting an interpretation of reality poses several challenges. The first is the possibility of new information emerging that may reveal inconsistencies or illogical aspects between the presented scenario and the actual events. The second challenge is the risk of offending individuals emotionally involved in the event, which was very apparent during the production of "KURSK."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The third observed problem is the right to use specific materials. Access to military documents of the submarine's crew was possible—in a realistic approach, the ideal solution would have been to create characters with the same names and appropriately modeled appearances. However, licensing issues, the right to likeness, and the feelings of the families of those who perished on the submarine stand in the way.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The fourth, more obvious aspect is finding a balance between depicting the truth and what will be interesting for the player. Game design has its own rules; players have become accustomed to certain patterns and solutions and have specific expectations regarding the tasks presented to them. Reality usually appears much simpler and duller—there is no point in engaging the player in several days of observing maneuvers from the submarine's perspective before the disaster occurs. In a realistic approach, they would spend most of the game standing next to the captain, listening to orders being given and received communications, only to later experience a brief episode with the disaster.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The fifth encountered problem is, of course, the budget. Faithfully recreating realism is associated with significantly higher costs—primarily, there is no possibility of using ready-made assets, or this possibility is very limited. More time needs to be devoted to gathering source material, verifying facts, and adjusting mechanics and storyline to them. Often, it will be necessary to purchase additional licenses, such as music from a given period or the rights to use trademarks or specific models.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Truck Simulation 19">Truck Simulation 19</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Continuing the discussion on licensing rights, it is worth looking at another game from the studio—</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.astragon.trucksimtwo&amp;hl=en_US">Truck Simulation 19</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The idea behind this production was to create a mobile truck simulator. To maximize realism, it was necessary to obtain licenses to use real truck models in the game. Besides the obvious financial considerations, it is important to remember that such licenses can come with additional requirements. For example, all trucks must have the same parameters to avoid presenting players with better and worse options. Only customization offered by the manufacturers is allowed—meaning all additional stickers, paint jobs, or super-tuning are excluded. Trucks cannot be shown in a negative light, which means forgoing damage systems or vehicle dirt. Moreover, using the vehicles for illegal purposes, such as street racing or transporting prohibited cargo, may also be disallowed. Licensing issues can thus force the abandonment of certain gameplay ideas but can also block some realistic aspects in games.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Take Off Flight Simulator">Take Off Flight Simulator</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The second simulator released for mobile devices is the flight simulator </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/take-off-the-flight-simulator-switch/">Take Off</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. In this game, the player takes on the role of a pilot building their airline company in the Hawaiian Islands. In this case, budget considerations led to the decision to forgo accurate representation of real aircraft, and instead, planes were created solely inspired by real models.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Originally, the game's idea was to enable the most faithful feeling of controlling an aircraft, with accurate physics and the behavior of the machine during winds, weather changes, and altitude differences, considering the size and type of the aircraft and its parameters. The problem encountered here was the computational power of mobile devices. Developing a game for mobile devices involves significantly less computational power than for PCs, so it was necessary to greatly simplify the physics and abandon realism in favor of accessibility on a larger number of devices.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Another realistic element that had to be abandoned was the realistic number of parameters that the pilot must control and the handling of individual mechanisms in the aircraft. Creating a true-to-life simulator that faithfully reproduces a pilot's work would significantly reduce the player base—few possess the skills that would allow them to enjoy such a game.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Deep Diving Adventures">Deep Diving Adventures</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/990030/Deep_Diving_Simulator/">Deep Diving Simulator</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, also known as Deep Diving Adventures, is a deep-sea diving simulator. A significant emphasis in this game was placed on realistically portraying the ocean floor with its flora and fauna, realistic aspects, problems and dangers of diving, and environmental conservation.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The first reason for deviating from realism here was age-related requirements and associated restrictions. In many markets, there are varied requirements for games aimed at children, making it impossible to include real weapons in the game—which were intended for fighting predators or removing obstacles. It was necessary to create a sound gun that only scared away aggressive fish with ultrasound and disintegrated obstacles with a laser without any shots.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The lack of weapons also ties into social issues and expectations for this type of game—we have all heard about the problems Assassin’s Creed faced related to hunting endangered fish species. Society is more accepting of killing monsters and humans in games, but when it comes to animals, especially rare ones, there is an outcry. Social expectations for environmental care are very high, and in the case of realistic games, there are expectations to align with this narrative.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The third aspect that had to be considered when deciding on the level of realism in this game was player knowledge. People entirely unfamiliar with diving will not understand why rapid changes in depth cause a decrease in health points, why the player automatically receives cold damage at lower levels, or that some marine creatures, though seemingly harmless, can be dangerous. It was necessary to decide what the player would be able to grasp or how to explain it effectively and quickly.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Covid the Outbreak">Covid the Outbreak</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1287000/COVID_The_Outbreak/?l=polish">Covid the Outbreak</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, or Virus the Outbreak, is a strategy game that was created as an artistic and social manifesto by the developers confined to their homes. The very short production period allowed for the release of a game created during the pandemic, about the pandemic, and for the pandemic. In this game, the player assumes the role of the director of the Global Health Organization, who can persuade all countries around the world to take specific actions in the fight against the virus. The game's goal was to show why governments make certain decisions and what impacts they will have—how to balance social, economic, tourism, and cultural issues in the face of combating the disease.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This type of game faced significant resistance due to its subject matter—once again highlighting the prevailing belief in society that games should not touch on important topics and are considered a lesser, less responsible medium.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Another problem encountered during this production was emotions—the aversion to the pandemic and the negative feelings associated with it carried over to the game's reception. The game caused a great stir—for example, the thread dedicated to it on the GOG store became one of the most popular topics, surpassing the biggest releases in terms of the number of comments.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The third problem related to this production was differing opinions. The developers tried to take a neutral approach—explaining the arguments of both sides, such as stating, “Lockdown is necessary to limit the spread of the virus, but the longer it lasts, the greater the socio-economic problems it may cause.” Extremist supporters did not appreciate this centrist approach.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The fourth problem was the prohibition and banning of certain words and topics. To release the game on some consoles, it was necessary to change the title to “VIRUS” and remove all references to COVID (even though the game depicted a completely different disease variant set in the future). For some sales platforms, even this change was insufficient, and they refused to publish a production concerning even an abstract pandemic—resulting in the game not being released on all devices.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The fifth problem was marketing issues and large corporations reducing the reach of certain keywords. As a result, not only did official materials and sponsored content have significantly lower reach, but gameplay videos from independent influencers were also demonetized, causing reluctance to record the game.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Realpolitiks Series">Realpolitiks Series</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1248060/Realpolitiks_II/">The Realpolitiks</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> games represent the cornerstone series for the company. As a grand strategy game set in real-time and contemporary times, it fills a niche left by Paradox, which is reluctant to undertake such realistic titles.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The first problem with realism in this series lies primarily in geopolitical conflicts—not just the delineation of borders, but also the names of countries, regions, and seas. For example, Japan does not recognize the name "East China Sea." Using this term not only resulted in threats against the developers but also led to the game being massively reported to Steam.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Contemporary issues such as terrorism, wars, refugees, and political opinions evoke strong emotions, controversies, and aversion. Many publishers are hesitant to tackle such topics. A company that tries to include them in its productions, even while maintaining full neutrality, must be prepared for negative reactions from the media, influencers, and some gamer communities.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Another obstacle to realism in games is banned symbols. Contrary to appearances, this list is quite extensive and, in addition to swastikas, also includes the international red cross symbol and various local symbols. An example is the first installment of the series, where it was necessary to remove the flag of the Islamic State from the game.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The next aspect is the expectation to combat harmful attitudes, especially when it concerns contemporary times. For example, in Stellaris, a player can create a fascist state enslaving all other nations in the galaxy without negative reception. However, in a strategy set in our times, calling the Belarusian government authoritarian rather than totalitarian caused many expressions of dissatisfaction.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It is also worth noting that with realistic games, many people engage in personal crusades against a particular topic. Again, referring to the first part of the series, the inclusion of the Silesian nationality resulted in several negative reviews from opponents of this solution.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A problem with realistic games is also the changing narrative in mainstream media. What was acceptable at the beginning of production can become forbidden and unwanted after several years of developing the game. For instance, during the production of Realpolitiks 3, the perception of Palestine and Israel, as well as migration issues to Europe, changed significantly.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Punk Wars">Punk Wars</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A less problematic approach to realism can be observed in the fantastical game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1541790/Punk_Wars/">Punk Wars</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. According to the studio's philosophy, every game must reference contemporary issues, so here they decided to show the dangers that excessive faith in technology, corporatism, and continuous industrialization can bring—leading to an apocalypse and the takeover of power by fanatical corporations trying to rebuild humanity.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">However, even such a large dose of speculative fiction must meet the expectations of realism among players—mainly in the form of certain patterns and beliefs already ingrained in the audience. If a faction wants to use steampunk technology, it must be consistent with the entire vision of that setting—meaning lots of clocks, gears, and specific colors. The same applies to dieselpunk, atompunk, and steelpunk. Players react negatively to breaking certain conventions derived from realism—real technological limitations or cultural sources different from those presented in the game.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Dark Moon">Dark Moon</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1105330/Dark_Moon/">Dark Moon</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" is an upcoming survival strategy game set in the near future, during the early stages of moon colonization. The player takes on the role of an employee of a large corporation, who is caught by a solar flare during a lunar mission, leading to the destruction of all electronics exposed to sunlight. The player must expand their mobile base and stay on the dark side of the moon, racing against time and the encroaching sunlight.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To give the catastrophe a realistic touch, the studio consulted with a satellite constructor to learn about satellite safeguards and procedures for such disasters. However, finding experts with such specialized knowledge who were willing to share it proved challenging. Several times, they faced refusals from NASA employees and academic lecturers. Thus, the problem here is the availability of experts or consultants.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="The Slavs">The Slavs</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The last production mentioned in this article is "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://jujubee.pl/?page_id=12">The Slavs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">," an unreleased turn-based strategy game focusing on the culture and beliefs of the Slavs compared to other ethnic groups in early medieval Europe. This game is fundamentally a cultural project, heavily based on realism, true sources, and history. Such productions enjoy great popularity in Poland and are strongly supported by the state. In this case, Jujubee received a grant to create a prototype of a strategic game about Slavic culture and history, funded by the Minister of Culture and National Heritage as part of the Creative Industry Development Center's "video game support program" under the task "creating prototypes of cultural video games" amounting to 261,678 PLN.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">During the production, they encountered problems related to the scarcity of sources and studies. The topic of the Slavs is not very popular or overexploited in pop culture but has a dedicated fan base. Thus, there was a problem with satisfying two extremely different audiences—those with extensive knowledge and those with none at all.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Another problem with creating games based on such sources, which are often tales and legends rather than real chronicles written by historians, is balancing realism and gameplay with mythology. Mythological and legendary events often contradict basic historical knowledge, creating another problem in choosing the game's content.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Lastly, cognitive biases in players present a problem. Pop culture has taught us certain patterns, but in the case of realistic references, these are often incorrect patterns (e.g., Vikings wearing horned helmets). For the Slavs, the biggest culprit is the local "The Witcher" series—widely perceived as a model of Slavic culture, but in reality, it draws more from Germanic mythology. The challenge is to confront players' expectations and understanding of Slavic culture with a realistic portrayal of its elements.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Summary">Summary</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Creating realistic games can take various forms. Realism does not always mean faithful representation in game mechanics but can also manifest as historical games, those based on cultural texts, or those reflecting current, real-world events. Realism can bring numerous benefits to a game, but it also entails additional challenges for developers—from the design phase, through production, to release, marketing, and product support. Often, it is only after years that it becomes clear whether the chosen approach was correct or not.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Examining 11 games designed with a high degree of realism, the following issues were identified:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ol data-testid="basic-list-ordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Shortage or excess of information and sources:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Problems with the availability or excess of historical, scientific, and cultural information can affect the game's authenticity.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Entrenched stereotypes:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Players may have ingrained false perceptions, which influence their expectations of the game.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Emotional approach to the subject:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> The game's theme can evoke strong emotions and controversies, affecting its reception.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Common perception of games:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> There is a belief that games are a less ambitious and mature medium, which may limit their acceptance in society.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Boundary between realism and playability:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Developers must balance between realistic representation of reality and what is attractive and playable.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Licensing restrictions:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Licenses for real elements (like vehicles, buildings) may come with restrictions that impact game content.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Budget constraints:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Realism often requires higher financial outlays, which can be a challenge for developers.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Difficulty in customer segmentation:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Limitations arising from varying levels of players' familiarity with the game's subject matter.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cognitive biases:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Players may have false perceptions of the facts presented in the game.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Top-down prohibitions and mandates:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Some topics may be banned or restricted by authorities, affecting the game's content.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>High controversy:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Realistic games may provoke controversies that influence their reception.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Reduced marketing reach:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Problems with promoting games with controversial themes.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Age requirements:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Restrictions resulting from the age classification of games.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Social issues:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Games may be criticized for addressing sensitive social topics.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Computing power:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Technological limitations affecting the game's realism.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Player skills:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> The complexity of the game must be adapted to the average player's abilities.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Habits from other games:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Players may expect certain patterns from other games, which may conflict with a realistic approach.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Balance between truth and attractiveness:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Developers must find a balance between faithfully depicting reality and what will be interesting to the player.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Emergence of new information:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> New sources and changing narratives can impact the game's reception.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cultural differences:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Cultural issues can influence how the game is perceived in different regions.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Geopolitical conflicts:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Contemporary conflicts and territorial disputes can affect the game's content.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Availability of consultants and experts:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Difficulties in finding experts willing to collaborate.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Reluctance to certain topics:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Some topics may be difficult for publishers and players to accept.</span></p></div></li></ol></div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Thus, realism in games can bring many benefits but also comes with numerous challenges. Developers must be prepared to face many issues to achieve the desired effect and create a product that is both authentic and attractive to players.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari acquires Surgeon Simulator franchise through Infogrames label]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/atari-acquires-surgeon-simulator-franchise-through-infogrames-label</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari-acquires-surgeon-simulator-franchise-through-infogrames-label.911637/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/atari-acquires-surgeon-simulator-franchise-through-infogrames-label<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Atari-owned publishing label Infogrames has acquired the Surgeon Simulator franchise from Tinybuild.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Surgeon Simulator is over a decade old, having debuted with the release of the original title in 2013. Since then, the franchise has expanded with a VR spin-off called </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Surgeon Simulator VR: Meet the Medic</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It also ventured onto Switch in the form of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Surgeon Simulator CPR</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, before a full-blown sequel, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Surgeon Simulator 2: Access All Areas</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, was released in 2020.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Infogrames hopes to expand distribution, potentially develop new titles or content, and explore brand and merchandising collaborations as part of a long-term plan to "preserve and expand" the series. The company didn't disclose how much it paid for the franchise.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Atari and Infogrames are back in the mix">Atari and Infogrames are back in the mix</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This is the second acquisition Infogrames has made since being </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/atari-relaunches-infogrames-immediately-buys-totally-reliable-delivery-service">revived by Atari in April</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The company previously purchased Totally Reliable Delivery Service (also from Tinybuild).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Atari said it resurrected Infogrames to acquire IP and publish games that fall outside the core portfolio associated with its brand.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Infogrames intends to actively manage its catalog of titles by expanding digital and physical distribution, and developing new collections and sequels. Consistent with Atari’s approach, Infogrames sees game preservation as a core component of its mission," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamespress.com/en-GB/Acquisition-Announcement---Publisher-Atari-Acquires-Surgeon-Simulator-">reads a press release</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Atari has expanded significantly in recent years with the acquisitions of studios including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/atari-acquires-system-shock-remake-developer-nightdive-for-up-to-19-5-million">Nightdive Studios</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/atari-to-acquire-preservation-and-restoration-studio-digital-eclipse-for-up-to-20-million">Digital Eclipse</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It also nabbed the rights to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Rollercoaster Tycoon 3 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">from Frontier Developments.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surgeon Simulator Acquired by Infogrames, nee Atari, nee Infogrames]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/surgeon-simulator-acquired-by-infogrames</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/surgeon-simulator-acquired-by-infogrames-nee-atari-nee-infogrames.911628/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/surgeon-simulator-acquired-by-infogrames<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Atari's distribution and publishing subsidiary Infogrames (formerly known as Atari, itself formerly known as Infogrames) has purchased the&nbsp;<em>Surgeon Simulator&nbsp;</em>IP from former owner tinyBuild.</p>
<p>In a press release, Infogrames head Geoffroy&nbsp;Châteauvieux says the IP represents "a popular and unique franchise" with a "timeless appeal", and that it's exciting to have&nbsp;<em>Surgeon Simulator&nbsp;</em>on the Infogrames label.</p>
<p>Infogrames says it plans to "expand distribution" of the IP, as well as potentially developing new games in the series. Additionally, the label will "explore brand and merchandising collaborations". Could this mean a&nbsp;<em>Surgeon Simulator&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dead-by-daylight-tomb-raider-crossover"><em>Dead by Daylight&nbsp;</em>crossover</a>? Probably not, but hey, who knows?</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/surgeon-simulator-ip-infogrames-gameplay.jpg?itok=bZS5tncu 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/surgeon-simulator-ip-infogrames-gameplay.jpg?itok=zbwDNv0P 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Surgeon Simulator&nbsp;</em>is now in the care of Infogrames. Let's hope they treat it better than this patient is being treated.</figcaption></figure><p>This is the second casual sim-style IP Infogrames has acquired since it was revived as a label back in April. The first is&nbsp;<em>Totally Reliable Delivery Service</em>, the acquisition of which was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atari-infogrames-publishing-revival">announced alongside the label's revival</a>.</p>
<p>The divestment of&nbsp;<em>Surgeon Simulator&nbsp;</em>fits with former publisher tinyBuild's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tinybuild-financials-2023">shift towards the purported "1000-hour game"</a>, i.e. live-service games or titles that can be played repeatedly rather than one-and-done affairs.</p>
<p>It's certainly true that players return to&nbsp;<em>Surgeon Simulator&nbsp;</em>time and time again, but it's not along the same lines as games like&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike&nbsp;</em>or&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/level-zero-extraction-release-date"><em>Level Zero: Extraction</em></a>, the latter of which is one of tinyBuild's upcoming games.</p>
<p>This also isn't the first time Atari and tinyBuild have done business. Back in late December, Atari <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atari-tinybuild-investment">invested $2 million in the publisher</a>, meaning Atari currently holds around 7.5% of tinyBuild's total share capital.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/surgeon-simulator-ip-infogrames-leaderboard.jpg?itok=2eURseCV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/surgeon-simulator-ip-infogrames-leaderboard.jpg?itok=_9eP7hoE 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>We may well see more&nbsp;<em>Surgeon Simulator&nbsp;</em>games from Infogrames in future.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Surgeon Simulator</em>, it's a series of casual, light-hearted simulation games in which the objective is, well, to perform surgery.</p>
<p>The setup is complicated somewhat by an intentionally tricky control scheme and a variety of wacky scenarios; this very much isn't a realistic surgery sim. If you want one of those, you might be better off with&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/autopsy-simulator-2024"><em>Autopsy Simulator</em></a>.</p>
<p>We'll have to wait and see what Infogrames intends to do with the&nbsp;<em>Surgeon Simulator&nbsp;</em>IP, but it certainly sounds like we haven't heard the last of it. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring's most popular mods make Shadow of the Erdtree far easier]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-most-popular-mods-make-shadow-of-the-erdtree-far-easier</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-rings-most-popular-mods-make-shadow-of-the-erdtree-far-easier.911625/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-most-popular-mods-make-shadow-of-the-erdtree-far-easier<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Punish the DLC instead of it punishing you!"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ER_SOTE_screenshot-(9).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
As Elden Ring players struggle with the high difficulty of Shadow of the Erdtree, the most popular mods since release focus on easing the challenge.
</p>
<p>
Over on <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/popular/">NexusMods</a>, plenty of new mods have already been uploaded since the launch of the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-tips-and-tricks">Elden Ring DLC</a> last week, ready for PC players to enter the Land of Shadow.
</p>
<p>
Many of these mods provide a save file to ensure players are ready for the DLC. To access the new quest, two specific bosses in the base game must be defeated - unless you've got a mod to do that for you, like those from <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5181">byDelamain</a> or <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5241">Yticaya</a>.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="7 Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree Beginners Tips - A REFRESHER COURSE FOR FORGETFUL TARNISHED" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JblbR93fNDk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>7 Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree Beginners Tips - A REFRESHER COURSE FOR FORGETFUL TARNISHED</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JblbR93fNDk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JblbR93fNDk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>7 Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree Beginners Tips<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JblbR93fNDk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>

Yet difficulty has proven contentious for Shadow of the Erdtree, with lots of mods aiming to make it easier. 
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5216">Syyyke's All in One Cheat Version</a>, for instance, includes free weapon and spirit upgrades, the ability to block all attacks without impacting stamina, and a Grand Merchant with access to any items. The mod is yet to be implemented on new DLC items.

</p>
<p>
Similar to that Grand Merchant, <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5192">Tom Clark's Glorious Merchant</a> has free access to every item for whatever build you want to make, and it's DLC compatible.

</p>
<p>
Alternatives include <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5229">Sereenaty's Unlimited Power mod</a> that adds free levelling, and <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5240">MaliceKy's mod</a> that provides a character at level 713 with maxed stats, maxed Blessings, and the base game fully completed with all gear acquired. There's also <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5080">justcookie68's mod</a> to summon bosses for help, or <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5178">GreyEnigma's mod</a> to reduce grinding.




</p>
<p>
And then there's Sereenaty's other mod, offering <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5244">Wolverine Mode</a>. Here players take 50 percent less damage, regenerate health and FP, do double damage, can recover runes immediately, and have infinite use of Blessing of Marika. "Punish the DLC instead of it punishing you!" they exclaim.
</p>
<p>
I'm also intrigued by <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/5207">Noctis' Graceborne mod</a> that adds a Bloodborne-inspired overhaul for a "more grim and sinister experience". It includes trick weapons and firearms that parry, removes equipment load, and switches lighting to permanent nighttime. It's in the early stages, but ideal for those waiting for a Bloodborne sequel (good luck with that).

</p>
<p>
Earlier today, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-patch-revises-shadow-realm-blessing-balance">FromSoftware added a patch to Elden Ring</a> to adjust the balance scaling of the Blessings in Shadow of the Erdtree, after players found the difficulty too high.

</p>
<p>
If you're wondering <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-to-do-first-in-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree">what to do first in Shadow of the Erdtree</a>, then check out our guide to get you started.


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 developers have big, opaque plans for Galactic War and that black hole you made]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-developers-have-big-opaque-plans-for-galactic-war-and-that-black-hole-you-made</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-developers-have-big-opaque-plans-for-galactic-war-and-that-black-hole-you-made.911622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-developers-have-big-opaque-plans-for-galactic-war-and-that-black-hole-you-made<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Game development studio and intergalactic war ministry Arrowhead have launched a new series of written update posts for players of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> to help keep the war record straight. Mostly, this is the usual case of somebody on the team gathering quotes as the developers batter their fingertips against keyboards to bring you, the video gamer, fresh cannons and what-have-you. But there is some insight into what the conflict-pushers at Arrowhead have enjoyed most about player actions over the last month, including bringing an entire planet to the liberated state of post-existence.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>To sum it up, the government is pleased with its soldiers. They judge the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-major-order-turns-planet-into-black-hole-as-rumours-of-returning-illuminate-faction-intensify">recent destruction of the planet Merida</a> as fortuitous, and the appearance of the black hole that showed up to replace it as "a reminder of all the hard-won battles that brought us here." That's according to mysterious game master Joel, who is also pleased at the speculation surrounding this black hole. "Keep it coming!" he says.</p>
<p>Now that this planet (and its supercolony of bugs) is gone, the studio is redirecting its players' vitriol towards the robotic Automaton enemies. </p>
<p>"[We] have discovered that the Automatons are planning a massive terraforming project on Cyberstan," says the post. "Obviously, we cannot allow them to continue with this plan... it's finally time to launch a counteroffensive against them to dismantle their unjust and illegal occupation."</p>
<p>It's more of the classic war-chat that makes Helldivers 2 such a popular playable inside joke. If you enjoy this ongoing back and forth between player and developer, there are hints that the dev team is seeking to make some "improvements" to Joel's role in directing the wartorn universe. </p>
<p>"I’m very excited to see the future improvements we want to make to the Galactic War and all the tools we have planned for the Game Master," says production director, Alex Bolle. "One of our pillars for the future is to focus on playing with (or against) the community, and what I see so far tells me that we’ll have a lot of fun."</p>
<p>The director also reiterated the studio's reasoning for reducing the number of updates to the game, in favour of more infrequent and thorough patches.</p>
<p>"We see our relationship with players like being a showman, and [we want to] delight them with regular updates," said Bolle. "But we noticed that those hotfixes became too usual for us to focus on bigger content. Rethinking our cadence helps us reach the quality expected, and incorporate more thorough bug fixes... We want to extend our bug fixing periods so that we pick up the biggest flaws earlier."</p>
<p>You can read all the Helldiver histrionics for yourself in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/4183362170401345632?l=english">the update post on Steam</a>. It's mostly a round-up of information players already know, but it's still a useful summary for anyone who doesn't tie themselves with patriotic fervour to every tweet and textbox. They'll do a similar post next month, they say, following whatever shenanigans are due to erupt in the meantime. Perhaps the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-cutting-edge-warbond-is-out-sparking-fresh-debate-about-the-illuminates-faction">long-rumoured third enemy faction, the Illuminate</a>, will have appeared by then? Who can say.</p>
<p>Helldivers 2 is built upon a running gag of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-not-just-helldivers-2-plenty-of-games-owe-a-lot-to-the-films-of-paul-verhoeven">Verhoeven proportions</a>. It's funny! But I do find a joke gets stale when you keep telling it over and over. I very much enjoy the satire of Starship Troopers, its principal inspiration, but that movie has the benefit of being 2 hours long. A luxury not shared by a video game designed to be replayed mission after mission. It will be interesting to see how the developers aim to keep the japes fresh.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Is Finally Back on PC via GOG, Resident Evil 2 and 3 to Follow]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-is-finally-back-on-pc-via-gog-resident-evil-2-and-3-to-follow</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-is-finally-back-on-pc-via-gog-resident-evil-2-and-3-to-follow.911619/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-is-finally-back-on-pc-via-gog-resident-evil-2-and-3-to-follow<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The original Resident Evil is now finally available on PC again thanks to a collaboration between Capcom and CD Projekt-owned storefront GOG.</p><p>An <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/news/capcom_and_gog_join_forces_to_release_the_original_resident_evil_trilogy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announcement</a> from the latter revealed the classic Resident Evil, not the remastered version, is now available on the store for $9.99. GOG also announced that Resident Evil 2 and Resident Evil will join it sometime in 2024, and a $24.99 bundle is available for those who want all three games.</p><p>Resident Evil originally arrived on PC in 1996 but didn't exist on any digital storefronts until now. Steam, which has the remastered version but not the original, is expected to get the classic version soon, however, as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/looks-like-the-original-resident-evil-is-coming-back-to-pc">a listing for it was spotted on European rating website PEGI</a>.</p><p>"In joint efforts with the original creators Capcom, we’re thrilled to announce the re-release of the original Resident Evil, the groundbreaking series that heralded the golden age of the survival horror genre," GOG said in the post.</p><p>"This iconic classic is now available with all its original content intact, featuring quality of life improvements and enhanced compatibility for modern systems. As part of GOG’s ongoing effort to protect and preserve classic games, Resident Evil is now available on the DRM-free GOG store."</p><p>The original Resident Evil is where the beloved franchise began, of course, but has been somewhat overlooked in recent years as Capcom favors developing new entries in the franchise as well as full remakes of older games.</p><p>These began with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/01/22/resident-evil-2-review">Resident Evil 2</a>, however, completely skipping the original, and have so far continued to include <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-3-final-review">Resident Evil 3</a> and the fan-favorite <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-4-remake-review">Resident Evil 4</a>. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-zero-and-code-veronica-remakes-reportedly-in-the-works-at-capcom">Capcom is reportedly working on remakes of Resident Evil Zero and Code Veronica too</a>, alongside a mainline ninth game.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Latest Elden Ring: Shadow Of The Erdtree Update Should Make Your Journey A Bit Easier]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/26/the-latest-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-update-should-make-your-journey-a-bit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-latest-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-update-should-make-your-journey-a-bit-easier.911616/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/26/the-latest-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-update-should-make-your-journey-a-bit<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>The one and only Elden Ring expansion we're getting, Shadow of the Erdtree, launched last week and thousands of Tarnished went to the shadow realm to take on dozens of new enemies, bosses, and more. Now, just a few days later, developer From Software has released a new patch for the game that should make Shadow of the Erdtree a bit easier.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now live, Calibration Update 1.12.2 targets the scaling of the attack and damage negation given to players with each Shadow Realm Blessing upgrade. Here's what's changed:&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
	<li>The attack and damage negation has been increased for the first half of the maximum amount of Blessing enhancements, and the second half will now be more gradual.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>The attack and damage negation granted by the final level of Blessing enhancements has been slightly increased.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P6JIclaNO84" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>This patch should apply automatically like any other Elden Ring update but if it doesn't – the Calibration Version listed at the bottom right reads "1.12.2" if it has – select "LOGIN" and that will apply the latest version of the game.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The only other thing this <a href="https://www.bandainamcoent.com/news/elden-ring-patch-notes-version-1-12-2">update</a> contains is word from From Software on a confirmed bug where the raytracing settings of Shadow of the Erdtree are automatically enabled (if you've previously loaded save data from previous game versions), which is causing framerate issues for some players. If you're encountering said issues, check to see if you have raytracing on or off in the game's system graphical settings.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This patch arrives after one that hit the game last week, which added <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/20/new-elden-ring-patch-adds-hairstyles-new-inventory-features-balance-adjustments-and">new hairtsyles, inventory features, balance adjustments, and more</a> to Elden Ring ahead of Shadow of the Erdtree's launch.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For more about the game, read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree/an-emphatic-exclamation-point"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree review</a>, and then check out this interview where <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/interview/2024/06/24/from-softwares-hidetaka-miyazaki-discusses-his-approach-to-difficulty">From Software's Hidetaka Miyazaki discusses his approach to difficulty</a> in games.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><em>What do you think of this update? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortal Kombat 1 to receive Terminator and Conan the Barbarian DLC characters, dataminer suggests]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-1-to-receive-terminator-and-conan-the-barbarian-dlc-characters-dataminer-suggests</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mortal-kombat-1-to-receive-terminator-and-conan-the-barbarian-dlc-characters-dataminer-suggests.911610/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-1-to-receive-terminator-and-conan-the-barbarian-dlc-characters-dataminer-suggests<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Conan_eXIKluh.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Universal Pictures/20th Century Fox</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>It looks like Conan the Barbarian and T-1000 from the Terminator series may be coming to Mortal Kombat 1.</p>
<p>According to dataminer <a href="https://x.com/interloko/status/1805357202481594595">Interloko</a>, six more characters will be coming to NetherRealm's fighter, likely as part of the next DLC pack, as well as two arenas and five new announcers.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: For Xbox, could this year finally be the one where it all pays off?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mPVhT_7O0iE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Leaked Mortal Kombat 1 characters from <a href="https://x.com/interloko">Interloko</a>'s datamining efforts are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Cyrax</li>
<li>Sektor</li>
<li>Noob Saibot</li>
<li>Ghostface (Scream)</li>
<li>Conan the Barbarian</li>
<li>T-1000 (Terminator)</li>
</ul>
<p>The inclusion of Ghostface in this list isn't exactly a surprise. Last year, dataminers managed to <a href="https://twitter.com/thethiny/status/1703601270953513035">unearth evidence</a> that alluded to some unannounced DLC content, and Scream's masked slasher was included in a list of voice lines that were discovered in the game. Mortal Kombat's cyborg Cyrax was also included here.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, back in September, Mortal Kombat boss Ed Boon shared an image of some of media's most famous slasher-flick faces, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ed-boon-gets-tongues-wagging-with-ghostface-and-jigsaw-tease-for-mortal-kombat-1">Ghostface was present among them</a>. Many surmised this was a clue from the developer that these less than friendly foes would soon be making their way into Mortal Kombat 1 as part of the game's DLC.</p>
<p>I just wonder if this leak does prove accurate, Arnie will voice Conan... We will update you when we know more.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>As for who is in the game right now, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/homelander-joins-mortal-kombat-1-next-week">The Boys' Homelander joined Mortal Kombat 1's roster</a> earlier in the month, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-1-shows-off-soul-powered-dlc-fighter-ermac-in-new-gameplay-trailer">Ermac arrived in April</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-1-gives-us-our-first-look-at-the-upcoming-dlc-character-omni-man">Omni-Man</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-1-trailer-reveals-quan-chi-gameplay-and-best-look-at-john-cenas-peacemaker">Peacemaker and Quan Chi</a> have also been added to the game.</p><p>

If you are more interested in the film side of the franchise, the upcoming <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-2-film-ties-down-release-date-but-its-not-out-until-next-year">Mortal Kombat movie sequel is due to release next year</a>.



        </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alan Wake 2: Night Springs Review – Unpredictable Narrative Insanity]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/alan-wake-2-night-springs-unpredictable-narrative-insanity/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alan-wake-2-night-springs-review-%E2%80%93-unpredictable-narrative-insanity.911607/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/alan-wake-2-night-springs-unpredictable-narrative-insanity/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
				<main>

					

					<!--<div class="ads-container banner-ad floated p-0">
						<div data-pg-ad-spot='div-gpt-ad-wccftechcom38564' style="min-height: 280px;"></div>
					</div>-->
					
										<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Alan Wake 2: Night Springs</h5><p><span>June 8th, 2024</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC (Epic Games Store), PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S</span>
						</p></div><div>
							<h5>Developer</h5><p><span>Remedy Entertainment</span>
						</p></div></div></div>
					<p>The wait for <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/alan-wake-ii-it-truly-was-an-ocean/">Alan Wake 2</a> was extremely long, but it was well worth it, as Remedy Entertainment put out something that wasn't just a simple survival horror game but an intense experience that is very difficult to forget.&nbsp; While another entry in the series won't be seeing the light of day anytime soon, especially with Remedy working on multiple titles (including the second entry in the Control series and remakes of the first two entries in the Max Payne series) the base Alan Wake 2 game isn't the last we will see of the tormented writer for a long time, thanks to the two planned expansions, Night Springs and Lake House. The former is already out and the subject of today's review.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Alan-Wake-2-Screenshot-2024.06.24-12.40.51.14-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The Alan Wake 2: Night Springs DLC is a rather short expansion comprised of three episodes starring three characters of the Remedy Connected Universe: the waitress Rose Marigold, Control's main character Jesse Faden, and Shawn Ashmore, the real-life actor who plays the sheriff in Alan Wake 2 as well as Jack Joyce from Quantum Break. While they are somewhat separated from the main story, the three additional episodes are masterfully woven into the Alan Wake world, as they are part of the Night Springs TV show, an in-universe TV show that was mentioned in multiple Remedy Entertainment titles. Better yet, the TV show premise allowed the developers to bring back the amazing Mr. Door, played by David Harewood, who provides an introduction for the three episodes and has a central role in one of them.</p>
<p>Having been conceived as episodes of a TV show, the three additional scenarios included in Alan Wake 2: Night Springs are not particularly long, lasting between 30 minutes and a little over an hour. And while they don't really shake up the gameplay formula of the base game, they are extremely entertaining. Remedy went all out with the wackiness, presenting some scenarios that could have been, maybe, too much even for the main game.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Alan-Wake-2-Screenshot-2024.06.24-12.51.27.40-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The first episode of the Alan Wake 2: Night Springs expansion is Number One Fan. Controlling the waitress Rose Marigold, players will have to save Alan Wake, who is holed up inside his mansion, an army of haters summoned by his evil twin brother (who is actually Mr. Scratch). Right from the start, it's clear how this scenario is, by far, the furthest in terms of atmosphere and gameplay from the base game. From receiving Alan Wake's distress signal from a Big Mouth Billy Bass to the banners and graffiti around town highlighting how the waitress and the writer are meant for each other and the 50s rock soundtrack, it's clear how the team wanted to go for a humorous, surreal tone. Needless to say, they succeed. The haters' comments are particularly funny and quite a bit meta, shouting to the world that Alan Wake is just a Stephen King knock-off, which I'm pretty sure is something that must have come to more than a few players' minds when experiencing the base game. Gameplay-wise, this episode does away with most of the survival-horror mechanics of the base game, including the flashlight mechanics, essentially offering the player infinite armor for two powerful weapons and, thus, the chance to go all out on enemies for a rather fun, and gory, romp.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Alan-Wake-2-Screenshot-2024.06.24-23.45.14.95-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The second episode of the Alan Wake 2: Night Springs expansion is North Star, starring Control's Jesse Faden. On her journey to find her brother, the young woman ends up in Coffee World, not knowing she will come into contact with a government conspiracy set around... coffee. While less in-your-face humorous and more in line in terms of mechanics and atmosphere with the base game, North Star is still pretty hilarious in its own way. Much like the previous episode, the one starring Jesse Faden is rather straightforward despite the inclusion of some simple puzzles and the return of the flashlight mechanics, though I was a little disappointed how none of her powers made even a brief appearance during the 40 minutes or so of her episode.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Alan-Wake-2-Screenshot-2024.06.25-00.20.06.01-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The third, and definitely the most interesting episode of the three, is Time Breaker. This episode stars actor Shawn Ashmore, who has been hired to star in Sam Lake's latest game, not knowing he will end up in the clutches of the mysterious Mr.Door, who will bring him on a psychedelic journey where realities collide and the surreal becomes very, very real. While the gameplay is pretty much in line with the North Star episode, this episode is considerably better than the other two and the one that feels the closest to the base experience. It is possibly even more daring than the base game in terms of visual presentation, masterfully blending together some very different styles, something that alone makes it worth the price of admission.</p>
<p>While it does not offer much in terms of gameplay, the Alan Wake 2: Night Springs expansion is a worthy DLC to experience for all fans of the base game and Remedy Entertainment's titles. Free from the limitations imposed by the base game's narrative, which was fairly loose to begin with, Sam Lake and his team have gone all out to provide some extremely entertaining scenarios that, unfortunately, are over way too soon and leave the player wanting more. Hopefully, the next expansion, Lake House, will offer something a bit meatier to complement the masterful storytelling that is as well showcased in Night Springs as it is in the base game.</p>
<p><em>PC version tested. Review code provided by the publisher.</em></p>

					
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>


					<div>
	<div>
			
			<p>Alan Wake 2: Night Springs</p>
		</div>
	<header>Alan Wake 2: Night Springs</header>
</div>

<p>With its three entertaining scenarios showcasing Remedy Entertainment's narrative and visual design prowess, the Alan Wake 2: Night Springs expansion is a more than worthy DLC for all fans of the base game and the Finnish developer, provided they can keep their expectations in check. The expansion's short length, a little over two and a half hours, and its stripped-down gameplay will inevitably disappoint those looking for something more substantial</p>

<div>
		<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Pros</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Extremely entertaining narratives for all three episodes
</li><li>Pushes Remedy's trademark visual presentation further, especially in the Time Breaker episode
</li><li>Short length makes it so none of the episodes overstay their welcome...</li>		</ul>
	</div>
			<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Cons</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>...but inevitably leave the player wanting for more
</li><li>Stripped down gameplay over the base game</li>		</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

					
				</main>
			</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 PS2 Emulation Issues Don’t Bode Well For The Rumored PS3 Emulation]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-ps2-emulation-issues/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-ps2-emulation-issues-don%E2%80%99t-bode-well-for-the-rumored-ps3-emulation.911604/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-ps2-emulation-issues/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A first round of PlayStation 2 games playable via a new PlayStation 5 emulator was made available recently, but they don't bode well at all for the <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-playstation-3-backwards-compatibility/">native PS3 backward compatibility</a> Sony is rumored to be working on.</p>
<p>The tech experts at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ri20Y6E89LE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Foundry</a> took a good look at this first batch of games, which include Tomb Raider: Legend and Sly Cooper, highlighting how emulation is really poor for both games. For the game starring Lara Croft, the experience is marred by a blurry image, which isn't the result of a low resolution, which nonetheless saw a slight boost over the original release, but of bad choices in image treatment that lead to bad results. The available visual modes are also bad, such as those featuring some bad CRT filters that fail to recreate the feel of older televisions. At the very least, games feature both NTSC and PAL options sporting 60 Hz and 50 Hz modes, respectively, and some performance improvements.</p>
<p><iframe title="PlayStation 2 Emulation on PS5 Tested... And We've Got Issues" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ri20Y6E89LE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It is really baffling how Sony can't seem to get PlayStation 5 backward compatibility right, as even the previous PS4 emulator used to play PS2 games on the current generation console is extremely flawed, making other options, such as upscalers and emulators, much better in terms of image quality. With the PlayStation 3 being a notoriously more complicated system to emulate, Sony not getting PS2 emulation right is definitely concerning. Hopefully, things will be improved in the future to offer proper backward compatibility that can do justice to these classic titles.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The MCU’s Fantastic Four will be a period piece, Kevin Feige confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24185973/fantastic-four-mcu-time-period-setting-kevin-feige</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-mcu%E2%80%99s-fantastic-four-will-be-a-period-piece-kevin-feige-confirms.911601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24185973/fantastic-four-mcu-time-period-setting-kevin-feige<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="CFzEKc"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/24072946/fantastic-four-movie-robot-herbie-marvel"><em>Fantastic Four</em></a> is the Marvel Cinematic Universe’s biggest mystery, and maybe its greatest hope. Beyond who’s playing each member of Marvel’s first family, we’ve been in the dark about most other details until now. On the first episode of the new Official Marvel podcast, president of Marvel Studios Kevin Feige appeared as a guest and revealed that <em>Fantastic Four</em> will in fact be a period piece, rather than taking place in the modern-day MCU. </p>
<p id="xUxhz5">Fans first started speculating that the series might take the universe back in time when its <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23715214/fantastic-four-2025-cast-marvel-movie-pedro-pascal-joseph-quinn">first artwork was revealed, which was in a decidedly mid-century style</a>. While the primary purpose of the art was to reveal the actors behind each member of the team — with Pedro Pascal as Reed Richards, Vanessa Kirby as Sue Storm, Ebon-Moss Bachrach as Ben Grimm, and Joseph Quinn as Johnny Storm — it also suggested to many fans that the movie might take place in the ’60s, the same decade that the Fantastic Four debuted. </p>
<p id="DaIPSL">But while Feige seems to confirm in his podcast appearance that the movie will take place in the ’60s, he also can’t help but include a few mysterious details to make sure the movie’s intrigue is intact. </p>
<p id="gXHlb1">“So it is a period piece,” Feige said. “There was <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24121000/marvel-fantastic-four-movie-hints-free-comics">another piece of art we released with Johnny Storm flying in the air and making a four symbol</a>, and there was a cityscape in the corner of that image. And there were a lot of smart people who noticed that that cityscape didn’t look exactly like the New York that we know, or the New York that existed in the ’60s in our world. Those are some smart, smart observations.” </p>
<p id="dtjhAs">This could mean that the movie takes place in an alternate dimension, and the Fantastic Four gang gets sent to the MCU’s Earth during the plot, or maybe it’s some other multiversal shenanigans, but either way Feige isn’t giving us any details just yet. </p>
<p id="B8fnP4">One other bit of news the Marvel boss shared that should be particularly exciting for fans is that the movie will start filming the day after Comic-Con 2024, which means that <em>Fantastic Four</em> will be in production in just about a month. </p>
<p id="Bzl5Rk">As for what we know for sure, <em>Fantastic Four</em> is due out in theaters on July 25, 2025. Along with the core cast, the movie will also star Ralph Ineson as Galactus, Julia Garner as Shalla-Bal (the Silver Surfer), as well as Paul Walter Hauser, Natasha Lyonne, and John Malkovich in unannounced roles.</p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Little Big Adventure: Twinsen’s Quest launches this fall for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/little-big-adventure-twinsens-quest-launches-this-fall-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/little-big-adventure-twinsen%E2%80%99s-quest-launches-this-fall-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.911598/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/little-big-adventure-twinsens-quest-launches-this-fall-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A remake of the 1994 action adventure game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>Little Big <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a>: Twinsen’s <a title="Platforms > Quest [105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a></em>, formerly <em><a title="Games > Little Big Adventure: Twinsen's Quest [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/little-big-adventure-twinsens-quest">Twinsen’s Little Big Adventure Remastered</a></em>, will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,870 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,290 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,566 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,544 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2318070/Little_Big_Adventure__Twinsens_Quest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/twinsens-little-big-adventure-remastered-1c39bb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/little_big_adventure_twinsens_quest" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOG</a> this fall, publisher <a title="Companies > Microids [189 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/microids">Microids</a> and developer [2.21] <a href="https://www.microids.com/microids-announces-little-big-adventure-twinsens-quest/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-895003"></span></p><p>Since its last showing in May 2023, <em>Little Big Adventure: Twinsen’s Quest</em> has recruited a full team, changed engines from Unreal Engine 5 to Unity, shifted from a remaster to a remake, and signed with a publisher.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Microids:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Step into Twinsun’s fantastical world in this <a title="Genres > Action [1,965 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> adventure remake! <em>Little Big Adventure: Twinsen’s Quest</em> brings brand new visuals, new music by the original composer, and smoother gameplay to the iconic classic released back in 1994.</p><p><strong>Embark on a Timeless Adventure, Reimagined</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Twinsen is back in this remake featuring a new stylish makeover and modernized gameplay. Faithful to the original game, <em>Little Big Adventure: Twinsen’s Quest</em> takes you on an epic journey on a small planet harboring both magic and technology.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_895006"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>A Tale of Destiny and Heroism</strong></p><p>On a planetoid with two suns, four species lived in perfect harmony… But that all changed when the brilliant scientist Dr. FunFrock invented cloning and teleportation, bringing the inhabitants under his total control. End the clone occupation while playing as Twinsen, a model citizen turned fugitive. Armed with your mysterious Magic Ball, explore beautiful landscapes, solve intricate puzzles, and face formidable foes!</p><p>Whether you’re a long-time fan or new to the series, <em>Little Big Adventure: Twinsen’s Quest</em> offers an adventure like no other. Are you ready to become the hero Twinsun needs?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Discover a compelling story with deep themes.</li><li>Navigate through Twinsun with a revamped level layout and redesigned controls.</li><li>Defeat foes with an enhanced Magic Ball.</li><li>Enjoy a brand new artistic direction.</li><li>Immerse yourself with a new soundtrack by the original composer.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/little-big-adventure-twinsens-quest/june-26-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Publisher Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Little Big Adventure – Twinsen's Quest – ESRB Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nCqH57JZrlk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>