<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 21:06:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle to Support NVIDIA DLSS 3.5 and Full Ray Tracing (Path Tracing) on PC]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-to-support-nvidia-dlss-3-5-and-full-ray-tracing-path-tracing-on-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-to-support-nvidia-dlss-3-5-and-full-ray-tracing-path-tracing-on-pc.958956/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-to-support-nvidia-dlss-3-5-and-full-ray-tracing-path-tracing-on-pc/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NVIDIA had another big Gamescom 2024 announcement to make, although it is a bit staggered due to a later embargo compared to the others: Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will join Cyberpunk 2077, Alan Wake 2, and Black Myth: Wukong in the very restricted club of PC games that support NVIDIA DLSS 3.5 and full ray tracing.</p>
<p>Also known as path tracing, it was only viable for offline rendering and, therefore, limited to usage in movies and TV series until not long ago. It was only the arrival of upscalers and specifically frame generation techniques that allowed its real-time application to gaming, starting with CD Projekt RED's open world game once Update 1.6.2 went live in April 2023. Alan Wake 2 followed suit last Fall, and Black Myth: Wukong launches today.</p>
<p>All of these games have been made with different engines (REDengine 4, Northlight Engine, and Unreal Engine 5) and the same is true for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, which is powered by id Tech. We don't know which version of the engine is being used, but it was most likely based on id Tech 7, which powered DOOM Eternal.</p>
<p>That game ran extremely well, but then again, it only featured ray traced reflections (added with a post-launch update). MachineGames does have some experience, having added ray traced reflections to Wolfenstein: Youngblood with a post-launch update, but the performance cost will be much higher in this case.</p>
<p>The official PC system specifications of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle have yet to be released, but we'll let you know once the developers share them. In related news, you can read our preview from the pre-Gamescom presentation and an in-depth developer Q&amp;A with MachineGames in this article. The game will launch on PC and Xbox Series S|X.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7 lets you mix and match history — and it’s a blast]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/24224489/civilization-7-hands-on-demo-impressions-firaxis-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-7-lets-you-mix-and-match-history-%E2%80%94-and-it%E2%80%99s-a-blast.958953/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/24224489/civilization-7-hands-on-demo-impressions-firaxis-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><p>Imagine Caesar Augustus at the head of an army of Mongol warriors or Ben Franklin building the Great Wall of China. In Sid Meier’s <em>Civilization 7</em>, such flights of historical fantasy can become historical fact. The game has new ages to experience, new civilizations to build up, new leaders to guide them, and — for the first time in franchise history — the ability to mix and match leaders and civilizations to build the empire of your wildest dreams. <em>The Verge</em> had the opportunity to test out the game and talk with its developers at Firaxis Games. The brief, three-hour demo wasn’t enough time to get a feel for how well leaders and different civilizations work together, but I left feeling excited about all the ways <em>Civilization VII</em> aims to change the course of history.&nbsp;</p><p>In previous <em>Civilization </em>games, civs were always tied to a specific leader who was usually, but not always, a noteworthy head of state. Later iterations of the game offered multiple leaders for civs, and on a couple of occasions where it made historical sense, one leader could straddle multiple civs like France and England both having access to Eleanor of Aquitaine, who, during her unusually-long-for-the-time-period life, was the queen of both countries.</p><div><p>“We’ve known for a long time that our community has wanted a ‘build my own civilization’ tool kit.”</p></div><p>In <em>Civilization VII</em>, leaders are no longer tied to specific countries, giving players the opportunity to synergize the special abilities and bonuses of leaders with the unique attributes and units of different civs.</p><p>“We’ve known for a long time that our community has wanted a ‘build my own civilization’ tool kit,” Ed Beach, <em>Civ 7</em>’s creative director, says. Beach explained that balance issues made this feature unfeasible for previous games, but it was a priority for <em>Civ 7</em>. “If we make all the leaders balance with each other and all the civs balance with each other, then mixing and matching will work.”</p><p>Before a <em>Civ 7</em> game starts, players will choose their leader, then their civ. The game will make recommendations as to what civ will best suit a particular leader according to the specific strengths and “styles” of each. I chose Amina, warrior-queen of Zazzau, as my leader. She’s an economic and militaristic leader suited for civs that like to fight or make a lot of money. I don’t like to fight, but cash rules everything around me, so I settled on pursuing an economic victory. And though her attributes make her well-suited to a civ like Egypt or Rome, I chose her to lead her native civ of Aksum.</p><p><small>In previous <em>Civ</em> games, Hatshepsut would lead Egypt. In <em>Civilization 7</em>, however, the choice is yours, and you can see what different civs she’s best suited to govern.</small></p><p>According to Beach, <em>Civ</em> games are developed according to a simple equation whereby one-third of the game is new, the other third is updated, and the final third stays the same.&nbsp;</p><p>Though <em>Civilization</em> is one of my “quintessentially me” game series, I completely skipped over <em>Civ 6</em>. But as I played Civ 7’s demo, I realized that the moment-to-moment gameplay fell into the “stayed the same” category. Despite missing out on an entire game, I was able to parse the new-to-me user interface. And what I didn’t quite grasp, like the feature that allows players to develop specialized districts within a city, the game’s tutorial was very good at catching me up on.&nbsp;</p><p>One feature that was part of the “update” slice of the <em>Civilization </em>development pie was the historical era system. Where before, the passage of time was marked by a civ progressing from the ancient era to the classical era, Firaxis has streamlined the many historical eras into just three chapters — antiquity, exploration, and modern. Within each chapter are legacy paths or goals the player pursues with each path arranged into one of four categories that’ll sound familiar to <em>Civilization</em>-heads like myself — economic, military, cultural, and science. Since I was gunning for the economic victory, its attendant legacy path required me to do things like establish several trade routes or amass a wide variety of resources other world leaders would pay top dollar to get their hands on.</p><p>At the heart of <em>Civilization 7 </em>is the idea that history is built in layers. Beach used the evolution of the city of London as an example, explaining how different empires dramatically changed the face of the city. The Romans built the city’s walls that the Saxons would later improve before the Normans came and updated them even further.&nbsp;</p><p>The ability to mix and match civilizations comes from this “layered” concept of history, and it doesn’t end when a player first picks their leader and civ. For the first time in the series’ history, players will be able to change their civilization at different points throughout the game. The game keeps track of the decisions players made and the legacy paths they pursued, then when a player progresses to the next chapter of history, they’ll get a new civilization to lead based on their choices.</p><div><figcaption><em>Cities look better than ever in Civilization 7. Will you let your city grow organically or meticulously engineer your city to perfection?</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Firaxis Games</cite></p></div><p>For example, at the start of the Exploration Age, I might have had the choice to change from Aksum into another economy-focused civ like the Dutch. Or, had I indulged her militaristic capabilities, I might have gotten the Spanish empire instead.&nbsp;</p><p>And though the idea of Ben Franklin leading the Chinese might upset some history buffs, the idea of civilizations evolving into something new based on the paths they take and the technologies they develop is sound history. London’s various evolutions from a regional Roman capital to the crown jewel of the British empire is just one example.&nbsp;</p><p>“We have a system that’s listening to events that are happening in the game world,” Beach says. “And it has multiple thousands of little stories that can come out of the game because something has triggered.”&nbsp;</p><p>Those events don’t have to be civilization-shaking in scale, either. My scientists had developed a new food treatment technique but needed to know how to deploy it: should they use it on some bitter berries to make them more palatable or use it to soak some hyena meat? Since the idea of eating grilled hyena didn’t sound too appealing, I chose the berries leading to the discovery of how to cultivate olives.</p><p>I bitterly lament that the demo didn’t let me progress to the next age to see how impactful the humble olive would have had on my civilization’s history or the new civs Aksum could have evolved into. That kind of dynastic storytelling has been missing from <em>Civilization</em> games, so I’m keen to see all the new histories<em> Civilization 7</em> will enable me to write.</p><p><small><em>Sid Meier’s Civilization 7</em> launches on PC, Mac, Xbox, PlayStation, and Nintendo Switch on February 11th, 2025.</small></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country coming in 2025, taking the series to early 20th century Sicily]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mafia-the-old-country-coming-in-2025-taking-the-series-to-early-20th-century-sicily</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-coming-in-2025-taking-the-series-to-early-20th-century-sicily.958950/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mafia-the-old-country-coming-in-2025-taking-the-series-to-early-20th-century-sicily<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Here's the news: there's a new Mafia game, it's called Mafia: The Old Country, and it's set in 20th century Sicily rather than in America as per the previous three games in the series.
</p>
<p>That's about all we know, but hop below and you'll find a trailer.
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mafia: The Old Country - Official Teaser Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mafia: The Old Country - Official Teaser Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=crDUx5suLm4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The Old Country is being developed by Hangar 13, the same studio responsible for Mafia 3. Technically, sorta, they're also the studio that made Mafia 1 and 2, since those games were made by Illusion Softworks, which became 2K Czech, which was merged into Hangar 13 in 2017. What a twisted web capitalism weaves.
</p>
<p>This new Mafia was revealed tonight at Gamescom's Opening Night Live, with a brief coda from Hangar 13's president Nick Baynes, who said that The Old Country would go "back to the roots" of what people liked about the seires and would have a "deep, linear narrative." I thought Mafia 3 had a linear narrative and was better than people gave it credit for - at least after the bugs were fixed - but hey-ho. I hope it being set further back in the past means the cars are even slower and more rubbish than ever. I hope the cars are so old and shit that they've got legs.
</p>
<p>2K will show more of Mafia: The Old Country in December of this year, ahead of a planned release sometime in 2025. This has been a big day for 2K generally, since they've also just <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/we-now-know-that-borderlands-4-is-a-borderlands-game-with-4-at-the-end-coming-2025">announced Borderlands 4</a> and stuck a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/firaxis-announces-civilization-7-release-date-alongside-new-trailer-full-of-nukes-wonders-and-period-celebs">release date on Civ 7</a>.
</p>
<hr>
<p><em>For more of the latest news and previews from Gamescom 2024, head to our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2024">Gamescom 2024 hub</a>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost Records Hands-On: The Life Is Strange Devs Explore The Good And Bad Of Nostalgia]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-preview-demo-90s-gamescom-1851626771</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lost-records-hands-on-the-life-is-strange-devs-explore-the-good-and-bad-of-nostalgia.958932/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-preview-demo-90s-gamescom-1851626771<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Don’t Nod, the studio behind the original <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/you-really-should-be-playing-life-is-strange-1694516049&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/you-really-should-be-playing-life-is-strange-1694516049"><em>Life is Strange</em></a></span> and its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/life-is-strange-2-is-a-heartbreakingly-accurate-brother-1840071123&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/life-is-strange-2-is-a-heartbreakingly-accurate-brother-1840071123">(stellar) numbered sequel</a></span>, has an earnest quality to its writing that still gets me, almost 10 years after Max Caulfield first strode down the halls of Blackwell Academy. So even when <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-dont-not-teenage-dialogue-1851442033&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-dont-not-teenage-dialogue-1851442033"><em>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</em></a></span>, the next game from the studio set to launch next year, leans into some of the hokiest, most saccharine dialogue I’ve heard in a hot minute, that earnestness keeps me invested. I recently played about two hours of <em>Lost Records</em>, and though the build I got to mess around with was a little janky, especially as it oscillates between its ‘90s-era flashbacks and present-day framing device, I’m already even more intrigued than I was when I <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-dont-not-teenage-dialogue-1851442033&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-dont-not-teenage-dialogue-1851442033">talked to the developers at Don’t Nod</a></span> about the project earlier this year.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196626" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Who Is The Best Hang In Unicorn Overlord? A Scientific Ranking" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="271" data-playlist="196626,197209,196923" data-current="196626"><div><p>Who Is The Best Hang In Unicorn Overlord? A Scientific Ranking</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22184.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><em>Lost Records </em>focuses on a group of four friends who met as teenagers in the ‘90s and bonded over their love of rock music and protagonist Swann’s camera. But what’s clear is that, by the time they reunite over two decades later, <em>something</em> happened to them as they shot music videos in their childhood hometown. <em>Lost Records</em> shifts back and forth between Swann’s past and present, toying with the player’s uncertainty about why this group of girls haven’t spoken in years to create a constant sense of unease. Mundane conversations I had with Swann’s friend Autumn across a diner table in the present felt tense even when we were reminiscing about wonderful times we had together as teens.</p><p>The demo I played deliberately cut out segments that might have alleviated some of that tension, and the carefully curated mystique of the moments Don’t Nod put before me left me tantalized and eager to discover what supernatural twist is waiting in the cuts to black.</p><figure id="" data-id="999b02fd3eb97e3eff42dfcccd56f72f" data-recommend-id="image://999b02fd3eb97e3eff42dfcccd56f72f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1536" data-height="864" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Autumn looks down at the table in front of her." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Autumn looks down at the table in front of her." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Don’t Nod Entertainment / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="999b02fd3eb97e3eff42dfcccd56f72f" data-recommend-id="image://999b02fd3eb97e3eff42dfcccd56f72f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1536" data-height="864" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Autumn looks down at the table in front of her." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The parts of Swann’s story I was able to play, however, were intriguing in their own way, touching on parts of my own ‘90s nostalgia that I think I’ve started forgetting about as I’ve gotten older and more preoccupied with the present. The demo starts with her looking through her childhood room trying to find a movie she’s rented from the local movie shop but has misplaced somewhere in another case. As I examined all the doodads scattered across her distinctly ‘90s room adorned in period-appropriate homages to properties like Trolls and Stephen King novels, it was like I could feel the plastic of the VHS cases in my hands after having not thought about those things for decades.<br></p><p>Between throwing stuff out over the course of my childhood and moving across the country in adulthood, I’ve shed a lot of physical items and memories of the things that were once pivotal to my life. Not every piece of ‘90s media evokes those buried recollections for me, but walking through Swann’s room was the first moment when <em>Lost Records</em> tapped into my nostalgia. But I didn’t revel in it. It wasn’t an upbeat dopamine hit of a reference to some fondly remembered thing. It was more of a somber feeling, a recognition that time has passed and things have changed.</p><p>So many of the tactile experiences I had as a child have been replaced by scrolling and convenience. I imagine the juxtaposition of how Swann interacts with the technology of her adolescence and the more modern world of the present-day segments is meant to create a contrast between the two distinct moments in her life, but it also reminds me of how impermanent and disposable almost everything we interact with is. I’m thinking of the box of VHS tapes that sat in my family’s storage building for decades as we replaced them with DVDs and Blu-rays, which were then subsequently replaced by streaming services that will delist a movie without warning. I don’t even feel wistful, I just feel dread.</p><figure id="" data-id="5bdca65020721392f2c07b62143176e6" data-recommend-id="image://5bdca65020721392f2c07b62143176e6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1536" data-height="864" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Swann records Autum playing her bass." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Swann records Autum playing her bass." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Don’t Nod Entertainment / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="5bdca65020721392f2c07b62143176e6" data-recommend-id="image://5bdca65020721392f2c07b62143176e6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1536" data-height="864" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Swann records Autum playing her bass." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Lost Records </em>is all about capturing these moments through technology that Swann couldn’t have conceived of being obsolete and likely forgotten years down the line. Beyond walking, talking, and examining items, I spent most of my time in Swann’s shoes recording shots of her room and her friend’s band practice on her camcorder. Her most precious adolescent memories are of her using the handheld camera to shoot 4:3 music videos for the friends she was dying to impress. <em>Lost Records</em>’ dialogue perfectly captures an awkward teen’s best efforts to fit in, to the point where I couldn’t help but empathize with her as I winced at the unabashed, unironic earnestness of how she speaks to her would-be friends.<br></p><p>While her anxiety may persist into adulthood, the raw, unpolished way she and her friends shoot a music video in the woods outside their hometown is but a distant memory. I don’t know yet if the shaky, awkward shots I took with Swann’s camera still persist in the game’s present day, but watching the end result of our time together and seeing how many clips were clearly born of me still getting used to which buttons did what in the game’s photo mode felt appropriate. Swann was still learning how to be a director at that age, just as I was still learning how to work the game’s controls. So yeah, the final result is not a professional, perfectly framed music video, but it’s the best I could do in the moment.</p><figure id="" data-id="75db80fcf4d3460c1c77da9ae09c7113" data-recommend-id="image://75db80fcf4d3460c1c77da9ae09c7113" data-format="jpg" data-width="1536" data-height="864" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Swann records something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Swann records something off-screen." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Don’t Nod Entertainment / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="75db80fcf4d3460c1c77da9ae09c7113" data-recommend-id="image://75db80fcf4d3460c1c77da9ae09c7113" data-format="jpg" data-width="1536" data-height="864" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Swann records something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>I expected <em>Lost Records </em>to play on ‘90s nostalgia, as Don’t Nod had told me it was a chance for the team to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-dont-not-teenage-dialogue-1851442033&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-dont-not-teenage-dialogue-1851442033">reflect on their own teenage years as adults</a></span>. But I don’t think I was prepared for how it would play on my own anxieties about how the world is, well, losing records of its past. The tactile ways we once held footage, photos, letters are dying out. Technology has improved our lives, but it’s also made us flippant about how easily something historically or personally significant can be discarded with the touch of a button. Where once you’d have to tear and burn a photo to destroy it, now you just have to delete it from your photo app or hard drive. I’m only in my 30s, thus I’m not quite as distanced from my adolescence as Swann and her friends are in <em>Lost Records</em>, but so many videos and photos of those years have already been wiped as social media accounts are deleted and old photo albums have been lost in the shuffles between homes. Maybe that’s just what happens to nostalgia as the world grows more dystopian. It stops being a rose-colored lens to view the good ol’ days and becomes a reminder that history can feel impossible to preserve.<br></p><p><em>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage </em>is coming to PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X/S in 2025.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blame Modern TV For Star Wars: The Acolyte's Cancellation]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-canceled-season-2-1851627217</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blame-modern-tv-for-star-wars-the-acolytes-cancellation.958929/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-canceled-season-2-1851627217<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-oshamir-ship-reylo-episode-8-1851600313&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-oshamir-ship-reylo-episode-8-1851600313"><em>The Acolyte</em></a></span> wasn’t perfect, but it did break new narrative ground in <em>Star Wars</em>, a franchise often haunted by Force ghosts and endlessly recurring characters. Led by Leslye Headland, the Disney+ series dared to reevaluate decades-old tropes, unpack the flaws of the Jedi Order, and play with the space sandbox setting in new, interesting ways. But <em>The Acolyte</em>, which starred Amandla Stenberg as twin sisters struggling to find balance in the Force and Manny Jacinto as a super-sexy baddie, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-acolyte-season-2-release-date-cancel-disney-1851626581&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-acolyte-season-2-release-date-cancel-disney-1851626581">was just officially canceled</a></span>.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195358" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Blasphemous 2 Developer Interview" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="297" data-playlist="195358,195697,193897" data-current="195358"><div><p>Blasphemous 2 Developer Interview</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195358/195358_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195358/195358_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195358/195358_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195358/195358_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20816.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>It won’t get a second season on Disney+, and right now the worst-behaved members of the <em>Star Wars</em> fandom are celebrating its demise. But while <em>The Acolyte</em>’s cancellation stokes the fires of that ongoing culture war, it’s also indicative of a much larger problem plaguing modern television—and streaming services and rising production costs are to blame.</p><h2 id="h8204"><a id=""></a><strong>The flaws of modern TV</strong></h2><p>The rise of a disparate (and expensive) collection of streaming services replacing the basic cable subscription for millions of paying customers has drastically changed the landscape of modern television. Back in the heyday of cable TV, there was far less time between seasons of a typical show than there is now. Look at <em>Breaking Bad</em>, widely considered one of the most prestigious of prestige television shows: The last episode of its first season aired in March 2008, while the first episode of the second season picked up almost exactly a year later. Now, there are routinely multiple years between seasons—two years elapsed before <em>House of the Dragon</em> season 2 followed its predecessor, nearly three years passed between seasons 2 and 3 of <em>The Mandalorian</em>, and the series finale of <em>Stranger Things</em> still doesn’t have a release window (the last season aired two years ago, and the next one just started production this year).<br></p><p>That is a massive amount of time for an invested audience to wait, and it can greatly diminish their enthusiasm for a series—it can also result in them literally losing the plot, as it’s difficult to remember what happened the previous season when it’s been several years since you last watched it. Plus, it’s tough to justify a second season when you know it’ll be in production for years—there’s no real reason to let a show breathe anymore, to let it iron out the first season’s kinks. If <em>Parks and Recreation</em> was canceled after season one, we’d have never gotten <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EmUYpgptBtY&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EmUYpgptBtY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one of the funniest scenes in modern television</a></span>.<br></p><figure id="" data-id="744586091189e11b62b605274da03b4d" data-recommend-id="image://744586091189e11b62b605274da03b4d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Ghoul grins. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Ghoul grins. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon / Bethesda</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="744586091189e11b62b605274da03b4d" data-recommend-id="image://744586091189e11b62b605274da03b4d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Ghoul grins. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Then there’s the cost of making prestige TV, which has skyrocketed in recent years. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://digiday.com/marketing/how-amazon-primes-fallout-series-highlights-the-power-of-post-apocalyptic-video-game-ip/#:~:text=Critics%20have%20lauded%20%E2%80%9CFallout%2C%E2%80%9D,through%20all%20the%20effusive%20praise.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://digiday.com/marketing/how-amazon-primes-fallout-series-highlights-the-power-of-post-apocalyptic-video-game-ip/#:~:text=Critics%20have%20lauded%20%E2%80%9CFallout%2C%E2%80%9D,through%20all%20the%20effusive%20praise." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Prime’s <em>Fallout</em> series reportedly cost $153M</a></span> for a single season. By the end of its run, <em>Game of Thrones </em>episodes required about $15M each for production after starting at around $6M an episode—and just a few years later, its spin-off <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2022/tv/news/house-of-the-dragon-budget-episode-cost-1235238285/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2022/tv/news/house-of-the-dragon-budget-episode-cost-1235238285/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>House of the Dragon </em>costs “less than $20m” per episode</a></span>. With production costs so high, companies want a return on their investment, and they won’t take “it’s just the first season, let it cook” for an answer.<br></p><p>According to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/07/14/why-the-acolyte-season-2-looks-increasingly-unlikely/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/07/14/why-the-acolyte-season-2-looks-increasingly-unlikely/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Forbes</em></a></span>, estimates place <em>The Acolyte</em>’s cost of production at nearly $180M for just eight episodes, and its viewership was about half that of <em>Ahsoka</em> and 75% less than <em>The Mandalorian</em>’s. When companies are increasingly concerned with numbers going up, it’s impossible to justify another season of a series that’s so expensive to make when its viewership numbers don’t match other shows within the franchise—and therein lies our final problem: the franchise.</p><h2 id="h8205"><a id=""></a><strong>The <em>Star Wars</em> problem</strong></h2><p>In recent years, the only “successful” deviation from traditional <em>Star Wars</em> media has been <em>Andor</em>, the spy-thriller-esque series starring Diego Luna that’s a spin-off of 2016’s <em>Rogue One</em>. Despite it reportedly not having as large a viewership as <em>The Mandalorian</em> or <em>Obi-Wan Kenobi</em>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/andor-season-2-rogue-one-k2so-luna-interview-teaser-tv-1851624333&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/andor-season-2-rogue-one-k2so-luna-interview-teaser-tv-1851624333"><em>Andor</em>’s second season</a></span> is set to debut sometime in 2025. Though <em>Andor </em>technically retreads old ground like so many other <em>Star Wars</em> series, it feels incredibly fresh when compared to the other shows that rely so heavily on nostalgia to try and placate older fans. So it’s a welcome surprise that Disney decided to bankroll another season—especially since there are no plans for season two of either <em>The Book of Boba Fett</em> or <em>Obi-Wan Kenobi</em>.<br></p><figure id="" data-id="3c9abbb03c5d05d68268aa45db23c438" data-recommend-id="image://3c9abbb03c5d05d68268aa45db23c438" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Osha looks off-camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Osha looks off-camera." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney / Lucasfilm</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3c9abbb03c5d05d68268aa45db23c438" data-recommend-id="image://3c9abbb03c5d05d68268aa45db23c438" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Osha looks off-camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>But <em>Andor</em> is an exception, not the rule. A specific sect of fans are notoriously resistant to perceived changes to lore or the centering of marginalized folks in <em>Star Wars</em> media, and <em>The Acolyte</em> pissed them off from the jump: run by a woman, with a Black non-binary lead, lesbian witches, and a blistering take on the flaws of the Jedi, it became the focal point of a culture war before it even aired. Both <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/conormurray/2024/06/20/the-acolyte-star-amandla-stenberg-slams-intolerable-racism-in-diss-track-after-weeks-of-anti-woke-attacks/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/conormurray/2024/06/20/the-acolyte-star-amandla-stenberg-slams-intolerable-racism-in-diss-track-after-weeks-of-anti-woke-attacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stenberg</a></span>&nbsp;and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://nuvomagazine.com/magazine/autumn-2024/manny-jacinto-wants-to-be-a-force-for-change&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://nuvomagazine.com/magazine/autumn-2024/manny-jacinto-wants-to-be-a-force-for-change" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jacinto</a></span> spoke out about the racist backlash <em>The Acolyte </em>faced, with the former even dropping a song that seems to reference the hate lobbed at them. At the time of writing, Stenberg’s latest Instagram post is filled with comments denigrating them: “Take the L never do <em>Star Wars</em> again,” reads one comment, while another asks, “How does it feel to have your terrible show canceled, princess?”<br></p><p>Unfortunately, in an age where modern television series are defined by their big price tags and (hopefully) bigger viewer numbers, a show like <em>The Acolyte </em>had an almost insurmountable feat in front of it in order to ensure its survival. If its mere existence hadn’t been used as the catalyst for conversations about “wokeism” in <em>Star Wars</em>, perhaps it would have had a fighting chance. But when a modern TV series takes place in a long-running franchise and dares to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-qimir-osha-ship-sexy-reylo-1851576215&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-qimir-osha-ship-sexy-reylo-1851576215">offer a different kind of fan-service</a></span>, the sad reality is it will likely serve as a reminder of how far a fandom still has to go. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Finally Gets a Release Date for Xbox...and PlayStation | gamescom 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-finally-gets-a-release-date-for-xboxand-playstation-gamescom-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-finally-gets-a-release-date-for-xbox-and-playstation-gamescom-2024.958917/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-finally-gets-a-release-date-for-xboxand-playstation-gamescom-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">We don't have to wait much longer.</h2></div><section><p>After its proper reveal <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/machinegames-unveils-first-look-at-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-xbox-direct-2024">earlier this year</a>, MachineGames has finally provided a release date for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, which is coming to PC and Xbox Series X/S on December 9, 2023. Additionally, we learned that it's coming to PS5 in Spring of 2025.</p><p>As part of Xbox's Gamescom 2024 announcements, the company confirmed the game's release dates, as well as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-and-possibly-starfield-are-reportedly-being-considered-for-ps5">confirmed various reports</a> that it was coming to PlayStation. Reports of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle's release date first surfaced in May when <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/30/24145262/xbox-games-showcase-summer-2024-call-of-duty-direct" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Verge reported</a> the project was <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsofts-xbox-game-release-windows-for-rest-of-2024-reportedly-revealed">targeting</a> a December release window. </p><p>Alongside the release dates, Xbox and MachineGames have provided a new trailer for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle. The trailer, narrated by Troy Baker, discusses his feelings on stepping into the boots of Indiana Jones. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>This reveal of a PS5 release is especially interesting, given Xbox head Phil Spencer <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/starfield-and-indiana-jones-are-still-xbox-exclusives-but-phil-spencer-doesnt-rule-out-ps5-release">previously insisting</a> that MachineGames' next project would remain an Xbox console exclusive. The move is part of Xbox's broader initiative for some of its first-party games to make their way onto other platforms, including <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/doom-the-dark-ages-announced-confirmed-for-ps5-xbox-games-showcase-2024">Doom: The Dark Ages</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-games-pentiment-and-grounded-confirmed-for-nintendo-switch-and-playstation">Grounded</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-games-pentiment-and-grounded-confirmed-for-nintendo-switch-and-playstation">Pentiment</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sea-of-thieves-coming-to-playstation-5-in-april-as-xbox-confirms-the-four-exclusives-headed-to-other-platforms">Sea of Thieves</a>, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-game-hi-fi-rush-confirmed-for-ps5-release-date-announced">Hi-Fi Rush</a>. </p><p>Set <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-fits-in-the-indy-timeline">between the events</a> of Indiana Jones's films Raiders of the Lost Ark and the Last Crusade; players control the titular character on another globetrotting adventure to uncover the secret to an ancient power connected to the Great Circle.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle - Gamescom 2024 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is set in <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-dev-explains-decision-to-go-first-person-over-third-person">a first-person perspective</a>. Troy Baker has been <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/troy-baker-is-playing-indiana-jones-in-upcoming-game-the-great-circle">cast to play Indiana Jones in the game</a>, while in the films, Indiana Jones is portrayed by actor Harrison Ford. </p><p>The project was first announced in January 2021, when it was revealed that MachineGames, in collaboration with LucasFilm, was working on a video game based on Indiana Jones. Todd Howard, a key employee at MachineGames' sister studio, Bethesda Game Studios, serves as the game's executive producer. </p><p><em>Taylor is a Reporter at IGN. You can follow her on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/TayNixster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@TayNixster.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Series Secret Level Reveals Animated Stories For God Of War, Sifu, Warhammer And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-series-secret-level-reveals-animated-stories-for-god-of-war-sifu-warhammer-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-series-secret-level-reveals-animated-stories-for-god-of-war-sifu-warhammer-and-more.958911/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-series-secret-level-reveals-animated-stories-for-god-of-war-sifu-warhammer-and-more<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next" tabindex="-1"><header></header><main id="main-content"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Bringing new stories to your favorite games.</h2></div><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-animation-starring-space-marine-2s-titus-reportedly-part-of-amazons-secret-level-anthology-series">Secret Level is an anthology series</a> coming to Amazon Prime Video, and it brings several games to animated form to tell new short stories for those games. The series was finally revealed with a teaser trailer during Gamescom 2024's Opening Night Live showcase. It comes from Blur Studio, the creators of <a href="https://www.ign.com/tv/love-death-and-robots">Love, Death, and Robots</a>, which is another animated anthology series that was well-received. Bringing that ethos to video game stories is what Secret Level sets out to do and it will release on December 10.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Several games were teased in the premier trailer, which you can watch above. Secret Level will have 15 episoides and includes the following games and series:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>God of War (PlayStation Studios)</li><li>Sifu</li><li>Warhammer 40K</li><li>Unreal Tournament</li><li>New World: Aeternum</li><li>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</li><li>The Outer Worlds 2</li><li>Pac-Man</li><li>Honor of Kings</li><li>Armored Core</li><li>Mega Man</li><li>Exodus</li><li>Spelunky</li><li>Crossfire</li><li>Concord</li></ul><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Secret Level gamescom ONL 2024 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>For more on all the news coming out of Gamescom 2024, be sure to check out our roundup of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-everything-announced">everything announced during Opening Night Live 2024</a>.</p></section><div><h3><svg focusable="false" viewBox="0 0 76 24" aria-hidden="false" role="img"><title>IGN</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></main></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monument Valley 3 Finally Has a Release Date, And It's Netflix Games Exclusive]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/monument-valley-3-finally-has-a-release-date-and-its-netflix-games-exclusive</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monument-valley-3-finally-has-a-release-date-and-its-netflix-games-exclusive.958905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/monument-valley-3-finally-has-a-release-date-and-its-netflix-games-exclusive<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Ida and Ro name a successor.</h2></div><section><p>Five years ago, ustwo games announced it was developing a third entry in the critically-acclaimed puzzle series, Monument Valley. Now, after all that waiting, it's finally coming out on December 10, 2024, and it will be exclusive to Netflix Games at launch.</p><p>In a trailer at Opening Night Live today, we got our first real look at Monument Valley 3. It's both familiar and new, featuring a new little protagonist named Noor carrying a lantern. Per a press release, Noor is searching for a new source of power "before the light of the world fades, forever." As before, the player uses the touchscreen to move M.C. Escher-like environments around and create paths for the character to progress.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Monument Valley 3 seems to use similar spatial and visual puzzle styles to its predecessors, but it looks like the lantern-carrying protagonist will occasionally have to lead other characters effectively through the mazes. The very first game starred a single protagonist, while the second featured a mother and her child navigating mazes together and explored themes related to their relationship. Both games were critically acclaimed for their design, with Monument Valley 2 winning the Game Award for Best Mobile Game in 2017, and winning best Puzzle at the 2018 Webby Awards.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Monument Valley 3 Screenshots gamescom ONL 2024</h3></div></output><p>Monument Valley 3 will technically be coming to both iOS and Android like its predecessors, but at launch will only be available via the Netflix Games app. Additionally, both Monument Valley and Monument Valley 2 will come to Netflix Games on September 19 and October 29, respectively. Netflix, as we've previously written, has struggled to lure in large amounts of subscribers, and has <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/netflix-considering-introducing-in-app-purchases-ads-to-its-games-platform">reportedly been discussing internally</a> whether or not to add in-app purchases or ads to its games platform in the future.</p><p><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield's Shattered Space DLC Reveals September Release Date | gamescom 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/starfields-shattered-space-dlc-reveals-september-release-date-gamescom-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starfields-shattered-space-dlc-reveals-september-release-date-gamescom-2024.958899/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/starfields-shattered-space-dlc-reveals-september-release-date-gamescom-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Plus, a new vehicle coming in a free update tonight.</h2></div><section><p>Shattered Space, the highly anticipated upcoming DLC for Bethesda's Starfield, will officially be releasing on September 30.</p><p>The announcement was made today at gamescom Opening Night Live, where it was also revealed that a new vehicle, the Rev-8, will be made available in a free update tonight. We got to see the vehicle in action <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rA1z1DbA_Io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in footage unveiled at gamescom</a>, showing off some fun world exploration. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Starfield Update Screenshots - gamescom ONL 2024</h3></div></output><p>Shattered Space, too, got a brief tease in the footage, although it didn't show <em>too </em>much outside of a darker tone, with much of the focus begin on the Rev-8.</p><p>Shattered Space got its <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/starfields-shattered-space-dlc-first-official-trailer-gives-players-a-first-look-at-house-varuuns-homeworld-xbox-games-showcase-2024">first trailer back in June</a> during the Xbox Games Showcase, and it'll focus on a mysterious new faction called House Va'Ruun. "Investigate a frightening cosmic threat, explore a new planet, and find unique weapons, spacesuits, and gear in this all-new adventure," <a href="https://bethesda.net/en/game/starfield/shattered-space" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Starfield's official website explains</a> in a page dedicated to the Shattered Space expansion.</p><p>Bethesda confirmed it was working <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-preps-starfield-shattered-space-story-expansion-for-post-launch">on the story expansion in 2023</a>, but we've been waiting for a release date since then. It's set to arrive both on Xbox and PC. </p><p>We gave Starfield a 7/10 <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/starfield-review">when we reviewed it last year</a>, writing at the time that it "has a lot of forces working against it, but eventually the allure of its expansive roleplaying quests and respectable combat make its gravitational pull difficult to resist."</p><p>For more from gamescom, check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-everything-announced">our roundup of everything announced</a> at Opening Night Live. </p><p><em>Alex Stedman is a Senior News Editor with IGN, overseeing entertainment reporting. When she's not writing or editing, you can find her reading fantasy novels or playing Dungeons &amp; Dragons. </em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sid Meier's Civilization 7 Release Date Announced, Gameplay Trailer Revealed | gamescom 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sid-meiers-civilization-7-release-date-announced-gameplay-trailer-revealed-gamescom-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sid-meiers-civilization-7-release-date-announced-gameplay-trailer-revealed-gamescom-2024.958896/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/sid-meiers-civilization-7-release-date-announced-gameplay-trailer-revealed-gamescom-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Sid Meier's Civilization 7</a> appeared during Opening Night Live to help kick off gamescom 2024 with a first-look gameplay trailer and a release date.</p><p>Firaxis’ strategy sequel launches February 11, 2025 on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X and S, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, and PC via Steam, with the deluxe edition including five days of early access (what amounts to an effective release date of February 6).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Based on the new trailer, Civilization 7 features a more grounded art style than the divisive Civilization 6 look. We <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/10/26/sid-meiers-civilization-vi-review">loved Civilization 6 when it came out back in 2016</a>, saying it would "go down in history as the most fully-featured launch version in the series." Though the series has <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/civilizations-past-and-future-as-told-by-its-lead-designers">changed leadership hands</a> a number of times over the years, it remains beloved and successful. In fact, the first human equipped with a Neuralink brain implant apparently <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/first-human-patient-to-receive-a-neuralink-brain-implant-used-it-to-stay-up-all-night-playing-civilization-6">stayed up all night playing Civilization 6 with the technology</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Civilization 7 Screenshots - gamescom ONL 2024</h3></div></output><p>Be sure to check out IGN’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-everything-announced">Opening Night Live roundup</a> to see everything announced during the show.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune Awakening Trailer Shows In-Depth Gameplay At Gamescom ONL]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-trailer-shows-in-depth-gameplay-at-gamescom-onl</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakening-trailer-shows-in-depth-gameplay-at-gamescom-onl.958887/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-trailer-shows-in-depth-gameplay-at-gamescom-onl<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Pledge allegiance to the worms.</h2></div><section><p>During the Opening Night Live showcase for Gamescom 2024, the upcoming survival-action MMO game Dune Awakening had a lengthy gameplay walkthrough trailer. It's highly anticipated given it's set in the Dune universe, but also because it left a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-is-looking-supremely-cool-as-it-was-written">good first impression when we saw Dune Awakening</a> back in March of this year.</p><p>The new gameplay trailer showed the character creator and early goings of assaulting deserter bases, climbing cliffs, and basic strategies when it comes to melee combat and shooting mechanics. We also saw what it's like to build your own bases and the advantages that comes with it like using blood purifiers to cleanse enemy blood to extract water, which is key for survival.</p><blockquote data-media-max-width="560" data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Survive the brutal desert of Arrakis. Expand your reach with ground and air vehicles. Control the production of spice at all costs.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DuneAwakening?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#DuneAwakening</a> is coming to PC Early 2025. Wishlist on Steam: <a href="https://t.co/J7u4MwnVXq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/J7u4MwnVXq</a> <a href="https://t.co/QpbSgQuSBV" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/QpbSgQuSBV</a></p>— Dune: Awakening (@DuneAwakening) <a href="https://twitter.com/DuneAwakening/status/1825967899879633357?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 20, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Additionally, you can save blueprints of your structures and sell them to other players. While there is a guild system where you'll be able to group up with hundreds of other players, you will also engage in story content – for example, going to Harko Village and pledging to the Harkonnen is part of Dune Awakening.</p><p>You'll also go beyond the Shield Wall to hunt for spice, but this is where you can expect hostile encounters, fighting other players over that spice in spicy emergent PvP battles. Arrakis is a dangerous place so you can also expect to encounter sandworms regularly while also managing water resources and navigating the harsh environment.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Dune Awakening gamescom ONL 2024 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Dune Awakening will be available sometime in early 2025 on PC, and PlayStation and Xbox systems at a later date. For more on the big stories coming out of Gamescom 2024, check out our roundup of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-everything-announced">everything announced during Opening Night Live</a>.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Finally Arriving in 2025, Playtesting to Begin This Fall | gamescom 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-finally-arriving-in-2025-playtesting-to-begin-this-fall-gamescom-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-finally-arriving-in-2025-playtesting-to-begin-this-fall-gamescom-2024.958881/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-finally-arriving-in-2025-playtesting-to-begin-this-fall-gamescom-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>After multiple delays since its initial unveiling in 2021, ARC Raiders is now set to arrive sometime in 2025.</p><p>The announcement was made at gamescom Opening Night Live, with Embark Studios also revealing that playtesting will begin this fall. You can watch the latest teaser for ARC Raiders below.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>ARC Raiders, from former Battlefield and Star Wars: Battlefront developers, was first announced <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-ex-dice-devs-new-game-co-op-pve-sci-fi-shooter-delayed-2023">at the 2021 Game Awards</a>, with Embark Studios saying at the time that it would be headed to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S in 2022. Shortly after, however, the studio delayed the game to 2023. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-has-changed-from-a-co-op-pve-game-to-a-pvpve-survival-extraction-shooter">It was also revealed in 2023</a> that the game had shifted from a co-op PvP game to a "PvPvE survival extraction shooter."</p><p>The game made quite an impression with its reveal trailer, introducing a vibrant sci-fi world. Today's trailer shows off a bit more of that, although not too much else.</p><p>Aleksander Grøndal, ARC Raiders' executive producer, shared an excerpt of ARC Raiders' lore in a 2023 <a href="https://medium.com/embarkstudios/whats-next-for-arc-raiders-fa9586281e0c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Medium post</a>, giving us some idea of what the upcoming game will focus on: </p><p>"People have fled to the underground colony of Speranza, seeking supplies to survive, and shelter from the machines," the text read. "Demand for resources is at an all-time high. But getting those resources is a risky job, and it isn’t for everyone. But it is a job for you. That’s why you’ve enlisted as a Raider, scavenging for vital supplies that are scattered across the landscape. Everything from leftovers from yesterday’s run-in with ARC to the unlikely remains of a pinball machine."</p><p>For more from gamescom Opening Night Live, check out our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-everything-announced">roundup of everything announced</a>. </p><p><em>Alex Stedman is a Senior News Editor with IGN, overseeing entertainment reporting. When she's not writing or editing, you can find her reading fantasy novels or playing Dungeons &amp; Dragons. </em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Dying Light Officially Announced at Gamescom 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/new-dying-light-officially-announced-at-gamescom-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-dying-light-officially-announced-at-gamescom-2024.958875/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/new-dying-light-officially-announced-at-gamescom-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>After a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/geoff-keighley-teases-the-beast-for-opening-night-live-fans-tie-it-to-mystery-dying-light-game">pretty on-the-nose tease from Geoff Keighley</a>, Techland has officially revealed a new Dying Light game at gamescom Opening Night Live, entitled Dying Light: The Beast.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>As seen in the trailer, The Beast features the return of protagonist Kyle Crane, and features a new open world region and 20 hours of gameplay.</p><p>According to a press release, The Beast is a full standalone game set in the post-apocalyptic Castor Woods. The player, as Kyle Crane (voiced once more by Roger Craig Smith), escapes after being held captive and experimented on for 13 years following his previous appearances in the series. Now free, he seeks revenge on those who help them captive. The titular "beast" is a massive monster roaming the woods...but Crane, following the experiments conducted on him, now has zombie DNA woven in with his own, giving him a "beast-like power" that he can use to take down. So who's to say who's really the beast of the title?</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Dying Light: The Beast Screenshots - gamescom ONL 2024</h3></div></output><p>The Beast will feature four-player co-op with shared progression, but also allow for solo players. What's more, owners of Dying Light 2: Stay Human Ultimate Edition will receive The Beast for free (it's $39.99 for everyone else). While the game originally started as a story DLC for Dying Light 2, after two years it "evolved into a standalone, self-contained experience."</p><p>Dying Light: The Beast is coming to PC via Steam and the Epic Games Store, Xbox, and PlayStation at an unknown date. The release date is expected to be shared later this year.</p><p><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Look at the Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Campaign | gamescom 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/first-look-at-the-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-campaign-gamescom-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-look-at-the-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-campaign-gamescom-2024.958869/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/first-look-at-the-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-campaign-gamescom-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Rifle through the details.</h2></div><section><p>Activision has shown off the <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> campaign during Opening Night Live, kicking off gamescom 2024 in the process.</p><p>After <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-3-single-player-campaign-review">the criticism the campaign for Modern Warfare 3 received</a> last year, the pressure was on Black Ops 6 campaign developer Raven Software to deliver with this follow-up to Black Ops Cold War. This time, the action is set in the early 1990s, a period of transition and upheaval in global politics, characterized by the end of the Cold War and the rise of the United States as a single superpower.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The trailer revealed Black Ops 6's new omnimovement feature, with the player throwing a knife from behind cover in a back prone position. The mission on show is called Most Wanted, in which the rogue team needs to rescue one of their own from a top-secret black site underneath Washington, D.C.</p><p>Here's the official blurb, from Activision:</p><blockquote>Playing the role of “Case”, a key member of the Black Ops team led by Frank Woods, your cohorts on the ground are comprised of Woods’ protégé Troy Marshall, backed up by technical guru Felix Neumann, and Sevati “Sev” Dumas, an infiltration and assassination specialist. As the action begins, Troy and Felix have commandeered a S.W.A.T. truck parked on the edge of the Capitol Station grounds, and the two are confirming Felix’s latest gadget – a camera with retinal scanning capabilities – is operational. Now the time has come for its first field test.</blockquote><blockquote>Marshall sums up the mission succinctly: You’re to show up to a political fundraiser, obtain retinal identification from a senator who has the clearance to enter the Black Site, and grab Adler from the Black Site before anyone knows what’s happening.</blockquote><blockquote>Naturally, that’s easier said than done.</blockquote><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Call of Duty Black Ops 6 - gamescom ONL Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Black Ops 6, the first mainline Call of Duty to release following Microsoft's $69 billion acquisition of Activision Blizzard, launches day one into subscription service Game Pass as well as in the normal, premium fashion, on October 25, 2024.</p><p>For more, check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-everything-announced">everything announced during Opening Night Live 2024</a>.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda Film Director Wes Ball Is Taking on Yet Another Video Game Adaptation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-film-director-wes-ball-is-taking-on-yet-another-video-game-adaptation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-legend-of-zelda-film-director-wes-ball-is-taking-on-yet-another-video-game-adaptation.958863/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-film-director-wes-ball-is-taking-on-yet-another-video-game-adaptation<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Ruiner is coming to the big screen.</h2></div><section><p>The Legend of Zelda movie director Wes Ball has reportedly set his sights on another adaptation that will see him leading a project based on Devolver Digital and Reikon Games’ <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/ruiner">Ruiner</a>.</p><p>Details on Ball’s next video game-to-movie adaptation come from <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/wes-ball-ruiner-video-game-movie-1235979164/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>The Hollywood Reporter</u></a>, which says that the filmmaker has partnered with Universal Pictures to help bring the cyberpunk shooter to the big screen. Its screenplay is being handled by Jerry Maguire, Meet Joe Black, and Fallen veteran Michael Arlen Ross. No release date or casting information has been revealed.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/20/ruiner-1724176415308.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Wes Ball is set to direct a movie based on Ruiner.</figcaption></figure></output><p>“RUINER is a brutal action shooter set in the year 2091 in the cyber metropolis Rengkok,” Ruiner’s description on Steam says. “A wired psychopath lashes out against a corrupt system to uncover the truth and retrieve his kidnapped brother under the guidance of a secretive hacker friend. Combine preternatural reflexes, augmented tools, and the arsenal of fallen foes to tear down and dismantle the corporate titans of virtuality dealers at HEAVEN.”</p><p>The Ruiner movie will be produced by Ball, Dmitri M. Johnson, Mike Goldberg, and Joe Hartwick Jr., with Timothy I. Stevenson, Dan Jevons, Marek Roefler, Magdalena Tomkowicz, and Jakub Stylinski attached as executive producers. It'll be overseen by Universal's senior vice president of production development, Ryan Jones, and its creative executive of production development, Jacqueline Garell.</p><p>Ball made a name for himself in the 2010s as director of the Maze Runner trilogy. A new wave of audiences took note of his work this year with the release of Kingdom of the Planet of the Apes, with Ball primed to enter another classic franchise with the eventual release of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-is-making-a-live-action-legend-of-zelda-movie"><u>the live-action Zelda movie</u></a>. Details about the Nintendo film are <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-the-zelda-movie-director-wont-reveal-his-favorite-zelda-game"><u>being kept secret</u></a>, though we do know that the director <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-director-not-planning-much-motion-capture-grounded-adaptation"><u>doesn’t plan on using much motion capture</u></a> in what he is calling a “grounded” project.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Live-Action Versions of Video Game Characters</h3></div></output><p>With Ball’s Zelda movie also without a firm release schedule, there’s no telling when Ruiner will hack its way into theaters. For now, we can at least look at <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-of-the-planet-of-the-apes-reveals-the-franchises-secret-to-success"><u>the success of his Planet of the Apes film</u></a> and hope he manages to deliver more stories based on iconic properties. We enjoyed this year’s soft reboot and gave it an 8/10 in <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-of-the-planet-of-the-apes-review"><u>our review</u></a>.</p><p><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Medievalpunk roguelike action game Reignbreaker announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/medievalpunk-roguelike-action-game-reignbreaker-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/medievalpunk-roguelike-action-game-reignbreaker-announced-for-pc.958860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/medievalpunk-roguelike-action-game-reignbreaker-announced-for-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>From publisher Thunderful Games and developer Studio Fizbin.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Thunderful Games [229 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/thunderful-games">Thunderful Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Studio Fizbin [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/headup/studio-fizbin">Studio Fizbin</a> have announced medievalpunk <a title="Genres > Roguelike [238 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Reignbreaker" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/reignbreaker">Reignbreaker</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,962 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2129810/Reignbreaker/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). A release date was not announced. <span id="more-906528"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Thunderful Games:</p><blockquote><p>In <em>Reignbreaker</em>, players wreak havoc on a dystopian kingdom as Clef, a child soldier turned anarchist rebel. From deep within the gothic sprawl of the Queen’s domain, Clef and a band of rebels dash and smash through legions of hostile high-tech medieval machines to breach the inner sanctums of the Bastion, a giant fortress where the unimaginable riches of the elite are stored. Players must plunder the coffers of the Bastion, smash the kingdom and become The Reignbreaker.</p><p><em>Reignbreaker</em> presents players with a unique hand-drawn dungeoneering experience with stylish inspirations from punk, anime and pop culture. The medievalpunk roguelike features brutal and fast-paced combat with several unlockable variations of motorized Javelins, Clef’s weapon of choice. Equal parts weapon and lockpick, the Javelin is a deadly tool used to fight machines, open doors and override traps. With a strong femme protagonist, eccentric characters and a seductive story about uprising and rebellion, <em>Reignbreaker</em> delivers an unforgettable power fantasy about smashing an oppressive system and returning power to the people.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/reignbreaker/august-20-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="Reignbreaker | Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6D14kf8FcyY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_906531"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sid Meier’s Civilization VII launches February 11, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-launches-february-11-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sid-meier%E2%80%99s-civilization-vii-launches-february-11-2025.958854/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-launches-february-11-2025<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A revolutionary new chapter in the esteemed strategy game franchise.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Sid Meier's Civilization VII [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,716 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,591 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Series, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,072 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,404 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, Switch, <a title="Platforms > PC [20,962 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, Mac, and Linux via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1295660/Sid_Meiers_Civilization_VII/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, as well as PC via <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/sid-meiers-civilization-vii" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, on February 11, 2025, publisher <a title="Companies > 2K [642 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/take-two-interactive-software/2k">2K</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Firaxis Games [41 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/take-two-interactive-software/2k/firaxis-games">Firaxis Games</a> announced. <span id="more-906712"></span></p><p>“We’re incredibly excited to take players on a new type of journey through history in <em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</em>,” stated Firaxi Games creative director Ed Beach in a press release. “With the introduction of revolutionary new features such as Ages, the ability to select leaders and civilizations independently to mix and match gameplay bonuses, a beautiful new art style and more, <em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</em> promises to be true to our goal of being the ultimate historical <a title="Genres > Strategy [189 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">strategy game</a>.”</p><p>Firaxis Games executive producer Dennis Shirk added, “Building an empire to stand the test of time has never felt more historically immersive. This is easily the biggest and most ambitious Civilization game we’ve ever made, one that we plan to support for many years to come.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via 2K:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Representing a revolutionary new chapter in the storied and esteemed strategy game franchise, which has sold-in more than 70 million copies worldwide, <em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</em> will be available on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,881 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series X|S</a>, Xbox One, <a title="Platforms > Nintendo [20,615 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a>&nbsp; Switch, PC via Steam and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [339 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store, and Mac and Linux via Steam. <em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</em> will feature support for cross-play and cross-progression, and is now available for pre-order.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Full details about <em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</em> were shared during Gamescom Opening Night Live and an ensuing gameplay showcase that highlighted the title’s innovative new features. The announcement also revealed Gwendoline Christie (<em>Game of Thrones</em>, <em>Star Wars</em> franchise) as the new narrator of the game via an enthralling live-<a title="Genres > Action [2,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> trailer.</p><p>In <em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</em>, your strategic decisions shape the unique cultural lineage of your evolving empire. Rule as one of many legendary leaders from throughout history and steer the course of your story by choosing a new civilization to represent your empire in each Age of human advancement.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Build an Empire to Stand the Test of Time</strong> – Lead your empire through distinct Ages of human history. Each Age is its own rich, nuanced journey, with unique playable civilizations, available resources, explorable land, and even entire gameplay systems, creating a deep, historically immersive strategy experience. Strive to accomplish significant scientific, cultural, militaristic, and economic milestones within each Age to unlock impactful advantages in the next!</li><li><strong>Evolve Your Empire as Each New Age Dawns</strong> – To build a legacy that truly stands the test of time, you must adapt. Forge your own path through history as you reshape your empire at the start of each Age, selecting from a pool of new Age-relevant civilization options determined by your prior gameplay accomplishments. Evolving your empire unlocks fresh gameplay bonuses and unique units, so your current civilization is always at the height of its power.</li><li><strong>Play as Visionary Leaders of Progress</strong> – Embody an illustrious leader with one of <em>Civilization</em>‘s most diverse rosters yet, from traditional heads of state known for their militaristic might or political prowess, to visionary leaders who made everlasting impacts in philosophy, science, human rights, and more! Each leader possesses a unique ability and can further be improved with customizable attributes earned through gameplay, empowering you to reinforce or pivot your strategy from one Age into the next. For the first time in franchise history, you can choose your leader separately from your civilization, giving you the freedom to create all-new strategies by mixing and matching gameplay bonuses.</li><li><strong>Explore a World Brought to Life Like Never Before</strong> – Make your mark on a gorgeously detailed world! Your empire comes to life with a vast, diverse range of cultural styles, represented across building architecture and unit design. Face-to-face interactions with other historic leaders immerse you in every act of diplomacy and declaration of war. As your territory expands and your cities continue to develop, lavishly rendered vistas of your empire seamlessly connect to create a vibrant metropolis.</li><li><strong>Test Your Strategic Mettle in <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [363 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a></strong> – Compete against other players online and prove your prowess as a great leader. Multiplayer matches can be epic multi-Age campaigns, or take place in a single Age so you can enjoy an entire game in a single session. Cross-play is supported between PC and consoles, so you can play together with friends wherever they are.</li><li><strong>An Enjoyable Strategy <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> for All</strong> – With more than 30 years of franchise legacy to draw from, <em>Civilization VII</em> features a vast wealth of gameplay improvements that will thrill series veterans and newcomers alike. The overhauled tutorial experience and refined gameplay systems make jumping into <em>Civilization</em> easier than ever, while returning players will appreciate a massive suite of gameplay improvements. Move your army as one under the leadership of a commander, unlock progression bonuses for your leaders across multiple gameplay sessions, traverse navigable rivers, and much, much more!</li></ul></blockquote><div id="carousel_907766"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Game Editions</strong></p><p><em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</em> will be available in three editions: Standard Edition, Deluxe Edition, and a limited-time Founders Edition. An additional limited-availability Collector’s Edition will be available, which includes physical collectibles themed around the game. A full breakdown is available on the <em>Civilization</em> website; edition details are as follows:</p><ul><li><strong>Standard Edition</strong> – The Standard Edition will be available for $59.99 on <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,802 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a>, and $69.99 on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PC via Steam and Epic Games Store, and Mac and Linux via Steam. It includes the base game; dual-gen entitlement is provided for digital copies on Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PlayStation 4 consoles respectively, linked to the same account. For physical copies, dual-gen entitlement is provided on Xbox One and Xbox Series X|S, but physical copies on PlayStation 5 do not grant dual-gen entitlement for PlayStation 4 as <em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</em> is digital-only on PlayStation 4.</li><li><strong>Deluxe Edition</strong> – The Deluxe Edition will be available for $89.99 on Nintendo Switch, and $99.99 on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PC via Steam and Epic Games Store, and Mac and Linux via Steam. It includes Early Access to play the game early starting on February 6, 2025, the “Tecumseh and Shawnee Pack,” the post-launch downloadable content “<a title="Games > Crossroads [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/crossroads">Crossroads</a> of the World Collection,” and the “Deluxe Content Pack.”</li><li><strong>Founders Edition</strong> – The Founders Edition will be available for $119.99 on Nintendo Switch, and $129.99 on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PC via Steam and Epic Games Store, and Mac and Linux via Steam. It includes Early Access to play the game early starting on February 6, 2025, the “Tecumseh and Shawnee Pack,” the post-launch downloadable content “Crossroads of the World Collection,” the “Deluxe Content Pack,” the post-launch downloadable content “Right to Rule Collection,” and the “Founders Content Pack.” The Founders Edition is a digital-only edition and is only available until February 28, 2025.</li></ul><p><strong>Pre-Order Bonuses</strong></p><p>Players who pre-order the Standard Edition will receive the “Tecumseh and Shawnee Pack”; additional content can be unlocked by creating and authenticating a 2K account, as well as linking a 2K account to a gaming platform to play <em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VI</em>.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new set of trailers and the official gameplay showcase below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/sid-meiers-civilization-vii/august-20-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Reveal Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Sid Meier’s Civilization VII - Gameplay Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kK_JrrP9m2U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span><a title="Companies > Narrator [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/narrator">Narrator</a> Reveal Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Sid Meier’s Civilization VII - Narrator Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qw6H7r8S_Wk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Official Gameplay Showcase</span></h2><p><iframe title="Sid Meier’s Civilization VII - Official Gameplay Showcase" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tc3_EO6Bj2M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Animal Crossing Fans Will Want To Keep An Eye On This Adorable Life Sim Set In The Clouds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/animal-crossing-fans-will-want-to-keep-an-eye-on-this-adorable-life-sim-set-in-the-clouds/1100-6525997/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/animal-crossing-fans-will-want-to-keep-an-eye-on-this-adorable-life-sim-set-in-the-clouds.958851/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/animal-crossing-fans-will-want-to-keep-an-eye-on-this-adorable-life-sim-set-in-the-clouds/1100-6525997/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525997">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Looking for a new game to scratch that Animal Crossing itch? Then you're in luck, as a very promising (and completely adorable) new title is now in the works. Announced during Gamescom Opening Night Live, Floatopia is an upcoming farming/life sim that sees players start a new, superpower-filled life in the clouds and features charming, Animal Crossing-esque visuals. You can check out some images of the game below.</p><p>Billed as "a whimsical world filled with toys, travel, superpowers, and floating islands," Floatopia is the next game from developer NetEase. The studio stated that the game will feature farming, fishing, logging, and home decorating, as well as plenty of magical powers and world customization. When not tending to their homestead, players will get the chance to travel to other realms inspired by "diverse cultures." According to NetEase, these islands will feature "mountaintop cities, ancient towns, deserts, frozen expanses, whimsical fairy-tale kingdoms, and culinary paradises."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1542677628" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464900,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Floatopia%20-%20Official%20Reveal%20Trailer%20%7C%20Gamescom%202024&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:89,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/floatopia-official-reveal-trailer-gamescom-2024\/2300-6464900\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464900\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464900\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464900\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464900&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464900,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525997&quot;,&quot;collection&quot;:&quot;gamescom&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,nintendo-switch,xbox-one,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464900},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464900\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/rOvwmJIK.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724187420,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="rOvwmJIK" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Floatopia - Official Reveal Trailer | Gamescom 2024</p>
      </div>
<figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353904-bd07180d-b1b6-4d92-b0dd-017a76d08634.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353905-ffc3e42f-c676-43fb-a1f3-5199040e62e3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353906-1da63f42-e259-4a2c-9a52-2415126cd4b2.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353907-064c2a6d-a580-49b6-811b-c949f5c6dd8a.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353908-74197792-521b-46fe-9e23-cd4799a4eb24.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353909-b784aa86-be74-48d3-ad59-fbef3ee08794.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4353904,1300-4353905,1300-4353906,1300-4353907,1300-4353908,1300-4353909" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4353904-bd07180d-b1b6-4d92-b0dd-017a76d08634.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4353905-ffc3e42f-c676-43fb-a1f3-5199040e62e3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4353906-1da63f42-e259-4a2c-9a52-2415126cd4b2.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4353907-064c2a6d-a580-49b6-811b-c949f5c6dd8a.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4353908-74197792-521b-46fe-9e23-cd4799a4eb24.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4353909-b784aa86-be74-48d3-ad59-fbef3ee08794.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353904-bd07180d-b1b6-4d92-b0dd-017a76d08634.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353905-ffc3e42f-c676-43fb-a1f3-5199040e62e3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353906-1da63f42-e259-4a2c-9a52-2415126cd4b2.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353907-064c2a6d-a580-49b6-811b-c949f5c6dd8a.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353908-74197792-521b-46fe-9e23-cd4799a4eb24.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4353909-b784aa86-be74-48d3-ad59-fbef3ee08794.jpg"></figure><p>In the official <a href="https://www.floatopia.game/news/official/20240819/40963_1175322.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Floatopia press release</a>, the studio delved into the overall themes, writing:</p><p>"Imagine a world where superpowers are just a phone call away. In this fantastical realm, the most sought-after superpowers are quickly reserved, leaving only the seemingly 'useless' powers behind. You play a character who, by a twist of fate, joins forces with others possessing these overlooked superpowers.</p><p>"As the main storyline unfolds, you gradually uncover the truth of the world and the meaning of your travels—'usefulness' is not the only measure of value. Every seemingly 'useless' ability has its own unique worth and hidden potential."</p><p>Those who <a href="https://www.floatopia.game/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">preregister to play the game</a> will be given a Special Island Gift Pack, which includes a new costume, seesaw, and more. Floatopia is scheduled to release on PS5, Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, and PC in 2025.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An Exciting Twist Makes Lost Records: Bloom And Rage More Than A Life Is Strange Imitator]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/an-exciting-twist-makes-lost-records-bloom-and-rage-more-than-a-life-is-strange-imitator/1100-6525805/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/an-exciting-twist-makes-lost-records-bloom-and-rage-more-than-a-life-is-strange-imitator.958848/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/an-exciting-twist-makes-lost-records-bloom-and-rage-more-than-a-life-is-strange-imitator/1100-6525805/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525805">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">When <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/life-is-strange/" data-ref-id="5000-306210">Life Is Strange</a> came out in 2015, it was following in the footsteps of many games before it, but the most apparent was those from Telltale, which at that time was on a hot streak of making adventure games with branching narratives and lots of dialogue choices. Don't Nod made this format its own with Life Is Strange, spawning several sequels and spin-offs over the years to come, always focusing on young people caught up in tumultuous situations but gifted with mysterious supernatural abilities.</p><p dir="ltr">Nearly a decade after that debut, and after having <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/developer/DONTNOD" rel="nofollow ">developed and published many other types of games</a>, Don't Nod is returning to the type of experience that made it famous. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/lost-records-bloom-and-rage/" data-ref-id="5000-612208">Lost Records: Bloom and Rage</a> is a third-person adventure game that is one part Stand By Me, one part I Know What You Did Last Summer, and totally exciting.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1123403349" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6463987,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Lost%20Records%3A%20Bloom%20%26%20Rage%20%7C%20Lo-fi%20Summer%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:84,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/lost-records-bloom-rage-lo-fi-summer-trailer\/2300-6463987\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463987\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463987\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463987\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6463987&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6463987,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525805&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;lost-records-bloom-rage&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;dontnod-entertainment&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6463987},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6463987\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4295119-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/dLTZI4P2.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1714411080,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="dLTZI4P2" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage | Lo-fi Summer Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Lost Records, like the original Life Is Strange, focuses on teenage girls. Only this time, it's not a pair of best friends like Max and Chloe, but a foursome of girls, including the protagonist, a newcomer to the group named Swann Holloway. Swann is an awkward, freckle-faced girl, probably 15 or so, who loves horror movies, fuzzy slippers, and her cat, Pumpkin. A two-hour preview build I played started me off in her bedroom, where she was arguing with her mom from a different floor of their house.</p><p dir="ltr">The year is 1995, and her room makes that abundantly clear, as it's covered wall-to-wall in her period-appropriate obsessions--the way most young people are known to do in any era. Legally distinct X-Files pictures have been cut out from magazines and hung like posters, Lisa Frank-esque neon notepads are strewn about her desk, and VHS rentals are tucked into nearly every corner of the floor.</p><p dir="ltr">The game's lo-fi soundtrack pulled me right back to being a '90s kid myself, and though Swann has about a decade on me in years, it all felt authentic and nostalgic. I'm really excited to see we're at a point where the 1990s are the new nostalgia-bait. I don't mind taking that bait one bit, and Lost Records leans way into it.</p><p dir="ltr">It doesn't seem as though Swann will have any supernatural powers, but in between choosing dialogue options and exploring a level to interact with a number of objects, she's also equipped with a camcorder--the type that seemingly every family had growing up in that era. It's this detail that has me especially excited for Lost Records.</p><p dir="ltr">With the camcorder, players jump into first-person and record Swann's life with few limitations. Recording certain things will trigger memoirs, or bundles of scenes you can put together as home movies, which are then narrated by Swann. The grainy filter that ends up over each finished project is like a time machine for my eyes.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4350306-bloom%26rage_screen_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4350306" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4350306-bloom%26rage_screen_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4350306"></a><figcaption>Making home movies is such a cool twist on Don't Nod's traditional adventure game mechanics.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4350306-bloom%26rage_screen_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">These home movies even use a player's exact recordings rather than fill them in with footage that looks "close enough," giving each player a chance to find their director's eye in an engaging way that I already love as a gameplay mechanic. If you don't love your first draft, you can go long on taping things and edit your videos on the fly in the memoirs menu.</p><p dir="ltr">As Swann and her three burgeoning besties headed off from band practice and trekked into the woods to make a music video for their after-school punk rock band, Bloom and Rage, the sunlight trickled through the flora and reminded me how pretty Unreal Engine 5's lighting can be. This isn't a Life is Strange game, but it looks a lot like one, except it would be the most gorgeous game in the series, without a doubt.</p><p dir="ltr">After several scenes are recorded, from the girls air-guitaring atop a small hill to even a close-up shot of deer poop, the girls ended their day watching the sunset at the edge of a not-entirely-safe lookout, their feet dangling over a cliff's edge so that they may feel that unique sense of invincibility that comes with being a teen. It's idyllic, but because this is Don't Nod, you know it's to be short-lived.</p><p dir="ltr">Back at their garage hangout, the girls are engrossed with what Swann's created. Before they can even rewind to watch it a second time, the camcorder suddenly seems to take on a life of its own, skipping ahead to late-night footage that Swann hardly remembered. What was on the footage isn't revealed in the demo, but it seemed to shock the girls. The demo ended abruptly at that point, leading me to wonder if there's a supernatural element after all--even if, perhaps, Swann isn't the one with such powers.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4350307-bloom%26rage_screen_2.png" data-ref-id="1300-4350307" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4350307-bloom%26rage_screen_2.png" data-ref-id="1300-4350307"></a><figcaption>Bloom and Rage isn't a good band, but that's the point; the girls are finding themselves.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4350307-bloom%26rage_screen_2.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">A framing device set in the modern day breaks up the flashbacks throughout the demo, and offers a bit more insight. In a bar as adults, Swann and Autumn speak with concerned voices about a strange package they received that is addressed to their band and decorated with knowing threats, like "I remember" and "I was there." It seems the girls got up to something that summer that they don't want getting out into the public, and now their past has come back to haunt them while it simultaneously teases me with the details just out of reach.</p><p dir="ltr">I can't wait to play more of Lost Records. The mix of '90s nostalgia with classic Don't Nod adventure game elements and the new camcorder mechanics makes for a story-driven game that I'll be thinking about until I can get behind the camera again.</p><p dir="ltr">Lost Records: Bloom and Rage was previously set to launch this fall, but it was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-dev-delays-its-new-game-to-avoid-the-sequel-to-the-series-it-used-to-make/1100-6524598/">pushed back to give Life is Strange: Double Exposure some breathing room</a> when it launches this October. As of now, Lost Records: Bloom and Rage is scheduled for early 2025 on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia is back and heading to The Old Country next year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mafia-is-back-and-heading-to-the-old-country-next-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-is-back-and-heading-to-the-old-country-next-year.958845/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/mafia-is-back-and-heading-to-the-old-country-next-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>On PS5, Series X/S, and PC.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/mafia-the-old-country-headline.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hangar 13/2K Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
It's been two years since Mafia developer <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/hangar13">Hangar 13</a> <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mafia-3-developer-confirms-new-mafia-development">confirmed it was working on a new entry</a> in its open-world crime series, and the time has finally come for it to be revealed to the world. It's called Mafia: The Old Country and is heading to PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC next year.
</p>
<p>
While 2016's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mafia-iii">Mafia 3</a> shunted the series forward in time to the late 60s (the first two games spanned the 1930s, 40s, and 50s between them), The Old Country is going backward, presenting players with a "gritty mob story set in the brutal underworld of 1900s Sicily."
</p>
<p>
"Fight to survive in this dangerous and unforgiving era," teases the scant bit of blurb accompanying today's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=crDUx5suLm4">teaser trailer</a>, "with action brought to life by the authentic realism and rich storytelling that the critically acclaimed Mafia series is known for."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mafia: The Old Country - Official Teaser Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mafia: The Old Country - Official Teaser Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Mafia: The Old Country teaser trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=crDUx5suLm4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
And that's pretty much all Hangar 13 is saying right now. Those hoping to learn more about Mafia: The Old Country will need to wait until this December, when the studio says it'll be sharing additional information.
</p>
<p>
So there you go; Mafia: The Old Country launches for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1941540/Mafia_The_Old_Country/">Steam</a> at some point next year. And if you've yet to experience the Mafia saga as it currently exists, all three titles are temporarily discounted - in both their original and remastered Definitive Edition forms - on Valve's storefront to coincide with today's big reveal.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country announced at the end of Opening Night Live]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/mafia-the-old-country-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-announced-at-the-end-of-opening-night-live.958830/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/mafia-the-old-country-trailer/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Rumours of a new Mafia game have been floating around for a while and they have now been confirmed with the reveal of Mafia: The Old Country. This time you will be heading to the 1900s Sicily underworld and the game will be out on PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC via Steam.</p>
<p><iframe title="Mafia: The Old Country - Official Teaser Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>“Uncover the origins of organized crime with a gritty mob story set in the brutal underworld of 1900s Sicily. Fight to survive in this dangerous and unforgiving era, with action brought to life by the authentic realism and rich storytelling that the critically acclaimed&nbsp;<em>Mafia</em> series is known for.”</p>
<p>“Across the first three entries in the&nbsp;<em>Mafia</em>&nbsp;franchise, we introduced players to the world of the Mafia through brutal stories set in different eras,” said Nick Baynes, President of Hangar 13. “In&nbsp;<em>Mafia: The Old Country</em>, we’re going back to the roots of what fans love about the franchise, crafting a deep, linear narrative with that classic mob movie feeling, visiting a stunning new setting, and delivering it all in a tight, focused package perfect for fans of immersive experiences.”</p>
<p>A full reveal of the game will occur in December, so I would guess that would be at The Game Awards 2024.</p>


<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=crDUx5suLm4">YouTube</a> / <a href="https://newsroom.2k.com/news/uncover-the-origins-of-organized-crime-in-mafia-the-old-country-coming-in-2025">2K</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>