<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 14:29:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/16/black-myth-wukong-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-review.955038/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/16/black-myth-wukong-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Black: Myth: Wukong is a game that’s been in the minds of many since its announcement. From its staggeringly beautiful first reveal to the swirl of controversy and controversy-driven popularity surrounding its development, the latest adaptation of Journey to the West can’t stay out of the limelight.</p>
<p><iframe title="Black Myth: Wukong - Final Trailer | Launching August 20, 2024" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bzyMLoSwYvk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As a huge fan of the Monkey King and a lot of the ways his story has been told in media, from Dragon Ball, Tower of God, and Enslaved: Odyssey to the West, I’ve been looking forward to Black Myth: Wukong since I first saw it. That anticipation for this game was dampened significantly by <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-black-myth-wukong-developers-history-of-sexism-is-complicating-its-journey-to-the-west">the reports on deeply seated sexist attitude within the studio</a>, but they’re not going to be taken into account for this review. However, they definitely bear mentioning.</p>


<p>Black: Myth Wukong makes a strong, albeit slow, first impression. Scenery flies by as you fly through the sky to get into a fight I’m not allowed to talk about according to the embargo rules and then, you pick up with the actual story, and off you go. You charge through the trees learning more about how to play the game why you take out different monstrous enemies as you go, and quickly come across your first boss to slay. However, things go poorly no matter how well you do, and this is where you meet a dude who has roots growing out of his face, and is your Navi equivalent for the game. He’ll appear and guide you throughout, and help you find your next checkpoint, which are little shrines, along with explaining some mechanics, warning you about bosses, and teaching you the odd trick or two.</p>


<p>Combat is a blend of unleashing physical and magical attacks, with some dodging thrown in for good measure. It’s pretty fluid, and some of the spells are incredibly cool, along with basically all of the animations being like sugar for your eyes. The enemy designs are also exceptional, with fights in just the opening few hours including fox demons, a big old frog, and a werewolf-looking boss that definitely climbed out of Bloodborne.</p>
<p>However, and this is kind of a big deal for me, the action never <em>felt</em> anywhere near as good as it looked. No combination of new abilities, bosses, or anything else, managed to change that through the run of the game. I just don’t think the feel of Black Myth: Wukong is anywhere near the looks of the game, and for me, that’s a big issue. I’d always rather play a game that looked worse than it played, and not the other way around.</p>

<p>I’m also not 100% sure where the Soulslike comparisons came from for this game. I’ve played nearly every Soulslike that’s come out (including a bunch of games that I’d frankly rather never think about again), and while this game does have things like a checkpoint that can respawn enemies, that’s about as far as it goes. This is just an action game where sometimes the bosses are hard.</p>
<p>They certainly get tougher as you go on, but there’s none of the fear that Soulslikes instills, nor is there any pattern recognition that’s really needed to succeed. Your hero dodges very well, which meant that I took down a lot of bosses on my first or second try, with the second try often being because I’d messed about too much in the boss run and used up all of my resources. Again, they all look incredible, but that’s about it.</p>

<p>I found the story enjoyable overall though, which is good news if that’s your main worry. It’s hard not to find a story of magic and monkeys enjoyable though, even if all of the dialogue hams things up. That’s a compliment, just so we’re all clear, but I do also appreciate the it might mean it misses for some people.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong Review – A Compelling Journey Into Chinese Tradition]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/black-myth-wukong-a-compelling-journey-into-chinese-tradition/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-review-%E2%80%93-a-compelling-journey-into-chinese-tradition.955035/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/black-myth-wukong-a-compelling-journey-into-chinese-tradition/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
				<main>

					

					<!--<div class="ads-container banner-ad floated p-0">
						<div data-pg-ad-spot='div-gpt-ad-wccftechcom38564' style="min-height: 280px;"></div>
					</div>-->
					
										<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Black Myth: Wukong</h5><p><span>August 20, 2024</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC, PlayStation 5; Xbox Series S|X (later)</span>
						</p></div></div></div>
					<p>Black Myth: Wukong made more than a few heads turn with its reveal trailer released back in 2020, but it was with the switch to Unreal Engine 5 that the action role-playing game developed by Game Science entered most players' radars. With beautiful environments and highly detailed characters enhanced by the engine, Black Myth: Wukong promised to be one of the first truly next-gen action role-playing games.</p>
<p>Being from an unproven studio, many wondered if Game Science had what it takes to create a compelling action role-playing game experience. After spending around 25 hours with the game, I can say that they definitely did, although the game doesn't exactly try to innovate the genre, presenting an engaging but not particularly innovative blend of elements lifted from multiple Soulslikes, including the Team NINJA's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nioh-2-the-complete-edition-grave-no-bar/">Nioh</a> series, CAPCOM's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/monster-hunter-rise-sunbreak-the-flame-of-kamura-burns-ever-hotter/">Monster Hunter</a> and more traditional action games.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/20240810140926_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Black Myth: Wukong is based on Journey to the West, a novel published in China in the 16th century detailing the story of Sun Wukong, a monkey born from a stone who eventually learns the art of the tao, 72 transformations, combat techniques, and the secret of immortality. After becoming incredibly powerful, Sun Wukong challenges Heaven, only to fail and lose the artifacts that gave him power. Years after his defeat, the Destined One, who looks exactly like Sun Wukong, sets out to recover the artifacts that Sun Wukong had lost, getting to know more about the land and how the artifacts themselves have shaped the lives of those touched by them.</p>
<p>The Black Myth: Wukong story is a concise retelling of the traditional story, so those familiar with it will not be wholly surprised by the game's story. Being not a direct adaptation, however, there are still some surprises along the way which manage to make the experience entertaining even for those who are extremely familiar with Journey to the West. Story presentation also makes the journey enjoyable, as do the personable characters accompanying the Destined One. The writing is solid, going for a different tone depending on the character or the chapter, although it gets a little confusing at times. Some of these characters are clear standouts, like the main character of Chapter 2, who delights the Destined One and the player with some catchy tunes in Chinese, but every character is well realized for the amount of screen time they get. Competent English voiceovers compound the solid writing, although the original Chinese dub should be the one to go with for an authentic experience.</p>
<p>The Black Myth: Wukong story is possibly made more enjoyable by the great amount of care developer Game Science put into world-building. Though hidden inside the menu, the game provides tons of information on the many Yaoguai the Destined One faces on his journey, painting a very vivid picture of the beautiful world they inhabit. The main story bosses, in this regard, receive special treatment, thanks to an assortment of special cutscenes that play after their defeat, employing various animation techniques that ecthes them in the player's memory. The amount of love poured into the game's setting is evident, and the whole experience greatly benefits from it.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/20240810142945_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>While the story may not be everyone's cup of tea, Black Myth: Wukong definitely delivers when it comes to gameplay, although it may feel a little lacking in depth compared to the games that inspired it. At its heart, the game is best described as a rather straightforward action game with elements lifted from the Souls series, such as stamina-based combat, bonfire-like checkpoints, dodge/rolling heavy defensive gameplay, and a main healing tool with multiple uses and some customization options like Elden Ring's Flask of Wondrous Physicks.</p>
<p>Unlike the Souls series, however, the Destined One can only use staves as the main weapon, which all come with the same moveset, which is comprised of a light combo string and a heavy attack that changes depending on the chosen stance. The stance, which can be switched on the fly, also changes the Varied Combo, which is a special combo initiated by using a heavy attack in the middle of a string.</p>
<p>Despite stances not altering the moveset a lot, they do make quite a difference. In Smash stance, for example, timing the Varied Combo to intercept an enemy attack will grant the Destined One increased staggering power, among other advantages that are unlocked via the dedicated skill trees, available for pretty much every combat tool. This is quite reminiscent of the counter-heavy playstyle of the Monster Hunter series Longsword. The Pillar stance, on the other hand, grants the Destined One the ability to climb on its extended staff to avoid ground attacks and deal massive damage from a safe position, while the Thrust stance gives access to attacks with longer range.</p>
<p>These powerful abilities are balanced out by the Focus system, which prevents spamming. By hitting the enemy with light attacks and with the staff spin maneuver, which also repels projectiles, Focus builds up to the point where a charge is stored. The more charges are stored, the more powerful the heavy attack will be, and the less time a heavy attack has to be charged to gain more Focus for better efficacy. Focus can also be gained via perfect dodges and other means, so there are different ways to play optimally despite the single basic moveset.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/20240810004928_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>While the Destined One can only use his staff as the main weapon, there are many other combat tools available, starting with spells. Belonging to three different types, these spells allow the Destined One to parry enemy attacks, immobilize enemies, create duplicates, and so on. These spells are rather powerful, and they are a central component in build-crafting together with the simple armor system, which grants different buffs depending on how many items from a set are equipped, similar to the Nioh series. Spirits, single attacks that can be unleashed by transforming into defeated enemies, also play a role in build-crafting, as they grant buffs that empower certain playstyles. Armor sets, alongside weapon upgrades that employ a weapon tree not too dissimilar from that seen in the Monster Hunter series, can be crafted from checkpoints using materials gathered on the field and special items obtained by defeating bosses.</p>
<p>Rounding up the combat tools available in Black Myth: Wukong are Vessels, accessories that can be activated at any time to grant different effects like improved resistances, and proper Transformations that turn the Destined One into one of the enemies he has defeated for a prolonged amount of time, giving access to different movesets and abilities. These options, like spells, have cooldown timers, so it is impossible to spam them repeatedly to win. Not that it is really needed, as Black Myth: Wukong is not a very difficult game. Most mobs are not a threat at all, and most bosses can be defeated the first time through, with only a few exceptions. Even then, a couple of tries should be more than enough for experienced action game players.</p>
<p>While this may sound disappointing, I've found Black Myth: Wukong's approach to difficulty refreshing. Though enemy placement and certain movesets are reminiscent of the Souls series, none reach the frustrating difficulty of many of the enemies in Elden Ring, whose boss design gets really extreme sometimes. Here, no boss will unleash an arena-wide attack with multiple swings that must be avoided with very strict timing or deliver a cheap kill all of a sudden. Considering how much I was frustrated by some of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-worthy-of-the-greater-wills-blessing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree</a> bosses, I really welcomed this approach, which still kept me on my toes but never made me feel like I was at a huge disadvantage, no matter what I did. The fact that regular enemy design is super varied and the main boss design is extremely good makes it all the easier to forgive the game for an experience that is, maybe, too little challenging at times.</p>
<p>Level design is also competent, although not particularly inspired. The game's very first chapter doesn't leave a very good impression, featuring a mostly linear design, but things improve greatly from the second chapter onward, as locations become bigger and feature multiple paths, many of them including additional items for crafting weapons and gear, and Mind Cores, which are used to craft a special type of medicine unlocked in late Chapter 2 which grants permanent stat boosts, introducing a sort of Soulslike leveling system, and optional bosses, of which there are quite a few, and some can only be found with some thorough searching and with specific items. Some of them are variants of other bosses, unfortunately, but it is to be expected when having so many of them. Even when the level design gets a bit more open, it definitely does not reach the heights of the interconnectivity that characterized Lordran in the original Dark Souls.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/20240811131949_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Exploration is also limited, with very little verticality, which is surprising given the Destined One's agility, and too many closed-off paths that look explorable at a glance, making it one of the less rewarding aspects of the game. That said, there are still plenty of secrets to be found for those looking for them. These secrets also extend the game's total playtime well past the 25 hours needed to complete the main campaign, though this number may vary depending on the player's skill.</p>
<p>Powered by Unreal Engine 5, Black Myth: Wukong looks great. Character models look highly detailed, while the environments succeed at fusing together natural landscapes with traditional Chinese architecture, giving the game a very charming atmosphere. The game, sadly, is not without some visual glitches, as I often experienced vegetation shadow flickering, which was a bit distracting. With full ray tracing support, the Black Myth: Wukong visuals get elevated to the next level with better shadows and reflections, but the improvements are, in my opinion, not really worth it due to the performance cost, which is rather big.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Black Myth Wukong PC 4K Gameplay [DLSS Balanced, No RT]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1NMN_vaoD9U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As many expected, Black Myth: Wukong sadly suffers from some performance issues, namely the stuttering issues that are sadly common in every current Unreal Engine 5 game. While the game attempts to reduce stuttering by pre-caching shaders before it launches for the first time, traversal stutters are still in. They are very frequent and sometimes very distracting, as some of them last for over one second, which is a massive problem when in combat. As such, I've found the benchmark tool a little misleading, as it shows no stuttering at all.</p>
<p>Generally, however, it is a decent enough representation of the performance you should expect during most of the game, minus the traversal stutters. Don't expect to be able to play the game decently at native resolution with everything maxed out and full ray tracing, however, as my system (i7-13700F, RTX 4080, 32GB RAM] couldn't average 60 FPS even at 1080p resolution. Thankfully, the game supports all three upscalers (DLSS, FSR, XeSS) alongside UE5's TSR (which looks worse than the others) and DLSS Frame Generation, so with some tweaking of the settings and NVIDIA DLSS at balanced, my system averaged 115 FPS in the benchmark. I could have gone with DLSS Quality for better image quality and run the game at around 90 FPS average, but for a fast-paced game like Black Myth: Wukong, I preferred prioritizing framerate.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Black Myth: Wukong couldn't have been a better debut for Game Science. Although their action role-playing game may not be innovative, it's got great production values, it's fun to play, it's engaging, and it's beautiful to look at. Some minor issues, such as a challenge level that could be too low for some and an experience that gets a little stale over time, hold back the game a bit, but in all honesty, I wouldn't be surprised to see more than a few players name Black Myth: Wukong their Game of the Year.</p>
<p><em>PC version tested. Review code provided by the publisher.</em></p>

					
					

<p>Black Myth: Wukong stands out as one of the strongest debut games released in recent times. While not groundbreaking in any way, it masterfully blends elements from several popular franchises to deliver an engaging action RPG experience that ranks just below the very best in the genre. Although stuttering issues and minor gameplay flaws hold it back slightly, these shouldn't deter any action RPG or action game fan from picking it up. The Journey to the West has rarely been this enjoyable.</p>

<div>
		<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Pros</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Great visuals and soundtrack
</li><li>Fun combat system with plenty of interconnecting mechanics
</li><li>Excellent enemy design
</li><li>Balanced difficulty...</li>		</ul>
	</div>
			<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Cons</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>...that maybe gets a little too low at times
</li><li>With combat focus and a limited moveset, the experience gets stale after a while
</li><li>Stuttering issues on PC</li>		</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

					
				</main>
			</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty Mod Shut Down by Activision One Day Before Release]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/call-of-duty-mod-shut-down-activision</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-mod-shut-down-by-activision-one-day-before-release.955029/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/call-of-duty-mod-shut-down-activision<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Activision has hit a popular&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered&nbsp;</em>mod with a cease and desist order just one day before the mod was due to launch.</p>
<p>The H2 Multiplayer Mod, which would have introduced&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare 2 Remastered&nbsp;</em>content into the base&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare Remastered</em>, <a href="https://x.com/H2Multiplayer/status/1824167247436542167" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced yesterday</a> that Activision had issued a cease and desist order and that the mod's creators intended to comply with it.</p>
<p>That means the mod will "[shut] down all operations immediately and permanently", so if you were looking forward to checking out some of&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare 2</em>'s multiplayer gameplay on modern systems, you're out of luck, unfortunately.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-mod-mw2.jpg?itok=xcxEBDxS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-mod-mw2.jpg?itok=jGo1Vfff 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Modern Warfare 2</em>'s campaign has been remastered, but its multiplayer has been left in the past, which this mod was aiming to fix.</figcaption></figure><p>The H2M mod was intended to bring&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare 2</em>'s maps and multiplayer gameplay into&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare Remastered</em>, owing to the lack of a multiplayer mode in 2020's&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 Campaign Remastered&nbsp;</em>(the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-remastered-announcement-surprises-no-one">clue's in the name</a>, I suppose).</p>
<p>It would have introduced new progression elements, attachments, and more to&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare Remastered</em>, as well as bringing in&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare 2</em>'s original killstreak bonuses, creating an experience akin to&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare 2</em>'s multiplayer mode.</p>
<p>Sadly, it looks like it was not to be. We don't know exactly why Activision issued the cease and desist order, but given that the mod would have used&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare 2&nbsp;</em>assets, we can make a few educated guesses.</p>
<p>Since&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare 2 Campaign Remastered&nbsp;</em>is more than four years old now, it's unlikely that the original 2009 game's multiplayer modes will be reintroduced to the package, so you'll have to content yourself with&nbsp;<em>Modern Warfare Remastered</em>'s multiplayer.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-price.jpg?itok=qfR5vPLS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-price.jpg?itok=Dqy-adx8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>At least you can still play&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered</em>'s multiplayer modes.</figcaption></figure><p>As you can probably expect, this cease and desist has resulted in a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/393080/Call_of_Duty_Modern_Warfare_Remastered_2017/#app_reviews_hash">massive review bomb</a> for&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered&nbsp;</em>on Steam, which is now sitting at an Overwhelmingly Negative user rating.</p>
<p>Lest you wonder whether H2M is the cause, many recent reviews directly reference it, and others simply refer to Activision as "greedy" or "evil", so it's not hard to guess what that's in relation to.</p>
<p>Sadly, it's unlikely that Activision will reverse its decision, so you might just have to get your&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>multiplayer kicks elsewhere. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty</em>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's A Complete Marvel Takeover (Again) In Fortnite Battle Royale Chapter 5 Season 4]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-doctor-doom-wolverine-1851624022</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/its-a-complete-marvel-takeover-again-in-fortnite-battle-royale-chapter-5-season-4.955023/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-doctor-doom-wolverine-1851624022<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="b4b46efbc5d9a54269e0976179290542" data-recommend-id="image://b4b46efbc5d9a54269e0976179290542" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Marvel characters run into battle. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Marvel characters run into battle. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Epic Games / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b4b46efbc5d9a54269e0976179290542" data-recommend-id="image://b4b46efbc5d9a54269e0976179290542" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Marvel characters run into battle. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Marvel’s heroes and villains are going to war in <em>Fortnite</em>. The battle royale’s chapter 5 season 4 update adds characters from X-Men, the Fantastic Four, and more, just in time to capitalize on the recent hype (or gloom) surrounding Robert Downey Jr.’s return to the MCU as Doctor Doom. Are you ready to save the world as Lego Peely Wolverine?</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196395" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="80" data-playlist="196395,194440,195386" data-current="196395"><div><p>The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21945.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/news/be-a-marvel-hero-in-fortnite-battle-royale-chapter-5-season-4-absolute-doom&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/be-a-marvel-hero-in-fortnite-battle-royale-chapter-5-season-4-absolute-doom" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The update is live as of August 16</a></span>, and has Doctor Doom taking over the <em>Fortnite</em> island with new locations. There’s also a bunch of additional items and unvaulted powerups to be found on the map, including Captain America’s returning shield, as well as a battle pass that will let you unlock Emma Frost, Mysterio, and more. A skin for Doctor Doom himself can also be earned, but won’t become available for a few weeks. Here’s the trailer for the new content:</p><p>And here’s a brief overview of what’s changing and getting added in chapter 5 season 4:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><h3 id="h20792"><a id=""></a>Locations</h3><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Castle Doom </li><li>Doomstadt </li><li>The Raft</li></ul><h3 id="h20793"><a id=""></a>New And Returning Items</h3><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Dual Micro SMGs</li><li>War Machine’s Arsenal (includes Auto Turret and Hover Jets)</li><li>Monarch Pistol </li><li>Striker Assault Rifle</li><li>Combat Assault Rifle</li><li>Ranger Pistol</li><li>Hammer Pump Shotgun</li><li>Gatekeeper Shotgun</li><li>Hyper SMG</li><li>Shockwave Grenade</li><li>Sovereign Shotgun </li><li>Striker Burst Rifle </li><li>Reveal Medallion </li><li>Siphon Medallion</li><li>Stealth Medallion</li><li>Doom’s Arcane Gauntlets </li><li>Captain America’s Shield</li></ul><h3 id="h20794"><a id=""></a>Absolute Doom Battle Pass</h3><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Gwenpool </strong><em>(unlocked right away!)</em>: “I played the Galactus Event. That makes me an Avenger, right?”</li><li><strong>War Machine</strong>: Ace pilot, military veteran, and trusted armored ally of Tony Stark.</li><li><strong>Peelverine</strong>: Nanamantium-infused skeleton with a ripen-eration mutant ability.</li><li><strong>Emma Frost</strong>: A devious and brilliant mutant psychic with an unbreakable will.</li><li><strong>Captain Jones</strong>: Take up the shield of justice.</li><li><strong>Mysterio</strong>: An inventive supervillain with illusions of grandeur.</li><li><strong>Shuri</strong>: The genius Princess of Wakanda and current Black Panther.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Doom’s Arcane Gauntlets and Captain America’s Shield will be two of the biggest returning iconic Marvel powerups players are fighting for, and both have been reworked since their initial debuts. Doom’s gloves have gotten buffed and now feature the attack ability from Iron Man’s Repulsors, but will also overheat. The shield, meanwhile, has a new charge capability and can block stuff even while you’re sliding and jumping. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/i-wont-miss-fortnites-marvel-season-1845768727&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/i-wont-miss-fortnites-marvel-season-1845768727">It’s been four years since the last Marvel takeover of <em>Fortnite</em></a></span><em> </em>when players banded together to repel the threat of Galactus. The battle royale was languishing a bit as recently as last year, though events like a return to the OG map had lapsed players returning in droves. It’s not shocking that Epic would go back to the Marvel well for another big event. It’s the <em>Fortnite </em>equivalent of Disney tapping Robert Downey Jr. to resurrect its fading MCU empire.</p><p>It’s also been four years since <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/apple-removes-fortnite-from-app-store-1844717397&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/apple-removes-fortnite-from-app-store-1844717397">Apple pulled <em>Fortnite </em>from iPhones</a></span> over Epic’s attempts to circumvent its App Store platform fees. Changing regulations in Europe means players there will once again be able to enjoy<em> Fortnite</em> on their Apple devices. In the U.S., however, iPhone players <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/16/24221361/fortnite-iphone-epic-games-app-store&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/16/24221361/fortnite-iphone-epic-games-app-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">are still blocked</a></span> from the game. For now, at least. If Captain America’s shield can come back to<em> Fortnite</em>, I’m sure <em>Fortnite</em> can find a way to come back to iOS in the states, too. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Adorable Pokemon In-Flight Safety Video Is Super-Effective At Grabbing Your Attention]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-adorable-pokemon-in-flight-safety-video-is-super-effective-at-grabbing-your-attention/1100-6525867/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-adorable-pokemon-in-flight-safety-video-is-super-effective-at-grabbing-your-attention.955020/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-adorable-pokemon-in-flight-safety-video-is-super-effective-at-grabbing-your-attention/1100-6525867/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525867">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Once you've flown a couple of times, airline safety videos are usually boring enough to easily ignore (although you <em>really </em>shouldn't). But a video featuring Pikachu and several other Pokemon teaching you proper airplane safety rules? Now that's an attention-grabber. All Nippon Airways and The Pokemon Company have teamed up to instruct passengers how to stay safe on aircraft, and the result is an adorable collaboration you'll want to watch.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SAolvci7SeA" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/SAolvci7SeA" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The video above has some pretty great cameos from various Pokemon, like Farfetch'd's tiny leek stick luggage taking up far too much space in the overhead compartment, Pikachu observing the seatbelt rule, and a Jigglypuff looking like it's ready to assault a vaper. This is all the information you'd typically expect from an airline video and staff before taking off, but the blend of live-action actors and Pokemon makes it both cute and educational. The video will be played aboard the special <a href="https://www.ana.co.jp/en/jp/international/theme/pikachujet/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Pokemon Air Adventures aircraft</a> from the ANA fleet, which are two airplanes decorated with Pikachu and Eevee designs.</p><p>ANA isn't the only airline to adopt a more-interesting approach to teaching passengers the rules of the air, as <a href="https://youtu.be/qOw44VFNk8Y" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Air New Zealand has several cool videos with a Middle-earth influence</a>. Back on solid ground, Pokemon fans can look forward to the release of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-legends-z-a-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6521882/" data-ref-id="1100-6521882">Pokemon Legends Z-A in 2025</a>. While only a few details on the game have been shared so far, it looks like players will be traveling to Lumiose City in Kalos from Pokemon X and Y when the game is eventually released.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525792&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-poltergeist-house-is-for-sale-and-its-preserved-in-1980s-goodness\/1100-6525792\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525764&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/randy-pitchfords-reaction-to-borderlands-flopping-might-be-funniest-thing-about-the-movie\/1100-6525764\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525682&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/horror-classic-i-am-legend-is-getting-a-new-edition-for-halloween-and-you-can-preorder-it-now\/1100-6525682\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525772&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/star-wars-skywalker-saga-complete-blu-ray-collection-gets-rare-discount-at-amazon\/1100-6525772\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525662&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tim-burtons-batman-is-getting-a-sequel-novel-in-october\/1100-6525662\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525814&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/deadpool-and-wolverine-actor-shares-his-response-for-former-wrestler\/1100-6525814\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525765&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/one-of-last-years-best-games-is-finally-coming-to-consoles\/1100-6525765\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525830&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-age-the-veilguard-preorder-guide\/1100-6525830\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525668&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-steelbook-case-up-for-preorder-comes-with-free-4k-blu-ray-disc\/1100-6525668\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525777&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-update-makes-earning-greater-affix-items-easier-again\/1100-6525777\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525775&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fill-out-your-warhammer-40k-library-on-pc-with-this-monster-fanatical-bundle\/1100-6525775\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525770&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/blizzard-may-have-just-inadvertently-confirmed-an-unannounced-wow-the-war-within-feature\/1100-6525770\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525841&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-elusive-exotic-class-items-are-coming-to-xurs-inventory\/1100-6525841\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525835&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/legacy-of-kain-is-getting-a-re-release-kind-of\/1100-6525835\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525773&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/warhammer-space-marine-board-game-is-only-32-ahead-of-space-marine-2s-launch\/1100-6525773\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525761&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arkham-horror-is-now-a-tabletop-rpg-and-the-starter-set-is-surprisingly-cheap\/1100-6525761\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525844&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/pastel-nintendo-switch-joy-con-controllers-get-big-discounts-at-amazon\/1100-6525844\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525807&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fortnite-festival-season-5-adds-karol-g-and-highly-requested-features\/1100-6525807\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525827&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/inside-out-2-4k-steelbook-preorders-live-releases-soon\/1100-6525827\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty Mod Shut Down By Activision Hours Before Launch, Leading To Review Bombing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-mod-shut-down-by-activision-hours-before-launch-leading-to-review-bombing/1100-6525865/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-mod-shut-down-by-activision-hours-before-launch-leading-to-review-bombing.955017/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-mod-shut-down-by-activision-hours-before-launch-leading-to-review-bombing/1100-6525865/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525865">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Activision has shut down a highly anticipated Call of Duty mod, just hours before it was due to release. The mod, H2M, was billed as a remastering of the original Modern Warfare II multiplayer experience, delivering <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-cod-modern-warfare-2-remastered-lacks-multipla/1100-6475496/" data-ref-id="1100-6475496">what Activision itself did not</a>. But it's not going to happen. As fans feared, Activision issued a cease and desist order to the developers, just like the company did with the <a href="https://x.com/sm2game/status/1658745182819598337" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">fan-made Call of Duty SM2 mod in 2023.</a></p><p>"We are complying with this order and shutting down all operations immediately and permanently," the developers said. The order to shut it down came on August 15, just a day before the modders were due to release the H2M mod on August 16.</p><p>The mod would have required a copy of 2017's Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered. In anticipation of the mod's release, sales of Modern Warfare Remastered rose significantly on Steam. After the news about the cease and desist order came out, however, players <a href="https://x.com/BobNetworkUK_/status/1824199921093722282" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">review-bombed Modern Warfare Remastered</a>, turning its recent reviews rating to "mostly negative."</p><p>Modern Warfare Remastered recently went on sale on Steam, prompting people to speculate that Activision was trying to capitalize on interest in H2M. However, the game regularly goes on sale. </p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/H2Multiplayer/status/1824167247436542167" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Today, our team members received a Cease &amp; Desist order on behalf of Activision Publishing in relation to the H2M-Mod project. We are complying with this order and shutting down all operations immediately and permanently.</p>  — H2 Multiplayer Mod (@H2Multiplayer) <a href="https://twitter.com/H2Multiplayer/status/1824167247436542167?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 15, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Fans who were impressed by the quality of the H2M mod have expressed interest in donating to the mod's creators to help them out, but one of the founders said the team has no plans to do this. "Anyone trying to make money off H2M is not us. Beware," the developer said. This person also said the modding group might turn its attention to an original game next.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VwBEmMPxuRU" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VwBEmMPxuRU" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>In other Call of Duty news, Activision will reveal what's next for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">Black Ops 6</a> during the Call of Duty Next event on August 28. Shortly after that, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-beta-dates-how-to-get-in/1100-6524124/" data-ref-id="1100-6524124">Black Ops 6 beta begins on August 30.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Crush House Is A Hectic Take On Reality TV]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/crush-house-impressions-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-crush-house-is-a-hectic-take-on-reality-tv.955005/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/crush-house-impressions-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I’m not a huge fan of reality TV (with the exception of <a href="https://go.tlc.com/show/sister-wives-tlc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Sister Wives</em></a> because it’s about religion), so I wasn’t sure recent game <a href="https://www.devolverdigital.com/games/the-crush-house" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Crush House</em></a> would be my thing. But the game is less about cringing at other people’s drama and more about what it’s like to use the core mechanic of filming that drama to explore what stands between a reality show's subjects and their audience.</p><p><em>The Crush House</em>, which came out last week, casts you as Jae, a producer on a reality show. You select a cast of four characters and then film them living in a glitzy mansion together, keeping different audiences satisfied enough to keep the show from getting cancelled. If you make it through a week-long season, the cast goes home, and then you start over with a new cast of your choosing.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="The Crush House | Reveal Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hHdOX9XpWJc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>There’s an underlying plot about things not being quite what they seem in the titular Crush House. To move that story forward, you need to do on-the-side tasks for cast members, which can’t necessarily be completed in one season of the show. This adds some structure to your repeated runs, but I could also find it a little annoying when I had to bring back cast members across seasons just to knock out their goals. But this also brings in <em>The Crush House</em>’s first layer of strategy: if I need to film softboi Milo making friends and enemies, I have to pick other cast members likely to form those relationships with him, like the sunny Charlie or the pretentious Gunther.&nbsp;</p><p>This cast makeup also matters for the audiences you have to satisfy to keep the show from getting cancelled. Every morning, you get a growing list of viewers with particular desires. Some are straightforward: Butt Guys want to see butts, and Plumbers want to see the house’s water fixtures. Voyeurs want to see the cast filmed from faraway, creepy angles, and Film Students want to see fancy shots. But other audiences can be harder to please, with unclear desires–what the hell do The Glitched or Nursing Home residents like?--or reliant on the cast doing things you may or may not be able to engineer. Divorced Dads want to see men bonding, so you’ll need male cast members likely to bond; Drama Queens want to see people fighting, so you’ll need cast members likely to clash.</p><p>Since you don’t know what audiences you’ll get when you’re picking a cast at the start of the season, this can be tough– once, I found myself needing to satisfy Girls for Girls fans when I had a cast full of boys. Luckily, fully satisfied audiences’ enthusiasm will leak over to other audiences, helping you make up the gaps. And you can also buy props, using money you get from ads Jae runs when she’s not filming, to make cast members more likely to engage in certain behaviors or to help satisfy audiences–Divorced Dads will be happy to look at the grill if you don’t have male cast members who are friends. But props can be expensive, and time spent running ads means time not filming, making each day a hectic balancing act.</p><p>Eventually, you’ll see all the audiences and know what they want, but the game felt the most fun to me when I’d get a brand-new audience and rush frantically around the house aiming my camera at everything to try to figure out what they wanted to see. There’s a thrill to staring down five audiences late into a season, with some wanting to see the garden, others wanting to see two characters fighting by the pool, and <em>others</em> wanting to see my cast full of enemies impossibly be friends. All this leaves me running back and forth, squeezing ads into the transition, hoping I make it to the end of the day.</p><p>At the same time, all this really boils down to just swinging your camera around until various icons appear on the screen, with the actual cast and their lives becoming secondary. I’m not sure if <em>The Crush House</em> wants you to be engaged in casts’ lives and desires, the way an actual reality TV audience is meant to, or if the game’s mechanics are meant to make you see them as just means to an end, number-go-up generators that keep the show going, the way the game’s deeper plot suggests. Most likely, it’s meant to be both–not so much to make a statement about reality TV as to situate you in that tension at its heart. I often felt like I had largely missed the actual relationships between people in a season, engaged in swinging between shots of the offshore lighthouse and a branded juice machine to give my audiences what they wanted while actual human drama went on out of frame.</p><p>I found the game more mechanically fun than I found it narratively engaging, but that’s not a bad thing. Each day felt stressful and exciting as I grew familiar with the best vantage points in the house or the perfect camera angle, squeezing in an ad or two to work toward a prop as I noticed drama stewing or romance about to ensue. Failure means starting a day over, and you can also set the difficulty so that the show is never cancelled, meaning the stakes are never high enough to make the game too frustrating if you’re unlucky with your audiences or cast. The core thing you do in the game is enjoyable, even if it’s not all that deep.</p><p>I’m enjoying the way <em>The Crush House</em> scratches a certain roguelike itch I have; I've seen other reviews liken it to a twist on a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/article/2024/aug/09/the-crush-house-review-love-island-with-a-dark-heart" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first-person shooter</a>, which is another fun way to look at it. Each day is a jumble of conflicting demands, a combination of repetition and randomness that I steadily master, selectively choosing from realities on offer while filming a lot of faucets and video game character butts along the way. </p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warzone Being Separated From Premium Call of Duty Games]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/warzone-being-separated-from-premium-call-of-duty-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warzone-being-separated-from-premium-call-of-duty-games.954999/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/warzone-being-separated-from-premium-call-of-duty-games/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In an attempt to reduce the download size of Call of Duty games, Warzone is being officially separated from premium <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-recieves-h2m-mod/">Call of Duty</a> games. The Activision developers are gearing up to make significant changes to the Call of Duty HQ launcher on PC so that those specifically interested in Warzone can only download files specifically for Warzone.</p>
<p>To allow this huge event to happen, they are slowly and carefully rolling out the new updates to the launcher. This is not only to ensure that things don't break along the way but also to reduce the install size of the other Call of Duty games by any amount. To ensure that the games are reduced in size, Activision will expand its stream tech and add more content to the streaming pool instead.</p>
<p>Doing this means that they will cycle the less frequently used content in the streaming cache and continue to expand what content can be streamed in general to lessen the load on the players. One part of this is the "On-Demand Texture Streaming" option, which will be changed to "On-Demand High Quality Streaming." While that may not sound too different from what it is now, there will be two options for players to utilize. One of the options will prioritize higher fidelity graphics that require more bandwidth, while the other forgoes graphical quality and uses less bandwidth.</p>
<p>By doing this mass revamp, they hope it will make other games on the launcher easier to access, with players only having to download specifically what they want to play. Unfortunately for some, players must download bigger files to pave the way for smaller download sizes. This is a lengthy process that Activision will be sinking a lot of time into.</p>
<p>PlayStation 5 users are most likely going to be the unhappiest of them all, as they will have to download four separate chunks in Season 5 Reloaded. This includes the initial system-level update and three more that are triggered by opening Modern Warfare 3 and Warzone. However, this is currently only necessary for current players who are playing now and continuing to keep up with the latest iterations of the franchise. Those completely new to the franchise won't have to deal with this.</p>
<p>Activision has<a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/08/call-of-duty-optimizing-experience-roadmap#:~:text=texture%20streaming%20tech-,Separating%20Call%20of%20Duty%3A%20Warzone%20from%20the%20default%20download%20for,for%20that%20game%20by%20default." target="_blank" rel="noopener"> posted its schedule for the big revamp</a> and is making way for Black Ops 6. Below is the schedule people can expect:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reorganizing game content, part of the Season 5 Reloaded update (August 21)</li>
<li>Black Ops 6 Open Beta (August 30)</li>
<li>New User Interface (Mid-October)</li>
<li>Black Ops 6 Launch (October 25)</li>
</ul>
<p>In addition, anyone who logs in after the Season 5 Reloaded update will get a package of Battle Pass Tier Skips and Double XP Tokens.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sims-Like InZoi Lets You Try Out Its Character Creator Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sims-like-inzoi-character-creator-tool</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sims-like-inzoi-lets-you-try-out-its-character-creator-next-week.954996/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sims-like-inzoi-character-creator-tool<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Krafton has announced that it's releasing a free&nbsp;<em>InZoi&nbsp;</em>character creator tool on Steam next week, allowing you to create your very own Zoi for the Early Access release (whenever that happens to be).</p>
<p>The tool will be released on Wednesday, August 21st, and will be available until August 26th, so you'll have five days to make your Zoi. Once the character is made, you'll then be able to use them in&nbsp;<em>InZoi&nbsp;</em>"post Early Access launch".</p>
<p>This is very much the full&nbsp;<em>InZoi&nbsp;</em>character creation tool; it'll come complete with "over 250 customization options", from hair, facial features, and complexion all the way to fingernails and more. As Krafton says, you're "limited only by [your] imagination".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inzoi-character-creator-example.jpg?itok=Ll5FAHTM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inzoi-character-creator-example.jpg?itok=wOGYtxc6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>InZoi</em>'s character creator will offer a very in-depth facility for making your Zoi.</figcaption></figure><p><em>InZoi&nbsp;</em>is also making use of generative AI; according to Krafton, AI will allow you to "create unlimited possibilities for patterns" for your Zoi's clothing. Weirdly,&nbsp;<em>InZoi</em>'s Steam page doesn't disclose its use of generative AI, which would, I think, technically be a contravention of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/group/4145017/view/3862463747997849618" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam's AI rules</a>.</p>
<p>Steam <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-changes-rules-on-ai-to-allow-vast-majority-of-games-that-use-it">does allow</a> games listed on its store to use AI, but said games are required to disclose its inclusion, whether the AI content is pre-generated or live-generated. We'll have to wait and see whether the&nbsp;<em>InZoi&nbsp;</em>character creator bears such a disclaimer when it arrives.</p>
<p>Once you've created your Zoi, you can then upload them to the built-in user-generated content platform Canvas, where other users can download them and leave a like if they think your Zoi is cool. You'd better make them the best Zoi they can be!</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inzoi-character-creator-example-2.jpg?itok=Pk15imTa 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inzoi-character-creator-example-2.jpg?itok=ijTh8YOP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You can share your&nbsp;<em>InZoi&nbsp;</em>character creations via the built-in UGC tool.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're wondering what exactly&nbsp;<em>InZoi&nbsp;</em>is, it's a&nbsp;<em>Sims</em>-style life sim currently in development over at&nbsp;<em>PUBG&nbsp;</em>publisher Krafton.</p>
<p>The game revolves around the lives of its characters, known as Zois, as they build relationships, get jobs, and generally live out their lives. Just like in&nbsp;<em>The Sims</em>, you'll be able to shape their stories, build their homes, and watch as they interact with one another.</p>
<p>Since the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/life-by-you-paradoxs-sims-competitor-has-been-cancelled">cancellation of Paradox's&nbsp;<em>Life by You</em></a> (and the subsequent <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paradox-profits-life-by-you-canceled">blow it dealt to the studio's finances</a>),&nbsp;<em>InZoi&nbsp;</em>is one of the only serious&nbsp;<em>Sims&nbsp;</em>competitors that remains in active development. We'll have to wait and see whether it manages to challenge EA for the life sim crown, though.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Goat Simulator 3 Gets ESRB Rating For Nintendo Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/goat-simulator-3-gets-esrb-rating-for-nintendo-switch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/goat-simulator-3-gets-esrb-rating-for-nintendo-switch.954990/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/goat-simulator-3-gets-esrb-rating-for-nintendo-switch/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>On the official <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40083/goat-simulator-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ESRB website</a>, Coffee Stain North’s Goat Simulator 3 now has a new rating for the Nintendo Switch platform. As expected, it earned a T rating for crude humor, language, and violence. </p>



<p>The rating confirms recent rumors about a Nintendo Switch version. A listing on Amazon Japan surfaced online for the new Switch version not long ago, though the site promptly took that page down.</p>



<p>Before Amazon Japan removed the listing, fans noticed a potential release date of November 7, 2024. However, neither developer Coffee Stain North nor Nintendo have confirmed a concrete release date. </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>An official Nintendo Switch release date announcement should arrive fairly soon now that Goat Simulator 3 has an ESRB rating.</p>



<p>Most recently, Coffee Stain North released Goat Simulator 3 – Multiverse of Nonsense DLC for the base game on June 19, 2024. The DLC earned ‘Very Positive’ reviews on Steam. It added 8 new playable goats, a brand-new map, over 100 new gears, and more.</p>



<p>In April 2024, Embracer Group announced plans to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/embracer-group-splitting-into-three-separate-companies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">split into three companies</a>, one of which is Coffee Stain &amp; Friends. That company will focus on a range of Premium and Free to Play PC, console, and mobile games.</p>



<p>Goat Simulator 3 first launched in 2022, and is available now on mobile, PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about Iron Galaxy co-CEO Adam Boyes announcing <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/iron-galaxys-co-ceo-announces-exit-after-8-years/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">plans to step down</a> after eight years of leadership, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Is Back On iPhone After 4 Years, Depending On Where You Live]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-is-back-on-iphone-after-4-years-depending-on-where-you-live/1100-6525849/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-back-on-iphone-after-4-years-depending-on-where-you-live.954987/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-is-back-on-iphone-after-4-years-depending-on-where-you-live/1100-6525849/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525849">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Epic Games Store has entered the mobile space. Starting today, Android and iOS users in Europe can download the Epic Games Store for mobile, through which they can access <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a>, Rocket League Sideswipe, and the brand-new mobile version of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fall-guys/" data-ref-id="5000-497671">Fall Guys</a>. This includes the first updated version of Fortnite for iOS in four years, just in time for the Marvel-centric <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-start-date-leaks-and-rumors/2900-5569/" data-ref-id="2900-5569">Absolute Doom</a>--it's poetic, since the last update for Fortnite iOS occurred just before the start of the previous Marvel season during Chapter 2.</p><p>Aside from the free rewards that we'll get to in a moment, the biggest item here is the arrival of the mobile version of Fall Guys--it's the same game, now on your phone. All your cosmetic items carry over, and Fall Guys has full cross-progression and cross-platform play between the mobile and console/PC versions.</p><p>Android users will be moving on from the old Epic Games Launcher, which simply allowed you to install and update Fortnite and Rocket League Sideswipe. The Epic Games Store for mobile is intended as an alternative app store, similar to the well-established Amazon Appstore for Android, so the idea is that it will also offer many games from other developers and publishers.</p><p>Installing the Epic Game Store on mobile will require you to sideload it, which any Android can do. For iOS users, only European phones will allow this for now, as a result of the European Union's Digital Markets Act. In the US, Epic's games, including Fortnite, will remain off of iOS devices for the foreseeable future due to the court battle between Epic and Apple which ruled, among other things, that Apple is free to keep the publisher's games off of its platform.</p><p>In other territories, such as the UK and Japan, rulings have yet to arrive in similar court battles, though speaking with Epic on Wednesday, the publisher told GameSpot it remains hopeful that similar decisions will win out in those places, too. For now though, today's significant changes only affect players in Europe.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4350957-epicgamesstoremobilerewards.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4350957" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4350957-epicgamesstoremobilerewards.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4350957"></a><figcaption>These are the free rewards available from the games on the mobile Epic Games Store.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4350957-epicgamesstoremobilerewards.jpg"></figure><p>Epic is incentivizing players to try out the new Epic Games Store for mobile by offering free unlocks across Fortnite, Fall Guys and Rocket League Sideswipe--there's even a free Fortnite skin involved.</p><p>You can unlock the Katalina skin and her various accessories--a back bling, a pickaxe, and a wrap--by gaining XP playing Fortnite on mobile. Fall Guys mobile is offering a holographic bean skin for use in Fall Guys, and a Yeetus Hammer pickaxe for Fortnite--just complete five levels, and the gifts are yours. And playing any amount of Rocket League Sideswipe will net you a gold-painted Diestro car for both Fortnite and regular Rocket League. You can earn any of these rewards until November 2.</p><p>Meanwhile, Fortnite's new season is now live. You can see <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/everything-new-in-fortnite-chapter-5-season-4/2900-5674/" data-ref-id="2900-5674">everything new in Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4</a>, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fortnite-new-weapons-in-chapter-5-season-4/2900-5681/" data-ref-id="2900-5681">new weapons</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fortnite-map-changes-in-chapter-5-season-4/2900-5680/" data-ref-id="2900-5680">map changes</a>, and the new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fortnite-battle-pass-chapter-5-season-4-all-skins-and-rewards/2900-5675/" data-ref-id="2900-5675">battle pass</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/112115755814061051052?rel=author">Phil Owen</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Patch Notes #1: Dispatches from AMAZE Sheffield]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/patch-notes-1-dispatches-from-amaze-sheffield</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/patch-notes-1-dispatches-from-amaze-sheffield.954981/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/patch-notes-1-dispatches-from-amaze-sheffield<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Game Developer / AMAZE</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Oh, would you look at that. Welcome to the first ever edition of Patch Notes! Newsletters are unequivocally </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>in </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">these days and instead of succumbing to crippling FOMO (that's 'fear of missing out'), we figured we'd join the party.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Patch Notes will be a casual hangout for the cool cats. A brooding, low-lit jazz bar filled with people who 'get it.' It's your favorite breakfast served in bed. A hallowed space for deep, pensive contemplation. Your dizziest daydream made corporeal. That one—alright, it's mainly just an excuse for news editor Chris Kerr (hello hello) to cut loose on a Friday and pore over the latest game industry happenings.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We'll be publishing a new edition of Patch Notes every two weeks to keep you in the know. Inside, you'll find a round-up of the hottest news and some headlines you might have missed; a fragrant platter of interviews and features that'll tickle your tastebuds; and a lovingly curated selection of blogs showcasing the brilliance of our expert community.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We reckon there'll be a little sumthin' sumthin' for everyone, so let's get stuck in.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Travel Man: I went to AMAZE Sheffield and all I got was this newfound sense of belonging">Travel Man: I went to AMAZE Sheffield and all I got was this newfound sense of belonging</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I joined a cult the other week. It all happened so fast. One moment I was wandering through a warehouse filled with bizarre contraptions in the outskirts of Sheffield. Then, I was surrounded by a group of people hellbent on mimicking the chants of a rhapsodic flamingo. The strange chorus of faces only illuminated by the streaks of pink neon that adorned the crumbling brick walls. Later, that same group would harness the power of touch to create a link between the mechanical world and our physical forms. This is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://2024.amaze-berlin.de/">AMAZE Festival</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It is magical.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The self-styled 'International Games and Playful Media Festival' usually takes place in Berlin over four days, but made its way to the UK for a one-day soiree featuring a bunch of experimental game installations, rapid 'Hyper Talks' touching on subjects like approachable design and generative AI (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/keyword/amaze-sheffield">read our coverage here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">), and a thumping warehouse rave that bled into the early hours.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The event is split across a daytime and evening program. The former is more serene, letting attendees browse installations at their leisure, attend workshops, and shoot the breeze with their peers. There was even a barbecue, although we're not quite sure if that's part of the standard offering (it absolutely should be).</span></p><p>Left to right: AMAZE attendees playing Crashboard, Between, and Hyper Wobbler</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The evening slalom is where AMAZE truly comes into its own. After a warm opening keynote from organizer Thorstenn Wiedmann and an icebreaker featuring that singing flamingo we mentioned earlier, we segue into an exhilarating Hyper Talk track that is ludicrous and brilliant in equal measure.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Speakers are introduced to screams of 'hyper, hyper' from a crowd who've been instructed to recite those hallowed words (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FFJIEK17b9M">all hail Scooter</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) whenever they burst on screen. Talks fluctuate between introspective and absurd. We quickly pivoted from a discussion about human touch as a game mechanic into a talk about iconic board game Dream Phone. There is wisdom in both. Then, the show floor opens up. What was previously a chilled space for chinwags becomes an electric hive of activity.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A huge group of attendees quickly breaks off to play a colossal game of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Bot Party</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, an interactive alt ctrl experience that asks players to help dinky robots communicate by interlocking their own limbs. I watch in quiet astonishment as people (many of whom I presumed were previously strangers) coalesce into a mammoth prayer circle to merge with their mechanical counterparts.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Wherever you look, you'll find more of the same. Friends and strangers holding hands and laughing as they breeze through experimental puzzler </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Between</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Amused onlookers encouraging those who've chosen to (quite literally) surf the world wide web in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Crashboard</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Laughter erupting from a crowd playing a completely unhinged twenty-player version of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Gang Beasts</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Every experience feels designed to spark chaos and camaraderie.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">AMAZE is so wonderfully fresh because it eschews conventional industry networking events, which too often prioritize those with a penchant for bars and alcohol (though, of course, you can grab a pint here if that's your thing). I often find those spaces cliquey and impenetrable. Here, in this warehouse full of tactile, offbeat game experiences, people are encouraged to approach each other and truly engage. Bonding over their shared pursuit of a high score or the fact they were sliding across the floor together, digits interlinked, mere seconds ago.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There's something deeply affirming about rocking up to an event where silliness is championed and unconventional ideas are celebrated. The industry could perhaps use a few more events like AMAZE, and after dipping my toes in the water a couple of weeks ago, I highly recommend everyone else do the same.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>P.S. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">AMAZE is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/AMazeFest/status/1821561139685163376">hosting a 'digital playground' event at Gamescom 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, so check it out if you're zipping to Cologne next week.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Status Report: The headlines that matter">Status Report: The headlines that matter</h2><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/krafton-acquires-tango-gameworks-and-hi-fi-rush-franchise-from-microsoft">Krafton acquires Tango Gameworks and Hi-Fi Rush franchise from Microsoft</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">The industry was ready to pour one out for Japanese studio Tango Gameworks after it was unceremoniously shuttered by Xbox despite being praised by its parent company for shadow-dropped success </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. This tale, however, had one last twist. Korean publisher Krafton (custodian of the PUBG franchise) swooped in to save the day after purchasing both Tango and the Hi-Fi Rush franchise from Microsoft. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/stephentotilo/status/1823815934458650940">According to Game File</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Krafton has structured the deal as an "acqui-hire" because it wants to "inherit the entire development team." It's a rare slice of positive news amid a relentless wave of layoffs and closures. We'll take it.&nbsp;</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/draknek-new-voices-puzzle-grant-is-offering-15-000-to-thinky-game-devs">Draknek New Voices Puzzle Grant is offering $15,000 to 'thinky' game devs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">If you're a puzzle game developer in search of funding, you might want to look into this grant from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Bonfire Peaks</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sokobond Express</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Draknek. The studio wants to dish out six no-strings-attached grants worth $15,000 to creators from underrepresented backgrounds. The company has a generous 'if in doubt, please apply' policy when it comes to submissions, so if you're on the fence where eligibility is concerned it's probably worth chancing your arm. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://grants.draknek.org/">You can find a robust FAQ here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The deadline for applications is October 7, 2024.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/foretold-studios-accused-of-failing-to-pay-wages-plunging-some-workers-into-debt">Foretold Studios failing to pay wages, plunging some workers into debt</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Here's a cautionary tale. We recently spoke with multiple developers at </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tollan Universe</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> maker Foretold Studios who claim the company owes them thousands of dollars in missed salary payments dating back to 2023. Outwardly, the studio appears in good health, with management attending major events like GDC 2024 and OTK Games Expo and recently announcing another entry in its Tollan franchise (despite struggling to bring a single project to market). CEO Michael Kuvshynov confirmed the studio has failed to pay some wages, but suggested he was transparent with employees from the outset. Our sources beg to differ. After our article was published, we pushed Kuvshynov for more information but have been met with radio silence. Curiously, the chief exec did agree to a Zoom interview prior to publication, but has now vanished into the aether.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Feature Creep: Originals and interviews for the discerning reader">Feature Creep: Originals and interviews for the discerning reader</h2><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/pc/what-the-heck-is-valve-doing-with-these-informal-deadlock-ndas-">What the heck is Valve doing with these informal Deadlock NDAs?</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer senior editor Bryant Francis looks at the chaos surrounding the surprise not-launch of Valve's in-development shooter </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Deadlock</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which has attracted over 20,000 concurrent users despite apparently being a super secret project and landed The Verge in hot water with some enraged souls for *checks notes* covering a video game project from a major company. Lock in for this one.&nbsp;</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-this-is-just-a-death-cycle-no-more-robots-gets-candid-about-the-state-of-indie-publishing">'This is just a death cycle': No More Robots gets candid about the state of indie publishing</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Sometimes it's important to vocalize hard truths. Just ask No More Robots founder Mike Rose, who last week told me the indie publishing industry is essentially "fucked." Assessing the state of the biz after seven years leading his own company, Rose explained why 'survive to 2025' is a dangerous fallacy, revealed what exactly publishers are after in the current market (projects that are "cheap as fuck or expensive as hell"), and outlined why pessimism and sustainability are good bedfellows.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/art/tossing-out-textures-to-build-a-visual-bridge-from-hyper-light-breaker-to-its-predecessor">Tossing out textures to build a visual bridge from Hyper Light Breaker to its predecessor</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">How do you turn a 2D indie darling into a 3D roguelike? That's the question </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hyper Light Breaker</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Heart Machine grappled with as it sought to create a sequel to acclaimed 2016 adventure </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hyper Light Drifter</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. You can hit the link above for a comprehensive answer, which explores notions like "lower-frequency" character design and intentional detail.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/book-excerpt-great-games-need-great-leaders">Book Excerpt: Great Games Need Great Leaders</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">In this snippet from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Great Games Need Great Leaders: Multiclassing to Lead Game Development Teams</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> by Matthew John Dyet, the author unites the "knowledge and perspectives of numerous past and present games industry leaders and practitioners to form a clear picture of how leadership operates in a game development studio."</span></p></div></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video Game Sales in July Are Up in Europe Despite No Major Releases]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/video-game-sales-in-july-are-up-in-europe-despite-no-major-releases/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-game-sales-in-july-are-up-in-europe-despite-no-major-releases.954975/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/video-game-sales-in-july-are-up-in-europe-despite-no-major-releases/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>As the title suggests, video game sales increased in July across Europe, which may seem quite bizarre. This month hasn't seen any major releases across any platform, but 2.4 million video games were sold in July, a <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/video-game-sales-up-in-europe-during-july-despite-a-lack-of-major-releases-european-monthly-charts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3.4% rise year-on-year</a>.</p>
<p>Considering the huge lack of major releases on any platform this July, it's impressive that video game sales have increased. Looking at the Top Ten for July, Luigi's Mansion 2 HD is the only game on the list released this year, with every other game being from last year, including top seller EA Sports FC 24.</p>
<p>While to some, the sudden rise of sales for EA Sports FC 24 may come as a shock, it's no surprise considering the European Championships took place in July. Because of this, EA Sports FC 24 sold 69% more copies this July than FIFA 23 did last year.</p>
<p>Looking further into the facts, July saw many gaming promotions that helped boost the sales of specific games. For example, Hitman Absolution, a game initially released in 2012, had a free game promotion on Amazon Prime, boosting the game significantly. Because of the promotion, Hitman Absolution was number eight on the list.</p>
<p>Games like Grand Theft Auto V remain on top, coming in second on the list, with Elden Ring sliding into third position. In the tenth position, It Takes Two is on the list, which is a surprise considering the game's release was in 2022.</p>
<p>Regarding new releases, EA Sports College Football 25 was highly successful in the UK but made it onto the European charts at number 39.</p>
<p>While game sales were up across Europe in July, the same cannot be said about console sales. 263,000 console units were sold across specific markets, <a href="https://wccftech.com/video-game-sales-in-the-uk-dropped-by-30-in-first-half-of-the-year/">excluding the UK</a> and Germany. Compared to last year, this is a massive 46% drop. For the month of July, PlayStation 5 took the lead in sales but still proceeded to see a drop of 56% since last year. Nintendo Switch is second on the list, and we also see a drop. However, the drop for Nintendo Switch is significantly smaller and comes in at 29% year-on-year.</p>
<p>In third place, the Xbox Series sold the least consoles this year but continued to experience a rather heavy deficit from the year before. Compared to last July, they had a decrease of 42% in all Xbox Series sales.</p>
<p>This month, there was no major news about new consoles or new major launches. People are still waiting restlessly for the Nintendo Switch 2, but it doesn't seem to be coming for a while.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact Version 5.0 Release Date Announced for Late August]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-50-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-version-5-0-release-date-announced-for-late-august.954972/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-50-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HoYoverse has announced the&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>Version 5.0 release date, and it's bringing a brand new nation, three new characters, and much more later this month.</p>
<p>Version 5.0, also known as "Flowers Resplendent on the Sun-Scorched Sojourn", launches on August 28th, and its main new addition to the free-to-play gacha RPG is the nation of Natlan, whose warriors will become your allies.</p>
<p>All you need to do in order to visit Natlan is to complete the Prologue of Mondstadt's Archon Quest. Once you've done this, a Teleport Waypoint will become available, even for "beginners and intermediates", per HoYoverse.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/genshin-impact-version-5.0-release-date-yumkasaurus.jpg?itok=F-5ieSyC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/genshin-impact-version-5.0-release-date-yumkasaurus.jpg?itok=-oNdn0HY 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>Version 5.0 has some adorable little critters for you to meet.</figcaption></figure><p>In the nation of Natlan, you'll encounter six tribes, although only three of them will be available in this first update: the Children of Echoes, the Scions of the Canopy, and the People of the Springs.</p>
<p>Each of them has a beast companion you'll also meet, and you'll be able to transform into said beast companions as well, making traversal across Natlan easier.</p>
<p>Of course, you can also look forward to new fighters for your team in&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>Version 5.0. This time around, three new characters are making their debut, two of whom are five-star characters and all of whom reflect the cultures of the tribes from which they hail.</p>
<p>The first five-star character is Kinich, a Dendro claymore user who can use a grappling hook. You'll also be able to recruit Mualani, a catalyst-wielding Hydro character who's got her very own signature surfboard. They're joined by four-star Geo polearm user Kachina.</p>

<p>In the first phase of Version 5.0, Event Wishes for Mualani and Kachina will run, alongside a rerun for Kaedehara Kazuha. The second phase of the update will see Kinich making his debut, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/genshin-impact-raiden-shogun-baal-build-guide">Raiden Shogun</a> will get a rerun during this phase as well.</p>
<p>As ever, several codes giving you the chance to nab some free stuff have also arrived alongside this update's reveal, and here they are.</p>
<ul><li>2SMTYV59TLFD - 100 Primogems, 10 Mystic Enhancement Ore</li>
<li>7SMTGV59BLXH - 100 Primogems, 5 Hero's Wit</li>
<li>8T4TGDLRA5E5 - 100 Primogems, 50,000 Mora</li>
</ul><p><em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>Version 5.0 arrives across all platforms on August 28th. You can <a href="https://genshin.hoyoverse.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">download and play the game for free right now</a> on PC, PlayStation, and mobile devices. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iron Galaxy’s Co-CEO Announces Exit After 8 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/iron-galaxys-co-ceo-announces-exit-after-8-years/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/iron-galaxy%E2%80%99s-co-ceo-announces-exit-after-8-years.954966/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/iron-galaxys-co-ceo-announces-exit-after-8-years/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-53203">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>In a new <a href="https://www.irongalaxystudios.com/blog-posts/my-next-adventure" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blog post</a>, Adam Boyes announced that they are stepping down as co-CEO of developer Iron Galaxy, with Chelsea Blasko continuing as the sole CEO.</p>



<p>Boyes thanked Iron Galaxy and its team and explained that they will “remain on as a member of this team until the end of the year.” </p>



<p>They also mentioned their plans moving forward, emphasizing the current state of the gaming industry. Boyes stated that “my new inspirations are to find ways to help people who make games solve their biggest problems.” </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Iron Galaxy’s co-CEO Boyes closed the new blog by reassuring readers that “you haven’t heard the last from me, and neither has IG.” They did not confirm their exact plans nor when fans should expect another update, but they will “talk about that later.”</p>



<p>Iron Galaxy is a developer that works on both original ideas and collaborative projects, and sometimes provide support as consultants. Some of their original titles include Extinction and the short-lived battle royale brawler Rumbleverse. </p>



<p>Fans may recognize Iron Galaxy for their collaborations on games like Uncharted Legacy of Thieves or Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy. The developer worked on bringing those iconic games to PC.</p>



<p>The Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-reveals-crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-more-coming-to-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">joined the Xbox Game Pass</a> this month, and Uncharted continues to thrive, building even more fans with another <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-uncharted-movie-confirms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">live-action movie under way</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about Sad Cat Studios revealing a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sad-cat-studios-reveals-13-minutes-of-replaced-in-new-gameplay-overview-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">13-minute gameplay overview</a> for Replaced shortly after delaying the game, and sign up for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-returns-for-ios-devices-in-eu-and-android-devices-globally/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-returns-for-ios-devices-in-eu-and-android-devices-globally/">Fortnite Returns for iOS Devices in EU and Android Devices Globally&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fortnite has been re-released on iOS devices in the European Union and Android devices worldwide. Here’s how to download it.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-is-live-heres-everything-new/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-is-live-heres-everything-new/">Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4 is Live: Here’s Everything New</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fortnite’s Chapter 5 Season 4 is now live. Here’s everything new, including POIs, weapons, skins and more. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/north-beach-stranded-deep-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/north-beach-stranded-deep-2/">North Beach To Develop Stranded Deep 2 in New Prague Studio</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Stranded Deep 2 is about to enter development at North Beach Games’ new Prague office. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/get-free-tokens-in-asphalt-8/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/get-free-tokens-in-asphalt-8/">How to Get Free Tokens in Asphalt 8 (2024 Guide)</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Are you playing this legendary racing game and trying to learn how to get free Tokens in Asphalt 8? Look no further than this guide.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvelous USA and XSEED Games announce PAX West 2024 lineup]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/marvelous-usa-and-xseed-games-announce-pax-west-2024-lineup</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvelous-usa-and-xseed-games-announce-pax-west-2024-lineup.954960/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/marvelous-usa-and-xseed-games-announce-pax-west-2024-lineup<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>'Additional exciting announcements' to come.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > XSEED Games [487 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/marvelous/xseed-games">Marvelous USA</a> and XSEED Games have jointly announced their games lineup for PAX West 2024, which will run from August 30 to September 2 at Seattle Convention Center in Seattle, Washington. <span id="more-906320"></span></p><p>Along with the announced titles, the publishers said it is planning “additional announcements that will bring even more excitement to their showcase.”</p><p>Of the announced titles, all are playable except&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Farmagia [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/farmagia">Farmagia</a></em>, which will exhibit the show with an experiential photo experience, complete with cosplayers, that aims to immerse visitors in the land of Felicidad. Attendees will also be able to win a variety of prizes, with information on how to participate and rewards available at the Marvelous USA / XSEED Games booth.</p><p>The lineup is as follows:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Marvelous USA</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Death the Guitar" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/death-the-guitar">Death the Guitar</a></em></strong> (<a title="Platforms > PC [20,921 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, Other Platforms TBA) (2025) – Play as a killer electric guitar whose owner was murdered in this violent 2D <a title="Genres > Platformer [510 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,084 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a>. Manipulate sound and electricity to exact revenge on humans, utilizing terrain and mobility to dispatch enemies before they know what hit them. There are only three controls in the game—move, jump, and GUITAR. <a title="Companies > Toroya My Battery is Fried" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/toroya-my-battery-is-fried">Toroya My Battery is Fried</a> is a graduate of <a title="Companies > Marvelous [1,317 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/marvelous">Marvelous</a>‘ iGi (Indie Game Incubator) program.</li><li><strong><em>Farmagia</em></strong> (<a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,680 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,791 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, PC) (November 1, 2024) – Featuring character and monster designs from iconic manga artist Hiro Mashima, <em>Farmagia</em> is a brand-new monster-farming and action game. Take the role of Ten and his fellow Farmagia friends, cultivating and commanding an army of home-grown monsters as they explore Felicidad’s treacherous lands, searching for valuable resources to improve their farm. Can these small-town heroes overthrow Glaza and free Felicidad from his despotic rule?</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>XSEED Games</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > The Big Catch [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-big-catch">The Big Catch</a></em></strong> (PC) (2025) – <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,668 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a> through a desert world as Caster, running errands to collect ingredients for his enigmatic employer Chef Leurre and discovering long-lost secrets along the way. Inspired by the creative 3D platformers of the 5th and 6th console generation, players will navigate a wasteland using fast, acrobatic movements to flip, swim, spin, and fight their way forward. A fisherman by trade, Caster’s rod doubles as both a weapon to defend himself and a powerful tool to overcome platforming obstacles in his search for the one thing that still has value in the wasteland: FISH.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Corpse Party II: Darkness Distortion [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/corpse-party-ii-darkness-distortion">Corpse Party II: Darkness Distortion</a></em></strong> (<a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,055 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a>, Switch, PC) (Fall 2024) – The cult-classic Japanese <a title="Genres > Horror [457 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> franchise returns with new characters, a new setting, and a terrifying new curse presented in full 3D! Will high school friends Haruka, Nemu, and Maria survive their “stay” in the Amare Est Vivere Hospital, or will they meet an unfortunate end at the hand of “Ayame’s Mercy”?</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Moonlight Peaks [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/moonlight-peaks">Moonlight Peaks</a></em></strong> (PC) (2026) – <em>Moonlight Peaks</em> takes place in its titular town, home to vampires, werewolves, mermaids, and other supernatural denizens who mostly come out at night—where the unnatural is the norm. As the grown-up progeny of Count Dracula, players will have to prove to their skeptical father that an (un-)life of compassion is possible, even for the undead. While players design their perfect vampire lair and learn the art of farming magical crops and witchcraft, they’ll get to know the eclectic mix of human and supernatural residents that also call Moonlight Peaks home, and maybe even find their eternal love!</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Potionomics: Masterwork Edition [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/potionomics-masterwork-edition">Potionomics: Masterwork Edition</a></em></strong> (PS5, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,847 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, Switch) (2026) – The art of <a title="Games > Potionomics [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/potionomics">Potionomics</a> begins with perfecting your potion-brewing craft and building your deck of haggling cards to help you make the most of each sale. In order to succeed in Rafta’s lively economy you’ll need to get to know the colorful residents who will help you collect recipes, elite ingredients, and even special cards for your deck. Whether it’s your first day on the job or you’re a sorcerer’s salesman, the magic of capitalism has never been more alive than in <em>Potionomics: Masterwork Edition</em>.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Slitterhead [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/slitterhead">Slitterhead</a></em></strong> (PS5) (November 8, 2024) – From the mind of legendary creator Keiichiro Toyama comes his latest spine-tingling action-horror title. Explore the densely cluttered streets of Kowlong as the formless entity known as the Hyoki, taking control of unsuspecting civilians to battle the monsters masquerading as humans, known as Slitterheads. Expose the Slitterheads’ true forms and defeat them using the blood of the bodies Hyoki inhabits as a weapon, all while investigating the mystery behind their appearance in Kowlong.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Ys Memoire: The Oath in Felghana [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ys-memoire-the-oath-in-felghana">Ys Memoire: The Oath in Felghana</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4, Switch) (Fall 2024) – A classic action-<a title="Genres > RPG [16,506 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> returns with remastered visuals and music, new character illustrations, and new voice acting for protagonist Adol. Adol and his companion Dogi return to Dogi’s homeland of Felghana to discover it in chaos, with monsters roaming the countryside and a greedy overlord extorting the residents. The two find themselves embroiled in a world of conspiracies and ancient legacies, taking them on an epic journey.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas VR "Indefinitely Delayed," Meta Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-san-andreas-vr-indefinitely-delayed-meta-says/1100-6525860/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-san-andreas-vr-indefinitely-delayed-meta-says.954957/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-san-andreas-vr-indefinitely-delayed-meta-says/1100-6525860/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525860">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>For nearly three years, gamers have awaited any word about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-san-andreas-is-coming-to-vr-via-oculus-quest-2/1100-6497503/" data-ref-id="1100-6497503">Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas VR</a>. It was originally announced in 2021 as a title for the Meta Quest 2. But as Meta moved on to the Meta Quest 3, further updates about the game were scarce. Now, Meta has said that GTA: San Andreas VR is "indefinitely delayed."</p><p>In response to a comment on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tAmNSjF9Big&amp;lc=UgwielXvTo--EHoQY7x4AaABAg.A77ZzS0z8DOA7A-RrmuyA-" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its official YouTube channel</a>, a Meta Quest VR representative stated that "GTA: San Andreas is on hold indefinitely while we both focus on other projects. We look forward to working with our friends at Rockstar in the future." Meta confirmed the news to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-san-andreas-vr-delayed-indefinitely-as-meta-focuses-on-other-projects" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN</a> shortly thereafter.</p><p>There are some questions about how far along the project was, since Meta never shared any screenshots or video of Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas VR. Rockstar's original version of the game was ambitious even when it was released in 2004. San Andreas had a much larger open world than either Grand Theft Auto III or Grand Theft Auto: Vice City, as well as an enthralling story.</p><p>Thanks to the game's enduring popularity, San Andreas was included alongside GTA III and Vice City on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-definitive-edition-review-wasted/1900-6417791/" data-ref-id="1900-6417791">Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy – The Definitive Edition</a>. That remastered compilation was released in 2021 for all of the modern consoles and PC. If Meta's GTA: San Andreas VR port remains on indefinite hold, then The Definitive Edition may be the only way to revisit the title going forward.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Randy Orton Has Put Over 600 Hours Into Elden Ring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/randy-orton-has-put-over-600-hours-into-elden-ring/1100-6525857/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/randy-orton-has-put-over-600-hours-into-elden-ring.954951/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/randy-orton-has-put-over-600-hours-into-elden-ring/1100-6525857/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525857">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Between May 2022 and November 2023, WWE wrestler <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wwe-star-randy-orton-auditioned-for-major-deadpool-2-role/1100-6525847/" data-ref-id="1100-6525847">Randy Orton</a> was forced to take a lengthy injury hiatus. And apparently, Orton spent much of that time playing From Software's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/elden-ring-review-death-of-the-wild/1900-6417832/" data-ref-id="1900-6417832">Elden Ring</a> and exploring the Lands Between. Orton may be back in action now, but he's logged 600 hours in Elden Ring since he first started playing.</p><p>Via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/wwe-superstar-randy-orton-says-hes-put-600-hours-into-elden-ring/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">VGC</a>, Orton revealed his devotion to Elden Ring during Undisputed WWE Champion Cody Rhodes' What Do You Wanna Talk About video series. Orton recalled teasing Rhodes for being a gamer, but now he's become even more of a gamer than Rhodes.</p><p>"I f***ing love Elden Ring," said Orton. "Let me preface this next statement with saying that I was out with spinal fusion surgery, so I had a lot of time on my hands. I got, like, 600 hours on the game... I love that game. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shadow-of-the-erdtree-renews-the-awe-and-adventure-of-elden-ring/1100-6523901/" data-ref-id="1100-6523901">DLC just came out</a>."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VqgcnX9MvNY" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VqgcnX9MvNY" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Since becoming the face of WWE, Rhodes doesn't have the same free time he used to. That's one of the reasons why he hasn't played Elden Ring yet. But Orton would still like to share that experience with his friend.</p><p>"You're killing it and you don't got the time, and I understand why," said Orton. "I would love to chop it up about some Elden Ring with you, trust me. I wish you were a fellow Tarnished, but you're not."</p><p>Orton recently signed a new five-year deal with WWE, which would presumably allow him to buy <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-elden-ring-book-is-going-to-cost-you-a-fortune/1100-6524860/" data-ref-id="1100-6524860">this upcoming Elden Ring book</a> that is extremely expensive. Even if he doesn't, it sounds like he intends to keep playing the game for a long time to come.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds weapon trailer – ‘Bow’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/monster-hunter-wilds-weapon-trailer-bow</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-weapon-trailer-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98bow%E2%80%99.954930/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/monster-hunter-wilds-weapon-trailer-bow<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Seek and destroy.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Capcom [2,517 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a> has released a new weapon trailer for <em><a title="Games > Monster Hunter Wilds [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a></em> introducing the Bow. <span id="more-906358"></span></p><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,680 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,847 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,921 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> in 2025.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Weapon Overview: Bow</span></h2><p>“Seek and destroy with the Bow in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>! Hit a monster with a Tracer and your arrows will home in on the target. With Focus Strike, blot out the sun by firing a volley of multiple arrows into the monster’s weak points.”</p><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="Monster Hunter Wilds: Bow | Weapon Overview" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6D0x3KLl8jA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『モンスターハンターワイルズ』武器紹介動画：弓" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Kx7l_28b_3s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls: Castles mobile game launches next month, pre-registration now open]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-castles-mobile-game-launches-next-month-pre-registration-now-open</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-elder-scrolls-castles-mobile-game-launches-next-month-pre-registration-now-open.954927/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-castles-mobile-game-launches-next-month-pre-registration-now-open<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>The Elder Scrolls mobile game, The Elder Scrolls: Castles, is set to launch on 10th September.</p>
<p>The Elder Scrolls: Castles - which was quietly released into <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elder-scrolls-just-got-a-fallout-shelter-style-mobile-game-on-google-play">early access</a> in September 2023 - is now open for pre-registration on both <a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/the-elder-scrolls-castles/id1594657136">Apple</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bethsoft.stronghold&amp;hl=en_US">Android</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Elder Scrolls: Castles - Developer Deep Dive" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZSFLKHTwDPY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Elder Scrolls: Castles - Developer Deep Dive</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZSFLKHTwDPY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZSFLKHTwDPY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Elder Scrolls: Castles - Developer Deep Dive.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZSFLKHTwDPY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>From the same "award-winning team" behind Fallout Shelter, The Elder Scrolls: Castles lets you reign supreme over your very own castle and dynasty within The Elder Scrolls universe.</p>
<p>"Oversee your subjects and make rulings as the years come and go, families grow, and new rulers take the throne," the team teases.</p>
<p>In related news, Bethesda boss <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/todd-howard">Todd Howard</a> recently confirmed there's no Elder Scrolls TV adaptation in the works.</p>
<p>Despite Amazon's Fallout adaptation getting a very positive reception, it doesn't seem likely that other Bethesda properties will be getting the same treatment. During the Fallout premiere in Los Angeles, Howard was asked if fans could expect TV adaptations from other Bethesda franchises, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/despite-fallout-tv-success-an-elder-scrolls-series-seems-unlikely">such as Elder Scrolls</a>.</p>
<p>"There's nothing in the works," Howard said at the time, before adding: "Everybody asks, like, about Elder Scrolls, and I keep saying no also. And I would approach those - I'll probably say no."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints: Friday, August 16]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nyt-connections-hints-and-answers-august-16-1851623869</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nyt-connections-hints-friday-august-16.954918/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/nyt-connections-hints-and-answers-august-16-1851623869<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Happy Friday! Time to wake up your gray matter to get your weekend rolling. Going to see <em>Alien: Romulus</em>? If you haven’t checked out <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/alien-movies-ranked-aliens-prometheus-predator-avp-1851621200&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/alien-movies-ranked-aliens-prometheus-predator-avp-1851621200">the previous <em>Alien</em> movies</a></span>, you might not have the stomach for that. But let’s start with your brain.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Your daily sweet 16 words are back and ready for your best grouping efforts. The popular <em>Connections</em> brainbuster from <em>The New York Times</em> has four groups of words with a shared theme or commonality, but they’re shuffled into random order for you to figure out. Remember to take your time — many words have multiple meanings, so think twice before you click.</p><p>Today’s words: <strong>OK, COWBOY, ANKLE, SUN, HI, TIDE, YO-YO, MA, FAIR GO-GO, AVERAGE, ELEVATOR, PA, SO-SO, OR, </strong>and <strong>THIGH-HIGH</strong></p><h2 id="h92039"><a id=""></a>Today’s NYT Connections Hints</h2><p>The rules are simple: Yellow group is the easiest, purple group is the hardest (and usually contains the most obscure wordplay), blue and green are somewhere in between. Pick four words at a time — four wrong guesses and you lose.</p><p>Without tipping our hand too much, here are your hints:</p><p><strong>YELLOW: </strong>Not terrific</p><p><strong>GREEN: </strong>Map quest</p><p><strong>BLUE: </strong>Made for walkin’</p><p><strong>PURPLE: </strong>Comes and goes</p><h2 id="h92040"><a id=""></a>Today’s NYT Connections Groups</h2><div><p>Still stumped? Now we’re in spoiler territory. Each group’s theme has a name. Here are today’s:</p><p><strong>YELLOW: </strong>Meh</p></div><p><strong>GREEN: </strong>US State Abbreviations</p><p><strong>BLUE: </strong>Kinds of Boots</p><p><strong>PURPLE: </strong>Things That Go Up and Down</p><h2 id="h92041"><a id=""></a>Today’s NYT Connections Answers</h2><p>Struck out? Don’t feel bad – the <em>Times</em> loves to throw some serious curveballs, and you probably tried it before you had your morning coffee. We’ll give you the big reveal here, and better luck next time! Or if you got it, congratulations!</p><p><strong>YELLOW: </strong>AVERAGE, FAIR, OK, SO-SO</p><p><strong>GREEN: </strong>HI, MA, OR, PA</p><p><strong>BLUE: </strong>ANKLE, COWBOY, GO-GO, THIGH-HIGH</p><p><strong>PURPLE: </strong>ELEVATOR, SUN, TIDE, YO-YO</p><p>Come back Monday before you dive into your daily dose of <em>Connections</em>!</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Returns for iOS Devices in EU and Android Devices Globally]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-returns-for-ios-devices-in-eu-and-android-devices-globally/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-returns-for-ios-devices-in-eu-and-android-devices-globally.954915/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-returns-for-ios-devices-in-eu-and-android-devices-globally/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-53193">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Epic Games announced today that Fortnite will be playable on iOS devices in the European Union and Android devices worldwide. Read more to learn how to download Fortnite on iOS, launch bonuses, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-how-to-install-fortnite-on-ios-devices">How to Install Fortnite on iOS Devices?</h2>



<ul>
<li>To download Fortnite on iOS devices, players should first pass Apple’s region check for European Union customers.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Ensure your device runs iOS 17.4 or higher and use Safari or Brave browser.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Then, visit the Epic Games Store <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/download/android?p=fortnite" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">website</a> and click the “Get it on iPhone” button.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Players will then receive a pop-up on their iOS device that will prevent them from allowing marketplaces by Epic Games. At that time, you need to press OK and head to the Settings app. There, players will find a banner under their iCloud profile that says, “Allow Marketplace From Epic Games.” Click on this banner and then press ‘Allow.’</li>



<li>Then, return to the browser and click ‘install’. You will receive another pop-up where you must select ‘Install App Marketplace’.&nbsp;</li>



<li>You will then have Epic Games Store installed on your iOS device. Launch the app from the homepage, sign in with your Epic Games Store ID and install the games you want to play. You can download Fortnite and other Epic titles, including Rocket League, Fall Guys, and more.&nbsp;</li>



<li>After that, launch the game, and you will be ready to play Fortnite on your iPhone again. Moreover, you can try all the modes, including Creator Made Islands, LEGO Fortnite, Rocket Racing, Fortnite Festival, and Battle Royale.</li>
</ul>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Learn How to Install the Epic Games Store on iOS in the EU" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_6cmu0NuM3g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-launch-bonuses">Launch Bonuses</h2>



<p>Fortnite is offering exclusive outfits and other cosmetics through quests to celebrate the return to iOS and Android devices. Till v.32.00 in November, Fortnite players on iOS and Android devices can unlock the Katalina Outfit, along with Tactical Kat Wrap, Kat Claws Pickaxe and Katalina’’s Kit Bag Back Bling. These rewards are exclusive to the Fortnite mobile app on Android and iOS in the European Union.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-is-live-heres-everything-new/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here’s everything new</a> in Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4. Also, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-snoop-dogg-this-november-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Snoop Dogg</a> is rumoured to collaborate with the battle royale title this November. What are your thoughts on Fortnite returning to iOS and Android devices?&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/north-beach-stranded-deep-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">North Beach Games opening a new studio in Prague to develop Stranded Deep 2</a>&nbsp;and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming&nbsp;newsletter</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-is-live-heres-everything-new/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-is-live-heres-everything-new/">Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4 is Live: Here’s Everything New</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fortnite’s Chapter 5 Season 4 is now live. Here’s everything new, including POIs, weapons, skins and more. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/north-beach-stranded-deep-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/north-beach-stranded-deep-2/">North Beach To Develop Stranded Deep 2 in New Prague Studio</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Stranded Deep 2 is about to enter development at North Beach Games’ new Prague office. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/get-free-tokens-in-asphalt-8/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/get-free-tokens-in-asphalt-8/">How to Get Free Tokens in Asphalt 8 (2024 Guide)</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Are you playing this legendary racing game and trying to learn how to get free Tokens in Asphalt 8? Look no further than this guide.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/delta-force-pay-to-win-elements-no/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/delta-force-pay-to-win-elements-no/">Delta Force Pay-to-Win Elements Will ‘Absolutely Not’ Be a Thing</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Team Jade has spoken about pay-to-win elements in Delta Force: Hawk Ops, stressing that they absolutely won’t be a thing.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Games Store Launches on Mobile; Fortnite Once Again Available on iOS in Europe After $1 Billion Fight]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/epic-games-store-launches-on-mobile-fortnite-once-again-available-on-ios-in-europe-after-1-billion-fight/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-games-store-launches-on-mobile-fortnite-once-again-available-on-ios-in-europe-after-1-billion-fight.954903/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/epic-games-store-launches-on-mobile-fortnite-once-again-available-on-ios-in-europe-after-1-billion-fight/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Epic Games Store has finally <a href="http://epic.download/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched</a> on mobile platforms. Users will find it worldwide on Android and in Europe on iOS, allowing Fortnite to again be available to play on Apple's ecosystem. The date is no coincidence, as today marks the launch of Fortnite Battle Royale Chapter 5 Season 4: Absolute Doom, which is centered on Marvel heroes with Doctor Doom as the main villain.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://wccftech.com/apple-to-bring-app-store-changes-thanks-to-digital-markets-act/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Markets Act</a> allowed the European launch, but Apple still blocks Fortnite and the Epic Games Store elsewhere. Tim Sweeney, CEO and Founder of Epic Games, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>The tide is turning, and the mobile ecosystem is finally opening up to competition. We are grateful to the European Commission for making it possible to launch the Epic Games Store and offer our games to iOS users in the European Union. Now European iOS users and all Android users can access our store and games, as they've always been able to do on open platforms like PC and Mac. The fight is far from over, but this is tangible progress for developers and consumers who can begin to benefit from competition and choice.</em></p>
<p><a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/epic-apple-google-fortnite-eu-tim-sweeney?utm_source=post-email-title&amp;publication_id=66124&amp;post_id=147768702" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Speaking</a> to Game File, Sweeney said that the fight against Apple and Google cost Epic around $1 billion, but added that it was a 'small' price to pay for the freedom of the company and anyone else interested in a free market.</p>
<p>Epic warned users that the process of installing the Epic Games Store on both Android and iOS is currently pretty convoluted. However, they prepared tutorial videos for each platform.</p>
<p><iframe title="Learn How to Install the Epic Games Store on iOS in the EU" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_6cmu0NuM3g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><iframe title="Learn How to Install the Epic Games Store on Android" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4C4RxVF-unI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Epic Games Store on mobile includes not only Fortnite but also Rocket League: Sideswipe and the brand new Fall Guys for mobile. There's a promotional offer valid until November 2 that rewards gamers who install and play the games on the new store and then complete in-game challenges to unlock a few outfits.</p>
<p>Moreover, Epic is partnering with third party mobile app stores to bring its games to every marketplace. This begins today with the launch of Epic's games on AltStore PAL for iOS users in the European Union. Epic also plans to bring the games to Aptoide's iOS store in the EU and the ONE store on Android.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars: Eclipse From Quantic Dream Loses Lead Writer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-eclipse-from-quantic-dream-loses-lead-writer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-eclipse-from-quantic-dream-loses-lead-writer.954897/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-eclipse-from-quantic-dream-loses-lead-writer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The long dormant Star Wars: Eclipse has lost its lead writer at Heavy Rain and Detroit: Become Human developer Quantic Dream.</p><p>Adam Williams announced on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7229820335083163649/?updateEntityUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afs_updateV2%3A%28urn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7229820335083163649%2CFEED_DETAIL%2CEMPTY%2CDEFAULT%2Cfalse%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a> he was leaving the studio to form one of his own after nearly ten years. Williams was the lead writer on Detroit: Become Human before taking on the same role with Star Wars: Eclipse.</p><p>"After almost 10 years at Quantic Dream, I am leaving to found a new studio, together with a group of very talented designers and developers," Williams said.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>"We can’t say too much just yet. We are working on something very innovative, very special and, for now, very secret. More on that soon. I’ve already been in touch with many of you guys at Quantic Dream and Lucasfilm, to thank you for everything on Detroit and Eclipse. It’s been a great adventure."</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-high-republic-star-wars-quantic-dream">Quantic Dream announced Star Wars: Eclipse in 2021</a> as narrative-heavy action adventure game taking place in the galaxy far, far away. It was still in early development at the time despite being revealed alongside a cinematic trailer, but Quantic Dream hasn't released any significant update since.</p><p>Vice president of marketing <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-eclipse-still-alive-quantic-dream-insists-its-simmering">Lisa Pendse told IGN in September 2023 that it "still exists,"</a> however. "Can I say it still exists? Because it exists," she said. "It's just not ready. It's simmering."</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tango Gameworks acquisition will transfer around 50 out of original 100 staff]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/tango-gameworks-acquisition-will-transfer-around-50-out-of-original-100-staff</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tango-gameworks-acquisition-will-transfer-around-50-out-of-original-100-staff.954891/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/tango-gameworks-acquisition-will-transfer-around-50-out-of-original-100-staff<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Job openings at the studio.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HiFi-Rush-Chai.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Tango Gameworks</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Following the news Krafton was saving Hi-Fi Rush developer Tango Gameworks from being shut down for good, the PUBG publisher has confirmed its plans to "transfer approximately 50 development staff" from the studio to its Japan subsidiary.</p>
<p>This is roughly half the number of the studio's initial development staff, which was over 100. <a href="https://gameranx.com/updates/id/505790/article/half-of-tango-gameworks-is-joining-krafton-because-the-other-half-already-found-new-jobs/">Gameranx</a> reports this is because others have since found employment elsewhere, and as such there are a number of <a href="https://tangogameworks.com/recruitment/animator.html?l=en">job openings</a> at the studio.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Is the closure of Hi-Fi Rush and Redfall's studios a sign Xbox Game Pass publishing is failing?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Dx4fu4H6us" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In an update on social media platform X by Game File's Stephen Totilo, the reporter shared a statement from Krafton's PR, which said those 50 staff who are part of the transfer will "continue to work on new projects, including the expansion of the Hi-Fi Rush IP, at Krafton".</p>
<p>In a separate email shared earlier this week, Totilo said the deal to purchase the Tokyo-based team had been in effect since 1st August, despite it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tango-gameworks-and-hi-fi-rush-acquired-by-pubgs-krafton-following-microsofts-studio-closure-in-may">only becoming public knowledge on Monday</a>.</p>
<p>Krafton's chief financial officer Dongkeun Bae called the deal an "acqui-hire" - a portmanteau of 'acquisition' and 'hiring' - during an earnings call held this week.</p>
<p>As shared within Totilo's newsletter, Bae said Krafton "wanted to inherit the entire development team", and a more traditional acquisition wasn't possible because <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-shuts-slew-of-bethesda-studios-including-redfall-hi-fi-rush-developers">Tango Gameworks had been closed down by Microsoft</a>.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Also from their PR: "KRAFTON plans to transfer approximately 50 development staff from Tango Gameworks to KRAFTON's Japan subsidiary. These transferred staff will continue to work on new projects, including the expansion of the HI-FI RUSH IP, at KRAFTON."</p>— Stephen Totilo (@stephentotilo) <a href="https://twitter.com/stephentotilo/status/1824108474868908472?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 15, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Tango Gameworks, which is also known for the likes of the Evil Within series, was founded by Shinji Mikami in 2010. In 2012, Bethesda parent company <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/resi-evil-creator-mikami-joins-zenimax">ZeniMax Media purchased Tango</a>, before it was then itself <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-buying-zenimax-parent-company-of-bethesda-id-software-and-more-report">acquired by Microsoft</a> years later.</p>
<p>Under Microsoft, Tango surprise launched Hi-Fi Rush last year to wide acclaim. Our Ed called it both "vibrant and self-assured" in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hi-fi-rush-review-an-unrepentant-riot-of-rhythm-action">Eurogamer's own Hi-Fi Rush review</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 May Release in the First Half of 2025 for $499]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-release-499/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-may-release-in-the-first-half-of-2025-for-499.954885/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-release-499/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 may not be released during the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-miss-early-2025-launch/">current fiscal year ending in March 2025</a>, but it may still launch in the first half of the year, according to a new report.</p>
<p>Tokyo Security analyst Hideki Yasuda said in a <a href="https://kabutan.jp/news/marketnews/?b=n202408150860" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new report</a> that the console should be released in the first half of the year for $499. As such, if the console won't indeed launch in the current fiscal year, it should become available between April and June.</p>
<p>As far as official information goes, very little is currently known about the Nintendo Switch 2, not even its official name. The system will deliver a level of performance <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-software-impact/">not too different from the Steam Deck</a>, although the console's stronger GPU and weaker CPU, compared to Valve's system, will make it run games at <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-higher-resolution-steam-deck/">a higher resolution but lower framerate</a>. The console is also said to support NVIDIA DLSS and Ray Reconstruction, which should give it an edge in a variety of situations, potentially making it superior to the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X when it comes to ray tracing.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 has yet to be officially revealed. We will let you know more about the system as soon as possible, so stay tuned for all the latest news.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>