<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 21:56:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[September’s Unmissable Game Releases]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/septembers-biggest-game-releases/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/september%E2%80%99s-unmissable-game-releases.968841/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/septembers-biggest-game-releases/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>We hope your wallet is ready because September’s biggest game releases are on the horizon, and there are a lot of them to sift through. Let’s look at the most exciting upcoming games of September, along with a handful of honorable mentions we think are also worth your time!</p>



<h2 id="h-upcoming-games-in-september-2024">Upcoming Games in September 2024</h2>



<p>At first glance, September looks like a fantastic month for the gaming community. We have countless indie projects finally launching after months or years of hype, alongside numerous high-profile releases. From space-based simulation games to previously console-exclusive titles, there’s a lot to play this month!</p>



<h3 id="h-star-trucker">Star Trucker</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Star Trucker  - Date Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ue68N_CpVlM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 3</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC, Xbox Series X|S</li>
</ul>



<p>In what felt like one of the most unique and surprising titles during Steam Next Fest, Star Trucker won us over with its science-fiction take on the truck simulator genre. Instead of hauling cargo from a small town in California to a hub in Texas, we’re roaming the stars in style, using a jet-powered truck cab that occasionally requires repairs. Oh, and it’s customizable. Star Trucker looks like it’ll shake up the transportation and hauling simulation community!</p>



<h3 id="h-the-casting-of-frank-stone">The Casting of Frank Stone</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Casting of Frank Stone | Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O1xixINNd6I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 3</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S</li>
</ul>



<p>I genuinely didn’t expect the Dead by Daylight franchise to spawn multiple spin-offs, yet here we are, eagerly awaiting the first one from developer Supermassive Games. The studio, known for its choice-driven horror stories, such as The Quarry, is creating a vibrant and enthralling story-driven experience in The Casting of Frank Stone. It’s a horror game in which friends uncover the mystery surrounding an infamous serial killer.</p>



<h3 id="h-astro-bot">Astro Bot</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Astro Bot - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/unYFdcEjV9k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 6</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PlayStation 5</li>
</ul>



<p>Utilizing the full power of the PlayStation 5 and its branding, Astro Bot launches us on an adventure spanning multiple levels and biomes, from jungles to volcanoes, as we unlock unique abilities and rescue lost crewmates. The PS5 exclusive features new powers and all-new enemies but retains its platforming mechanics that so many fell in love with. </p>



<h3 id="h-warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Warhammer 40k: Space Marine 2 - The Angels Of Death Cinematic Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-vnbKeOFPrI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 9</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S</li>
</ul>



<p>How much fan service can you fit into one game? All of it is the answer. Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 lets us finally step into the up-armored boots of an Ultramarine, wielding various melee and ranged weapons, including the iconic Chainsword, Thunder Hammer, and Heavy Bolters, as we stomp, slash, and slay Tyranids across multiple planets. With a full single-player campaign, cooperative missions, and a PvP mode, there’s a lot to love about Space Marine 2!</p>



<h3 id="h-dead-rising-deluxe-remaster">Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FIAiUWhxmrs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 18</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S</li>
</ul>



<p>Frank returns, albeit with a new voice actor, in the upcoming Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster. This remaster is more like a remake, with enhanced graphics, modern controls, quality-of-life features, and full voice acting across the board. But despite its monumental changes on the technical side of the spectrum, DRDR retains its core gameplay loop of infiltrating the Willamette Mall, rescuing civilians, and fighting psychopaths amid a zombie apocalypse!</p>



<h3 id="h-god-of-war-ragnarok">God of War: Ragnarok</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="God of War: Ragnarok - PC Announcement Trailer | State of Play 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wSHZIckO8kw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 19</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC</li>
</ul>



<p>God of War launching on PC was a most welcome surprise, but it left us eager for more. Thankfully, Sony enjoys money, so it wishes to capitalize on the PC gaming community by releasing more of its console-exclusive titles. In September, we’ll see God of War: Ragnarok, the continuation of Kratos and Atreus’ story. The PC port features unlocked frame rates, high-fidelity graphics, enhanced lightning, upscaling, and ultrawide support on day one!</p>



<h3 id="h-frostpunk-2">Frostpunk 2</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Frostpunk 2 | Official Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PWlLOpqIYjA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 20</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC</li>
</ul>



<p>To many, the survival city-building genre set itself apart with Frostpunk. The tough-as-nails strategy game tasked players with building a society following a worldwide calamity that froze the planet to its core. Now, the sequel aims to expand and enhance the formula that won over so many—us included—by introducing new mechanics and new settings and pushing the story forward by 30 years. It all goes down in September!</p>



<h2 id="h-honorable-mentions-for-september">Honorable Mentions for September</h2>



<p>Of course, the few we’ve listed here are just a snippet of what’s launching in September. There’s also:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Ale &amp; Tale Tavern</strong></li>



<li><strong>Selfloss</strong></li>



<li><strong>Mirthwood</strong></li>



<li><strong>Lollipop Chainsaw RePop</strong></li>



<li><strong>REKA</strong></li>



<li><strong>Chef RPG</strong></li>



<li><strong>Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown</strong></li>



<li><strong>Wild Bastards</strong></li>



<li><strong>Final Fantasy 16</strong></li>



<li><strong>Tiny Glade</strong></li>



<li><strong>Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed</strong></li>



<li><strong>Greedfall 2: The Dying World</strong></li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>September is jam-packed with hot new titles, but there’s one I’ve personally got my eye on. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-forever-winter-early-access-september/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Forever Winter launches into Early Access this month</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pick Up This Outstanding, Delightfully Weird Shooter On Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/control-playstation-sale-remedy-connected-universe-1851637320</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pick-up-this-outstanding-delightfully-weird-shooter-on-sale.968811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/control-playstation-sale-remedy-connected-universe-1851637320<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Last year, Remedy released the survival horror title <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-review-control-max-payne-1850994952&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-review-control-max-payne-1850994952"><em>Alan Wake 2</em></a></span>, a sequel effectively 13 years in the making and the next step in the studio’s universe of connected games. Among them is <em>Control</em>, a brilliant and utterly weird third-person shooter focusing on the character <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-sexiness-of-control-1840876335&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-sexiness-of-control-1840876335">Jesse Faden </a></span>and her exploits with the Federal Bureau of Control, a government agency that tries to contain supernatural threats and phenomena. In <em>Control</em>, you face off against these forces inside of The Oldest House, a brutalist office building in the heart of New York whose unwieldy innards are constantly shifting.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196470" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Reignited Rivalries And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="123" data-playlist="196470,195922,196345" data-current="196470"><div><p>The Week In Games: Reignited Rivalries And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22020.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>That is just the tippy top of the bizarre iceberg that is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/control-the-kotaku-review-1837569523&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/control-the-kotaku-review-1837569523"><em>Control</em></a></span><em>, </em>which is not only celebrating a fifth anniversary this week but is also coincidentally on sale on PlayStation.<strong> If you care (and I do believe you should), you can nab yourself the ultimate edition of </strong><em><strong>Control </strong></em><strong>(including its very necessary DLCs) for $10.</strong><br></p><p>I say that these are necessary because <em>Control </em>isn’t just tangentially connected to <em>Alan Wake </em>and the universe that Remedy is building. It and its supplementary material (as well as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/surprise-two-more-control-games-are-in-the-works-1847196296&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/surprise-two-more-control-games-are-in-the-works-1847196296">the sequel and multiplayer spinoff</a></span> that are on the way) are quintessential to understanding the connectedness of it all. You get a much fuller picture of the scope of things by first playing <em>Control</em>, which outlines a lot of the concepts, like Altered World Events and Objects of Power, that factor into <em>Alan Wake 2</em> quite heavily. It’s like a kind of side-sequel to the first <em>Alan Wake</em>, providing a wider window into the larger world that it only teased and connecting countless dots in the interim.</p><p>Beyond its role as connective tissue, <em>Control </em>is also its own loving ode to all things weird. The FBC is basically just <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SCP_Foundation&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SCP_Foundation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the SCP Foundation</a></span>, which has its own basis in the history of internet creepypasta and urban myths. It is a world where the weirdo monsters we created as children are real and where cursed objects do exist. Some, like the floppy disk, grant blessings like the ability of telekinesis. Others, like a rubber duck, might dart around and prove to be a simple nuisance. And then there are fridges that might contain powerful beings beyond comprehension unless someone maintains eye contact with it at all times.</p><p>Much like the things it attempts to contain, the FBC’s headquarters is impossible to pin down. Unless you know to look for it, or are a particularly powerful parautilitarian, you can’t actually find and enter the Oldest House. Once you’re there, there’s no guarantee you won’t get lost within its walls either. That, or die in one of its “shifts” that drastically changes the layout of whole floors and departments. </p><p>All the while, the Oldest House is simultaneously the most aggressively mundane office building. Everywhere you look, concrete walls are blanketed by the glow of sterile white office lights. Typical desks and office chairs dot cubicles and offices that you explore. Little boxes all the same as far as the eye can see. But despite that, the environment is still suffused with an uneasy, sometimes menacing, feeling. One office will have <em>way</em> <em>too many</em> post-it notes adorning its surfaces, while a hallway in another wing of the building will seemingly spiral into nothingness. Bodies of office employees hang suspended in the air. And for all of the bland office space, there are jaw-dropping and impossible vistas to be seen in places like the Black Rock Quarry, or the very bottom of the Oldest House.<br></p><p>The environment does a lot of talking in <em>Control</em>. Whole stories can be gleaned from the layout of things, but <em>Control </em>also<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/fiddlecub/status/1828741627365429748&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/fiddlecub/status/1828741627365429748" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">features <em>a lot </em>of notes</a></span>, often shared between workers in departments that expertly build out and add further mystique to the game’s fiction. And then <em>Control </em>does one of my favorite things that only a game can do, and allows you to occasionally explore and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mysteries-are-the-heart-of-control-1844900378&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mysteries-are-the-heart-of-control-1844900378">uncover the mysteries</a></span> it builds up in the background of the central thrust of the story. Reader, it rarely, if ever disappoints on this front.<br></p><p><em>Control</em>, down to its central weapon, is just endlessly intriguing and teeming with possibility. The Service Weapon, itself an Object of Power, can morph into all manner of firearms, including a pistol, a shotgun, and eventually even a kind of grenade launcher. In tandem with Jesse’s increasing range of abilities, such as levitation and a shield, it’s very easy to become this all-encompassing powerhouse. Maybe that’s what I really love about <em>Control. </em>Not the power fantasy of it all, but how impossible it feels to fence in or nail down, how consistently and expertly it adapts different modes and forms that feel they can all breathe within <em>Control</em>’s seemingly limitless possibilities.</p><p><em>Control</em> is, simply put, one of the most special games of the last generation. Despite struggling a bit out the door, it eventually found its audience and has already grown into a title worthy of reverence. If you don’t already know what’s up, do yourself a favor and block off some time to pick up <em>Control </em>and just sink beneath its surface. You will not regret the time you’ll spend uncovering what the Oldest House has to hide.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Squirrel with a Gun Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/squirrel-with-a-gun-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/squirrel-with-a-gun-review.968808/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/squirrel-with-a-gun-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">This amusing sandbox game has a lot of heart, but is every bit as shallow and short-lived as its goofy premise seems.</h2></div><div><section><p>Few premises are more immediately appealing than Squirrel with a Gun’s. A sandbox game where you control a gun-toting rodent and wreak havoc on the local population? Yes, please! And that premise certainly delivers to some extent, with quite a few laugh-out-loud funny moments right out the gate and a lot of enjoyment to be found in the goofy adventure’s opening hours. But this wacky Sciuridae simulator isn’t sitting on a stockpile of comedic acorns, instead stuffing its cheeks with silly gags all in one go, before finding its stores empty as the winter season fast approaches. Compounding that short-lived mirth are fairly serious performance issues, including regular crashes that made me repeat long stretches, which really took the wind out of my furry wings. Squirrel with a Gun still offers a couple hours of amusing sandbox goofiness, and I eagerly await a more fleshed out sequel in the same vein as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/goat-simulator-3-review">Goat Simulator 3</a>, but this first shot misses the target once the joke has run its course.</p><p>Like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/09/20/untitled-goose-game-review">Untitled Goose Game</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2014/04/24/octodad-dadliest-catch-ps4-review">Octodad: Dadliest Catch</a> before it, Squirrel with a Gun is a zany sandbox game where you play a troublemaking animal who becomes a real problem for the humans around them. After obtaining a pistol from a clumsy government spook, you’re let loose on a suburban community to rob people at gunpoint, wantonly destroy personal property, and exercise your Second Amendment right to blast fools in the face like the bloodthirsty little varmint you are. It’s a good time! But that dopey bit is exactly as shallow as it sounds, and though it only took me four hours to roll credits, it took even less time for the laughs to peter out.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"></output><p>Fighting as a squirrel packing heat proves pretty hollow. You’ll use pistols, rifles, and even grenade launchers to send <a href="https://www.ign.com/movies/franchise/the-matrix"><u>Agent Smith</u></a>-looking sons of a gun to their doom – and they mostly stand around and let you do so while putting up very little resistance. They’re the only enemies to be found here, and they all go down in a couple of shots. One highlight is when you stun enemies and are then able to kill them off with a special finishing move, like peppering an enemy with lead from an uzi or swatting their grasping hands away while you perform gunjitsu like a furry <a href="https://www.ign.com/movies/franchise/john-wick"><u>John Wick</u></a>. Unfortunately, there’s only one of these animations for each weapon, so like a lot of things in this adventure, the novelty runs out fairly quickly. There isn’t much to combat beyond these basics, and each weapon feels like just another indistinctive piece in the arsenal in a matter of seconds.</p><p>There are two boss fights to shake things up, however, where you take on giant military vehicles, like a tank. These encounters are quick sequences where you shoot at glowing spots and whittle down a health bar, which doesn’t provide much of a challenge, but they are at least a nice change of pace and have a few gags that made me smile. If more stuff like this made it into the story, it might have gone a long way to extend my enjoyment, but like everything else in this brief adventure, these antics are fleeting.</p><p>The puzzle-platforming, on the other hand, is much more satisfying. Firing your weapons as a means of double-jumping or otherwise propelling yourself into the air to overcome platforming challenges is far more interesting than any of the combat in Squirrel with a Gun. The submachine gun is a great way to keep yourself airborne for extended periods of time while crossing gaps, but nothing beats the rocket launcher in terms of pure height – it sends you sailing into the air to land (mostly) safely on faraway platforms. None of the platforming is particularly tricky, but making your fluffy avatar sail from place to place doesn’t get old nearly as quickly as the rest of the gameplay.</p><p>Unfortunately, Squirrel with a Gun’s good times are prone to interruption by technical issues that proved quite problematic, even during its brief runtime. I found myself staring at a frozen screen more than five times in as many hours, losing a good chunk of progress in the process, and was forced to repeat entire sections. By the end, I got into the fear-driven habit of rushing over to the static save points that can be found in each area – and a good thing too, because crashes seemed to happen more frequently in the back half of the adventure. And that’s not the only issue I ran into, either: One cutscene triggered and forgot to add the squirrel where he’s supposed to go, which broke everything and forced me to reset, and there were several times where my tiny buddy passed through geometry when moving at high speeds and sent me tumbling to the ground, which forced me to repeat certain platforming sections. Thankfully, Squirrel with a Gun already embraces a certain kind of chaotic energy, so the occasional goofy glitch isn’t the end of the world. But it did make some of the otherwise entertaining sections lose some of their luster once I had to replay them a third time in the wake of a crash.</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3>Verdict</h3><p>Squirrel with a Gun is an awesome, immediately charming idea with legs as short as its fluffy protagonist. While platforming around by firing off weapons and causing mayhem in the small sandbox areas yields plenty of enjoyable moments, shallow combat, numerous technical issues, and short runtime left me wanting more. Even the over-the-top boss fights, which are definitely a high point in the zany adventure, come to an end all too quickly and are in short supply. I still adore this violent rodent and have high hopes for a sequel that’s bigger, more fleshed out, and less prone to crashing, but this first shot leaves a fair bit to be desired.</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3><div><h3 data-cy="object-review-title">Squirrel with a Gun Review</h3><div><p>okay</p><p>Squirrel with a Gun is a uniquely amusing sandbox game, but it’s as shallow and short-lived as its goofy premise seems.</p><a href="https://www.ign.com/person/Tieguytravis" title="Travis Northup"><span></span><figcaption><p>Travis Northup</p></figcaption></a></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IGN Is Your Ultimate Destination for Star Wars Outlaws]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ign-is-your-ultimate-destination-for-star-wars-outlaws</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ign-is-your-ultimate-destination-for-star-wars-outlaws.968805/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ign-is-your-ultimate-destination-for-star-wars-outlaws<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Explore the galaxy like never before.</h2></div><div><section><p>Star Wars Outlaws is one of the biggest gaming releases of 2024, and IGN is your ultimate destination for the game. Whether you're looking for guides to assist your journey through each of the massive planets or for a review to determine if you're going to pick up the game, we've got you covered.</p><h3>Detailed Map Genie Maps for Each Planet</h3><div id="206556" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Map Genie</h3></p><div><p>Explore Toshara, Tatooine, Kijimi, and Akiva with Map Genie to never miss a quest, collectible, or POI.</p></div></div><p>The IGN team has Map Genie maps live for each planet in the game, ensuring you won't miss a collectible or side quest in your playthrough! These maps will continue to be updated throughout the next week, but dozens of collectibles are already live across four planets!</p><h3>Leading Game Help</h3><p>IGN is your go-to for all the latest guides on Star Wars Outlaws, from a <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/Walkthrough">complete walkthrough</a> to tips on <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/Kessel_Sabacc_-_How_to_Play_and_Rewards">Kessel Sabacc</a>. Check out some of our available tips to help you get started below:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/How_to_Earn_Credits_(Money)_Fast">How to Earn Credits (Money) Fast</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/Secrets_and_Easter_Eggs">Star Wars Outlaws Secrets and Easter Eggs</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/All_Outfit_Sets">All Outfit Sets</a></li></ul><p>Be sure to stay tuned for more, as we'll be updating and adding new guides well past launch day!</p><h3>Star Wars Outlaws - The IGN Review</h3><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>IGN Video Producer <a href="https://www.ign.com/person/tristan_ign_au">Tristan Ogilvie</a> reviewed Star Wars Outlaws, giving the game <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-review">a 7/10</a>. In our review, he stated, "It’s ironic that Kay’s ship is called the Trailblazer, since there’s actually not a whole lot of ideas in Star Wars Outlaws that haven’t been done before in other action and open-world adventures. Instead, it’s quite like the Millenium Falcon: a bucket of bolts held together with repurposed parts and prone to breaking down, but at its best it’s more than capable of jolting your pleasure centres into Star Wars fan hyperspace."</p><h3>More Star Wars: Outlaws Content on IGN</h3><p>Beyond game help, Map Genie, and our review, IGN has even more Star Wars Outlaws coverage available now and on the way! Our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-star-wars-outlaws-fulfills-the-starship-fantasy-ign-first">IGNFirst coverage</a> dives deep into the game with exclusive commentary from the developers at Ubisoft Massive. Moving forward, we'll also have plenty of breakdowns surrounding the game's biggest features, analysis on the story, and all kinds of news surrounding the upcoming DLC. </p><h3>Star Wars Collection at IGN Store</h3><p>Last but not least, be sure to check out our Star Wars Collection at IGN Store. Whether you're in the market for a new shirt, figure, or even hot sauce, there's dozens of Star Wars-themed items available now. </p><div><div id="206517" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>STAR WARS Dark Side Hot Sauce by TRUFF</h3></p></div><div id="206518" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Star Wars - Comic Caper - T-Shirt</h3></p></div><div id="206519" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Star Wars: The Mandalorian - This Is The Bouquet Grogu - Button Down</h3></p></div></div></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 30, 2024 7:10 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed Feels Just as Vibrant As Ever in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-feels-just-as-vibrant-as-ever-in-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-feels-just-as-vibrant-as-ever-in-2024.968802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-feels-just-as-vibrant-as-ever-in-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Warren Spector’s love letter to Disney was already great, but this faithful remake looks to fix its biggest flaws.</h2></div><section><p>There’s something… well… magical about 2010’s Wii-exclusive Epic Mickey getting a remake in 2024. As those who played the original know, the game itself is a quest through a realm of forgotten Disney characters and attractions called the Wasteland and, after playing a demo of Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed at D23, I’m more confident than ever that this adventure with an impressive new coat of paint will thankfully not be lost to the unforgiving hands of time, like some that sadly came before it.</p><p>What impressed me the most about Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed is how much it looks and, perhaps most importantly, feels like a 2024 game. In our original Epic Mickey review, we gave it an 8/10 and said that this ‘Great’ game was held back by a camera and control system that were “flawed to a point where the larger experience becomes damaged.” None of those issues were present in what I played of the remake and it felt like an absolute joy to play. Oh, and it running at a smooth 60FPS didn’t hurt its case either.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Mickey himself has also improved in the 14 years since he first entered the Wasteland, as he can now sprint, dash, and ground pound around the gorgeous-yet-dark world that is very much like a twisted version of Disneyland. These new traversal additions are the Minnie to Mickey’s paint brush abilities, and they dance in a way that is just as beautiful as Disney Parks’ best nighttime spectaculars. </p><p>I just had the biggest smile on my face as I jumped around the opening level of Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed and didn’t have to deal with the frustrating motion and camera controls of the Wii version, leaving me to paint and thin with ease while feeling so much more agile. The best remakes implement changes that seem almost preposterous to think they were never there, and these fit that bill. </p><h3>A Remake in Every Sense of the Word</h3><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>As for the visuals of Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed, they are another highlight in large part to remake developer Purple Lamp’s decision to not only rebuild the whole game with the original assets so it was playable from start to finish, but to then remake every asset from scratch and do it all over again. This dedication appears to have been worth it, as the Wasteland is now a place I wish I could explore forever.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Fans will be able to look forward to three times as many collectibles to find, from pins to film reels to artwork and so much more. </p></div><p>From the inky black paint-like blot floating off Mickey as he runs and jumps to the colors and sharpness of the alternate flying elephant  and tea cup attractions, Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed takes place in a world that I can just watch and listen to a subtle and haunting version of ‘Once Upon a Dream’ and still feel like I had a worthy play session. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The side-scrolling, 2D projector stages that take Mickey from one level to another also look so much better and, in one of the new additions to Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed, you can go back and play through them again as you wish in the game’s Main Street Cinema. This means you can replay levels based on such classic Mickey cartoons as Steamboat Willie, Mickey and the Beanstalk, and more as you please. </p><p>Now, there isn’t a ton new in Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed as it is a very faithful remake, but fans will be able to look forward to three times as many collectibles to find, from pins to film reels to artwork and so much more. The team also told me there will be some new puzzles to solve, but that’s really about it.</p><p>So, if you didn’t love the story or painting gameplay or the first interaction between Mickey Mouse and Oswald the Lucky Rabbit, these modern upgrades may not be enough to sway you. However, like me, if you saw in the original something that was held back from greatness on the Wii - or you never had a Wii and just love Disney and Mickey - this is one adventure you should keep an eye on.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>I’ll be very curious to see how the rest of the game holds up, as I was only able to play that opening level, but what I experienced left such an impression on me that it’s making September 24 a whole lot harder to wait for. </p><p>To end, I just wanted to share a few words from my chat with game design legend Warren Spector, the creative director on the original who also consulted on Rebrushed, as he sums up why Epic Mickey is one the games he is “most proud of.” High praise from the creator of Deus Ex and System Shock.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>“I wanted to make a game for families that parents and children could play together, that kids could teach their parents how to play because that's the way it would work, not the other way around.”</p></div><p>“The thing that I love the most about this game is that it touched people emotionally,” Spector said. “I wanted to make a game for families that parents and children could play together, that kids could teach their parents how to play because that's the way it would work, not the other way around.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>“Additionally, one of the things that characterizes Disney is that things last. They have lasting value. How many 1937 films are people still watching today that weren't made by Walt Disney? So, the idea that a game had that kind of impact and longevity is really special. But the biggest thing, really the biggest thing, is when people come up to me as they have at D23 and say, ‘I played this game as a child and now I get to play it with my child.’ That brings tears to my eyes. It just shows the real power and potential of games to do more than I think most of us realize.”</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An Astro Bot Sequel May Already Be In The Works]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/atro-bot-platinum-trophy-sequel-or-dlc-1851637283</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/an-astro-bot-sequel-may-already-be-in-the-works.968784/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/atro-bot-platinum-trophy-sequel-or-dlc-1851637283<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="373cd92b09aa772543830445688270ef" data-recommend-id="image://373cd92b09aa772543830445688270ef" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony Interactive Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="373cd92b09aa772543830445688270ef" data-recommend-id="image://373cd92b09aa772543830445688270ef" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>As far as games, September looks to be just as fruitful as August, with the month that was owned by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-steam-reviews-1851634466&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-steam-reviews-1851634466"><em>Black Myth: Wukong</em></a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-review-size-how-big-hours-xbox-ps5-pc-1851631123&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-review-size-how-big-hours-xbox-ps5-pc-1851631123"><em>Star Wars Outlaws</em></a></span> being followed by yet another hyped release in <em>Astro Bot</em>. And for those who can’t resist looking even further ahead, you may be in for a treat. It seems Team Asobi, the developer behind <em>Astro Bot</em>, is considering a sequel even before the first game launches worldwide. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196805" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="I Hate This FF7 Rebirth Character’s Whole Vibe" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="93" data-playlist="196805,195905,196646" data-current="196805"><div><p>I Hate This FF7 Rebirth Character’s Whole Vibe</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196805/196805_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196805/196805_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196805/196805_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196805/196805_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22362.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Over on X/Twitter, user <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Genki_JPN/status/1829165000910602705?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Genki_JPN/status/1829165000910602705?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Genki_JPN</a></span> uncovered the game’s Platinum Trophy, which reads, “<strong>Earned all trophies. Well done, and see you in Astro’s next adventure</strong>.”</p><p>It’s important to note that a trophy description isn’t an official announcement or confirmation from the team regarding a sequel. This description could easily point toward DLC, a full-blown expansion pack, or even a crossover with another game such as <em>Fortnite</em>. (Let’s be honest. Everyone is doing a crossover with <em>Fortnite </em>these days.)<br></p><p>On the topic of <em>Astro Bot</em>, the team recently discussed the potential for a PC version but shut down the PlayStation VR2 hype. A PC release remains on the table so long as there is fan interest, so the studio asked everyone who wants one to voice their excitement online.<br></p><p>No matter what you think of the prospect of an <em>Astro Bot </em>sequel (even if you’re soulless enough to not want as many installments as we can get), we’ll likely see more of the lovable character in some capacity following the game’s launch in September. It’s just a matter of how much and how soon. </p><p>Stay tuned more PlayStation news, which includes the three free titles (<em>Harry Potter: Quidditch Champions</em>, <em>MLB The Show 24</em>, and <em>Little Nightmares II)</em>&nbsp;<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/harry-potter-quidditch-champions-free-ps-plus-september-1851634283&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/harry-potter-quidditch-champions-free-ps-plus-september-1851634283">coming to PS Plus next month</a></span>.</p><p>.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon II free Kingdoms update part one coming this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/darkest-dungeon-ii-free-kingdoms-update-part-one-coming-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/darkest-dungeon-ii-free-kingdoms-update-part-one-coming-this-year.968766/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/darkest-dungeon-ii-free-kingdoms-update-part-one-coming-this-year/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Darkest Dungeon II is getting a major campaign expansion for free called Kingdoms, alongside a paid DLC called Inhuman Bondage, and Red Hook Studios has released details about both. First off the paid DLC, Inhuman Bondage, will be coming in Q4 2024. This will add a new Hero who will have unique trinkets, weapons, palettes, and mechanics. It will also add a new region the size of the Sluice which will also add a new enemy faction and items.</p>



<p>The Kingdoms campaign will be released in three parts and the first of that is Hunger of the Beast Clan. This release will need players to protect the realm from a new enemy factions, which in this case are the beast men. Players will have to travel across the land to complete quests and upgrade the inns around the realm. Kingdoms will run parallel to the main Confessions campaign.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/07/31/darkest-dungeon-ii-review-highway-to-hell/">Darkest Dungeon II Review – Highway to Hell</a></h2>
<p>In our Darkest Dungeon II review, Steve said, <em>“Darkest Dungeon II is to be applauded for not resting on its laurels, instead opting to make significant changes from its predecessor. The style, challenge, and strategic brilliance remain and that is enough to make it stand out still. However, the focus on roguelike randomness and excessive grind does make this a very different experience and one that didn’t gel for me. If you have the patience to explore the rich detail of the mechanics and the stoicism to deal with the inevitable deaths and disappointments then this is a journey worth taking. Just don’t expect it to be a comfortable ride.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.threads.net/@redhookstudios/post/C_Q-FQZSJWm/?xmt=AQGzp-IQ7gWdQW_lz0PKueU3IbRE5PBaujFwjoXBzKEZNg">Threads</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Castlevania Dominus Collection Is Already On Sale For 25% Off]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/castlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off/1100-6526214/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/castlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off.968763/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/castlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off/1100-6526214/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526214">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The newly released Castlevania Dominus Collection is the latest remaster of classic Castlevania games, and if you're looking for a monster-hunting fix on PC, Green Man Gaming has you covered. The retailer is offering <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgreenmangaming.sjv.io%2Fc%2F1804712%2F1219987%2F15105%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.greenmangaming.com%2Fgames%2Fcastlevania-dominus-collection-pc&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fcastlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off%2F1100-6526214%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Dominus Collection for 25% off</a> its list price, knocking the cost down to $18.74 for four 2D Castlevania titles. If you grab this deal, you'll get a key to redeem on Steam, which is pretty cool considering Steam itself has the collection for the full $25 price.</p><p>Castlevania Dominus Collection includes three side-scrolling games that were originally released on the Nintendo DS: Castlevania: Dawn of Sorrow, Castlevania: Portrait of Ruin, and Castlevania: Order of Ecclesia. The ports bring all those games to a single screen, as opposed to the DS's dual screens for which they were designed, which means all three have been slightly redesigned to compensate. Map and inventory screens now appear on the right side, as opposed to the bottom screen on DS. Another notable change is Dawn of Sorrow's stylus drawing mechanic has been been adapted into quick-time events.</p><p>In addition to the three Nintendo DS Castlevanias, the Dominus Collection also includes a remaster of the first Castlevania arcade game, Haunted Castle. The port features a reworked version of the arcade game, as well as the option to play it in its original format.</p><p>Dominus Collection also adds a few quality-of-life improvements to all the games, like rewind features and save states.</p><p>This is actually the third Castlevania game collection as Konami has released old entries in the series that were only available on dated hardware. You can also snag the PC version of 2019's <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fcastlevania-anniversary-collection&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fcastlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off%2F1100-6526214%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Anniversary Collection on Fanatical</a>, which knocks 20% off the list price, bringing the cost down to $15.74 from the usual tag of $20. The Anniversary Collection includes eight games: Castlevania, Castlevania II Simon's Quest, Castlevania III: Dracula's Curse, Super Castlevania IV, Castlevania The Adventure, Castlevania II Belmont's Revent, Castlevania Bloodlines, and Kid Dracula. It also packs in the ebook History of Castlevania - Book of the Crescent Moon, which documents the franchise's development history.</p><p>The Dominus Collection is slated to get a physical release with multiple cover options from Limited Run Games, and preorders will be available in September. You can also get physical additions of the Castlevania Anniversary Collection and Konami's other re-release of Castlevania games, Castlevania Advance Collection, on Amazon, some of which offer alternative cover art. Check out the list below. Fair warning: Many of these physical editions are quite expensive, as they are out of print and sold by third parties.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Anniversary-Collection-Limited-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B09ML8N2K6?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Anniversary Collection (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Collection-Advanced-Limited-Run/dp/B0D14WQVX2?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Advanced Edition (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Advanced-Limited/dp/B0D14WKWL1?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Advanced Edition (PS4)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Advanced-Limited-Xbox/dp/B0D3JGG6MB?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Advanced Edition (Xbox One)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Sorrow-Limited/dp/B0CWP6Z6NY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Aria of Sorrow Cover (PS4)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Sorrow-Cover-Limited/dp/B0CZ2TRQ5S?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Aria of Sorrow Cover (Xbox One)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Classic-Circle/dp/B0CWP883FS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Circle of the Moon Cover (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Circle-Cover-Limited/dp/B0CZ2QD42B?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Circle of the Moon Cover (Xbox One)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Classic-Dracula/dp/B0CQBF61X2?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Dracula X Cover (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Playstation-Dracula/dp/B0CQB5H595?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Dracula X Cover (PS4)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Classic-Dissonance/dp/B0CQ7MFKDW?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Harmony of Dissonance Cover (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Playstation-Dissonance-4/dp/B0CQC32JKF?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Harmony of Dissonance Cover (PS4)</a></li></ul><p><em>Disclosure: GameSpot and Fanatical are both owned by Fandom.</em></p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/berserk-the-complete-1997-tv-series-is-only-37-at-amazon-best-price-yet/1100-6524954/">Berserk: The Complete 1997 TV Series Is Only $37 At Amazon, Best Price Yet</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/astro-bot-ps5-dualsense-controller-preorder/1100-6525376/">Astro Bot PS5 Controller Preorders Restocked At Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-the-skywalker-saga-complete-digital-collection-is-only-20-at-amazon/1100-6526122/">Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga Complete Digital Collection Is Only $20 At Amazon</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-atari-2600-gets-huge-price-cut-at-best-buy/1100-6520830/">Lego Atari 2600 Gets Huge Price Cut At Best Buy</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-preorder-guide/1100-6522523/">Star Wars Outlaws Preorders - Where To Find The Best Bonuses</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/buy-two-get-one-free-nintendo-switch-games-and-preorders-my-best-buy-members/1100-6525928/">B2G1 Free All Nintendo Switch Games - Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom, Mario &amp; Luigi, And More Preorders</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-preorder-guide/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition Preorders Live Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-anthology-preorders-quakecon-2024/1100-6525656/">Doom Anthology Preorders Are Live - Comes With 6 Games, Steelbook Case, And Replica BFG</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 Q&A with Tim Willits – ‘We Have a Game That Will Exceed Expectations’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-qa-with-tim-willits-we-have-a-game-that-will-exceed-expectations/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-q-a-with-tim-willits-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98we-have-a-game-that-will-exceed-expectations%E2%80%99.968745/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-qa-with-tim-willits-we-have-a-game-that-will-exceed-expectations/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At Gamescom 2024, I had the amazing opportunity to speak with veteran developer Tim Willits about Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2, Saber Interactive, and the industry as a whole. Willits worked at id Software for 24 years, eventually becoming Studio Director. He left the Texan developer in July 2019 and <a href="https://wccftech.com/ex-id-software-studio-director-tim-willits-joins-saber-interactive-as-chief-creative-officer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">became</a> Chief Creative Officer at Saber Interactive only about a month later.</p>
<p>Of course, the main focus of our chat was the impending launch of Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 (due on September 9, with a full year of post-launch roadmap already <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-reveals-first-year-of-post-launch-support/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a>), but we also discussed ongoing issues within the industry and how Saber is tackling those challenges. Keep scrolling to read a very interesting conversation.</p>
<p><iframe title="Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 - The Angels Of Death" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/buT5yuGwg8s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>With Space Marine 2, you are taking a beloved game and finally making a sequel around a decade later. Are you feeling the pressure of the fans?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. The Warhammer 40K franchise has been around for 45 years now, and millions of people love the franchise in itself. The first game was very popular. But I also want to say that if you, as a fan or as an action gamer, have never played the first game, don't worry about that. You can start with Space Marine 2 and it's a complete game. It's actually difficult to play the first game now because it's only on Steam.</p>
<p>There is an expectation from Warhammer 40K fans that we treat the universe with respect and that we get things correct. Then there's an expectation from fans of the first game, as well as just fans of Saber and action games. So yes, the expectations are very high, but I believe that we have a game that will exceed those expectations. We have a very dense game with a campaign mode that you can play by yourself or with two friends. We have our PvE missions where the story kind of runs parallel to the campaign, and then we have a full 6v6 PvP mode with three game modes, so it's a lot to offer. It's all wrapped together in our Saber proprietary technology with the Swarm tech and AI director, so we believe we are delivering the true ultimate Space Marine experience.</p>
<p><strong>How long did it take to make this game?</strong></p>
<p>Games always take a long time nowadays. About four years or so in this case, but we're very proud of where it is now. We're very happy with our work, and the people who played the preview were happy. Preorders are great. Right now, what we're focused on is September 9, you know, making sure that the servers are up and running for everyone, making sure that any issues are ironed up, but everything's looking good; it's all green lights. The game is fun and solid, so yeah, I'm excited about the launch.</p>
<p><strong>I believe the game was originally meant to come out in late 2023. Can you share what were the reasons behind this nine-month delay and what did you improve during this additional time?</strong></p>
<p>We just needed more time to polish it. You know that old saying a game is only late until it ships, but a bad game is bad forever. We wanted to focus on making sure that every component, the single player campaign and the PvE co-op mode, all those were solid.</p>
<p>There's a lot to this game and I feel that players will feel good regarding value and content. When you have all those systems, you have progression, and you have multiplayer, sometimes things take longer to get right, but I'm glad that we took the time we needed to make sure that we got it correct because Warhammer 40K fans want it correct. If we screwed something up, they would be mad, you know, and so we really wanted to honor the franchise, we wanted to respect the universe, and we wanted to make the game that people want to play.</p>
<p><strong>You worked closely with Games Workshop, right?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, they were a great partner. Everything had to be approved, from a small insignia to iconography, dialogue, etc. But they were great to work with and helped us every step of the way, so it was a real partnership.</p>
<p><strong>I guess that includes the storyline.</strong></p>
<p>Definitely. Our storyline with Titus - did you play the original?</p>
<p><strong>Not much.</strong></p>
<p>Okay, which is fine because, again, like I said, you don't have to play the first one.</p>
<p><strong>I know Titus, the protagonist, was demoted at the end of the first game.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, and then he spent 200 years in Deathwatch. This is kind of a fresh start for him, but we tried to add more personality and emotions into his story and his relationship with his squadmates and how they feel about him. He needs to win their trust while also saving the universe, so it is more than just a run-and-gun game. Titus's story is an important part of the experience.</p>
<p><strong>Especially because nowadays gamers want more. They're not just fine with shooting, like in the days of the original DOOM.</strong></p>
<p>Yes. It's important to note that the Warhammer 40K universe has been an inspiration for so many video games throughout the last decades. Just look at the original DOOM space marine; what does he look like? Look at the chain sword in Gears - where did that come from? Look at things like the Power Armor in Fallout. That looks a lot like a Space Marine. This IP has influenced many games, so I hope gamers who may be younger or may not understand the 40K universe can look at this and understand how effective it is.</p>
<p><strong>Speaking of the storyline, something I noticed while playing the preview is that one of Titus's squadmates is very confrontational with him.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, Gadriel and Chairon. Yes, he gets a little whiny, and I want to punch him, but yes, he's like, "What is up with you?" There's an event in the game between Titus and him, but it is interesting to see how that plays out.</p>
<p><strong>Based on your estimates, how long is the campaign going to be?</strong></p>
<p>It took me 12 hours to complete it, but it all depends on how you play it, on the difficulty, whether you are with your human buddies or by yourself, etc.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'We have plans to add more classes to the multiplayer modes after launch.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>The PvE co-op Operations mode basically continues the story of the campaign, right?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. When you play through the campaign, there are times when other Space Marine squads go off and do other important missions in the big storyline, so it's like there's one mission where you have to send a signal, and the defenses have to be knocked out, and you hear that there's a squad doing that. Well, when you play PvE Operations, you're that squad. The battle is so big and there's so much going on that we've engineered these co-op missions to fit into the story and make you feel part of the bigger conflict.</p>
<p><strong>I know you have a class system for the multiplayer modes. Can you talk about that?</strong></p>
<p>Indeed. Are you familiar with World War Z? It's a little similar. Our game director, Dmitry Grigorenko, was the Game Director on World War Z, and he's very good at progression, class identities, and attributes. As you play, even in PvE, as you progress, you unlock different classes and you can earn experience. You can use some of that experience to upgrade your characters even in PvP, so it's like World War Z, where you have things like the Assault class, the Heavy class, and the Support class. We have Warhammer 40K names for them, but you can pick one that you like that fits your style and then you can you can apply your experience to those classes.</p>
<p><strong>Okay. How deep is the progression for each class?</strong></p>
<p>It's deep. World War Z was deep. I don't have the numbers off the top of my head, but I feel that players will be happy. Like World War Z, we will have updates where we will expand classes, weapons, and game modes, all for free.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have plans to add new classes to Space Marine 2 post-launch?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, we have plans for it. There will be new stuff for everything.</p>
<p><strong>Is there some sort of randomness attached to the co-op mode to keep things interesting?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. The game knows that you've played those missions before, and if you play them again, you can have different enemies, so you may play a mission, and then all of a sudden, Chaos Marines show up. We do add variety to that. It comes back to our AI Director, which is a key component in our <a href="https://www.pcgamingwiki.com/wiki/Engine:Swarm_Engine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Swarm Engine</a>. We have the Swarm Deck, which controls the actions of the Swarms of Tyranids. When the Swarm breaks and each Tyranid starts to come at you, then the AI Director kicks in and it understands the state of the battles.</p>
<p>It can bring in heavies, and it can bring in ranged attack Tyranids. As a Space Marine, you are the ultimate killing machine. You are plowing through these Tyranids, but at some point, you start to feel overwhelmed, and you're fighting and fighting, and then you just finally make it through with barely enough armor left to survive.&nbsp;But you've done it, and that is all due to this very advanced AI director that helps kind of orchestrate those battles.</p>
<p><strong>Are the class skills in multiplayer the same across PvE and PvP, or did you balance them differently?</strong></p>
<p>There are similarities, but there are also differences because, obviously, fighting Chaos Marines is way more difficult than fighting Tyranids. There are behind-the-scenes changes and adjustments that allow for challenging yet approachable gameplay in PvP, as well as having fun with your buddies in PvE.</p>
<p><strong>When you're in PvE, it's okay to feel overpowered. In PvP, not so much.</strong></p>
<p>Yes. What's great about PvP is something I call the Dance of Death, where you can't just button mash; you gotta move. You have your blocks, you have your grabs, you have your counters, you have your fast melees, you have your long melees, and then you can have weapons. You need to keep moving and then attack, block, attack, so there is this Dance of Death that we've created in PvP.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'Nothing has really changed since we returned independent. The great thing about Saber is there's me, Matthew, Andrey, and Anton. There's like four of us that make all the decisions. That was always the case. We've announced some other games we're working on, like Jurassic Park Survival, A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead, coming out in October, and&nbsp;Toxic Commando.&nbsp;We'll be talking about that soon after we launch Space Marine 2. Things are going well for us.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You're independent again, with Saber CEO Matthew Karch owning parent company Beacon Interactive after the <a href="https://wccftech.com/saber-interactive-splits-embracer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">split</a> with Embracer. How does it feel, and what changed?</strong></p>
<p>Nothing really. The great thing about Saber is there's me, Matthew, Andrey, and Anton. There's like four of us that make all the decisions. That was always the case before we were purchased by Embracer, even while we worked with Embracer, and now that we're independent again, it really hasn't changed much.</p>
<p>I'm focusing on the games. That's my job, making sure that each of the teams has what they need to make the best game they can. I jump in when I'm free. I'm not in the trenches like Dmitry, but I do have exposure to all the titles and work with the teams, which makes my job awesome, I love my job. But nothing's really changed. We work with Focus for Space Marine 2 and RoadCraft. <span>We've announced some other games we're working on, like Jurassic Park Survival, <a href="https://wccftech.com/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-launches-17-october/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</a>, coming out in October, and&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/john-carpenters-toxic-commando-is-a-co-op-fps-powered-by-sabers-swarm-engine-and-due-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Toxic Commando</a>.</span>&nbsp;We'll be talking about that soon after we launch Space Marine 2. Things are going well for us.</p>
<p><strong>Are you maybe going to self-publish some titles, too?</strong></p>
<p>Yeah. We're self-publishing Jurassic Park Survival and A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead, and we're also publishing third-party games like <a href="https://wccftech.com/saber-interactive-announces-the-knightling-a-fantasy-action-adventure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Knightling</a>. We own 3D Realms, so there are a number of titles that we publish.</p>
<p><strong>Recently, the industry was shaken by various events, like studio closures and mass layoffs. Some developers are quite pessimistic about the future. What do you think?</strong></p>
<p>I have seen all the cycles. I started in 1995, and I remember the death of consoles; I remember the death of the PC. I remember that, yes, there's always cycles, but good games and good teams will always be successful. One of the things that Saber has done well is that we have studios around the world and we focus on the right scopes for our games. We focus on the right deal for our games. Each of our studios has multiple projects, so we don't have 200 people sitting around waiting for pre-production to finish. We're very smart with our money, and we focus on the core aspects of the game. We focus on what's truly fun, whether it's a $5 million game, $10 million game, or $50 million; it doesn't matter.</p>
<p>But if that core game loop is not there, it's not going to be a success, and we've done well by managing our teams, having teams and around the world at different cost structures, and finding the most talented people. If you're a world-class artist, you don't need to be in California.</p>
<p><strong>I guess, like you said, perhaps the secret is really managing your budget really well. Because some game franchises have had their budgets balloon with certain sequels.</strong></p>
<p>Well, that's because some teams have, especially in North America, 150-200 people. They pay everyone well. If your burn rate is a couple of million dollars a month and you wanna change an idea three months later, that's like $6 million wasted. We can make a game for $6 million.</p>
<p>That's one of the problems, you got these huge teams working on one game. If they want to iterate, that's expensive. Each studio at Saber has a main team working on something, and it's a natural ramp, and we have people experimenting with ideas that are starting some really small projects. Maybe five people want to work on an idea, and they can change it, they iterate, they're not spending millions of dollars. As soon as that idea is solid and we're happy with it, after going through our evaluations and our gates, then we ship people over to that project.</p>
<p>We also have a culture at Saber where everyone can work on every project. I've seen studios in North America where people are like, I'm on the red team; I'm not going to work on the blue team. But here, we're all Team Saber. For instance, we are ramping people off Space Marine 2 because it's coming out soon. Now, those people will work on Jurassic Park Survival or Toxic Commando. That's how we remain lean and make money. We don't have ridiculously expensive budgets, so we don't have to sell four million copies to be a success, you know what I'm saying? There are games in North America that, if they don't sell 4 to 6 million copies, they are a failure. That is dangerous.</p>
<p><strong>Just one last question. Electronic Arts actually came out a few months ago during an investor's call after canceling a Star Wars game in development at Respawn to <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-lays-off-5-of-its-employees-cancels-star-wars-respawn-fps-and-seeks-to-move-away-from-licensed-ips/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">say</a> that they would lean less on licensed franchises in the future. Do you think that's where the industry is headed, partially to offset those growing budgets?</strong></p>
<p>Oh no, no. We're working on a Jurassic Park game. That's one of the world's biggest IPs, and we have other things we are working on that we haven't announced yet. No, you have to manage how much money you are spending on your team. You have to manage how your teams are working.</p>
<p>If you have the right brand, the right IP, it can really benefit you. Even we have had great success working with other IPs. Look at World War Z. I believe the game has made more money than the movie did—I believe, but I'm not sure about that. But you have to manage your teams and your business, and you have to make the right game with the right budget in the right part of the world. That's what we do well.</p>
<p><strong>Okay, well, thank you a lot for your time.</strong></p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Black Ops 6 Being Forced To Wipe The Slate Clean Led To Its Biggest New Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-black-ops-6-being-forced-to-wipe-the-slate-clean-led-to-its-biggest-new-feature/1100-6526217/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-black-ops-6-being-forced-to-wipe-the-slate-clean-led-to-its-biggest-new-feature.968742/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-black-ops-6-being-forced-to-wipe-the-slate-clean-led-to-its-biggest-new-feature/1100-6526217/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526217">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/" data-ref-id="5000-630093">Black Ops 6</a> arrives on October 25, and tons of new information was revealed for multiplayer and Warzone during Activision's Call of Duty: Next event on August 28, including live gameplay featuring Treyarch's new omnimovement system. GameSpot was able to attend the event and speak with Treyarch about the changes in development for the new shared engine and how it enabled the studio to create Call of Duty's new advanced movement.</p><p dir="ltr">The last Treyarch game was 2020's Black Ops Cold War, which was a Call of Duty that was created on a shorter development cycle and required a pivot to work-from-home conditions during the pandemic. Now, Treyarch is back in the action again with an extended four-year development cycle for Black Ops 6, and it is the studio's first game on Call of Duty's new shared engine, which was introduced with 2022's Modern Warfare 2 reboot.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1399487230" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465027,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;39%20Minutes%20of%20COD%3A%20Black%20Ops%206%20Zombies%20Gameplay%20Full%20Round%20On%20Liberty%20Falls&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:2356,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/39-minutes-of-cod-black-ops-6-zombies-gameplay-full-round-on-liberty-falls\/2300-6465027\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465027\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465027\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465027\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465027&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465027,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526217&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty-black-ops-6&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,playstation-5,pc,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;activision,microsoft-game-studios&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465027},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465027\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4359245-gameplay_cod_blops6_zombies_ray_gun_v1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/bjrFrATG.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724965200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="bjrFrATG" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> 39 Minutes of COD: Black Ops 6 Zombies Gameplay Full Round On Liberty Falls</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">This is also the most ambitious Call of Duty game since Infinite Warfare in the jetpack era, with Black Ops 6's new omnimovement system that allows players to sprint, slide, and dive in any direction. Players can also go prone and spin around 360 degrees, making fancy moves that let them play out their own action-hero fantasy in matches of Call of Duty across multiplayer, Zombies, and Warzone.</p><p dir="ltr">We spoke with associate design director Matt Scronce and senior director of production Yale Miller, and while the discussion held a focus on the development cycle and movement system, we were also able to touch a little on Black Ops 6's integration into Warzone.</p><p dir="ltr">When discussing Black Ops 6's longer development time, Miller provided more insight into the first year of that development, explaining, "Part of that time was just getting the core Black Ops experience, rebuilding that from the ground up, and getting multiplayer to feel like Black Ops."</p><p dir="ltr">Miller stated he's not sure if Black Ops 6's new movement system would've come to fruition without the transition to the new engine, saying, "I don't know if omnimovement would have happened the same way, [and] I don't know if it's specifically because of the time, but I think part of it was because of the fact that we had to wipe the slate clean and start fresh with rebuilding movement from the beginning."</p><p dir="ltr">"And it really forced the team, and this is my perspective," Miller clarified, "to think of all the pieces that were really important, and that kind of led us down the path of, well, fluidity is king."</p><p dir="ltr">Putting a focus on fluidity for Black Ops 6 led Miller and the team to consider plenty of questions about movement in the game that eventually led to omnimovement.</p><p dir="ltr">"And you maybe wouldn't have had that [thought process] if you were building from the prior code base," Miller said.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359787-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0152.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359787" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359787-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0152.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359787"></a><figcaption>Dive in any direction with omnimovement</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359787-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0152.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Treyarch games are also known for having a faster pace, a more arcade-style design, and a vibrant color palette. One of the community concerns prior to seeing Black Ops 6 footage, was wondering if Treyarch would lose its signature style on the new shared engine.</p><p dir="ltr">Scronce shared some insight to the studio's initial thoughts on keeping Treyarch's style when moving to the new engine. "It was definitely a huge focus," he said. "I wouldn't say it was a worry, really. That first year was like, let's get it feeling like a Black Ops game. Then, we started asking ourselves, what does a Black Ops game feel like? So, asking those hard questions and you come up with some really interesting answers, and it really lets you kind of galvanize what is a Black Ops game?"</p><p dir="ltr">"Every Black Ops has its own story," Scronce said. "And this one was like, oh, we're redefining what it means to be a Black Ops game."</p><p dir="ltr">Omnimovement is the biggest feature of Black Ops 6, and following the integration into Warzone, it will become one of the main focuses of battle royale for the new year. When discussing how Treyarch and Raven Software will keep Warzone fresh, Miller said, "I think the biggest change to Warzone, frankly, is going to be movement, and that's where a lot of our focus is. Working with that crew [Raven Software] on how we can make sure this stuff all feels right."</p><p dir="ltr">Unfortunately, for Warzone players hoping to prestige this year, there will be a bit of a disadvantage. Black Ops 6 brings back Call of Duty's traditional prestige system, which will rest progression and locks all of the guns and attachments from level 1-55.</p><p dir="ltr">This might not be a burden for old-school Call of Duty players, but Treyarch confirmed this would be a shared prestige system across multiplayer, Zombies, and Warzone. This will be Warzone's first year with a classic prestige system, so players who choose to prestige will need to grind to earn all of those weapons and attachments again for their meta loadouts. However, this classic-style prestige choice in Black Ops 6 and Warzone will be optional.</p><p dir="ltr">The choice to prestige in Black Ops 6 will offer some rewards, including unique Black Ops-themed cosmetics and permanent unlocks for things like weapons and perks. And the developer said players can choose to protect certain items from the reset with those permanent unlock token rewards, but otherwise all content unlocked from levels 1-55 will be reset with each prestige, regardless of which mode you play.</p><p dir="ltr">Black Ops 6 will integrate with Warzone by adding Treyarch's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-cod-warzone-map-area-99-is-where-nuketown-was-born/1100-6526171/">new Area 99 Resurgence map</a>. In past years, a new Call of Duty integrated into Warzone with a standard, large-scale battle royale map, but this year will focus on a new Resurgence experience with Urzikstan remaining the large map until Warzone's original <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-warzone-is-finally-returning-to-verdansk-in-2025/1100-6526178/">Verdansk map arrives in the spring</a>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359788-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0022.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359788" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359788-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0022.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359788"></a><figcaption>Area 99 map layout</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359788-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0022.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Scronce explained this by saying they were really focused on the new Resurgence map, because it was themed around Black Ops lore with it being the birthplace of Nuketown.</p><p dir="ltr">"That has been the focus," Miller added. "Bringing in an awesome new Resurgence map that only Treyarch can do was some of the way that we thought about it. The spring news is pretty big. So, I think it's going to be nice with Area 99, and then we're going to have big news in the spring, which obviously we have not had that kind of an opportunity in this way."</p><p dir="ltr">"Before you got a big map in the start, but you didn't get one in the spring," Miller continued. "So, I think it's about pacing the experience."</p><p dir="ltr">Our full GameSpot interview with Treyarch can be found below. For more on Black Ops 6, here are all <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/">the announcements for launch-day content</a>. Players can get hands-on with multiplayer during the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-beta-dates-how-to-get-in/1100-6524124/">Black Ops 6 beta</a>, which is live now with week one.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>GameSpot:</strong> <strong>Just looking at the development time, this is the longest development cycle you guys have had. Do you feel like that was more or less pressure, and is there a feature that probably wouldn't have made it into the game if you didn't have this extended time? </strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> We moved from the Treyarch engine to the shared Call of Duty engine. So, part of that time was just getting the core Black Ops experience, rebuilding that from the ground up, and getting multiplayer to feel like Black Ops. That was a huge part of it. And I think with that huge transition of even just the tech change, how we needed to rebuild stuff, but also just all the really talented people at all the studios working on the stuff who came from working on the Treyarch engine to the Call of Duty engine. We were learning all the new tools and all those things. So, that was a big part of it.</p><p dir="ltr">I think the other one there is just like, because of how we rebuilt the stuff. I don't know if omnimovement would have happened the same way, but I don't know if it's specifically because of the time, but I think part of it was because of the fact that we had to wipe the slate clean and start fresh with rebuilding movement from the beginning. And it really forced the team, and this is my perspective, to think of all the pieces that were really important, and that kind of led us down the path of like, well, fluidity is king. Because you're reimplementing only sprint forward. You're like, why does that work that way? Why don't we try this? And you maybe wouldn't have had that [thought process] if you were building from the prior code base.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Is omnimovement something you guys would be open to tweaking later on?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> Probably during the beta and probably beyond, that's probably the reality of it, because we'll try things.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>I think a lot of people were worried that with this new shared engine, Treyarch would maybe lose their signature style, but it definitely still looks like a Black Ops game. Were you guys worried about making the move over?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> It was a focus.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> It was definitely a huge focus. I wouldn't say it was a worry, really. That first year was like, let's get it feeling like a Black Ops game. Then, we started asking ourselves, what does a Black Ops game feel like? So, asking those hard questions and you come up with some really interesting answers, and it really lets you kind of galvanize what is a Black Ops game?</p><p dir="ltr">It was fun. I've worked on every single Black Ops game. Every Black Ops has its own story. And this one was like, oh, we're redefining what it means to be a Black Ops game. So, I'm glad it's come through.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359791-bo6_multiplayer_action_branded2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359791" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359791-bo6_multiplayer_action_branded2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359791"></a><figcaption>Black Ops 6's Rewind multiplayer map</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359791-bo6_multiplayer_action_branded2.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr"><strong>For the Gunsmith, you talked about the global builds, but it seems like a more simplified version of the Gunsmith. Does this mean what we're seeing is what we're getting, or will there be additional features like aftermarket parts, or anything like that coming to the Gunsmith? </strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> I think what you're seeing is what you'll be getting in the beta. We're still working on some things, but you're right that it is a more simplified approach.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Which I don't think it's a bad thing!</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Absolutely not. It was a big goal.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> Intentional.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Every single thing we've done in Black Ops 6 is like, how do we streamline? How do we make it easier to get into? I mean, on the attachments, right? We talked about it. We have almost no cons on our attachments, right? We just want it to always feel great to put an attachment on your weapon. Now, some like a magazine, if you've got a big mag, you're gonna reload a little bit slower, but for the large majority of things, it's just gonna they're like, don't worry about it. What's your play style? Do you want ADS fast? You wanna move fast? Slap that on, put five attachments on, or throw a Wildcard on, go for eight attachments, and just have fun.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>But that's not set in stone, right? That's just what we're seeing for the beta, but you guys might still have other things to change it up?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Yeah, for sure.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Are there any game modes that we haven't seen today that are more centered around the omnimovement? I feel like this would play well with a mode like Blitz or Gridiron. Are there any other modes you can talk about today? </strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Nothing to talk about right now. It's definitely a topic of conversation within the game modes team. And since omnimovement is a big part of Black Ops 6, we feel like it is a part of every game mode, just like you know, the weapons team make sure that it sits well within that world, but specifically movement based game modes and how can we lean into that? And some of the fun post launch stuff, we'll definitely talk about it.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> New seasons will have new maps and modes.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359792-bo6-cod-next-02-mp-0202.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359792" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359792-bo6-cod-next-02-mp-0202.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359792"></a><figcaption>Take opponents hostage and use them as a meat shield in MP and Warzone</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359792-bo6-cod-next-02-mp-0202.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr"><strong>It's so important to have loadouts in battle royale, but if you prestige in Black Ops 6, do you lose your gun and attachment unlocks across all modes, including Warzone?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> You can choose, and you can also choose to protect items.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Yeah, permanent unlock tokens. But yeah, it'll, it'll reset your level 1 to 55 content.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Being four years into Warzone and once Black Ops 6 integrates, what do you plan on doing to keep it fresh content wise?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> So, I think for Ted [Timmins, Warzone Senior Creative Director at Raven Software] and all the folks at Raven, I think some of the big things are quality of life and improving the experience. And they're doing a lot of work looking at loot and even little things like zip lines and ascenders. Just improvements, improvements, improvements. We're excited.</p><p dir="ltr">I think the biggest change to Warzone, frankly, is going to be movement, and that's where a lot of our focus is. Working with that crew [Raven Software] on how we can make sure this stuff all feels right.</p><p dir="ltr">And then taking an intentional pass across all the perks, gear, and all those things. Just because Black Ops 6 stuff is coming, doesn't mean if there's this awesome piece of gear from a previous title or something that it should go away. So, it's like the best of everything.</p><p dir="ltr">The foundational change, though, I think is a big one. Really talking about Season 1, it's movement. Movement is going to be a huge change. And then I think they have a ton of plans, which we can't talk about here, on how to take it forward.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>With Warzone in past years, we've gotten a big map within the integration during Season 1 or Season 1 Reloaded. But it looks like we're getting Verdansk in the spring, and we're keeping Urzikstan. Are we keeping that for the entirety of the time? Is there a reason you can provide for why a new big map isn't coming early on? </strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> I can, I mean, we were heavily focused on Area 99 as the birthplace of Nuketown for Resurgence.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> So, yeah, I think, that has been the focus. Bringing in an awesome new Resurgence map that only Treyarch can do was some of the way that we thought about it. The spring news is pretty big. So, I think it's going to be nice with Area 99, and then we're going to have big news in the spring, which obviously we have not had that kind of an opportunity in this way.</p><p dir="ltr">Before you got a big map in the start, but you didn't get one in the spring. So, I think it's about pacing the experience.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout's three-game Classic Collection is free again on the Epic Store]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallouts-three-game-classic-collection-is-free-again-on-the-epic-store</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallouts-three-game-classic-collection-is-free-again-on-the-epic-store.968739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fallouts-three-game-classic-collection-is-free-again-on-the-epic-store<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>As is Wild Card Football.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-og.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Black Isle Studios/Bethesda</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
As Dame Shirley Bassey once famously <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yzLT6_TQmq8">bellowed</a>, "It's all just a little bit of history repeating". And so it is with this week's Epic Games Store giveaway of the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout">Fallout</a> Classic Collection, which Tim Sweeney previously wafted at storeshop visitors in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-fallout-2-and-fallout-tactics-all-free-from-the-epic-games-store">December 2022</a> and February this year.
</p>
<p>
For those who didn't grab it previously, the good news is there's some <em>neato</em> stuff in the Fallout Classic Collection. You get, for instance, the game that started it all - Black Isle Studios' original 1997 post-apocalyptic RPG, Fallout - plus its 1998 sequel. Both, of course, are bona fide classics, and Eurogamer sang their praises as part of a retrospective back in 2011.
</p>
<p>
"From the unrelentingly bleak, darkly ironic tone to the novelty of the open-world, post-apocalyptic setting," Keza MacDonald <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-retrospective-article">wrote</a>, "from the inspired, cerebral turn-based combat system to the immense degree of variety and personality in the character-customisation, the superbly-written quests and characters and the gallows humour that underpins the games without lessening their emotional impact, even the well-placed, gritty violence; there's very little about the games that doesn't command as much respect now as they did a decade ago."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="18 things you didn't know about Fallout 1 &amp; 2" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iRA37myO-zE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>18 things you didn't know about Fallout 1 &amp; 2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iRA37myO-zE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/iRA37myO-zE?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>18 things you didn't know about Fallout 1 &amp; 2.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iRA37myO-zE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
As for the Fallout Classic Collection's third game, 2001's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-tactics-brotherhood-of-steel">Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</a>, it's less widely revered, but still solidly enjoyable, introducing squad-based combat action to the isometric wasteland of its illustrious RPG predecessors. That, though, isn't <em>quite</em> everything Epic is giving away this week, and its full list of freebies looks something like this:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Fallout 1</li>
<li>Fallout 2</li>
<li>Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</li>
<li>Wild Card Football</li>
</ul>
<p>
That last one, if it's previously managed to pass you by (I, also, was unfamiliar), comes from Saber Interactive, and is described as a "fun pick-up-and-play arcade-style football game featuring 7v7 team-focused gameplay with the unique Wild Card system that lets you change the course of the action in an instant with special power-ups and rule-breaking abilities."
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/wild-card-football">Wild Card Football</a> and the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/bundles/fallout-classic-collection">Fallout Classic Collection</a> can be permanently added to your Epic Games Store library for zero pee right now until next Thursday, 5th September. At which point Football Manager 2024 and Sniper Ghost Warrior will stumble blinking into the freebie arena, waiting to be snapped up by curious hands.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Ubisoft's Once-Popular FPS Is Running Out Of Time]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xdefiant-ubisoft-months-season-3-low-playercount-pc-ps5-1851637209</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-ubisofts-once-popular-fps-is-running-out-of-time.968709/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/xdefiant-ubisoft-months-season-3-low-playercount-pc-ps5-1851637209<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ubisoft’s big <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xdefiant-open-beta-review-call-of-duty-black-ops-test-1850568211&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xdefiant-open-beta-review-call-of-duty-black-ops-test-1850568211"><em>Call of Duty</em>-like FPS, <em>XDefiant</em></a></span>, might only have until Season 3 to turn things around, increase its player count, and start making more money or the publisher could end post-launch updates and effectively kill the FPS. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196049" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="134" data-playlist="196049,196406,196653" data-current="196049"><div><p>This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21580.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Developed by Ubisoft San Francisco,<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-new-fps-xdefiant-servers-matchmaking-ps5-pc-1851492107&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-new-fps-xdefiant-servers-matchmaking-ps5-pc-1851492107"><em>XDefiant </em>finally launched in May</a></span> for consoles and PC following numerous delays and a well-received beta. Ubisoft’s <em>Call of Duty</em>-like free-to-play shooter came out of the gate with big player numbers, good reviews, and a solid amount of content. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xdefiant-review-is-it-good-free-call-of-duty-ubisoft-1851499598&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xdefiant-review-is-it-good-free-call-of-duty-ubisoft-1851499598">I really enjoyed the game</a></span> as it provided me with a fast-paced arena shooter, but didn’t take up 200 GB of space on my console. But now, a few months later, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xdefiant-ubisoft-bunny-hopping-balance-maps-interview-1851540682&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xdefiant-ubisoft-bunny-hopping-balance-maps-interview-1851540682"><em>XDefiant</em></a></span> is reportedly bleeding players and Ubisoft has set a deadline for things to improve or it could be over the shooter. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On August 30, <em>Insider Gaming</em> reported</a></span> that Ubisoft execs had started to sour on <em>XDefiant</em>. At first, the publisher <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-says-xdefiant-helped-with-early-2024-financial-success/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-says-xdefiant-helped-with-early-2024-financial-success/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">praised</a></span> the game’s success and revenue, but now it reportedly isn’t happy with the shrinking playerbase and profits. According to <em>Insider Gaming</em>, <em>XDefiant </em>has until season 3, which is likely to arrive in November, to improve things or Ubisoft will stop supporting the game with updates and new content. </p><p>It’s reported that the game has been struggling to reach 20,000 concurrent players across all platforms. Another source told <em>Insider Gaming</em> that Ubisoft “would probably be happy” with that number, which seems to imply that the current number of players is even lower. </p><p>Due to the low player count and Ubisoft’s deadlines and concerns, some within Ubisoft San Fran are worried about layoffs. The publisher already laid off some San Fran employees <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-cuts-45-jobs-across-cary-and-san-francisco-teams&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-cuts-45-jobs-across-cary-and-san-francisco-teams" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">earlier this month</a></span>. </p><p><em>Kotaku </em>has contacted Ubisoft about the report. </p><p>Some staff blamed the leaders of the studio for not taking responsibility and working to improve the company’s workplace culture. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://insider-gaming.com/behind-xdefiant-toxic-work-culture-crunch-and-years-of-delays/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://insider-gaming.com/behind-xdefiant-toxic-work-culture-crunch-and-years-of-delays/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As previously reported by <em>Insider Gaming</em> in March</a></span>, some employees claimed that a small group of people at the studio—known as “The Boys Club”—were making bad decisions, giving certain friends more power, and treating employees poorly. It’s suggested that this group led to the game being delayed multiple times. </p><p>The plan now is to focus on Season 3 in the hopes of turning things around for <em>XDefiant</em>. However, Season 3 will be landing around the time <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-direct-everything-we-know-1851531121&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-direct-everything-we-know-1851531121"><em>Black Ops 6</em></a></span> hits consoles and PC. Sources told the outlet that they aren’t feeling too good about the game or the studio’s future. </p><p>One source reportedly said: “Expect more Ubisoft San Fran layoff headlines within six months.”<br></p><p> .</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive: Meet Showa American Story’s New Boss Character, Texan Samurai-Cowboy Gokou]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/exclusive-meet-showa-american-storys-new-boss-character-texan-samurai-cowboy-gokou</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-meet-showa-american-story%E2%80%99s-new-boss-character-texan-samurai-cowboy-gokou.968703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/exclusive-meet-showa-american-storys-new-boss-character-texan-samurai-cowboy-gokou<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">That is some impressive chest hair.</h2></div><section><p>When Showa American Story was first announced in 2022, its reveal trailer depicting a parallel 1991 in which the United States had become a colony of Japan went viral, <a href="https://youtu.be/9zpJ8Uw9fh0?si=6pSEEkRI1kKHfu48" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>with nearly half a million views on IGN’s YouTube channel</u></a> alone. It has been a year since the last update via <a href="https://jp.ign.com/showa-beikoku-monogatari/70327/interview/1st" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>an interview with IGN Japan</u></a>. Chinese developer Nekcom has since pushed back the game’s release, switched development from Unreal Engine 4 to 5, and devoted additional time and resources in order to meet gamers’ intense expectations. </p><p>Now, in a fresh interview with Creative Director XY.Luo, IGN can exclusively reveal a brand new boss character and several new screenshots that show how work is progressing on this fascinating new game.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/30/nekcom-sas-screenshot-09-ign-japan-1725035189295.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Meet Gokou, an American politician with blonde hair and a muscular chest covered in beastly chair. Image Source: </figcaption></figure></output><p>Gokou is the impressive new boss that players will face at some point in their adventure. This American politician has blonde hair and a muscular chest covered in beastly hair, and harbours a treacherous past.</p><p>“Gokou is a character who is a mix of an American cowboy and a Japanese samurai,” explains Luo. “Although he is American, he is deeply knowledgeable about Japanese culture, and when you fight him, you will notice he pulls from both Eastern and Western cultures in his combat style.”</p><p>Luo continues, “While I cannot go into detail yet about the techniques Gokou uses in battle, he is closely connected with the background story of the game. He’s not the final boss or the overarching villain, but in our alternate history, Gokou is the Governor of Texas, and it was him who sold the land of Texas to Japan.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>In our alternate history, Gokou is the Governor of Texas, and it was him who sold the land of Texas to Japan</p></div><p>While Gokou’s character model appears almost photorealistic, and development has included some photogrammetry, Luo explains that Gokou and most of the other main characters were initially hand-drawn, before being converted to 3D and added to the game. “Gokou’s design was inspired by a certain famous 1980s American rock star,” hints Luo. “Whether each character is created by hand or based on a 3D facial model, we take care to make sure they express realism. Since our development team is small – just 26 members – we are outsourcing some of the asset creation.”</p><p>Indeed, you can see from our exclusive set of new screenshots that the visual quality of the game has markedly improved since it was first revealed. Luo says that development is proceeding “as planned”, with his team aiming to achieve the quality they had first envisioned. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Show American Story - Exclusive Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>“With over two years of hard work by our incredible development team since the first trailer was revealed, and upgrading the game engine from Unreal Engine 4 to Unreal Engine 5, the game looks much more solid, including the graphics,” says Luo, “However, compared to a large development team, I must say Showa American Story is not a AAA game, but I believe that it will exceed players’ expectations when it comes out.”</p><p>Showa American Story follows protagonist Chouko, a teenage action stuntwoman mysteriously revived from the dead, as she fights her way through hordes of monsters and zombies in a postapocalyptic 1980s United States that has been colonized by Japan. Heavily influenced by B-movies and American and Japanese pop-culture, the game is currently in development for PlayStation 5 and PC. The release date is still tbc.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p><em></em><a href="https://x.com/NoMoreDaniels" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><em>Daniel Robson</em></u></a><em> is Chief Editor of IGN Japan, and </em><a href="https://x.com/ryuichi_kataoka" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><em>Ryuichi Kataoka</em></u></a><em> is a freelance writer for IGN Japan</em>
</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This New Tamagotchi Is Totally Egg-Cellent, Because That's What It's Made Of]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-new-tamagotchi-is-totally-egg-cellent-because-thats-what-its-made-of/1100-6526215/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-new-tamagotchi-is-totally-egg-cellent-because-thats-what-its-made-of.968697/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-new-tamagotchi-is-totally-egg-cellent-because-thats-what-its-made-of/1100-6526215/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526215">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Bandai Namco will release a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DCWNNNSC?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tamagotchi Original</a> next year that not only looks like an egg, but actually contains recycled eggshells. That's not all, either. The packaging for the device--featuring the programming from the 1990s--will be made with recycled paper when it comes out February 5, 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">Earlier this year, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bandai-namco-revives-popular-tamagotchi-connection-virtual-pets-for-20th-anniversary/1100-6523459/" data-ref-id="1100-6523459">Tamagotchi Connection was revived to celebrate its 20th anniversary</a>. This device was the evolved version of the original Tamagotchi and let owners link up with each other. Players can even have their digital pets get married, so this planet-friendly Tamagotchi Original isn't the first time Bandai Namco has capitalized on nostalgia.</p><p dir="ltr">But Bandai Namco also has a new line of Tamagotchi, too. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-tamagotchi-uni-reinvents-your-childhood-with-wi-fi/1100-6514872/" data-ref-id="1100-6514872">The Tamagotchi Uni was launched last year</a> and features online connectivity. It also comes with a wrist strap, making the device resemble a watch.</p><p dir="ltr">Tamagotchi originally released in Japan in 1996 before arriving in the US in 1997. Bandai Namco notes that roughly 91 million Tamagotchi devices have been sold as of March 2023.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Astro Bot Trailer Showcases His Abilities]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-astro-bot-trailer-showcases-his-abilities/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-astro-bot-trailer-showcases-his-abilities.968682/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-astro-bot-trailer-showcases-his-abilities/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The <a href="https://wccftech.com/astro-bot-length/">Astro Bot game</a> isn't far away, with a release date of September 6, 2024. Players can expect plenty of references from previous PlayStation games, allowing them to get heavily involved in the nostalgia of previous consoles. Today, Sony Interactive Entertainment released the first of five trailers in the series 'Behind the Scenes of ASTRO BOT.'</p>
<p>In addition to the trailer, a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/08/30/meet-astro-bots-new-monkey-friend-and-go-behind-the-scenes-with-team-asobi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">brand new blog</a> on the PlayStation website written by Nicolas Doucet, the Studio Head of Team Asobi, unveils the new trailer and showcases some of the features that players can expect to see in the game.</p>
<p><iframe title="Astro Bot - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/unYFdcEjV9k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The trailer is just two minutes long but showcases a lot of the fast-paced gameplay that people can expect from the upcoming Astro Bot game. One of the main features that will appear is a monkey that attaches to Astro's back and has long arms that allow Astro to climb, swing, and use giant hand slams to attack enemies and complete puzzles.</p>
<p>The Muteki armor set is also revealed, which allows Astro to roll around in spiky areas without taking damage, fit inside tight spaces, or be blasted through the air like a cannonball. Last of all, players will be able to use the Muteki armor to become the size of a mouse, allowing players to explore the world through the eyes of a very tiny creature.</p>
<p>In total, there are 300 bots that players can rescue worldwide, all serving their purpose to assist Astro in their own way. Out of the 300 bots, 150 of them are PlayStation cameos, allowing you to see little robots dressed up and styled to look like famous characters from previous franchises. The cameo bots will reenact moments from their respective games, allowing those who are playing Astro Bot to get a hit of nostalgia and remember all of the good times they've had with PlayStation.</p>
<p>This trailer and blog post combined also answer a lot of burning questions for those who want to know more about Astro Bot and his hero powers. Throughout your journey in the game, you will be able to use powers such as utilizing Kratos' Axe in a specific level tailored to the God of War franchise.</p>
<p>There are plenty more Hero powers that Astro will get to use throughout the game,&nbsp; but as the blog post says, it's being kept under wraps right now so that players will get to experience it as it's "one of the nicest features to discover yourselves."</p>
<p>In addition to the trailer and the blog post, a new Behind the Scenes series for Astro Bot has been announced. The first episode will be released today. It's only two minutes long but showcases some of the work that went into crafting the game play.</p>
<p><iframe title="Astro Bot - Behind The Scenes Series EP1: Crafted Gameplay | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aH0haX-5iZ8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In this episode, members of Team Asobi speak about what goes into the gameplay of Astro Bot to make it feel as smooth. In the short interview, they spoke about how they faced various challenges when making the game as smooth as possible and how making the game feel good was incredibly important. By making it feel good to play as well as good to watch, as "that is the difference between a good game and a great game," as said by Nicolas Doucet.</p>
<p>When asked what the most important thing is when creating a platformer, Hironori Yatoku, Lead Game Designer replied, "Tempo. You create your own melody through the rhythm of the movements." Adding on to that statement Masayuki Yamada, the Lead Gameplay Programmer. He believes that reactions are the most important thing: "I think it is most important when you press a button, the game reacts instantly. And if you knock the stick the other way, the right thing should happen."</p>
<p>Astro Bot is set for release on September 6, 2024. More Behind the Scenes videos will showcase the development process behind this upcoming PlayStation exclusive.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Borderlands movie hides its best ideas under painful jokes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/30/24232389/borderlands-movie-review-interview-video-on-demand</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-borderlands-movie-hides-its-best-ideas-under-painful-jokes.968679/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/30/24232389/borderlands-movie-review-interview-video-on-demand<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><p>The <em>Borderlands</em> movie, which released in theaters all of 21 days ago, <a href="https://gizmodo.com/borderlands-movie-streaming-release-date-vod-eli-roth-lionsgate-2000491551">is already available to watch at home</a> through video on demand. This three-week turnaround could be indicative of the movie’s <a href="https://variety.com/2024/film/box-office/box-office-it-ends-with-us-beats-exectations-borderlands-flops-1236103106/">poor box office performance</a> coupled with its <a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/borderlands-review-a-total-catastrophe.html">poor</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/article/2024/aug/11/borderlands-review-cate-blanchett-stalks-her-way-through-a-disastrous-video-game-adaptation-eli-roth">critical</a> <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/08/10/the-borderlands-movie-debuts-with-a-0-on-rotten-tomatoes/">reception</a>. After seeing it for myself, I agree it’s not the best example of a video game movie. However, I also saw moments where the movie took its source material and remixed it into something entertaining. Whether you watch this movie in theaters, at home, or not at all, <em>Borderlands </em>deserves your respect.</p><p>Part of that is because honestly, the movie isn’t <em>that</em> bad. It’s visually impressive, with gorgeous styling and action sequences that were actually intelligible instead of greasy-looking smears of CG. It has a bog standard found family / magical MacGuffin plot that manages to say something interesting about the whole “chosen one” trope.&nbsp;</p><p>Cate Blanchett stars as Lilith, a bounty hunter who travels to the planet Pandora to rescue a girl named Tina (Ariana Greenblatt) from the clutches of Roland, a Crimson Lance soldier gone rogue (Kevin Hart) and his psycho accomplice — movie’s description, not mine — Krieg (Florian Munteanu). Lilith discovers that Tina went willingly with her captors and with the unhelpful help of the robot Claptrap (voiced by Jack Black) and the expertise of Dr. Patricia Tanis (Jamie Lee Curtis), Lilith decides to help Tina acquire a powerful artifact to keep it out of the hands of her disgustingly wealthy father, Deukalian Atlas (Edgar Ramírez), CEO of the Atlas Corporation.</p><div><p>“[Borderlands] isn’t a video game movie.”</p></div><p>Pandora is a harsh desert planet marred by prodigious amounts of waste from both its human and natural inhabitants. If the movie<em> </em>followed the trends currently dominating television and film, the planet would look dark even in the daytime, and everything would be cast in the sickly orange filter Hollywood trots out every time there’s a movie set in a desert — looking at you, <em>Dune</em>. Instead, locations and characters are thoughtfully designed — and adequately lit, imagine that! — making for a movie that is visually pleasing to watch.</p><p>I was thoroughly taken aback by how good Cate Blanchett looked as Lilith. With her bright orange hair and deep blue sparkly jacket, Blanchett looked like she had been ripped directly out of the first <em>Borderlands</em> game. When Lilith made her first appearance, I turned to my husband and remarked that this is the most video game looking-ass video game movie I’ve ever seen (affectionate!). Everything else, from the rest of the cast to the props and sets, matched that visual energy without looking cartoonish or fake.</p><div><figcaption><em>Blanchett looks great and performs even better as Lilith.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Photo: Lionsgate</cite></p></div><p><em>Borderlands</em>, for good or ill, eschewed some of the typical conventions for making a video game movie. Usually, there’s some moment in these kinds of films that functions as a nod to its progenitor. The first-person action sequence in <em>Doom</em> or the Rainbow Road race in <em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em> come to mind.</p><p>In an interview with Randy Pitchford, creator of the <em>Borderlands</em> games and the film’s executive producer, I asked how he blurred the line between game and film. “We didn’t do any of that,” Pitchford answered. “I hate that shit.”&nbsp;</p><p>According to Pitchford, originally there were plans to make him the movie’s Easter egg for fans of the game, but seeing another video game movie made him change his mind.</p><div><p>“We didn’t do any of that. I hate that shit.”&nbsp;</p></div><p>“I voice a character in the games named <a href="https://borderlands.fandom.com/wiki/Crazy_Earl">Crazy Earl</a>, and I did five hours of makeup to become Crazy Earl,” he said. Pitchford said that he shot scenes for the movie but had a change of heart after seeing the moment in <em>Uncharted</em> when Mark Wahlberg and Tom Holland randomly run into Nolan North, the voice actor who plays Nathan Drake in the games.&nbsp;</p><p>“There were two problems with that,” he said. “If you know who that is, you’re immediately pulled out of the universe. And if you don’t know, none of that makes any sense. It’s a complete non-sequitur to the storyline, so I asked them to cut me from the movie.”</p><p>According to Pitchford,<em> Borderlands</em> “isn’t a video game movie.” Rather, he says, it’s a movie that incorporates the characters, themes, and storylines from the first game, which have been greatly enhanced by stand-out performances from Blanchett and Greenblatt.</p><p>Lilith and Tina play well off each other. Neither has a loving family to speak of and is so desperate for one that they latch on to anyone and anything that comes within their orbit. Tina immediately adopts Kreig as her older brother / bodyguard. And despite the fact that Claptrap and Lilith hate each other, they still worked well together.</p><div><figcaption><em>The infamous pee scene.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Lionsgate</cite></p></div><p>The dialogue, though, didn’t work so well. Make no mistake: <em>Borderlands</em> isn’t funny. Its style of irreverent humor and stream-of-consciousness dialogue stopped being entertaining around the time <em>Tales for the Borderlands</em> came out in 2014. Hearing Kevin Hart deadpan, “It’s pee. Now I got pee all in the middle of my truck,” made me white knuckle my armrests to keep me from scratching out my eyes.&nbsp;</p><p>The movie also didn’t make good use of its ensemble cast. Take Dr. Patricia Tanis, for example. In the movie, she’s just a plot exposition vehicle, but she could have been much more. According to Tanis’ actress, Jamie Lee Curtis, she brought herself into the role of the reclusive, socially awkward doctor and her attraction to inanimate objects — but that didn’t make it into the final film.</p><p>“The whole idea of objective sexuality — the idea of an isolated person falling in love with inanimate objects — I find it a fascinating character trait and played the shit out of it,” Curtis said. “And they cut it all because, I think, people just wouldn’t understand it.”</p><p>Lilith and Tina are the main drivers of the film, but the rest of the cast did absolutely nothing until the plot gave them something to shoot, smash, or exposit. I don’t understand how a movie that has both Jack Black and Kevin Hart — two of the most successful comedians in Hollywood — didn’t make me laugh. On top of being woefully miscast as the stoic soldier Roland, Hart was simply window dressing. The movie gave him a big hero moment similar to the one in <em>Borderlands 2</em>, but since he had no personality beyond “There’s pee in my truck,” I didn’t care. Meanwhile, it seemed like the only direction Black got was to be as annoying as possible. Fitting for his character, sure, but ultimately a waste of Black’s manifold talents.</p><p>Paying $20–25 to watch <em>Borderlands</em> at home is a tough sell but ultimately worth it. For all the bad decisions in <em>Borderlands</em>, putting Lilith at its center was by far its smartest. Characters like her — cranky, jaded, childless, older women — do not lead action films. And in real life, women like that are all but invisible. But <em>Borderlands</em>, in its styling and storytelling, made Lilith pop off the screen. You couldn’t miss her if you tried. <em>Borderlands </em>earned its poor reception, but for what it does with Lilith, it’s also earned my respect.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shadow, Amy's Absence, And More The Internet Can't Stop Talking About From The Sonic 3 Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-movie-trailer-reaction-keanu-reeves-shadow-amy-1851637185</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadow-amys-absence-and-more-the-internet-cant-stop-talking-about-from-the-sonic-3-trailer.968676/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-movie-trailer-reaction-keanu-reeves-shadow-amy-1851637185<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="5e57a414ee181ed043f466ab6b50b5da" data-recommend-id="image://5e57a414ee181ed043f466ab6b50b5da" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow looks over his shoulder." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shadow looks over his shoulder." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="5e57a414ee181ed043f466ab6b50b5da" data-recommend-id="image://5e57a414ee181ed043f466ab6b50b5da" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow looks over his shoulder." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Don’t ask me how many times I’ve watched the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-3-first-trailer-keanu-reeves-shadow-1851632082&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-3-first-trailer-keanu-reeves-shadow-1851632082">first trailer for <em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3</em></a></span>, the third entry in Paramount’s live-action adaptation of the life and times of Sega’s speedy mascot. Don’t ask me if I just watched it again after typing that sentence. While the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-3-movie-trailer-shadow-paramount-1851483101&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-3-movie-trailer-shadow-paramount-1851483101">wait was excruciating</a></span>, fans’ reactions to the first three minutes of footage from the upcoming live-action adaptation have been pretty much universally positive. It’s still a few months before the movie premieres on December 20, but with nearly 20 million views <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/SonicMovie/status/1828417645202329922&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/SonicMovie/status/1828417645202329922" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on Twitter alone</a></span>, the first trailer has been a viral sensation all its own.<br></p><p>Let’s break down some of the big talking points coming out of the first trailer.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="c3ad075fbfbd513811a4889504d6aa34" data-recommend-id="image://c3ad075fbfbd513811a4889504d6aa34" data-format="jpg" data-width="1024" data-height="576" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow glares at something beneath him." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shadow glares at something beneath him." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c3ad075fbfbd513811a4889504d6aa34" data-recommend-id="image://c3ad075fbfbd513811a4889504d6aa34" data-format="jpg" data-width="1024" data-height="576" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow glares at something beneath him." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Ever since we found out that <em>The Matrix </em>star <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-shadow-keanu-reeves-reaction-1851414208&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-shadow-keanu-reeves-reaction-1851414208">Keanu Reeves would be voicing Shadow the Hedgehog</a></span>, the blue blur’s rival and the antagonist of the third movie, fans have been waiting to hear what he would sound like. And he sounds like the most broody version of Reeves you can imagine, but it also works with the enigmatic, dangerous version of Shadow we see in the trailer.</p><p>What we’ve seen thus far feels like a happy medium between the theatrical villain he was in <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em> and the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-dark-beginnings-anime-expo-1851580851&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-dark-beginnings-anime-expo-1851580851">boorish loner he’s become as of late</a></span>. However, that drama comes through in his mannerisms and the stylish way he fights. Skeptics are leaving the trailer as believers. However, some folks want to hear the full breadth of his performance and feel like they were expecting Reeves to put on more of a “voice.” This has been a contentious discussion point surrounding films like the <em>Super Mario Bros. Movie</em>, which notoriously had actors like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-chris-pratt-jack-black-bowser-1850280964&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-chris-pratt-jack-black-bowser-1850280964">Chris Pratt</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-seth-rogen-donkey-kong-voice-1850293751&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-seth-rogen-donkey-kong-voice-1850293751">Seth Rogan</a></span> speaking basically just like themselves. But I’d argue Reeves’ delivery fits Shadow more than those actors fit Mario and Donkey Kong.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a75f05768fd466e3152ca3221b759a3f" data-recommend-id="image://a75f05768fd466e3152ca3221b759a3f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1767" data-height="994" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow and Maria look at each other through glass." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shadow and Maria look at each other through glass." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a75f05768fd466e3152ca3221b759a3f" data-recommend-id="image://a75f05768fd466e3152ca3221b759a3f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1767" data-height="994" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow and Maria look at each other through glass." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Shadow is the focus of much of the trailer, and that includes a look at his tragic backstory. In <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em>, Shadow’s path of destruction begins after the death of Maria Robotnik, a young girl who Shadow was created to save from a life-threatening illness. Maria will be portrayed by <em>Furiosa </em>actor Alyla Browne, and based on the trailer, it looks like she will meet a similar fate in the film. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-movie-shadow-maria-death-actor-1851227374&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-movie-shadow-maria-death-actor-1851227374">Fans are (jokingly) excited</a></span>, but some also hope that the jokes don’t make their way into the theater, because hearing a bunch of people cheering as a child dies on-screen would not capture the somber tone of the scene.<br></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="6f98191c30c27b269f0410495d2e53a0" data-recommend-id="image://6f98191c30c27b269f0410495d2e53a0" data-format="jpg" data-width="806" data-height="453" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic, Tails, and Knuckles race." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sonic, Tails, and Knuckles race." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6f98191c30c27b269f0410495d2e53a0" data-recommend-id="image://6f98191c30c27b269f0410495d2e53a0" data-format="jpg" data-width="806" data-height="453" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic, Tails, and Knuckles race." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>While Reeves has been mostly praised for his portrayal of Shadow thus far, a big point of contention surrounding <em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3</em> is that we’re three movies in and none of the women in the <em>Sonic </em>series have made an appearance yet. There was a lot of speculation ahead of the movie’s proper unveiling that Rouge the Bat, the treasure-hunting spy who works with Shadow in <em>Sonic Adventure 2,</em> may make her live-action debut in the film, but there’s no sign of her in the first trailer. Amy Rose, the hammer-swinging hero who also has a pretty significant role in <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em>, is also nowhere to be seen. Though the movies have been gradually introducing Sonic’s anthropomorphic crew rather than dumping them all into the series at once, the lack of two major players and the obvious gender disparity is bumming fans out. Some are keeping hope alive, however, and theorize Amy may have been edited out of the trailer to surprise fans at a later date.<br></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="ab23b76aadc9c39d5f21ed76b83cf028" data-recommend-id="image://ab23b76aadc9c39d5f21ed76b83cf028" data-format="jpg" data-width="1123" data-height="632" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow throws a punch." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shadow throws a punch." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ab23b76aadc9c39d5f21ed76b83cf028" data-recommend-id="image://ab23b76aadc9c39d5f21ed76b83cf028" data-format="jpg" data-width="1123" data-height="632" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow throws a punch." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>So much happens in the <em>Sonic 3 </em>trailer that it feels like dozens of in-jokes have already sprouted up just from these three minutes of footage. This has ranged from putting exaggerated screams into footage of Shadow absolutely owning Knuckles to making edits of the villain’s chaos and destruction. The jokes are good, and the trailer also added to a longstanding meme of Shadow beating up Sonic’s best friend Tails, as he once again lays out the two-tailed fox in another continuity.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="0c6fa973f00f1c0dab98feed788a2235" data-recommend-id="image://0c6fa973f00f1c0dab98feed788a2235" data-format="jpg" data-width="2843" data-height="1600" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Robotnik puts one of Sonic's quills in his mouth." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Robotnik puts one of Sonic's quills in his mouth." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0c6fa973f00f1c0dab98feed788a2235" data-recommend-id="image://0c6fa973f00f1c0dab98feed788a2235" data-format="jpg" data-width="2843" data-height="1600" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Robotnik puts one of Sonic's quills in his mouth." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The jokes are all well and good, but fans are looking for any clue about what’s coming from the trailer, and some theories seem pretty plausible. One scene shows Sonic giving Jim Carrey’s Doctor Robotnik one of his superpowered quills, and fans are already speculating this could be used to create his <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-trailer-robotnik-metal-quill-theory-ending-1851634404&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-trailer-robotnik-metal-quill-theory-ending-1851634404">synthetic doppelganger Metal Sonic</a></span>. While that’s a fun theory, there are also less fun ones sprouting up around possible death flags. One scene shows James Marsden’s Tom Wachowski, the human lead of the live-action movies, shouting for Sonic during what appears to be one of Shadow’s rampages. These movies haven’t shied away from death, as Sonic, Knuckles, and Shadow each have tragic backstories, but this might be the first time the movies kill off a main character. If Tom kicks the bucket, it would be thematically in-line with the topics of grief the movie is wrestling with.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="2fb9013535d1eb7d89168226567c1c34" data-recommend-id="image://2fb9013535d1eb7d89168226567c1c34" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="675" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow does the Akira motorcycle slide." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shadow does the Akira motorcycle slide." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2fb9013535d1eb7d89168226567c1c34" data-recommend-id="image://2fb9013535d1eb7d89168226567c1c34" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="675" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow does the Akira motorcycle slide." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Theory-crafting, jokes, and critique are great, but what I love most about big blowouts like this is how they inspire creativity within the community. The trailer is full of moments that have already been beautifully recreated by fan artists, as well as fans taking some scenes and running with them. This one of baby Sonic making the chalk drawings shown of him and Longclaw is one of my favorites.<br></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1cdc04ce6a920f26f3c9e1d83af5f356" data-recommend-id="image://1cdc04ce6a920f26f3c9e1d83af5f356" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="672" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic and Tails flying a helicopter." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sonic and Tails flying a helicopter." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1cdc04ce6a920f26f3c9e1d83af5f356" data-recommend-id="image://1cdc04ce6a920f26f3c9e1d83af5f356" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="672" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic and Tails flying a helicopter." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The hype for <em>Sonic 3 </em>is real, but seeing so much love outpouring for the movie is dizzying considering how the original draft for the live-action Sonic looked much, much worse. It’s been <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-movie-first-trailer-ugly-design-delay-redesign-1851446390&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-movie-first-trailer-ugly-design-delay-redesign-1851446390">five years since the horrendous original trailer</a></span> broke the internet and nearly ended the live-action franchise before it started. Now, we’re only a few months away from seeing a much better-looking Sonic face off against Shadow. It’s nice to live in the timeline where that crisis was avoided, but fans decided to remind us what Shadow could have looked like if someone didn’t grab hold of the steering wheel.<br></p><p><em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 </em>arrives in theaters on December 20. For more on the trailer, check out our <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-shadow-gerald-trailer-explained-1851632861&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-shadow-gerald-trailer-explained-1851632861">extensive breakdown</a></span> of everything we saw.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Romantic Dinner For You And Your Cat Is Up For Grabs, Thanks To Gori: Cuddly Carnage]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-romantic-dinner-for-you-and-your-cat-is-up-for-grabs-thanks-to-gori-cuddly-carnage/1100-6526213/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-romantic-dinner-for-you-and-your-cat-is-up-for-grabs-thanks-to-gori-cuddly-carnage.968673/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-romantic-dinner-for-you-and-your-cat-is-up-for-grabs-thanks-to-gori-cuddly-carnage/1100-6526213/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526213">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The indie action game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gori-cuddly-carnage-lets-you-wage-war-on-angry-toys-as-a-badass-cat/1100-6509276/" data-ref-id="1100-6509276">Gori: Cuddly Carnage</a> is out this week and it allows players to assume the role of an anthropomorphic cat who is in conflict with mutant toys. To promote the game, Gori's publisher, Wired Productions, is offering players a chance to win "Tinner 4 Two," so they can share a "romantic" dinner with their cat.</p><p>Wired Productions, Community Manager Steve Williamson made the offer on social media to fans who share the message, follow the company, and reply by quoting a specific Gori review from Steam.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1373394256" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465021,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Gori%3A%20Cuddly%20Carnage%20%7C%20Gameplay%20Launch%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:86,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/gori-cuddly-carnage-gameplay-launch-trailer\/2300-6465021\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465021\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465021\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465021\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465021&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465021,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526213&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;gori-cuddly-carnage&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,platformer&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,nintendo-switch,xbox-series-x,xbox-one,playstation-5,playstation-4&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;wired-productions,h2-interactive-co-ltd&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465021},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465021\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4359027-33.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/FprRFZ8b.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724941080,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="FprRFZ8b" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Gori: Cuddly Carnage | Gameplay Launch Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Tinner 4 Two is a joke collectible that Wired Productions <a href="https://shop.wiredproductions.com/products/tinner-4-two?srsltid=AfmBOopJ6gv6hmaWVLfYlV8vPAJaMtvjZh80-r0wBZwZqgbyXzr_lFB7" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">offered for sale on its site</a> that combines cat food and spaghetti. However, it's not an actual blend of the two. The final product actually has two different tins joined together, one for the cat food and one for the spaghetti. A writer for <a href="https://www.the-sun.com/tech/12311281/gori-cuddly-carnage-tinner4two/amp/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Sun</a> sampled it and described the spaghetti as "inedible." So perhaps this is one collectible that's better left in the can.</p><p>Plus, as anyone who has ever owned a cat can attest, felines tend to prefer to be left alone while eating their own food. But if you ever dare to dine on something that a cat might enjoy--such as any meat product--then suddenly your furry companion won't leave you alone. So the idea of any "romantic" meal with a cat was always doomed from the start.</p><p>Gori: Cuddly Carnage is available on all consoles and PC. There's also a demo, if you want to try it before buying it.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>