<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 12:34:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem Will Be a ‘Complete Rollercoaster Ride’ Like Never Before in the Series, Says CAPCOM]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-complete-rollercoaster-ride-never-before/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-requiem-will-be-a-%E2%80%98complete-rollercoaster-ride%E2%80%99-like-never-before-in-the-series-says-capcom.1283865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Aside from Grand Theft Auto VI, which was not featured at Gamescom 2025, Resident Evil Requiem is undoubtedly among the most hyped upcoming titles, and the German convention confirmed it. The first public hands-on of the ninth mainline chapter in CAPCOM's horror franchise convinced press and fans alike, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/gamescom-2025-awards-resident-evil-requiem-capcom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">evidenced by the many Gamescom awards won</a>.</p>



<p>During Gamescom, CAPCOM also discussed Resident Evil Requiem in greater depth throughout a few interviews. For example, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tooB3GgtU8Y" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speaking with Gamesradar</a>, Game Director Koshi Nakanishi explained that the new game will feel like a complete rollercoaster ride thanks to much greater extremes when it comes to all the classic Resident Evil elements of horror, tension, action, and release.</p>



<p><em>I think the two recent titles, Resident Evil 4 remake and Village, are more on the action side of the series in terms of the mixture of elements that they have. Resident Evil Requiem is something different. If I had to compare it to past titles, it's more along the lines of Resident Evil 7 or the Resident Evil 2 remake. You could call it old school Resident Evil, you know, with exploration and backtracking and that kind of thing. It does, of course, feature all the classic core pillars of Resident Evil features that everyone knows and loves, such as combat, exploration, puzzle solving, resource management of limited number of items, and we've given it our own spin this time for Resident Evil Requiem's game atmosphere.</em></p>



<p><em>Speaking then to Resident Evil 7 and 2, I think they reflect a typical game design that we have for this series, where you can't keep the horror tension to the max through the whole game, because it's quite exhausting. So, you need to have this dynamic pacing curve where you'll have a a very tense, horrific sequence, and then we give you a bit of a release or a catharsis from that and let you come down from that with more slightly peaceful exploration or some exciting comba,t and then we gradually bring you back up the horror part of the curve.</em></p>



<p><em>Again, that's the standard practice for Resident Evil. The difference this time is there's a new system that I can't quite get into yet, but if you think of the difference between the tension and the release being a certain size of wavelength, as it were, of that curve, I want to make the distance between those aspects bigger than ever before in the series, and it just becomes a complete roller coaster ride between the different aspects of the series. I'm very excited for people to eventually understand what I mean by that.</em></p>



<p>Resident Evil Requiem is scheduled to launch on February 27, 2026 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X. On PC, the game <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-supported-175-games-resident-evil-requiem-path-tracing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">will support path tracing</a> (the first RE Engine title to do so) and NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-complete-rollercoaster-ride-never-before/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater New Mod Addresses One of the Game’s Most Critical Issues]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-mod-critical-issues/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-new-mod-addresses-one-of-the-game%E2%80%99s-most-critical-issues.1283862/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater mod now available for download addresses one of the most critical issues found in the PC version of the game: the 60 FPS framerate cap.</p>



<p>The Better Uncap FPS mod, now available for download from <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/metalgearsoliddeltasnakeeater/mods/47?tab=description">Nexus Mods</a>, allows users to cycle between different FPS targets between 30, 60, 100, 120, 144, and uncapped, with the uncapped option being the default. In addition, the mod also features an experimental audio sync fix, disables Depth of Field, Motion Blur, Refraction Blur, Chromatic Aberration, Lens Distortion, Film Grain, and Tonemapper for cleaner and sharper visuals and fully supports Lossless Scaling. Before downloading the mod, you can check it out in action in the video below.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Better Uncap FPS v1.2 for METAL GEAR SOLID Δ: SNAKE EATER" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ypg27q2Xb4E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Although this new Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater mod definitely goes a long way in improving the game, the new options are not enough to completely fix a game released in a rather bad state. Some of its visual elements, such as particle effects, cause some massive performance drops, as highlighted on X by Benchmarking, so it definitely looks like developer Virtuos has <a href="https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-patch-gameplay-issues-crashes/">a lot of work ahead</a> to fix a game that deserved to be released in a much better state on all platforms.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Another issue I noticed in this broken game is that whenever particles (especially dust) spawn near the camera, performance drops significantly. <br>The only solution I found is to disable these particles entirely using:<br>[SystemSettings]<br>fx.EnableNiagaraSpriteRendering=0<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MGSDelta?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MGSDelta</a> <a href="https://t.co/BJClQuino6">pic.twitter.com/BJClQuino6</a></p>— BenchmarKing (@BMKing23) <a href="https://twitter.com/BMKing23/status/1961089149873623136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 28, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S. You can learn more about the remake of one of the best entries in the series by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-ps5-review-based-on-a-hideo-kojima-game/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-mod-critical-issues/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony’s XM4 Headphones Restocked at Nearly 50% Off, Perfect for Listening to K-Pop Demon Hunters Soundtrack]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonys-xm4-headphones-restocked-at-nearly-50-off-perfect-for-listening-to-k-pop-demon-hunters-soundtrack-2000621034</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony%E2%80%99s-xm4-headphones-restocked-at-nearly-50-off-perfect-for-listening-to-k-pop-demon-hunters-soundtrack.1283856/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>What is good noise? “Golden” by Hunter/X from <em>K-Pop Demon Hunters</em> is good noise. New episodes of Jamie Loftus’ <em>Sixteenth Minute (of Fame) </em>podcast is good noise. The guns firing in the bank heist scene of Michael Mann’s <em>Heat</em> is good noise. What about bad noise? The couple on the bus with you arguing is bad noise. The turbine engines on flight is bad noise. Your cubicle’s neighbor punching away at their mechanical keyboard is bad noise. Wouldn’t it be swell if we could just cancel out the bad noise so we can focus in on the good noise? Well, you can do just that with <strong>the Sony WH-1000XM4 wireless noise cancelling headphones.</strong> <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3787/">For a limited time, Amazon has them for a whopping 43% off this labor day weekend. Normally priced at $348, you can currently pick them up for a solid $150 off.</a> That means you only have to pay $198.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3787/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>
<p>The Sony WH-1000XM4 headphones utilize digital noise cancellation to ensure you can hear each and every note or word clearly with no disruptive sounds from your environment coming through. Two microphones in each earcup work together to capture and eliminate surrounding noise when listening to your music, podcasts, or audiobooks, removing it in real time with the help of the HD Noise Cancelling Processor QN1.</p>

<p>The noise-cancelling tech also works to amplify your voice during calls. Five microphones work to deliver clear voice quality. They isolate your voice from any background noise so the person on the other end hears you and just you.</p>
<p>The headphones are designed for all day listening. You can expect a full 30 hours of battery life on a single charge. That’ll last you the whole workday, your commute, and beyond. If you ever find yourself having forgotten to charge it, no need to worry. Just plugging it in for 10 minutes will let you listen for a solid five hours.</p>



<h2>Multipoint Connection</h2>
<p>One standout convenience with the Sony WH-1000XM4 headphones is that they can be paired with two Bluetooth devices at once. This is great as it allows you to be connected to your phone and a gaming console at the same time. It’s perfect for wanting to listen to your own music or podcasts through Spotify or something while playing a game on your Nintendo Switch. You can take a call without disconnecting and reconnecting anything.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3787/">Through Labor Day weekend, you can grab yourself a pair of the Sony WH-1000XM4 wireless noise-cancelling headphones for $150 off.</a> The price is down to just $198 for a limited time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3787/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sonys-xm4-headphones-restocked-at-nearly-50-off-perfect-for-listening-to-k-pop-demon-hunters-soundtrack-2000621034]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Long to Beat Cronos: The New Dawn? Game Length Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-game-length/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-long-to-beat-cronos-the-new-dawn-game-length-explained.1283853/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>With September stacked full of huge releases, knowing the amount of time it will take to complete games like Cronos: The New Dawn is important for you to plan effectively, so we’ve got the details on the game length.</p>



<p>Launching <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-release-date-explained-start-times-release-date-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">September 5</a>, Cronos: The New Dawn impressed in our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hands-on preview</a>, but it lands in a packed release schedule that also includes the likes of Hollow Knight: Silksong and Borderlands 4.</p>



<p>If you’re planning to play multiple new releases in September, we’ve got everything you need to know on the game length of Cronos: The New Dawn.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-many-hours-to-beat-cronos-the-new-dawn">How Many Hours to Beat Cronos: The New Dawn?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Dark journey. Image via Bloober Team</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Cronos: The New Dawn will take around 18 hours to beat, according to the developer themselves.</strong></p>



<p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.techradar.com/gaming/cronos-the-new-dawn-developers-reveal-that-it-will-take-around-18-hours-to-beat" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tech Radar</a> in April, game directors Wojciech Piejko and Jacek Zięba stated that the game was being completed by play tests in 18 hours. However, it was added that it could change as the team was still “balancing everything.”</p>



<p>It’s unclear whether the game length has extended or shortened since, but it should give players a decent indication of how long it will take to progress through the main story. Depending on how you play, it could take up to 20 hours or as little as 16.</p>



<p>If you want to uncover every secret hidden in the game, it will naturally take you longer until you reach the end, but it’s all down to your playstyle.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-long-is-a-cronos-the-new-dawn-full-completionist-run">How Long is a Cronos: The New Dawn Full Completionist Run?</h2>



<p><strong>The length of a full completionist run in Cronos: The New Dawn has not been stated, although players are encouraged to play through the main story at least twice.</strong></p>



<p>Replaying the game unlocks new skins, access to a higher difficulty option in New Game+, experimenting with the upgrade system, or trying out different approaches. Crucially, the developers have stated the game needs to be played “at least twice to understand most of it.”</p>



<p>Two playthroughs would total around 36 hours, giving you plenty of time to sink into the title, and it’s clear that replayability is a crucial feature.</p>



<p>How many times do you think you’ll play through Cronos: The New Dawn? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Cronos: The New Dawn, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whether it will be available on Xbox Game Pass</a>, and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-gets-new-trailer-gamescom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">horrifying trailer shown at Gamescom</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-game-length/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong's release date causes delays for more games than you might think]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksongs-release-date-causes-delays-for-more-games-than-you-might-think</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksongs-release-date-causes-delays-for-more-games-than-you-might-think.1283850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bennett Foddy / Team Cherry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Have you heard of a game called <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight Silksong</a>? Silly question - the chances are you heard little else during <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a> week. This near fabled sequel finally got a release date after several long years of development, and large parts of our gaming world erupted in response. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/not-only-is-hollow-knight-silksong-real-ive-played-it-and-its-harder-and-faster-than-the-original-but-is-it-better">The Gamescom queues to play Silksong</a> were enormous. History had happened. The 4th September - mark it in your diary.</p>
<p>But it wasn't good news for everyone. Announcing the date so late in the game's development - a mere two weeks from release - meant a slew of games which already had early September release dates were suddenly in a difficult position. What should they do - hold ground and go against Silksong? Or move?</p>
<p>The choice was easier for some. Silksong, for all its legendary status, is an indie game made by a small team, so it will appeal particularly to players of indie games, especially tricky side-scrolling Metroidvanias. Blockbuster-styled games like moody action adventure Hell is Us should prove more resistant to Silksong-related audience leech, ditto shooters and other games without obvious crossover appeal. It's to indie games we should look to see the Silksong effect - and it didn't take long to be felt.</p>
<p>Swiftly, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/demonschool-delayed-due-to-hollow-knight-silksong-release-the-gta-of-indie-games">role-playing game Demonschool</a> and literal walking simulator Baby Steps lunged out of the way, delaying their releases by a couple of weeks. Then <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dorfromantik">Dorfromantik</a> developer Toukana pushed the release of its new game Star Birds back a bit. With each new day came another alteration, so instead of listing each Silksong-related delay game by game, I thought I'd round them up. I thought I'd take a closer look at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/2025-video-game-release-schedule#section-9">the 2025 release schedule</a> and investigate what has and hasn't moved, and there was a lot more movement than I expected.</p>
<p>The movers:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1811330/view/542240556668944880?l=english">Lord Ambermaze</a>, from 2nd September to 17th September - "guess why lol"</li>
<li><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/demonschool-delayed-due-to-hollow-knight-silksong-release-the-gta-of-indie-games">Demonschool</a>, from 3rd September to 19th November</li>
<li><a href="https://x.com/comfygirlgame">Comfy Girl</a>, from 3rd September to 8th October</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3314790/CloverPit/">CloverPit</a>, from 3rd September to 26th September - <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3314790/view/520848458437886253?l=english">"if we stick to our original date we would risk the launch of CloverPit a fair bit"</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1410400/Kejora/">Kejora</a>, from 4th September to January 2026</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2719750/Star_Birds/">Star Birds</a>, from 4th September to 10th September</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1594940/Little_Witch_in_the_Woods/">Little Witch in the Woods</a>, from 4th September to 15th September - "we fear that launching LWIW on the same day would not only dishearten our dedicated team but disappoint our devoted audience"</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1605250/view/507338294049112424?l=english">Moros Protocol</a>, from 4th September to 18th September</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1281040/view/544492356480533061?l=english">Baby Steps</a>, from September 8th to September 23rd</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1280080/view/496078660487348547?l=english">Faeland</a>, from 9th September to release date TBC - <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1280080/view/496078660487348547?l=english">"we want to make sure it arrives at time where it can receive the attention and care that it deserves"</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2710920/Aeterna_Lucis/">Aeterna Lucis</a>, from 18th September to 2026 - <a href="https://x.com/aeternathegame/status/1960819936571613209">"The good thing is that I’ll get to enjoy #Silksong just like any other fan"</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3405340/Megabonk/">Megabonk</a>, to 18th September - <a href="https://x.com/MegabonkGame/status/1959235591154872547">"UH OH MEGABONK DELAY"</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The non-movers:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/990380/METAL_EDEN/">Metal Eden</a>, 2nd September</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3135840/Hirogami/">Hirogami</a>, 3rd September - <a href="https://x.com/Kakehashi_Games/status/1960737573011161500/photo/1">"Hirogami's launch date is staying exactly where it is"</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2820820/Jotunnslayer_Hordes_of_Hel/">Jotunnslayer</a> 1.0 release, 3rd September</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1292460/Adventure_of_Samsara/">Adventure of Samsara</a>, 4th September</li>
<li>Hell is Us, 4th September</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2865670/JETRUNNER/">Jetrunner</a>, 4th September</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1054430/Fling_to_the_Finish/">Fling to the Finish</a> on consoles, still 4th September - "yes, we know what else is coming out that day"</li>
<li>Everybody's Golf Hot Shots, 4th September</li>
<li>Dark Deity 2 on Switch 2, 4th September - Silksong's release announcement <a href="https://x.com/DarkDeityGame/status/1960048637322592502">"was not as fun for me as I had hoped"</a></li>
<li>Cronos: The New Dawn, 5th September</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1342490/Daemon_X_Machina_Titanic_Scion/">Daemon X Machina: Titanic Scion</a>, 5th September</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3216500/SHUTEN_ORDER/">Shuten Order</a>, 5th September</li>
</ul>
<p>I'll try to keep this list updated if and when any other games' dates move around, by the way. But what about you - did the Silksong news affect you? Are you eager to play it? Or are you nonplussed?</p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksongs-release-date-causes-delays-for-more-games-than-you-might-think]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CD Projekt's mysterious Project Hadar is now their research focus, as Cyberpunk 2 and Witcher 4 gather steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekts-mysterious-project-hadar-is-now-their-research-focus-as-cyberpunk-2-and-witcher-4-gather-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cd-projekts-mysterious-project-hadar-is-now-their-research-focus-as-cyberpunk-2-and-witcher-4-gather-steam.1283835/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>800 people now working across new Cyberpunk and Witcher games, plus one enigmatic original</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The headcounts of both <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2</a>'s dev teams continue to steadily climb, as the two <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPGs</a> inch closer to our fingertips. Meanwhile, CD Projekt have confirmed that their research division are still busy deciding what the mysterious original game codenamed Project Hadar will look like.</p>
<p>All of these details, plus some Nintendo Switch stuff we've avoided hearing by sticking our mouse and keyboard-focused fingers in our ears, were revealed in the Polish publishers' <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/media/news/cd-projekt-wraps-up-the-first-half-of-2025/">financial report</a> covering the first half of 2025.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>First, the big guns. As outlined by the handy chart below, The Witcher 4 had 422 people working on it as of April 30 and saw that number grow to 444 people by the close of July, while Cyberpunk 2 has hopped over the three digit threshold in that time, going from 96 chooms to 116. Oh bugger, sorry for dropping the c-bomb, that Cyberpunk playthrough I'm still on with is clearly getting to me.</p>
<p>"Our recruitment efforts have significantly sped up over the last three months, and as a result the total number of talented developers working across our projects has grown by 10%, reaching almost 800 people," CD Projekt joint-CEO Michał Nowakowski explained in a presentation to investors. It's worth noting that this current growth follows the studio <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-red-announces-another-batch-of-layoffs-affecting-around-100-employees">laying off staff</a> back in 2023, with some remaining workers <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-staff-form-union-after-layoffs-and-want-everybody-in-the-industry-to-join">deciding to unionise as a result</a>.</p><div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>With Cyberpunk 2 now having fully moved from the research section of CD Projekt's books into the development section - it's been <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-sequel-is-now-cyberpunk-2-and-is-therefore-about-burial-mounds-bows-and-pottery">in pre-production</a> for a little while now - the mysterious Project Hadar's the <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2025/08/management-board-report-on-cd-projekt-group-activities-in-h1-2025-1.pdf">most expensive research project</a> CD Projekt have on the go. While we have some sense now of The Witcher 4, Cyberpunk 2, and Molasses Flood's Witcher spin-off Project Sirius, Hadar remains an enigma several years on from its <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-red-are-making-a-new-witcher-trilogy-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-and-a-brand-new-ip">initial announcement back in 2022</a>.</p>
<p>We know it's going to be an original story, and some <a href="https://tech4gamers.com/cdpr-project-hadar-action-rpg-melee-combat/">job listings</a> have suggested that it's an action RPG with melee combat. Nowakowski's also been <a href="https://x.com/michalnowakow/status/1758597188555591758">weirdly specific in ruling out</a> that it's a "cosmic horror in feudal Japan". Aside from that, shrug emoji. Though, with Hadar's 22 person strong team now looking to be the main focus of CD projekt's research department, the company's investors are clearly as curious for more info on it as we are.</p>
<p>In the <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2025/08/transcript-h1-2025-earnings.pdf">call accompanying these financials</a>, one of them rather bluntly asked whether any decisions regarding the game's future would be made by the end of this year or 2026. Nowakowski seemed a bit taken aback by the idea of sharing more so soon.</p>
<p>"Hadar is still basically an IP concept, so not a game development project yet," he responded. "We’re working on the game’s story, its background – so to say; there is some prototyping going on in terms of gameplay, because it’s hard not to do that when the end goal is to make a video game – but I’m not sure what you mean by 'decisions' – I mean, as in to progress to development, or whether we’re going to make [a game] or not…? We want to make this IP happen, so that decision is sort of made in terms of – when we’re going to go into development, we will announce it in due time, I think."</p><p>You could argue it's been a bit of a strange move for CD Projekt to have announced Hadar at the same time they did the fresh Witcher trilogy and Cyberpunk 2, if they were still going to be at this early a stage with it nearly three years down the line. Then again, that kind of transparency's great for us journos and has probably helped CD Projekt recruit folks to work on Hadar. My money's on it being a Keanu Reeves gacha game with 4X strategy elements and a roguelike mode based around the concept of the word 'woah'.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekts-mysterious-project-hadar-is-now-their-research-focus-as-cyberpunk-2-and-witcher-4-gather-steam]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign Is About To Get Even Harder In New Update]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-is-about-to-get-even-harder-in-new-update/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-is-about-to-get-even-harder-in-new-update.1283832/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>You might think the last thing a FromSoftware game needs is the option to make a game harder. Elden Ring Nightreign is getting just this with the new Deep of Night setting, which ups the difficulty across the board.</p>



<p>FromSoftware’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-complete-all-elden-ring-nightreign-remembrances/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring Nightreign</a> is a unique twist on traditional Elden Ring. It factors in battle royale elements, and there’s an emphasis on speed and succinctness. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-next-set-of-everdark-sovereigns-arrive-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Everdark Sovereigns</a> have been thrust into the game over time, and now a new update is preparing to make Nightreign harder than ever. Yay.</p>



<h2 id="h-deep-of-night-mode-to-make-elden-ring-nightreign-more-difficult">‘Deep of Night’ Mode to Make Elden Ring Nightreign More Difficult</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Beating the first night took long enough. Credit to FromSoftware</figcaption></figure>



<p>If you’re a sadist who loves Souls games and finding new ways to challenge yourself, you’re in luck. <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/news/elden-ring-nightreign-high-difficulty-expedition-mode-deep-of-night-has-appeared?utm_source=SM_Official&amp;utm_medium=official_post&amp;utm_campaign=ER-NIGHTREIGN-ChaosMode" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Bandai Namco</a> has shed light on Deep of Night: “The enemies that appear are stronger than usual.”</p>



<p>The new game mode option arrives on September 11, giving you plenty of time to prepare. Bandai Namco describes the new setting as a “High-difficulty challenge mode&nbsp;designed for seasoned players who have navigated through the Night many times.”</p>



<p>In short, if you’ve mastered Nightreign and can beat all the nights and all the bosses upside down with a blindfold on, you’re probably the person that Deep of Night caters to. The setting also adds new Relics and Gear exclusive to Deep of Night.</p>



<p>A previously hinted-at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-could-be-getting-an-endless-ranked-mode-datamine-reveals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Endless option</a> also accompanies the update. This allows you to keep going until you die, and will really test your ability.</p>



<p>Does Deep of Night sound like your sort of thing? Is making Elden Ring Nightreign harder high up on your wishlist? You know what to do; let us know through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-testing-is-back/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield Labs testing resuming</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-movie-paramount-seeking-rights/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Paramount allegedly seeking rights to make a Call of Duty Movie</a> for more IG news.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-is-about-to-get-even-harder-in-new-update/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Cronos: The New Dawn Coming to Xbox Game Pass?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-xbox-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-cronos-the-new-dawn-coming-to-xbox-game-pass.1283829/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>September’s stacked release schedule will certainly put a strain on the wallets of gamers worldwide, so it’s natural to wonder if titles like Cronos: The New Dawn will launch on Game Pass.</p>



<p>Releasing <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-release-date-explained-start-times-release-date-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">September 5</a>, Cronos: The New Dawn lands in a packed period of releases alongside the likes of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-release-date-start-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Borderlands 4</a>, but our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hands-on preview</a> at Gamescom certainly caught our eye.</p>



<p>If you’ve not pre-ordered Cronos: The New Dawn yet and want to know if you can save money with a Game Pass subscription, we’ve got all the details.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-cronos-the-new-dawn-on-xbox-game-pass">Can You Play Cronos: The New Dawn on Xbox Game Pass?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Terrifying. Image via Bloober Team</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No, Cronos: The New Dawn will not be available to play with an Xbox Game Pass subscription when it launches on September 5th.</strong></p>



<p>Cronos: The New Dawn is not a first-party Xbox title, which would mean automatic inclusion in the service, and there hasn’t been any announcement of the title being added to the catalog.</p>



<p>Although we’re still waiting for the first wave of <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/xbox-game-pass" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Game Pass</a> titles for September to be announced, big releases like Cronos are usually announced well in advance. The biggest indicator is the Xbox Store, which would have a ‘Coming to Game Pass’ badge by the purchase button.</p>



<p>As we’ve had no news to suggest otherwise, and the Xbox Store itself doesn’t advertise a Game Pass drop, don’t expect to see this title drop in the catalog.</p>



<h2 id="h-will-cronos-the-new-dawn-come-to-xbox-game-pass">Will Cronos: The New Dawn Come to Xbox Game Pass?</h2>



<p><strong>There is no indication of whether Cronos: The New Dawn will eventually come to the Game Pass service, though it cannot be ruled out entirely.</strong></p>



<p>Bloober Team’s Layers of Fear was previously available in Xbox’s now retired Games with Gold service in March 2019, showing that the developer does have a previous relationship with Microsoft. On top of this, The Medium was also included in Game Pass in the past, so there’s certainly a track record that could be followed.</p>



<p>Naturally, though, any potential release for Cronos: The New Dawn on Game Pass would come later down the line, with the initial intention of maximizing sales. Eventually, it could open the door for a new audience to enjoy the game in future.</p>



<p>Have you secured your pre-order for Cronos: The New Dawn? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For your next read, take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hell-is-us-trophy-list-all-achievements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full trophy list for Hell Is Us</a>, and find out how you can <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-sign-up-for-battlefield-labs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign-up to test Battlefield 6</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-xbox-game-pass/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact Studio Has An All New Honkai Adventure On the Way — Honkai: Nexus Anima]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/genshin-impact-studio-has-an-all-new-honkai-adventure-on-the-way-honkai-nexus-anima</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-studio-has-an-all-new-honkai-adventure-on-the-way-%E2%80%94-honkai-nexus-anima.1283826/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Expect a new blend of "creature collection with strategic adventure."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">HoYoverse — the team behind <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/genshin-impact"><u>Genshin Impact</u></a> — has unveiled a brand-new Honkai game: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/honkai-nexus-anima">Honkai: Nexus Anima</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">From now until September 12, <a href="https://hoyo.link/iGWlWKfx7" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>early adopters can sign up </u></a>on iOS or PC to participate in the first closed beta, entitled the Nexus Bond Test and try out Honkai: Nexus Anima's own blend of "creature collection with strategic adventure." There's no release date yet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"In a world where unseen bonds between concepts like Light and Dark or Life and Death have ruptured, players will forge connections with companions known as Anima," the description teases. "Each carries unique powers that can be combined in battle, setting the stage for fresh strategies and new stories in the Honkai universe."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's also a 90-second long announcement video, which shows off the sun-dappled shores and leafy meadows, as well as some of the wonderfully cute characters you can expect to meet. You can check it out below:</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/genshin-impact-discontinues-ps4-support-due-to-limitations-related-to-hardware-performance-and-platform-application-size">HoYoverse confirmed it was discontinuing support for Genshin Impact on PS4</a> "due to limitations related to hardware performance and platform application size." We thought it was 'amazing' when it released back in 2020, awarding it 9/10 in the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/genshin-impact-review"><u>IGN Genshin Impact review</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/genshin-impact-studio-has-an-all-new-honkai-adventure-on-the-way-honkai-nexus-anima]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delaying Space Marine 2 Was 'The Smartest Thing We Ever Did' — Saber Reflects on the Biggest Warhammer 40,000 Game of All Time After a Year of DLC and]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/delaying-space-marine-2-was-the-smartest-thing-we-ever-did-saber-reflects-on-the-biggest-warhammer-40000-game-of-all-time-after-a-year-of-dlc-and-looks-to-the-future</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/delaying-space-marine-2-was-the-smartest-thing-we-ever-did-%E2%80%94-saber-reflects-on-the-biggest-warhammer-40-000-game-of-all-time-after-a-year-of-dlc-and.1283823/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> is a breakout hit for developer Saber Interactive, selling over 7 million copies in less than a year. As the game approaches its first anniversary, and with the hotly anticipated Patch 10 imminent, development chief Tim Willits has a lot to be happy about.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It has not been on any streaming service,” Willits told me in an interview at gamescom 2025. “You want to play it, you got to buy it. And it's just rocking and rolling. And it wasn't overpriced. It wasn't overscoped. It wasn't over-designed."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But Space Marine 2 was not a guaranteed success. No video game is. In fact, things were looking ropey when Saber and publisher Focus Entertainment <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-delayed-to-second-half-of-2024">announced a significant delay to the game</a>, from 2023 to the second half of 2024.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This, Willits says, was the “smartest” move Saber has ever made - and you can see why. Space Marine 2 is easily the biggest Warhammer 40,000 video game of all time, impressing veteran fans of the famous grimdark tabletop game and newcomers alike. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/space-marine-2-sees-highest-concurrent-player-peak-ever-for-a-warhammer-40000-game-on-steam">Huge player numbers followed</a> as well as record sales. As Willits told me last year, Space Marine 2 changed everything for Saber, and it wasn’t long before the inevitable Space Marine 3 was announced. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-year-2-roadmap-reveals-content-plan-for-patch-10-right-up-to-2026s-patch-15-including-new-weapons-a-new-class-and-much-more">A full second year of content for Space Marine 2 is also in the works</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“With Space Marine 2, if you remember, we actually delayed that,” Willits said. “It was f***ing worth it! And that was the smartest thing we ever did.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Reflecting on Space Marine 2's first year, Willits admitted it is an ongoing challenge to release enough DLC, both free and premium, to satisfy fans who are always hungry for more content. He pointed to the free horde mode, dubbed Siege, as a particular high point of Space Marine 2’s first year. “Can you name any giant AAA games that release free modes within months after the game?” Willits wondered. “The team is passionate about it. They're super Space Marine nerds, and fan appetite for it is over the top.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Black Templars Champion Pack and Imperial Fists Cosmetic Pack</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Saber, who evolved its impressive zombie tech for prior game World War Z and applied it to the Tyranids for Space Marine 2, was prepared to provide DLC post-launch, Willits said. “We learned our lesson in World War Z. So when World War Z came out, we were unprepared to be honest. We were like, ‘Oh my god, this is a success. Go!’ And so we were way more prepared. We had people working on stuff a year plus before we released, because we knew. We knew. And we learned our lesson. But you're right, feeding the machine is hard.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Space Marine 2 is certainly set for plenty of DLC in its second year, but will it get a story expansion? Or will fans have to wait until <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/with-the-inquisition-watching-tight-lipped-saber-chief-wont-say-much-about-warhammer-40000-space-marine-3-but-he-has-revealed-games-workshop-is-offering-up-some-ideas-that-are-amazing">Space Marine 3</a> comes out to find out what happens next to Titus and friends? “I mean we have some plans, but we have to work with Focus to get the right announcement,” Willits teased. “Nothing is off the table.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Space Marine 2’s success has even positively impacted the development of other Saber games, and given the company the confidence to delay again knowing how beneficial it can be in the long run. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/john-carpenters-toxic-commando-puts-an-80s-horror-spin-on-left-4-dead">John Carpenter's Toxic Commando</a>, for example, was delayed out of this year and into early 2026, and Willits is perfectly calm about it.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“Space Marine 2 was so successful for us that we wanted to make sure that we didn't rush out Toxic Commando immediately after that,” he explained. “And we wanted to make sure that the team had resources and the time and the testing. We've done multiple beta tests, we've got normal people playing it. We had sign-up a few weeks ago.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“That is one of the great things about Saber. We manage our business well and we do not over scope, over design and bloat our teams or our projects, which then allows us to be like, ‘Hey, you know what? Let's actually spend a little more time on Toxic. Space Marine's doing great, we're making content for that. People love it.’</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Because gamers are smart. They always know when a game is rushed or like, ‘You could have done better if you’d spent a little more time with it.’ So we are in a position because of how we make games and how we do work, and that gives us the flexibility and freedom to focus on making sure the games are as good as they can be. So yes, it's a little longer past Space Marine, but I think it'll be much better.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/29/image1-wide-lmcl29nu75-1756463334899.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Hats off to Titus and Space Marine 2. Image credit: Games Workshop.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While Warhammer 40,000 was doing fantastically well for Games Workshop before Space Marine 2 came out, the video game has certainly lifted the setting to another level. Games Workshop recently announced the first ever officially licensed wearable Space Marine helmet — and it’s styled after Lieutenant Titus from Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Surprisingly, Willits didn’t know about it when I brought it up. “That's cool. I had no idea!” he said. “And I usually buy all that stuff.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/delaying-space-marine-2-was-the-smartest-thing-we-ever-did-saber-reflects-on-the-biggest-warhammer-40000-game-of-all-time-after-a-year-of-dlc-and-looks-to-the-future]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What We Played – Herdling, Shinobi: Art of Vengeance & The Rogue Prince of Persia]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/29/what-we-played-herdling-shinobi-art-of-vengeance-the-rogue-prince-of-persia/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-we-played-%E2%80%93-herdling-shinobi-art-of-vengeance-the-rogue-prince-of-persia.1283814/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The last week of August is always a pretty barmy one for me. Coming back from Gamescom means I have to write up tons and tons of previews, and so I’ve been shouting about everything from <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/28/tides-of-tomorrow-preview-youre-not-the-first-player-to-come-through-these-parts/">Tides of Tomorrow</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/28/crushed-in-time-brings-grabbing-and-slapping-to-the-classic-point-click/">Crushed in Time</a> to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/25/john-carpenters-toxic-commando-preview-world-war-z-with-a-side-of-roadcraft/">Toxic Commando</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/24/hands-on-pokemon-legends-z-a-real-time-battles-are-mega/">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> in the past seven days.</p>
<p>But I have had some other things on the go. I played through the opening of Shinobi: Art of Vengeance, which is slick, empowering and satisfying so far, I got <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/26/gears-of-war-reloaded-ps5-review/">Gears of War: Reloaded</a> downloaded, and The Rogue Prince of Persia is also ready to go when I find some time this weekend. I’m looking forward to both!</p>

<p>And with good reason, because <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/26/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-review/">The Rogue Prince of Persia is easily one of the best roguelites of the year</a>, in Ade’s estimations, but he’s not limiting himself to just two dimensions as he’s also been playing plenty of Marvel Rivals and is getting up to an acceptable level – “I’m certainly not an embarrassment anymore as one of my supposed teammates so nicely pointed out.”</p>
<p>But Ade absolutely buried the lede on this one, leaving it to Laura to reveal that the pair of them are now engaged as of last weekend! Congratulations! This, she says, somewhat eclipsed her achievements in Islanders: New Shores, where she reached level 20, and made a start on Sword of the Sea.</p>

<p>Aran regaled us with tales of his musical skiing escapades in Fresh Tracks, which “honestly may be my pick for soundtrack of the year when awards season hits.” Alongside that, he’s been playing Wild Hearts, making his way past the chapter 3 boss thanks to a bit of weapons and armour upgrade grinding.</p>

<p>Something quite remarkable has happened this week, as Tuffcub followed up his <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/27/herdling-review/">Herdling</a> review by installing a game on his PC for the first time! I mean, it’s Destiny: Rising, so it’s actually a mobile game that’s running in an Android emulator, but he’s got his DualSense plugged in and working and is having a pretty good time of it. So yes, Tuff is back to playing Destiny again… and he says, “Honestly, I think this might kill off Destiny 2. It’s Destiny, but all brand new and that’s what everyone wants.”</p>
<p>That’s got Jim a little curious about how tricky it might be to set up – it’s literally advertised on the Destiny: Rebirth site that you can do this – especially since he’s just finished the main campaign of Far Cry 5, just as he was starting to tire of its open world. He did play a bit of the Hours of Darkness DLC, though.</p>
<p>Miguel has been playing the Japanese indie FPS The Citadel, alongside his usual Fortnite and Helldivers 2, plus a review of Shuten Order which you’ll get to read a bit later today. Meanwhile, Gamoc polished off a review playthrough of Echoes of the End, and snuck in an hour of Mortal Kombat 1.</p>
<p>It’s been all post-apocalyptic in Steve’s world this week, as he returned to the cutest vision of this in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/27/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-switch-2-edition-star-crossed-world-review/">Kirby and the Forgotten Land’s Switch 2 Edition and frosty DLC</a>. He’s also been mushing fluffy creatures through The Herdling, but is weighing up whether to play Shinobi when there’s Silksong on the way…</p>

<p>And finally, Dom’s been away again, and has been sneaking in a bunch of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/25/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-review/">Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</a> in moments of downtime. He also rather enjoyed playing through <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/29/the-knightling-review/">The Knightling</a> and has made a start on our Madden 26 review. Is it good? “So far… yes?”</p>
<p>Now, what have you played?</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/29/what-we-played-herdling-shinobi-art-of-vengeance-the-rogue-prince-of-persia/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[System Shock 2 Has Been Updated On Switch, Here Are The Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/system-shock-2-has-been-updated-on-switch-here-are-the-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/system-shock-2-has-been-updated-on-switch-here-are-the-patch-notes.1283805/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Fix this, insect</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="System Shock 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/5b7a55f60b323/system-shock-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nightdive Studios</em></figcaption></figure><p>Following the rollout of <a href="https://nightdivestudios.com/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-patch-notes-1-2/">a new patch</a> on PlayStation, Xbox, and PC last week, the same has now been applied to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/system_shock_2_25th_anniversary_remaster">System Shock 2: 25th Anniversary Remaster</a> on the Nintendo Switch.</p>
<p>Patch 1.2 offers up a healthy batch of fixes and improvements, including gameplay tweaks, visual updates, and quality-of-life additions such as a separate save slot for quick saves. It's all very welcome, and should go toward making an already-excellent game even better.</p>
<p>We gave System Shock 2 a score of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster">9/10 in our recent review</a>, highlighting the amazing story and explorative elements, but noting that the combat could feel slightly dated at times.</p><div><figure data-videoid="gbGX-nnXc-E" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gbGX-nnXc-E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/gbGX-nnXc-E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gbGX-nnXc-E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5d3c45rqozig&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gbGX-nnXc-E" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>832k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>Now, without further ado, let's check out the patch notes:</p>
<h2>System Shock 2 - Patch 1.2 Notes</h2>
<p><strong>MULTIPLAYER</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Select multiplayer enemies will no longer become invincible under specific conditions.</li>
<li>Fixed missing or overlapped items in the player’s inventory upon loading a save.</li>
<li>Adjusted multiplayer behavior so that if a player disconnects from the game, everyone will return to the main menu. This is to prevent saving when players have left the session, altering the amount of players saved in that session.</li>
<li>Fixed cases of player script data disappearing when returning to a previous level after loading a save, causing O/S Upgrades to be locked incorrectly, among other issues.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash on the Recreation Deck caused by the spiders in the ceiling.</li>
<li>Fixed cases of script data piling up causing “infinite” load screens. Depending on the specific circumstance, a new session may be required.</li>
<li>Fixed several AI-related crashes when saving.</li>
<li>Fixed multiplayer to prevent team killing during cutscenes.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>GAMEPLAY</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added a separate save slot for quick saves.</li>
<li>Fixed collision bugs where the player could randomly get stuck in geometry.</li>
<li>Fixed an uncommon crash in the penultimate level when entering water.</li>
<li>Fixed the “Advanced Ammo Usage” English text being incorrect.</li>
<li>Fixed numerous ways of breaking the cutscene on the ops deck.</li>
<li>Fixed the Marines Year 1 voice line not playing.</li>
<li>Fixed issue where players were not being pushed around properly by the steam vents in the penultimate level.</li>
<li>Improved head tracking for enemies and multiplayer characters.</li>
<li>Fixed head tracking on crew bodies, which was especially visible when in water.</li>
<li>Fixed dropping armor and implants on gamepad not removing their bonuses.</li>
<li>Fixed the sharpshooter trait incorrectly using the lethal weapon multiplier instead.</li>
<li>Fixed one of the software shorthands reading RSRH for Research.</li>
<li>Fixed the direction of the mouse wheel being flipped.</li>
<li>Added support for mouse wheel scrolling in the MFD panels.</li>
<li>Fixed the cyber interface only warning about toxic hazards upon opening the menu after loading a save.</li>
<li>Fixed the Marine’s Port MacArthur Weapons Range posting only granting +1 to Standard Weapons. It now correctly grants +2.</li>
<li>Fixed a rare crash in the MFD golf code when going between levels.</li>
<li>Fixed subtitles being incorrectly disabled when clicking reset in the options menu.</li>
<li>Fixed some XERXES subtitles using A instead of R when referring to some hacked turrets.</li>
<li>Misc localization fixes.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>INPUT</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed custom binds not applying to inventory mode until the game was restarted.</li>
<li>Added a joystick smoothing checkbox to the options menu.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>DISPLAY / UI</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed flickering objects.</li>
<li>Fixed bloom affecting full-screen flashes.</li>
<li>Fixed 3D objects in the MFD panels not properly updating the ambient light color.</li>
<li>Fixed psi invisibility not fading your weapon.</li>
<li>Fixed the alignment of many buttons in the main menu.</li>
<li>Focus now starts on the confirm button when saving the game, instead of the name text box.</li>
<li>Added a dimming effect when depressing buttons with a mouse click.</li>
<li>Fixed filtering of images in the menu.</li>
<li>Fixed the “hold crouch” and “toggle crouch” text being swapped.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>AUDIO</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed audio looping when loading with the FMOD audio driver.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>ASSETS</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed a banner in the Space Station having missing polygons on one side.</li>
<li>Fixed a misaligned ceiling window in the Bonne Chance lounge.</li>
<li>Fixed misalignment of the tall windows in the Bonne Chance lounge.</li>
<li>Fixed a misaligned window in the final level.</li>
<li>Updated KEX Engine video.</li>
<li>Added new Vault content!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>NINTENDO SWITCH</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Enabled ad-hoc multiplayer.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash when playing back videos with no audio in the Vault.</li>
<li>Removed ambient occlusion option due to performance concerns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>MODS</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed wrong Relation IDs (and LinkIDs as well) when compared to NewDark.</li>
<li>Fixed dbmod fingerprinting check.</li>
<li>Swapped weapon scripts to use a metaproperty for achievements, instead of taking up the second script slot.</li>
<li>Additional improvements to the underlying engine to give the game better compatibility with NewDark.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:184947,186708 @ 1756469757 -->
<p><em>Have you played System Shock 2 on the Switch yet? What are your thoughts on the game so far? Share your opinion with a comment down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://nightdivestudios.com/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-patch-notes-1-2/" rel="noopener" href="https://nightdivestudios.com/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-patch-notes-1-2/">nightdivestudios.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/f628c3d5bd9b14436edec7852bc953c0 @ 1756468696 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/system-shock-2-has-been-updated-on-switch-here-are-the-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield Labs Testing Resumes Following End of BF6 Open Beta]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-testing-is-back/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-labs-testing-resumes-following-end-of-bf6-open-beta.1283802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Battlefield 6 Open Beta was a huge success for EA and Battlefield Studios. A lot was learned about the next mainline BF game. If you think you can’t play Battlefield 6 again until October, think again—Battlefield Labs has returned.</p>



<p>Before the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-record-stats/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">open beta</a>, there was Battlefield Labs. EA’s new initiative is to incorporate player feedback more than ever before. We all complained vociferously about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2042-road-to-battlefield-6-pass-all-exclusive-bf6-rewards-how-to-get-them/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 2042</a>‘s shortcomings, and it looks promising as EA clearly doesn’t want to make the same mistake twice.</p>



<h2 id="h-you-can-sign-up-for-battlefield-6-labs">You Can Sign Up For Battlefield 6 Labs</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Start playing again right now. Image Via Battlefield Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p>The Battlefield Communications <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">page</a> announced on August 29 that “Battlefield Labs Resumes.”</p>



<p>The community update explained that you can register your interest again—and we have an in-depth guide on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-sign-up-for-battlefield-labs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to sign up for Battlefield Labs</a> so you can play and test BF6.</p>



<p>It also explained: “The end of the Open Beta now provides us with the opportunity to return to Battlefield Labs play sessions. This time around, these sessions may occur at more varied intervals as we target finalizing the launch balance and features of Battlefield 6.”</p>



<p>A significant amount of new content is being added to Battlefield Labs that was previously unplayable. The Portal function is being added to Labs—albeit a basic and stripped-back version—and the announced Server Browser functionality is also included in the latest round of testing.</p>



<p>The development team is also using this test to “Determine the official setting for Hardcore mode, and we look forward to working with players to define it.”</p>







<hr>



<p>Don’t expect the Battlefield news to stop between now and release. The new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-pc-trailer-reveals-most-advanced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 PC Trailer</a> blew our minds, and even the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/first-battlefield-6-camos-have-leaked-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first Battlefield 6 Camos have leaked</a>.</p>



<p>Let us know how excited you are for Battlefield 6 through the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>, featuring gaming conversations every day.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-testing-is-back/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Closed Beta to Start Testing Server Browser and 'Player-Owned' Servers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-closed-beta-to-start-testing-server-browser-and-player-owned-servers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-closed-beta-to-start-testing-server-browser-and-player-owned-servers.1283799/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Our main goal is to observe how it works in practice."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">A server browser will be available in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6"><u>Battlefield 6</u></a> via Battlefield Portal, Battlefield Studios has announced.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As the Battlefield studios get ready to "resume testing the latest updates and content" with the Battlefield Labs closed player tests, the team has revealed players will not only get to try out new maps not previously available in either closed or open betas, but they'll also get "a first look at the Server Browser."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As EA explains it, Battlefield Labs is an experimental environment where "the latest changes and work-in-progress ideas are tested with players in a closed and private space." The content available will be in various stages of production, including items in alpha state, which may result in less polished and/or unstable builds. This allows the development team to balance and make adjustments much faster as it "shapes the future of the game with the community to shape the future of the game."</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/29/bf-labs-resumes-update-1756460090903.jpeg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The Battlefield Portal user interface. Image credit: EA.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This next collection of play sessions will focus primarily on hosting, where the team will "concentrate on the ease of setting up player-owned servers with predefined shortcodes, altering descriptions, selecting tags, and joining those experiences." And as part of this, we've been given our first look at the Battlefield Portal user interface.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Some of the most frequent questions from the community have been about Server Browser availability and functionality," the team explained in a <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/battlefield/battlefield-6/news/community-update-battlefield-labs-testing" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>community</u></a> blog. "In an upcoming Battlefield Labs play session, we will enable an early implementation of this Portal functionality within the Community tab. At this stage, our main goal is to observe how it works in practice, with initial feedback focusing on accessibility and UI clarity."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Players will be able to use the experience library to find a verified Conquest experience using a shortcode, after which players can then choose from a pre-filtered list of active servers, or host their own, where they'll be able to alter descriptions, rotations, tags, and so on. Of course, this should still be treated as a work-in-progress for now, and the Battlefield Studios would like feedback from Battlefield Labs participants as they play.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The next batch of closed tests will also usher in new maps, Operation Firestorm and Mirak Valley, which are designed for combined arms combat and vehicles, including quad bikes, tanks, and aircraft. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We're having a great time with what we've played so far, writing in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-review-multiplayer"><u>Battlefield 6 review-in-progress</u></a>: "Right now, even in beta form, Battlefield 6 might be the most fun shooter I’ve played this year."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Don't forget that from now until October 7 — Battlefield 6's launch day — EA has a "wave of content" planned for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-2042"><u>Battlefield 2042</u></a>, including a free new pass "celebrating the legacy of Battlefield," new hardware, and a reimagining of the fan favorite Iwo Jima map. As you progress through the 'Road to Battlefield 6' pass, you can expect 50 exclusive cross-rewards, including 20 for Battlefield 6 that will be ready for you on launch day, on which you can also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-dev-dice-confirms-big-changes-coming-to-player-movement-especially-horizontal-speed"><u>expect big changes to player movement, maps, modes, and player counts.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-closed-beta-to-start-testing-server-browser-and-player-owned-servers]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[400 People at This Massive Support Studio Worked on The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered — but You Probably Don't Know They Exist]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/400-people-at-this-massive-support-studio-worked-on-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-but-you-probably-dont-know-they-exist</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/400-people-at-this-massive-support-studio-worked-on-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-%E2%80%94-but-you-probably-dont-know-they-exist.1283796/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It is the driving force behind many of your favorite video games released in the last few years, but it largely flies under the radar. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> are just a few of the many games that were and continue to be supported by Virtuos, one of the largest independent video game companies in the world with over 20 studios globally employing about 4,000 staff. Still, the average gamer probably doesn’t know Virtuos exists.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s starting to change though, with Virtuos’ profile rising with each new release. Oblivion Remastered is perhaps Virtuos’ biggest project yet, and its heavy involvement with its development was made a key part of the game’s announcement by Bethesda. Meanwhile, CD Projekt livestreams feature members of the Virtuos development team. Looking ahead, Ken Levine’s BioShock follow-up, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/judas">Judas</a>, and Riot’s League of Legends fighting game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/2xko">2XKO</a>, will both come out with Virtuos’ help.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But it has not all been plain sailing. Last month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/despite-laying-off-270-staff-development-studio-virtuos-remains-fully-committed-to-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-cyberpunk-2077-and-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Virtuos laid off approximately 7% of its global workforce</a>, or around 270 staff. In a statement, Virtuos said it was "evolving to meet the changing needs" of its partners and the wider video games industry. Most of the layoffs affected Virtuos’ Asian workforce.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a wide-ranging interview with IGN at gamescom 2025, Virtuos CEO Gilles Langourieux discussed the company’s history, its recent projects, and what it’s hoping to achieve in the future. The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered, which has gone a long way to putting Virtuos on the map this year, was a big part of our chat.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/28/virtuos-gilles-langourieux-landscape-1756412895462.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Virtuos CEO Gilles Langourieux.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Langourieux said Virtuos’ expertise when it came to remasters (Batman, Final Fantasy, Dark Souls Remastered) meant it was a natural part of the conversation around Oblivion’s return.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We managed to convince Todd Howard and his team that we could do it,” Langourieux began. “He had known us for a while. And then how does it work? You prove what you're capable of during a pilot phase. You deliver a convincing vertical slice or pilot. You align with the team at Bethesda on what they believe is the level of quality or detail required to meet their audience goal, and you continue all the way to final ship.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Virtuos developed Oblivion Remastered using Unreal Engine 5. It runs at 4K resolution and 60 frames per second, as you'd expect, but other changes are more meaningful. Everything from the leveling systems to character creation, and combat animations to in-game menus have been improved. Meanwhile, there's lots of new dialogue, a proper third-person view, and new lip sync technology. The changes went down well with fans, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-fans-react-to-all-the-biggest-changes-say-its-good-enough-to-be-called-a-remake"><u>some of whom believe Oblivion Remastered would be more accurately described as a remake</u></a>. Bethesda, however, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-comments-on-the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-changes-we-never-wanted-to-remake-it"><u>has explained why it went down the remaster route</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Langourieux said Virtuos knew it had to use a new engine for Oblivion Remastered to bring the classic RPG up to date in terms of graphics and performance, but also retain the original engine so veteran fans would recognize Oblivion’s gameplay. As Todd Howard himself described it, Bethesda was keen for the Oblivion remaster to have some of that “old charm.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We realized that one of the solutions would have to be to combine the original engine with a new engine. Virtuos happens to have a long experience working with Unreal,” Langourieux said. “We've done a number of projects like this where we combine — it's called engine pairing — we pair two engines to work together so that the gameplay comes from the original engine, but the rendering and the new modern bells and whistles come from the new engine. And our experience doing that, our experience with Unreal, was one of the things we had to bring to the table.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, hundreds of artists were mobilized to work on Oblivion Remastered to “nail” the Oblivion art style while also modernizing it. Virtuos had its studio in Paris lead the project, making technical, design, and artistic choices about the game, with the help of other Virtuos studios. At Bethesda, a small team under the direct supervision of Todd Howard monitored Virtuos’ work.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At peak, around 400 people at Virtuos worked on Oblivion Remastered. This was a true AAA development effort spread out across a number of years. The end result was a successful release, a video game played by over 9 million people at this point, and a (largely) impressed fanbase. Virtuos itself was made a part of Bethesda’s official Oblivion Remastered announcement video, which Langourieux appreciated.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“Sometimes when you tackle these kinds of projects, you worry about talking about a new developer because you're worried that new developer name might not resonate so well with the audience,” he said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“They put their money where their mouth is by supporting us very transparently and openly, and that has given us more visibility than other projects have. So credit to them for that.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Cyberpunk 2077, Oblivion Remastered, Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater… what’s next? With all sorts of rumors swirling around about more Bethesda remasters, could Virtuos be helping out with, say, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/after-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastereds-success-ex-bethesda-dev-expects-a-fallout-3-remaster-would-significantly-improve-the-not-good-gun-combat">a Fallout remaster of some description?</a> Of course, Langourieux won’t name names, but did talk generally about what Virtuos has up its sleeve, and teased “similar” titles to Oblivion Remastered coming from the company in the years ahead.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I won't be able to share specifics,” he began, “but what I can say is that you've seen what we're capable of for a big, impactful remaster like Oblivion. You can expect more similar titles to come out of Virtuos in the coming years. And you can also expect to see us involved in expanding the life of large-life titles. Those would be two directions that I'm super excited about.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But will Virtuos break out of its support act status and make an original IP of its own? Langourieux seems happy with where his company is at right now, insisting “not everyone aspires to be the rockstar.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We have a lot of ambition,” Langourieux said. “We've built one of the largest, most stable game developers in the business, and we intend to continue doing that. We've done it by being very clear about what we're good at and how we can serve our clients in the industry. And there's a lot of ambition with that. Not everything is about being the rockstar. Not everyone aspires to be the rockstar. We're playing a different role."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/400-people-at-this-massive-support-studio-worked-on-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-but-you-probably-dont-know-they-exist]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 dev says "a significant number" of users played the game below the minimum recommended specs, as EA points to the importance of weaker h]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-dev-says-a-significant-number-of-users-played-the-game-below-the-minimum-recommended-specs-as-ea-points-to-the-importance-of-weaker-hardware</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-dev-says-a-significant-number-of-users-played-the-game-below-the-minimum-recommended-specs-as-ea-points-to-the-importance-of-weaker-h.1283787/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>A "substantial number" of players during the beta were around the minimum spec mark.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A "substantial number" of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a> open beta players were playing on or around the minimum recommended specs, according to technical director Christian Buhl.</p>
<p>In an interview with Eurogamer, Bulh broke down some user data for the initial wave of PC players who hopped into the game earlier this month, stating that of the "millions of players" who were jumping in, a sizable portion of them were doing so on lower-end hardware.</p>
<p>Speaking about some of the lengths Battlefield Studios and EA went to to ensure the game was playable by those on older setups, Buhl stated: "We built maps, and had to go to our artists and tech artists to adjust these maps so they were more performant. We've put in a lot of effort across the board to make sure these performance targets were set, and whether you're on min spec or ultra spec you're going to get the experience we're targeting."</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Battlefield 6 Official PC Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nMBBXqu0OLE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Battlefield 6 Official PC Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nMBBXqu0OLE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nMBBXqu0OLE?autoplay=1" title="Battlefield 6 Official PC Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's the Battlefield 6 PC trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nMBBXqu0OLE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>When asked how important it is to serve minimum spec players at a time when PC hardware is getting more expensive, due to bloated prices or general economic challenges right now, Buhl responded by saying: "Min spec is certainly one of our most important specs [...] it's super important from both a commercial and business perspective - we want as many people as possible playing the game."</p><p>Buhl continued with an anecdote from earlier in the game's development: "We did a lot of analysis, we did tests on the game on a wide range of hardware above and below our minimum and recommended specs. We figured out what we can hit, what we need to hit from a business perspective, and that was to capture a wide audience on PC. It's been super critical."</p>
<p>When asked what percentage of players were playing at or around that min spec, Buhl could not recall the exact number,  dubbing it a "meaningful percentage". He also noted a number of players below the minimum spec, emphasizing the existence of this group.</p>
<p>In a follow up email after the interview, EA PR would not provide the exact number, pointing to Buhl's prior statement that it was a "substantial number" of players</p>
<p>The current state of affordable computing in the USA, Battlefield 6's primary market, is one of turmoil. Not only has a cost-of-living crisis made the price tag on high end hardware unpalatable for a sizable number of gaming enthusiasts, ongoing political policy <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1W_mSOS1Qts&amp;ab_channel=GamersNexus">has had a drastic impact on international trade</a>.
</p><p>Buhl also spoke to Eurogamer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/it-really-sucks-battlefield-6-technical-director-bummed-out-about-those-unable-to-play-due-to-secure-boot-requirement-believes-anti-cheat-cat-and-mouse-game-will-never-end">about the anti-cheat used in Battlefield 6</a>, it's ability to curb a sizable portion of cheaters during the betas, and the reality that some players weren't able to play <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bios-shock-getting-past-battlefield-6s-anti-cheat-error-was-the-faffiest-thing-a-pc-game-has-ever-required-of-me">due to Secure Boot requirements</a>. Nonetheless, this beta proved exceptionally popular, taking the title <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-the-best-battlefield-has-ever-done-one-million-in-steam-pre-orders">as most popular Battlefield beta of all time</a>.</p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-dev-says-a-significant-number-of-users-played-the-game-below-the-minimum-recommended-specs-as-ea-points-to-the-importance-of-weaker-hardware]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paramount Seeking Rights To Make A Call of Duty Movie, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-movie-paramount-seeking-rights/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/paramount-seeking-rights-to-make-a-call-of-duty-movie-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1283778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It has been reported that Paramount is seeking the rights to adapt Call of Duty into a movie, with the film reportedly being a ‘priority’ for the 110-year-old picture production firm. Nothing has been confirmed beyond this, and it’s not yet known in what form a potential Call of Duty movie would surface.</p>



<p>Fans were quick to criticize the news, with some stressing that it’s not the right time for a Call of Duty movie and others wondering if the film would include ‘Beavis and Butthead skins’.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-is-a-call-of-duty-movie-being-made">Is a Call of Duty Movie Being Made?</h2>



<p>Before the Microsoft x Activision Blizzard acquisition, rumors regarding a Call of Duty movie were circulating. In a recent report from <a href="https://puck.news/author/matthew-belloni/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Puck News</a>, the claim surfaced along with a note that a Call of Duty film is a high priority for Paramount’s new leadership team.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>The sentiment surrounding the news has been pretty tough, with fans suggesting it could be ‘another Borderlands movie’, which was released in 2024 to a woeful reception. Other Call of Duty fans have posted screenshots of the countless ‘war flicks’ we’ve received over the last few decades, stating that they’re <strong>all </strong>Call of Duty movies, in theory.</p>



<p>Paramount might go the route of creating something original, but for it to be a <strong>Call of Duty movie</strong>, it might need to follow a path already established by the game franchise. For instance, a movie-based replication of the Modern Warfare series might do well because it’s already so cinematic, but then it lacks originality.</p>



<p>What would you like to see from a Call of Duty movie? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/konami-addresses-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-launch-issues/">Konami has addressed launch issues with Metal Gear Solid Delta</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-movie-paramount-seeking-rights/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Developers Detail Clever System That Increases the DLC's Difficulty Based on How Much of the Base Game You've Playe]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-developers-detail-clever-system-that-increases-the-dlcs-difficulty-based-on-how-much-of-the-base-game-youve-played</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-developers-detail-clever-system-that-increases-the-dlcs-difficulty-based-on-how-much-of-the-base-game-youve-playe.1283775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nearly a year on from the launch of MachineGames' brilliant <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a>, the studio is back with an additional chapter, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-the-order-of-giants">The Order of the Giants</a>, which arrives on September 4.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For those who enjoyed the base game's blend of puzzle-solving and fisticuffs, this fresh DLC adds more of what you love — and takes a novel approach to tuning its difficulty, based on your experience with the Great Circle so far. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking to IGN last week at Gamescom, creative director Axel Torvenius and lead game designer Zeke Virant explained how The Order of the Giants will smartly adapt its combat to suit both new and veteran players, due to the DLC's addition within the base game's narrative, branching off of its Rome location. And while the pair remained tight-lipped on word of an Indiana Jones sequel, discussion was still had about MachineGames' intention for the overall narrative of the game — and how it's sometimes best to leave players keen for more.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"The conventional way of doing DLC is to add something that stands after, or a miniature game on the side," Torvenius begins, "but we didn't really feel that that was the best for our game." He pauses, smiles. "Though it would've been the easiest. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I can tell you we had a lot of struggles or challenges with the technical side of things, making sure that people's existing save states [work]. The systems we had in place did not fully support us just splicing in a lot of new content in the middle of the game. So there was a lot of hard work from engineers and programmers and also on the design side. It was not an easy thing to do, but we felt it was the best to do."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For those who are yet to play Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, the idea is that Order of the Giants simply adds onto the game's already generous Rome section, with additional areas outside and underneath the Vatican to explore. And for players who have finished the game already, who will likely be familiar with dipping back into previous areas to hunt down remaining side-missions and collectibles via their journal, the DLC simply acts as a huge new side-quest to pursue. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The integration makes the experience the most seamless," Torvenius continues, "and makes it feel like it's really expanding on the existing content. There was a balance, because obviously the DLC is its own completely standalone adventure. So there are hooks and the red threads between the main storyline and the DLC, but the DLC story does not impact the main story, even if the DLC story will give you a deeper understanding of some elements. So it was absolutely not the easiest [way to do DLC], and maybe not the smartest, but the best."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: The Order of Giants DLC Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Obviously, though, players still finding their feet in the Vatican's sunny courtyards will have a different experience approaching Order of the Giants' content than those who have played another 40 hours, seen Indy's journey to the end and buffed up their archeologist with all sorts of upgrades and bonuses. And it's because of this, Virant says, that MachineGames was forced to get even smarter under the game's hood.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Players who are at the end of the game don't need to worry about the difficulty [being too easy] as actually we have a new system in place where players are dynamically scaled based on how far they progressed," Virant explains. "We know a lot of players are coming back from the endgame and would like to have a continuation of that difficulty, especially if they have health upgrades and a lot of abilities.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We tried a few different things, but the one that was simplest and actually just what felt right was that if you've progressed to the Vatican but you haven't gotten to Giza yet, we keep it on a first tier of difficulty. If you've gotten to Giza, then we adjust it up to a second tier. And then once you've gotten to Sukhothai, we adjust to a third tier. From there we [can tune] the different amount of combos enemies can use, different amounts of health and also how many will gang up on you at the same time."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's a smart system, though one which need not come into play at all during the DLC's first hour, as Indy kicks off his new adventure with some impressive-looking new adventuring and puzzle sections, set just outside the bounds of the base game's existing area. It's here that Indy meets Father Ricci, a priest obsessed with the legend of a secret chamber that houses a giant helmet - something that immediately sparks our hero's interest. (Brilliantly, Father Ricci also has a pet parrot, Pio, who rather steals the show. Torvenius confirmed that while the parrot speaks, this is not another turn from the talented Troy Baker, and is instead another voice actress who provides the parrots' voice and much of its chirping sounds.)</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The DLC's focus on the main game's race of giants, otherwise known as the Nephilim Order, will likely pique the intrigue of fans who enjoyed piecing together their story during the Great Circle's campaign. Sadly, the late Tony Todd, who played Locus, was not able to contribute to the DLC — though Torvenius said his presence "would have been amazing."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"To some extent this was never really about telling the background story of Locus as a character," he said. "Even though for me personally, I would've loved to play a game that was where you just play as Locus for 15 hours on all of his grand adventures. That would've been interesting. But this was more about deepening the story of the tribe of the giants and the Nephilim Order. And obviously Locus is part of that since he's part of the race, but it's more about the origins and the mystery of it and how it connects with the Vatican and the streets of Rome."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When asked whether players will learn everything there is to know about the giants before the end of the DLC, or whether MachineGames was purposefully keeping some elements of their story secret, Torvenius remained coy. "Yes and no," he replied. "I would say I think absolutely this will help for people that have played through the main game, and when they have played the DLC in addition to that, they will get a deeper understanding of the mystery around the Nephilim Order. But there are things that maybe are to some extent left unanswered, though the majority of it I think starts to paint a pretty good picture."</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/28/giants-dlc-cavern-4k-1756390200862.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Was this secrecy a desire to hold some story elements back for use in the future, I wondered, or simply a decision not to explain too much — the Midichlorians effect — of something that could otherwise remain a cool mystery? "In my mind, both as a consumer myself but also as a creator, I enjoy when maybe sometimes everything isn't explored," Torvenius responded. "Sometimes there will be still like a fog of war on the map that is best left unexplored.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We have internally fleshed it out completely," he continued, discussing the lore of the giants. "I could write a blurb that explains how everything is connected, but would that be fun?" <em>Yes</em>, I say, to which Torvenius laughs. "We are always working towards giving players the sensation they have figured it out and it should make sense when it's all connected. But for me it's always important to make sure you slowly get a bigger picture without saying too much."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For Torvenius and Virant, Order of the Giants has been a challenging but enjoyable victory lap for one of 2024's most widely-praised games. Development on Indiana Jones and the Great Circle began amid the height of Covid lockdowns, with the studio forced to collaborate via Microsoft Teams. For the DLC, however, its developers have been together throughout, able to build on what has come before, in the knowledge they're working on something that is already beloved.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The overall quality of the DLC is absolutely on par and in some instances higher than main game," Torvenius concludes. "For people that love the Great Circle and the world of Indiana Jones that MachineGames built, this is more of that. It's really for them. And if you haven't played the base game, we are really hoping that this is a great opportunity for people wanting to play. It's been a great adventure doing it, a lot of hard work, but it's been fun to see. Sometimes you work on a game for many years and towards the end there can almost be a bit of fatigue, or you're a bit exhausted. But when production really geared up on the DLC, people were still energized. I think that passion for Indiana Jones shines through, and we are extremely proud of it."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-developers-detail-clever-system-that-increases-the-dlcs-difficulty-based-on-how-much-of-the-base-game-youve-played]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Madden NFL 26 Update Adds Nike Rivalries And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/first-madden-nfl-26-update-adds-nike-rivalries-and-more/1100-6534367/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-madden-nfl-26-update-adds-nike-rivalries-and-more.1283772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/madden-nfl-26/" data-ref-id="5000-675129">Madden NFL 26</a> has only been out for two weeks, but EA has already prepared the first update for this year's edition. Most of the changes address bugs or other issues that have come up since the game officially launched on August 14. It's also introducing Nike Rivalries, a new feature that will bring "community pride" to some of the most famous rivalries in the league.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/madden-nfl/madden-nfl-26/news/title-update-august-28-2025" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">EA</a>, Nike Rivalries is part of a new four-year deal between Nike and the NFL that will "celebrate football's most storied rivalries" with customized uniforms that represent their respective cities. Each iteration of Nike Rivalries will focus on teams from two different divisions, and this year's subjects are the AFC East and NFC West.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4558728-nflrivalries.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4558728" data-ratio="0.56230769230769" data-width="1300" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4558728-nflrivalries.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4558728"></a><figcaption>Players from the NFC West and AFC East show off their custom looks in Nike Rivalries.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4558728-nflrivalries.jpg"></figure><p>EA also announced that the Madden NFL 26 update will introduce a customized playbook that was created in collaboration with retired quarterback Kurt Benkert. The playbook is called Benkert's Dimes, and it's available in Play Now when selecting playbooks.</p><p>The remaining issues addressed in this update are largely specific to certain plays or situations. Additionally, EA notes that it will address a few other fixes in later updates, including the Class Import Process incorrectly modifying player body types, the inability to take players off of the IR list, and nose tackle archetypes displaying a different OVR in the front end.</p><p>The complete list of changes in Madden NFL 26's first update can be found below:</p><h3>Gameplay</h3><p>Cover 2 Tampa - The middle defender now gets deeper, maintaining better leverage position against deep threats, especially vs. 3x1 formations.</p><p>Cover 2 Hard Flats - Addressed an issue with Hard Flats where defenders were dropping too deep and too far inside before reacting to flat routes. Defenders now drop more accurately with their zone responsibilities, improving coverage consistency in the shallow flats.</p><p>Cover 3 Match: Logic improvements for Defenders when reacting to Slot WRs attempting to outleverage the defense on deep routes. This includes Buzz Mable and Zone Blitz 3 playcalls</p><p>Cover 6 &amp; Cover 4 Palms - Fixed an issue where Outside Quarters CBs in Cover 6 and Cover 4 Palms were oftentimes losing the press giving up easy touchdowns. We adjusted the CBs alignment so they will no longer attempt to press the WR.</p><p>Zone coverage defenders now drop back quicker when shading coverage ‘overtop’.</p><p>Fixed a post play animation defect where a defender would do “read steps” when standing in place after the whistle.</p><p>Addressed a visual issue around the previous play graphic obscuring the offensive play call formation.</p><h3>Franchise</h3><p>Addressed our UI Transitions surrounding the Player Card. Reducing the transition time it takes to go into the Player Card.</p><p>Dev Notes: This current fix only addresses going into the Player Card. Our resolution for exiting out of the player card back to the Franchise Main Menu will be in our next TU.</p><p>Resolved an issue allowing commissioners to send multiple league invites simultaneously.</p><p>Addressed an issue that prevented Edge Players from adding Pass Rushing Traits</p><p>Addressed an issue during the Draft where the Draft Board was improperly transparent, showing through to the background.</p><h3>Title Update</h3><p>Class Import Process incorrectly modifying Player Body Types, specifically Offensive Linemen.</p><p>Players on IR unable to be peeled off the IR list.</p><p>Nose Tackle archetypes displaying a different OVR in the front end.</p><h3>Superstar Mode</h3><p>Fumble rate chance has been decreased in Snow Games.</p><p>Fixed an issue where players would play in the wrong position.</p><p>Fixed a rare issue where players’ knees would be invisible during the NFL Combine.</p><p>Several stability fixes.</p><h3>Ultimate Team</h3><p>Play A Friend will now respect each individual users passing settings</p><p>Remedied an issue where opening a Fantasy Pack after a H2H game caused visual artifacts during the pack open</p><p>Fixed an issue where rewards images failed to appear on some screens</p><p>Fixed multiple occasions where players were navigated to the wrong menu</p><p>Fixed a text issue where “Rank Down” appeared instead of “Rank Up”</p><p>Fixed an issue where progress in Ranked was not visually displaying</p><p>Fixed multiple occasions of overlapping text</p><p>Fixed an occasional crash when returning to lobbies</p><p>Items displayed during presentation did not always match their actual rarity</p><h3>Audio</h3><p>Fixed an issue where commentary referred to a few rookies by an incorrect last name.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/first-madden-nfl-26-update-adds-nike-rivalries-and-more/1100-6534367/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix Is Shutting Down Two Games A Decade After Their Debut]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-is-shutting-down-two-games-a-decade-after-their-debut/1100-6534366/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-is-shutting-down-two-games-a-decade-after-their-debut.1283769/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534366">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Earlier in 2025, Square Enix executives <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-reveals-its-plan-to-reboot-the-company-over-the-next-three-years/1100-6531527/" data-ref-id="1100-6531527">shared their desire to "reboot" the company</a> over the next three years. However, not every game will make it out to the other side of that time frame. Two mobile games from Square Enix's top franchises are set to be shut down in Japan at the end of October.</p><p>The impending ends of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/final-fantasy-brave-exvius/" data-ref-id="5000-450306">Final Fantasy: Brave Exvius</a> and Dragon Quest of the Stars were confirmed in Square Enix's <a href="https://x.com/FFBE_JP/status/1959873628691939371" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">social media</a> <a href="https://x.com/hoshidora_info/status/1959874494463635469" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">posts</a> (via <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/square-enix-shutters-two-ten-year-old-mobile-games-1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GamesIndustry.Biz</a>). Both titles originally launched in 2015, although Final Fantasy: Brave Exvius was shut down outside of Japan last year and Dragon Quest of the Stars was closed internationally in 2021. Now, both games are getting delisted on October 31. In-app purchases for each title have also been suspended.</p><p>Before the final shutdown goes into effect, Dragon Quest of the Stars will reach its 10th anniversary on October 15, followed by Final Fantasy: Brave Exvius on October 22.</p><p>According to Final Fantasy XI director Yoji Fujito,, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-considered-ending-support-this-23-year-old-game-but-too-many-people-still-play-it/1100-6531645/" data-ref-id="1100-6531645">Square Enix also wanted to shut down that 23-year-old game</a> last year. However, Final Fantasy XI was spared because there are still too many people who play the MMO. Outriders fans weren't as lucky. Developer People Can Fly <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/outriders-2-was-canceled-after-issues-with-publisher-square-enix-report/1100-6532913/" data-ref-id="1100-6532913">reportedly wanted to make Outriders 2</a> before the company was overruled by is publisher, Square Enix. People Can Fly was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gears-of-war-co-developer-cancels-games-layoffs-coming/1100-6531972/" data-ref-id="1100-6531972">subsequently hit by layoffs</a> and Outriders 2 was said to be one of two canceled projects in the wake of those departures.</p><p>There are still some fresh games coming from Square Enix, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-adventures-of-elliot-the-millennium-tales/" data-ref-id="5000-688786">The Adventures of Elliot: The Millennium Tales</a>, which is a brand-new HD-2D action-RPG that will hit Switch 2, Xbox Series X|S, and PC in 2026.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-is-shutting-down-two-games-a-decade-after-their-debut/1100-6534366/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloober Team has plans for more horror games on Switch 2 - could Silent Hill 2 be next?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/bloober-team-has-plans-for-more-horror-games-on-switch-2-could-silent-hill-2-be-next</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloober-team-has-plans-for-more-horror-games-on-switch-2-could-silent-hill-2-be-next.1283763/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>And why Luigi's Mansion is inspirational.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bloober / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/bloober-team">Bloober Team</a> has plans to release more horror games on Nintendo's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-nintendo-switch-2-the-digital-foundry-hardware-review">Switch 2</a>, following the release next month of its latest game Cronos: The New Dawn.
</p>
<p>
"I'm trying to make my personal dreams come true," Bloober CEO Piotr Babieno told <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight">The Game Business</a>. "I am a huge Nintendo fan. I grew up with Nintendo consoles. The most important horrors, like <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/eternal-darkness">Eternal Darkness</a>, Resident Evil 0, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/resident-evil-4">Resident Evil 4</a>... were available on Nintendo GameCube. It was a gold time for Nintendo fans. In some ways, we would like to be the one to open a new chapter for Nintendo right now."
</p>
<p>
He continued: "We have some plans. We are not able to share our vision for the future yet. But definitely Nintendo fans could take a look at Bloober Team."
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Cronos: The New Dawn – Nintendo Direct: Partner Showcase 7.31.2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/91BaLCOQa24?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Cronos: The New Dawn – Nintendo Direct: Partner Showcase 7.31.2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/91BaLCOQa24?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/91BaLCOQa24?autoplay=1" title="Cronos: The New Dawn – Nintendo Direct: Partner Showcase 7.31.2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Cronos: The New Dawn – Nintendo Direct: Partner Showcase 7.31.2025<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=91BaLCOQa24" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>
Babieno also hinted Bloober has an eye on cosy games, citing the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/luigis-mansion">Luigi's Mansion</a> series as an example of how the genre can cross over with horror.
</p>
<p>
"The best [example] is Luigi's Mansion," said Babieno. "What [Nintendo game director] Kono-san did with this title was pretty impressive. And I believe that there is a huge possibility to repeat such an idea in the future."
</p>
<p>
Could we see the Silent Hill 2 remake on Switch 2. It's currently a console exclusive on Sony's PlayStation 5, but that exclusivity ends after the game's first year on sale - that'll be 8th October.
</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Sony</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
If Cronos: The New Dawn is coming to Switch 2, then perhaps Silent Hill 2 could follow suit in the future. Otherwise there's an opportunity for ports of Bloober's previous games (there's a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bloobers-the-medium-will-be-adapted-to-film-courtesy-of-it-and-annabelle-writer-producer-gary-dauberman">film adaptation of The Medium on the way</a>), or whatever else the studio is working on in the future.
</p>
<p>
Cronos: The New Dawn is out on 5th September across Switch 2, PS5, Xbox Series X/S, Windows, and macOS. Eurogamer's Ian Higton went <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cronos-the-new-dawn-feels-like-a-combination-of-every-other-survival-horror-game-ive-played-before-it-which-isnt-always-a-good-thing">hands-on with Cronos back in July</a>, but found it a little derivative.
</p>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-29th-august-what-went-wrong-with-football-manager-25-and-helldivers-2-wholesomeness">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/bloober-team-has-plans-for-more-horror-games-on-switch-2-could-silent-hill-2-be-next]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rumour: Sony Is Gunning For The Switch 2 With A Handheld, Dockable PS6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/rumour-sony-is-gunning-for-the-switch-2-with-a-handheld-dockable-ps6</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rumour-sony-is-gunning-for-the-switch-2-with-a-handheld-dockable-ps6.1283748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Game on</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Switch 2 / Vita" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/210b61a9a6315/switch-2-vita.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Ollie Reynolds / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Despite Sony's PS5 being on the market for nearly five years at this point, it still somehow feels <em>way</em> too soon to be talking about the inevitable PS6 – who even wants or needs one yet? Alas, here we are.</p>
<p>The latest rumour from YouTube channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MooresLawIsDead">Moore's Law is Dead</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/08/rumour-ps6-handheld-device-can-be-docked-like-nintendo-switch-2">Push Square</a>) is particularly significant, because it seems to hint that Sony is planning to launch a variant of the PS6 that will not only be handheld, but can be docked – just like the Switch and Switch 2.</p>
<p>Codenamed 'Canis', the handheld is supposedly one of three SKUs planned for the PS6. The main one will be the 'Orion', which will be your bog-standard 'flagship' console with <em>all the specs</em>. The second is the 'Canis' handheld, and the third is the 'Canis' console, or the 'PS6 S'.</p>
<p>The latter two will share similar specs and will likely lean closer to what Sony is currently offering with the PS5/PS5 Pro, albeit with a few minor upgrades here and there.</p>
<p>So essentially, rather than focusing on sheer power – because if it ain't obvious by now, we're very much in the era of diminishing returns – Sony is seemingly looking to capture both the console and handheld market. Hopefully this might also mean that it's is able to offer slightly cheaper options, because if the so-called 'Orion' is going to retail at a similar price to the PS5 Pro ($749.99 / £699.99), Sony's going to have a real hard time shifting many of them.</p>
<p>Still, it's early days yet. It's best to take these rumours with a grain of salt for now until Sony officially reveals its plans.</p>
<p>Tell you what though, we know we said it's still way too early for a PS6, but a proper, native handheld PlayStation sounds awfully tempting...</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:180859,183643 @ 1756467548 -->
<p><em>Would you be keen to try out a handheld, dockable PS6 console? Or are you quite happy with what you've got with the Switch/Switch 2? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/@MooresLawIsDead" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/@MooresLawIsDead">youtube.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/08/rumour-ps6-handheld-device-can-be-docked-like-nintendo-switch-2" rel="noopener" href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/08/rumour-ps6-handheld-device-can-be-docked-like-nintendo-switch-2">pushsquare.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1756467413 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/rumour-sony-is-gunning-for-the-switch-2-with-a-handheld-dockable-ps6]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Over 450 Diablo developers vote to unionise, because "passion can’t protect us from job instability"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/over-450-diablo-developers-vote-to-unionise-because-passion-cant-protect-us-from-job-instability</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/over-450-diablo-developers-vote-to-unionise-because-passion-can%E2%80%99t-protect-us-from-job-instability.1283745/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"This is just the first step for us joining a movement spreading across an industry that is tired of living in fear"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Blizzard</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A group of more than 450 <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/diablo-iv">Diablo</a> developers have voted to form a union at Blizzard, under the banner of the Communications Workers of America (CWA).</p>
<p>According to a CWA press release, the new union is made up of game developers, artists, designers, engineers, and support staff across the Diablo series, and has already been formally recognised by Blizzard parent company Microsoft. These workers join the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/over-500-world-of-warcraft-developers-at-blizzard-have-voted-to-form-microsofts-biggest-wall-to-wall-union">over 500</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/world-of-warcraft">World of Warcraft</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-devs-have-formed-an-almost-200-person-strong-union-with-the-cwa-called-the-overwatch-gamemakers-guild">almost 200</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/overwatch">Overwatch</a> devs who each formed their own unions earlier this year.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>As you'd imagine, Microsoft's recent <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-layoffs-are-reportedly-underway-with-zenimax-and-king-employees-losing-their-jobs">mass layoffs</a> were a big factor in these Diablo staffers opting to union up now, with other concerns including the avoidance of crunch and a "passion tax" that centres around the idea you might feel obligated to accept less for a dream job.</p>
<p>"With every subsequent round of mass layoffs, I've witnessed the dread in my coworkers grow stronger because it feels like no amount of hard work is enough to protect us," said Kelly Yeo, a Diablo game producer and member of the organising committee member. "I am overjoyed that we have formed a union—this is just the first step for us joining a movement spreading across an industry that is tired of living in fear. We are ready to begin fighting for real change alongside our Diablo colleagues."</p>
<p>Ryan Littleton, another Diablo game designer and committee member, added:</p>
<blockquote>The day after the third round of mass layoffs, I walked into the office, and when I tried to open the door to the cafeteria, my badge was denied. For a moment, I wondered if getting breakfast was how I'd find out I was part of that round. While luckily it was just a technical issue, none of us should have to live with that constant worry that we might be let go at the drop of a hat. A union allows us to organize across the industry to make great games and protect the developers who create them from the constant pressures of layoffs, passion tax, and crunch.</blockquote>
<p>Teams at Blizzard aren't the only folks at Microsoft who've moved to unionise recently. Staff at the likes of Call of Duty developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/raven-software-qa-staff-win-their-fight-for-union-vote">Raven Software</a>, Fallout and Elder Scrolls studio <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bethesda-game-studios-developers-ecstatic-to-announce-a-241-strong-wall-to-wall-union">Bethesda</a>, and Elder Scrolls Online developer ZeniMax have also opted to seek protections. In the case of unionised ZeniMax staff, their union claimed it was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenimax-union-say-theyre-fighting-for-staff-left-in-limbo-by-microsoft-cancelling-mmo-as-part-of-mass-layoffs">fighting for the jobs of workers</a> left in limbo by the abrupt cancellation of an unannounced MMO as part of Microsoft's July mass layoffs.</p>
<p>Solidarity to these freshly-unionised Diablo devs.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/over-450-diablo-developers-vote-to-unionise-because-passion-cant-protect-us-from-job-instability]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 is free this weekend on Steam as horrible mosquito folk swarm the Kingdom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-is-free-this-weekend-on-steam-as-horrible-mosquito-folk-swarm-the-kingdom</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/darkest-dungeon-2-is-free-this-weekend-on-steam-as-horrible-mosquito-folk-swarm-the-kingdom.1283742/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Red Hook release third and final part of boardgame-style spin-off mode</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Red Hook have just released the third and final part of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/darkest-dungeon-2">Darkest Dungeon 2</a>’s Kingdoms mode - a boardgame-style add-on experience that sees you moving a stagecoach around a map’s worth of benighted inns, fending off pigmen, witches and - as of this update - giant mosquitos. 
</p>
<p>
To celebrate, they’ve also made the base roguelike <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> free on Steam until September 1st. Admittedly, being offered Darkest Dungeon 2 for free is a bit like somebody warmly offering to give you the plague. But this is the fun kind of plague, a plague rich in dicey turn-based battles, grindy but engrossing character development, and suppurating vistas of cthulhoid swampfields.
</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Darkest Dungeon II - Kingdoms: Curse of the Court Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G5TSpfxsFew?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Darkest Dungeon II - Kingdoms: Curse of the Court Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G5TSpfxsFew?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/G5TSpfxsFew?autoplay=1" title="Darkest Dungeon II - Kingdoms: Curse of the Court Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G5TSpfxsFew" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
I think that, on balance, I prefer the first <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/darkest-dungeon">Darkest Dungeon</a>’s cliffside ambience and town/dungeon format. I find the older side-scrolling dungeons less fussy than the second game’s branching 3D road systems, and I think the original game’s handling of sanity and darkness is expressed more compellingly through the layered dungeon soundtrack. Here is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-review">what Joe Donnelly thought about it</a> in 2016: "You’ll cry. And cry and cry and cry. But I think you’ll love it."</p><p>I think the second game’s combat system is superior, though – it boils off some of the numberfluff and introduces a more readable system of HUD tokens, while retaining the same, diabolical relationship between party member positioning and skill availability. Laena Hafer summarised the game thusly in our 2023 <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-review">Darkest Dungeon 2 review</a>: "A roguelite sequel that takes a few steps forward and one or two back from the original, but keeps the gloomy but intense spirit alive."
</p>
<p>
If you’ve played neither, both are fine, gruelling RPGs with amazing narration and glorious visuals cut straight from the pages of Hellboy. Kingdoms brings back a little of the first game’s feel, married to the second game’s wagoneering, but is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2s-free-kingdoms-mode-is-out-now-and-its-got-its-red-hooks-in-me-already">pretty much its own thing</a>. You must defend inns as they come under siege, while travelling about to gather party members and complete a central questline before the map is swamped by nasties. Speaking of which, here's what they're adding in the third major Kingdoms update Curse of the Court, which is available now:
</p>
<blockquote>Swarms of Bloodsuckers have descended upon the Kingdom, bringing with them a supernatural contagion that can inflict your heroes with the dreaded Crimson Curse! Players will be challenged in an all-new questline to find a cure for this rapidly spreading infection and exterminate The Bloodsuckers before time runs out! Additionally, this release features new achievements to earn, and three new Kingdoms maps, each with a different layout that presents a unique set of challenges. These new maps are playable on any of the three different Kingdoms modules.</blockquote>
<p>
If you come down with a severe case of Dankest Sturgeon 2 this weekend, take comfort in the knowledge that they’re running a discount alongside the free timed promotion - 63% off, or more if you buy a bundle with all the DLC. Read more on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1940340/Darkest_Dungeon_II/">Steam</a>.
</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-is-free-this-weekend-on-steam-as-horrible-mosquito-folk-swarm-the-kingdom]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Try Lost Soul Aside Before You Buy With Surprise Free Demo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/try-lost-soul-aside-before-you-buy-with-surprise-free-demo/1100-6534363/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/try-lost-soul-aside-before-you-buy-with-surprise-free-demo.1283736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534363">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/lost-soul-aside/" data-ref-id="5000-460422">Lost Soul Aside</a> demo has been released alongside the Final Fantasy-inspired action game's launch today, allowing curious players to get a taste of the gameplay before committing to purchase.</p><p dir="ltr">According to its listing on the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/HP9000-PPSA31743_00-0000000000000000" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation store</a>, the free demo will include two of the game's boss battles. Both battles appear to be from different parts of the game, allowing you to try out both basic and advanced abilities. The first fight is against the Rose Queen, a quick enemy who deals out "flurries of rapid strikes." You can try out some late-game abilities and a two-handed greatsword in the second boss battle against Holy Knight Commander Victor and the Ancient Mecha. Keep in mind that your progress in the demo will not transfer to the full game.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="545506496" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465568,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Lost%20Soul%20Aside%20%E2%80%93%20Gameplay%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:53,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/lost-soul-aside-gameplay-trailer\/2300-6465568\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465568\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465568\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465568\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465568&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4417685-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/PstsLMBN.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1734536400,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="PstsLMBN" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Lost Soul Aside – Gameplay Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Lost Soul Aside started as the <a dir="ltr" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lost-soul-aside-will-launch-on-ps5-debuts-new-gameplay-trailer/1100-6490929/">solo project of Chinese developer Yang Bing</a>, who started building it from Unreal Engine assets back in 2016. The project gained visibility and traction through trailers. Eventually, thanks to the Sony program China Hero Project, a full dev team joined Bing, founding the studio UltiZero Games.</p><p dir="ltr">Previously, <a dir="ltr" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lost-soul-aside-slices-and-dices-at-playstation-state-of-play-coming-in-may/1100-6529413/">Lost Soul Aside had a release date of May 30, 2025</a>, but it was delayed to August just a month before it was set to launch, which the studio said was to allow additional time to "polish" the game.</p><p dir="ltr">In other PS5 News, Sony recently revealed the slate of <a dir="ltr" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-plus-essential-free-games-for-september-2025/1100-6534226/">PlayStation Plus Free games for September</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        <div>
	<p>
		Latest in
		Lost Soul Aside
	</p>

	
</div>
  
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534262&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/grounded-2-patch-fixes-some-of-the-games-major-annoyances\/1100-6534262\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534263&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/heres-doom-running-on-a-charging-station\/1100-6534263\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534271&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/pokemon-go-tales-of-transformation-season-brings-fresh-content-in-september\/1100-6534271\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534272&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mass-effect-tv-shows-latest-update-reveals-a-key-detail\/1100-6534272\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534273&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-latest-silksong-induced-game-delay-doesnt-hide-its-reasoning-in-new-trailer\/1100-6534273\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534243&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/concords-failure-led-to-increased-oversight-says-sony-exec\/1100-6534243\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534242&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/years-after-its-announcement-cyberpunk-action-game-replaced-finally-has-a-release-window\/1100-6534242\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534238&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-corpse-party-tetralogy-pack-brings-four-horror-visual-novels-to-switch\/1100-6534238\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534241&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-developers-credit-borderlands-3-dlcs-for-inspiring-the-sequels-tone\/1100-6534241\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534245&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/silksong-prompts-yet-another-game-delay-as-the-great-looking-demonschool-gets-pushed-back\/1100-6534245\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534246&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/super-smash-bros-melee-mod-inserts-a-2024-gaming-darling\/1100-6534246\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534247&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/switch-2-dev-kits-still-sound-somewhat-rare-even-2-months-after-launch-report\/1100-6534247\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534244&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-makes-ceo-a-little-nervous-due-to-the-games-challenging-sections\/1100-6534244\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534233&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/delta-force-surges-beyond-200000-concurrent-users-on-steam\/1100-6534233\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534248&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kojima-has-already-written-death-stranding-3s-concept\/1100-6534248\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534249&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/turok-origins-feels-like-a-worthy-co-op-revival\/1100-6534249\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534250&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/zombie-swarms-and-vehicle-tech-make-john-carpenters-toxic-commando-more-than-just-another-co-op-fps\/1100-6534250\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533598&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/h-p-lovecraft-experience-deluxe-book-box-set-new-horror-box-set-august-2025\/1100-6533598\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534019&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fairy-tail-100-years-quest-season-one-coming-to-blu-ray-this-fall\/1100-6534019\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/try-lost-soul-aside-before-you-buy-with-surprise-free-demo/1100-6534363/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Over three quarters of Cyberpunk 2077's Nintendo Switch 2 sales were physical]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/over-three-quarters-of-cyberpunk-2077s-nintendo-switch-2-sales-were-physical</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/over-three-quarters-of-cyberpunk-2077s-nintendo-switch-2-sales-were-physical.1283733/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Cartridge before the horse.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CDPR</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Earlier this year, the team at CD Projekt Red announced that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> would be a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-nintendo-switch-2-the-digital-foundry-hardware-review">Switch 2</a> launch title. Not only that, the studio was going to offer those interested a physical game cartridge to purchase, with the actual game on it.</p>
<p>This decision put CD Projekt in the relative minority, as many other third party studios were instead favouring 'key cards' for their own Switch 2 releases. These key cards don't actually contain game data, and instead trigger a download from the Nintendo eShop when they are popped into the device.</p>
<p>And, this move has paid off. Last night, CDPR released its latest <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/pl/wp-content/uploads-pl/2025/08/prezentacja-wynikowa-h1-2025-en.pdf">financial results</a> and it turns out that the Switch 2 community really does like its physical media. Of Cyberpunk 2077's Switch 2 sales in June, over 75 percent were physical.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>As you can see in the image below, only 24.6 percent of the games Switch 2 sales were digital.</p>
<p>While we don't have sales figures for Cyberpunk 2077, back in June it was reported <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-third-party-sales-reportedly-very-low-despite-record-breaking-console-launch">CD Projekt's Cyberpunk 2077 was the "best-selling third-party game during the launch of Switch 2"</a>, and did "reasonable numbers" on Nintendo's latest console.</p>
<p>Prior to its Switch 2 debut, CD Projekt's VP of business development Jan Rosner said having Cyberpunk 2077 as a "cartridge with a plug and play experience" on Switch 2 was "the right thing to do". At this time, the studio exec noted that physical games remain vital to Nintendo's player base, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cyberpunk-2077-developer-comments-on-switch-2-key-cards-says-having-proper-cartridge-with-a-plug-and-play-experience-is-right-thing-to-do">developers should not "underestimate" this</a>.</p>
<figure>


</figure>
<p>CDPR isn't the only studio to buck the third-party 'key cards' trend. Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sonic-racing-crossworlds-will-buck-third-party-switch-2-trend-with-full-game-on-card">Sega announced Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds' release will have the full game on the Switch 2 card</a>.</p>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-29th-august-what-went-wrong-with-football-manager-25-and-helldivers-2-wholesomeness">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/over-three-quarters-of-cyberpunk-2077s-nintendo-switch-2-sales-were-physical]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard's Diablo team forms union seeking protection in wake of Microsoft layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/blizzards-diablo-team-forms-union-seeking-protection-in-wake-of-microsoft-layoffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blizzards-diablo-team-forms-union-seeking-protection-in-wake-of-microsoft-layoffs.1283724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"We are ready to begin fighting for real change."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Blizzard</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Blizzard's Diablo team is the latest group of Microsoft workers to form a union, with over 450 developers voting in favour of representation with the Communications Workers of America.
</p>
<p>
The decision follows <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-xbox-layoffs-june-2025-tracking-the-situation-as-it-happens">mass layoffs at Microsoft back in June</a>, with workers at the company seeking fair compensation, job security, and an opportunity to improve workplace conditions.
</p>
<p>
Other unions formed by Microsoft workers include Blizzard's story and franchise development team, as well as employees at ZeniMax Media and Raven Software. There are now over 3,500 employees at Microsoft in CWA organised unions.
</p>
<p>
"With every subsequent round of mass layoffs, I've witnessed the dread in my coworkers grow stronger because it feels like no amount of hard work is enough to protect us," said Kelly Yeo, a game producer on Diablo and organising committee member. "I am overjoyed that we have formed a union - this is just the first step for us joining a movement spreading across an industry that is tired of living in fear. We are ready to begin fighting for real change alongside our Diablo colleagues."
</p>
<p>
The union includes developers, artists, designers, engineers, and support staff working across the Diablo franchise.
</p>
<p>
"My entire career as a developer has seen my peers and I paying the 'passion tax' for working in an industry that we love," said Nav Bhatti, a senior software engineer and organising committee member. "At some point you have to choose between fight or flight, and forming a union is us doing just that - standing our ground in the industry."
</p><p>
"Diablo workers are the latest to show that California has become a hub for video game worker organising," said CWA local 9510 president Jason Justice. "What's happening here is part of a much larger story about turning the tide in an industry that has long overlooked its labour. Entertainment workers across film, television, music, and now video games are standing together to have a seat at the table. The strength of our movement comes from that solidarity."
</p>
<p>
Eurogamer recently <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pay-rises-ai-regulation-and-layoff-protection-what-activision-blizzards-newly-unionised-employees-want-from-microsoft">spoke to members of Blizzard's story and franchise development team about their union</a>, discussing their demands from Microsoft.
</p>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-29th-august-what-went-wrong-with-football-manager-25-and-helldivers-2-wholesomeness">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/blizzards-diablo-team-forms-union-seeking-protection-in-wake-of-microsoft-layoffs]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Knightling Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/29/the-knightling-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-knightling-review.1283721/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>True adventure isn’t that easy to come by, but perhaps if you’re a squire to the world’s greatest knight, things are just that little bit easier. It sure seems that way at the opening of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/the-knightling">The Knightling</a>, the latest third-person action adventure from the team at Twirlbound. Out on patrol with Sir Lionstone, you’re ambushed by an Earthborn creature, nearly dying at its hands were it not for Sir Lionstone throwing his shield, Magnustego, in front of you. As your liege gives chase and disappears, you’re faced with a trek back to town, heavy shield in tow, and the slight sinking feeling that he’s not going to be back for a while.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Knightling - Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DFjhAL2m8uI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It’s a gut instinct you should listen to, as The Knightling embarks on his own adventures in the absence of Lionstone. Starting off small and learning the tricks and techniques to owning a massive shield, you’re soon making yourself indispensable to the local townsfolk before starting to impress the Queen and the landed gentry, all the while keeping a watchful eye on the horizon in the hope of your mentor returning.</p>


<p>The Knightling is immediately endearing. It’s hard to explain what it is that gets straight under your skin. Perhaps it’s the chunky, characterful art design – there’s a dash of Breath of the Wild and a hint of Darksiders here – or the animated facial movements of the Knightling despite only really being a pair of eyes. It may be just incredibly relatable. That position as an apprentice who’s thrust into bigger and tougher tasks without any real guidance, is one that few could forget.</p>
<p>The Knightling manages to evoke an incredible sense of scale with its chunky, playful visuals. Huge chasms, immense palaces and never-ending fields are laid out in front of you, simply begging to be explored, whether bouncing and jumping to the highest point, riding the wind, or slip sliding all the way down on the back of your shield. Movement is one of the game’s greatest achievements, and just getting from one point to another, working out the best route, and playing with the different systems is fun from start to finish.</p>


<p>That sense of scale is enhanced by a light approach to side quests and additional tasks. There are plenty of things to find, discover and do out here, from discovering treasure to taking part in races on your shield, but they get the balance right between things to distract and things that are meaningful and interesting.</p>
<p>Side Quests often leave you with artefacts which stand as a reminder of the people you’ve helped along the way, giving each activity a permanence that many games simply don’t manage all the way through. In fairness, I’d actually have liked a few more, but the focus and scope here remain tight, presumably, in part, due to the game’s budget.</p>
<p>There’s a strong sense of forward motion at all times, with the Knightling and Magnustego both capable of growth, upgrading each through different collectables and growing your range of offensive and defensive skills.</p>

<p>You’ll need to utilise and maximise every one of them too, with combat in The Knightling proving to be no slouch, despite the welcoming visuals. Blocking, parrying and dodging play a key role, while you steadily grow more proficient at bashing everything in sight with your immense shield.&nbsp;It builds into a serious task as you struggle to handle large groups of bandits and creatures at the same time, but it rarely feels unfair, and save points are generous enough that you don’t lose too much progress when they take you down.&nbsp;There’s not a huge breadth of enemies, but those that are here, particularly the larger boss characters, retain the same idiosyncratic characterisation as the central cast, and they look great.</p>
<p>Besides fighting, there’s a lot of platforming, with the Knightling capable of a reliable double jump, before expanding his moveset to include a handy glide ability. Getting to the top of things is often part of an area’s allure, and, barring a few annoying sections, movement remains continually fun. That’s helped by the various races that appear throughout the game, lending the game an old-school Banjo or 3D Mario feel, and going fast is often rewarded with a heap of treasure. They’re very addictive, and the kind of thing you find yourself losing serious time with in the quest for the gold.</p>

<p>Mention has to go to the orchestral soundtrack, with the Tumult Kollektiv trio – made up of Jonathan Howe, Leonhard van Voorst and Alexander van der Kruijf – providing a stream of beautiful compositions shifting between playful, dramatic and epic with barely a pause. Exploration in particular gives you a real chance to appreciate the melodies and nuance of each piece, and the sense of scale, drama and adventure here wouldn’t be the same without them.</p>
<p>The Knightling’s only occasional misstep is in performance, and on standard PS5 there are occasions where the frame rate dips, or there’s pop-in of textures and details. It’s actually moderately power-intensive – based at least on my experience of playing it for preview on my 3070-equipped PC – but they’re minor kinks that feel as though a patch would smooth them out. They’re few and far between enough not to detract from the experience, as is the very occasionally wayward camera, and they’re easy things to forgive when the rest of the game is so enjoyable.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/29/the-knightling-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>