<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:53:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lords of the Fallen 2 Enters Full Development as CI Games Reveals New Details]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/lords-of-the-fallen-2-enters-full-development-as-ci-games-reveals-new-details</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lords-of-the-fallen-2-enters-full-development-as-ci-games-reveals-new-details.998412/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/lords-of-the-fallen-2-enters-full-development-as-ci-games-reveals-new-details<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Lords of the Fallen publisher CI Games has confirmed the 2026 sequel has entered full development while revealing a handful of details about the action role-playing game.</p><p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lords-of-the-fallen-sequel-now-in-full-development" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eurogamer</a> spotted the tidbits in CI Games' latest <a href="https://cigames.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/CI-Games-Strategy-Update-and-Product-Roadmap-2025-2028.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">financial report</a>, where the publisher revealed Lords of the Fallen 2 (for lack of an official name) will have a "more commercial" art style and narrative, suggesting it wants the game to have more mainstream appeal.</p><p>CI Games also promised gameplay improvements, more game mode options, and full "shared-progression" co-op alongside the "core" single-player campaign, all developed with "elevated production values" fueled by Unreal Engine 5.</p><p>The publisher confirmed it had received a "major investment" from Epic Games for PC exclusivity on the Epic Games Store, which means Lords of the Fallen 2 will not initially launch on Steam.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The Lords of the Fallen Review Screenshots</h3></div></output><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/next-lords-of-the-fallen-game-confirmed-for-2026">A 2026 release window was revealed in June</a> alongside its release on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X and S, but practically nothing else is known about the sequel. Expect an announcement proper at some point in 2025.</p><p>Lords of the Fallen is a dark fantasy RPG released in 2023 as a sequel/reboot of the 2014 original. Taking inspiration from the Dark Souls games, it tells the story of a fabled Dark Crusaders who must embark on an epic quest to overthrow Adyr, the demon God.</p><p>In our 8/10 <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lords-of-the-fallen-review-2023">Lords of the Fallen review</a>, IGN said: "Lords of the Fallen is an awesome Soulslike with a fantastic dual-realities premise, even when performance shortcomings and wimpy bosses crash the party."</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree Patch 1.15 Fixes Bugs and Makes Performance Improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-patch-115-fixes-bugs-and-makes-performance-improvements</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-patch-1-15-fixes-bugs-and-makes-performance-improvements.998409/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-patch-115-fixes-bugs-and-makes-performance-improvements<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring">Elden Ring</a> developer FromSoftware has released patch 1.15 for the action game and its expansion, <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree">Shadow of the Erdtree</a> across PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X and S, and PC via Steam.</p><p>Patch 1.15 comes hot on the heels of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-update-114-makes-shadow-of-the-erdtrees-final-boss-easier-as-part-of-significant-balance-changes">Elden Ring’s big balance-changing 1.14 update</a>, and thus does not contain any further balance changes or additional features. Check out the patch notes below, courtesy of publisher <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/news/elden-ring-patch-notes-version-115" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bandai Namco</a>.</p><p>Elden Ring is one of the biggest video games of recent years, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-reaches-25-million-units-sold-ahead-of-shadow-of-the-erdtree"><u>selling an incredible 25 million copies</u></a> since going on sale in 2022. The Shadow of the Erdtree DLC is a hit, too, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/those-tough-elden-ring-dlc-requirements-didnt-stop-shadow-of-the-erdtree-sales-it-sold-an-incredible-5-million-in-just-3-days"><u>selling five million in just three days despite tough requirements</u></a>.</p><p>IGN's <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-review"><u>Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree review</u></a> returned a 10/10. We said: "Like the base game did before it, Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree raises the bar for single-player DLC expansions. It takes everything that made the base game such a landmark RPG, condenses it into a relatively compact 20-25 hour campaign, and provides fantastic new challenges for heavily invested fans to chew on."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree DLC Review Screenshots</h3></div></output><h2><strong>Elden Ring update 1.15 patch notes:</strong></h2><h2><strong>Bug Fixes</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed a bug where the cutscene that plays when entering the Shadow Keep Church District would play again when re-entering the area.</li><li>Fixed a bug where some of the Golem Fist weapon attacks would not deal damage when the player was affected by certain special effects.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Golem Fist weapon one-handed heavy attack power was lower than expected.</li><li>Fixed a bug that prevented the Aspects of the Crucible: Thorns incantation from being cast when used in quick succession.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Smithing Talisman effect did not apply to some weapons’ throwing attacks.</li><li>Fixed a bug that prevented the use of ashes in some areas of the Scadutree Avatar battle arena.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Rellana, Twin Moon Knight would sometimes perform unexpected actions when interacting with objects in the battle area.</li><li>Fixed a bug that allowed Skills to be used in incorrect combinations with Weapons under certain circumstances.</li><li>Fixed a bug that caused unexpected rendering and behavior of some enemies under certain circumstances.</li><li>Fixed a bug where some sound effects did not play correctly.</li><li>Several performance improvements and other bug fixes.</li><li>Further fixes were added to the game’s end credits.</li></ul><h3><strong>Possible unstable performance fixes</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>For the PS5 version of the game, unstable framerate may be improved by using the "Rebuild Database" option from the device’s safe mode.</li><li>In some PC versions, Ray Tracing may be unintentionally enabled and cause unstable performance. Please check the Ray Tracing setting in the "System" &gt; "Graphics " &gt; "Ray Tracing Quality" from the title screen or in-game menu.</li><li>In the PC version, the message "Inappropriate activity detected" may appear without cheating.<ul data-cy="list"><li>To fix this issue, please verify the integrity of the game's files before restarting the game.</li></ul></li><li>In the PC version, unstable framerate may be caused by third party applications that control mouse behavior.  Deactivating these third party applications may improve performance.</li></ul><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Famitsu Review Scores: Issue 1868]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1868</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1868.998406/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1868<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Metaphor: ReFantazio and Silent Hill 2 scored.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>This week’s Famitsu review scores are in. <span id="more-919041"></span></p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Metaphor: ReFantazio [32 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/metaphor-refantazio">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a></em> (<a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,103 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,188 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,279 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a>) – 9/9/10/9 [37/40]<ul><li>It takes about 80 hours to clear the story, or 100 hours with side activities.</li></ul></li><li><em><a title="Games > METRO QUESTER: OSAKA [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/metro-quester-osaka">METRO QUESTER: OSAKA</a></em> (PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,536 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,123 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>) (7/8/7/7) – [29/40]</li><li><em><a title="Games > Silent Hill 2 (2024) [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/silent-hill-2-2024">Silent Hill 2</a></em> (PS5) – 8/9/9/9 [35/40]<ul><li>It takes about 16 to 18 hours to clear.</li></ul></li><li><em><a title="Games > Touhou Genso Wanderer: FORESIGHT [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/touhou-genso-wanderer-foresight">Touhou Genso Wanderer: FORESIGHT</a></em> (PS4, Switch) – 7/7/8/7 [29/40]</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Thanks, <a href="http://ryokutya2089.com/archives/79857" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ryokutya2089</a>.</p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield Next DLC Expansion Will Continue Constellation’s Storyline – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/starfield-next-dlc-constellation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starfield-next-dlc-expansion-will-continue-constellation%E2%80%99s-storyline-%E2%80%93-rumor.998385/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/starfield-next-dlc-constellation/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The next Starfield DLC expansion will provide a continuation of the Constellation and Artifact storyline, according to rumors circulating online.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://x.com/Odah_SFA/status/1838732164310999264">@Odah_SFA</a>, the next expansion, which should be named <a href="https://wccftech.com/starborn-trademark-could-hint-at-starfields-next-expansion/">"Starborn</a><span><a href="https://wccftech.com/starborn-trademark-could-hint-at-starfields-next-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,"</a> will be about the disappearance of Constellation's founder, Sebastian Banks, providing a continuation of the organization and the Artifact storyline,</span>&nbsp;which makes up much of the base game's story.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">OK. So, I've heard some gossip that <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Starfield?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Starfield</a> 's next Expansion titled "Starborn" will be about the disappearance of Sebastian Banks, Founder of Constellation and the continuation of the Artefact story. Will post more info once I know more <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Starborn?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Starborn</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bethesda?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bethesda</a></p>
<p>— Odahfield (@Odah_SFA) <a href="https://twitter.com/Odah_SFA/status/1838732164310999264?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<p>As the first Starfield story expansion, Shattered Space, has only just released, it is unlikely we will hear anything about Starborn anytime soon, so it may a while until we learn if the expansion will indeed be more tightly related to the base game's main campaign. Considering how the first expansion is more of a side story, however, it would make sense for Bethesda to go in this direction and explore more of Constellation's origins.</p>
<p>Starfield is now available on PC, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. You can learn more about the game by checking out my<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/starfield-the-elder-space-scrolls/"> review.</a></p>
<p><em>With an engaging story, well-developed characters and lore, and a huge amount of meaningful content, Starfield is one of Bethesda's finest games and one of the best role-playing games released in the past few years. The lack of seamless exploration and real innovation of the typical gameplay formula from the studio are noteworthy, but those willing to forego these issues will find a reactive and sprawling sci-fi universe to lose themselves in for hundreds, if not thousands, of hours.</em></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Throne And Liberty Launches To Big Concurrent Player Numbers (But Not As Big As New World Or Lost Ark)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/throne-and-liberty-launches-to-big-concurrent-player-numbers-but-not-as-big-as-new-world-or-lost-ark/1100-6526849/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/throne-and-liberty-launches-to-big-concurrent-player-numbers-but-not-as-big-as-new-world-or-lost-ark.998382/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/throne-and-liberty-launches-to-big-concurrent-player-numbers-but-not-as-big-as-new-world-or-lost-ark/1100-6526849/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526849">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/throne-and-liberty/" data-ref-id="5000-582820">Throne and Liberty</a>, the free-to-play fantasy MMORPG from Korean developer NCSOFT and published by Amazon Games, is off to a big start on Steam--though not quite as big as Amazon's two previous MMOs.</p><p dir="ltr">An early-access period in which players could pay to play five days early saw Throne and Liberty's concurrent player counts peak at around 56,000. On October 1, when the game launched for free-to-play players, those numbers rapidly climbed. Throne of Liberty reached 326,377 concurrent players on launch day and for a time was the fourth most-played game on Steam.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2dS4OpIWM6U" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2dS4OpIWM6U" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">As often seems to be the case with the launch of a new MMO, server woes and login queues plagued Throne and Liberty in its opening hours, with NCSOFT rapidly spinning up new servers to meet demand. There were also a handful of other issues shortly after launch that NCSOFT said it was working to resolve, including some players being unable to create new characters or missing characters for those who played during early access.</p><p dir="ltr">Throne and Liberty's Steam launch numbers are nothing to sneeze at, but far behind the launch of Amazon's previous two MMOs, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/new-world/" data-ref-id="5000-489582">New World</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/lost-ark/" data-ref-id="5000-533053">Lost Ark</a>. New World, internally developed by Amazon, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-world-passes-900000-concurrent-players-on-steam/1100-6496765/" data-ref-id="1100-6496765">broke Steam records when it launched in 2021</a> and saw more than 913,000 concurrent players despite its $40 price tag. Lost Ark, another free-to-play Korean MMO localized and published by Amazon, fared even better during its launch in 2022, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lost-ark-passes-1-3-million-concurrents-overtakes-cyberpunk-2077-dota-2-and-cs-go-to-become-steams-2nd-biggest-game-of-all-time/1100-6500630/" data-ref-id="1100-6500630">hitting 1.3 million concurrent players</a>. It is worth noting that unlike Lost Ark or New World, Throne and Liberty is also available on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S, meaning that its Steam concurrent players don't paint the full picture.</p><p dir="ltr">Amazon prior to launch detailed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/being-a-free-player-in-amazons-new-mmo-wont-be-quite-so-rough-thanks-to-new-changes/1100-6525061/" data-ref-id="1100-6525061">all the changes it would be making to Throne and Liberty compared to the Korean version</a>, with the goal of adjusting the game's business model to better fit the expectations of Western players. Those changes included lowering the price of the game's battle pass and leveling pass, as well as additional rewards and the removal of an optional subscription called the Blessing of Solisium. Amazon said it would "evaluate" how the subscription needed to change in order to "serve the needs of our players."</p><p dir="ltr">Throne and Liberty wasn't even going to be the only MMORPG Amazon published in 2024. The juggernaut also planned to publish the Western version of Bandai Namco's anime MMO <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/blue-protocol/" data-ref-id="5000-499449">Blue Protocol</a>. The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-and-bandai-namco-cancel-western-release-for-mmo-as-service-ends-in-japan/1100-6526156/" data-ref-id="1100-6526156">Western release of Blue Protocol was canceled in August</a>, with the Japanese servers set to go offline in January.</p><p dir="ltr">Even if Amazon has a reputation for creating and publishing MMOs (it's currently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-still-trying-to-find-the-hook-for-lotr-mmo/1100-6526064/" data-ref-id="1100-6526064">working on a Lord of the Rings MMO</a> and is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-world-aeternum-revamps-the-mmo-for-consoles-with-solo-play-and-more-changes/1100-6524219/" data-ref-id="1100-6524219">reworking New World for consoles</a>), the company is looking to branch out into other genres. It was announced as part of Gamescom 2024 that Amazon would publish the co-op dungeon crawler <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/king-of-meat/" data-ref-id="5000-640430">King of Meat</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom speedrunners pounce on glitch that lets you beat game in an hour]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-speedrunners-pounce-on-glitch-that-lets-you-beat-game-in-an-hour</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-speedrunners-pounce-on-glitch-that-lets-you-beat-game-in-an-hour.998379/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-speedrunners-pounce-on-glitch-that-lets-you-beat-game-in-an-hour<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom">The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</a> features an eye-opening glitch that lets you teleport to the game's final boss, allowing speedrunners to beat the whole adventure in under an hour. 
</p>
<p>
The exploit, which warps protagonist Zelda to Echoes of Wisdom's final dungeon, skips the vast majority of the new Nintendo Switch game. 
</p>
<p>
Inevitably, Zelda's speedrunning community has seized on the glitch to massively boost completition times - though it is unclear how long the exploit will stick around. 
</p>
<p>
"It's now possible to [warp] from after you beat the first dungeon to the final dungeon (although it softlocks)," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/speedrun/comments/1ft6tfr/echoes_of_wisdom_game_breaking_glitch_discovered/">reddit</a> user xIceblue wrote, on a post which shows the exploit's method in detail. 
</p>
<p>
"So we found a way to [warp] to right before, fight the boss there, and proceed into the final area. That flag apparently removes the softlock, and allows us to beat the game with four hearts."
</p>
<p>
Footage posted by xIceblue, embedded below, shows the game's Echo ability being manipulated using a method that involves dropping signposts on top of trees, until multiple menus overlap on top of one another. This is clearly not intended behaviour. From here, users can open up the game's world map and simply drop Zelda down to near Echoes of Wisdom's finale.
</p>
<p>This should go without saying, but you should not watch the footage of someone warping to the game's final area if you do not wish to see the game's final area.</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="509"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/speedrun/comments/1ft6tfr/echoes_of_wisdom_game_breaking_glitch_discovered/">Echoes of Wisdom game breaking glitch discovered</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/xIceblue/">u/xIceblue</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/speedrun/">speedrun</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>
Over on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/twitch">Twitch</a>, Zelda speedrunner <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/onakutv">Onaku</a> has already posted an "any%" completion of the game at just 52 minutes (which you can watch on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VMPUrSFLQW4">YouTube</a>), but isn't stopping there. Onaku is currently streaming now, at the time of writing, and aiming to get that time even lower - at under 50 minutes.
</p>
<p>
It'll be interesting to see if this exploit lasts, or whether Nintendo patches it out in an upcoming update. 
</p>
<p>
"Thanks to playful puzzles and an imaginative reinvention of Hyrule's historic iconography, Echoes of Wisdom emerges as a bold and creative new chapter in Zelda's legend," Katharine wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-review-a-rebellious-remix-of-past-and-present">Eurogamer's The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom review</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League season three debuts to less than 300 Steam players]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-season-three-debuts-to-less-than-300-steam-players</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-season-three-debuts-to-less-than-300-steam-players.998376/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-season-three-debuts-to-less-than-300-steam-players<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Houston, we have a Gotham.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(383).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rocksteady</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league">Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</a>'s third season is here, but its Steam debut has failed to entice players back to the game.</p>
<p>Season three of Rocksteady's misfit co-op shooter arrived yesterday, 1st October, bringing new playable character Zoe Lawton with it. This season also lands players back in Gotham, but not as we have seen it before.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League - Season 3 - &quot;Meet Lawless&quot;" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WPubwl-kLUA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League - Season 3 - "Meet Lawless"</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WPubwl-kLUA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WPubwl-kLUA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League - Season 3 - "Meet Lawless". <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WPubwl-kLUA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"In this Elseworld, Earth held its last stand against Brainiac in Gotham City, rather than Metropolis," read <a href="https://www.suicidesquadgame.com/en-us/community/season-of-lawless-available-october-1">season three's notes</a>. "And after it fell, Brainiac decided he had little use for the failing city, leaving it to fall into the void."</p>
<p>All of this has left rivers of lava to pour through the city, and so on. Other additions this season include new gear and a number of bug fixes.</p>
<p>However, it seems not many people are really interested in seeing this version of DC's iconic city. According to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/315210/charts/">SteamDB</a>, Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League had a 24-hour player peak of just 248.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, at the time of writing, there are just 144 Steam players in the game.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GYvCelUWMAAr7yq.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rocksteady</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It's no secret Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League didn't take off with the success developer Rocksteady and publisher Warner Bros. had hoped.</p>
<p>Back in February of this year, Warner Bros. Discovery's chief financial officer Gunnar Wiedenfels said <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-fails-to-meet-warner-bros-expectations">Rocksteady's release had "fallen short" of its expectations</a>. Warner Bros. went on to attribute a $200m revenue loss to Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League. A report then followed in July which stated a culture of perfectionism, an ill-suited genre pivot, and a constantly shifting vision were <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squad-flopped-due-to-perfectionism-and-ill-suited-genre-pivot-report">key reasons for the live-service game's failure</a>.</p>
<p>In August, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squad-flop-leads-to-41-drop-in-warner-bros-gaming-revenue">Warner Bros. reported a 41 percent fall in gaming revenue year-on-year</a> due to the "weak performance" of Suicide Squad. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rocksteady-hit-by-layoffs-after-suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-underperforms">Layoffs were then confirmed at Rocksteady last month</a>, with the game's underperformance a reason for this "restructuring".</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squads-first-post-launch-season-includes-playable-elseworlds-joker">fourth season of Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</a> still appears to be on the cards.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2 May Not Be Only 30, 40 Percent Complete]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-not-40-percent-complete/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-may-not-be-only-30-40-percent-complete.998373/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-not-40-percent-complete/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Last week, it was widely reported that Death Stranding 2: On the Beach, the second entry in the series by Kojima Production, is only around 30,40 percent complete but is still targeting 2025. However, there's the chance that the development of the game could be in a more advanced state.</p>
<p>As reported by multiple users on X, it seems like the 30, 40 percent figure mentioned by Hideo Kojima during last week's Tokyo Game Show event may not be related to the actual development of the game or the Japanese voiceover recording. Kojima-san mentioned it while talking about his current work on balancing parts of the game the individual teams have done, so it could be that he is 30, 40 percent done with this balancing work rather than the entire game, which wouldn't make much sense for a game that is, at worst, only 14 months away.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The headline is wrong.</p>
<p>The community note too.</p>
<p>Kojima says that he’s currently balancing the parts of the game the individual teams have done. He just says 30-40% mid sentence, whether that’s 30-40% they’ve finished, he’s finished, or how much it makes up the game isn’t clear. <a href="https://t.co/kydK2tHfvM">https://t.co/kydK2tHfvM</a> <a href="https://t.co/Fe7ku1rMUo">pic.twitter.com/Fe7ku1rMUo</a></p>
<p>— Marcus (@Vamplosion) <a href="https://twitter.com/Vamplosion/status/1841268266762915970?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<p>In many ways, Death Stranding 2: On the Beach is set to outdo the previous entry in the series in a <a href="https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-looks-even-crazier-than-the-first-one-in-the-new-tgs-2024-footage/">lot of different ways</a>. Not only the game's Photo Mode will be wild and will influence the story of the game in some ways, but there will also be animated in-game concerts featuring actual artists.</p>
<p>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach launches sometime in <a href="https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-trailer-state-of-play-release-window/">2025</a> on PlayStation 5. A PC version of the game has yet to be announced, though it is likely it will be released around one year after the game's debut on console.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon’s new free to play MMORPG Throne And Liberty is coming for the Banana game’s crown]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amazons-new-free-to-play-mmorpg-throne-and-liberty-is-coming-for-the-banana-games-crown</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon%E2%80%99s-new-free-to-play-mmorpg-throne-and-liberty-is-coming-for-the-banana-game%E2%80%99s-crown.998370/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amazons-new-free-to-play-mmorpg-throne-and-liberty-is-coming-for-the-banana-games-crown<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>You can literally carry your mates</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/throne-and-liberty-golem.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Amazon Games/NCSOFT</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Despite just releasing yesterday, Amazon and NCSOFT’s massively mate-filled <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG </a><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/throne-and-liberty">Throne And Liberty</a> has already shot right up <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2429640/THRONE_AND_LIBERTY/">Steam</a>’s most played charts. It's sitting just behind <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukong-release-date-details-everything-we-know">Black Myth: Wukong</a> at number six at time of writing, which is sort of like getting the wobbly chair at a lavish dinner party. Sure, you’re 5% certain you’re going to break your neck at some point, but you’re still eating smoked salmon and chortling, so it’s a good evening. It had a beta earlier this year, which looks like it’s gone some way to drum up serious interest. It’s still not quite on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/banana-game">Banana</a>'s level, mind.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="THRONE AND LIBERTY: Claim the Throne | Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2dS4OpIWM6U?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>THRONE AND LIBERTY: Claim the Throne | Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2dS4OpIWM6U?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2dS4OpIWM6U?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2dS4OpIWM6U" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Set in a medieval fantasy world of knights, goblins, and very large lads made of rock dispatched solely for the purpose of destroying other things made of rocks, Throne And Liberty’s trick is it lets you transform into beasts like fish and birds to aid with travel, or even the massive golems shown in the trailer above. My research tells me you can then smash down castle walls during massive sieges. Or, as shown in the header image, literally carry your party. That’s fun! What happens if you then do a dancing emote, I wonder? Do they all fall to their death, or simply cling on to gargantuan, boogying form?</p>
<p>The golems are a great selling point, although it seems to take a good long while to get to that point - further exacerbated by the primary flavour of player gripes at the moment, which are targeted at long queue times and microtransactions. As <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/throne-and-liberty-rushes-steam-charts">spotted by Ian Games</a>, some players are spending up to 45 minutes creating a character, then getting disconnected. There’s also some freshly introduced issues with the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-games">Steam Deck</a>, apparently brought on by the anti-cheat. I believe James, who long ago replaced three of his favourite limbs with Steam Decks, is looking into this as we speak.</p>
<p>As for positives - and a lot of folk are clearly enjoying themselves - it’s apparently quite the looker in action, and both combat and questing are getting some compliments, too. There are also no set classes. Instead, you’ll switch roles by switching weapons. The main question I have before considering any MMO is this: is this going to be like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/final-fantasy-xiv-a-realm-reborn">Final Fantasy 14</a> where I’m having a really nice time until I have to do dungeons with other players then get really nervous about whether I’m performing my role in the party correctly? What if someone is watching the specific combination of attacks I’m using and thinks it’s stupid and suboptimal? I can’t deal with this. I can’t deal with it all. That’s not so much a question as it is a minor spiral into the depths of my fractious psyche, but that’s the MMO experience for me. Let me know if this one is a bit more chill than, uh, the famously chill FF14.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VALORANT is Moving to Unreal Engine 5 With “New Playable Experiences”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-is-moving-to-unreal-engine-5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-is-moving-to-unreal-engine-5-with-%E2%80%9Cnew-playable-experiences%E2%80%9D.998367/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-is-moving-to-unreal-engine-5/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-59350">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Riot Games has announced that VALORANT will move from Unreal Engine 4 to Unreal Engine 5.</p>



<p>The announcement was made by SVP and Head of&nbsp;VALORANT&nbsp;Studios, Anna Donlan, who said “we [Riot Games] have squeezed literally every ounce of everything we could get out of UE 4, so now we make the move to UE5, and that is not an easy feat when your game is a live service game but it is necessary.”</p>



<p>Donlon continued, “This upgrade is not going to significantly change how Valorant looks or performs, at least not right away.”</p>



<p>Donlon went on to tease that developers are “very excited what about UE5 can do for us [Riot Games] in the future” and that “maybe those devs are working on something I can’t talk about and maybe those devs are thinking about ways to expand the Val universe into new playable experiences.”</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>It remains to be seen what these “new playable experiences” are, but such comments are sure to get the Valorant community speculating on the possibilities.</p>



<p>For now though, Valorant continues to be a huge success for Riot Games since its release in June 2020. Last year, it was revealed that Valorant has 28 million players, 70% of which are Gen Z.</p>



<p>What do you think of Valorant moving to Unreal Engine 5? And what do you think what these “new experiences” are? Let us know in&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news regarding&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/">the latest Project Rene leaks</a>&nbsp;and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-remake-gameplay-leaked/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-remake-gameplay-leaked/">3 Hours of Until Dawn Remake Gameplay Leaks Online</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Three hours of the Until Dawn remake has leaked online ahead of the game’s official release on October 4, 2024.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-mobile-release/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-mobile-release/">Krafton Signs Agreement With Pockerpair to Bring Palworld to Mobile</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Krafton has singed an agreement with Palworld developers Pockerpair to bring Palworld to mobile.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-battle-royale-details-video-games/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-battle-royale-details-video-games/">Cancelled Halo Battle Royale Details Surface Online, Video Claims</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Several key details regarding the cancelled Halo battle royale project have surfaced online in a video, it has been claimed.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/">Project Rene Leaks Reveal ‘Disappointing’ Mobile Gaming Mechanics</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In a recent round of leaks from within Project Rene, screenshots have surfaced revealing some of the worst mobile mechanics.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony ensures PS5 30th Anniversary pre-orders have better scalper protection in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-ensures-ps5-30th-anniversary-pre-orders-have-better-scalper-protection-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-ensures-ps5-30th-anniversary-pre-orders-have-better-scalper-protection-in-japan.998364/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-ensures-ps5-30th-anniversary-pre-orders-have-better-scalper-protection-in-japan<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>After eBay flooded with resold consoles elsewhere.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/5be63d624c866414c7e7d6ff2bcdb9f960ad2963.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sony</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Pre-orders for the limited edition PlayStation 5 30th Anniversary range will come with an extra layer of scalper protection in Japan, Sony has said, following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ps5-pro-30th-anniversary-bundles-already-selling-for-thousands-on-ebay">the rampant relisting of consoles with exorbitant prices on eBay</a> seen elsewhere.
</p>
<p>
Japanese PlayStation fans <a href="https://www.playstation.com/ja-jp/local/campaigns/ps5-30th-register-to-pre-order/">can now place pre-orders</a> for the 30th Anniversary collection but require a PlayStation Network account with at least 30 hours' worth of play to be eligible. This is different to the method elsewhere, where any PSN account could be used.
</p>
<p>
In Japan, fans have far longer to register a pre-order - from now until midnight on Monday 14th October - to reduce queuing issues. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Introducing the PlayStation 30th Anniversary Collection" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/amdZnHooTkk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Introducing the PlayStation 30th Anniversary Collection</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/amdZnHooTkk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/amdZnHooTkk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Introducing the PlayStation 30th Anniversary collection.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=amdZnHooTkk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
After that time, all eligible pre-orders will be placed into a lottery system to give every potential customer a fair chance (if the number of pre-orders ends up exceeding the amount of stock, which is of course inevitable).
</p>
<p>
Any stock not bought by lottery winners will then be entered into a "re-lottery" in late November, with unsuccessful pre-order customers from the first round given another shot. 
</p>
<p>
It all seems a far fairer and more straightforward system than <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ps5-pro-30th-anniversary-bundle-priced-960-sells-out-in-seconds">the one used in the UK and US, where customers saw consoles sold out in seconds</a> - if they could get through the wobbly queuing process at all.
</p>
<p>
Another check of eBay listings here in the UK today shows dozens of recently-sold PS5 30th Edition console pre-orders that have changed hands, the vast majority in the low thousands of pounds - a markup by scalpers of around double to quadruple the console's original price.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[God of War Ragnarok PC Patch 4 Improves AMD FSR 3 Frame Generation, Fixes NVIDIA Memory Leak Issues]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-patch-4-frame-generation-improvements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-patch-4-improves-amd-fsr-3-frame-generation-fixes-nvidia-memory-leak-issues.998355/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-patch-4-frame-generation-improvements/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new God of War Ragnarok patch is now live for the PC version of the game, improving AMD FSR 3 frame generation and fixing a variety of issues.</p>
<p>Patch 4 focuses on fixing several issues, including crashes, authentication flow, and texture issues, which will no longer unload while looking at the menu for a set amount of time and won't be shown loading in while using fast travel through the Realm Between Realms.</p>
<p>The new God of War Ragnarok patch also fixes an NVIDIA memory leak issue caused by switching between different Frame Generation settings. The patch, as mentioned above, also brings some AMD FSR 3 frame generation improvements, fixing flickering in the pause menu, performance and frame pacing issues, and a small memory leak caused by turning it on and off. Rounding up the changes brought by the patch, which can be found detailed in full<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2322010/view/4681018807420990578?l=english"> here</a>, are Steam Deck offline mode and DualSense controller fixes.</p>
<p>God of War Ragnarok finally launched on PC last month after almost two years since its console release, and the port is definitely a solid one, although it has some <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-worse-playstation-5/">issues</a> that make it not look as good as the PlayStation 5 version. The port also doesn't offer many options to scale beyond the PS5 version's Quality Mode.</p>
<p>God of War Ragnarok is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, and PlayStation 4 worldwide. You can learn more about the latest entry in the series by checking out our<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/god-of-war-ragnarok-becoming-a-good-father/"> review.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite maker now "financially sound" after mass layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-maker-now-financially-sound-after-mass-layoffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-maker-now-financially-sound-after-mass-layoffs.998349/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-maker-now-financially-sound-after-mass-layoffs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>A year after 830 people lost jobs.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Unreal-Fest-Seattle-2024-_-Opening-Session-27-32-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Epic Games is now "financially sound" after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-games-is-reportedly-laying-off-900-employees">shedding around 830 staff during last year's mass layoff</a>, founder Tim Sweeney has said. 
</p>
<p>
Speaking last night during a stage presentation at Unreal Fest, Sweeney briefly acknowledged the job losses as the show opened, before going on to mention last year's high watermark of engagement with the hugely-lucrative <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a>, that featured a massively successful throwback "OG" season. 
</p>
<p>
"Last year's Unreal Fest began with some sad news," Sweeney said. "The company had to get its finances in order, and we just had some major layoffs. We spent the last year rebuilding and also really executing solidly on all fronts.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Unreal Fest Seattle 2024 | Opening Session" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KYGEfQJPqW8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Unreal Fest Seattle 2024 | Opening Session</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KYGEfQJPqW8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KYGEfQJPqW8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Unreal Fest 2024 opening keynote.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KYGEfQJPqW8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"I'm happy to tell you now that the company is financially sound, and that Fortnite and the Epic Games Store have hit new records in concurrency and success. Fortnite hit 110 million monthly active users last holiday, an all-time peak."
</p>
<p>
It's worth noting that Fortnite player numbers have dropped back down since then, and the launch of last year's new modes have had mixed success, though <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/lego-fortnite">Lego Fortnite</a> in particular remains popular.
</p>
<p>
Epic Games remains hugely busy, with ongoing work across the ubiquitous Unreal Engine and its UEFN toolset for building and launching games in Fortnite, the growth of Epic Game Store, and a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-launches-major-new-lawsuit-in-app-store-fight-this-time-against-samsung-and-google">fresh legal battle announced this week with Google and Samsung</a>.
</p>
<p>
On UEFN, new modes developed by Epic Games using the technology for Fortnite were mentioned - an all-new experience set to arrive in the game this year, and a new version of the popular Fortnite Reload mode, due in the next few weeks.
</p>
<p>
And on the Epic Game Store, a new "Launch Everywhere with Epic" offer will trim Epic's existing royalty from five to 3.5 percent from 1st January 2025, to incentivise launching on its storefront. This will apply to games available on Epic's platform first or at the same time as other platforms such as Steam.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld is Coming To Mobile With PUBG Publisher Krafton Securing Global License For The Title]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/palworld-is-coming-to-mobile-with-pubg-publisher-krafton-securing-global-license-for-the-title/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-is-coming-to-mobile-with-pubg-publisher-krafton-securing-global-license-for-the-title.998346/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/palworld-is-coming-to-mobile-with-pubg-publisher-krafton-securing-global-license-for-the-title/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Krafton is best known for publishing PUBG Battlegrounds, the game that transformed the battle Royale genre and paved the way for its popularity. South Korea continues to expand and invest in new technologies and platforms. Now, the gaming giant has announced that it will partner up with Pocketpair to bring its popular survival crafting game Palworld to mobile devices and has secured licensing agreements for the extension of the game to mobile platforms.</p>
<h2>Krafton has announced today about signing a licensing agreement with Pocketpair to bring Palword to mobile devices</h2>
<p>Pocketpair is increasingly focusing on expanding its Palworld, a highly anticipated open-world survival game, to Xbox, PC, and PS5. It is now taking the leap in the mobile gaming industry with the help of Krafton, a South Korean game publisher that gained massive popularity for its PUBG Battlegrounds.</p>
<p>In a<a href="https://www.krafton.com/news/press/%ed%81%ac%eb%9e%98%ed%94%84%ed%86%a4-%ed%8c%b0%ec%9b%94%eb%93%9c-%eb%aa%a8%eb%b0%94%ec%9d%bc-%ea%b2%8c%ec%9e%84-%ea%b8%80%eb%a1%9c%eb%b2%8c-%eb%9d%bc%ec%9d%b4%ec%84%a0%ec%8a%a4/"> press release</a>, Krafton announced that it would secure a licensing agreement for Palworld's intellectual property (IP) to bring the game to mobile platforms. The game would be developed by PUBG STUDIOS under Krafton, who would mimic the game's main elements and make it suitable for the mobile environment. In the press release, the company explains:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>It plans to faithfully reinterpret and implement the original’s main fun elements to fit the mobile environment. The project will be handled by the development team of ‘PUBG STUDIOS,’ a creative studio under Krafton.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Palworld's <a href="https://wccftech.com/palworld-is-now-the-most-popular-game-on-xbox-game-pass/">expansion</a> to Xbox and PC has already helped the company gain 25 million players and sell over 15 million copies, and the game even has secured the third-highest number of concurrent users on Steam. It further extended its platforms by making its debut on PS5 this September. The game owes its popularity to the enticing gameplay that keeps the players hooked and the monster-breeding mechanics incorporated into a charming world.</p>
<p>Krafton and Pocketpair partnering up to bring Palworld to mobile devices would help gain a wider player base and can also aid the company with its leading position in the survival crafting category.&nbsp; Although Pocketpair has managed to gain massive popularity, especially after its continuous expansion, it is not entirely a breeze as Nintendo has recently sued the company for patent infringement.</p>
<p>Palworld is currently available on PC, Xbox Series XIS consoles, and PlayStation 5 and can be accessed through Xbox Game Pass. Soon, players will be able to enjoy unique gaming on their mobile devices.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Nintendo’s Pokémon Lawsuit, Palworld Dev Pocketpair Signs Deal for Mobile Version]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-nintendos-pokmon-lawsuit-palworld-dev-pocketpair-signs-deal-for-mobile-version</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amid-nintendo%E2%80%99s-pok%C3%A9mon-lawsuit-palworld-dev-pocketpair-signs-deal-for-mobile-version.998343/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-nintendos-pokmon-lawsuit-palworld-dev-pocketpair-signs-deal-for-mobile-version<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/palworld">Palworld</a> developer Pocketpair has signed a deal with PUBG company Krafton to develop a mobile version of the hit game.</p><p>Krafton, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hi-fi-rush-2-dev-wants-it-to-have-a-more-open-world-type-of-experience-new-owner-says">fresh from acquiring Hi-Fi Rush developer Tango Gameworks from Microsoft</a>, has now inked a licensing agreement with Pocketpair to expand the Palworld intellectual property to mobile devices, <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/krafton-to-develop-palworld-mobile-game" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gematsu</a> reported.</p><p>Krafton’s subsidiary PUBG Studios will develop the mobile version of Palworld, which reimagines and adapts the core gameplay elements for mobile. No release window was mentioned.</p><p>PUBG Studios is the development arm behind the phenomenally successful battle royale as well as its equally successful mobile versions. Indeed, PUBG Mobile has had over one billion players since launching in March 2018.</p><p>The announcement of Palworld mobile comes hot on the heels of Nintendo and The Pokémon Company’s joint lawsuit against Pocketpair for alleged patent infringement, and the subsequent launch of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/palworld-ps5-release-postponed-in-japan-amid-nintendo-pokmon-patent-lawsuit">Palworld on PlayStation 5 everywhere except Japan</a>, where the lawsuit was filed.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/palworld-developer-pocketpair-responds-to-nintendo-pokmon-lawsuit-says-its-unaware-of-the-patents-its-accused-of-infringing"><u>Pocketpair has</u> insisted</a> it has no idea which patents it’s accused of infringing, but experts have pointed to a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-vs-palworld-killer-patent-may-be-about-the-mechanic-of-catching-pokmon"><u>“killer patent” that revolves around the mechanic of catching Pokémon itself</u></a>. Last week, one patent expert said <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-lawsuit-shows-just-how-seriously-nintendo-views-the-threat-of-palworld-patent-expert-says">the lawsuit shows “just how seriously Nintendo views the threat of Palworld.”</a></p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Palworld vs. Pokémon Comparison</h3></div></output><p>After Palworld’s huge launch earlier this year on PC and Xbox, comparisons were made between Palworld’s Pals and Pokémon, with some accusing Pocketpair of "ripping off" Pokémon designs. But rather than file a copyright infringement lawsuit, Nintendo and The Pokémon Company have gone down the patent route.</p><p>It is worth noting that Palworld <em>does</em> include a mechanic that involves throwing a ball-like object (called a Pal Sphere) at monsters out in a field to capture them, similar to the mechanic seen in the 2022 Nintendo Switch exclusive <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-legends-arceus"><u>Pokémon Legends: Arceus</u></a>, and this may prove the key to the lawsuit.</p><p>Palworld launched on Steam priced $30 and straight into Game Pass on Xbox and PC earlier this year, breaking sales and concurrent player number records in the process. Pocketpair boss Takuro Mizobe has said Palworld's launch was so big that the developer <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/palworld-dev-says-massive-profits-are-too-big-for-a-studio-with-our-size-to-handle"><u>couldn’t handle the massive profits the game generated</u></a>.</p><p>Still, Pocketpair acted swiftly to capitalize on Palworld’s breakout success, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/palworld-dev-signs-deal-with-sony-to-form-palworld-entertainment-and-expand-the-ip"><u>signing a deal with Sony</u></a> to form a new business called Palworld Entertainment that’s tasked with expanding the IP.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Pokémon Trading Card Game Pocket Images</h3></div></output><p>While the Pokémon games are mostly at home on consoles, Nintendo has launched a number of spin-offs aimed at other devices, including mobile. <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-go">Pokémon GO</a> has seen enormous success since launching in 2016, generating billions of dollars in revenue. There’s also <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-unite">Pokémon Unite</a>, a MOBA released for mobile and Nintendo Switch, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-sleep">Pokémon Sleep</a>, a sleep-tracking game that rewards the user with Pokémon depending on the quality of their sleep.</p><p>Indeed, a new Pokémon mobile game is right around the corner: <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket">Pokémon Trading Card Game Pocket</a>, a mobile version of the Pokemon TCG, launches October 30, 2024.</p><p>Pocketpair has said it will begrudgingly investigate the patent infringement claims while continuing to update Palworld despite the lawsuit, and apologized to players left concerned about the future of the game.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two F-Zero games headed to Switch Online, including previously Japan-only release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/two-f-zero-games-headed-to-switch-online-including-previously-japan-only-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-f-zero-games-headed-to-switch-online-including-previously-japan-only-release.998340/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/two-f-zero-games-headed-to-switch-online-including-previously-japan-only-release<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Plus F-Zero 99 gets an update.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Game-Boy-Advance-%E2%80%93-October-2024-Game-Update-%E2%80%93-Nintendo-Switch-Online-%2B-Expansion-Pack-0-14-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nintendo</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Two F-Zero games are headed to Nintendo's Switch Online subscription, including a previously Japan-only release.</p>
<p>Both games launched on the Game Boy Advance and will be available on Switch from 11th October.</p>
<p>The first is F-Zero: GP Legend, which followed GBA launch game F-Zero: Maximum Velocity and was released in Europe in 2004. It plays similarly to the SNES original, but includes a Story mode based on the anime of the same name.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Game Boy Advance – October 2024 Game Update – Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VxqYOmjPWF0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Game Boy Advance – October 2024 Game Update – Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VxqYOmjPWF0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VxqYOmjPWF0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Game Boy Advance – October 2024 Game Update – Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VxqYOmjPWF0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The second is F-Zero Climax, a sequel to GP Legend that was previously only available in Japan, also released in 2004. It's more of an expansion than a full sequel, but is notable for its Course Editor that allows players to create their own tracks using specific pieces.</p>
<p>F-Zero Climax was the last release in the series for 19 years, until F-Zero 99 arrived on Switch Online last year.</p>
<p>Speaking of, F-Zero 99 has received a new update with additional content that's available today.</p>
<p>There's a new Grand Prix Ace League, five new tracks (including some from the Satellaview), new machine decals, and an expanded Practice Mode. Additionally, some balance tweaks have been made to the Wild Goose and Fire Stingray machines.</p>
<p>Nintendo is also holding a one-year anniversary event, where players can earn 12 anniversary badges, backdrops, borders, and emotes.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>I enjoyed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/f-zero-99-feels-like-a-battle-royale-in-a-pinball-machine">F-Zero 99 when it was released last September</a>, describing it as "a battle royale in a pinball machine".</p>
<p>It's great to see Nintendo updating the game further and including more games from the series in its Switch Online offering. Now all we need is a proper brand new game - wishful thinking?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Tsushima follow-up will have a less repetitive open world]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ghost-of-tsushima-follow-up-will-have-a-less-repetitive-open-world</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-tsushima-follow-up-will-have-a-less-repetitive-open-world.998334/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ghost-of-tsushima-follow-up-will-have-a-less-repetitive-open-world<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>And a story of "underdog vengeance".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ghost-of-Y%C5%8Dtei---Announce-Trailer-_-PS5-Games-2-11-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sucker Punch</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Ghost of Yōtei, the newly revealed follow-up to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ghost-of-tsushima">Ghost of Tsushima</a>, will have a less repetitive open world.</p>
<p>Sucker Punch's Nate Fox and Jason Connell, creative directors on Ghost of Tsushima, were interviewed by <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/24/arts/ghost-of-yotei-tsushima-sequel-playstation.html?smtyp=cur&amp;smid=tw-nytimes">The NY Times</a> to discuss the sequel, due out next year on PS5.</p>
<p>"One challenge that comes with making an open-world game is the repetitive nature of doing the same thing over again," said Connell. "We wanted to balance against that and find unique experiences."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Ghost of Yōtei - Announce Trailer | PS5 Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7z7kqwuf0a8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Ghost of Yōtei - Announce Trailer | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7z7kqwuf0a8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/7z7kqwuf0a8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Ghost of Yōtei - Announce Trailer | PS5 Games<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7z7kqwuf0a8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Indeed, the first game was criticised for its repetitive activities used to fill out its open world. With Yotei, new protagonist Atsu will be able to master firearms in addition to melee weapons, and players will have greater control over her story.</p>
<p>Ghost of Yōtei will be a story of "underdog vengeance", as Atsu travels across grasslands and tundras.</p>
<p>That setting was inspired by two research trips by Sucker Punch to northern Japan, with the view of Mount Yōtei across Lake Toya inspiring awe. "I sat there for two hours just staring at the mountain," said Connell. "It was stunning."</p>
<p>The Shiretoko National Park, in the northeast of Hokkaido, also proved inspirational. "Inside the park, you have to watch a video telling you about the dangers of bears," said Fox. "Being in this incredibly beautiful park with jagged cliffs and water, yet all the time being aware there were dangerous bears, was electrifying.</p>
<p>"We strive to bring that into the video game - that feeling of danger."</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-reveals-ghost-of-yotei-the-follow-up-to-ghost-of-tsushima">Ghost of Yōtei was unveiled at Sony's recent PlayStation State of Play</a>. The trailer introduced Atsu and has something of a Western vibe to it, set a few hundred years after Ghost of Tsushima.</p>
<p>"To create something fresh but familiar, we looked beyond Jin Sakai’s story and the island of Tsushima, and shifted our focus to the idea of the Ghost instead," wrote Sucker Punch communications manager Andrew Goldfarb on the PlayStation Blog.</p>
<p>"At Sucker Punch we love origin stories, and we wanted to explore what it could mean to have a new hero wearing a Ghost mask, and uncovering a new legend. This led us to Ghost of Yōtei: a new protagonist, a new story to unfold, and a new region of Japan to explore."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 deserves better than these awful WizKids miniatures that look like they’d melt on a mildly temperate afternoon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-deserves-better-than-these-awful-wizkids-miniatures-that-look-like-theyd-melt-on-a-mildly-temperate-afternoon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-deserves-better-than-these-awful-wizkids-miniatures-that-look-like-they%E2%80%99d-melt-on-a-mildly-temperate-afternoon.998322/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-deserves-better-than-these-awful-wizkids-miniatures-that-look-like-theyd-melt-on-a-mildly-temperate-afternoon<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bg3-cast.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Larian Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Look. Having basically sold both of my best standing legs to buy more <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/55690/kingdom-death-monster">Kingdom Death Monster</a> expansions, I can’t bemoan anyone spending silly amounts of money on whatever plastic tat makes them happy. But I love<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii"> Baldur’s Gate 3</a>, and it makes me sad to see all the wonderful art, writing, and acting that went into its characters reduced to $6 miniatures that look like their limbs would melt if I rubbed them between my thumb and forefinger.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/baldurs-gate/official-baldur-s-gate-3-miniatures-are-coming-but-the-origin-characters-will-set-you-back-50/">As spotted by PC Gamer</a>, WizKids have recently opened pre-orders for a set of greasy pre-painted fetishes based on Larian’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a>. WizKids, of course, being the maker of supermarket-discount-aisle-ass toys but, ah, they’ve got a base on them so we can pretend they’re proper models and charge you accordingly. Moaning about toys now, are we Nic? Is this what the profession has been reduced to? And to that I say: videogames are toys anyway, they’re just slightly better at hiding it. Also, several of them are worth owning.</p>

<p>Look how they plas-acred my boy:</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/astarion-wizkids.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>WizKids/Wotc</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Okay, sure. The sculpts aren’t totally terrible in terms of silhouettes and detail, but at $25 for four randomised figures, I expect something a bit more, uh, good. Astarion above is from the <a href="https://shop.wizkids.com/collections/pre-order-collection/products/d-d-icons-of-the-realms-baldurs-gate-3-character-boxed-set">bigger box set</a>, which features all six origin characters, plus withers, for $50, or about £38. You’d have to go to a third party retailer, admittedly, but you could buy an entire 40K Kill Team for that. Don’t like Warhammer? Fine. You know who’d look much, much better on your D&amp;D table, and also comes with four miniatures for about the same price? This guy:</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/boris.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Goblin King Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This is Boris The Bunny Summoner from <a href="https://www.moonstonethegame.com/">Moonstone</a>, and he is but one of many beautiful miniatures they sell. Don’t like Boris? That’s fine. For the same price, you could get six halfling shieldmaidens riding walruses from <a href="https://ttcombat.com/collections/half-tilt">TT COMBAT</a>. You cannot tell me this wouldn't be a more fun dungeon encounter than Karlach's evil, waxy twin busting through a wall.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/shieldmaidens.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>TTCOMBAT</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Okay, one more. Check out this Owlbear <a href="https://zealotminiatures.com/product/owlbear/">from Zealot Miniatures</a>.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Zealot_Miniatures_Owlbear.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Zealot Miniatures</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Now look at this actual bear from Wizkids:</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wizkids-bear.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>WizKids/Wotc</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Yes, yes. Paint and glue. I know. Point still stands. This bear looks like it came from a bucket on the counter of a museum gift shop. If anyone from WizKids reads this then... 1. It’s satire. I’m writing about your stupid, defective products satirically, and 2. Do NOT send me any bears to try and prove their worth. I know where they've been.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Krafton and Pocketpair partner to bring Palworld to mobile platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/krafton-and-pocketpair-partner-to-bring-palworld-to-mobile</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/krafton-and-pocketpair-partner-to-bring-palworld-to-mobile-platforms.998313/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/krafton-and-pocketpair-partner-to-bring-palworld-to-mobile<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Krafton has penned a licensing agreement with Pocketpair to bring </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Palworld</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to mobile platforms.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Korean company explained the project will be overseen by </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>PUBG: Battlegrounds</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer PUBG Studios.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.krafton.com/news/press/%ED%81%AC%EB%9E%98%ED%94%84%ED%86%A4-%ED%8C%B0%EC%9B%94%EB%93%9C-%EB%AA%A8%EB%B0%94%EC%9D%BC-%EA%B2%8C%EC%9E%84-%EA%B8%80%EB%A1%9C%EB%B2%8C-%EB%9D%BC%EC%9D%B4%EC%84%A0%EC%8A%A4/">In a translated press release</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Krafton said it will "faithfully reinterpret and implement" the core elements of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Palworld</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Palworld</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> launched earlier this year for console and PC and has </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/palworld-evolves-to-25-million-players">attracted over 25 million players</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The title has been compared to Pokemon over its inclusion of recruitable monsters (captured via a ball-tossing mechanic), but there are some key differences between the two franchises–including the fact </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Palworld's</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> adorable creatures can wield firearms.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Even so, the similarities have pricked the ears of Nintendo and The Pokemon Company, which recently </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-sues-palworld-developer-pocketpair-for-alleged-patent-infringement">filed a patent infringement lawsuit against Pocketpair</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/pocketpair-says-nintendo-hasn-t-revealed-what-patents-palworld-allegedly-violates">In response</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Pocketpair said it's "unaware of the specific patents" it has supposedly violated and described the situation as "truly unfortunate."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pocketpair remains keen to expand the franchise. Its partnership with Krafton has been announced a few months after the Japanese company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/pocketpair-forms-palworld-entertainment-with-sony-music-and-aniplex-to-expand-ip">formed Palworld Entertainment</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in tandem with Sony Music and Aniplex to "develop new businesses associated with the hit game."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The joint venture will be responsible for developing the reach of the intellectual property and for expanding commercial business endeavors, including the global licensing and merchandising activities associated with Palworld, outside of the interactive game," reads a press release issued in July.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"[Our] efforts will begin with the development of exclusive merchandise based on the game—which will debut and sell at the Pocketpair booth during Bilibili World 2024."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Krafton, meanwhile, will be developing a mobile version of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Palworld</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> alongside a sequel to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company, which recently </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/krafton-acquires-tango-gameworks-and-hi-fi-rush-franchise-from-microsoft">acquired Tango Gamesworks from Microsoft</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, confirmed it plans to create a sequel to the critically acclaimed rhythmic adventure </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-we-don-t-think-hi-fi-rush-2-is-going-to-make-us-money-krafton-ceo-says-tango-gameworks-acquisition-is-about-legacy">during a recent interview with Game Developer</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Hours of Until Dawn Remake Gameplay Leaks Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-remake-gameplay-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/3-hours-of-until-dawn-remake-gameplay-leaks-online.998301/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-remake-gameplay-leaked/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Three hours of gameplay of the Until Dawn remake has leaked online ahead of the game’s official release on October 4, 2024.</p>



<p>Twitch streamer <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2265248394" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Nikolai7PT</a> leaked the three hours of Until Dawn Remake gameplay during a live stream on October 1, with the VOD still available to watch on his channel. </p>



<p>As expected, the VOD was soon posted to the /r/GamingLeaksAndRumours subreddit, where the game was criticized for being full-priced. User <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/BARD3NGUNN/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">/u/BARD3NGUNN</a> said, “I mean if Horizon can redo all it’s graphics, add in Duelsense features, and rerecord over 10hrs of motion capture to bring cutscenes upto modern standards and charge $10 to existing players, then realistically Until Dawn should have done the same.”</p>



<p>He continued, “It’s a great game, but there’s nothing this remaster can really do to improve the gameplay considering the limitations of the genre, and they’ve not expanded the story, so you’re basically left with a remaster of an interactive movie that’s releasing alongside the likes of Silent Hill, Dragon Ball, and Metaphor (all around a similar price physical) – it’s really a hard sell.”</p>



<p>In September, Until Dawn Remake developers <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ballistic-moon-layoffs/">Ballistic Moon announced </a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ballistic-moon-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">t</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ballistic-moon-layoffs/">hat the studio had faced layoffs</a>, affecting an undisclosed number of developers. </p>



<p>Until Dawn currently has a film adaption in the works from PlayStation Productions and Sony’s Screen Gems, which is believed to be in early production.</p>



<p>In our guide here, you can see all <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-trophy-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">29 trophies coming to Until Dawn</a>.</p>



<p>What do you think of the Until Dawn Remake gameplay? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news regarding&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/">the latest Project Rene leaks</a>&nbsp;and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kill Knight Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/02/kill-knight-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kill-knight-review.998286/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/02/kill-knight-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/02/kill-knight-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Kill Knight Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Miguel Moran">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-10-02">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-10-02">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Sometimes, video games are complicated pieces of art. They have multiple layers of intertwining mechanics and themes and inspirations that are almost impossible to summarize unless you open with “okay so, this is a lot but basically…” and pray the person you’re talking to is a really good listener. Other times, though, video games aren’t like that at all. They’re like <em>Kill Knight. </em>You’re a knight. You kill. Done. I didn’t realise how long it’s been since I’ve had a simple, smooth, endless action game to sink my teeth into, but <em>Kill Knight </em>quickly reminded me<em>. </em>Combining the addictive “one more run” mentality of <em>Downwell </em>and <em>Devil Daggers </em>with <em>Hades-style </em>lightning-reflex combat and a sleek yet violent aesthetic has resulted in one of the most electrifying games of the year.</p>
<p><iframe title="KILL KNIGHT |  RELEASE DATE ANNOUNCEMENT" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6IXLFc0L4z0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>There’s an obscure RPG-inspired artbook series I’m in love with called <em>Vermis. </em>Sold as a lost player guide to a forgotten roleplaying game, it’s full of haunting medieval-fantasy art where something is just always kind of… <em>off. </em>I’ve never seen that uncomfortable yet alluring aesthetic replicated anywhere else until I started playing <em>Kill Knight. </em>Menus and UI are sharp, yet the art and visual accompanying them give off a violent, zine-style setting where you have no idea where you are or what you’re doing but you still can’t help but love it. It’s a game full of barely comprehensible monster designs, equipment covered in spikes and blades, and menu backgrounds lifted straight from screen-printed sludge metal band shirts. I see a lot of new games come out where the mechanics are sharply defined or uniquely inventive, but they lack any sort of visual identity that matches that creativity. <em>Kill Knight </em>delivers on both.</p>


<p>Your goal is simple – survive wave-based combat in a constantly evolving arena, and if you do, you’ll unlock another arena with new visuals, enemies, and hazards to tackle. You’ve got a pretty simple set of abilities to use in order to achieve that, but they all feed into each other in a circular loop that keeps your brain firing on all cylinders as you play. You’ve got a standard gun attack, and when you need to reload you can tap three different buttons to activate three different Overdrive abilities.</p>


<p>Tap the fire button to Overdrive your primary weapon and activate a bonus ability, tap the melee button to activate a buffed melee attack, or tap the Absorb button to instantly suck up every dropped gem on the field. You can melee whenever you want, too, and melee kills earn you ammo for your heavy weapon. Absorbing can be done at any time at a slower rate, and when you absorb enough, you can unleash a special Heavy attack that will drop health pickups from anything it hits. Add on a quick-dash and a melee parry, and you’ve got a combat system that’s simple on paper, but complicated in execution.</p>
<p>My first few runs were rough. I’d focus too much on one attack type, or get so caught up watching enemy behaviour I wouldn’t even realize they had me overwhelmed until it was too late. When you’re on your toes and racking up kills, the combo meter isn’t just for flair – it feeds into a system that buffs all of your abilities the higher your racked-up combo gets. Systems like that where your score and combo are directly tied into beneficial gameplay systems, rather than just being for glory and bragging rights, are one of my favourite things to see in games. I rarely care how high my score is or how sick my combo gets, but when that stuff directly helps me survive more waves, you bet I’m paying attention.</p>

<p>If you fail a run, you’ll still earn some points and a spot on the leaderboard. Points can be hoarded to spend on unlocking new equipment, but you’ll be able to unlock all those tools even quicker if you successfully achieve their per-requisite missions during any run. It’s a really solid combination of parallel goals that always gave me something to focus on in each run. By the time I got comfortable with one combination of equipment and one stage, I was already ready to tackle another stage, or try out some new equipment, or both. I was kept on a consistent and constantly engaging pattern of unlocks through all five stages of the game, and I couldn’t get enough of it.</p>
<p><em>Kill Knight </em>is just a blast. Runs are quick, hectic, and satisfying even in defeat. It’s a lot to learn at first, but the second I overcame that learning curve I couldn’t put the game down until I saw it through to the end.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Playing Kill Knight feels like what happens if you gave a medieval peasant a bottle of soda. It's violent, and unexpected, and adrenaline-charged and fun as hell. 	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Incredible, haunting art style</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Addictive, engaging combat</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Solid amount of unlocks and equipment variety</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Difficult initial learning curve</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Patch 1.15 Improves Performance, Fixes Bugs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-patch-1-15-improves-performance-and-fixes-bugs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-patch-1-15-improves-performance-fixes-bugs.998283/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-patch-1-15-improves-performance-and-fixes-bugs/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>FromSoftware has <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/news/elden-ring-patch-notes-version-115?utm_source=SM_Official&amp;utm_medium=official_post&amp;utm_campaign=ER-PatchNotes115" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> a new Elden Ring patch today, updating the game to version 1.15. This is a small patch, but it contains a number of performance improvements and several bug fixes, as listed below.</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed a bug where the cutscene that plays when entering the Shadow Keep Church District would play again when re-entering the area.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug where some of the Golem Fist weapon attacks would not deal damage when the player was affected by certain special effects.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug where the Golem Fist weapon one-handed heavy attack power was lower than expected.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug that prevented the Aspects of the Crucible: Thorns incantation from being cast when used in quick succession.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug where the Smithing Talisman effect did not apply to some weapons’ throwing attacks.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug that prevented the use of ashes in some areas of the Scadutree Avatar battle arena.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug where Rellana, Twin Moon Knight would sometimes perform unexpected actions when interacting with objects in the battle area.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug that allowed Skills to be used in incorrect combinations with Weapons under certain circumstances.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug that caused unexpected rendering and behavior of some enemies under certain circumstances.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug where some sound effects did not play correctly.</li>
<li>Several performance improvements and other bug fixes.</li>
<li>Further fixes were added to the game’s end credits.</li>
</ul>
<p>The changelog of the Elden Ring patch also includes some tips on improving performance in case you're experiencing issues. According to the developers, the PlayStation 5 version of the game might improve frame rate stability by using the Rebuild Database option from the console's safe mode. PC players should check whether ray tracing has been automatically enabled; if so, they can disable it. Third-party apps that handle mouse behavior may also negatively impact the performance of Elden Ring. Lastly, FromSoftware says that the message 'inappropriate activity detected' may appear even mistakenly. In that case, PC users should verify the integrity of the files.</p>
<p>Elden Ring won't get any more expansions after <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-worthy-of-the-greater-wills-blessing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shadow of the Erdtree</a>, but the studio will likely update it with minor patches for a while.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hi-Rez Studios lay off unknown number of workers to give Smite 2 "a sustainable future"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hi-rez-studios-lay-off-unknown-number-of-workers-to-give-smite-2-a-sustainable-future</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hi-rez-studios-lay-off-unknown-number-of-workers-to-give-smite-2-a-sustainable-future.998280/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hi-rez-studios-lay-off-unknown-number-of-workers-to-give-smite-2-a-sustainable-future<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Who has "reprioritization" on their newspeak bingo card?</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Smite-2-screen10.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Titan Forge Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/smite-2">Smite 2</a> developers Hi-Rez Studios have laid off an unspecified number of workers, as part of what they call a "internal reorganization and reprioritization". The layoffs would ultimately benefit Smite 2, claimed the company's boss, who added that the cuts "disproportionally affect" those working on cosmetic skins and game "system features", as well as people in marketing and publishing roles.  </p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Today, we’re making difficult but necessary changes to ensure Hi-Rez's long-term success, with a specific focus on positioning Smite 2 for a long and sustainable future," said CEO Stewart Chisham in <a href="https://x.com/schisam/status/1841072179028324382">a Xitter post</a> yesterday. </p>
<p>"This move follows a comprehensive review of our strategy and operations. In the game division, we have decided to concentrate our efforts entirely on Smite 2, outside of small teams supporting light updates for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/paladins">Paladins</a> and Smite 1.</p>
<p>"While these changes are difficult, we believe they are necessary and we will emerge stronger from them."</p>
<p>The executive called the measures a "heartbreaking decision" reflecting "a failure in my leadership, and one for which I take personal accountability." It's not clear whether he means the act of "reprioritization" has affected himself somehow, or whether these are simply the usual words of empty sympathy from management often spoken in such times. </p>
<p>Hi-Rez also had a round of layoffs last year, with <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/layoffs-expected-as-hi-rez-studios-restructures">30 people losing their jobs</a> as part of a larger restructuring that saw the company's uberstructure split into several different chunks, all overseen by a new corporate entity known as Hi-Rez Ventures. </p>
<p> As for the studio's focus shifting heavily towards Smite 2, that's sort of expected, and likely would have happened whether or not people lost their jobs. The game itself is grand enough, as MOBAs go, at least according to Matt Cox when he wrote our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/smite-2-early-access-review">Smite 2 early access review</a>. Although he did mention <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/deadlock">Deadlock</a> as an obvious and superior competitor, calling it "Valve’s third-person elephant in the lane". </p>
<p>The layoffs, meanwhile, happen amid a wider trend of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-iv-support-studio-hit-by-layoffs-putting-139-people-out-of-work-proving-that-embracers-restructuring-is-not-over">"restructuring"</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-publishers-take-two-cancel-games-and-lay-off-hundreds-to-rationalize-their-pipeline">"rationalizing"</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-toss-another-650-jobs-onto-the-layoff-pyre-in-the-name-of-sustainable-future-growth">"aligning"</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ceo-andrew-wilson-tells-ea-staff-5-of-them-will-be-laid-off-via-empty-and-infuriating-email">"sunsetting"</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destiny-creators-bungie-lay-off-220-people-and-form-new-studio-within-sony-to-stave-off-financial-ruin">"integrating"</a>. If this keeps up, the games industry may soon run out of hollow synonyms for cutting jobs. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Krafton Signs Agreement With Pockerpair to Bring Palworld to Mobile]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-mobile-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/krafton-signs-agreement-with-pockerpair-to-bring-palworld-to-mobile.998277/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-mobile-release/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-59339">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Krafton has singed an agreement with Palworld developers Pockerpair to bring Palworld to mobile.</p>



<p>The announcement comes from a <a href="https://www.krafton.com/news/press/%ed%81%ac%eb%9e%98%ed%94%84%ed%86%a4-%ed%8c%b0%ec%9b%94%eb%93%9c-%eb%aa%a8%eb%b0%94%ec%9d%bc-%ea%b2%8c%ec%9e%84-%ea%b8%80%eb%a1%9c%eb%b2%8c-%eb%9d%bc%ec%9d%b4%ec%84%a0%ec%8a%a4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Krafton Press Release</a>, which reveals that the company has signed a licensing agreement for the intellectual property (IP) of ‘Palworld.’</p>



<p>The announcement reads that, “Through this contract, Krafton will expand the Palworld IP to the mobile platform. It plans to faithfully reinterpret and implement the original’s main fun elements to fit the mobile environment. The project will be handled by the development team of ‘PUBG STUDIOS,’ a creative studio under Krafton.”</p>



<p><span>Palworld’s release on PC and Xbox attracted 25 million players and reached the third-</span>highest number of concurrent users on Steam of all time. The game made its debut on the PlayStation 5 in September.</p>



<p>Last month, it was revealed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-and-the-pokemon-company-suing-palworld-developer-pocketpair/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo will be pursuing legal action over Palworld</a> for patent infringement, to which Pocketpair replied that, “we will do our utmost for our fans, and to ensure that indie game developers are not hindered or discouraged from pursuing their creative ideas.”</p>



<p><span>Despite its success, the game received some community backlash upon its release due to its&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/did-palworld-really-plagiarize-pokemon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">overwhelming similarities to Pokemon.</a>&nbsp;Many fans of </span>Pokemon compared the images and assets online accusing Pocketpair of plagiarism and the conversation around the issue has seemingly never been squashed. </p>



<p>Are you looking forward to playing Palworld on mobile? Let us know in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news regarding&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/">the latest Project Rene leaks</a> and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-battle-royale-details-video-games/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-battle-royale-details-video-games/">Cancelled Halo Battle Royale Details Surface Online, Video Claims</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Several key details regarding the cancelled Halo battle royale project have surfaced online in a video, it has been claimed.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/">Project Rene Leaks Reveal ‘Disappointing’ Mobile Gaming Mechanics</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In a recent round of leaks from within Project Rene, screenshots have surfaced revealing some of the worst mobile mechanics.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/epic-games-financially-sound-ceo-reveal/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/epic-games-financially-sound-ceo-reveal/">Epic Games is Now ‘Financially Sound’, CEO Reveals</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Tim Sweeney, Epic Games’ CEO, has revealed that the firm is finally financially stable. Check out the full comment here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps-japan-plan-ps5-pro-scalpers/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps-japan-plan-ps5-pro-scalpers/">PlayStation Japan Has a Playtime Plan To Foil PS5 Pro Scalpers</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>PlayStation Japan has put in place a few blockers that should prevent scalpers getting their hands on the PS5 Pro 30th Anniversary Edition.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ryujinx Switch Emulator Is Dead, Too, Taken Down by Nintendo Like Yuzu]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ryujinx-switch-emulator-is-dead-too-taken-down-by-nintendo-like-yuzu/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ryujinx-switch-emulator-is-dead-too-taken-down-by-nintendo-like-yuzu.998274/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ryujinx-switch-emulator-is-dead-too-taken-down-by-nintendo-like-yuzu/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ryujinx, the sole remaining Nintendo Switch emulator for PC after the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-emulator-yuzu-shut-down-nintendo-gets-paid-2-4-million/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">closure of Yuzu</a>, has also been taken down by Nintendo. The news came a few hours ago from one of the main collaborators on the open source project, which was the first emulator to boot commercial Switch games.</p>
<p>Here's the Discord message shared with the community:</p>
<p><em>Yesterday, gdkchan (the author) was contacted by Nintendo and offered an agreement to stop working on the project, remove the organization and all related assets he's in control of. While awaiting confirmation on whether he would take this agreement, the organization has been removed, so I think it's safe to say what the outcome is. Rather than leave you with only panic and speculation, I decided to write this short message to give some closure. These words are my own. I don't want to speak for anyone else here, so just remember that while reading.</em></p>
<p><em>Thank you to everyone who has contributed code, documentation, or issue reports to the project. Thank you all for following us throughout the development. I was able to learn a lot of really neat things about games that I love, enjoy them with renewed qualities and in unique circumstances, and I'm sure you all have experiences that are similarly special. I'm extending my own massive thanks to our moderation team, who have been here through some rough circumstances and always found ways to make light of it.</em></p>
<p>Indeed, Ryujinx can no longer be downloaded via GitHub or the official website, where the <a href="https://ryujinx.org/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener">download page</a> is now entirely blank. It may have taken them years, but Nintendo finally decided to completely crack down on the Switch emulator and pirate scenes.</p>
<p>Recently, they also <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-is-officially-suing-pocketpair-creators-of-palworld/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> a lawsuit against Palworld, alleging that Pocketpair infringed multiple patents with their game. Whereas with the emulators, the companies likely had no choice but to fold even merely due to lack of funds for the legal expenses, the same appears unlikely with Palworld, which is one of the best-selling games released in 2024 so far.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Mighty Bowser Lego Set Gets Very Rare Discount At Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-mighty-bowser-lego-super-mario-set-gets-very-rare-discount-at-amazon/1100-6526848/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-mighty-bowser-lego-set-gets-very-rare-discount-at-amazon.998268/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-mighty-bowser-lego-super-mario-set-gets-very-rare-discount-at-amazon/1100-6526848/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526848">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The largest Super Mario Lego set has received an extremely rare discount ahead of Prime Big Deal Days. Over at Amazon, you can get <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible/dp/B0B2Y3WNH4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Mighty Bowser for $234 instead of its usual $270</a></strong>. At face value, a $36 savings isn't a huge price cut, but The Mighty Bowser has almost always sold for full price since launching two years ago--exactly two years ago, in fact, as of October 1.</p><div title="[Various] Lego Mighty Bowser Mario Set" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2701" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="[Various] Lego Mighty Bowser Mario Set" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible/dp/B0B2Y3WNH4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible\/dp\/B0B2Y3WNH4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible/dp/B0B2Y3WNH4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">Lego Super Mario: The Mighty Bowser</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible/dp/B0B2Y3WNH4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible\/dp\/B0B2Y3WNH4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible/dp/B0B2Y3WNH4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">$234 (was $270)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>The discount is from a third-party seller, but your purchase will be shipped from Amazon and is eligible for Prime. Since your order is fulfilled by Amazon, you can return it within 30 days for free, just like any order that is officially sold by Amazon.</p><p>The Mighty Bowser is certainly one of the coolest Lego Mario sets. Bowser may consistently fail in his attempts to rule the Mushroom Kingdom alongside Princess Peach, but he does own the record for highest brick count in the Lego Super Mario series. At 2,807 pieces, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible/dp/B0B2Y3WNH4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Mighty Bowser</a> stole the crown from the replica <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Nintendo-Entertainment-Building-Creative/dp/B08FCW3SB7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Nintendo Entertainment System kit (2,646 pieces)</a>.</p><p>Once fully built, King Koopa is 12.5 inches tall and 16 inches wide, so you may need to clear some shelf space to display the big guy. With the included stand and Bowser's tail, the build has a depth of 11 inches.</p><p>While you could call The Mighty Bowser a statue, it's also a giant action figure. His tail, arms, and legs are posable, so you can display Bowser in a variety of different poses. In addition to articulated joints, Bowser's jaw snaps and buttons beneath it turn his head. He can also shoot fireballs to (try to) stop Mario from thwarting his plans once again. When on his stand, Bowser is flanked on each side by fiery towers.</p><p>There's also a hidden POW Block, which was implemented specifically for <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Adventures-Interactive-Playset-Nintendo/dp/B0CV2G23D8?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lego Mario</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CV27VY6L?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Luigi</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Adventures-Interactive-Princess-Nintendo/dp/B0CV2CNDYZ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Peach</a> figures to step on. While The Mighty Bowser isn't considered a playset--it's one of the five Lego Mario sets geared primarily toward adults--it does interact with the figures included in the starter courses. If you press Lego Mario against Bowser's shell, he will react to Bowser's presence.</p></div>                      </div><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4377482-legosupermarioadventureswithmario.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4377482" data-ratio="0.75" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4377482-legosupermarioadventureswithmario.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4377482"></a><figcaption>Adventures with Mario Starter Set</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4377482-legosupermarioadventureswithmario.jpg"></figure><p>The Mighty Bowser isn't the only set in the Lego Mario series focused on King Koopa. For a much more affordable option, check out <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Bowsers-Muscle-Expansion-Collectible/dp/B0CGY1MQFD?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bowser's Muscle Car</a></strong>, which released earlier this year and is available for only $24 at Amazon. In August, <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Express-Para-Biddybuds-Nintendo-Birthday/dp/B0CV25S3S7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Bowser Express Train</a></strong> became one of the largest expansion sets at 1,392 pieces. That set is $120, but you can get the 1,321-piece <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Expansion-Buildable-Figures-Collectible/dp/B0BSR9PV75?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dry Bowser Castle</a></strong> on sale for only $94 right now. It comes with a significantly smaller version of (skeletal) Bowser.</p><p>It's also worth noting that you can pair The Mighty Bowser with Bowser Jr. by opting for the new edition of the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Adventures-Interactive-Playset-Nintendo/dp/B0CV2G23D8?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Adventures with Mario Starter Set</a></strong>. Released in August for $50, the revamped starter set comes with the interactive Mario figure, Yoshi, Bowser Jr. and his Koopa Clown Car, and more.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Adventures-Interactive-Playset-Nintendo/dp/B0CV2G23D8?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Adventures With Interactive Lego Mario (218 pieces)</a> -- $50</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CV27VY6L?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Adventures With Interactive Lego Luigi (210 pieces)</a> -- $50</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Adventures-Interactive-Princess-Nintendo/dp/B0CV2CNDYZ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Adventures With Interactive Lego Peach (208 pieces)</a> -- $50</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Bowsers-Muscle-Expansion-Collectible/dp/B0CGY1MQFD?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bowser's Muscle Car Expansion Set (458 pieces)</a> -- $24 (<del>$30</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Express-Para-Biddybuds-Nintendo-Birthday/dp/B0CV25S3S7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Bowser Express Train Expansion Set (1,392 pieces)</a> -- $120</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Expansion-Buildable-Figures-Collectible/dp/B0BSR9PV75?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dry Bowser Castle Expansion Set (1,321 pieces)</a> -- $94 (<del>$110</del>)</li></ul><hr><h3>Lego Super Mario Display Models</h3><p>The Mighty Bowser isn't the only <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-super-mario-piranha-plant-drops-to-best-price-yet-at-amazon/1100-6526845/" data-ref-id="1100-6526845">Lego Mario display set on sale</a> at Amazon. The smallest and cheapest of the five, the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BXQ3M8JH?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Piranha Plant</a></strong>, has also received a rare discount, dropping the cost to only $48.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-mario-world-lego-set-has-arrived-get-it-at-amazon-sold-out-at-walmart/1100-6525283/" data-ref-id="1100-6525283">Lego <em>just </em>released its latest Super Mario display set</a> featuring retro depictions of Mario and Yoshi on October 1. Based on their sprites from Super Mario World, the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Super-Mario-World-Collectible/dp/B0CYM2V9FS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">new Mario &amp; Yoshi Lego display model</a></strong> is a 1,215-piece kit made to resemble Super Nintendo graphics. With the help of the included display stand, the completed build is 15.5 inches tall. The Mighty Bowser probably won't be pleased to see Mario towering over him, but these two sets would look cool displayed next to each other.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible/dp/B0B2Y3WNH4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Mighty Bowser at Amazon (2,807 pieces)</a> -- $234 (<del>$270</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Super-Mario-World-Collectible/dp/B0CYM2V9FS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Super Mario World: Mario &amp; Yoshi (1,215 pieces)</a> -- $130 | Also at <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D13923%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fsuper-mario-world-mario-yoshi-71438&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fthe-mighty-bowser-lego-super-mario-set-gets-very-rare-discount-at-amazon%2F1100-6526848%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lego Store</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BXQ3M8JH?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Piranha Plant at Amazon (540 pieces)</a> -- $48 (<del>$60</del>) | Also at <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F71426%2F2651673420%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fthe-mighty-bowser-lego-super-mario-set-gets-very-rare-discount-at-amazon%2F1100-6526848%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Super-Mario-World-Collectible/dp/B0CYM2V9FS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Super Mario World: Mario &amp; Yoshi (1,215 pieces)</a> -- $130 | Also at <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D13923%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fsuper-mario-world-mario-yoshi-71438&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fthe-mighty-bowser-lego-super-mario-set-gets-very-rare-discount-at-amazon%2F1100-6526848%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lego Store</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09FMVDHDM?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Super Mario 64 Question Block at Amazon (2,064 pieces)</a> -- $200</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Nintendo-Entertainment-Building-Creative/dp/B08FCW3SB7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lego NES at Amazon (2,646 pieces)</a> -- $262 (<del>$270</del>) | <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Flego-super-mario-nintendo-entertainment-system-set-71374%2F-%2FA-80130334%3Ftag%3Dgamespot-promos-20&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fthe-mighty-bowser-lego-super-mario-set-gets-very-rare-discount-at-amazon%2F1100-6526848%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Also at Target</a></li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cancelled Halo Battle Royale Details Surface Online, Video Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/halo-battle-royale-details-video-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cancelled-halo-battle-royale-details-surface-online-video-claims.998262/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/halo-battle-royale-details-video-games/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a video dubbed an exclusive report, one creator and reporter has broken down a series of claimed details about Project Tatanka – later known as Project Ekhert – the famed and failed Halo battle royale title. It was claimed that Tatanka (or Ekhert) was cancelled in 2023 because of a desire to focus on the next main Halo game and because the battle royale genre was wavering.</p>



<p>Read on to check out the full array of claims about the cancelled Halo battle royale project.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-what-might-have-been">What Might Have Been</h2>



<p>Many fans were excited about the prospect of a Halo battle royale title, including some prolific streamers with a penchant for first-person shooters. Unfortunately, all signs point to 343 Industries having cancelled the project, capping it to work on bigger and better things for the series. </p>



<p>In January, it was claimed that 343 Industries was heading in an entirely different way for the next Halo title, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-unreal-engine/">‘starting from scratch’</a> and utilising a new engine. Shortly after, Project Tatanka (Project Ekhert) was shut down, as the claim goes.</p>



<p>In a post on social media that accompanied an ‘exclusive’ YouTube report, creator ‘Rebs Gaming’, who has spotted key Halo-related details in the past, listed a bunch of details tied to the cancelled Halo battle royale game.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Project Tatanka: Halo Infinite’s Canceled Battle Royale Mode (Exclusive Report)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MEUh_vS4b5w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>He stressed it was being playtested ‘weekly’ by 343 Industries, which is where many of these details came from. Players would drop into a map on the Zeta Halo ring made up of multiple fragments, and they’d get there through an ODST-style drop-pod system. As players explored the map, they’d pick up power items, equipment, and shields, all while completing ‘mini objectives’.</p>



<p>As the game unravelled, Pelicans would fly over and drop off vehicles — Warthogs, Mongooses, Falcons, and the like.</p>



<p>These details are yet to be corroborated, but whether they’re accurate or not, the fact remains — there is no Halo battle royale game on the horizon and it was once heavily rumoured that one would materialise. In the absence of such a game, some savvy creators have started piecing together their own Halo battle royale mode, which shows how there’s an appetite for the game.</p>



<p>Do you think a Halo battle royale would have done something to save the series? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news regarding <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/">the latest Project Rene leaks</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Project Rene Leaks Reveal ‘Disappointing’ Mobile Gaming Mechanics]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/project-rene-leaks-reveal-%E2%80%98disappointing%E2%80%99-mobile-gaming-mechanics.998259/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/project-rene-leaks-mobile-mechanics/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In recent days, new shots from a test build of Project Rene have allegedly leaked online, showcasing several changes that have left The Sims community disappointed. At first blush, it appears that Electronic Arts has changed the conceptual style revealed so many months ago and pivoted to a more mobile-friendly design complete with ‘grindy’ tasks and microtransactions.</p>



<p>On September 17, the team revealed that there were no plans to release The Sims 5, and instead, it would keep pushing updates into The Sims 4, the decade-old title.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-going-mobile">Going Mobile</h2>



<p>Project Rene has been in development for the longest time, and the team at Electronic Arts hasn’t exactly been forthcoming with updates. From leaks concerning an open-world map to a developer diary that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-sims-5-new-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exposed some prototype art</a> for the game, details have been drip-fed into the community over the last few years.</p>



<p>In the last few days, some leaked images have surfaced online revealing what’s claimed to be a more updated test build of Project Rene. These images have caused fans to lash out against the developers for creating what appears to be a typical and rather generic mobile game:</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">i can’t believe my eyes that Project Rene has switched its course from being a promising successor of the Sims 4 to some ugly ass mobile game that will be another cash grab full of ads <a href="https://t.co/55zBbi4vJI">pic.twitter.com/55zBbi4vJI</a></p>— tom (@simshive) <a href="https://twitter.com/simshive/status/1840433234867359749?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>What’s ironic is that in January 2024, it was revealed that The Sims Mobile would receive no further updates. It’s almost written in stone that Project Rene will be a replacement of sorts for the mobile title that was online for so many years, but some fans aren’t happy with that revelation.</p>



<p>In the leaked screenshots, we see a microtransaction tab powered by ‘Simoleons’ and some examples of quests that users will grind to earn XP and in-game currency. It’s assumed that they’ll use that currency to unlock clothing, furniture, and other items, making this as typical a mobile game as you could ever hope to play.</p>



<p>In addition to these images, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1frtd5c/new_project_rene_formerly_the_sims_5_screenshots/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a post surfaced on Reddit</a> from a user taking part in an ongoing playtest. They explained that it’s a game based on a ‘collaborative multiplayer experience’ that’ll see players form relationships with other, real players. </p>



<p>Are you concerned that Project Rene is headed in the wrong direction? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/epic-games-financially-sound-ceo-reveal/">Epic Games is financially sound</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Games is Now ‘Financially Sound’, CEO Reveals]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/epic-games-financially-sound-ceo-reveal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-games-is-now-%E2%80%98financially-sound%E2%80%99-ceo-reveals.998247/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/epic-games-financially-sound-ceo-reveal/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a keynote speech at Unreal Fest 2024, Epic Games CEO Tim Sweeney took to the stage to deliver some fantastic news. He explained that after several years of peaks and troughs, Epic Games is finally ‘financially sound’. This news comes following months of success for Fortnite and record-breaking performances across the Epic Games Store on PC.</p>



<p>It has been a tough journey getting there, though.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-weather-the-road">Weather the Road</h2>



<p>Last year, Epic Games performed mass layoffs that impacted almost 1000 workers. The firm also had to pour hundreds of millions of dollars into court cases, particularly those going up against the likes of the FTC, Apple, and Google. </p>



<p>On the upswing, Fortnite became more successful than ever around a year ago, pulling in record-high players amid a ‘return to OG’ event that saw staggering numbers of people flood the platform. Also, the Epic Games Store has continued to soar, securing considerable revenue growth and raking in $1.25 billion in 2023.</p>



<p>Speaking during the Unreal Fest 2024 keynote, Tim Sweeney said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Last year’s Unreal Fest began with some sad news. The company had to get its finances in order, and we just had some major layoffs. We spent the last year rebuilding and also executing solidly on all fronts.</p>



<p>I’m happy to tell you now that the company is financially sound, and that Fortnite and the Epic Games Store have hit new records in concurrency and success. Fortnite hit 110 million monthly active users last holiday, an all-time peak.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The full video is available here:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Unreal Fest Seattle 2024 | Opening Session" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KYGEfQJPqW8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Epic Games remains one of the most innovative and diverse tech titans in the world of gaming. From the Unreal Engine to the UGC ecosystem promoted in Fortnite, and from the overwhelming success of the ‘free games’ initiative on the Epic Games Store to the cutthroat defence of its products, Epic Games is doing a fantastic job of weathering the industry’s ongoing struggles. </p>



<p>It’s just a shame it cost almost 1000 jobs to get there.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps-japan-plan-ps5-pro-scalpers/">PlayStation Japan is fighting back against PS5 Pro scalpers</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>