<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:27:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles gameplay trailer released]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/20/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-gameplay-trailer-released/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-gameplay-trailer-released.1275744/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Square Enix has released a new Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles gameplay trailer that gives a look at what to expect in this new release of the game. The trailer shows various clips from what appears to be the enhanced version of Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles, to showcase the differences with the original version, which is also included in the package.</p>
<p><iframe title="FINAL FANTASY TACTICS - The Ivalice Chronicles | Gameplay Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wVCaeyucLTE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>This Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles trailer includes the new user interface that players will see in the enhanced edition, where it will be easier to see turn order and issue commands. There is a birds eye tactical view added so you can better plan your strategy in battles. A battle speed option is also present in the enhanced version so you can speed through battles instead of waiting for every animation to play out at normal speed. The trailer also shows the enhanced visuals over the original so the art looks on modern displays. The game will feature new voice acting and new conversations that have been written by Yasumi Matsuno.</p>
<p>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles is available for pre-order, with two versions including a standard edition and a deluxe edition. The Deluxe edition, which costs £54.99 includes:</p>

<ul>
<li>FINAL FANTASY TACTICS – The Ivalice Chronicles full game</li>
<li>Weapon:&nbsp;Akademy Blade (Raises a unit’s speed attribute slightly while equipped)</li>
<li>Headwear:&nbsp;Akademy Beret (Prevents the Charmed status while equipped)</li>
<li>Combat Garb:&nbsp;Akademy Tunic (Grants Shell while equipped)</li>
<li>Accessory:&nbsp;Ring of Aptitude (Boosts JP earned while equipped)</li>
<li>Consumable Items:&nbsp;Phoenix Down x10</li>
<li>Black Equipment for Ramza</li>
<li>Red Equipment for Ramza</li>
</ul>
<p>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles will be released on September 30th for PC, PS5, PS4, Xbox Series XS, Switch, and Switch 2.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.square-enix-games.com/en_US/news/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-trailer">Square Enix</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/20/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-gameplay-trailer-released/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead Cells Dev's 'The Rogue Prince Of Persia' Leaps Onto Switch 2 Later This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/dead-cells-devs-the-rogue-prince-of-persia-leaps-onto-switch-2-later-this-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dead-cells-devs-the-rogue-prince-of-persia-leaps-onto-switch-2-later-this-year.1275741/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>What a surprise!</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>As a part of today's Xbox Gamescom showcase, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/dead_cells">Dead Cells</a> dev Evil Empire finally lifted the lid on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/rogue-prince-of-persia">The Rogue Prince of Persia</a>, revealing that it will be coming to Switch and Switch 2 "later this year".</p>
<p>While every other platform landed the full release of this Prince of Persia roguelike today, we're pleased to see it finally confirmed for Switch. We've had this one on our radar since it was <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/04/prince-of-persia-roguelite-from-dead-cells-dev-revealed-switch-not-confirmed">first revealed</a> early last year, and have been following it throughout its early access period ever since. A surprise <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/dead-cells-devs-prince-of-persia-roguelike-has-been-rated-for-switch">Switch age rating</a> for the game popped up earlier this summer, but today's showcase if the first <em>official</em> confirmation that it will be coming our way.</p>
<p>If this is the first you've heard of this one, The Rogue Prince of Persia is a super stylish-looking roguelike, that is all about movement and combat. It packs in a bunch of familiar moves you'll likely recognise from the iconic Ubisoft series (hello, wall running), and shapes it into the 'one more run' format that Evil Empire so brilliantly hit upon in the past with Dead Cells' post-launch content.</p>
<p>Here's a rundown of a game's key features and a handful of screenshots from its Steam page:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Become the Prince of Persia</strong><br>
Flow seamlessly between platforming and combat, using your acrobatic skill to outmaneuver and outsmart your enemies. Run on the walls to open new routes of attack, avoid traps and explore hard to reach areas, or chain it with kicks, dodges and stomps to fight through swathes of enemies without a scratch.</p>
<p><strong>Save your People</strong><br>
Awakening in an Oasis outside the capital after a furious battle with magic-wielding invaders, you rush to the city to stop the brutal invasion. When you die, your mysterious bola returns you back in time to the Oasis, ready to throw yourself into the fray again and again. Discover new areas, characters and knowledge through non-linear storytelling as you strive to find a way to save Persia.</p>
<p><strong>Choose your Playstyle</strong><br>
Switch between a wide variety of deadly weapons during each run and equip &amp; upgrade medallions to enhance both them and your moveset, unleashing devastating synergies. Change your loadout mid-run to adapt to new challenges or stick with your favourites – the choice is yours!</p>
<p><strong>No Two Runs are the Same</strong><br>
New weapons, medallions, difficulty modifiers &amp; more are unlocked with each run, so there’s always something new to explore. Every level is also procedurally generated - renewing the challenge with each foray into the city.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>We'll be keeping an eye out for more information on the Switch and Switch 2 release in the coming months, but let's hope that we don't have to wait too long.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184598 @ 1755703226 -->
<p><em>Will you be checking this one out on Switch later this year? Wall run down to the comments and let us know.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/dead-cells-devs-the-rogue-prince-of-persia-leaps-onto-switch-2-later-this-year]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rogue Prince of Persia Has Surprise-Launched on PS5 and Xbox Series X/S Today, Also Available on Xbox Game Pass]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-release-date-ps5-xbox-series-xbox-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-has-surprise-launched-on-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s-today-also-available-on-xbox-game-pass.1275738/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Rogue Prince of Persia, developed by Evil Empire and published by Ubisoft, has surprise-launched on PS5 and Xbox Series X/S consoles today during Gamescom 2025, with a Nintendo Switch and Nintendo Switch 2 launch to come sometime later this year.</p>



<p>It's also dropped on Xbox Game Pass, so players who have a Game Pass subscription and have yet to check out the game since its Early Access launch last year can jump into the action without making an extra purchase.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Launch Trailer - The Rogue Prince of Persia" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YdJJbvwrAsI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The news was unveiled during Xbox's Gamescom 2025 live stream, and though it is still technically a shadow-drop, it's not that much of a surprise since Ubisoft previously revealed an <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-reveals-release-date-for-anno-117-pax-romana-a-1-0-release-window-for-the-rogue-prince-of-persia-and-showcases-a-new-game-morbid-metal-at-sgf-2025/">"<em>August 2025</em>" launch window for the game's 1.0 version this past June</a>.</p>



<p>The game has come a long way since its early access launch in May 2024, but even at that launch, it already looked like an impressive 2D action game that fans of the roguelite genre wouldn't want to miss. This, again, isn't all that surprising considering it was developed by the same team that worked on Dead Cells.</p>



<p>When <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-early-access-review-the-year-of-the-prince/">Wccftech's Francesco De Meo reviewed the early access version</a> of The Rogue Prince of Persia last May, he wrote "<em>Even in its early state, The Rogue Prince of Persia masterfully blends the best of Prince of Persia and Dead Cells in a solid package offering a more involved narrative, excellent platforming, dynamic combat and a lot of death, as is tradition for a proper roguelite."</em></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-release-date-ps5-xbox-series-xbox-game-pass/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On the eve of Gamescom, Microsoft workers occupy the Xbox company's campus in protest at dealings with the Israeli military]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/on-the-eve-of-gamescom-microsoft-workers-occupy-the-xbox-companys-campus-in-protest-at-dealings-with-the-israeli-military</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/on-the-eve-of-gamescom-microsoft-workers-occupy-the-xbox-companys-campus-in-protest-at-dealings-with-the-israeli-military.1275735/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>No Azure for Apartheid sit-in dispersed by police</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>No Azure For Apartheid / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>This week, dozens of Microsoft employees occupied the company's east campus in Redmond, Washington in protest against the use of Azure and generative AI technologies by the Israeli military, during their on-going assault on Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza. </p><!--more-->
<p>This follows an announcement from Microsoft that they would <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/15/microsoft-launches-inquiry-claims-israel-used-tech-mass-surveillance-palestinians">commission another "external" inquiry</a> into their business relationship with Israel's armed forces, after the Guardian and other papers reported on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-equipped-israels-indiscriminate-palestinian-surveillance-operation-with-azure-cloud-tech-claims-report">an alleged collaboration with one particular intelligence division, Unit 8200</a>, that has seen Israel gather data from phones and store it on Microsoft servers overseas.</p>
<p>Amongst other things, the surveillance data is reportedly being used to target airstrikes in the course of an invasion of Gaza that has claimed the lives of tens of thousands, the majority of them civilians. Microsoft declined to comment on the recent Guardian allegations concerning Unit 8200 when approached by RPS, but have <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-confirm-theyve-supplied-ai-tech-to-the-israeli-military-for-use-in-gaza-following-bds-xbox-boycott">previously insisted</a> that their own internal reporting has found "no evidence to date that Microsoft’s Azure and AI technologies have been used to target or harm people in the conflict in Gaza."
</p>
<p>The protest at Microsoft's campus was brief. According to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/aug/19/microsoft-workers-protest-washington-israel">the Guardian</a>, current and former staff declared one area a 'Free Zone', and occupied it with placards that read "Join The Worker Intifada - No Labor for Genocide" and "Martyred Palestinian Children's Plaza".</p><p>The protestors have also published <a href="https://noazureforapartheid.com/worker-intifada/">a call to action online</a>, which reads: "the Liberated Zone is born out of radical love for the rich humanity of Palestinian people. Today, we answer Gaza's call to action to mobilize, confront, and escalate to force an end to this genocide powered by Microsoft technology." The protestors were dispersed by police after around two hours, under threat of arrest for trespassing.
</p>
<p>Israel's current attack on Gaza is a response to a Hamas-led militant strike across the border that killed over a thousand people in October 2023. Most of the dead were civilians, with hundreds of others taken hostage.</p>
<p>In amongst ceasefire negotiations with Hamas, Israel's government now <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c7417pl3ddpo">aim to take control of Gaza City</a> after levelling much of the territory and forcibly displacing millions of people, many of whom now <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2025/08/israel-opt-new-testimonies-provide-compelling-evidence-that-israels-starvation-of-palestinians-in-gaza-is-a-deliberate-policy/">face starvation thanks to Israel's obstruction of aid</a>. All this follows decades of brutal occupation of Palestinian territories, in what a former head of Israel's own intelligence agency has described as <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/sep/06/israel-imposing-apartheid-on-palestinians-says-former-mossad-chief">"an apartheid state"</a>.
</p>
<p>Microsoft employees have grown outspoken about the company's subsequent dealings with Israel, as the invasion of Gaza has worn on. Among those demonstrating at Microsoft's east campus this week was Hossam Nasr - one of two former employees <a href="https://mondoweiss.net/2025/05/meet-the-fired-microsoft-employees-challenging-the-companys-complicity-in-the-gaza-genocide/">fired in October 2024</a> for organising a vigil for massacred Palestinians. He and the other fired tech worker, Abdo Mohamed, are part of activist group No Azure For Apartheid, which has called on Microsoft to divest from Israel in a <a href="https://noazureforapartheid.com/petition/">petition signed by hundreds of staff</a>, including members of the Xbox division and subsidiary companies Activision, Bethesda Softworks and Mojang. 
</p><p>Last week, unionised members of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dishonored">Dishonored</a> developers Arkane Studios also <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/arkane-studios-union-publishes-open-letter-to-microsoft-demanding-a-stop-to-israeli-support">threw their weight behind</a> a recent <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bds-calls-for-boycott-of-microsoft-and-xbox-gaming-products-over-alleged-israeli-military-connections">Boycott, Divestment, Sanctions call</a> for consumers to stop buying Microsoft gaming and Xbox products. "We think that Microsoft has no place being [an] accomplice of a genocide," the Arkane union wrote in an open letter, "and as Microsoft employees, we don't want to be part of this sinister project for Gaza."
</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/on-the-eve-of-gamescom-microsoft-workers-occupy-the-xbox-companys-campus-in-protest-at-dealings-with-the-israeli-military]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 Already Shaping Up For A Big 2026 With Starfield Also Reportedly Getting Ported]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-starfield-gamescom-2025-ff14-port-release-date-2000618841</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-already-shaping-up-for-a-big-2026-with-starfield-also-reportedly-getting-ported.1275732/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> might not be the only massive sci-fi RPG on Switch 2 for long. Could <em>Starfield</em> get ported as well? Why is <em>Dead Space</em>‘s old Creative Director all-in on AI? And How did an AI replica of a real content creator make its way onto the official <em>First Descendent</em> TikTok channel? Welcome to the latest edition of Morning Checkpoint,<em> Kotaku</em>‘s brief daily roundup of gaming culture and news, where we’re doing a bunch of clean-up from the first day of Gamescom 2025.</p>  <p>Podcaster NateTheHate, who’s quickly developed a reputation for accurate leaks around upcoming Nintendo announcements, now claims Bethesda’s open-world sci-fi RPG is coming to the company’s handheld hybrid next year. “<em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> won’t be the only Bethesda game coming to Nintendo Switch 2 in 2026,” he <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1957886310896796027">posted on X</a> yesterday. “See that planet? You can go there. Aside from landing on PS5…<em>Starfield</em> is planned for release on Nintendo Switch 2 in 2026.” FromSoftware’s <em>The Duskbloods</em> has also been confirmed for Switch 2 in 2026, and Nintendo has yet to reveal any of its expected slate for the console’s second year. <em>Starfield</em> is reportedly coming to PS5 next year as well, <a href="https://kotaku.com/starfield-ps5-second-expansion-shattered-space-date-2000614380">seemingly closer to whenever the second expansion launches</a>.</p> <h2><em>The First Descendent</em> blames TikTok for AI slop video</h2> <p>Nexon’s free-to-play loot shooter, also known as “Gooner <em>Destiny</em>,” <a href="https://kotaku.com/ai-ads-tiktok-the-first-descendant-nexon-2000618182">accidentally shared an AI-generated ad on TikTok</a> that ripped off another content creator. <a href="https://tfd.nexon.com/en/news/3100882">The publisher now says</a> a TikTok marketing program automatically solicited the ad and linked it to <em>The First Descendants’</em> account with no controls to verify copyright infringement or other content concerns. Sounds bad! “<span lang="EN-US">We will also be committed to continuously being more transparent and responsible to regain the trust of our community and creators,” the company writes. “</span><span lang="EN-US">Once again, we deeply apologize for the disappointment and inconvenience this incident has caused.”</span></p>

 <h2><em>Final Fantasy 14</em> could be coming to Switch 2</h2> <p>Director Naoki Yoshida <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/yoshi-p-reveals-positive-discussions-over-nintendo-switch-2-final-fantasy-14-port/">told <em>VGC</em></a> at Gamescom that Square Enix is in talks with Nintendo about porting the hit MMORPG over. “The discussions have been positive, so I do hope that players will look forward to hopefully good news in the future,” he said. It sounds like <em>Final Fantasy 16</em> isn’t out of the question either. Yoshida added, “For me, it’s just my aim to provide <em>Final Fantasy 14</em> and <em>16</em> to as many players as possible, and I hope that as many players as possible will be able to enjoy those two games.”</p> <h2>The director of <em>Callisto Protocol</em> is going all-in on AI</h2> <p>Glen Schofield <a href="http://AI is going to be fantastic">told<em> The Game Industry</em></a> “AI is going to be fantastic.” He said he’s holding seminars about how AI can make creatives more efficient and thinks the technology will be an inevitable part of game development in 5-10 years, but he’s not sure exactly how it will all shake out. “Is it going to be an engine?” he said. “Right now, it’s a whole bunch of things that just kind of suck it in… and into what? It’s going to have to settle down a bit before we actually use it.” Schofield also claimed<em> Callisto Protocol</em> sold over 5 million copies, but regretted not delaying it. He said AAA games are not dead and is looking for someone to pay him to make another.</p> <h2><em>High on Life 2</em> gets a release date</h2> <p>The sci-fi comedy shooter <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/20/high-on-life-2-demo-hands-on-preview-gamescom/">will arrive</a> on PC and console, including on Game Pass, on February 13, 2026. Ralph Ineson, best known as Cid in <em>FF16</em> and more recently Galactus in <em>The</em> <em>Fantastic Four: First Steps</em>, will be voicing the newest gun in the game.</p>

 <h2><em>Triangle Strategy</em> shadow-drops on Xbox</h2> <p>The HD-2D homage to games like <em>Final Fantasy Tactics</em> was previously a Switch exclusive on console. Square Enix’s port is <a href="https://x.com/Genki_JPN/status/1958158169240371511">now on Xbox</a> with a starting discount of 30 percent off.</p> <h2><em>Stalker 2</em> comes to PS5 in November</h2> <p>The survival horror shooter <a href="https://x.com/stalker_thegame/status/1958150213127798847">makes the jump</a> on November 20 as more former Xbox console exclusives get ported and help round-out Sony’s previously anemic 2025 release slate.</p> <h2>The biggest lines at Gamescom are for <em>Silksong</em></h2> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">THIS IS THE LINE OF HOLLOW KNIGHT SILKSONG ON PRESS DAY AT 9AM. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Gamescom?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Gamescom</a> <a href="https://t.co/lNz1q62AZ5">pic.twitter.com/lNz1q62AZ5</a></p> <p>— Daan K. 🔜 Gamescom 2025 (@NintenDaan) <a href="https://twitter.com/NintenDaan/status/1958063065150226808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 20, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>The <em>Hollow Knight</em> sequel is getting a special announcement on August 21—<a href="https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-announcement-gamescom-stream-2000618437">a release date, hopefully?</a>—but in the meantime, attendees at Gamescom are making the <em>Silksong</em> demos at the Nintendo and Xbox booths the highlights of the show so far. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/hollow-knight-silksong-offers-buttery-smooth-performance-on-switch-2">Nintendo Life&nbsp;already went hands-on</a> and confirmed the Metroidvania Soulslike supports 120Hz refresh on Switch 2 in TV mode.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/kirby-air-riders-switch-2-release-date-nintendo-direct-trailer-2000618410">Kirby Air Riders has a release date and looks refreshingly old-school</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/bioshock-4-delay-layoffs-rod-fergusson-diablo-gears-2000618449">Rod Fergusson is trying to save BioShock a second time</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/denshattack-train-game-tony-hawk-anime-onl-gamescom-2025-trailer-2000618578">This Japanese train game was the best thing revealed at Gamescom</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch This:</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Hidden SECRETS In GTA 3" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xBpNWVDQ5QM?feature=oembed"></iframe></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-starfield-gamescom-2025-ff14-port-release-date-2000618841]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Fremont Steam Console Appears On Geekbench]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valve-fremont-steam-console-appears-on-geekbench/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-fremont-steam-console-appears-on-geekbench.1275726/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Valve Fremont, which is the long-rumored console running SteamOS, has appeared on popular benchmarking platform Geekbench. The appearance comes as rumors of Valve’s return to Steam consoles continue to swirl.</p>



<p>According to the <a href="https://browser.geekbench.com/v6/cpu/13390426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Geekbench listings</a>, the Valve Fremont features a six core/12 thread processor running at 3.2 GHz base frequency. The device tested also has 8GB of DDR5 memory. </p>



<p>It should be noted, however, that just because it appears on Geekbench, it doesn’t mean the specs are 100% locked in. There could be various changes between when the testing appears and when something becomes official or is released. One example is that on the benchmark, it mentions running Windows 11 Pro. The final device would likely have the SteamOS Linux-based operating system.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-a-long-time-coming">A Long Time Coming?</h2>



<p>Rumors of a new Steam console from Valve have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rumors-pointing-to-a-new-steam-console-from-valve" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">been circulating for months</a>, known Valve insider Brad Lynch has talked about the device for a while, and added some more context after it showed up on Geekbench.</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/SadlyItsBradley/status/1958024995273068544" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">According to Lynch</a>, Valve Fremont is a “TV focused PC box/console running SteamOS” that “has [a] dedicated HDMI port.” He addes that it’s a semi-custom CPU based on Hawk Point 2 with the integrated GPU removed. </p>



<p>Lastly, speaking of the GPU, it has a dedicated AMD RX 7600 that will all fit in a custom Valve case.</p>



<p>When it launches, the Valve Fremont is expected, according to Lynch, to release alongside the new “Ibex” controller, “Deckard” VR headset, and it’s “Roy” controllers.</p>



<p>Valve has yet to confirm the existence of the Fremont console. But with official benchmarks appearing online, it could be only a matter of time before things become official.</p>



<p>What do you think of a new Valve console for your TV? Let us know down below, and take the discussion even further in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-and-asus-delay-xbox-ally-price-reveal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest news surrounding the ASUS ROG Xbox Ally</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/valve-fremont-steam-console-appears-on-geekbench/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song Remastered International launches December 9]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/romancing-saga-minstrel-song-remastered-international-launches-december-9</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/romancing-saga-minstrel-song-remastered-international-launches-december-9.1275723/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New edition of remastered RPG dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song Remastered International [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/romancing-saga-minstrel-song-remastered-international">Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song Remastered International</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,160 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,270 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,537 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on December 9, publisher <a title="Companies > Red Art Games [37 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/red-art-games">Red Art Games</a> announced in cooperation with <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>. It is a new edition of <em><a title="Games > Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song Remastered [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/romancing-saga-minstrel-song-remastered">Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song Remastered</a></em>, sold separately from the original release, with English, French, Italian, German, and Spanish localizations. <span id="more-986418"></span></p><p>The physical edition will be available for PlayStation 5 and Switch in North America, and for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and Switch in Europe. The standard edition will be available at multiple retailers at launch, while limited and collector’s editions will be exclusive to <a href="https://videogamesplus.ca/search?type=article%2Cpage%2Cproduct&amp;q=%22Romancing*+Saga*+-Minstrel*+Song-*+Remastered*+International%22*" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Video Games Plus</a> in North America and <a href="https://www.redartgames.com/search?controller=search&amp;s=%22Romancing+Saga+-Minstrel+Song-+Remastered+International%22" rel="noopener" target="_blank">RedArtGames.com</a> in Europe.</p><p>Here is an overview of the editions and game:</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ Physical Special Editions</strong></p><p><strong>Standard Edition</strong></p><ul><li>A copy of the game</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Deluxe Edition</strong> (500 PEGI-rated copies per platform, RedArtGames.com-exclusive)</p><ul><li>A copy of the game with a reversible cover</li><li>An exclusive sleeve with alternate cover art</li><li>A manual</li><li>A PVC keychain</li></ul><p><strong>Special Edition</strong> (500 ESRB-rated copies per platform, Video Games Plus-exclusive)</p><ul><li>A copy of the game with a reversible cover</li><li>A PVC keychain</li></ul><p><strong>Collector’s Edition</strong> (1,000 PEGI-rated and 1,000 ESRB-rated copies per platform, RedArtGames.com-exclusive in Europe, Video Games Plus-exclusive in North America)</p><ul><li>A copy of the game with a reversible cover</li><li>A box with retro-inspired cover art (Switch and <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [48,285 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> versions have different boxes)</li><li>A Steelcase</li><li>An artbook</li><li>A manual</li><li>Three postcards</li></ul><p><strong>■ Fact Sheet</strong></p><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>The gods created man and man created stories. The primordial creator Marda brought forth the land of Mardias. In ages past a mighty battle rocked this land, when Elore, the king of the gods, fought three malicious deities: Death, Saruin and Schirach. After a long and drawn-out struggle, Death and Schirach were sealed away and rendered powerless, with the final deity Saruin also trapped through the power of the <a title="Series > Fate [69 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a>stones and the noble sacrifice of the hero Mirsa.</p><p>Now 1,000 years have passed since that titanic battle. The Fatestones lie scattered across the world and the gods of evil are resurgent once more. Eight heroes set off on their own journeys, as if guided by the hand of fate. What tales will these <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,480 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>rs weave across the vast tapestry of Mardias? You are the only one who can decide!</p><p>The original <em>Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song</em> included many of the <em>SaGa</em> series trademark elements, such as the Glimmer and Combo mechanics and was considered to be the epitome of the series when it first released. The free scenario system that lets you create your own storyline remains at the core of the game, letting you select one of eight protagonists with completely different origins and backstories, then set off on a unique journey. This remastered edition has evolved in all areas, featuring upgraded high-definition graphics and numerous enhancements to improve playability. And for the first time ever, the game will be fully playable in French, German, Italian, and Spanish. This makes it highly recommended for both fans of the original and newcomers to the <em>SaGa</em> series.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Brand new localization in French, German, Italian, and Spanish. (English also included.)</li><li>Full high-definition graphical update.</li><li>Schiele, Marina, Monica, and Flammar can now be recruited.</li><li><a title="Companies > Enhance [32 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>d and more difficult bosses.</li><li>High speed mode.</li><li>Mini Maps.</li><li>New Game+ mode.</li></ul><p><strong>■ Staff Comments</strong></p><p><strong><a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>anori Ichikawa, <em>SaGa</em> Series Producer</strong></p><p>“When I was thinking about how I wanted to share this treasured game series with players overseas, Red Art Games approached me, and I truly felt their deep love for <em>SaGa</em>. That was the beginning of this project. And now, I am delighted to announce that the release date has been set for December 9, 2025. This has been made possible thanks to the dedication of many people and the passionate voices of <em>SaGa</em> fans around the world. From the bottom of my heart, thank you very much.”</p><p><strong>Hiroyuki Miura, <em>Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song Remastered</em> Producer</strong></p><p>“The release date for <em>Romancing SaGa: Minstrel Song Remastered International</em> has been announced. With additional language support, we believe players will be able to enjoy the story on an even deeper level. The special editions with brand new merchandise will also be released, so please look forward to it!”</p></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/romancing-saga-minstrel-song-remastered-international-launches-december-9]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RAEV: Kingdom on the Distant Shores – Gamescom 2025 trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/raev-kingdom-on-the-distant-shores-gamescom-2025-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/raev-kingdom-on-the-distant-shores-%E2%80%93-gamescom-2025-trailer.1275717/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Your kingdom, your empire.</p><p>Welcome to the world of Nytland, your new home, my Liege!</p><p>Design intricate cityscapes across diverse biomes, tackle logistical challenges, and make choices that will define the fate of your people.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>There are plenty of elements to build with, from towering castles to quaint hamlets. Go beyond the walls of your first settlement, across multiple regions, building many villages and growing them all into bustling cities, to create a vast trade network that spans the continent. Conquer the surrounding land to expand your area of influence. Your vision will shape an empire that stands the test of time.</p><p><em>RAEV: Kingdom on the Distant Shores</em> pushes the boundaries of city-building—it’s a Kingdom builder, allowing you to build not just one city but many as you construct your kingdom. Every decision matters, from resource <a title="Genres > Management [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> to diplomacy, trade, and citizen welfare. Will you create a utopian paradise, a bustling economic powerhouse, or a militaristic stronghold? The fate of your kingdom is in your hands.</p><p><strong>The <a title="Series > Fate [69 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a> of a Kingdom</strong></p><p><em>RAEV: Kingdom on the Distant Shores</em> is more than just a typical city-builder—it blends elements of <a title="Genres > RPG [17,524 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a>, city building, and grand strategy, making for a novel approach to the genre. As your land grows, dangers will come to threaten your power, from bands of bandits to ancient perils lurking in dungeons and forgotten ruins. Assemble bands of brave <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,480 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>rs to quell such dangers, as a prosperous kingdom will need strong defenses and a keen mind.</p><p><strong>Meet the Raevins</strong></p><p>Your charming citizens, known as Raevins, assist in gathering resources, managing towns, and even uncovering hidden secrets across the land. Their distinct personalities and interactions will make them an integral part of your kingdom, fostering a world that feels alive and enchanting. Train them in unique careers, watch them grow, and shape their destinies.</p><p><strong>Freedom to Build</strong></p><p>Create your dream kingdom, from towering castles to serene gardens and bustling trade hubs. Shape your towns the way you want, making the best of the lands you settle on.</p><p><em>RAEV: Kingdom on the Distant Shores</em> lets you build without the limitation of a grid, place anything you want where you want, paint your roads, and grow your city organically!</p><p><em>RAEV: Kingdom on the Distant Shores</em> offers approachable complexity, making it easy to learn yet rich with depth to master. You begin with a simple village and gradually transform it into an intricate, interconnected realm, balancing strategy and growth as you progress. Build freely in any of your cities and upgrade your buildings through tech advancements as you build an empire worthy of renown.</p></div><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/raev-kingdom-on-the-distant-shores-gamescom-2025-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Made Me Quit Competitive Gaming]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-rivals-made-me-quit-competitive-gaming/1100-6534063/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-made-me-quit-competitive-gaming.1275714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>After far too many hours struggling to climb the hero shooter's ranks, I realized Marvel Rivals was bringing out the worst in me</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A few weeks ago, after yet another frustrating match of Marvel Rivals caused me to power off my console and loudly deride the game and its players, my boyfriend asked how many hours I had played. The game launched shortly after my segue into the world of freelancing, and I had a lot of spare time on my hands. When my boyfriend, who often plays when I do, told me he had logged 16 hours so far, I conservatively guessed "at least double that."</p><p dir="ltr">When I looked at my stats, I nearly threw up. I had spent more than 16 <em>days</em> in the NetEase hero shooter's ranked mode (I don't play anything else) since its December 2024 launch. That's over 400 hours, and for most of that time, I was frustrated, annoyed, or "tilted," as the kids say--desperate to reach an arbitrary goal I had set for myself before I could properly take a break from the game.</p><p dir="ltr">Those shocking gameplay numbers, coupled with an unceremonious rank tumble after the Season 3 rank reset a few weeks ago, made me realize something.</p><p dir="ltr">I have a problem, and it's competitive matchmaking.</p><p dir="ltr">So I quit.</p><hr><p dir="ltr">Marvel Rivals isn't the first game I played competitively. As a high schooler, I would play round after round of SWAT in Halo 3 to try and reach the coveted level 50. I did the same thing years later with Gears of War 3, grinding matches to reach level 100. Later, I spent time on ranked Apex Legends, preferring it to the casual modes.</p><p dir="ltr">But for years, my game of choice was competitive Overwatch. Of the nearly 1,500 hours I've dedicated to the sequel alone, almost all of that time has been spent in competitive play. For a while, I was a globally ranked Moira player on console. I only stopped playing Overwatch 2 when I had grown too tired of the grind and Rivals glittered on the horizon.</p><p dir="ltr">Every game that I play competitively, I play alone, queueing up for ranked matches solo and, in hero shooters, as a support character. This is widely considered a Bad Idea: Solo queuing means you get a new team every match, which means no squad chemistry--and support players are often the least appreciated and the first to get yelled at when something goes awry.</p><p dir="ltr">With Rivals, my quality as a support player never felt like enough to carry a team to victory, and my fruitless efforts to rank up while playing the most thankless role began weighing on me.</p><p dir="ltr">So when I caught wind of a rumor that suggested NetEase's hero shooter is baking the bad experience into the game with its matchmaking system, I perked up. Maybe the problem isn't me…maybe it's the game.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4553333-4282226-marvelrivals%285%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4553333" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4553333-4282226-marvelrivals%285%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4553333"></a><figcaption>Two super hero teams battle it out in Marvel Rivals</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4553333-4282226-marvelrivals%285%29.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Matchmaking is a confusing and hotly contested topic in the world of competitive gaming. I've written extensively about skill-based matchmaking (or SBMM), a system used by games like Call of Duty and Apex Legends to determine which players populate in-game lobbies. Though the actual numbers that go into these systems usually vary by game or developer, the core logic is simple: Players are matched with similarly skilled players, whether that's based on kill/death ratio, hours logged, or total wins.</p><p dir="ltr">Since implementation of these systems varies from game to game, there are instances in which players have grown increasingly more frustrated with a specific studio's take on SBMM. In January 2023, <a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-matchmaking-reset-ranked-fix-mmr-season-3-1850050963" rel="nofollow ">Overwatch 2 addressed "community pain points with competitive matchmaking"</a> and made adjustments. Later that year, <a href="https://dotesports.com/call-of-duty/news/mw3-reddit-ama-sbmm-community-demands-answers" rel="nofollow ">Call of Duty fans flooded a Reddit AMA for Modern Warfare III</a><em>, </em>begging and/or demanding that Activision rework its SBMM system.</p><p dir="ltr">But SBMM isn't the only system multiplayer games use to create matches. A <a href="https://web.cs.ucla.edu/~yzsun/papers/WWW17Chen_EOMM.pdf" rel="nofollow ">2017 paper from a former Electronic Arts intern discusses EOMM</a>, or engagement optimized matchmaking, laying out a framework for an ideology that prioritizes engagement over fairness. EA patented this concept, but as far as I know, there isn't a game in its portfolio (which includes Apex Legends and the Battlefield franchise) that uses it.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/marvel-rivals-matchmaking-eomm-optmatch-netease-multiplayer-anger/" rel="nofollow ">Marvel Rivals players are convinced, however, that NetEase is using EOMM in its matches</a>. Though the company did publish a <a href="http://google.com/search?q=netease+optmatch&amp;rlz=1C1RXQR_enUS1119US1119&amp;oq=netease+optmatch&amp;gs_lcrp=EgZjaHJvbWUyBggAEEUYOTIMCAEQIxgnGIAEGIoFMgcIAhAAGIAEMg0IAxAAGJECGIAEGIoFMg0IBBAuGMcBGNEDGIAEMgcIBRAAGIAEMgYIBhBFGDwyBggHEEUYPNIBCDE3OTNqMGo0qAIAsAIB&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">2020 academic paper about a matchmaking system called OptMatch</a>, which emphasizes player engagement, the system does not appear to value engagement more than fairness.</p><p dir="ltr">But I get it. Rivals using EOMM (or some version of it) would certainly make so many of us frustrated by the rank climb grind feel a bit better about our abilities, right? I'm not stuck in Platinum because I suck; I'm stuck in Platinum because the Rivals matchmaking system determined I needed to go on a losing streak, get completely tilted, and then hand me a win to keep me from embedding my controller in the television.</p><p dir="ltr">It just doesn't seem to be the case, guys. In response to the rumors, NetEase<a href="https://x.com/MarvelRivals/status/1955117077561593877" rel="nofollow "> <em>just</em> released a statement on X</a> on August 12, stating, "We want to reiterate that Marvel Rivals does not use EOMM. We are currently working on a video to demonstrate our developer insights on the matchmaking and ranking system, which is expected to be released next week."</p><hr><p dir="ltr">Though the matchmaking debate piqued my interest again for a bit, no matter what NetEase tells us about their matchmaking system, it won't bring me back. The embarrassing knowledge of the time I've invested in Marvel Rivals is now forever a part of me, embedded in the sinews of my muscles like an ever-present ache.</p><p dir="ltr">Those numbers helped me realize that so much of my time as a gamer has been spent trying to excel in first-person shooters, which are largely male-dominated spaces that are consistently and persistently hostile for people like me. I think, subconsciously, I've spent the last 20 years trying to be good at competitive games as a way to undeniably prove that I deserve to be in this space, that I'm just as much of a "gamer" as the men screaming slurs at me.</p><p dir="ltr">Rivals broke that spell, snapping me out of my single-minded quest to be the best. Even if my bad time is because of a questionable matchmaking mechanic, does that negate all the frustration I've felt? Confirmation that there's some kind of mathematical formula ensuring carrot-and-sticking me so I stay around longer doesn't change the reality: These kinds of games are bad for me.</p><p dir="ltr">Do you know what's way more fun than trying to heal a raging DPS player who just demanded I fellate him? Dropping into Fortnite as Lady Gaga, head-shotting Peely, and popping the A$AP Ferg "Socks" emote before driving away in a yellow Corvette blasting "Juno" by Sabrina Carpenter.</p><p dir="ltr">Goodbye, competitive gaming. I'd say I'll miss you, but I won't.</p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
              


  

    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-rivals-made-me-quit-competitive-gaming/1100-6534063/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Won't (Or Can't) Reveal ROG Xbox Ally X Price Yet But Report Says It Could Be $900]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-wont-or-cant-reveal-rog-xbox-ally-x-price-yet-but-report-says-it-could-be-900/1100-6534122/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-wont-or-cant-reveal-rog-xbox-ally-x-price-yet-but-report-says-it-could-be-900.1275708/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534122">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Microsoft announced the release date for the ROG Xbox Ally devices today, confirming they will <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rog-xbox-ally-handheld-launch-date-set-for-october-features-steam-deck-style-compatibility/1100-6534120/" data-ref-id="1100-6534120">release worldwide on October 16</a>. However, the company has not disclosed the price points, telling fans to sit tight for a bit longer for pricing and preorder dates. Additionally, a report has emerged that claims the price of the most expensive ROG Xbox Ally device could run you $900.</p><p>Xbox executive Jason Ronald told <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-still-cant-say-how-much-the-rog-xbox-ally-x-will-cost-due-to-macro-economic-conditions-despite-announcing-release-date-and-availability-details" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN</a> that the "macro-economic climate is challenging" when it comes to pricing. This is likely a reference to the ongoing tariff situation, which has led to increases in prices for some products, including gaming items.</p><p>Beyond the impact of tariffs and other macro-economic factors, Ronald said it's "always a challenge" to set a product's price and have it strike the "right balance between affordability and price point."</p><p>"And I think especially in a mobile form factor that also adds in dimensions such as battery life in as well," Ronald said.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VTaboYwSyuc" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VTaboYwSyuc" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Asus executive Shawn Yen said the company needs "more time to figure out the macro-economic impact to pricing." Fans can expect pricing and preorder details to be revealed later. <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/20/rog-xbox-ally-handheld-release-date-october-features/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Microsoft's official word on the matter</a> is that more details on pricing and preorder details will arrive "in the coming weeks."</p><p>A <a href="https://x.com/billbil_kun/status/1958097960241123337" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report from billbil-kun</a> said the ROG Xbox Ally will be $550, with the ROG Xbox Ally X coming in at $900. These prices are not confirmed, though <a href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1958166743160881435" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Best Buy posted product pages showing these prices before removing them.</a> It's possible these prices are not real or could change due to tariffs and other market factors. Many may recall how Nintendo delayed Switch 2 preorders due to tariffs. While the price for the console didn't go up, Nintendo did decide to charge more for certain accessories. </p><p>In addition to revealing the release date for the ROG Xbox Ally devices, Microsoft announced the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rog-xbox-ally-handheld-launch-date-set-for-october-features-steam-deck-style-compatibility/1100-6534120/" data-ref-id="1100-6534120">Handheld Compatibility Program</a>, which is a Steam Deck Verified-like program that filter games by whether or not they are "Handheld Optimized" or "Mostly Compatible."</p><p>Additionally, Microsoft revealed a new "advanced shader delivery" feature that preloads game shaders during download, which Microsoft claims allows select games to boot up to 10 times faster, along with running more smoothly and using less battery power. Additionally, Microsoft said the ROG Xbox Ally X will have new AI-powered features delivered via an update in 2026 that will add things like automatic super resolution and a "highlight reel" feature that uses AI to capture "standout gameplay moments."</p><p>Microsoft is also working on a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-gen-xbox-console-aims-to-put-players-first-says-microsoft/1100-6534059/" data-ref-id="1100-6534059">new Xbox home console in partnership with AMD</a>. The Xbox Series X|S generation is <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7361111873749991426/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">winding down</a>, but there is no word yet on when the next Xbox console will be revealed.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-wont-or-cant-reveal-rog-xbox-ally-x-price-yet-but-report-says-it-could-be-900/1100-6534122/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield Is Coming To Nintendo Switch 2, Leaker Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfield-is-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2-leaker-claims/1100-6534121/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starfield-is-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2-leaker-claims.1275705/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534121">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>With Xbox bringing more games to other platforms, word has just emerged of Bethesda's first game heading to Switch 2. Now, a leak suggests that another Bethesda game, Starfield, is also on the way to the handheld.</p><p>Yesterday's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements-games-and-trailers/2900-6888/" data-ref-id="2900-6888">Gamescom Opening Night Live</a> presentation included the announcement of a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-order-of-giants-looks-like-the-best-of-the-great-circle-and-its-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2-too/1100-6534094/" data-ref-id="1100-6534094">Switch 2 port of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> coming out sometime in 2026--and according to NateTheHate, Starfield will come out on Nintendo's recently released console in the same year.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1957886310896796027" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Indiana Jones &amp; the Great Circle won't be the only Bethesda game coming to Nintendo Switch 2 in 2026.<br>See that planet? You can go there.<br>Aside from landing on PS5... Starfield is planned for release on Nintendo Switch 2 in 2026. <a href="https://t.co/DmcgEpbPuN" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/DmcgEpbPuN</a></p>  — NateTheHate2 (@NateTheHate2) <a href="https://twitter.com/NateTheHate2/status/1957886310896796027?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 19, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>NateTheHate also claimed that Starfield is indeed coming to PlayStation 5, as rumors have persisted since the RPG's 2023 release. A separate report from this month <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfield-could-come-to-ps5-next-spring-report/1100-6533651/" data-ref-id="1100-6533651">alleges that Starfield will release on PS5</a> in the spring of 2026.</p><p>While Bethesda has not officially confirmed plans for Starfield receiving a multiplatform release outside of Xbox and PC, Microsoft Gaming CEO <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-reveal-doesnt-make-microsoft-nervous-about-its-own-next-gen-plans-phil-spencer-says/1100-6530893/" data-ref-id="1100-6530893">Phil Spencer stated his intention to support the Switch 2</a> in the past. Putting out the highly acclaimed Indiana Jones and the Great Circle may be the first step of the publisher's Switch 2 strategy. </p><p>Besides Indiana Jones, there is a strong precedent for Bethesda games on the original Switch, including ports of The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim, Doom Eternal, and Wolfenstein II: The New Colossus. Microsoft-owned Activision also committed to bringing Call of Duty titles to Nintendo platforms, but there has yet to be any indication of Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 coming to Switch 2.</p><p>Switch 2 ports of Indiana Jones and Starfield should also prove to be interesting cases on how current-generation games run on the handheld platform--on the lower-end Xbox Series S, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfield-adds-60fps-on-xbox-series-s-along-with-other-performance-updates/1100-6526021/" data-ref-id="1100-6526021">Starfield has multiple performance options</a>, including 30fps and 60fps modes. And from the perspective of Starfield players, the release of a Switch 2 version may give them hope of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfield-fans-losing-hope-after-space-adventure-absent-from-xbox-showcase/1100-6532288/" data-ref-id="1100-6532288">Bethesda giving the title some additional attention</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfield-is-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2-leaker-claims/1100-6534121/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Naked Gun Will Heal Cinema]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/naked-gun-2025-review-movie</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-naked-gun-will-heal-cinema.1275687/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure><figcaption><span><p>Credit: Paramount Pictures</p>
</span></figcaption></figure></div><div><p>Theatrical comedies in general have taken a beating in the last few years. <em>The Naked Gun</em> is a blast from the past, a reminder that we are not better than the most puerile, 3rd grade bits and gags you can throw at us. Chris Person and Gita Jackson sat down to discuss why they love the various gags, spoofs and bits of Detective Frank Drebin Jr. and Beth Davenport.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Gita</strong>: Hello Chris! We are here to talk about <em>The Naked Gun</em>, a very very funny movie I had no idea was directed by Akiva Schaeffer from The Lonely Island! I had a hell of a lot of fun watching this one in a theater full of laughing people. I went in completely blind, just off the recommendations of friends, and I actually have never seen a <em>Naked Gun</em> movie before this. What's your relationship to the series, if you have one?</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Top Secret! - Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q5zen7sHQFI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><strong>Chris: </strong>I have a deep love for the spoof movie genre in every era, and basically anything descended from or adjacent to the Zucker brothers (especially <em>Top Secret!</em>) It's hard enough to get a comedy out there generally, let alone one of these, and I had a feeling they were on to something the second I saw they had cast&nbsp; Liam Neeson to replace Leaslie Nielsen.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Gita: </strong>Man, Liam Neeson really killed it in this movie. Some of his line reads were so unexpected and hilarious. I especially loved the way he tackled the part of the character that takes everything extremely literally. But to me the real standout of the film was Pamela Anderson. A delight in every scene.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="The Naked Gun | Official Trailer (2025 Movie) - Liam Neeson, Pamela Anderson" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uLguU7WLreA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><strong>Chris:</strong> She's doing the Priscilla Presley role from the original series and I'm glad they cast her, it's the perfect role for her. She has always been underrated in comic roles and she organically knew how to nail the tone. Also she looks good! And she and Liam Neeson are apparently dating now.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Gita: </strong>THEY'RE SOOOOOOOOO CUTE TOGETHER. They had such incredible chemistry in the movie, I'm so happy they got together.</p><p><strong>Chris: </strong>Though I don't think it's important to know the details of a plot like this because it's just pure gags, it's fun to do anyway. Neeson plays Frank Drebin Jr., son of Leslie Nielsen's character from the first series. It starts with the big <em>Dark Knight</em> style bank heist from the trailer, but the whole thing is a cover for the bad guys to get away with a P.L.O.T. Device. This propels Frank towards a mysterious car crash, the victim's sister Beth Davenport (played by Anderson) and tech billionaire named Richard Cane played excellently by Danny Huston.</p><p><strong>Gita</strong>: This is a movie where the script is designed to cram as many jokes as humanly possible into each and every scene. It's a little bit <em>Simpsons</em>-esque in that it's always trying to make someone laugh, creating this environment where someone is always laughing in the theater with you. I cracked the fuck up at a gag related to the uncensored version of "Lets Get It Started" by The Black Eyed Peas, because, as you know, the DJ played it at my wedding. But the movie is filled with random gags you might even miss if you're not paying attention.</p><p><strong>Chris P:</strong> They subscribe to the ideology of the original movie that there should constantly be a machine gun spray of bits aggressively happening, oftentimes building one on top of another. A lot of times it's the Zucker style "Don't Call Me Shirley" wordplay filling in the gaps, the audience should not have room to rest. If one doesn't land, wait half a second.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Don't Call Me Shirley - Airplane! (9/10) Movie CLIP (1980) HD" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ixljWVyPby0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Personally I love the recurring bit about the fact that the cops just keep getting cups of coffee handed to them, and are throwing the old ones away, and the cups just keep getting bigger. That's not smart humor but smart humor is overrated. Gimmie the stupid stuff. Give me that 2 brain cells <em>Scary Movie</em> stuff.</p><p><strong>Gita:</strong> God that bit is so good. I also loved Liam Neeson's bodycam footage later in the movie where he keeps eating chili dogs and starts crying about how disgusting he is. But by far my favorite gag is the windshield thing.</p><p><strong>Chris P: </strong>God that bit kept going. I hate to relate everything to <em>The Simpsons</em> but that is a Homer bit.</p><p>I hate calling a movie "important" because that is loaded and in the case of <em>Naked Gun</em> seems absurd to say, but the reason it is doing well is because a core need has not been satisfied for a very long time. Every culture needs its silly goof movies, in Hong Kong in the 90s it was "<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mo_lei_tau" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mo lei tau</a>" (think Stephen Chow) and we had ours until various forces decimated theatrical comedy. Now the stuff that survived is too clever by half or too poorly made in a cynical way. We needed this W.&nbsp; It feels of a piece of the last movie we chatted about: <a href="https://aftermath.site/the-day-the-earth-blew-up-looney-tunes-warner-bros-zaslav" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Day the Earth Blew Up: A Looney Tunes Movie</em></a>.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Gita:</strong> Right! I was thinking that while I was in the theater with my husband. As we walked out of the cinema, he told me he was hoping that this movie had the same impact on a teenager as <em>Anchorman </em>had on him. The mid budget comedy used to rule the box office—the Judd Apatow movie was once my bread and butter. Like the rom-com, that has given way for the superhero movie, which feels like a real shame. There is simply nothing that makes you feel closer to your fellow man than laughing your ass off to the same stupid joke in the theater. It does feel important. Like, I want to remember how good it feels to be a part of the human race.</p><p><strong>Chris</strong>: Comedy and horror are two of the most important genres to see theatrically if you can. You need other people there! Laughter, like fear, is infectious. A minor joke might not land with you until you see someone laughing way too hard and then it'll catch you. Other people can sell you on a joke in ways that you'll never be sold with streaming.</p><p><strong>Chris:</strong> I also just think on a basic level everyone involved understood the assignment, and gave it their all. You can tell that these people have a deep reverence for these movies, that they have studied what makes them work. There's a part where Frank Dreben Jr. is expounding on how he wants to be both paradoxically exactly like his dad but totally different and fresh in every way, and that's just the riddle of the film. Can you pull that off? And the answer is yes.</p><p><strong>Gita: </strong>As soon as I saw that Akiva Schaefer directed this, I understood why this movie worked. It's the Lonely Island thing of being highbrow and lowbrow at the same time. The reason why "Spring Break Anthem" works is because it is a both an incredibly silly juxtaposition of the heterosexual debauchery of spring break culture with the genuine love of two men getting married—and also a damning juxtaposition of how American culture tolerates straight men going out of control and objectifying women but also condemns homosexuality. Important to note that gay marriage wasn't legal in every state when this was made! The Naked Gun isn't reaching for that level of dissonance—though in there is a critique of Silicon Valley and tech oligarchs in there—-but it has the same ability to communicate two ideas at once.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Spring Break Anthem (Music Video Only Version)" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jUw4Qh9uFK8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><strong>Chris: </strong>Adjacent to that a lot of people slept on <em>Popstar: Never Stop Never Stopping</em>. Also apparently everyone involved in this worked on that <em>Chip 'n Dale: Rescue Rangers</em> movie and now I'm wondering if that movie was cooking.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Popstar: Never Stop Never Stopping - Official Trailer (HD)" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q9RoNzJrmDo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><strong>Gita: </strong>Fuck... <em>Popstar </em>is one of my favorite comedies of all time. Do I have to watch <em>Chip 'n' Dale</em>?</p><p><strong>Chris: </strong>I think we might have to Gita.</p><p><strong>Gita:</strong> Well if we do it, we gotta get a crowd. You really need it for a good comedy.</p><p><strong>Chris: </strong>I think I realize why I never saw it: it was sent to die on Disney+.</p><p><strong>Gita: </strong>GOD. You're so right about comedies and streaming. It's hard to say exactly how much seeing this one in theaters improved the viewing experience, but honestly, reacting to a movie with other people is just one of the best things in the world. There was a couple on a date in my screening and on the way out they were telling each other their favorite lines. You can't replicate that on streaming unless you get all your friends together, and most often I end up streaming movies because I'm bored and alone.</p><p>It feels like the mid budget comedy is now, essentially, a streaming only genre. I think <em>The Naked Gun</em> makes a case for changing that status quo. I mean, what was it like for you to be surrounded by other viewers for the extended bit where Neeson and Pamela Anderson go to a romantic getaway in a cabin, only to use a magic spell to bring a snowman to life that tries to kill them both out of jealousy? It's a joke so absurd that you want other people around, to make sure it's actually happening.</p><p><strong>Chris</strong>: <em>Naked Gun</em> is the future. <em>Naked Gun</em> is the past. <em>Naked Gun</em> is a movie that will heal cinema.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/la-divina-commedia-game-gamescom-dantes-inferno"><h3>OK History, That’s Enough Rhyming For One Day</h3></a><p>Another Dante's Inferno action game was not on my bingo card for this year, or... life</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/ai-voice-acting-soundalike-video-games"><h3>‘It’s Just Not Impressive If A Robot Is Doing It:’ Soundalike Voice Actors On AI</h3></a><p>Jennifer Hale joins voice actors calling for ethical boundaries as AI reshapes (and erases) the traditions of soundalike performances</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/mafia-old-country-review-impressions"><h3>Curling Up With A Sandwich, A Warm Drink And Mafia: The Old Country</h3></a><p>'I'm genuinely wistful for a good 'ol 7/10, last-days-of -summer video game'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/esports-world-cup-new-global-sport-conference-2025-hideo-kojima"><h3>Come On, Guys</h3></a><p>Nobody is forcing Hideo Kojima and a host of industry luminaries to attend a Saudi sportswashing conference. And yet!</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/naked-gun-2025-review-movie]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Hate This Place Launches on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, Nintendo Switch and PC this November]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/i-hate-this-place-release-date-ps5-xbox-nintendo-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-hate-this-place-launches-on-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-nintendo-switch-and-pc-this-november.1275660/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>After debuting our first look at gameplay for the '80s-looking isometric horror action game, I Hate This Place, <a href="https://wccftech.com/i-hate-this-place-gameplay-trailer-debut/">just last month</a>, developer Broken Mirror Games and publisher Skybound Games have announced that I Hate This Place will land on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, Nintendo Switch, and PC this coming <strong>November 7, 2025</strong> as part of this week's Gamescom 2025 festivities.</p>



<p>The release date trailer shows off even more gameplay and more of the '80s aesthetic that makes the game stand out in the crowd of isometric games available on the market today. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="I Hate This Place - Release Date Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VbXG7Zcl61U?start=2&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>I Hate This Place is a debut title for both its developer and publisher. It's Broken Mirror Games' first title after being founded in 2024, and it's the first game that publisher Skybound Games is working on since the publisher was founded by <a href="https://wccftech.com/bloober-team-announces-partnership-with-skybound-entertainment-developing-a-new-title-by-2025/">Bloober Team at the end of 2023</a>.</p>



<p>Even though we've just seen a few trailers at this point, it already looks like it is shaping up to be one hell of a debut game. And if you're in attendance at Gamescom 2025, then you'll be able to put that theory to the test, since you can head over to the studio's booth in Arena Hall 10.1, Stand A:044 to check out I Hate This Place and play it for yourself.</p>



<figure></figure>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/i-hate-this-place-release-date-ps5-xbox-nintendo-pc/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom’s Upcoming Blockbusters Feel Old In The Best Way]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/onimusha-way-sword-pragmata-resident-evil-9-preview-2000618849</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom%E2%80%99s-upcoming-blockbusters-feel-old-in-the-best-way.1275654/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p><span>These days, most AAA video game companies are struggling to gain and maintain momentum in a fickle marketplace when games are taking longer than ever to make. Capcom, meanwhile, is on a hot streak. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/street-fighter-6-review-world-tour-story-mode-roster-1850481281"><i><span>Street Fighter 6</span></i></a><span>, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dragons-dogma-2-review-ps5-1851349573"><i><span>Dragon’s Dogma 2</span></i></a><span>, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-review-ps5-open-world-rpg-capcom-1851766113"><i><span>Monster Hunter Wilds</span></i></a><span>, and the continued renaissance of the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-4-re4-remaster-remake-review-capcom-ps5-1850278891"><i><span>Resident Evil</span></i></a> <span>series are just a few examples of the developer being in a no-skips, all-hits era. I recently got a chance to play three of the company’s upcoming games: </span><i><span>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Pragmata</span></i><span>, and </span><i><span>Resident Evil Requiem</span></i><span>, and my limited time with each spoke both to the variety in the company’s line-up, but also indicated a refreshing “back to basics” mentality that a lot of AAA companies can’t seem to fathom in 2025. These games feel like they’re from a different era, and that’s for the better.</span></p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Onimusha: Way of the Sword - 3rd Trailer: The Genma Experiments | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bf1cAQIKpWA?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><i><span>Onimusha: Way of the Sword </span></i><span>was the first game I played during my preview session, and after 20 years away, the latest </span><i><span>Onimusha </span></i><span>feels surprisingly untouched by the RPG trappings that have latched onto many modern action games. The section I played was the same one I saw at Summer Game Fest, which showed samurai warrior Musashi Miyamoto slicing his way through a mostly derelict village overrun by underworldly monsters. At first blush, </span><i><span>Way of the Sword </span></i><span>might feel a bit simple to the modern action game fan who has become so used to skill trees and Soulslike difficulty. But there was a time in the PlayStation 2 era when a good parry and dodge mechanic was enough to satisfy you for about 10 to 15 hours.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>When I played </span><i><span>Way of the Sword</span></i><span>, I was caught off guard by how “of its time” it felt. It’s as if it picks up where the series left off 20 years ago, but with a bit of modern flair and finesse. The boss fight at the end of the demo against Ganryu Sasaki, a fellow Oni Gauntlet-wearing swordsman, was challenging enough to prove that skillful swordplay is enough to carry an action game in 2025, even as the genre more frequently de-emphasizes those core fundamentals.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Pragmata - First Contact Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PdDVyBtYrUI?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><span>That same streamlined focus was evident when I played </span><i><span>Pragmata</span></i><span>. I already </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pragmata-capcom-preview-summer-game-fest-impressions-1851784342"><span>wrote up impressions of the demo</span></a><span> I played at Summer Game Fest, and this appointment was mostly focused on the same early section of the game, just with a boss fight at the end. Like </span><i><span>Way of the Sword</span></i><span>, the sci-fi puzzle shooter feels like something plucked out of a previous generation. Its over-the-shoulder shooting, brutalist sci-fi aesthetic, and dad game setup make it feel exactly like something you would’ve seen on a GameStop shelf during the PS360 generation. As I said back in June, it keeps from feeling like a rote retread of old tropes by combining its shooting with a real-time puzzle-solving element that has you breaking down enemy defenses and opens a window for your bullets to actually do real damage. Separately, these mechanics are simple and perhaps unremarkable; together, they create a big-budget shooter that would have been the kind of fun, one-off experiment a company like Capcom would have released between big sequels. Even as Capcom has put out hit after hit, the company has become pretty reliant on sequels in the same way pretty much every other AAA developer has. It’s refreshing to see that it still has the chops to put out something like </span><i><span>Pragmata</span></i><span>, a non-sequel which may pull from old motifs, but also feels novel as games like it have gone out of style in recent years.</span></p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Resident Evil Requiem - Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/POz1-EmLsTY?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><span>That brings us to </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-requiem-9-grace-trailer-gamescom-mother-2000618547"><i><span>Resident Evil Requiem</span></i></a><span>, the latest entry in a series that has spent the better part of a decade reinventing itself. What I played of the ninth mainline game in the long-running survival horror series felt more evocative of </span><i><span>Haunting Ground</span></i><span>, a cult classic hide-and-seek horror game Capcom put out in 2005, than the misadventures of Chris Redfield and Leon Kennedy. As we see more of it, </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>may eventually adopt the more action-oriented flow of 2021’s </span><i><span>Resident Evil Village </span></i><span>or stay in the escape room-esque hide-and-seek loop of the segment I played, but in the demo&nbsp; section, at least, it felt like the game had been stripped down to its core elements to leave you with a terrifying helplessness. All I had to defend myself from a horrifying monstrosity that followed me back and forth through a dimly lit hallway was my wits, glass bottles, and whatever light sources I could find to scare it away. </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>has been experimenting with what it means to carry that name for a while, and so perhaps it’s fitting that what I played of </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>didn’t make me think of </span><i><span>Resident Evil</span></i><span> much at all, but rather of a </span><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/survival-horror/after-20-years-capcom-removes-its-website-for-controversial-usd500-ps2-horror-game-and-i-know-the-bad-ending-might-get-you-pregnant-but-im-prepared-to-stage-a-funeral-if-there-isnt-a-remake/"><span>long-lost gem that Capcom has mostly forgotten</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>All three of these games are coming out in 2026, and by then, we’ll be another trip around the sun removed from the games that seemingly inspired each of them, and they could feel even more out of time. Even so, Capcom’s dedication to the old ways of doing things, when it feels like every other month we’re hearing about a beloved franchise or </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-bioware-layoffs-mass-effect-1851784416"><span>company</span></a><span> being handcuffed to&nbsp; modern practices solely meant to make every game a time suck, is a big part of the reason it’s put out mostly bangers for the past few years. I’m not usually one to say “things were better back in my day,” but it is nice to have reminders that not every developer has learned the wrong lessons. At least one major player is willing to go back to the well, find what worked before, and meaningfully iterate on it instead of breaking it apart to turn it into something we no longer recognize.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/onimusha-way-sword-pragmata-resident-evil-9-preview-2000618849]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tropico 7 Announced For 2026 Release]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tropico-7-announced-for-2026-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tropico-7-announced-for-2026-release.1275651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The next game in the long-running Tropico series has been announced as Tropico 7 is heading to console and PC in 2026.</p>



<p>In a short reveal trailer during the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lu6R8W91lM8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Gamescom showcase</a>, it was announced that Tropico 7 will be available for Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC. The game will also be available day one on Xbox Game Pass. </p>



<p>No other details about the game were revealed. Nor was it mentioned when more information will be announced.</p>



<p>Are you excited to for the next game in the popular dictator-simulation franchise? Let us know down below, and take the discussion even further in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-and-asus-delay-xbox-ally-price-reveal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest news surrounding the ASUS ROG Xbox Ally</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tropico-7-announced-for-2026-release/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong - We Played It! | gamescom 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-we-played-it-gamescom-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksong-we-played-it-gamescom-2025.1275642/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I finally played Hollow Knight: Silksong. No, I don’t mean to brag, but instead find myself having to type it out just to convince my eyes that it actually happened. Yes, it may have only been for around 20 minutes, but the long-awaited sequel shows little sign of disappointing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">During my demo at gamescom 2025, I was faced with a choice of two areas to play in: Moss Grotto or Deep Docks. Of course, I was going to try both, but first went for Moss Grotto — based on nothing apart from green being my favourite colour — which turned out to be the right decision. This sunlit grassy zone appears to be the very beginning of Silksong, as I fell into it following a brief cutscene in which a caged Hornet (the playable princess-protector protagonist) breaks free from the metal wagon she’s held captive in by collapsing the bridge it’s being paraded on. Developer Team Cherry seems keen on immersing us straight back into the world of Hollow Knight right from the very beginning, teasing lore via a passage of Conductor Romino's Pharloom Folly.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Hollow Knight: Silksong 2025 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Moss Grotto itself, it felt very much like a (re)introduction to the core mechanics of Hollow Knight. A mixture of rudimentary platforming and simple battles was littered across its grassy floors in a short but sweet section of Silksong’s presumably sprawling labyrinth of a world. It all ended with a boss fight against a large queen-bee-like insect that attempted to lock me in her lair. Moss Mother gave me little boss bother, though, dispatching them by unlocking that long-dormant Hollow Knight muscle memory as I leapt over darting diagonal attacks and evaded crumbling rocks falling from the sky. It was action platforming 101, but still felt incredibly satisfying.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I then swiftly moved onto Deep Docks, which turned out to be an entirely different proposition. Tools such as kunai, which can be thrown horizontally to pierce foes, were added to my arsenal, along with skills such as a familiar dash ability. Things naturally get more complex with more items to juggle, which is reflected in Deep Docks' level design that comprises a maze of clanking metal elevators and the numerous semi-hidden levers that operate them. I may have only spent a handful of minutes there, but I could already see myself getting hopelessly lost without the aid of one of Cornifer’s ever-valuable maps.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Discovering the secrets of Hollow Knight's world was maybe the purest of its joys to me; I wouldn't want Silksong to feel like running into a brick wall too often.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Upon unlocking a boss arena, I was confronted by an enemy of far greater threat than any I had encountered yet. Lace, a balletic white insect, not too dissimilar in look to Hornet herself, dazzled me with intricate combos delivered at a speed my poor brain could not compute quickly enough. Defeated, I moved on, knowing this would be a battle for another day and not one I particularly wanted the dozens of people waiting in the queue behind to witness me losing again and again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While it's too early to gauge the overall difficulty of Silksong, the jump up in this later area was noticeable, with enemies capable of far more than simple prods and darts. I usually welcome added complexity and evolution of combat when it comes to sequels, so I have no great issue here. I just hope that in totality, fights won't become too tiresome with exploration and progress being halted too often. Discovering the secrets of Hollow Knight's world was maybe the purest of its joys to me; I wouldn't want Silksong to feel like running into a brick wall too often.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There are concessions to make you feel more powerful compared to the original, though. Health regain is now divorced from skills, meaning you can throw those kunai liberally without having to sacrifice a potential life-saving heal. Attack is still the best form of defense, echoing some of my favourite systems from the likes of Control, Doom Eternal, and, of course, the original Hollow Knight. This is emphasised by the fact that you can only trigger health regen when your silk-white bar is full, encouraging even more offensive maneuvers to build that up quickly. Dodging will only get you so far in Hollow Knight Silksong.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All of these tweaks and changes tie together to create a more aggressive minibeast, and, although I certainly have a soft spot for the original Hollow Knight, I’m finding myself instantly drawn to Silksong more. 2018's game often placed you on the back foot, but here I felt instantly more empowered and ready to go toe-to-toe with my aggressors. As someone who traditionally enjoys the push of faster-paced action games as opposed to the pull of more modern examples of the genre (I’m really trying my hardest not to use the term soulslike here), I’m left encouraged. Creature design is still one of the highlights in the sequel, with the borderline adorable adversaries <em>almost </em>being too cute to stab. At one stage, I got locked in a room with some flying nuisances with pots over their heads who lobbed molten rocks at me, as well as a pudgy little round lad with a saucepan for a shield. I almost felt bad killing them. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But in truth, combat was never the highlight of Hollow Knight for me anyway, but rather the layers of exploration and discovery lurking beneath each of its beautifully crafted environments. And while I’ve barely scratched the surface of what secrets Silksong has stored in this regard, initial impressions promise a similar bounty of nooks and crannies packed full of insect friends and foes. Platforming through these mazes is still a joy; a delicately delightful balance between precision and floaty jumping that tests your skills, that crucially never feels unfair when dropping into a gap unwillingly. The addition of mantling in the sequel helps this massively, with edges freely within grasp even when slight misjudgments are made.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I was instantly taken by how much more colourful the environments are this time around. Cinders dance around caves dripping with lava and glowing green moss dresses earthy overhangs, themselves floating precariously above pools of glistening water. Hornet's red cape billows against the painted backdrops, both acting in harmony to form the sort of Saturday morning cartoon look you'd expect if one were to hang in the Louvre. Hornet also feels bigger on the screen, dominating the frame to a greater degree than her meeker-yet-still-mighty forebearer. That visual design feels like a deliberate choice, one aimed at creating more of a power trip sensation this time around. It's these ideas — from revamped combat design to its repainted world – that appear to be acting in concert to a magical degree, and impressive proof, even in this small dose, of what Team Cherry has been brewing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Yes, we've been waiting many, many years for this sequel, but everything at this stage points to it being worth it. Each aspect feels authored and prescribed to a clear vision — a piece of playable art that is as fun to wield as it is to watch (I should know, the gamescom queue was very long). It may have been the shortest of demos, but so far, Silksong is very much singing to me, maybe even more than the original.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-we-played-it-gamescom-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Blood of Dawnwalker Offers 2 Very Different RPG Playstyles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-blood-of-dawnwalker-offers-2-very-different-rpg-playstyles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-blood-of-dawnwalker-offers-2-very-different-rpg-playstyles.1275639/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Witcher series really did well to capture that sense of exploring a brutal fantasy world as a protagonist who knew how to get their hands dirty. But in the upcoming dark fantasy RPG The Blood of Dawnwalker, a new game from a team of former creatives behind The Witcher 3, it leans further into a morally ambiguous setting as you decide which path its protagonist will take – one that maintains his human form and ideals, or one that embraces newfound powers as a half-vampire.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just ahead of Gamescom 2025, we got an extended walkthrough of The Blood of Dawnwalker from the devs at Rebel Wolves that put a spotlight on the parallel playstyles of human and vampire action-RPG gameplay. So far, The Blood of Dawnwalker is putting forth some strong concepts for its take on a dark-fantay RPG that's all about navigating two different worlds in cunning fashion.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Blood of Dawnwalker - Gamescom 2025 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Part of what makes vampires so compelling as horror characters is that they can be tragic figures. Having to contend with supernatural forces that potentially put them at odds with humanity is a concept that can be great to explore in video games. That idea is at the heart of The Blood of Dawnwalker.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Set in a supernatural version of 14th-century Europe, The Blood of Dawnwalker focuses on Coen and his vendetta against a powerful coven of vampires that seek to take over Europe with violence and even some old-fashioned medieval-era politicking. After Coen has a violent encounter with the vampire leader Brencis following the abduction of his family, the protagonist develops a special strain of vampirism that transforms him into a half-vampire that can navigate the increasingly blurry line between human and supernatural. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The protagonist develops a special strain of vampirism that transforms him into a half-vampire that can navigate the increasingly blurry line between human and supernatural.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Our extended preview focused on a quest called "A Monk and a Saint," which saw Coen travel to the settlement of Svartrau to uncover a hidden tomb – and the town's more nefarious side. This quest features a round of combat sequences against some foes capable of withstanding Coen's abilities in both his human and vampire forms. It initially seemed standard fare for an RPG quest, but where Dawnwalker differs is in how the quest can change depending on the time of day and which form you take on to complete it. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The leading narrative hook carrying players forward is the month-long time limit, giving Coen only a limited period to rescue his family. You can largely advance the day at your choosing, and Dawnwalker doesn't necessarily pressure you to make some time-specific choices. That said, your approach to progression will very much influence the course of events in Coen's journey – especially with which side of Coen is taking the lead. Time is essentially a resource that you spend with each passing quest and activity, and depending on what you do and when you do it. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The developers gave us a run of the preview's main quest from two different sides, as both Coen's human and vampire forms. When playing as the latter, Dawnwalker shifts to a stealth-action playstyle, where the protagonist must avoid detection from guards and civilians. Coen's vampire abilities are also unleashed in this state, allowing players to walk on walls, teleport, and use blood abilities and vampiric claws to cut down foes. And yes – you'll also be able to drain the blood from humans, foe and non-combative alike, for stealth takedowns or outright executions.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I was impressed by how much the action and pacing looked like a mix between The Witcher's grand scope and the immersive-sim elements of Dishonored when seeing Coen in his vampire form – you can truly leap across rooftops and get the jump on some foes, which was very satisfying to see. However, it shows how players will have to grapple with some moral choices, as Coen, who needs to feed to maintain his vampire abilities during the night, must do. While you can feed on animals to offer some temporary relief, the larger payout comes from human targets.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The vampire form looks to present a more direct and action-heavy approach to engaging with the quests. However, Coen's human form presents an interesting contrast by focusing more on investigation and tactical methods. Because Coen can blend in with others in his human form, there are far more opportunities to engage with the different characters and uncover pathways for success without the need for bloodshed. It was also fascinating to see how the characters react to knowing that vampires are now in control of the region and that life is, understandably, far worse off.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">When things pop off, combat shows the stark differences in Dawnwalker's playstyles. I adopted the tactical-action approach, which feels like a blend of The Witcher 3's versatile swords and sorcery combat flow, combined with the calculated nature of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2's swordplay. It presents an opportunity for players to feel powerful as Coen, where they have to exploit vulnerabilities. In his human form, Coen relies on his swordplay, along with gadgets and hex spells, to overcome some enemies. Similar to The Outer Worlds, you can pull up a tactical menu to target an enemy to execute attacks that can stun foes or deliver killing blows.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Coen's massive claws can tear into enemy defenses, and he can pull off combat finishers where he can lay into foes.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Combat gets a bit more hectic when in Coen's vampire form, which sees him unleash his supernatural blood-based abilities. In addition to his sword, Coen's massive claws can tear into enemy defenses, and he can pull off combat finishers where he can lay into foes. However, Dawnwalker still presents some challenges with elite foes, such as the human Blood Guards who have armor and weapons to stand up to Coen's vampiric abilities, along with some more dangerous monsters and the rival vampires that can overpower the protagonist if you're not careful.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">An interesting detail that the developers highlighted during the presentation was that players could make a beeline to the primary goal of the game early on – think of how players might try to defeat Ganon in the opening hours of The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild. However, the team stated that it'll be a challenge to pull off, as the core game is all about powering up Coen with new gear and abilities. Still, I’ll be curious to see if it'll be possible for players to clear the campaign early on in Coen's journey.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I wish we had more of an opportunity to see what the larger world would be like, but so far, The Blood of Dawnwalker captures that feeling of navigating two different worlds as a half-vampire, which is a very compelling premise for a role-playing game. Compared to The Witcher 3 or developer Dontnod's Vampyr, The Blood of Dawnwalker captures that open-ended, freeform nature of classic role-playing games like Gothic 1 and 2, which is exciting to see. Hopefully, the full game will be able to deliver on the concept of a vampire RPG with some world-changing stakes.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-blood-of-dawnwalker-offers-2-very-different-rpg-playstyles]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles ‘Gameplay’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-%E2%80%98gameplay%E2%80%99-trailer.1275633/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Lead your units to victory on grid-based maps.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> has released a new gameplay trailer for <a title="Genres > Strategy RPG [444 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/strategy-rpg">strategy RPG</a> remaster <em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles">Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</a></em>. <span id="more-986469"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Square Enix:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>The dramatic tale of ambition, betrayal, and honor will come to life with an updated and enriched script with fully voiced dialogue, alongside improved graphics that bring a new level of immersion and playability to the battlefield. Additionally, the enhanced version brings quality-of-life updates like new difficulties, a revamped UI, auto save, and more that make the game more accessible to newcomers. The game features strategic, turn-based combat and an elaborate character progression system that makes every battle exhilarating and filled with unexpected twists.</p><p>Hailed as one of gaming’s greatest stories, in this standalone game, players will step into the Kingdom of Ivalice—a medieval world steeped in political conflict—in which players uncover the truth behind the young noble Ramza Beoulve, whose role on history’s stage has been buried from view.</p><p>The new key art of Ramza and Delita, the two heroes of this story, is drawn by Akihiko Yoshida. The art depicts the complex relationship of the two individuals—whether they stand together to protect one another, or the start of a departure as they walk divergent paths. Above them, Ovelia and Alma, both of whom have strong ties to Ramza and Delita, solemnly look into the distance, foreshadowing the direction that fate will lead them.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Legendary developers from the original game will make their return in <em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em>, including Kazutoyo Maehiro (director), Hiroshi Minagawa (art director), and Yasumi Matsuno (original script, scenario writer and editor).</p><p><em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> will include both enhanced and classic versions of the game. The enhanced version features modern upgrades and quality-of-life changes, including fully voiced characters, a ground-up graphical overhaul and an updated user interface that make <em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> the perfect entry point to the tactical <a title="Genres > RPG [17,524 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> classic for new players. The classic version is a nostalgic recreation of the game, developed for players who want to experience the original <em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy Tactics [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-tactics">Final Fantasy Tactics</a></em> from 1997.</p><p><em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em>‘ voice cast featuring an all-star lineup of new and returning <em><a title="Series > Final Fantasy [141 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/final-fantasy">Final Fantasy</a></em> cast members, including Joe Pitts (Ramza), Gregg Lowe (Delita), <a title="Games > Hannah" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hannah">Hannah</a> Melbourn (Agrias), Timothy Watson (Cidolfus), Harry McEntire (Mustadio), Ben Starr (Dycedarg), and cameos by Cody Christian (Cloud Strife from <em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy VII Remake [107 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-vii-remake">Final Fantasy VII Remake</a></em> series) and Briana White (Aerith Gainsborough from <em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em> series).</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Challenging, Tactical Turn-Based Battles</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the addictive tactical turn-based combat and deep character progression system that made the game an instant tactical RPG classic. Players will test their battle acumen against a host of powerful enemies, and use the various terrains, characters and customizations, as well as their strategic thinking, to achieve victory.</li><li><strong>Customizable Job System with Dynamic Character Progression</strong> – Players can master a robust roster of over 20 jobs—including black mage, dragoon, geomancer (who can use the environment against foes), summoner (who can call forth the iconic <em>Final Fantasy</em> moogle and other espers), time mage (who uses time magick), thief, and more—and over 300 character abilities to strategically build endless party combinations.</li><li><strong><a title="Companies > Enhance [32 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>d Gameplay Features and a Faithful Classic Version</strong> – The enhanced version features a revised script and fully voiced dialogue, offering a new level of enjoyment to this classic story. Additionally, a brand-new user interface, improved graphics, as well as additional character conversations and dialogue create a new level of immersion. Additionally, many new features have been added to make the game even more approachable including the ability to confirm unit turn order with the press of a button, scout the battlefield from afar with the tactical view feature, speed up battles with fast forward, auto save during battles, adjust game difficulty to match your play style, and more. The classic version faithfully recreates the 1997 release of <em>Final Fantasy Tactics</em> alongside the acclaimed War of the Lions translation—perfect for fans who wish to relive the original experience.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,160 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,725 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [345 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,270 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,537 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,978 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1004640/Final_Fantasy_Tactics__The_Ivalice_Chronicles/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on September 30.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="FINAL FANTASY TACTICS - The Ivalice Chronicles | Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wVCaeyucLTE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-gameplay-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft and Asus’ answers to SteamOS and the Steam Deck launch on October 16]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/asus-and-microsofts-xbox-handhelds-arrive-october-16-but-pricing-remains-a-mystery/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-and-asus%E2%80%99-answers-to-steamos-and-the-steam-deck-launch-on-october-16.1275630/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          <p>Asus and Microsoft will be launching their <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/06/microsoft-dives-into-the-handheld-gaming-pc-wars-with-the-asus-rog-xbox-ally/">ROG Xbox Ally series of handheld gaming PCs</a> starting October 16, according to an Asus announcement that went out today.</p>
<p>An Xbox-branded extension of Asus' existing ROG Ally handheld line, the basic ROG Xbox Ally and more powerful ROG Xbox Ally X, both run a version of Windows 11 Home that's been redesigned with a controller-first Xbox-style user interface. The idea is to preserve the wide game compatibility of Windows—and the wide compatibility with multiple storefronts, including Microsoft's own, Valve's Steam, the Epic Games Store, and more—while turning off all of the extra Windows desktop stuff and saving system resources. (This also means that, despite the Xbox branding, these handhelds play Windows PC games and not the Xbox versions.)</p>
<p>Microsoft and Asus initially announced the handhelds in June. Microsoft still isn't sharing pricing information for either console, so it's hard to say how their specs and features will stack up against the Steam Deck (starting at $399 for the LCD version, $549 for OLED), Nintendo's Switch 2 ($450), or past Asus handhelds like the ROG Ally X ($800).</p>
<p>Both consoles share a 7-inch, 1080p IPS display with a 120 Hz refresh rate, Wi-Fi 6E, and Bluetooth 5.4 support, but their internals are quite a bit different. The lower-end Xbox Ally uses an AMD Ryzen Z2 A chip with a 4-core Zen 2-based CPU, an eight-core RDNA2-based GPU, 512GB of storage, and 16GB of LPDDR5X-6400—specs nearly identical to Valve's 3-year-old Steam Deck. The Xbox Ally X includes a more interesting Ryzen AI Z2 Extreme with an 8-core Zen 5 CPU, a 16-core RDNA3.5 GPU, 1TB of storage, 24GB of LPDDR5X-8000, and a built-in neural processing unit (NPU).</p>
<p>The beefier hardware comes with a bigger battery—80 WHr in the Ally X, compared to 60 WHr in the regular Ally—and that also makes the Ally X around a tenth of a pound (or 45 grams) heavier than the Ally.</p>

          
                      
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/asus-and-microsofts-xbox-handhelds-arrive-october-16-but-pricing-remains-a-mystery/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ROG Xbox Ally Handheld Launch Date Set For October, Features Steam Deck-Style Compatibility]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rog-xbox-ally-handheld-launch-date-set-for-october-features-steam-deck-style-compatibility/1100-6534120/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rog-xbox-ally-handheld-launch-date-set-for-october-features-steam-deck-style-compatibility.1275627/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534120">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A release date for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rog-xbox-ally-x-impressions-green-with-envy/1100-6532506/">ROG Xbox Ally</a> has been revealed, as the handheld gaming PC will be go on sale starting <strong>October 16</strong>. Microsoft hasn't confirmed pricing for the devices yet, but it did explain how games will be optimized for these systems. One thing to note here is that there will be two different versions of the ROG Xbox Ally--a base model and a more premium "X" handheld--so performance will vary across them.</p><p>During its Gamecom 2025 livestream, Microsoft said that the base model Xbox Ally targets a resolution of 720p, while the Xbox Ally X aims for a 1080p resolution. Both units can run in one of three modes--Silent, Performance, and Turbo--and for frame rates, games that hit certain benchmarks will receive a specific compatibility tag.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VTaboYwSyuc" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VTaboYwSyuc" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Microsoft says that it has worked with game studios to optimize thousands of games for handheld compatibility, with the overall goal here being that you can install them and start playing right away. This has resulted in two tags that will accompany optimized games, similar to Valve's Steam Deck Verified program for its handheld gaming PC:</p><p><strong>Handheld Optimized</strong></p><p>Games that are ready to go with default controller inputs, an intuitive text input method, accurate iconography, clear text legibility, and appropriate resolution in full-screen mode.</p><p><strong>Mostly Compatible</strong></p><p>Games that may require minor in-game setting changes for an optimal experience on handheld.</p><p>Additionally, there'll be other tags that will give you an idea of how well a game will perform on the Xbox Ally:</p><p><strong>Should perform well on your device</strong></p><ul><li>Games that run at 30fps or above</li></ul><p><strong>Should perform great on your device</strong></p><ul><li>Games that run at 60fps or above</li></ul><p><strong>Performance check not available yet</strong></p><ul><li>Games that haven't been tested yet</li></ul><p>Microsoft added that more technical features will also be made available in the future, including advanced shader delivery that preloads game shaders during download. This will make games run more smoothly and use less battery power on first play. Enhancements to the docking experience for the devices are also in the works and several accessories will be released for it as well.</p><p>The company also recently spoke about how handheld consoles like the Xbox Ally tie into its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-gen-xbox-console-aims-to-put-players-first-says-microsoft/1100-6534059/">next-gen console plans</a>, as Microsoft is looking to create a broad ecosystem for players that will allow them to play their games at home or on the go.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rog-xbox-ally-handheld-launch-date-set-for-october-features-steam-deck-style-compatibility/1100-6534120/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drowning in the sea of Opening Night Live game announcements? Here are the under-the-radar gems we're most excited about]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/drowning-in-the-sea-of-opening-night-live-game-announcements-here-are-the-under-the-radar-gems-were-most-excited-about</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/drowning-in-the-sea-of-opening-night-live-game-announcements-here-are-the-under-the-radar-gems-were-most-excited-about.1275624/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Trains! Cowboys! Cylons! Bobcats! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



  


            <p>
At this point, it's almost tradition that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a> Opening Night Live draws to a close with a collective sigh. Again I send my prayers to the stars that the OmniGeoff may one day concede - and this goes for the equally interminable likes of Summer Game Fest and The Game Awards - that shorter, more focused is always better. Imagine the sustained enthusiasm you could generate without all that flaccid, glassy eyed filler! And so in that spirit of relative brevity, here's a quick list of some of the slighty under-the-radar announcements from this year's show (and pre-show) that managed to get us quite excited.
</p>
<h3>Denshattack!</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Denshattack! - Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o_Xmv9eAIZA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Denshattack! - Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o_Xmv9eAIZA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/o_Xmv9eAIZA?autoplay=1" title="Denshattack! - Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Denshattack! reveal trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o_Xmv9eAIZA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
One of a couple of Opening Night Live standouts relegated to the pre-show warm-up, Denshattack! is the work of developer Undercoders. And it's easy to imagine the studio's pitch for this one as 'what if <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/jet-set-radio">Jet Set Radio</a> but runaway trains?', given its cell-shaded aesthetic and tricking, grinding action would be pretty familiar if it wasn't for the fact it switches out skateboards for graffiti-strewn, gravity defying locomotives.
</p>
<p>
Story wise, it sees players rail-riding across Japan, traversing vibrant countryside and urban city sprawls, all in a quest to defeat the sinister Miraidō corporation. You'll ollie and kickflip in a bid to win over rivals and rack up points, with everything from magical mecha girls to moving castles making an appearance too. It looks an absolute blast and it's coming to PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC next year.
</p>
<h3>Valor Mortis</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Valor Mortis - Reveal Trailer | First-Person Soulslike" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cIF7cL0KRDU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Valor Mortis - Reveal Trailer | First-Person Soulslike</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cIF7cL0KRDU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cIF7cL0KRDU?autoplay=1" title="Valor Mortis - Reveal Trailer | First-Person Soulslike">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Valor Mortis trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cIF7cL0KRDU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
I've fond memories of developer One More Level's cyberpunk action-parkour adventure <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ghostrunner">Ghostrunner</a>. Or at least, I've fond memories of its first couple of hours, after which everything is lost in a bright red haze of pure fury. The point, though, is it was Pretty Good (Eurogamer's Bertie Purchese <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ghostrunner-review-an-exhilarating-display-of-acrobatic-first-person-platforming">said it more eloquently in his review</a>), so there's every reason to be curious about what One More Level is doing next now the Less Good <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ghostrunner-2">Ghostrunner 2</a> is behind it.
</p><p>
And that, it transpires, is Valor Mortis - a gory "first-person action Soulslike" that's arriving next year. I appreciate there's a general air of Soulslike fatigue about these days, but Valor Mortis does at least attempt to carve its own niche with, firstly, that shift in perspective, and also a pretty distinctive set-up. It's the 19th century and the Napoleonic Wars are raging; you're a soldier in Bonaparte's Grande Armée and also, regrettably, dead. Until, that is, you awaken on a battlefield ravaged by a mysterious supernatural plague, former friends and foe now twisted into awful abominations. Expect a combat-focused adventure incorporating the likes of parries, dashes, and some pretty brutal finishers when Valor Mortis comes to PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC next year.
</p>
<h3>Death by Scrolling</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Death By Scrolling - Publishing Announcement" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fXIGtCVH5Wo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Death By Scrolling - Publishing Announcement</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fXIGtCVH5Wo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fXIGtCVH5Wo?autoplay=1" title="Death By Scrolling - Publishing Announcement">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Death by Scrolling announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fXIGtCVH5Wo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
For readers of a certain age, Ron Gilbert needs no introduction: he's the writer and designer best known for his point-and-click adventures, including Maniac Mansion, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/thimbleweed-park">Thimbleweed Park</a>, and, of course, the legendary Monkey Island series. Every now and then, though, Gilbert strays outside of those genre bounds; there's 2013's puzzle-platform adventure The Cave, for instance - made in conjunction with Double Fine - and now there's Death by Scrolling.
</p>
<p>
Developed by Gilbert's Terrible Toybox studio, Death by Scrolling has the air of a top-down 16-bit RPG, but there's seemingly a lot more to it - it is, after all, described as a "rogue-like vertically scrolling RPG". Your ultimate goal - playing as one of several characters, each with their own unique perks and abilities - is to race upward through endless levels in order amass enough money to pay the Ferryman and escape Purgatory. That involves battling enemies, swiping gems, grabbing power-ups, completing side quests, and a spot of shopping, all while outsmarting the ever-pursuing Grim Reaper. There's no release date for Death by Scrolling yet, but it's coming to PC.
</p>
<h3>Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster - Announcement Trailer | Nightdive Studios" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qx4O0OmaFNg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster - Announcement Trailer | Nightdive Studios</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qx4O0OmaFNg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qx4O0OmaFNg?autoplay=1" title="Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster - Announcement Trailer | Nightdive Studios">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qx4O0OmaFNg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Sorry to keep calling you out, people of a certain age (and I include myself in this increasingly withered demographic), but here's another name that's likely to get old-timers a-flutter. Outlaws, developer LucasArts' fondly remembered - if, perhaps, oft-overlooked - Wild West FPS is making a return, courtesy of remaster specialists Nightdive Studios.  
</p><p>
First released in 1997 - around the time LucasArts was dipping its toes in new genres after dominating the point-and-click scene for so long  - Outlaws aimed to build on the success of the studio's beloved Star Wars: Dark Forces by taking the FPS to hitherto unseen frontiers. Namely, the cowboy ones. According to Wikipedia, it was perhaps the first shooter to introduce a sniper zoom and one of the first to feature a gun reloading mechanic, but my own memories - which don't extend much further than a well-worn cover disc demo - remain positive but decidedly hazy. Nightdive's remaster, which also includes 1998's Handful of Missions expansion, promises the likes of high-resolution textures, redrawn art, crossplay multiplayer, and gamepad support, and it's coming to PC, PlayStation, Xbox, and Switch this year.
</p>
<h3>Unbeatable</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="UNBEATABLE: FINAL TRAILER " data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vkvi71znX_Q?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>UNBEATABLE: FINAL TRAILER </span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vkvi71znX_Q?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Vkvi71znX_Q?autoplay=1" title="UNBEATABLE: FINAL TRAILER ">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Unbeatable final trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vkvi71znX_Q" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
If you had a vague sense of déjà vu when Unbeatable popped up during Opening Night Live, you're not the only one. A quick trip down memory lane (Google) confirms Unbeatable was first announced back in 2021, when it got a whole bunch of people, including me, excited for the very first time. It had a fantastic demo, released to promote what would go on to be a successful Kickstarter, after which it was time for developer D-Cell to knuckle down.
</p>
<p>
Four years later, and the rhythm adventure where "music is illegal and you do crimes" is back. Unbeatable promises "big emotions" and "arcade-flawless rhythm gameplay" as the story of Beat and her band unfolds, charting their efforts to gig and stay one step ahead of the cops. "Half the game is walking around and taking things at your own pace," D-Cell says of Unbeatable's story mode. "The other half is trying to keep up with ours." It's also got an "unlimited" arcade mode featuring a "entire double album" of music, alongside acoustic versions, and remixes. Unbeatable looks and sounds like a winner, and it's coming to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S, on 6th November.
</p>
<h3>Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes | Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZJsmoFJE-vs?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes | Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZJsmoFJE-vs?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZJsmoFJE-vs?autoplay=1" title="Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes | Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZJsmoFJE-vs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The only thing I can remember about Battlestar Galactica, apart from that cool swishy visor thing the robots did in the original series, is that woman in red spending bloody ages pretending she wasn't real. Which is to say I'm not exactly an leading expert. And yet there's something about Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes that's caught my eye. For starters, it's by Alt Shift, the team behind well-received tactical rogue-lite Crying Suns, and it's promising an interesting mix of turn-based and real-time action too.
</p><p>
Officially a "story-rich tactical roguelite", Scatted Hopes plays out in two distinct halves. On one side, you - a Gunstar Captain attempting to rendezvous with the Battlestar Galactica - have a galaxy to traverse, navigating planets and galactic points of interest turn-by-turn, all while dealing with tough dilemmas. You'll need to juggle the sometimes opposing interests of different factions, perhaps, or manage dwindling resources, or try and identity impostors onboard. With every decision, the Cylons draw nearer, and your choices impact your chances of success when battle comes. Space combat plays out in real-time (tactical pause is available), as players attempt to last long enough to engage their FTL and scarper, with talk of deployable squadrons, missiles, and more. It all sounds pretty neat and Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes is aiming for a Q1 launch on PC next year.
</p>
<h3>Bubsy 4D</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Bubsy 4D - Official Announcement Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H4bq6P8e5gk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Bubsy 4D - Official Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H4bq6P8e5gk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/H4bq6P8e5gk?autoplay=1" title="Bubsy 4D - Official Announcement Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Bubsy 4D trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H4bq6P8e5gk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Okay, look, Bubsy might not exactly - or even remotely - be a byword for quality as far as video game platform mascots go, but credit where credit's due; his name has managed to linger far longer (like a bad smell perhaps), compared to the largely forgotten likes of Socket, Rocky Rodent, Awesome Possum, and Vexx. After two so-so 2D platformers in the 90s and the absolute nadir that was Bubsy 3D in 1996, most would assume the titular bobcat would have hung up his jumping boots for good (pedants, please note I am aware Bubsy doesn't wear shoes). Instead, he inexplicably returned two decades later for two more middling side-scrolling platformers. The legacy of Bubsy, to reiterate, is not great.
</p>
<p>
And yet! I'm absolutely fascinated by the prospect of Bubsy 4D, and not just because of the bobcat's almost admirable refusal to bow out gracefully. Rather, this latest entry in the mascot's dubious back catalogue is the work of indie studio Fabraz, which, if you're unfamiliar, has made some pretty enjoyable games - including Demon Turf and Slime-San. Plus, it's upcoming Demon Tides looks good too. So it's an enticing pairing. As for Bubsy 4D, it's got rolling, jumping, gliding, a bunch of evil sheep, a bunch of evil <em>robot</em> sheep, vibrant 3D worlds with a sort of old-school air to their design, and I really like the music in the trailer. Bubsy 4D doesn't have a release date yet, but it's coming "soon", and I am cautiously optimistic.
</p>
<p>
<em>And those are our Gamescom Opening Night Live picks that might have got a little lost. Do feel free to add your own favourites in the comments below.</em>
</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/drowning-in-the-sea-of-opening-night-live-game-announcements-here-are-the-under-the-radar-gems-were-most-excited-about]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: At Last! We've Played Hollow Knight: Silksong On Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/previews/video-at-last-weve-played-hollow-knight-silksong-on-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-at-last-weve-played-hollow-knight-silksong-on-switch-2.1275606/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Threading the needle</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>You've read the title, you've seen photos of the booths online, so you know it's coming — six years after its last official public demo, we've <em>finally</em> played <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>. And, we've played it on Switch 2, too.</p>
<p>Ahead of the game's special broadcast tomorrow, 21st August, we — or, more specifically, the lovely Felix — has spent some hands-on time with the highly-anticipated sequel to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hollow_knight">Hollow Knight</a>.</p>
<p>Now, it's only about 15-minutes or so, but that's 15 minutes more than we had before. So, was it worth the two-hour-long wait? (Yes, <em>two</em> hours)</p>
<p>Of the two demos available — one from near the beginning of the game in a green area, and another later in the game in a magma-filled stage — Felix picked the second one. And, as we've already confirmed, there's a 120fps mode.</p>
<p>There's more dialogue (given that Hornet speaks), more collectible, and different movement options. And, of course, Felix took on the demo's big boss, Lace. So, it's more Hollow Knight with more features, at least for now.</p>
<p><em>So, if you want your first look at Silksong on Switch 2, here's the place for it — check out Felix's video up-top and then let us know if you're looking forward to Silksong in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186809,186752 @ 1755703036 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/previews/video-at-last-weve-played-hollow-knight-silksong-on-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ROG Xbox Ally Officially Launches This October]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/rog-xbox-ally-x-release-date-gamescom-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rog-xbox-ally-officially-launches-this-october.1275603/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><strong>Update 20/08/2025:</strong> Wario64 on X (formerly Twitter) spotted that Best Buy has already listed the prices for the ROG Xbox Ally and the Xbox Ally X, confirming the prices leaked by Billbil-kun below. Pre-orders are not yet live, but should be any moment, since <a href="https://wccftech.com/rog-xbox-ally-pre-orders-go-live-gamescom-2025/">Billbil-kun already reported that they would go live today.</a></p>



<figure></figure>



<p><strong>Original Story:</strong></p>



<p>Xbox has announced the official release date for the ROG Xbox Ally and the ROG Xbox Ally X at Gamescom 2025, which will officially launch this coming October 16, 2025.</p>



<p>The news was announced during Xbox's first day of livestreaming during this year's Gamescom, but it's not news for anyone that's been paying attention to the ROG Xbox Ally, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/rog-xbox-ally-release-date-october-2025/">Billbil-kun from Dealabs leaked the release date last week</a>.</p>



<p>Billbil-kun even leaked the prices, though Xbox has yet to confirm them at the time of this writing. Earlier today,<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/billbil-kun.bsky.social/post/3lwt47zevds24"> in a Bluesky post</a>, they claimed the US prices would be <strong>$549.99 </strong>for the ROG Xbox Ally and <strong>$899.99</strong> for the ROG Xbox Ally X. Billbil-kun <a href="https://wccftech.com/rog-xbox-ally-prices-leaked/">leaked the European prices last month</a>.  </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Inside the ROG Xbox Ally: Game Access and Compatibility" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VTaboYwSyuc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The Gamescom live stream also went over a few details for the Ally, like the fact that it will come with Microsoft's Co-Pilot for Gaming built in, and that games will carry a performance tag similar to what Valve has for the Steam Deck. Instead of something being 'Ally verified' or not, games will carry one of three tags telling players what kind of performance they can expect.</p>



<p>If the game in question has been tested and can hit at least 30FPS on the ROG Xbox Ally, it'll get a "<em>Should perform well on this device</em>" tag. If it has been tested and can hit at least 60FPS, it'll have a "<em>Should perform great on this device</em>" tag. If it's not been tested, it'll have a "<em>Performance check not available yet</em>" tag.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Introducing Handheld Compatibility" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uQiwumMYsGA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Regarding that testing, Xbox also introduced its Handheld Compatibility Program, which is "<em>a new Xbox initiative designed to make more games ready to play on your supported handheld</em>,"<em> </em>according to an <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/20/rog-xbox-ally-handheld-release-date-october-features/">Xbox Wire post</a>. Xbox has been working with studios to test "<em>thousands of games for handheld compatibility,"</em> to ensure they're ready for players picking up an Ally this coming October.</p>



<p>It's nice to see the release date get an official confirmation, even if the news was spoiled before Xbox got the chance to shout it out itself. Hopefully, we'll have the prices confirmed soon. </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/rog-xbox-ally-x-release-date-gamescom-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gamescom Opening Night Live 2025 - All the News and Announcements]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-recap</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-all-the-news-and-announcements.1275597/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>This year's Gamescom Opening Night Live aired just last night, and it came packed with a ton of reveals and new information about existing games. Here's everything that was announced during the show, including the pre-show stream!</p>

<hr>

<p>We'll begin with everything that was revealed during the pre-show segment, which ran for a little under half an hour. Believe it or not, it was packed with news as well. Here we go!</p>

<h3><em>Bubsy 4D</em></h3>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bubsy-4d-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=WK7OwcgS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bubsy-4d-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=K8gPjW2i 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Bubsy&nbsp;</em>is back, baby.</figcaption></figure><p>First up, we got a look at a brand new 3D platformer from Atari and Fabraz, namely&nbsp;<em>Bubsy 4D</em>. That's right; everyone's (least?) favorite feline mischief-maker is still around, and his latest game is coming to PC and consoles sometime in the near future.</p>

<h3><em>Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes</em></h3>

<p>The next game on Gamescom's 2025 agenda was&nbsp;<em>Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes</em>, a roguelite strategy game in which you must "take command of a fleet escaping the annihilation of the Twelve Colonies". Early 2026 for this one.</p>

<h3><em>Outlaws</em></h3>

<p>Nightdive continues its mission to single-handedly revive all of retro gaming with a remaster of the 1997 Western-themed FPS&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>. You can expect to check this one out on November 20th.</p>

<h3><em>Denshattack!</em></h3>




<p>I'm not sure how to describe&nbsp;<em>Denshattack!</em>. Train platformer? On-rails skating racer?&nbsp;<em>Yellow Train Goes Choo-Choo</em>?&nbsp;Well, at any rate, it's coming in 2026, and it looks like exactly the kind of off-the-wall insanity the indie industry excels at.</p>

<h3><em>Keeper</em></h3>

<p>Next on the agenda was an interview with&nbsp;<em>Keeper&nbsp;</em>creative director Lee Petty, who told us a little more about the way Double Fine's upcoming lighthouse sim (?) will work. As a reminder, the game is due to launch on October 17th.</p>

<h3><em>He-Man and the Masters of the Universe: Dragon Pearl of Destruction</em></h3>

<p>Try saying that name ten times fast.&nbsp;<em>He-Man and the Masters of the Universe: Dragon Pearl of Destruction&nbsp;</em>is a classic-style pixel-art beat-'em-up featuring iconic characters like He-Man, She-Ra, and Man-at-Arms, and it's coming soon.</p>

<h3><em>Absolum</em></h3>

<p>We got a look at another beat-'em-up next in the form of&nbsp;<em>Absolum</em>, which launches on October 9th. If you want to know more about this one, you can read our very own Andrew's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/absolum-features-gorgeous-story-and-flashy-combat-to-keep-you-coming-back-over-and" rel="nofollow">preview of it right here</a>.</p>

<h3><em>Long Gone</em></h3>

<p>Hey, have you had enough of zombies yet? <i>Long Gone&nbsp;</i>sure hopes you haven't. It's a narrative survival adventure inspired by "games of old", according to developer Hillfort Games, and it launches soon.</p>

<h3><em>Valor Mortis</em></h3>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/valor-mortis-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=RKOayitY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/valor-mortis-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=2FrLM7Xh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Wouldn't want to run into him on a dark&nbsp;<em>rue</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>The developers behind&nbsp;<em>Ghostrunner&nbsp;</em>are trying their hands at a Soulslike, it turns out, and that Soulslike is&nbsp;<em>Valor Mortis</em>. It's a rather distinctive-looking first-person action game set to debut next year, so keep an eye out for this one.</p>

<h3><em>Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant</em></h3>

<p>It's okay; you can just call this one&nbsp;<em>PVKK&nbsp;</em>if you want. It's a sim that sees you operating a planetary defense cannon amidst an interplanetary invasion, and you'll have to press all the right buttons if you want to fend said invasion off.</p>

<h3><em>Routine</em></h3>

<p>Yeah, that's right,&nbsp;<em>Routine&nbsp;</em>is still alive! Remember this one from back in the day? The narrative-based horror game is still very much alive (although there's no guarantee you'll stay that way during your playthrough), and it's coming in late 2025.</p>

<h3><em>Swords of Legends</em></h3>

<p>Okay, okay, I know this one's from an established franchise, but come on.&nbsp;<em>Swords of Legends</em>? They may as well have called it&nbsp;<em>Quest of Hero</em>. In any case, it's a single-player action Soulslike set to arrive...uhh, sometime in the future.</p>

<h3><em>Road Kings</em></h3>

<p>From Saber Interactive and Focus Entertainment comes&nbsp;<em>Road Kings</em>, a "next-gen truck simulation" that has you hauling cargo across the American South while dealing with natural disasters along the way. It's coming in 2026.</p>

<h3><em>Pac-Man&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Sonic&nbsp;</em>are getting crossover DLC packs</h3>

<p>Next, we got to see DLC packs for both&nbsp;<em>Pac-Man World 2 Re-Pac&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Sonic Racing CrossWorlds</em>, both of which are getting DLC themed around the other game.&nbsp;<em>Pac-Man</em>'s comes in late 2025, while&nbsp;<em>Sonic</em>'s arrives early next year.</p>

<hr><h2>Gamescom Opening Night Live 2025 - Main Show Announcements</h2>

<p>Well, that's everything from the pre-show, so now we're getting into the meat of things. Here's everything we got to see during the main Gamescom Opening Night Live 2025 ceremony!</p>

<h3><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em></h3>

<p>Ahead of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/major-hollow-knight-silksong-announcement-set-for-this-week" rel="nofollow">big announcement for&nbsp;<em>Silksong&nbsp;</em>tomorrow</a> (which is almost certainly going to be a release date), we got to see some new gameplay footage, and hey, it certainly looks like&nbsp;<em>Hollow Knight</em>. Hype is building yet again for this one.</p>

<h3><em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em></h3>

<p>Next up, it's a look at the characteristically bonkers-looking&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em>, and a giant man smashing his fist into one of the game's campaign stages is just one of the weird sights you're going to see when the shooter launches on November 14th.</p>

<h3><em>Lords of the Fallen 2</em></h3>




<p>CI Games announced its Soulslike followup&nbsp;<em>Lords of the Fallen 2&nbsp;</em>next (<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lords-of-fallen-2-2026-epic-exclusive" rel="nofollow">well, officially, anyway</a>), and it's got more of the pseudo-Biblical designs and ruined kingdoms that the first game loved so much. It's coming in 2026.</p>

<h3><em>Sekiro: No Defeat</em></h3>

<p>No, it's not a followup to 2019's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sekiro-shadows-die-twice-sales" rel="nofollow">hugely popular</a>&nbsp;<em>Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice</em>, but an anime adaptation of the game with some pretty gnarly-looking art. It's coming exclusively to Crunchyroll next year.</p>

<h3><em>Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight</em></h3>

<p>You're in luck if you love Batman and Lego, because this new game will marry the two once again. It's a sort of anthology experience that takes in many of the Dark Knight's most iconic movie, TV, and comic appearances, and it's coming next year.</p>

<h3><em>Warhammer 40k: Dawn of War IV</em></h3>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-40k-dawn-of-war-iv-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=SsQ15cXt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-40k-dawn-of-war-iv-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=7nhSeNXN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dawn of War IV&nbsp;</em>brings the franchise back to its roots, by the looks of things.</figcaption></figure><p>The iconic RTS franchise returns, although it's not being helmed by its usual custodian Relic Entertainment this time around, instead being developed by&nbsp;<em>Iron Harvest&nbsp;</em>studio King Art. Happily, though, it looks exactly like&nbsp;<em>Dawn of War&nbsp;</em>should. 2026 for this one.</p>

<h3><em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>and<i>&nbsp;Final Fantasy XIV&nbsp;</i>cross over</h3>

<p><em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>has crossed over with&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy XIV&nbsp;</em>before, and they're about to do so again when&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy</em>'s iconic Omega monster finds its way into <i>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</i>in late September.&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy XIV&nbsp;</em>is also getting itself a new&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>encounter in October.</p>

<h3><em>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</em></h3>

<p>Next, Capcom showed off its upcoming hack-and-slash revival&nbsp;<em>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</em>, and hey, it sure looks like an&nbsp;<em>Onimusha&nbsp;</em>game, complete with lots of fancy swordwork and creepy-looking enemies. No release date beyond 2026 for this one yet.</p>

<h3><em>Arknights: Endfield</em></h3>

<p>We got to see a moody trailer for the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Arknights&nbsp;</em>spinoff&nbsp;<em>Arknights: Endfield&nbsp;</em>next, and it'll marry action RPG gameplay with, uh, base-building and factory simulation. This one doesn't yet have a release window.</p>

<h3><em>Europa Universalis V</em></h3>

<p>If you're one of the players who was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/civilization-vii-slow-start-take-two" rel="nofollow">disappointed</a> by&nbsp;<em>Civilization VII</em>, then perhaps Paradox's (admittedly more complex)&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paradox-europa-universalis-v-project-caesar-maybe" rel="nofollow">Europa Universalis V</a>&nbsp;</em>will work better for you. We got to see it in action during Gamescom ONL, and it's coming on November 4th.</p>

<h3><em>Daemon x Machina: Titanic Scion</em></h3>

<p>I didn't have a sequel to&nbsp;<em>Daemon x Machina&nbsp;</em>on my 2025 bingo card back when it was announced in 2023, but here we are. We got to see a new trailer for it during yesterday's ceremony, too. It's set for launch on September 5th.</p>

<h3><em>Void/Breaker</em></h3>

<p>Playstack and Stubby Games' futuristic roguelite shooter&nbsp;<em>Void/Breaker&nbsp;</em>is next, and hey, wouldn't you know it, the game is out right now. You can check it out right this instant if you think you'd be interested!</p>

<h3><em>Fallout&nbsp;</em>season 2</h3>




<p>Prime Video's second season of its acclaimed&nbsp;<em>Fallout&nbsp;</em>show got itself an airing following&nbsp;<em>Void/Breaker</em>, and we got to see some clips of the show, which will be heading to New Vegas <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fallout-season-3-confirmed-season-2-december" rel="nofollow">when it begins airing</a> on December 17th.</p>

<h3><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle&nbsp;</em>is coming to Switch 2</h3>

<p>A trailer for&nbsp;<em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle&nbsp;</em>confirmed that the game will be making its way to the Nintendo Switch 2 sometime next year, which is a pretty impressive feat of porting prowess. No specific release date for this yet, though.</p>

<h3><em>Deadpool VR</em></h3>

<p>Yep,&nbsp;<em>Deadpool VR&nbsp;</em>is still a thing, and we got to see a new trailer for it during Gamescom Opening Night Live last night. It looks exactly as irreverent and silly as you'd expect a&nbsp;<em>Deadpool&nbsp;</em>game to look, so bonus points for that, I guess.</p>

<h3><em>World of Tanks 2.0</em></h3>

<p>The "biggest update" in&nbsp;<em>World of Tanks</em>' history is scheduled to launch in early September, and it'll bring an entirely new tier of vehicles, a brand new map, and plenty more. If you're a&nbsp;<em>World of Tanks&nbsp;</em>devotee, you won't want to miss this.</p>

<h3><em>John Carpenter's Toxic Commando</em></h3>

<p>Saber Interactive's co-op FPS is shaping up to be the perfect tribute to the 80s oeuvre of its titular filmmaker, and a new trailer last night further confirmed that the game is going to be full of over-the-top insanity when it arrives next year.</p>

<h3><em>Death Scrolling</em></h3>

<p>Now here's something you don't see every day: an auto-scroller that scrolls upwards, not sideways.&nbsp;<em>Death Scrolling&nbsp;</em>comes to us from legendary publisher MicroProse and equally legendary developer Ron Gilbert, and it has plenty of fantasy-inflected action for you.</p>

<h3><em>Zero Parades</em></h3>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/zero-parades-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=vdQ41vm_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/zero-parades-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=-a6TkDmi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>ZA/UM has a lot to prove with&nbsp;<em>Zero Parades</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>ZA/UM's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zaum-project-c4-disco-elysium" rel="nofollow">new RPG</a> is called&nbsp;<em>Zero Parades</em>, and it's a "story-rich espionage RPG" in which you must "untangle a bloody web of intrigue at the End of History". Here's hoping ZA/UM, or <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/disco-elysium-developer-zaum-confirms-game-cancellation-and-layoffs" rel="nofollow">what's left of it</a>, can pull this one off.</p>

<h3><em>Neverness to Everness</em></h3>

<p>A new trailer for Hotta's&nbsp;<em>Neverness to Everness&nbsp;</em>showed us that yes, the game definitely does look like a big ol' melange of everything HoYoverse is currently running, and no, we still don't have a release date.</p>

<h3><em>Unbeatable</em></h3>

<p>In this rhythm-action game, "music is illegal and you do crimes", according to D-Cell Games and publisher Playstack. I've got a bit of a bee in my bonnet about "rock'n'roll can save the world" stories, but I guess we'll see if this one can change my mind on November 6th.</p>

<h3><em>Honor of Kings: World</em></h3>

<p><em>Honor of Kings: World&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/honor-of-kings-world-cross-platform-action-rpg" rel="nofollow">still exists</a>, and we got to see more of its, erm, world during a trailer last night. It all looks very grandiose and fantastical, although we still don't have any idea when we can actually play this one.</p>

<h3><em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em></h3>

<p>We're just a few weeks away from&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden 4&nbsp;</em>now, and just in case the story was the part of this frenetic hack-and-slash game in which you're most interested, that's what last night's trailer focused on. More slashing, please!</p>

<h3><em>Cinder City</em></h3>




<p>Turns out NCSoft's Project LLL is actually&nbsp;<em>Cinder City</em>, an MMO shooter that takes place in an alternate-future version of Seoul devastated by a mysterious crisis. This one looks suitably ambitious, combining squad-based tactics, vehicles, and more.</p>

<h3><em>Time Takers</em></h3>

<p>Time (ahem) to see another live-service shooter now in the form of&nbsp;<em>Time Takers</em>, a team-based game in which "time is your lifeline - and every second is earned, spent, or lost in combat". It's another NCSoft game, and a playtest is coming to Steam soon.</p>

<h3><em>Silent Hill f</em></h3>

<p>We got another look at upcoming survival horror&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill f&nbsp;</em>next, and though it looks a bit more action-oriented than I'm used to from this franchise, it seems as though Konami has its mojo back. We'll find out in late September.</p>

<h3><em>La Divina Commedia</em></h3>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/la-divina-commedia-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=6O4PKbXu 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/la-divina-commedia-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.jpg?itok=2cYJvMEG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Previous attempts at adapting&nbsp;<em>The Divine Comedy&nbsp;</em>haven't exactly been roaring successes.</figcaption></figure><p>Perhaps this attempt at adapting Dante Alighieri's famous&nbsp;<em>The Divine Comedy&nbsp;</em>into an action game will be more successful than EA's famously mid effort, although its "procedural extraction dungeon generation" system doesn't exactly fill me with confidence.</p>

<h3><em>Cronos: The New Dawn</em></h3>

<p>Yup, Bloober Team's upcoming survival horror game sure looks like a horror game alright. I'm on record as a Bloober hater, but perhaps, between this and&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2</em>, the studio can redeem itself in my eyes. I'm sure they're itching to do just that.</p>

<h3><em>The Outer Worlds 2</em></h3>

<p>Obsidian's RPG has some pretty big shoes to fill, not to mention an entire first game to apologize for (sorry, I'm on record as a hater for that as well). Let's hope the studio has learned its lesson and can deliver a satisfying RPG experience this time around!</p>

<h3><em>inZoi: Island Getaway</em></h3>

<p>Next, we got to see a DLC pack for Krafton's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/krafton-generative-ai-characters-pubg-inzoi" rel="nofollow">AI-filled</a>&nbsp;<em>Sims</em>-like&nbsp;<em>inZoi</em>, with&nbsp;<em>Island Getaway&nbsp;</em>bringing tons of idyllic new scenery and other features. It's out today, so if you love&nbsp;<em>inZoi</em>, you can already check it out!</p>

<h3><em>Fate Trigger</em></h3>

<p>Yup, that's right: it's another anime-style live-service shooter.&nbsp;<em>Fate Trigger&nbsp;</em>launches in the first quarter of 2026, and I can only speak for myself, but its art style makes it a little difficult for me to get particularly hyped for this one.</p>

<h3><em>The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin</em></h3>

<p>We got to see this anime action RPG in, well, action next, and there's a closed beta test on the cards as well, so if you want to get a chance to try out Netmarble's game, you can do just that.</p>

<h3><em>Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault</em></h3>

<p>Next, we learned that Digital Sun and 11 bit studios'&nbsp;<em>Moonlighter 2&nbsp;</em>will be <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/moonlighter-2-early-access-release-date" rel="nofollow">launching in Early Access on October 23rd</a>, bringing more action-RPG-slash-shop-management shenanigans with it.</p>

<h3><em>Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2</em></h3>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-gamescom-opening-night-live.jpg?itok=xGJQwcRB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-gamescom-opening-night-live.jpg?itok=BBUMHq1E 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Could all the roadblocks finally have been removed?</figcaption></figure><p><em>Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2&nbsp;</em>finally, finally, finally has a release date, and I really, really hope The Chinese Room and Paradox don't delay it again (unless it's absolutely necessary for quality, of course). October 21st for this one.</p>

<h3><em>Enshrouded</em></h3>

<p>Update 7 is coming soon for&nbsp;<em>Enshrouded</em>, and "Wake of the Water", as it's known, will bring lots of sunken treasures for you to plunder. The update is in the works now, although we don't know when it's landing just yet.</p>

<h3><em>Age of Empires IV</em></h3>

<p>The latest title in the long-running&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires&nbsp;</em>series of real-time strategy games is coming to the PlayStation 5, together with its&nbsp;<em>Dynasties of the East&nbsp;</em>DLC. The game launches for Sony's machine on November 4th.</p>

<h3><em>Cult of the Lamb</em></h3>

<p>Devolver Digital's beloved roguelite action-slash-management game (the composer of which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cult-of-lamb-composer-narayana-johnson-dies" rel="nofollow">we sadly lost last year</a>) is getting a "massive paid expansion" in the form of&nbsp;<em>Woolhaven&nbsp;</em>next year, bringing new weapons and much more for you to intimidate your followers with.</p>

<h3><em>World of Warcraft: Midnight</em></h3>




<p>Next up, we got a new cinematic trailer for the&nbsp;<em>World of Warcraft&nbsp;</em>expansion&nbsp;<em>Midnight</em>, which forms the next part of Chris Metzen's Worldsoul Saga, as well as some gameplay. It's coming next year, so make sure you're leveled accordingly.</p>

<h3><em>Project Spectrum</em></h3>

<p>You might not be able to tell it from the creepy and evocative trailer, but&nbsp;<em>Project Spectrum&nbsp;</em>is actually a multiplayer game; it's kind of like&nbsp;<em>Phasmophobia&nbsp;</em>meets&nbsp;<em>Hunt: Showdown</em>, by the sound of things. No release date for this one yet.</p>

<h3><em>Ghost of Yōtei</em></h3>

<p>Hey, look at that.&nbsp;<em>Ghost of Yōtei&nbsp;</em>is getting its own&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/co-op-is-coming-to-ghosts-of-tsushima" rel="nofollow"><em>Tsushima</em>-style multiplayer DLC</a> next year, bringing a "fantastical, supernatural setting" to contrast against the core game's historically-accurate locations. Cool stuff!</p>

<h3><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em></h3>

<p>If you were hoping for some actual, y'know, gameplay from&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil Requiem</em>, you'd have left yesterday night's show disappointed, but perhaps more will be on the way soon. At any rate, we did get to see a fun and spooky snippet of new gameplay, so that's something, at least.</p>

<h3><em>Black Myth: Zhong Kui</em></h3>




<p>Lastly, we got to learn that Game Science is working on a brand new followup to last year's&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/black-myth-wukong-review-serious-monkey-business" rel="nofollow">which I rather liked</a>.&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Zhong Kui&nbsp;</em>will follow the titular Chinese folk hero and is currently in development.</p>

<hr><p>Well, that's everything! I hope you've enjoyed this recap of all things Gamescom Opening Night Live 2025.</p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-recap]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft and Asus’ new Xbox Ally handhelds launch on October 16th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/762116/microsoft-asus-xbox-ally-handheld-release-date-compatibility</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-and-asus%E2%80%99-new-xbox-ally-handhelds-launch-on-october-16th.1275594/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Microsoft and Asus are putting a date on their <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/682009/microsoft-asus-rog-xbox-ally-devices-new-windows-xbox-experience">new Xbox Ally handhelds</a>: October 16th. Both the Xbox Ally and Xbox Ally X will be available on the same day in a variety of markets worldwide, but Microsoft and Asus aren’t opening preorders yet or revealing pricing. Microsoft also announced its handheld compatibility program to identify games optimized for the new Xbox Ally devices.</p><p>Leaks have suggested that the Xbox Ally will debut at €599 (around $699) and the top-of-the-line Xbox Ally X model at €899 ($1,049). I understand Microsoft and Asus had planned to announce Xbox Ally pricing and release date information today, but then it decided to only reveal a release date. Microsoft is now promising pricing and preorder information “in the coming weeks.”</p><p>The price information delay could be related to the leaks or ongoing uncertainty with US tariffs. <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/rog-xbox-ally-on-connait-enfin-la-date-exacte-de-sortie-60340"><em>Dealabs </em>reported</a> yesterday that the Xbox Ally could be priced at $549.99 and the Xbox Ally X at $899.99 in the US. It will be interesting to see if Microsoft and Asus can subsidize this further for this important Xbox hardware release.</p><div><p><figcaption><em>The homescreen of the Xbox Ally X.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>Both Xbox Ally handhelds will be available on October 16th in the following: Australia, Belgium, Canada, Czech Republic, China (only the Xbox Ally X), Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Hong Kong, Italy, Ireland, Japan, Malaysia, Mexico, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Norway, Philippines, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Saudi Arabia, Singapore, South Korea, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, Taiwan, Turkey, United Arab Emirates, United Kingdom, United States, and Vietnam.</p><p>That covers a lot of key markets for Asus and Xbox at launch, and there are also plans to introduce these handhelds in Brazil, India, Indonesia, and Thailand. The white ROG Xbox Ally is designed for 720p gaming, and the more powerful black ROG Xbox Ally X targets 1080p gaming. Like the existing ROG Ally and Ally X, the new ones share the same 7-inch 1080p screen, complete with a 120Hz refresh rate and VRR support.</p><p>The Xbox Ally uses AMD’s Ryzen Z2 A chip, combined with 16GB of LPDDR5X-6400 RAM and 512GB of M.2 2280 SSD storage. The Xbox Ally X upgrades the chip to AMD’s Ryzen AI Z2 Extreme processor, 24GB of LPDDR5X-8000 memory, and a 1TB M.2 2280 SSD.</p><p>Alongside release date confirmation, Microsoft also announced its handheld compatibility program today. “We have worked with game studios to test, optimize, and verify thousands of games for handheld compatibility, allowing you to jump into the game without having to tweak settings, or requiring only minor adjustments,” says Roanne Sones, CVP of gaming devices and ecosystem at Xbox.</p><p>There will be two forms of handheld compatibility: Handheld Optimized and Mostly Compatible. While Handheld Optimized games will have default controller inputs, accurate icons, and the correct screen resolution in full-screen mode, Mostly Compatible titles “may require minor in-game setting changes for an optimal experience on handheld.”</p><div><p><figcaption><em>The task switcher on the Xbox Ally X lets you switch into the Windows desktop.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>Microsoft will also mark games with a Windows Performance Fit indicator, so you’ll get the benefit of knowing if a game is compatible and how well it will play. Both Xbox Ally devices will ship with the Xbox full screen experience that Microsoft has been developing to improve Windows on handheld devices. This will boot as default, with the Windows desktop hidden away but still accessible through an option in the Xbox Game Bar UI.</p><p>Microsoft is also working on improving the game shader experience on Windows, with a new “advanced shader delivery” feature. This will preload game shaders during download on the Xbox Ally devices, so certain games can launch a lot faster and run smoother without the typical stutters that shader compilation introduces on Windows. This is key on a handheld as it will help with battery life and performance, but it’s not clear which games will support this just yet.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/28/24166413/microsoft-windows-auto-super-resolution-sr-qualcomm-npu-dlss-fsr">Automatic Super Resolution (Auto SR)</a>, which is an NPU to upscale games, is also arriving in early 2026 on the Xbox Ally X. Microsoft is planning to use the NPU on this device to introduce a highlight reels feature that uses AI models to automatically capture gameplay moments and make them easily shareable with friends or on social networks.</p><p>Additional improvements to the docking experience for the Xbox Ally devices are also coming soon. Microsoft is working “to enable a seamless, high-performance setup that supports big-screen gaming, Auto SR, intuitive controller pairing, optimized display output, and more,” according to Soanes.</p><p><em>Photos by Tom Warren / The Verge</em></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/762116/microsoft-asus-xbox-ally-handheld-release-date-compatibility]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>