<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 13:49:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Story Of Seasons: Grand Bazaar - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition - The Series' Best Remake Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-nintendo-switch-2-edition</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-nintendo-switch-2-edition-the-series-best-remake-yet.1279737/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 1 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158182/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure><p>Sometimes the lines between remaster and remake can be blurred. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_remastered">Metroid Prime Remastered</a> seems much more like a full remake, and a few games called remakes don’t quite live up to expectations. For <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</a> - based on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/harvest_moon_ds_grand_bazaar">Harvest Moon DS: Grand Bazaar</a> - even the term remake doesn’t quite seem to do it justice. This feels more like a fresh new entry in the <strong>Story of Seasons</strong> franchise that picks up the best elements of the DS title to deliver a spectacular farming sim that gleefully digs its own path.</p>
<p>Grand Bazaar casts you as a fledgling farmer in Zephyr Town, a gorgeous little place with a friendly cast of characters waiting to become your friends, or if you play your cards right, your spouse. While you may be familiar with the regular farming mechanics in this series, Grand Bazaar’s titular mechanic - the bazaar - adds an engaging twist to proceedings that kept me up for hours.</p>
<figure><a title="Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 2 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158187/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Every Saturday you take your best produce or crafted items to the bazaar and peddle off as much as you can, granting you the ability to earn a little more cash than the regular way of selling, but also the chance to level up your bazaar. Doing so brings other vendors to Zephyr Town along with more options as new shopkeepers allow you to spend your hard-earned money on new gameplay elements, expansions for your barn, farm, or pockets, and other neat additions.</p>
<p>Much like the addictive push and pull of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/moonlighter">Moonlighter</a>’s shop mechanics, Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar effectively balances its addictive farming gameplay with the bazaar-building side of things to keep you hooked. Ringing your little bell draws customers over, and occasionally they will flash up with an item they want; if you quickly place the requested item on your stall, they'll rush over. Plus, you can use the new Nature Sprites (more those later) to cheer for you, which unlocks helpful bonuses and put a big stupid grin on my face every time I set off this fanfare.</p>
<figure><a title="Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 3 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158185/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Actually navigating your bazaar is a touch annoying, as you use full 3D movement to approach your stalls. I would have preferred to just press left and right to move, which would make the process much quicker. But, for me at least, the addictive loop of farming and selling at the bazaar meant often I played the game until I fell asleep holding my Switch 2 in bed. While I’ve never played the DS original, I have played other <strong>Harvest Moon</strong> / <strong>Story of Seasons</strong> games, and with the upgrades on Switch 2, Grand Bazaar might nestle into the very best of the series.</p>
<p>Now onto the other side of things, the farming. Much of this is what you expect, especially if you’re a genre aficionado. Grab some seeds, use a hoe to till some soil, scatter the aforementioned seeds, then keep them watered and fertilised to see the fruits of your labour. You eventually get a barn and get to look after some animals, and keeping them fed and happy rewards you with produce like eggs, milk, and even wool.</p>
<p>One thing that gets my goat with farming games is when the farming feels like busy work, and occasionally Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar nudges that feeling. Thankfully, better farming tools are steadily introduced which improve your ability to till crops and slowly allow you to make more crops and earn more cash. However, you'll also have to contend with your stamina, much like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/stardew_valley">Stardew Valley</a>.</p>
<figure><a title="Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 4 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158179/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Here, managing stamina is particularly painful. Smashing rocks or watering multiple tiles of soil sees your stamina plummet, and while you can eat food or take a bath to replenish this, you essentially have the energy of an 80-year-old after a marathon. Importantly, you can find ways to permanently increase your stamina, but for the first 40-50 hours of the game at least, these opportunities are very sparse.</p>
<p>One of the key changes in Grand Bazaar is the movement. You can double jump, just like the original, but you now also have a glider, which you can use to take advantage of the wind to sail across Zephyr Town easy-breezy. Between the ability to farm multiple tiles at once, the immensely satisfying platforming, and the small but richly-packed Zephyr Town, it's so fun to scurry around and do your chores. You can even hop across rooftops and, on very windy days, you can use the extra height to glide to hidden areas and smash some rare rocks or find other foragable items. Just watch out for hurricanes, where you’ll have to use the new windscreens to keep the blustery menace from ruining your crops.</p>
<figure><a title="Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 5 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158180/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Another new mechanic comes in the form of those aforementioned Nature Sprites, adorable little creatures dotted around the map. Hand them your foragables like fish, mushrooms, and more, and they will increase the overall quality of these. However, the vast variety of items and different possible qualities means your inventory fills up much quicker than you’d like. Make sure to invest in storage or pocket space immediately. Thankfully you can quickly place boxes around town and in the many windmills - where you can craft better and more complicated delights - so you don’t have to lug everything around.</p>
<p>Fishing, unfortunately, is easily the weakest part of the game, which is a shame as I normally love catching fish. The actual gameplay is fine — you press certain buttons to reel in your fish — but it is painfully slow, especially with bigger fish. Compared to catching bugs, which you pick up immediately, or the fact you can just instantly smash rocks, I rarely wanted to spend my precious moments reeling in fish, so this part of the game stayed largely forgotten for me.</p>
<p>However, one part I really love is cooking. You earn recipes by eating food from the local restaurant, unlocking the item once you’ve gulped it down for the first time. Cook with your crops and animal produce to make dishes that not only top up your stamina, but also grant buffs like increased running speed or temporary stamina increases. It’s all instant, and you can make multiple of the same recipe at once provided you have the materials. I’ve been eagerly anticipating the occasional Cook-Offs, one of the many seasonal events that give you a chance to show off your wares, or earn some trophies for your house.</p>
<figure><a title="Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 6 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158184/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>There’s a lot of smart choices in Grand Bazaar which help to make the most of your time and keep you engaged. A request system helps you unlock new bazaar vendors, and these often test your abilities. You can ring a bell to say hello to folks as you run around, allowing you to build friendship points easily. And when it comes to bazaar time, you can choose different pieces of decor to help keep food fresh or sell more items in bulk.</p>
<p>Marvelous has really taken a lot of time to perfect the gameplay loop of Grand Bazaar, and that polish has also spilled out into the characters and the visuals. When greeting your townsfolk, you’ll now be met with fully voice-acted dialogue, adding charm and personality to every interaction. The voiceover work here is lovely, and makes it <em>much</em> harder to choose who you want to marry. You aren’t restricted by gender option either, so there’s plenty of bachelors or bachelorettes to pick from, and that’s before mentioning some of the new characters added to this remake. If you must know, I’m hoping to settle down with June if I can impress her with enough tea.</p>
<figure><a title="Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 7 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/158188/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>While the Harvest Moon series is well known for its adorable chibi style, here everyone has been given more human-like proportions. It works with the gorgeous visuals to make Zephyr Town feel a touch more realistic and homely. The visuals on Switch 2 are crisp and colourful, with a rock-solid frame rate. Trees blow with the wind and the water ripples with a gorgeous detail. It might not be the most demanding game on the Switch 2, but it might be the best-looking Story of Seasons entry, even if the occasional texture can look very pixelated up close.</p>
<p>After about 50 hours with the game, I do have a few other small nitpicks. While it’s nice to be able to organise your items by quality or freshness, it’s annoying you can’t quickly sort by sale price. One other niggle is the implementation of HD Rumble. I might be spoiled by the clip-clop of the horse in Stardew Valley, but here it’s just a flat ‘BZZZTT’ whenever you hit anything. It’s annoyingly sharp and loud, especially in handheld.</p>
<p>Overall, though, Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar is a fantastic reinvention filled with smart choices and heartfelt polish. I’ve had a blast doting over my farm animals, training up my dog so he can better corral my flocks, and spending time getting ready for the bazaar. Then, when Saturday hits, I open up my shop and enjoy the flurry of purchases, before spending my money on some much-needed new abilities, changes to the town, or some of the many customisation features. Even if they do demand quite a lot of wool and dye from you.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>If you’re in the mood for an engaging, endearing, and cute farming game, Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar should tickle your pickle with aplomb. It might not have the depth of other farming sims, but it's fantastic to control, and the well-written (and voiced) characters alongside the many tasks and calendar packed with events to occupy your time, make you feel like part of a bustling little community.</p>
<p>I fell in love with Zephyr Town, and thanks to the satisfying gameplay and intricately connected web of rewards, I can't see myself putting it down any time soon.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-nintendo-switch-2-edition]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turok: Origins First Impressions from Gamescom 2025 – Saber Goes Sci-Fi]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/turok-origins-first-impressions-gamescom-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/turok-origins-first-impressions-from-gamescom-2025-%E2%80%93-saber-goes-sci-fi.1279734/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At The Game Awards 2025, Saber Interactive <a href="https://wccftech.com/turok-origins-is-an-upcoming-co-op-game-by-saber/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> Turok: Origins, a sort of reboot of the classic sci-fi shooter franchise. </p>



<p>As some old-school gamers may already know, Turok was originally a comic book character who appeared as a master Native American tracker, survivalist, and hunter in late 1954 in comics published by Dell Comics. Later, he would also appear in comics published by Valiant Comics, Dark Horse Comics, and Dynamite Comics, but his fame mainly came from the successful video game series created by Acclaim in 1997. Five years later, just before the launch of Turok: Evolution, Acclaim could boast that the franchise had already generated over $250 million in sales revenue.</p>



<p>However, the IP's luck didn't last much longer. Following the release of Evolution, there was only one more installment, the 2008 game developed by a studio called Propaganda Games. While not well-received by critics, the game sold more than one million copies in its first two months on the market, prompting the Vancouver-based studio to start working on a sequel. Propaganda was owned by Disney Interactive Studios, though, which decided to shut down the studio (and the new Turok title) in 2011 after Tron: Evolution also disappointed.</p>



<p>Around seventeen years later, Saber Interactive is hoping to reignite the interest of long-time fans in the series. They are, after all, quite experienced in the feat following the successful revival of Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine, not to mention the upcoming Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic remake.</p>



<p>During a Gamescom 2025 presentation, we learned that most of Saber Madrid, a studio composed of around 250 employees, has been working on Turok: Origins for nearly five years now. The game will feature a story campaign of around fifteen hours, and the narrative will somehow connect to that first game installment from 1997.</p>



<p>The story sees the legendary warriors dealing not only with the usual dinosaurs but also with an alien threat, the so-called Xenia civilization, that seeks to eradicate all human life from the galaxy. The Turok and humankind as a whole are losing the war, so they embark on an interplanetary quest to find a superpower capable of turning the tide of the conflict. Yes, that means there will be various planets to visit in the final game; Ancient temples, wasteland canyons, and dense jungles are just a few examples of the places you'll find in Turok: Origins. </p>



<p>Following the brief presentation, we tried a demo of the game itself. The game supports three-player online cooperative action, so it's no wonder that there are three playable characters with their own weapons and perks and Ultimate abilities. During game sessions, players can also extract Echoes from fallen foes and the environment to unlock powers in real-time.</p>



<p>Other than that, Turok: Origins plays like pretty standard shooter fare. The maps are fairly linear and don't allow that much exploration, so you'll just be mowing down enemies while heading toward the next control point. When you have injured a foe enough, you can swoop into melee range to trigger a cool-looking execution move. The demo required using the grappling hook occasionally, but it was only available at predefined points, rather than giving players free rein on where to go.</p>



<p>One thing that long-time franchise fans will be happy to learn is that the developers have added the option to switch in real-time (by long-pressing the d-pad) between first and third-person view. The game had been announced as a third-person title, but Turok games have always been played in first-person view, and now you have that option available.</p>



<p>The highlight of the demo was the boss fight with a giant Tryceratops-like creature, which not only charged us but could also teleport and had a lightning attack. Indeed, Saber had previously said that the Xenia aliens control some of the dinosaurs with their technology and have empowered them with it.</p>



<p>Turok: Origins doesn't have a release window yet, but it looked fairly polished based on the Gamescom 2025 demo. Whether its structure and content will be enough to draw players remains to be seen once the final version becomes available. Meanwhile, we can confirm that the game will run at 60 frames per second on consoles (<a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-s-cant-run-turok-origins-60-fps/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">except for the Xbox Series S version</a>). </p>









			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/turok-origins-first-impressions-gamescom-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA will Announce the Early Access Release Date for Skate Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ea-skate-early-access-release-date-cover-art-reveal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-will-announce-the-early-access-release-date-for-skate-tomorrow.1279731/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The next entry in EA's Skate series will have its cover art revealed tomorrow, but more importantly, the early access release date for Skate is due to be announced in a new trailer premiering tomorrow, August 26, 2025, at 9am PT / 12pm ET / 5pm BST.</p>



<p>EA <a href="https://wccftech.com/skate-launches-into-early-access-in-summer-2025-major-playtest-update-coming-july-2/">announced this past June</a> that Skate would launch in early access sometime this summer. Well, at the time of this writing, summer is nearly over, so if that's still the case, then we might see Skate get shadow-dropped tomorrow. Or, it'll be out in the coming weeks. Either way, Skate has been in closed playtesting for months at this point, and considering that it'll be an early access release, it feels like EA could decide to launch it at any point.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="skate. | Early Access Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p14MSdRtNIo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Which, admittedly, feels odd considering the amount of excitement there was around the return of the series when EA and Full Circle <a href="https://wccftech.com/skate-4-new-studio-full-ciricle-staffing-up/">first announced it.</a> Back in 2021, when Full Circle was just starting up for the purposes of making this new Skate game, you never would have guessed that the hype around a Skate 4 would wane as much as it has, or that EA might just drop the game without much of a marketing lead-up.</p>



<p>In fairness, that was before we knew that this new iteration of Skate would be a <a href="https://wccftech.com/skate-free-to-play-live-service-full-crossplay-2/">full live service-focused game</a>, and that it would require <a href="https://wccftech.com/skate-always-on-online-multiplayer-activities-some-without-skateboards/">players to always be online</a>. Neither fact has helped ingratiate players to this new version, and it'll be interesting to see how the early access release fares once it is in public hands and no longer just for playtesters with access to a closed beta.</p>



<p>After years of waiting, tomorrow, Skate fans will finally have a date to look forward to for a new Skate game.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ea-skate-early-access-release-date-cover-art-reveal/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar Review - A Warm Welcome Home]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-review-warm-welcome-home</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-review-a-warm-welcome-home.1279728/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>With every <em>Story of Seasons</em> release, developing studio Marvelous gets closer and closer to finding the best recipe for a farming/life simulator, and <em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> is its next remake that blends old-school farming sim mechanics with all of the quirks that made Zephyr Town a beloved location in the franchise.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> is a remake of the original Grand Bazaar title, though it was called <em>Harvest Moon DS: Grand Bazaar</em> at the time. The game sends players to Zephyr Town, where they not only take the role of the local farmer but also open a booth at the local bazaar.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-farm-view.jpg?itok=VOXcfesh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-farm-view.jpg?itok=LctRgiJr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Certain areas around&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>give special views of the surrounding areas that change through the seasons.</figcaption></figure><p>In the latest iteration of the game, players are asked to grow the bazaar after the previous farmer left town years prior. There’s a storyline that drives this bazaar growth, making <em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> more narrative-driven than ever before in the franchise (with the exception of perhaps <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="34bff8c7-b745-4cf9-b20f-236a7829b85f" href="https://techraptor.net/games/story-of-seasons-wonderful-life" rel="nofollow"><em>Story of Seasons: A Wonderful Life</em></a>).&nbsp;</p>

<p>Every Saturday, players will sell anything they have at their own bazaar stall. The bazaar is also where players will buy most of their things, though there is a general store that carries seeds and animal food for emergencies.</p>

<p>That leaves the rest of the week for farming and general day-to-day activities, like talking to villagers and foraging for supplies.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> Makes Every Area Shine</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-bazaar-day.jpg?itok=k8TWXc2R 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-bazaar-day.jpg?itok=2dXaos11 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Selling at your own stall in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>makes the stakes of farming feel even higher as you appeal to customers and try to boost your profits.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>Whether it’s a busy bazaar Saturday or a leisurely Tuesday, <em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> makes every in-game day enjoyable. Between an impressive number of events around town and plenty to do, there’s a feeling that every day matters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Of course, the bazaar days are constantly busy. Selling to customers involves getting their attention with a cowbell and placing items they like on display. Don’t be fooled, this is harder than it sounds – things get hectic easily, and it’s easy to lose the interest of some customers while you’re serving others.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-playing-with-pet.jpg?itok=MvE8fwZT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-playing-with-pet.jpg?itok=Ec5St1JC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The animals in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>are as full of life and love as the characters.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>Events crop up around the map consistently as you get to know the characters, breathing life into an already-bustling town. Not only do these give each day meaning, they’re easy to find – a map with notifications when an event is happening and where leads you to where you need to be.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These events highlight all the villagers in Zephyr Town, and some of them are sweet glimpses into the lives of townspeople you’d otherwise know little about. These also do a great job at pushing the relationships of bachelors and bachelorettes and the main story.</p>

<p>All of this also helps push the idea that the player is welcome in a loving, full-of-life town. It also helps that, for the first time ever, the major events and story are completely voiced.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-windmill.jpg?itok=m2qEq-T5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-windmill.jpg?itok=9jG5vShL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The windmills in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>are the key to making high profits -- once you've restored them, of course.</figcaption></figure><p>Even without events, there are plenty of quests to focus on. Villagers will ask for help as your relationship with them builds. Additionally, you can endlessly gather materials and forage to donate to sprites. Not only does this give rewards, but it also increases various quality levels of the things you donate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Plus, crafting things is a major part of the game, and crafting takes time. As you get further into the game, you’ll be going through long, multiple-step crafting formulas using a variety of materials.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This isn’t something that’s really a big focus in newer games in the genre. It’s definitely something that adds complexity to a farming sim in a great way without being overbearing, and its presence in the remake is a welcome reminder of where the genre was nearly 20 years ago.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-mountain-view.jpg?itok=67jjSZMk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-mountain-view.jpg?itok=DlsgDy2r 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Some of the views around&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>give a hint at the world around Zephyr Town that some of the other characters frequently visit.</figcaption></figure><p>However, all of this does take a bit to set up.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It’s easy to feel like things are slow at the beginning, as unlocking every available thing to do and starting to build relationships takes time. This does make the first Spring feel a bit slow, particularly if you know your way around farming sims or have played the original <em>Grand Bazaar</em> title.</p>

<p>After the first Spring, things progress at a nice pace, and I found I always had something to do around town the entire rest of the first year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Even Spring of Year 2, while a bit slower on festivals, still had plenty for me to focus on doing. As someone who’s an avid farming/life sim lover, this was something I’d never really experienced in other games in the genre.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Zephyr Town Has Never Been More Beautiful</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-sophie-and-june.jpg?itok=lzCR5pKN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-sophie-and-june.jpg?itok=KtrggFvO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The characters in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar&nbsp;</em>make every day an adventure between events, new dialogue, and quests.</figcaption></figure><p>It’d be easy for everything already mentioned to make a great <em>Story of Seasons</em> game, but <em>Grand Bazaar</em> outdoes itself with the aesthetics of Zephyr Town.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Zephyr Town is arguably the best-looking town in <em>Story of Seasons</em> history, and it’s always been gorgeous. It strikes a great balance between the natural environment and a tiny, yet bustling, town, and the windmills and traversal mechanics have always been fun.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The wind and movement mechanics, including jumping around and gliding to other areas, feel intuitive and make running around entertaining.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-fishing-in-the-rain.jpg?itok=hWMoKTL9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-fishing-in-the-rain.jpg?itok=BzvJi6AM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The first time I heard the rainy day music in&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em>, I fished all day just to listen to it.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>And then, perhaps the most surprising part of <em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em> for me was the music. Farming Sims aren’t known for their soundtracks, but <em>Grand Bazaar</em> had several gorgeous tracks that forced me to stop and appreciate them.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Overall, Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar Is One of The Best Yet</h2>

<p><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c66e36ec-389d-4125-b93f-0d46957d3097" href="https://techraptor.net/games/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar" rel="nofollow"><em>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</em></a> is a home run for players who loved the original and an amazing introductory farming/life sim for newcomers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It’s cozy without being too simple, the characters and town are brimming with life, and it’s one of the prettiest <em>Story of Seasons</em> games. I had high hopes for the remake, and I’m glad to see that Marvelous did more than deliver – it awed.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</strong> was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the developer over the course of 49 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Brittany's been gaming since she could walk -- literally. A doctor told her parents to get her a handled console to improve her hand-eye coordination… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/brittany-alva">More about Brittany</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/story-of-seasons-grand-bazaar-review-warm-welcome-home]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cronos: The New Dawn Release Date Explained—Start Times & Release Date Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-release-date-explained-start-times-release-date-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cronos-the-new-dawn-release-date-explained%E2%80%94start-times-release-date-confirmed.1279722/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>We’re into the period of the year where big releases are coming thick and fast, with Cronos: The New Dawn included in that window, with a release date that is rapidly approaching.</p>



<p>A <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-gets-new-trailer-gamescom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">terrifying new trailer at Gamescom</a> has ignited additional excitement ahead of release, and gamers around the world don’t have too much longer to wait until enjoying the apocalyptic adventure can begin.</p>



<p>If you’re looking to circle the release of Cronos: The New Dawn in your calendar, we’ve got the release date details and the exact time you can start playing. </p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-cronos-the-new-dawn-coming-out">When is Cronos: The New Dawn Coming Out?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Terrifying. Image via Bloober Team</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>September 5 is the official release date for Cronos: The New Dawn, which will be available on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, PC, and Nintendo Switch 2.</strong></p>



<p>The release date is locked in and is rapidly approaching, so there shouldn’t be any delays, and it won’t be long until your survival adventure begins.</p>



<p>With exploration in a brutal future, combined with travel to 1980s Poland to extract key people, the adventure through the timestream looks set to be one of the biggest games launching in this release period.</p>



<h2 id="h-cronos-the-new-dawn-start-times">Cronos: The New Dawn Start Times</h2>



<p><strong>Cronos: The New Dawn will be available to play from 7am PT, with the start time being confirmed by store listings of the title.</strong></p>



<p>The <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10011556" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Store</a> page details exactly when you can jump into Cronos: The New Dawn, which, unlike many other titles, has a global release window. This means that everyone around the world can begin at exactly the same time, rather than the staggered launch adopted by other titles.</p>



<p>In the table below, we’ve highlighted the precise release times for major time zones across the world to make for easier viewing. Remember, though, these have not been confirmed officially and are subject to change.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Cronos: The New Dawn Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">07:00 – September 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Centreal Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">09:00 – September 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">10:00 – September 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">British Summer Time (BST)</td><td data-align="center">15:00 – September 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Standard Time (AEST)</td><td data-align="center">00:00 – September 6</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>What are you looking forward to most in Cronos: The New Dawn? Will it be one of the year’s biggest releases? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For your next read, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-release-date-start-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date and start times of Borderlands 4</a>, and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-the-hollow-knight-silksong-review-embargo-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hollow Knight: Silksong review embargo date</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-release-date-explained-start-times-release-date-confirmed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rumors Of The Next Nintendo Direct Pick Up Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rumors-of-the-next-nintendo-direct-pick-up-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rumors-of-the-next-nintendo-direct-pick-up-steam.1279719/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-141526">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Rumors are circling regarding the next Nintendo Direct event. According to multiple reports, Nintendo is planning to hold its next direct showcase sometime in September.</p>



<p>According to SwitchForce, who has been accurate with Nintendo information in the past, the next direct appears to be planned for September 12.</p>



<p>“Nintendo tried to phone in an emergency about the missing Switch 2 games, but they accidentally dialed 912,” <a href="https://x.com/TheSwitchForce/status/1959828809559249019" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">they said</a>.</p>



<p>It’s not just SwitchForce claiming a direct is coming. While not confirming the date, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/a-nintendo-direct-is-reportedly-planned-for-mid-september" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">VGC</a> did say that its own sources tell them that a mid-September Nintendo Direct is planned.</p>



<p>As far as what this upcoming direct would cover, that’s currently unknown. There has been speculation that it will focus on Metroid Prime 4: Beyond, especially with it <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metroid-prime-4-beyond-receives-esrb-rating-ahead-of-launch/">recently receiving an ESRB rating</a>. The game is also scheduled to release sometime this year, and with only four months left in the year, signs point to it being time to give fans a deeper dive into the game.</p>



<p>What are you hoping to see from the next Nintendo Direct? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out what game is currently <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-6-to-be-revealed-at-tokyo-game-show/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rumored to be revealed next month</a> at Tokyo Game Show 2025. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-skate-game-gets-official-cover-art-and-early-access-release-date-teaser/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-skate-game-gets-official-cover-art-and-early-access-release-date-teaser/">
                                New Skate Game Gets Official Cover Art And Early Access Release Date Teaser                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The official cover art for EA’s brand-new Skate game has been revealed, and we also know when the early access release date is coming.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-gamer-celebrates-15000-platinum-trophies/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-gamer-celebrates-15000-platinum-trophies/">
                                PlayStation Gamer Celebrates 15,000th Platinum Trophy                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>On social media, a PlayStation gamer has flexed unlocking his 15,000th Platinum Trophy on the PlayStation Network.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-duckov-preview-gamescom/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-duckov-preview-gamescom/">
                                Escape from Duckov PREVIEW: I Plucked This Beak-Biting Eggstraction Shooter and It’s No Yolk                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>If you’re at all interested in Escape from Duckov, you’ll want to read this full preview of the game’s demo. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/blood-of-dawnwalker-preview-witcher-coded-vampirism/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/blood-of-dawnwalker-preview-witcher-coded-vampirism/">
                                Blood of Dawnwalker PREVIEW: Witcher-Coded But Laced with Stunning Vampirism                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>At Gamescom, The Blood of Dawnwalker was presented behind closed doors, offering viewers a live gameplay segment. Here’s my full preview.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/rumors-of-the-next-nintendo-direct-pick-up-steam/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CHAOS;HEAD / CHAOS;CHILD Love chu chu!! DOUBLE PACK announced for Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/chaoshead-chaoschild-love-chu-chu-double-pack-announced-for-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chaos-head-chaos-child-love-chu-chu-double-pack-announced-for-switch.1279713/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out on November 27 in Japan.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > MAGES. [535 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/colopl/mages">MAGES.</a> has <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000193.000046985.html" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > CHAOS;HEAD / CHAOS;CHILD Love chu chu!! DOUBLE PACK [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/chaoshead-chaoschild-love-chu-chu-double-pack">CHAOS;HEAD / CHAOS;CHILD Love chu chu!! DOUBLE PACK</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,578 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>. It will launch on November 27 in Japan for 7,480 yen. <span id="more-987733"></span></p><p>A limited edition will also be available for 9,680 yen, which includes a special box illustrated by Mutsumi Sasaki featuring Serika Onoe and Rimi Sakihata in swimsuits, and a soundtrack DVD featuring MP3 and FLAC versions of music from all four titles in the series (including <em><a title="Games > CHAOS;HEAD NOAH [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/chaos-head-noah">CHAOS;HEAD NOAH</a></em> and <em>CHAOS;CHILD</em>).</p><p>As its title implies, <em>CHAOS;HEAD / CHAOS;CHILD Love chu chu!! DOUBLE PACK</em> includes the <em>Science <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,509 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a></em> series spin-off <a title="Genres > Romance Visual Novel [88 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel/romance-visual-novel">romance visual novels</a> <em>CHAOS;HEAD Love Chu Chu</em> and <em>CHAOS;CHILD Love chu chu!!</em>, originally released in 2010 and 2017, respectively.</p><p>Visit the official website <a href="https://game.mages.co.jp/chaosdouble/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/chaoshead-chaoschild-love-chu-chu-double-pack-announced-for-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Koei Tecmo announces TGS 2025 lineup]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/koei-tecmo-announces-tgs-2025-lineup</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/koei-tecmo-announces-tgs-2025-lineup.1279710/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Hyrule Warriors, NINJA GAIDEN 4, and Nioh 3.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,084 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo</a> has opened its <a href="https://www.gamecity.ne.jp/tgs/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tokyo Game Show 2025 website</a> and announced its lineup of games for the event, which will run from September 25 to 28 at Makuhari Messe in Chiba, Japan. <span id="more-987731"></span></p><p>The company’s lineup is as follows:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a></em> (<a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [362 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>) – Playable</li><li><em><a title="Games > NINJA GAIDEN 4 [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ninja-gaiden-4">NINJA GAIDEN 4</a></em> (<a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,238 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,800 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [24,085 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>) – Playable</li><li><em><a title="Games > Nioh 3 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/nioh-3">Nioh 3</a></em> (PS5, PC) – Playable</li></ul><p>Further information about Koei Tecmo’s Tokyo Game Show 2025 plans will be announced at a later date.</p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/koei-tecmo-announces-tgs-2025-lineup]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Immensely Satisfying Satisfactory Releases On PS5 And Xbox In November]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-immensely-satisfying-satisfactory-releases-on-ps5-and-xbox-in-november/1100-6534225/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-immensely-satisfying-satisfactory-releases-on-ps5-and-xbox-in-november.1279707/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534225">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Last year, Coffee Stain Studios brought <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/satisfactory/" data-ref-id="5000-483395">Satisfactory</a> out of its half decade in early access with an announcement <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/satisfactory-is-now-in-the-works-for-consoles-following-1-0-launch-on-pc/1100-6526360/" data-ref-id="1100-6526360">that console versions would follow</a>. Now, the studio is inviting players on PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X|S to join PC players on planet MASSAGE-2(A-B)b when Satisfactory launches on consoles on November 4.</p><p>In Satisfactory, players assume control of Pioneers who have traveled to an alien world on behalf of the mega corporation FICSIT Inc. to build factories and exploit the natural resources of MASSAGE-2 (A-B)b. You'll construct increasingly elaborate sets of automated machinery to mine, craft, and expand.</p><p>It's a big job, but luckily <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-cross-platform-games/2900-5425/" data-ref-id="2900-5425">cross-play</a> is supported across all consoles and PC, and up to four players can work together via co-op.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TURoNOy6eC0" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/TURoNOy6eC0" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The console versions of Satisfactory will launch with everything in the PC version up to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/satisfactory-gets-a-1-0-release-and-flushable-toilets-in-september/1100-6524709/" data-ref-id="1100-6524709">the 1.1 update that debuted in June</a>. For example, the toilets will be flushable from the very beginning. The Xbox version supports game suspend, while on PlayStation, there is support for the integrated controller speaker support and haptics. There will also be performance presets, including Quality mode target at 30fps, Balanced at 40fps, and Performance at 60fps. Additionally, players can utilize cloud saves to take their assembled factories across consoles or PC, depending on which platform they choose to use.</p><p>Satisfactory isn't the only factory simulation game that's set on an alien world. Earlier this summer, developer Creepy Jar shared a look at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/starrupture/" data-ref-id="5000-590982">StarRupture</a>, a game that seems very similar to Satisfactory, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starrupture-early-access-trailer-looks-more-dangerous-than-satisfactory/1100-6534020/" data-ref-id="1100-6534020">also more dangerous</a>. The alien inhabitants in this game appear to be very lethal. StarRupture will debut in early access on January 6, 2026.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-immensely-satisfying-satisfactory-releases-on-ps5-and-xbox-in-november/1100-6534225/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 6 Reportedly Set To Be Revealed At Tokyo Game Show Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/forza-horizon-6-reportedly-set-to-be-revealed-at-tokyo-game-show-next-month/1100-6534227/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forza-horizon-6-reportedly-set-to-be-revealed-at-tokyo-game-show-next-month.1279704/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534227">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>After tours across France, England, and Mexico, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/possible-forza-horizon-6-leak-suggests-were-racing-in-japan/1100-6534178/">Forza Horizon 6 is reportedly shifting the series over to Japan</a> for its next slice of car racing action. According to several leaks--and at least one now-deleted Instagram post hinting at it--the next chapter is set to be revealed next month at the Tokyo Game Show.</p><p>That's according to prolific leaker <a href="https://x.com/natethehate2/status/1959666173936796128" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">NateTheHate</a>, and <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/forza/report-forza-horizon-6-may-be-announced-this-year-in-the-same-place-the-game-is-set" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Windows Central</a> has backed up this report by claiming that it has seen documentation "suggesting" Forza Horizon 6 will be officially shown off during the annual gaming event.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1146823319" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465724,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Forza%20Horizon%205%20-%20Horizon%20Realms%20Official%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:48,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/forza-horizon-5-horizon-realms-official-trailer\/2300-6465724\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465724\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465724\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465724\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465724&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4451385-screenshot2025-02-27at10.15.55%E2%80%AFam.png&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/TZEpAeEG.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1740680040,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="TZEpAeEG" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Forza Horizon 5 - Horizon Realms Official Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Earlier this month, an Australian car import company uploaded an Instagram post showing off a Playground Games employee digitally scanning a rare compact Japanese car, adding more fuel to the fire when the post mentioned that it was for a new Forza Horizon game. The Tokyo Game Show takes place September 25-28, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/xbox-tokyo-game-show-2024-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-5799/" data-ref-id="2900-5799">Microsoft has in the past held dedicated showcases</a> during the event.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/forza-horizon-5-review-its-about-four-wheeled-family/1900-6417778/">Forza Horizon 5 launched back in 2021</a>, and it saw the game's titular festival move to Mexico and it was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstations-biggest-game-of-2025-is-a-former-xbox-exclusive-analyst-says/1100-6533368/">the best-selling game on PS5 this year, per gaming analyst Alinea</a>. The game was well-reviewed and featured hundreds of vehicles to collect with frequent content updates, eventually <a href="https://x.com/GAMERNEWSonX/status/1958214507739922667" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">reaching 50 million players across all platforms</a>.</p><p>Recently, the cadence of those updates has slowed down, leading many to suspect that developer Playground Games was gearing up for a sequel, in addition to its work on the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fable-4-everything-we-know/1100-6485774/" data-ref-id="1100-6485774">next Fable game</a>. Japan has been a frequently requested location for a Forza Horizon game to take place in, as the country has a rich history and appreciation for car culture, car meets, and an infamous underground racing scene.</p><p>The rumors come after numerous layoffs and the cancellation of several games at Microsoft's game studios, and Forza Motorsport developer Turn 10 was hit particularly bad <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-7-forza-studios-impacted-by-xbox-layoffs/1100-6532918/">with reportedly 50% of its staff affected</a>. The studio says that it still <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/forza-studio-turn-10-breaks-month-long-silence-on-its-future-following-recent-layoffs/1100-6533793/">plans to support the more-realistic counterpart to Forza Horizon</a>, with several events for the game having already kicked off recently.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/forza-horizon-6-reportedly-set-to-be-revealed-at-tokyo-game-show-next-month/1100-6534227/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Go finally expands trainer level cap]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-finally-expands-trainer-level-cap</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-go-finally-expands-trainer-level-cap.1279701/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>XP Celebration on the way.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Niantic</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/pokemon-go">Pokémon Go</a> is at long last expanding its trainer level cap.
</p>
<p>
At present, the maximum level for trainers is 50, but from 15th October this will be increased to 80 to rebalance the existing curve for more frequent level ups due to less XP required for each level.
</p>
<p>
As a result, some trainers may jump in level automatically if excessive XP past level 50 has already been gained. Niantic will share more details on how many levels in the future, but noted no trainers will drop in level.
</p>
<p>
Any tasks for Level-Up Research for levels 41 - 50 will be removed, while new tasks will be added for levels 71 - 80. Trainers at level 70 or higher will have an increased chance of becoming Lucky Friends with others.
</p><p>
However, some existing rewards will be removed - notably, the level 50 exclusive jacket. While this will still be in-game for those trainers who have already received it, it will no longer be obtainable. Further, avatar items earned by reaching levels 40 - 50 before the update will not be available after 15th October.
</p>
<p>
To mitigate this, Pokémon Go will host an XP Celebration event from 25th August until 14th October, with extra XP rewards to help players level their trainers ahead of the level cap increase.
</p>
<p>
Event bonuses are as follows:
</p>
<ul>
<li>2x Catch XP from Nice, Great, and Excellent throws</li>
<li>+3000 XP for winning raids</li>
<li>+3000 XP for winning Max Battles</li>
<li>Level-Up Research update for level 48 - now reduced from walking 25km eight times in a week to twice in a week</li>
</ul>

<p>
The Trainer Level change will not effect Pokémon levels, which will remain capped at Level 50.
</p>
<p>
For more on levelling, check out our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-level-cap-increase-level-50-rewards-item-list-7002">Pokémon Go level requirements guide</a>.
</p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-finally-expands-trainer-level-cap]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["The Best-Looking Thing I've Seen On Switch 2" - Digital Foundry Talks Final Fantasy 7 Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/the-best-looking-thing-ive-seen-on-switch-2-digital-foundry-talks-final-fantasy-7-remake</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-looking-thing-ive-seen-on-switch-2-digital-foundry-talks-final-fantasy-7-remake.1279683/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"I would say it looks better than the PS4 version"</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="FF7 Remake" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/194501ab62791/ff7-remake.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</a> was playable on Switch 2 last week at Gamescom, and it seems that most who managed to go hands-on with the game came away feeling pretty positive about it.</p>
<p>Now, in a new post from Digital Foundry advertising its latest DF Weekly episode, John Linneman has come out and said that FF7R is "the best-looking thing I've seen on Switch 2". High praise, indeed! Now, this is only from a short clip posted on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:sdkjeb6sj3aqwwtwnbuusybk/post/3lx6fxspghc2r">Bluesky</a>, so we might be missing a little bit of extra context here, but the overall sentiment is that this is a really solid Switch 2 port from Square Enix.</p>
<p>Here's what Linneman had to say:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"I'm gonna say right now, this is the best-looking thing I've seen on Switch 2. Seeing that game running at a stable 30fps, with that excellent motion blur especially, it looked fantastic. It was completely stable, it looked on par – actually I would say it looks better than the PS4 version, at a glance.</p>
<p>"If I had to guess – and I haven't been able to compare because we don't have footage – it's gonna fall somewhere between the PS4 and PS5 versions. So we'll see if that holds true for the final game, but that's the sensation I got while playing it. The image quality was absolutely superb, like it looked really great, it matched the 1080p screen. I was really, really happy about that. So that's a good one."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>There's no firm release date for Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade just yet, but it's supposedly still on track to launch later this year.</p>
<p>Square Enix is adopting a new approach with its games, striving to make as many of them available on all major platforms where possible. It recently detailed its efforts to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/05/square-enix-details-plan-to-reboot-and-awaken-its-business">'reboot and revive'</a> its business in the midst of challenging financial results.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186891,186830 @ 1756127710 -->
<p><em>Are you excited to play FF7R on the Switch 2? Have you already played it elsewhere? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:sdkjeb6sj3aqwwtwnbuusybk/post/3lx6fxspghc2r" rel="noopener" href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:sdkjeb6sj3aqwwtwnbuusybk/post/3lx6fxspghc2r">bsky.app</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/bf81f9ca5b5a6b9df3125e3fc2e920d5 @ 1756126925 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/the-best-looking-thing-ive-seen-on-switch-2-digital-foundry-talks-final-fantasy-7-remake]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Release Date Explained—Start Times & Release Date Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-release-date-start-time/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-release-date-explained%E2%80%94start-times-release-date-confirmed.1279677/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Borderlands 4’s release date is screeching into sight and is set to be one of the biggest releases in 2025, and we’ve got all the details you need.</p>



<p>Our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-preview-reveal-harlowe-demo-exclusive/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hands-on preview of Borderlands 4</a> at Gamescom raised our excitement levels for the title, which comes a whopping six years after the previous entry in the series landed, and there’s plenty to take in, with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-will-feature-30-billion-guns/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">30 billion guns featured</a>.</p>



<p>If you’re looking to lock in for release, perhaps calling in sick from work for the day, we’ve got all the crucial release datte and start times information you need.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-borderlands-4-coming-out">When is Borderlands 4 Coming Out?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Claptrap is waiting. Image via Gearbox</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>September 12 is the official release date for Borderlands 4 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC, with Nintendo Switch 2 players having to wait a while longer until October 3</strong>.</p>



<p>With the Borderlands 4 release date now locked in and on the horizon, there shouldn’t be any changes to the release date. Gearbox has already made the rather unusual move of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-release-date-move-forward-after-randy-pitchford-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">bringing the Borderlands 4 release date</a> forward, with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/randy-pitchford-addresses-gta-6-release-date-rumors-after-borderlands-4-is-moved-up/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CEO Randy Pitchford then denying</a> the decision had anything to do with Grand Theft Auto 6. </p>



<p>The release date was brought forward by “confidence in the game and development trajectory,” giving fans a nice early bonus. As mentioned, however, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-nintendo-switch-2-release-date-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Switch 2 players have a little while longer to wait</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-borderlands-4-start-times">Borderlands 4 Start Times</h2>



<p><strong>Borderlands 4’s official start times are yet to be announced, but listings on the PlayStation store suggest it will be available a midnight regionally.</strong></p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/borderlands-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">UK PlayStation Store</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-au/games/borderlands-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Australian PlayStation Store</a> both have midnight in their respective time zones, while the <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/borderlands-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">US PlayStation Store</a> has a midnight release in Eastern Time stated—though it’s unclear whether this means those in other US time zones will gain access at the same moment.</p>



<p>A midnight regional release would also open the door for players to gain earlier access by switching their time zone, which is much easier to do on Xbox Series X|S than it is on PlayStation. However, we won’t know for sure if this is possible until the release times are confirmed.</p>



<p>For easier viewing, the table below shows the release times in popular time zones. Please remember that these are subject to change; we’ll be sure to keep them updated.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Borderlands 4 Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">21:00 – September 11</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">23:00 – September 11</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">00:00 – September 12</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">British Summer Time (BST)</td><td data-align="center">00:00 – September 12</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Standard Time (AEST)</td><td data-align="center">00:00 – September 12</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Is Borderlands 4 the title you’re most excited to play in 2025? Let us know your thoughts in the Insider Gaming forum.</p>



<p>For more Borderlands 4, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-pitchford-nervous-challenge-borderlands-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive with Randy Pitchford admitting his nerves for tougher parts of the game</a>, and our exclusive on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-randy-pitchford-100-million-units-borderlands-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pitchford predicting over 100 million units will be sold</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-release-date-start-time/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons & Dragons and a Grounded Setting Are Why Dragon Age: Origins' Mage Ended Up Overpowered, Ex-BioWare Developer Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dungeons-dragons-and-a-grounded-setting-are-why-dragon-age-origins-mage-ended-up-overpowered-ex-bioware-developer-says</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-dragons-and-a-grounded-setting-are-why-dragon-age-origins-mage-ended-up-overpowered-ex-bioware-developer-says.1279671/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans have always felt that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dragon-age-origins">Dragon Age: Origins</a>’ mage class was more complete, perhaps even more dominant, than the game’s other two classes, the rogue and the warrior. But why was that? Former BioWare executive producer Mark Darrah has said it’s mostly about second edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://youtu.be/qwdaQo6Cdv4?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recently published video</a>, Darrah explained why the mage in BioWare’s much-loved 2009 role-playing game ended up feeling so much better to play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It's actually I would say more because the design space that Dragon Age: Origins was being built into was heavily influenced by second edition D&amp;D," Darrah, who worked at BioWare from 1997 to early 2021, said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"So in that case, the reality is mages and rogues were less… they were thinner classes, they were simpler classes. And the mage was the stronger, more fully implemented, more fully considered class. Much more complicated, much more in terms of spells and such.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Age: Origins was not designed to be played with Dungeons &amp; Dragons 2nd Edition rules, but rather it was built on a custom system that was heavily influenced by the design principles of the 2nd edition era of D&amp;D.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Darrah also said Origins’ more grounded tone affected the abilities of the warrior and the rogue, which in turn had more grounded abilities than in subsequent games in the fantasy franchise.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Also, of all the Dragon Ages, Dragon Age: Origins is the most grounded. It's the one that's worrying the most about everything making perfect sense within the overall lore of the game. So, warriors and rogues in Origins basically don't have talents, or they don't have talents or skills that violate physics.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Whereas, as we move into Dragon Age 2 and Inquisition and Veilgard, you get a lot more things that are not really possible for someone to physically do.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN BioWare Game Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s plenty of agreement with Darrah’s assessment from fans, particularly on his point about Origins’ more grounded setting and tone, but also on how important mages were to the game’s story. Morrigan, a mage party member, ended up one of the most popular in Origins. That was in part because she was powerful, but there were also… other considerations.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, this unbalance was rectified for subsequent Dragon Age games, as Darrah points out. But following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/report-sheds-new-light-on-dragon-age-the-veilguards-development-turmoil-reveals-dialogue-rewrite-sparked-by-forspokens-failure">the failure of Veilguard</a> and the layoffs that followed, fans often point to Origins as the kind of Dragon Age they would love to see BioWare return to one day.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Will that day come? It seems unlikely any time soon, given BioWare is focused squarely on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mass-effect-next-chapter">Mass Effect 5</a>. Darrah, meanwhile, via his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MarkDarrah" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube channel,</a> has been running through his time at the studio, explaining everything from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-has-there-never-been-a-dragon-age-origins-remaster-bioware-exec-explains-past-plans-and-continued-difficulties">why there has never been a Dragon Age: Origins remaster</a> to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/former-bioware-executive-producer-breaks-down-what-really-happened-to-anthem">what went wrong with Anthem</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/dungeons-dragons-and-a-grounded-setting-are-why-dragon-age-origins-mage-ended-up-overpowered-ex-bioware-developer-says]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy: Brave Exvius to end service on October 31 in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/final-fantasy-brave-exvius-to-end-service-on-october-31-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-brave-exvius-to-end-service-on-october-31-in-japan.1279668/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>"Memorial Version" to be released after closure.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [432 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">Free-to-play</a> <a title="Genres > RPG [17,562 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Series > Final Fantasy [141 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/final-fantasy">Final Fantasy</a>: Brave Exvius</em> will end service on October 31 in Japan, <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,369 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/FFBE_JP/status/1959873628691939371" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-987732"></span></p><p>The global version of <em>Final Fantasy: Brave Exvius</em> originally <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/final-fantasy-brave-exvius-global-version-to-end-service-on-october-30">ended service</a> on October 30, 2024, but there were no plans to end service for the Japanese version at the time.</p><p><em>Final Fantasy: Brave Exvius</em> first launched for iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/final-fantasy-brave-exvius/id1078553808" rel="noopener" target="_blank">App Store</a> and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.square_enix.android_googleplay.FFBEWW&amp;hl=en_US" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Google Play</a> on October 22, 2015 in Japan, followed by a worldwide release on June 30, 2016.</p><p>A “Grand Finale Campaign” will be held until service ends, and a “Memorial Version” of the game allowing players to view Units and Vision Cards will be released for iOS and Android after closure.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/final-fantasy-brave-exvius-to-end-service-on-october-31-in-japan]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shinobi: Art of Vengeance Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/25/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-review.1279659/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>It’s been far too long, but Shinobi is back! After fourteen years in the wilderness, Joe Musashi has a new main series entry to showcase what he does best; running and jumping from left to right and killing mechanised ninjas with unstoppable style and grace. At this point, I could tease whether Lizardcube has been successful in rebooting one of Sega’s finest, but when a game is this good, it should be shouted about from the opening paragraph. And Shinobi: Art of Vengeance isn’t just good; it’s a masterclass in 2D platforming.</p>
<p><iframe title="SHINOBI: Art of Vengeance | Demo Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D164gIK7JkM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The ENE Corporation is up to no good, and has decided, as you do, to take over the world. The only obstacle in their path to global domination is the Shinobi Joe Musashi and his Ninja village. In a blistering opening chapter, the forces of ENE decimate Joe’s home, forcing the eponymous shinobi to go on a mission of vengeance; and for the player to have a very good time in the process.</p>


<p>First things first, you’ll notice that Shinobi: Art of Vengeance looks bloomin’ gorgeous. Lizardcube did an excellent job with the beautiful 2D visuals and slick animation of Streets of Rage 4, but with Shinobi, they’ve truly outdone themselves. The sumptuous movment of Joe himself is something to behold, as he darts across the screen, flipping over obstacles, unleashing a flame attack, all while his ninja garb billows in the breeze. Levels are cram-packed full of layered detail, with everything from spooky underground labs to stinky fish markets rendered with a visual flare that makes other 2D games green with envy. The character design is gorgeous too. Enemy monsters, mechs, mercs, and mutants have a distinctive and charismatic Bandes dessinées look that makes them a joy to hack apart.</p>


<p>Speaking of the hacking, all the visuals would matter little if the combat didn’t deliver, but thankfully, it absolutely does. Fighting is smooth, responsive, and bombastically satisfying. The only blemish in the other wise silky smooth skin of Joe Musashi is some pesky slow down that can sneak in when a whole load of explosions are kicking off on screen – hopefully an issue that can soon be remedied.</p>
<p>Each combat encounter is meticulously crafted, demanding that the player moves and thinks like a ninja, darting around the environment to take out vulnerable targets before focusing on bringing down bigger foes. Joe has a number of unlockable combos at his disposal, many of them bringing a welcome Dante-like juggle to proceedings, allowing you to knock enemies into the air before delivering a cavalcade of strikes and then seamlessly transitioning into one of the varied and visually explosive special attacks at your disposal. Ultimately, combat comes down to managing the space, separating enemies and fighting them on your terms, as it’s all too easy to be overwhelmed by their sheer numbers if you just button bash. Lizardcube places other demands on the player too, varying encounters by incorporating healers, snipers, and little things that take great delight in exploding in your face in order to keep things fresh. The challenge is furious but fair, pushing you to your limit and ensuring you earn your way to the boss.</p>

<p>Bosses are eminently memorable, each encounter testing different aspects of Joe’s ninja abilities. Be it using your newly acquired grappling hook to reach a flying foe or utilising your shield smashing abilities to break through a big bad’s defences, each bout has a reason for existing, rather than being stuck at the end of a level just for the sake of it. The bosses themselves are wonderfully distinctive too, from demons who attack you with the sword impaled in their own chest, to enormous screen smothering beasties, and a host of returning foes that are sure to please series stalwarts. Thankfully, every boss fight shares one consistent quality; they’re initially brutal, but once you’ve finally learned the attack patterns and incorporated your newest ability correctly, you can wipe the floor with your foe in seconds, leading to you feeling like a total super ninja bad ass.</p>
<p>Platforming is, as you would hope, precise and thrilling. Joe does double jumping, dashing, and wall climbing with easy abandon. Whilst it’s certainly challenging making your way past a cornucopia of traps, a suite of accessibility options makes the game doable for players of any ability. You can tinker with nearly every element of difficulty, even lowering the damage the traps cause so they are a mere annoyance rather than a game over causing insta-killer. But if you want unrelenting pain in your game, Shinobi: Art of Vengeance has you covered. Each level can be returned to and further explored with your new abilities, we’re not talking to a labyrinthian metroidvania extent, but there’s certainly a host of secrets to be found off the beaten path.</p>

<p>My one small gripe? Once you’ve uncovered a secret, it remains highlighted on the map, causing confusion if your trying to one hundred percent each level. However, this frustration is eased by the smart decision to allow the place to fast travel to any save point at any time, preventing any irritation from running along the same corridors again and again to get to the bit you want to further explore. Some of these secrets are brutal combat encounters against specialist troops, whilst others offer the demanding platforming perfection last scene in Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown. Many of these were out of reach of my abilities, but the few I did manage resulted in some darn cool new weapons, spells, and skills, each shaking up combat encounters and traversal in fun ways, so there’ll no doubt be many more treats for the skilful player to discover.</p>
<p>What’s the downside to all this brilliance? Well, there’s an undoubted brevity to Shinobi: Art of Vengeance, you’ll see through the main story in six hours or so, depending on your ability level, and everything else in a few more. But when every minute of the experience is killer, with no filler, is that really such a problem?</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/25/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turok: Origins Preview – New beginnings for a dino-blasting FPS legend]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/25/turok-origins-preview-new-beginnings-for-a-dino-blasting-fps-legend/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/turok-origins-preview-%E2%80%93-new-beginnings-for-a-dino-blasting-fps-legend.1279656/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Turok’s heyday as a first person shooter franchise came and went in what feels like a blink of Mario’s eye. Bursting onto the N64 to pioneer the first person shooter on console, half a year before GoldenEye, and being an FPS mainstay over the following years. But Turok’s time-travelling, dino-blasting adventures lost their lustre when trying to jump to later generations, and it’s now been some 17 years since the last attempt. Saber are no strangers to a licensed franchise reboot, though, and are hoping to weave the same magic that they did for Space Marine 2 for Turok: Origins.</p>
<p><iframe title="Turok: Origins - Announcement Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rK2sg_RgY2M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Turok world has existed since the 1950, going through multiple iterations as the variously named Turok characters –&nbsp;is it their actual name, or an honorific? –&nbsp;gradually come to battle dinosaurs across time and space. Turok: Origins reimagines this once again, with the team at Saber stating right up front that they’ve engaged with the Native American community to ensure that the way that their culture is represented is respectful. Of course, this is still a comic book-inspired sci-fi action romp with squads of soldiers from the Order of Turok being a bit like a planet-hopping Native American Delta Force.</p>


<p>Oh, right. Turok: Origins is now all about co-op play instead of a sole hero, with up to three players diving in to take the fight to the reptillians and Xenia, able to lean into different weapon loadouts and character builds to compliment one another. It’s also both a first person and a third person shooter, letting you switch back and forth with a long button press, right in the middle of the action.</p>
<p>For our hands on, we jumped through a handful of different scenarios, getting to see the different aspects of co-op shooter that Turok: Origins provides.</p>


<p>It started with a trek through a reptile-filled maze of a swamp, looking to battle through these basic enemies to reach power nodes and gain access to the next area. While we navigated the lower pathways of this area, various reptilian enemies would come at us, often shooting lasers from the tops of ridge-lines, or dropping down from them to close the gaps.</p>
<p>Before heading into the fray, we’d had the choice of three biomorphic Mantle suits and prepared weapon and ability loadouts. Raven came with a high-tech bow and arrow, rifle with bouncing projectiles and rocket launcher, while Bison’s shotgun made them great for closer range, combined with a pulse rifle and minigun for laying down damage. I also rather enjoyed Cougar, though, coming with an automatic crossbow and something called a Cerebral Bore to home in and explode the heads of enemies. All of these weapons had alternate fire modes, some lifted directly from previous games and some new creations.</p>

<p>While we didn’t really have time to fully explore each of the abilities granted to us, there’s a progression system for all aspects of your loadout, from the weapons to the abilities and the Mantle itself, which is a conduit for unlocking an animalistic primal energy within you. Through gathering the echoes from fallen enemies and plants in the environment, you can unlock the ability to use in combat. It’s something that can build up quite quickly as well, encouraging you to quickly use the powers as soon as they charge up and deal as much damage as possible.</p>
<p>That became more important as we made our way through each successive demo area. From the first labyrinthine area, we jumped to a facility of the Xenia forces, with a bony alien look to it as we progressed deeper and fought through now humanoid Xenia aliens. This area gave us a first use of the grapple hook, enhancing movement with grapple points to let us get up to higher platforms and navigate multi-layered areas.</p>

<p>Jumping ahead once again, and the hunt for a superweapon to turn the tide of war took us to an ancient temple biome, descending into darkness with more of a platforming angle, though with some fights against Xenia lieutenants and a variety of other enemies to keep things mixed up. The real treat, though, was the battle against a giant cybernetically enhanced triceratops. This towering beast could blast energy from its electrically charged horns, unleashed bullet hell barriers of energy to avoid, and could even teleport around before reappearing and rampaging through the arena.</p>
<p>All I’ll say is that it was actually quite handy that the Gamescom demo seemed to have deaths disabled, or I would have been downed half a dozen times during the tougher segments of this demo.</p>
<p>As a first taster of this game, I’m certainly intrigued and curious to see more of how Saber is reimagining and rebooting this franchise. Thirty minutes was not really long enough to dig deep into the various gameplay mechanics, the co-op and to appreciate the differences between a bunch of different loadouts, but there’s clearly a lot of variety baked into the new narrative, good touches like the 1st and 3rd person toggle, and bombastic dinosaur battling. There’s still a fondness for Turok from the N64’s heyday, and a new beginning could certainly bring this series back to the forefront.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/25/turok-origins-preview-new-beginnings-for-a-dino-blasting-fps-legend/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nioh 3, Ninja Gaiden 4, Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment Are Part Of Koei Tecmo’s Tokyo Game Show 2025 Lineup]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-ninja-gaiden-4-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-tokyo-game-show-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nioh-3-ninja-gaiden-4-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-are-part-of-koei-tecmo%E2%80%99s-tokyo-game-show-2025-lineup.1279650/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Koei Temco announced its Tokyo Game Show 2025 lineup, which will include Nioh 3, among a few other games.</p>



<p>As reported on <a href="https://x.com/Genki_JPN">X</a> by Genki today, the third entry in the masocore series developed by Team NINJA will be among the games the Japanese publisher will bring to this year's edition of the Tokyo Game Show besides Ninja Gaiden 4, which Team NINJA is also developing in collaboration with PlatinumGames, and Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment. As we have seen very little so far of both Nioh 3 and the third entry in the Zelda spin-off series, this is definitely good news, as together with showing more of both games, the publisher could announce release dates as well.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Koei Tecmo announced its Tokyo Game Show 2025 lineup including Hyrule Warriors Age of Imprisonment playable for the first time which means a release date should be announced soon! 👀</p><p>- Nioh 3<br>- Hyrule Warriors Age of Imprisonment <br>- Ninja Gaiden 4<a href="https://t.co/5So8aJbRxg">https://t.co/5So8aJbRxg</a> <a href="https://t.co/Jo6w41nVPW">pic.twitter.com/Jo6w41nVPW</a></p></div>— Genki✨ (@Genki_JPN) <a href="https://twitter.com/Genki_JPN/status/1959935906447794679?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 25, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Though we have seen little of Nioh 3 so far, PlayStation 5 users had the chance to try out the new entry in the series last June thanks to a limited time demo that did a pretty good job showing how the series will evolve in its third iteration with a more open level design and a new Ninja fighting style that is sure to open up some interesting gameplay options. <a href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-visual-performance-improvements/">Earlier this month</a>, Team NINJA and Koei Tecmo confirmed some of the changes being made to the game following feedback received from players that played the demo, which include balance, controls, and performance improvements, among many other things.</p>



<p>Nioh 3 launches in early 2026 on PC and PlayStation 5.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-ninja-gaiden-4-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-tokyo-game-show-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Series S Can’t Run Turok: Origins at 60 FPS, Says Developer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-s-cant-run-turok-origins-60-fps/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-series-s-can%E2%80%99t-run-turok-origins-at-60-fps-says-developer.1279644/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During a Gamescom 2025 presentation of Turok: Origins, Saber Interactive Madrid Game Director Jesús Iglesias revealed that the upcoming first and third-person cooperative shooter game will run at 60 frames per second on consoles such as Sony's PlayStation 5 and Microsoft's Xbox Series X. When asked about the latter console's smaller sibling, the Xbox Series S, Iglesias admitted that the same wouldn't apply there, as the studio simply found no way to make that happen. As such, the Xbox Series S will run Turok: Origins at 30 frames per second.</p>



<p>This isn't exactly the first game to set this frame rate target on the smaller Xbox Series console. The Series S has less memory (10GB versus 16GB of the X) and, more importantly, is equipped with just 20 Compute Units, whereas the Series X has 52 Compute Units. The teraflops difference between the two Xbox consoles is even more stark, with the Xbox Series S rated at 4 teraflops and the Series X at slightly more than 12 teraflops. Indeed, game developers have long criticized Microsoft for making their lives harder with the console. The Xbox team wanted to give users a console at a more accessible price, but even that wasn't nearly enough to get the sales up.</p>



<p>Anyway, Turok: Origins is powered by Unreal Engine 5 technology, although it is a round-based cooperative shooter played in linear levels that doesn't really push visuals forward much. PC system requirements are still to be released by Saber Interactive (the game has no specific release window yet), which is self-publishing the game, by the way. </p>



<p>You can read our first impressions from Gamescom 2025 in this hands-on article.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-s-cant-run-turok-origins-60-fps/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shinobi: Art of Vengeance Review - Cutting Edge]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-review-cutting-edge</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-review-cutting-edge.1279641/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It was during last year's The Game Awards that SEGA <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0VHYLJR9pNg" rel="nofollow">announced</a> the revival of several classic IPs. Revivals included&nbsp;<em>Golden Axe, Jet Set Radio,</em>&nbsp;and more. The one that stood out to me the most, however, was&nbsp;<em>Shinobi</em>:&nbsp;<em>Art of Vengeance,&nbsp;</em>if anything, due to the excitement of this old-school series' fans.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance&nbsp;</em>is a gorgeous, hand-drawn 2D platformer with <a href="https://techraptor.net/genre/metroidvania/games" rel="nofollow">Metroidvania </a>elements. It's my first foray into this longtime franchise, yet it serves as the perfect starting point for anyone interested in the adventures of Joe Musashi. Fluid combat with impeccable style makes this a triumphant return for the series.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-wide-shot.jpg?itok=lebbdFWh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-wide-shot.jpg?itok=fM7VlIR- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Aura farming: Part 1.</figcaption></figure><h2>Return of the Legendary Joe Musashi</h2>

<p>Legendary shinobi Joe Musashi is living a peaceful life in his ninja village, but suddenly his world is uprooted as everything he loves is burned to the ground. His pregnant wife is in danger, and only a few survivors remain from the aftermath wrought by the wretched ENE Corp and its leader, Ruse.</p>

<p>Thus begins your adventure. Through the flames, Joe Musashi furiously slashes through the invading ninjas. This introductory sequence makes for a strong prologue and immediately sets the tone for&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>: A relentless, challenging, and exhilarating adventure on your quest for revenge.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-fireworks.jpg?itok=UXbvmCdA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-fireworks.jpg?itok=W23VRNe9 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Aura farming: Part 2.</figcaption></figure><p>Joe Musashi is a&nbsp;<em>very</em>&nbsp;capable ninja; in fact, I see him in the same light as the deadly and efficient Ryu Hayabusa from&nbsp;<em>Ninja Gaiden</em>. Joe's a relentless force to be reckoned with, and&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>'s combat captures that feeling of power and expertise in the shinobi arts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>You're equipped with a myriad of abilities, and as you progress through a great variety of Metroidvania-like levels, you'll gain new abilities to help you combat stronger foes, as well as traverse new obstacles.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-combat.jpg?itok=HxdiBQyx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-combat.jpg?itok=HcNJxYs_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Even when you're outnumbered, it's an unfair fight... for the enemy.</figcaption></figure><h2>Combat Flows Like Water</h2>

<p>It's been a good while since I've played a 2D game with combat this fluid. Joe moves like water as he weaves between foes. Dodging while in between attacks allows you to flow back and forth, continually attacking while also avoiding enemy moves.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As you gain more abilities and unlock additional moves, your ability to combo enemies expands greatly. Almost like a fighting game, or perhaps more appropriately a beat 'em up (the developer, Lizardcube, is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/streets-of-rage-4-review" rel="nofollow">no stranger</a> to that genre), you can juggle enemies to increase your combo count.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-parry.jpg?itok=nbdiv15d 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-parry.jpg?itok=B5ycLATw 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Just another day at the market.</figcaption></figure><p>You're incentivized to keep up your combo and not get hit. Combo amulets are items that grant you various bonuses if you reach a certain combo count. Keeping that combo alive isn't necessary to succeed, but it's always a blast to see how high it can go while also being rewarded for your efforts.</p>

<p>There are also passive amulets that enhance your abilities; chiefly, your Ninpo and Ninjutsu. The former are spells that are mostly damage-based. These include fire breath, which is an easy-to-master damage ability. Some are more complex, like Water Ninpo, which is essentially a parry that retaliates with strong damage.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-nijutsu.jpg?itok=Z25XE73l 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-nijutsu.jpg?itok=MRAsN3St 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Aura farming: Part 3</figcaption></figure><p>With eight Ninpo total, you have a good variety to choose from. Now, combine those with Ninjutsu, and you're a true force to be reckoned with. Ninjutsu takes longer to charge up and has devastatingly good effects: Karyu brings forth hellfire that consumes the entire screen, dealing huge damage to enemies and bosses.</p>

<p>Joe's toolkit also comes with Ningi. These include claws to traverse rocky walls and ceilings, a glider to float in the air, and a hook that latches onto anchors. With seven total, most of these are your typical Metroidvania upgrades; essentially, tools that help you get to previously unreachable areas.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-glider.jpg?itok=XFAfg1yl 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-glider.jpg?itok=cNYSfBRD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Everyone loves a good glider.</figcaption></figure><h2>Is&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: The Art of Vengeance&nbsp;</em>a True Metroidvania?</h2>

<p>While I use the term Metroidvania, in truth, it's more that it borrows elements from this genre. <em>Shinobi: Art of Vegeance&nbsp;</em>doesn't take place within one huge area. Rather, it's level-based, so it'll take you from level-to-level with a boss at the end of each.</p>

<p>There will be areas you can't access immediately, and that's where Ningi comes in.&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>&nbsp;is chock full of collectibles and items that'll aid you in your adventure, so going back to these areas with your new tools is advantageous.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A lot of these previously unreachable areas feature some of&nbsp;<em>Shinobi</em>:&nbsp;<em>Art of Vengeance</em>'s most challenging platforming segments. Hazards are aplenty here, with sharpened spikes, fire, and other dangers lurking around every corner.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-challenge-area.jpg?itok=NrAXqJhA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-challenge-area.jpg?itok=0yexuwQp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Quite the fall!</figcaption></figure><p>Platforming is pretty fluid, but I found myself frustrated with hitboxes. Platforming segments are well-designed, but many of my deaths felt like they weren't my fault.</p>

<p>Deceptive hit boxes on certain hazards felt frequent in some platforming-oriented challenge areas, so it was a true situation of trial and error. A lot of these segments use Joe's claws that latch onto ceilings and other objects, but the way he moves with these claws felt a tad too unrefined and led to my death.</p>

<p>This is all exacerbated by the deadly nature of hazards. They instantly kill you, or rather, they respawn Joe with a bit less health. But the checkpoints involving these can be inconsistent and lead to further frustration. When you're in the middle of combat with powerful foes and you die from a spike, it all ruins the flow a bit.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-fire-ninjutsu.jpg?itok=weJDlN83 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-fire-ninjutsu.jpg?itok=o0CfiDg1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Sometimes you just need to hit the panic button to survive.</figcaption></figure><h2>Bosses and Other Dangerous Foes</h2>

<p>Even if some areas can be a tad annoying, <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>&nbsp;does a good job of intermingling enemy encounters with creative placement of hazards.</p>

<p>As always,<em>&nbsp;</em>a proper shinobi takes advantage of all of his tools and skills. Some enemies have armor, so your abilities might be more focused on dealing damage to armor as opposed to health. It's up to you to learn these moves and use them when appropriate, and it's gratifying to absolutely dominate a wave of enemies, hardly stopping, as you traverse these levels.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-training-mode.jpg?itok=70W3wHgz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-training-mode.jpg?itok=E32zLB8p 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>There's a training room to practice your moves!</figcaption></figure><p>Most enemies, with the exception of bosses and some weaklings, have what's called an Execution Gauge under their health bar. Using your attacks gradually builds up this bar, and you can then execute them for additional rewards. Shuriken deal extra damage to the gauge, so I enjoyed throwing those in between attacks to further my combo and execute enemies.</p>

<p>I mentioned bosses, and yes, you'll face plenty of them here. In games with similar elements, these bosses can be hit-or-miss. I was pleasantly surprised by the depth of&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>'s bosses. They have a nice diversity in attacks, and most of them feel distinct from one another.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-enemies.jpg?itok=4mmA247J 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-enemies.jpg?itok=y8NHRzMD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Humans and yokai make a potent combination.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>I especially appreciated the fact that you could just combo the hell out of some bosses. Learn a boss' move and utilize your full kit, and you'll be running circles around these guys. That's not to say they're without challenge -- they do have measures in place to counter Joe in some ways -- but once you get a grasp on&nbsp;the mechanics of combat, you have the potential to dominate these challenges.</p>

<p>Beat&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>, and you'll gain access to the Boss Rush and Arcade modes. Boss Rush is an uncompromising tour through all of the game's bosses. There are no safeguards here. Die, and you'll have to redo the whole gauntlet. Those looking for a greater challenge will definitely enjoy this mode.</p>

<p>Likewise, Arcade is a more traditional take on the genre. The level layouts remain the same, but you're aiming for a high score. As this is more old-school, you're not able to quickly travel across levels by choosing a checkpoint. Again, this is another good way to challenge players, though something like a global rankings for scores would be nice to see.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-escape-sequence.jpg?itok=8HAIng-W 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-escape-sequence.jpg?itok=y124om01 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Plenty of exciting segments await players.</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance&nbsp;</em>is a Sight to Behold</h2>

<p>I mentioned this before, but&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance&nbsp;</em>is breathtakingly beautiful. The hand-drawn visuals are expertly animated and complement the sort of traditional Japanese aesthetic perfectly. Of course, Joe Musashi is a ninja of the modern era, so you'll find plenty of different locales outside of the classic Japanese countryside.</p>

<p>That includes neon-soaked cities, underground laboratories, arid deserts, and much more. These levels all have a distinct feel from one another, and art design plays a huge part in that. The backgrounds of these stages are beautifully drawn and packed with a ton of detail, so it truly is a feast for the eyes.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ninjutsu-shinobi-art-of-vengeance.jpg?itok=IRMTfxIg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ninjutsu-shinobi-art-of-vengeance.jpg?itok=5aNoWqJc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This healing Ninjutsu helped more times than I care to admit.</figcaption></figure><p>What stands out the most about&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em>'s art design is when Joe uses his various abilities. Every attack has weight and flair. Ninjutsu are the highlight here, though. Whether it's that fire move Karyu I mentioned, or Shisui, a water-based healing move, the whole screen is consumed with some of the finest animation and art in gaming.</p>

<p>Besides its visuals,&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance&nbsp;</em>is accompanied by a wonderful soundtrack by Tee Lopes.&nbsp;For this game, he infuses traditional Japanese instruments with more contemporary electronic instruments.&nbsp;The intermingling of Japanese instruments with modern rock-and-roll and electronic music is a similar approach to the recent&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/ninja-gaiden-ragebound-review-razor-sharp-retro-platformer" rel="nofollow"><em>Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound</em></a>, though I'd say&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance&nbsp;</em>is going for something more modern.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-dog.jpg?itok=cXy1Ek24 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-dog.jpg?itok=Ou-84eas 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Now that's a good boy right there.</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance&nbsp;</em>Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>A lot of fellow writers in my field have been gassing up&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance&nbsp;</em>since Summer Game Fest Play Days last June, so I was excited to see what all the hubbub was about. I see it now. It's fast. Exhilarating. Deadly. Cutting edge. Fans of ninjas, platformers, or games with plenty of combo potential will certainly love&nbsp;<em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance.</em></p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</strong>&nbsp;was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the developer over the course of 14 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-review-cutting-edge]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shinobi: Art of Vengeance: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-the-kotaku-review-2000619735</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-the-kotaku-review.1279635/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Reflecting on my time with </span><i><span>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</span></i><span> while I watched the credits roll, I recalled a close friend of mine from high school. Before the start of first period, she’d usually vent to me about how stressed she felt juggling so many extracurricular activities that she wound up staying at school for nearly 12 hours every weekday. Her reason for maintaining such a rigorous afterschool schedule was that so many different people were counting on her, and she didn’t want to let anyone down. Concerned for her health and happiness, the only advice I could offer her was, “You don’t have to be everyone’s friend.”</span></p> <p><span>I won’t bury the lede too deep here: I enjoyed </span><i><span>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</span></i><span>. It’s a cool game that’s rich with Sega nostalgia, and you’ll probably have fun with it if it seems like your kind of thing. However, much like my high school friend, </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>feels stretched thin by the sheer amount of bases it tries to cover despite its relatively small scope.</span></p> <p><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>places players in the shoes of Sega’s original </span><i><span>Shinobi </span></i><span>protagonist, Joe Musashi. His peaceful life with his very pregnant wife is immediately thrust into turmoil after his clan’s village is brutally attacked by a paramilitary organization bent on—you’re not gonna believe this—world domination. With rage boiling in his heart, Joe embarks on a quest to pursue his attackers and exact his revenge. Of course there’s that “save the world” business too, but make no mistake, this battle is personal. Unfortunately, the blade of revenge cuts both ways, and Joe will have to come face to face with the very cycle of life and death itself before he can rest at journey’s end.</span></p>

 <p><span>To address the elemental ninjitsu in the room, </span><i><span>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>is wildly dissimilar to last month’s </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ninja-gaiden-ragebound-review-2d-blasphemous-1851787265"><i><span>Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound</span></i></a><span>. Sure, both are revivals of dormant ninja-themed sidescrollers that originated in the late 80s. Heck, Joe’s call to adventure even resembles the way </span><i><span>Ragebound </span></i><span>opens with a demon attack on the Hayabusas’ village. However, while I’d describe </span><i><span>Ragebound </span></i><span>as a retro-influenced game that can appeal to modern audiences, </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance</span></i><span> comes off as a modern character action game distilled into a 2D form that retro enthusiasts can enjoy. Comparing the two is like comparing apples to potatoes.</span></p> <h2><strong>C-C-C-Combo Breaker</strong></h2> <p><span>Though Joe Musashi hasn’t played the starring role in a video game for over three decades (I’m sorry if this makes you feel old), his moveset in </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>shows he’s no worse for wear. From the moment you hit the start button, the ninja master can effortlessly throw kunai, chain together light and heavy attacks, and bust out limited special moves to diffuse otherwise dire situations. As a fledgling ninja-in-training learning the controls, I immediately fell in love with how fluid this combo-heavy combat felt. I could effortlessly weave together strings of attacks while I dashed around enemies after mere minutes of practice, and I loved how Joe could instantly fly straight through weakened enemies all over the screen to perform executions. Even when the game cranks up the challenge later on, it’s one hell of a power fantasy from start to finish.</span></p> <p><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>does take a while to fully unlock its combat system, though. While Joe’s starting kit is serviceable, most of his attacks are locked behind shop upgrades and hidden unlocks (more on this later). That said, this system did let me learn and ease into every move in my arsenal, which the game absolutely rewards. Sure, I </span><i><span>could </span></i><span>button-mash my way to victory if I wanted to. But to efficiently take down opponents, I had to note which attacks deplete enemy armor, inflict the most damage, or just let me strike from an angle that wouldn’t see me eating a counterattack. This might sound daunting, but if anything, fully unlocking Joe’s kit makes it easier to pull off flashy and intuitive combos. </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>feels simultaneously simple and expressive via its controls.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000619737" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000619737"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000619737">©Sega</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Regardless of your skill level, it’s easy to feel like a badass when playing a game as outrageously gorgeous as </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance</span></i><span>. Developer Lizardcube has worked on some great-looking games, so I don’t say lightly that </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance</span></i><span> is by far the team’s best work yet. The hand-drawn character animations look absolutely spectacular, and the level backgrounds are so rich with detail that I often stopped just to soak in the scenery. As I scoured through my screenshots to find images for this review, I couldn’t believe how often the in-game action looked like those impossibly good-looking bullshots that publishers use to market games that never look </span><i><span>that </span></i><span>phenomenal in actuality. To say </span><i><span>Shinobi </span></i><span>has never looked better is an understatement: This is a visual labor of love down to the smallest details.</span></p> <h2><strong>Character action adventure</strong></h2> <p><span>The mechanical foundation and presentation of </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>is fantastic, but where it starts to lose me is in its level design. To answer the question lingering in the minds of any sidescrolling enthusiasts reading this, this game </span><i><span>is </span></i><span>a Metroidvania…kind of. It’s technically stage-based, but each level is expansive and littered with optional paths that lead to collectibles and permanent stat boosts. In true Metroidvania fashion, most of these secrets require late-game traversal upgrades to reach. </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>presents itself as an action game first and foremost, but I got the sense that Lizardcube added these exploratory elements to offer players some optional challenges and pad the total runtime a bit.</span></p>

 <p><span>In practice, most areas were worse off for this “have your cake and eat it too” approach. I didn’t find the level exploration especially compelling, as it usually devolved into finding obvious detours and turning around whenever I saw walls. Additionally, many of these wide-open levels fail to emphasize the game’s stellar combat system. I was genuinely alarmed by how easy it was to just pass by many enemies rather than spend time fighting them. Meanwhile, several instances where combat </span><i><span>is </span></i><span>required consisted of waves of enemies that rarely forced me to switch up my battle strategy. Fortunately, boss battles were always a blast and rewarded mastery of Joe’s abilities, so I always looked forward to those highs at the end of each stage.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000619738" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000619738"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000619738">© Sega</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Some levels do admittedly benefit from the open-ended approach. Neo City is a shining example: Its nonlinear layout creates great replay value, and the backing track from Tee Lopes that perfectly emulates Yuzo Koshiro’s classic </span><i><span>Streets of Rage </span></i><span>sound (Koshiro himself appears on the soundtrack!) made the entire area a joy from start to finish. Meanwhile, stages like the Submarine Base that see Joe s-l-o-w-l-y pushing canisters into holes to unlock doors were okay my first time through, but a genuine slog to revisit in the postgame Arcade Mode.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>It’s not just the exploration that made the game feel a bit stretched thin. </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>sprinkles in numerous platforming challenges, mostly as obstacles to overcome to get those aforementioned secrets. Some stick the landing, like the frantic autoscrolling challenges where Joe has to run away from monsters and enemy gunfire while vaulting from platform to platform.&nbsp; Meanwhile, during the precision platforming segments I sometimes felt as if I was battling against</span> <span>the game’s core controls, such as in moments when I had to hold the jump button at the right time to run up a wall without accidentally double jumping. The platforming’s mostly okay, but it for sure ain’t </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/celeste-the-kotaku-review-1822420606"><i><span>Celeste</span></i></a><span>.</span></p> <p><span>Even the story never settles on a consistent tone. There’s a running gag about Joe only communicating via grunts, which did get a chuckle out of me the first four or five times I saw it. However, </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>absolutely </span><i><span>refuses </span></i><span>to let up this bit, even during dramatic scenes that are otherwise treated seriously. It’s certainly possible to mix drama with absurdity—the edgy </span><i><span>Pac-Man</span></i><span> reboot </span><i><span>Shadow Labyrinth</span></i> <a href="https://maxutmost.com/review-shadow-labyrinth/"><span>actually did this well</span></a><span>.</span> <span>However, </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance</span></i><span>’s efforts to do so are clunky where deftness is required; the game doesn’t know when to let a serious moment just be a serious moment. Taken together, these issues create a game that feels incohesive despite its strengths.</span></p>

 <h2><strong>It’s everyone’s friend</strong></h2> <p><span>Nothing about </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>made me outright dislike</span> <span>it. Rather, I mostly wish it focused more on exploring its combat system. As much as I loved learning and unlocking all of Joe’s attacks, by the endgame I found myself settling on a couple go-to attacks that efficiently dealt with 90 percent of my opponents. I actually went back and scored S-Ranks in every level just to see if I’d ever feel pressured to change my strategy, but ironically, the opposite happened. Because the scoring system weighs avoiding damage so heavily, I felt outright </span><i><span>discouraged</span></i><span> from getting inventive with the combat when simply jumpkicking everything with the right build was way safer and just as effective.</span></p> <p><span>Still, for all my misgivings, I’ll say that </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>did make me care about </span><i><span>Shinobi </span></i><span>again. As video game historian Jeremy Parish notes in </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r8QexCK4kIs"><span>his retrospective of </span><i><span>Shinobi</span></i></a><span>, a major strength of this series is its ability to remix its own concepts to “suit the current moment.” Indeed, there is an absolute abundance of inspiration on display here from classic games that </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>draws on, yet the game itself feels distinctly modern in its design philosophy. So if the goal was strictly to recapture the spirit of </span><i><span>Shinobi</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>is undeniably a success.</span></p> <div>       <div>                                         <figure>                            </figure>                           <div>                      <p>             Shinobi: Art of Vengeance           </p>                                       </div>       </div>               <div>           <ul>                           <li>                 <p>back-of-the-box quote</p>                 <p>"At long last, the dog from Shadow Dancer returns!"</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Type of game</p>                 <p>2D hack-and-slash platformer with some Metroidvania elements.</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Liked</p>                 <p>Jaw-dropping visuals, excellent combat mechanics, great boss encounters.</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Disliked</p>                 <p>Exploration felt unfulfilling and took focus away from combat, story is tonally inconsistent, platforming is hit or miss.</p>               </li>                               </ul><ul>                                         <li>                 <p>Developer</p>                 <p>Sega, Lizardcube</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Platforms</p>                 <p>PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X/S, Xbox One, Switch, PC (Played).</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Release Date</p>                 <p>August 26, 2025 (Early Access), August 29, 2025 (General Release).</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Played</p>                 <p>32 hours. 100% completed the story mode. Earned S-Ranks in every stage in Arcade Mode. Earned all achievements.</p>               </li>                                     </ul>         </div>           </div>  <p><span>I had fun with this video game, no questions asked. I also feel slightly empty as I think back on it. I can respect the effort that was put into the wide net of play experiences the game offers, just as I can see why my friend wanted to know and help everyone she knew. That said, this is also the first time I’ve really remembered that friend in nearly 20 years. Pleasant memories aren’t always lasting memories, and that’s how </span><i><span>Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>sits with me: A game that was worth my time, but didn’t strongly resonate with me either.</span></p> <p><i><span>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance </span></i><span>has all the right stuff at its core. The fluid action is a blast at its best, and the breathtaking visuals are a sight to behold. Unfortunately, the unfulfilling exploration and so-so platforming keep the game from hitting its full potential. It’s an enjoyable playthrough on a rainy day, especially for the person who wants a strong hit of Sega nostalgia or needs to decompress from more intensive games. But like spending time with someone who wants to be everyone’s friend, the experience feels a little too shallow for its own good. <em>Shinobi</em>’s long overdue return is easy to like, I just wish I could love it too.&nbsp;</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-the-kotaku-review-2000619735]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Under Par Golf Architect HANDS-ON Preview: A Golf Tycoon Simulator Scoring More Birdies Than Bogeys]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/under-par-golf-architect-hands-on-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/under-par-golf-architect-hands-on-preview-a-golf-tycoon-simulator-scoring-more-birdies-than-bogeys.1279632/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Gamescom 2025 was my first hands-on with Under Par Golf Architect. A fully golf-centric tycoon simulator where you control all aspects of golf course management. As a huge golf fan, this was right up my street. It’s the perfect hybrid of golf sim and golf creation aspects, it irons out any doubts I had, you should putt this on your wishlist if you’re a golf fan, and you wood be doing yourself a disservice if you didn’t.</p>



<p>It feels apt that I’m writing this as the 2025 Tour Championship has concluded to wrap up the FedEx Cup. Whereas everyone was waiting for the monolithic presence of Scottie Scheffler or Rory McIlroy to take home the richest prize on the PGA Tour, it was a relative underdog in Tommy Fleetwood who comfortably prevailed.</p>



<p>In this scenario, EA Sports PGA Tour and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pga-tour-2k25-trophy-list-all-achievements-and-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2K’s PGA Tour</a> are Scottie and Rory, and Under Par Golf Architect is rightly Tommy.</p>



<h2 id="h-makes-the-complexities-of-a-golf-complex-rather-simple">Makes The Complexities of a Golf Complex Rather Simple</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The control is in your hands. Credit to Broken Arm Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>I love playing real golf, and I also can’t get enough of simulated golf, where I can immerse myself in a virtual world to pretend I’m actually good at golf and escape my real-world inadequacies and lack of talent. From the 00s Tiger Woods games to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-sports-pga-tour-gets-latest-major-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA Sports PGA Tour</a> and HB Studios’ decade-long golf-game efforts, I’ll play everything.</p>



<p>So it was intriguing to hear about <a href="https://www.underpargame.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Under Par Golf Architect</a>. I can’t think of a dedicated golf sim game on this macro level since Sid Meier’s SimGolf in 2002. I had to see it for myself at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gamescom-2025-awards-all-award-winners/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gamescom 2025</a>. A private setup gave me a hands-on look and learning experience. Its premise is similar to any other ‘tycoon’ game: Micromanage every aspect of a golf course’s infrastructure.</p>



<p>You build a golf course in a plot of land, surround it with amenities to increase public satisfaction and optimize consumption of the facilities, appease your patrons, earn lots of money, and maximize customer enjoyment. You do this by tweaking the golf course to adhere to the golfer’s feedback, ensuring your workforce is on top of course maintenance, and various other factors. I visibly giggled every time I saw raccoons feeding on the course’s rubbish if left untidied for too long.</p>



<p>I quickly whipped up a nice little brute of a Par 3 surrounded by water, offering a horrendously undulating green. The controls were easy enough to execute my vision, and the hole design seemed funny to me. However, I quickly realized the novelty would soon be met with the hostility and incredulity of visitors—you need to be smart and channel your inner Pete Dye or Alister Mackenzie.</p>







<p>I exhaled a slight “ooo” when Broken Arms Games CEO Yves Hohler showed me what was essentially an AI data model you can use to test your golf holes. It takes into account High, Mid, Low, and Scratch Handicappers and simulates how they’d all play the hole. It gives you useful insight into where they’re landing their shots—or where the less-talented of us would inexplicably be spraying and praying our golf ball around the property.</p>



<p>This foresight and knowledge can help you make vital changes to the course. But don’t make the course too easy, or your more experienced golfers will scoff and leave in search of a challenge. On the contrary, you need to be mindful about not making every hole narrow, hazard-filled, and with green speeds even Augusta National would consider a glass-like menace.</p>



<p>Under Par is a single-player tycoon sim with multiple levels and biomes arriving at launch. I’ve been assured that the playing aspect was added in response to community feedback and is there if you fancy a quick knockabout. The business and simulation principles are where the game’s priorities lie. If you find PGA Tour 2K’s course creator to be a bit advanced, time-consuming, or cumbersome, I think you’ll really enjoy this.</p>



<p>A lot of love has gone into making Under Par Golf Architect. Time will tell if it’s a bona fide major winner, but I think it’s earned its tour card and is ready to see if its vision can become par for the course.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Under Par Golf Architect - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xR0BmvgbMVs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p>Even non-golf fans will find plenty to love about Under Park Golf Architect. The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a> is the perfect place to discuss your love of golf or other tycoon games, including the Two Point series or <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/jurassic-world-evolution-3-ditches-generative-ai-content-after-negative-feedback/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jurassic World Evolution</a>.</p>



<p>The IG team got exclusive looks at many titles during Gamescom 2025. Check out our other previews: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valor-mortis-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Valor Mortis</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/super-meat-boy-3d-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Super Meat Boy 3D</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hell-let-loose-vietnam-hands-on-preview-jungle-warfare-has-never-been-this-immersive-in-a-video-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hell Let Loose Vietnam</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-preview-reveal-harlowe-demo-exclusive/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Borderlands 4</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gaime-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">G’AIM’E</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/under-par-golf-architect-hands-on-preview/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japan's National Library Says Game-Key Cards Are Not Eligible For Preservation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/japans-national-library-says-game-key-cards-are-not-eligible-for-preservation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/japans-national-library-says-game-key-cards-are-not-eligible-for-preservation.1279620/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Gee, ya think?</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Raidou - GKC" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/c99fcacdec82f/raidou-gkc.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Ollie Reynolds / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Japan's <a href="https://www.ndl.go.jp/en/">National Diet Library</a> (or 'NDL', for short) is one of the biggest libraries in the world and, from the year 2000, began to obtain video game CDs and cartridges for preservation purposes.</p>
<p>According to an article from <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202508/48598">Famitsu</a> (thanks, <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/nintendo-switch-2-game-key-cards-not-eligible-for-preservation-by-japans-national-diet-library-officials-say/">Automaton</a>), however, the library does not consider the Switch 2's Game-Key Cards as 'proper' physical media and therefore will not be accepting them into its 9,600-strong catalogue of game titles.</p>
<p>It shouldn't <em>really</em> come as a surprise when you consider what Game-Key Cards are. As discussed at length since the Switch 2's reveal back in April, Game-Key Cards don't hold any data beyond a license to download a game title from the eShop.</p>
<p>Not only does this present potential issues regarding storage and the near-mandatory need to purchase SD Express cards, but it's also a huge risk to preservation efforts should the eShop ever suspend its functionality.</p>
<p>So yeah, no one's going to preserve a piece of plastic that has no meaningful data on it, right? But to be super clear, the NDL stated the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Since a key card, on its own, does not qualify as content, it falls outside of our scope for collection and preservation.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Seems about as clear-cut as you can get. Nintendo has recently been attempting to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/nintendo-sends-out-second-game-key-card-and-physical-game-survey">gauge interest in Game-Key Cards via customer surveys</a>, but at the time of writing has not made any moves to introduce more options for third-party publishers and customers alike.</p>
<p>Only a handful of third-party Switch 2 games have received a proper physical release, and according to a recent online listing, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/yooka-replaylee">Yooka-Replaylee</a> can <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/yooka-replaylee-appears-to-be-getting-a-proper-physical-release-for-switch-2">potentially be counted amongst the elite few</a>. An official announcement seems to be just around the corner, so we'll be sure to provide an update as soon as we hear more.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184691,183387 @ 1756128617 -->
<p><em>Does this come as even a remote shock to you? Leave a comment with your thoughts and let us know.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.famitsu.com/article/202508/48598" rel="noopener" href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202508/48598">famitsu.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://automaton-media.com/en/news/nintendo-switch-2-game-key-cards-not-eligible-for-preservation-by-japans-national-diet-library-officials-say/" rel="noopener" href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/nintendo-switch-2-game-key-cards-not-eligible-for-preservation-by-japans-national-diet-library-officials-say/">automaton-media.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/7124d34772d6d91385d63b31f17dc351 @ 1756126925 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/japans-national-library-says-game-key-cards-are-not-eligible-for-preservation]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater on Xbox Game Pass?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-on-xbox-game-pass.1279617/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater is bringing the neglected franchise back to life after a few years of dormancy, and we’ve got all the details on whether the title is available through Game Pass.</p>



<p>Releasing on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-release-date-start-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">August 28</a>, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-trophy-list-all-achievement-trophy-differences-in-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full achievement list for Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> shows details of the adventure that lies ahead of Solid Snake, though confirmation that<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eaters-multiplayer-mode-doesnt-have-crossplay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> the title doesn’t feature crossplay is a blow</a>.</p>



<p>If you’re on the fence about purchasing Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater and are wondering if it will be included in a Game Pass subscription, we’ve got all the details.</p>







<figure><figcaption>Almost time. Image via Konami</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No, Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater will not be available through an Xbox Game Pass subscription when it launches on August 28th.</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://www.konami.com/mg/mgs3r/eu/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> is not a first-party Xbox title, which would result in automatic inclusion in the service, and there has not been any announcement of it landing on the service. As such, it won’t be included.</p>



<p>Microsoft has already announced the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-august-2025-wave-2-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">second wave of August titles coming to Game Pass,</a> covering until the end of the month, and Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater did not feature. If it was, it would’ve been one of the highlights of the service, receiving a lot of attention.</p>







<p><strong>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater is unlikely to come to the Xbox Game Pass catalog in the future, and any inclusion would surely be quite far away.</strong></p>



<p>Virtuos, co-developer of Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater alongside Konami, has released several titles on the Game Pass service in the past, though the final decision with this title will more than likely fall upon Konami.</p>



<p>Konami’s publishing on Xbox is much more limited, and their titles barely ever feature in the Game Pass catalog, so it seems unlikely that Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater will make an appearance in the library anytime soon. However, stranger things have happened.</p>



<p>If you do want to play Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater on Xbox, the best approach is to purchase the game for launch.</p>



<p>Are you planning on picking up Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-review-embargo-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details of the review embargo</a>, and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-remake-original-mgs-snake-eater-3-differences-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">differences between the new title and the original</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-game-pass/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['On Borderlands 3, in Our Worst Hours, It Sometimes Felt Like Parody' — Gearbox Explains Borderlands 4's More Grounded Story]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/on-borderlands-3-in-our-worst-hours-it-sometimes-felt-like-parody-gearbox-explains-borderlands-4s-more-grounded-story</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/on-borderlands-3-in-our-worst-hours-it-sometimes-felt-like-parody-%E2%80%94-gearbox-explains-borderlands-4s-more-grounded-story.1279614/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">With <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/borderlands-3">Borderlands 3</a> and its divisive story in the rearview mirror, developer Gearbox Software is driving full speed ahead to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> and the totalitarian planet of Kairos.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The long road to the launch of a fourth mainline Borderlands game had a bumpy start. While plenty fell in love with Borderlands 3 and its improvements to the looter-shooter series' gunplay, others still struggle with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-narrative-director-remains-firm-in-his-criticism-of-borderlands-3s-overabundance-of-toilet-humor">its joke-fueled story and reliance on toilet humor</a>. It will have been almost exactly six years since its launch when Borderlands 4's September 12, 2025 release date arrives. Now, fans are on the edge of their seats, waiting to see how Gearbox spent its time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We caught up with Gearbox narrative director Sam Winkler, lead writer Taylor Clark, and managing director of narrative properties Lin Joyce to learn more about why the team decided to create a more grounded story for Borderlands 4. Along the way, we found out how the elusive Timekeeper can stand toe-to-toe with Handsome Jack, how controversial characters like Ava could still have a future in the series, and we even learned how the upcoming DLC will fit in with Borderlands 4's main campaign.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: Gearbox has been very clear that Borderlands 4 will feature a more grounded story and tone. How did the conversations to shift the tone begin, and is this the direction the team has followed from the beginning of development?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Sam Winkler:</strong> Those conversations started as early as the conversations of, 'Hey, what the hell does Borderlands 4 look like?' Even before Borderlands 3 was shipped and out the door. Something I like to remind people is that the devs are often the first fans of a game and also the first critics. I think that we had some own internal critiques about the tone and the level of humor present in Borderlands 3.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">[It's] something that we already were starting to address in the DLCs for Borderlands 3, but we wanted to really make that a central point of Borderlands 4. So, as we had these very large conversations of, in world context, 'Where is this? What does it mean? Why are we doing this next big, monolithic game with a 4 in its title?' [we said], 'How are we also going to evolve the storytelling, the humor, and the characters, and what we want to do with them?’</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Taylor Clark:</strong> I came aboard a lot later than Sam. I've been on the game for a couple of years, and it was definitely something from the moment that I came on board, when I was talking to Sam, the grounded tone was a priority. Grounding the humor in the world, he made it very clear that if I tried to put a meme in the game, he would come to my house with a baseball bat [laughs]. So, it was definitely in the brief from the beginning to make the tone fit the world.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler: </strong>I don't want to swing the needle too hard on that front. I am not anti-meme. In fact, hey, exclusive: There's a specific meme in this game, and I feel justified putting it in because I accidentally created it. Yes, I didn't mean for it to become a meme, but it became a meme, and it's in the video game. That is all I'm going to say.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: We can't know what meme it is?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> Look, I have a couple of Know Your Meme pages that credit me, and I will let you do any journalistic dirty work that you need to.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> It does not involve a Skibidi Toilet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> It does not. Yeah, there are toilets in our game. I'll say that.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> Where else would you get ammunition?</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> Exactly. In Borderlands, only toilets and washing machines.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: No Skibidi Toilets, though.</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark: </strong>No. No.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> None.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Borderlands 4 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: I think some people are going to be really happy to hear that. I'm wondering if you can compare the tone in Borderlands 4 to some of the previous games. It seems like the team definitely wanted to have a more grounded tone than 3, for sure. So, how would you compare the tone or joke frequency to something like 1, 2, or even spinoffs like Tiny Tina's Wonderlands?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> The way that I've always talked about it, personally, was that, in Borderlands 1, 2, and 3, we were on Pandora, right? Pandora was a wild west. It was a place where corporations were stabbing each other in the back for supremacy. So, there was a lot of antic energy in that place, and with those villains that we were dealing with, it made a lot of sense to have more zany, like, gun-slinging jokes, you know? Hip-firing jokes tone.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Kairos is a different place. Kairos is a totalitarian planet ruled over by this dictatorial figure known as the Timekeeper, who sits far above it all. In this context of global oppression, the Whac-A-Mole joke style didn't make as much sense. So, a lot of it had to do with making sure that the tone fit the stakes of the world, and that the humor was rising organically out of situations, out of character moments, rather than the wild west feel of the first games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Lin Joyce:</strong> I will let Sam talk to the contrast, too, in the mandate between 3 and 4, but I will double tap too, that what we were looking for is that the humor in Borderlands 4 works at the level of Kairos and the characters. We weren't making jokes that would only land for the player.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It was a gut check, 'Is this as funny to the characters and their lived experience as it is to the player? Can we do both?' That situational comedy and context helped us also keep the tone grounded, and the comedy then has purpose. But Sam can talk about the frequency between Borderlands 3 and 4.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler: </strong>I mean... I went back and played every single Borderlands game. 1, 2, Pre-Sequel, [Tales from the Borderlands], everything like that. Just to observe, not just the tone of humor, but also the vectors of humor, right? I think people talk a lot about our humor from the perspective of people chatting in your ear. But I was really struck by, for example, in Borderlands 1, most of the NPCs didn't have a ton of actual audio to say.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It was pretty sparse on that front, and a lot of the humor came out of situations. Comedic, usually darkly comedic, circumstances, but also the way things were named, the text in the mission accept, that sort of thing. I think that contributed a lot to players' perception of Borderlands 1 as having a more dark, grounded tone, is it is a quieter game, and a lot of the humor stems situationally and organically.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So, that was something that we tried to work with the design team, the mission design team, and everything like that, to say, 'Hey, we can have heavy moments. We can have grounded moments, but we can also have wacky circumstances that arise out of the players' actions and the NPCs that come at them.' We wanted to make sure that humor wasn't just some sticker that we're slapping on something, you know what I mean? The other thing is that, with design shifts, our mentality to humor had to shift as well. With Borderlands 4 going into this seamless, explore-to-your-own-tastes gameplay experience, we could not control where the player was going to go next.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We couldn't always script people's open-world exploration, [and] that allowed that space to just be naturally filled. Whether it's through combat dialog or player characters, or just silence and soundtrack and ambience and mood. It just inherently changed our approach to it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: One of my other questions is, 'Why should players who have been with the series for 16 years not be worried about this shift?' But I think that kind of answers it. It still feels and sounds like it's very Borderlands.</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> For sure. It is unmistakably Borderlands, but we're constantly tweaking the dials of certain factors to make the tone match the game that we want to create, and to respond to our internal and external feedback.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Joyce: </strong>At no point did we say, 'Let's stop being funny in Borderlands. Let's not do that anymore.' It is still a Borderlands game made by a Borderlands team, many who have been here since 1.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> We're not making an arthouse Borderlands game [laughs].</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> But, also, it's a big game, right? It is not a monolith. There are areas of our game that are more serious. There are areas of our game that are more humor-filled. There are characters that don't take things as seriously, in a diegetic way. For the players who have been long-time franchise fans, I think they're going to find flavors that they're looking for all across Kairos. If they play one side mission or interact with one character that doesn't quite vibe with them, there's probably another one not too far off that they will vibe with.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: For the sake of comparison, are there any other stories from across movies, books, TV, or games that the team feels are similar to the tone that you guys are going for? Are there any particular inspirations that you can point to?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Joyce:</strong> There have to be so many. We're constantly throwing around, 'Have you seen...? It's a little like that.' But now that you're asking it directly, I'm like, 'Which one...'</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> I don't want to use it as a straight comp, but a show that I've been really inspired by has been <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/star-trek-lower-decks">Star Trek: Lower Decks</a>, which is very, very much a comedic show. It has wacky energy to it, but it works, and it works really well — it just won a Hugo Award — because it takes its characters seriously. It takes its circumstances seriously, and if something is wacky, there's usually someone there to point out, like, 'This is wacky and super unsafe, and it shouldn't work that way.'</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It is a project that is clearly made out of love for Star Trek and the characters in the story, rather than some sort of parody of it. I think that on Borderlands 3, in our worst hours, it sometimes felt like parody, and that is where we edged into a red line, I think, for a lot of fans and for myself, personally. So, we wanted to look towards other media that could balance that. [That] could balance both humor, levity, and authentic character storytelling that takes itself seriously.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: One character I did want to ask about from Borderlands 3 that I didn't particularly mind at all but others had a problem with is Ava. She's a character that a lot of fans associate their dissatisfaction with Borderlands 3's story with. With so many other memorable faces back for Borderlands 4, can fans expect to see her show up, too? If not, is there any room for her to return in the future?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> I don’t think we’re going to answer any questions about characters that we haven’t shown off yet. I think the only thing that I will say is, I am not a huge fan of removing or killing off characters off-screen unless it absolutely has to happen. We don’t forget about characters, and we want to make sure that storylines are completed. That’s it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I hear all the complaints about Ava. I had some issues with how we were able to portray her. We were unable to show some of, I think, her more heartfelt moments in the base game of BL3. We used the Director’s Cut to show off what Maya’s funeral could have been and what the relationship between Ava and Lilith could have been. We didn’t have that opportunity in Borderlands 3, but it’s the kind of thing that I still believe in and that I would love to address again some other time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: In typical Borderlands fashion, Gearbox has free and paid post-launch DLC in the works. A lot of it, by the sounds of it. We don’t have to get too into specifics; I know a lot of that stuff is still very much in development. But will that same grounded tone carry over to the DLC? Will the team take the opportunity to show us some of the less grounded corners of Kairos?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> Just like the last question, I think we are limited in what we can say about the post-launch content that we’re working on. I think it’s safe to say that the plan is for the tone to be consistent between the products.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> I’ll say this: the best thing about Borderlands extra content, like full campaign DLCs, or some of the live events that we’ve done — we did the holidays and stuff like that in previous games — is it allows us to explore different tones and different corners of the Borderlands world and do different genres and everything like that. So, I would expect that same level of creativity and exploration from where we go in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Joyce:</strong> I would extend it to be... I would look at the DLC content and call it complementary, right? It complements the base game. It is going to be different, but complementary. Or, if you prefer a different metaphor, the pieces of attire will be coordinated to make a nice outfit, really. You pick which metaphor you like better there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> It’s tough to talk about in vague terms. We’d love to talk about it more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> Especially because some of it we don’t know yet. It is in active development. Borderlands 4 is getting stamped onto DVDs somewhere and... actually [laughs] I think it’s Blu-rays. But in the meantime, we are cooking on that next group of content, and we know a whole bunch of it. We’re actively working on it, but some of it is still in development.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: How long do you think it will take to complete Borderlands 4’s main campaign, and then how long will it take to complete the main campaign plus all of the side content?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> This came up some in prior interviews. The answer that I and Chris Brock, our lead producer, gave on this was to point out that, while we can't say a specific number, we can say that, when we got together to do a playthrough together — Sam, me, Lin, a bunch of others, our creative director, Graeme [Timmins], Randy Pitchford — when we were doing work, doing play throughs of this stuff, and to evaluate how it was going, playing through the entire main campaign took us days and days. It took a long time. It is a meaty piece of content.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> And that was a straight line. That was doing basically no side content.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> That was scaling damage to 10,000% and just mowing through stuff.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Joyce:</strong> The other anecdote I could probably give there, safely, is, I meet every week with Andrew Reiner, our global creative executive officer. Last week he said, 'I've started, I'm going to say, the million-teenth run of the game.' He's like, 'This time, the goal is 100% it.' I was like, 'How long have you been playing?' All week. 'How far have you gotten?’ Still in the first zone [laughs].</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> That's a very good factor, and going back to what I said, the seamless world allows players to have a little bit more choice about the order in which they take on the story. We have seen play testers want to go through the mainline, so they're bouncing around between the different zones and seeing all sorts of the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We've also seen testers who are just like, 'I'm going to go into this zone. I'm going to see everything I can possibly see. I'm going to scrape the barrel, and then I'm going over to the next zone.' One player's first 15, 20 hours could look very, very different from another player's.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: It's a big Borderlands game.</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> It do be big.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: For so many people, Borderlands villains are the reason a lot of folks show up for this series. Obviously, Handsome Jack is one of the all-time great video game villains. I'm wondering, because there are so many theories about the Timekeeper, specifically, and I don't want to know what it is, but does this character have any identity past that Timekeeper name? Is there some mystery, some intrigue you want to build up with him?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Joyce:</strong> You ask great questions [laughs]. To what degree can we answer them is a tough one.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> The Timekeeper is like an onion. He has layers... No one's used that before, right?</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> I think the answer is yes. Is there a mystery to him? Yes [laughs].</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Joyce:</strong> We could talk about, certainly, how we approached crafting him and writing him. That's another angle into answering your question. The timekeeper, one of the things that makes him different and keeps an air of intentional mystery around him, is that he is not in your face at all times. He sits in his high tower with a view of the entire planet, and his prerogative is to keep the entire planet under order.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, when we first show up, the Vault Hunter is mildly of interest, but he's got many other things to do. So, we also have to, as players, over time, gain his attention more and more. That was a very different way to approach writing a villain into a Borderlands game than we had done before. And I'll let Sam and Taylor run from there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> I think we, as creative people, are always challenging ourselves to not repeat ourselves, to have characters who are appreciably different, who have different kinds of stories and have different kinds of things to say in each entry. The Timekeeper is appreciably different from the prior villains in the Borderlands series. He is a new frontier, I think, as a character.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/24/borderlands-4-screenshot-timekeeper-1756016445955.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The Timekeeper in Borderlands 4. Image credit: Gearbox Software.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: One of the things I see pop up so often is comparisons to Handsome Jack. It always goes back to him. The theories go back to him. It's a bit mind-boggling, almost, at this point, to be more than a decade removed from that character, and still it's brought up. What kind of pressure does the team feel, if any, to continue creating villains as impactful as him, specifically? Did that pressure ever influence the direction you've taken for the Timekeeper?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler:</strong> Oh, I mean, how could it not, right? Imagine working on Star Wars, and you have to come up with something as scary as Darth Vader. Handsome Jack is a gaming icon, and I was a fan of Borderlands 2 before I set foot in Gearbox, so I had that thought in my head as well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Something I really, really liked about Borderlands 2 was, as you're going across Pandora, pretty much everyone you meet has been screwed over by Handsome Jack in some way. Their life is measurably worse, or they're under threat, or they know someone who died because of Handsome Jack. That was really inspiring for the Timekeeper, for us to be able to show a villain, not just through phone calls where he says, 'Hey, you're a dick,' while you're while you're going through trying to collect guns, but also how everyone you meet has, in some way, been affected by him and is living under his totalitarian rule.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Their circumstances are different and vibrant and their reactions to the Timekeeper... like they might be so scared of him that they don't want to rise up in resistance against him, or they might be so pissed off at him that they do, or they have a complicated relationship with the Timekeeper when they once kind of looked up to him, but now they are in danger because of him. With the goal of making this character feel a little bit more omnipresent, a little bit always watching, we wanted that to shine through in all of our NPCs. So, as we meet new friends — and each of these zones has this big over boss that we have to, ultimately, deal with, each of those villains has a different relationship with the Timekeeper. As we're learning about them, we're also learning about him.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: The Timekeeper will fall into place with that more grounded narrative. He's a lot more straightforward. He's not calling you while you're collecting guns and telling you, 'You're a dick.'</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> Not those specific words, no [laughs].</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: So, what is it about this character specifically that makes him the next great Borderlands villain? What makes him stand apart?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> I think that he has a gravity and an ominousness. Jack's animosity towards us is so hot and personal, and the Timekeeper, by contrast, feels so all-powerful and inescapable. Jack just feels like one kind of gnat who's really influential but could be swatted away. The Timekeeper feels chronic and insurmountable, like a mountain. This whole planet basically casts in his image, and I think that's a cool mountain to climb.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: We're just a few weeks out from launch. Did the decision to switch up the tone for Borderlands 4 pay off? Is Gearbox sitting here saying, 'This was worth it. We dialed everything correctly. We're proud of where this is.' Also, what were some of the challenges that the team faced when adapting to this change?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Clark:</strong> I'm personally proud of the work that we've done, and I think it's paid off. I think we struck a fun, resonant balance between light-hearted moments and serious, resonant moments. We get, for the first time, I think, we get real character depth with Claptrap, of all people, for example. One of my favorite missions in the game is an emotional moment with Claptrap that, I think, really hits hard, so I'm personally very happy with where we landed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Joyce: </strong>I agree. I think that we have succeeded with what we set out to do, and it’s even more than just about tone. This was about creating the next, right? You can come to Borderlands 4 as a new player, and this can be your first experience into an incredibly expansive world, and in that way, it needed to be fresh and have something new to offer and change perspective on our series while still maintaining that connectivity. So, if you’re a returning fan, we built Kairos for you. If you’re a new fan, we built Kairos for you. This was the goal. It took a really big world and a big game to do it. I think we succeeded there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winkler: </strong>I think it is going to be, ultimately, up to the fans to the fans, of course, to tell us if we nailed it or not, and I think that the best possible scenario is that we put this game out, they say, ‘This is what we wanted. Let’s go even further. We want more. We want more.’ I hope we get that opportunity. To echo what Taylor and Lin said, I’m very proud of the work that we did, and I think that we accomplished our goals, and the mark of success if being able to continue. Hopefully, we can continue, we can build back some of the trust, and yeah. Have a good one. Have a good video game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/on-borderlands-3-in-our-worst-hours-it-sometimes-felt-like-parody-gearbox-explains-borderlands-4s-more-grounded-story]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Skate Game Gets Official Cover Art And Early Access Release Date Teaser]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-skate-game-gets-official-cover-art-and-early-access-release-date-teaser/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-skate-game-gets-official-cover-art-and-early-access-release-date-teaser.1279602/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>EA’s long-awaited Skate sequel is in the works. We know it’s progressing well, and confirmation of this comes courtesy of the game’s X account, which has not only showcased its awesome cover art but also gone one step further and teased us with a tricky early access release date notice.</p>



<p>15 years—yes, FIFTEEN—years have come and gone since Skate 3. EA released one of the most popular skating games in history. Then capitalized on this by…doing nothing. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/eas-skate-does-not-have-an-offline-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Skate</a> fans have had to wait a long time for a new game, and even then, development on the new Skate title has taken several years. However, the updates are coming thick and fast, including news on its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/skate-promises-big-update-next-week-as-early-access-looms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">early access release date</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-skate-early-access-release-date-coming-very-soon">Skate Early Access Release Date Coming Very Soon</h2>



<figure><figcaption>We’re ready for the grind. Credit to EA</figcaption></figure>



<p>The official EA Skate <a href="https://x.com/skate" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X page</a> has shown off the stunning new Skate art. The vibrant and almost pastel-like cover is a clean and smooth image, and is all the game cover needed to be. It’s a win-win in my books.</p>



<p>But even more eye-catching is the news of Skate’s early access release date. While the X account hasn’t let the info slip just yet, we know it’s arriving imminently: <strong>August 26</strong>, to be exact.</p>



<p>“We’re stoked to reveal the official skate. cover art! Come back on Tuesday 8/26…we’re giving you the Early Access release date. See ya then,” said a post on Skate’s social media page.</p>



<div><article><p><span>We’re stoked to reveal the official skate. cover art! Come back on Tuesday 8/26…we’re giving you the Early Access release date. See ya then. 🛹 </span></p></article></div>



<p>You don’t have to wait much longer to find out when you get to finally tinker with your trucks, get your pads on, and Skate like hell. Let us know through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a> if you’re excited for a new era of skating games riding alongside each other.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/eas-skate-does-not-have-an-offline-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA’s Skate does not have an Offline Mode</a> and the latest on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-skate-microtransactions-range-from-e5-e99-in-closed-alpha/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Skate’s microtransactions</a> for more content.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-skate-game-gets-official-cover-art-and-early-access-release-date-teaser/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: So Just How Might These Third-Party Games Run On Switch 2?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/video-so-just-how-might-these-third-party-games-run-on-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-so-just-how-might-these-third-party-games-run-on-switch-2.1279590/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Let's test it</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>The announcement that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> would be making its way to the Switch 2 in <strong>2026</strong> came as a <em>very</em> pleasant surprise during the recent Gamescom festivities.</p>
<p>Whether you've played through the game before or simply seen the odd trailer here and there, we can probably all agree that The Great Circle looks pretty spectacular – particularly in its environmental design. So just how will a game like this run on the Switch 2?</p>
<p>Well, that's what our lovely video producer Alex is looking to find out. Using the Xbox Series S as a rough guide, he presents a hypothetical vision of what The Great Circle might look like on Nintendo's new system. He doesn't stop there though – oh no. He also checks out the following games:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-series-x/baldurs_gate_3">Baldur's Gate 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-series-x/doom_the_dark_ages">Doom: The Dark Ages</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-series-x/clair_obscur_expedition_33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-series-x/elder_scrolls_iv_oblivion_remastered">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a></li>
</ul>
<p>As Alex notes in the video, these are not outright predictions about which games will likely come to the Switch (beyond Indy, of course), but merely hypothetical glimpses into how they <em>might</em> run with the Switch 2's specs. It's not an exact science, but it should give you a flavour, at least.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186780,185781 @ 1756126908 -->
<p><em>Which of these games would you like to see on Switch 2? Do you think the footage represents an accurate depiction of their potential performance? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/video-so-just-how-might-these-third-party-games-run-on-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill f Producer Says the Game Is Not a Soulslike, and The Combat Mechanics Aren’t Exclusive to That Genre Anyway]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-f-producer-game-is-not-a-soulslike/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-f-producer-says-the-game-is-not-a-soulslike-and-the-combat-mechanics-aren%E2%80%99t-exclusive-to-that-genre-anyway.1279587/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Series fans were surprised to find out that Silent Hill f, the upcoming new chapter in KONAMI's horror franchise, had several action elements, like dodging and a stamina meter. Now that a lot of gameplay footage is out, some of them have labeled it akin to a 'Soulslike' game, but Game Producer Motoi Okamoto strongly rejected the notion in a Gamescom 2025 interview <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/these-things-arent-new-and-exclusive-to-soulslike-games-silent-hill-f-producer-wants-to-set-the-record-straight-on-combat" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">with IGN</a>.</p>



<p><em>This is one of the things that we see — the term soulslike — being thrown around on the internet quite a bit. And I think it’s a label that’s a little bit disingenuous. Modern players will see like, oh there’s a stamina meter, there’s a dodge, and they're like, ‘Okay, it’s a soulslike.’ But to be very honest, a lot of these things we actually pulled from classic Silent Hill titles. Look at Silent Hill 4 — there’s a charge meter for your attacks, kind of like our Focus meter. And even for Silent Hill 3 there's a stamina meter. You see it later on.</em></p>



<p><em>These things aren’t new and exclusive to soulslike games. They’ve been a part of action horror games for a very, very long time. If you have these things you’re labeled a soulslike. And we’d like to reiterate we are an action horror game, but we are not a soulslike.</em></p>



<p>The game developed by NeoBards Entertainment is coming out very soon, anyway, given its planned release date of September 25, exactly a month from today. It won't be long before we get our hands on Silent Hill f and decide for ourselves whether the game deserves that title, not to mention, more importantly, whether it respects the series' legacy. </p>



<p>As a reminder, the game is set in 1960s Japan, and Shimizu Hinako, a high-school student, is the protagonist. The story has been crafted by acclaimed Japanese writer Ryukishi07. You can read more about Silent Hill f <a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/silent-hill-f-everything-we-know-brand-new-chapter-konami-horror/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in our roundup article</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-f-producer-game-is-not-a-soulslike/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is The Hollow Knight: Silksong Review Embargo Date?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-the-hollow-knight-silksong-review-embargo-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-the-hollow-knight-silksong-review-embargo-date.1279584/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Hollow Knight: Silksong is nearly upon us, and all eyes are cast towards the review scores, and we’ve got the details on when the review embargo lifts.</p>



<p>Hollow Knight: Silksong <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">releases Sep</a>tember 4, and is included with an Xbox Game Pass subscription, with anticipation for the title reaching fever-pitch levels following the long-awaited release date announcement.</p>



<p>Whether you’re on the fence about playing or want to see how hyped everyone is for the launch of Hollow Knight: Silksong, here are all the review embargo details.</p>



<h2 id="h-hollow-knight-silksong-review-embargo-date-explained">Hollow Knight: Silksong Review Embargo Date, Explained</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Almost here. Credit to Team Cherry</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Hollow Knight: Silksong review embargo is expected to be September 4, when the game releases, with Team Cherry reportedly not distributing early codes.</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3lwwfrbrtwc2x" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Bloomberg’s Jason Schreier</a> stated that Team Cherry is not planning on sending out early codes for Hollow Knight: Silksong, so players should not expect to see any reviews until after the September 4 launch.</p>



<p>This is because the developers “felt like it’d be unfair for critics to be playing before Kickstarter backers and other players,” though they are also a small team and it would take a lot of time to get codes and distribute them, particularly given the amount of work that lies ahead before the release.</p>



<p>Therefore, players shouldn’t expect to see any reviews published until the September 4 release, and, even then, the first drop may not be a full reflection of the game and may be an in-progress review as journalists, like everyone else, push through to complete the game.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-hollow-knight-silksong-scores-can-we-expect">What Hollow Knight: Silksong Scores Can we Expect?</h2>



<p><strong>Hype for Hollow Knight: Silksong has been in overdrive for a while, and, given the success of the first game, expect to see the sequel rate very highly.</strong></p>



<p>Our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hands-on preview at Gamescom</a> resulted in a verdict that the title is well worth the wait, with no suggestion that Hollow Knight: Silksong will score poorly. In fact, it could end up being one of the most successful launches of the year, score-wise.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/hollow-knight/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Metacritic</a> for the original Hollow Knight is impressively high, with an average of 90 from critic reviews, while the user score, based on 4,321 reviews, puts the game at 9.1.</p>



<p>Though the first game set a very high bar, we expect Silksong to follow suit with some equally impressive numbers to establish itself as one of the must-play titles of the year.</p>



<p>How highly rated are you expecting Hollow Knight: Silksong to be? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Hollow Knight: Silksong, read <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/why-hollow-knight-silksong-took-so-long-to-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">why the game took so long to release</a>, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/can-you-download-the-hollow-knight-silksong-demo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whether a demo is available to download</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-the-hollow-knight-silksong-review-embargo-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>