<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:45:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons & Dragons: Heroes of the Borderlands Review - The Starter Set Everyone Deserves To Start With]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-heroes-of-borderlands-review-starter-set-everyone-deserves-to</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-dragons-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-the-starter-set-everyone-deserves-to-start-with.1292811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>With the continued popularity of <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3579fb91-ffa9-4c99-a750-de9f92ba642f" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a>, and how it's leaking out all over various forms of media and pop culture, every day, there's someone experiencing their first game of <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>. If no one in your group has played before there have been Starter Sets that are a decent place to start, but with the release of <em>Heroes of the Borderlands</em>, there's now a <em>best</em> place to start.</p>

<h2>What's In The <em>Heroes of the Borderlands</em> Box?</h2>

<p>Inside the <em>Heroes of the Borderlands</em> Box a DM will be able to find:</p>

<ul><li aria-level="1">Four Booklets: 1 for the basic rules (essentially taken from the<a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="56eebec3-a321-4403-b71c-54e4edf91d0c" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-5e-2024-dungeon-masters-guide-review-true-dms-best-friend" rel="nofollow"> 2024 DMG</a>), and three Adventure Booklets (One for the Keep, one for the Borderlands, and one for the Caves of Chaos)</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Character sheets for Cleric, Rogue, Wizard, and Fighter from levels 1-3 (including two different sub-class options)</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Game Cards for spells, equipment, magic items, NPCs, Monsters, and more</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Tokens to represent players, monsters, and unique terrain</li>
	<li aria-level="1">18 maps including overworld maps as well as battle and dungeon maps</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Handouts related to shopping locations and key NPC interactions</li>
	<li aria-level="1">A set of 11 dice (the core polyhedral set with one extra D20 and three extra D6)</li>
	<li aria-level="1">A pad of Combat Initiative Tracking sheets</li>
	<li aria-level="1">Four plastic ziplock sleeves (for keeping player cards together for extended games)</li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-box-contents.jpg?itok=OmS9W7aD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-box-contents.jpg?itok=oXUKgPrA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>I was blown away by just how much was in the box. Having learned to play D&amp;D myself with the Mines of Phandelver starter kit I was all too familiar with how much there can be to learn, how information can be spread all throughout the rules and adventure books, and trying to 'prepare' could have you pulling information from all over the place.</p>

<p>Splitting out all of the relevant information among cards, it creates a more component-heavy experience, but splits up the learning and the onus of having that knowledge among all of the players and doesn't just rely on the GM to take on everything.</p>

<p>The best way that I can think to describe it is that by making it more component-heavy, and tweaking things like the character sheet, they've 'board game-ified' Dungeons &amp; Dragons and created an experience that you could just pick up and run on a whim.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-cleric-character-sheet.jpg?itok=wYPSIAOj 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-cleric-character-sheet.jpg?itok=DvUXByjZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Including monster and terrain tokens alongside maps feels like a more sensible approach to an official way to start playing as opposed to purchasing a Starter Set and then also picking up something like a Campaign Case. This feels like the evolved form of them all.</p>

<h2>Creating Your Character</h2>

<p>The character sheet for <em>Heroes of the Borderlands</em> has been completely redesigned to be as beginner-friendly as possible and to work in conjunction with the card system that has been developed.</p>

<p>In front of the player, they'll be able to see each of their abilities and the modifying values (organized by stat and not alphabetically), stats such as speed, initiative, and HP, and their class features. To the right of their sheet, a player also has an indicated space for their species and background cards to be played.</p>

<p>Taking up the center of the card is space for players to place their equipment cards or stack up their spell cards. Within each of these spaces, you'll see recommendations for equipment as well as rules relevant to that space on your player board.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-character-sheet-wizard.jpg?itok=vqOBf1FD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-character-sheet-wizard.jpg?itok=2VlP8DEy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The last part of putting together your character is collecting the required health, ability, and gold tokens to have a visual representation of these components on your board. As a player, you likely won't ever need to pick up a pen to note something or keep track of your stats and abilities.</p>

<p>Placing your starting equipment on your player board, you can immediately understand the capabilities of your character, how to hit something or deal damage, how many uses you have of any ability, and understand how class features, species, and background can all work interchangeably.</p>

<p>Spellcasters have the added bonus of having cards for each of their spells. The back of each card features the full rules for a spell, while the front gives quick information such as the range and area of effect. For spells that call on a cone, or a magical effect in a range centered on the player, there's even a diagram showing you how it will work.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-spell-cards.jpg?itok=dfxh4IqQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-spell-cards.jpg?itok=fnnhyvBy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>These spell cards have already been getting pulled out again for my regular home games</figcaption></figure><p>While there will be a learning curve, going from this sheet to a normal character sheet or a digital D&amp;D Beyond sheet, for a beginner with no prior knowledge, this character sheet is clear and approachable.</p>

<p>The only part of this character sheet that I can really fault is the health tokens. Gold, which is spent less frequently, makes the exchange of tokens fun, and the ability tokens moving off or returning to the board is easy enough, but swapping out HP tokens can be a bit of a pain.</p>

<p>I would have loved to have seen some kind of sliding tracker. Letting you move a HP token up and down your maximum health bar for the side of the character sheet you were on. It would have saved some time swapping out a 5hp token for 3hp tokens, only for the character to drink a potion and need more tokens again.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-fighter-character-sheet.jpg?itok=zb_3ByAd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-fighter-character-sheet.jpg?itok=zPfkpJUy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Adventures At The Borderlands</h2>

<p>The new <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> Starter Set puts a party of four and their Dungeon Master in the Borderlands. This is an update of the setting from the 1979 <em>D&amp;D</em> adventure, <em>Keep on the Borderlands</em>. Time has moved on, and it's a good, setting-agnostic location to branch out and explore more of the world after getting comfortable with what's in the book.</p>

<p>In the Keep booklet, you'll have multiple locations for your party to visit in town. These can be roleplay locations, like the chapel or shops, to acquire new goods at. To further assist in shopping, you'll also find handouts for the different items on sale.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-adventure-and-rule-books.jpg?itok=vcFfK_nS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-adventure-and-rule-books.jpg?itok=d83b0jqy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Each location has an NPC to meet and an odd job that they might be recruited for. These jobs will test not only players' roleplaying skills, but also prompt them for a variety of skill checks. While simple, these checks serve as a built-in tutorial for what you can do with your different abilities.</p>

<p>The Wilderness book provides you with some random travel encounters. These are a mix of combat and roleplay, and it's also where you'll find the combat tutorials for players. Easing them into gameplay with a combat encounter on the side of a road.</p>

<p>The final book is for a series of caves that each act as a mini-dungeon with a theme. It might be goblins, cultists, spiders, or really any other staple Dungeons &amp; Dragons monster that inhabits them. Each adventure is a short series of rooms with combat and exploration so it's easy to get in and out of with very little notice.</p>

<p>There is definitely a downside to not having a planned and structured adventure like the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a96fb387-895f-4837-9061-7bbd56e12239" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/phandelver-and-below-shattered-obelisk-review-not-quite-sure-what-it-wants-to-be" rel="nofollow"><em>Mines of Phandelver,</em></a> but the upside is that <em>Heroes of the Borderlands</em> has more than enough content for planned mini-adventures and to teach all of the basics for a party to understand what kind of adventure they might be into before they set out on a larger adventure.&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-tutorial-for-dm.jpg?itok=YEBOfBm0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-tutorial-for-dm.jpg?itok=7Z8LUYoZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Dungeon Master Assistance For First Timers</h2>

<p>For a new DM running a game can be a somewhat daunting task. There's a few ways that I think this Starter Set tackles things fantastically.</p>

<p>The first is in the separation of the information across quick to reference cards. You'll reach a new place at the Keep, or a new dungeon, and the book will inform you of exactly what NPC cards, monsters, etc you'll need. You can keep them to the side, all with their relevant information, and you never need to be flipping through a book or trying to determine what to do next.</p>

<p>The other way that these adventures make being a DM easy is by maintaining a bite-sized approach. There isn't any grand story that will take the party from level 1-5, but there's roleplay to perform at the Keep, random encounters to have in the Wilderness, and then a plethora of caves that act as multi-room dungeons.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-random-encounters.jpg?itok=ABgLUbRd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-random-encounters.jpg?itok=JjS5FUTq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Because each encounter or setting has only about a page worth of information no matter where the party goes you'll never need to read much to stay ahead of them.</p>

<p>This bite-sized information also means that each session can be ~2 hours without needing much prep time, and the role of DM can rotate around the table. You might have DM'd for Caves A and G, but that doesn't mean you know what's going on in Cave E when it's your turn to be a player.</p>



<p>This box set is absolutely the way anyone new should be getting into D&amp;D. The massive benefits that this has is a large number of bite-sized adventures, a unique approach to character creation and stat tracking that creates a more casual experience, and the lack of a need to do any major prep.</p>

<p>The only recommendation I'd make for players is organize a different way to track health so that you aren't worrying about moving a whole bunch of health tokens around.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-dungeon-exploration.jpg?itok=yyzrK5jw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dd-heroes-of-the-borderlands-review-dungeon-exploration.jpg?itok=GOAOBzaY 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>By the nature of the shorter adventures and mini-dungeons you won't get the same sweeping narrative as you might in the other Starter Sets or full Adventure Books but by playing <em>Heroes of the Borderlands</em> with your friends you'll be able to solve the basic questions of finding out who wants to be the longer term Dungeon Master, and what type of adventure/playstyle you're most interested in.</p>

<p>Alternatively, <em>Heroes of the Borderlands</em> opens <em>D&amp;D</em> up to being a casual game night endeavor where any group of up to five friends can casually create some characters, and run through a micro-dungeon with next to no prep necessary.</p>

<p>While the cost has increased compared to previous Starter Sets it's well worth it with so many tokens, reference cards, and maps that you can continue to use time and time again.</p>

<hr><p><strong><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Heroes of the Borderlands</em> was reviewed with a copy provided by Wizards of the Coast over the course of 10 hours of gameplay - all photos were taken during the process of review.</strong></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-heroes-of-borderlands-review-starter-set-everyone-deserves-to]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planet Coaster 2 Sorcery Pack DLC Weaves a Spell on Your Park Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/planet-coaster-2-sorcery-pack-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/planet-coaster-2-sorcery-pack-dlc-weaves-a-spell-on-your-park-next-week.1292808/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Frontier has announced the Sorcery Pack DLC for&nbsp;<em>Planet Coaster 2</em>, promising hundreds of magical new scenery pieces, several new rides, and more for your park if you decide to pick it up.</p>

<p>Per a press release, the Sorcery Pack will add scenery pieces like castle spires, buttresses, gargoyle statues, and other sorcerous decorations, so if you want to give your park a mystical, magical angle, this is the DLC for you.</p>

<p>Additionally, you'll also get access to a brand new entertainer in the form of Vesper, who wanders the "winding alleys of the bustling town" that is your park, and new visual and sound effects have also been added for "even more immersion".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/planet-coaster-2-sorcery-pack-dlc-scenery.jpg?itok=xXghU6DS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/planet-coaster-2-sorcery-pack-dlc-scenery.jpg?itok=3jsczjJF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Planet Coaster 2</em>'s Sorcery Pack lets you create a truly magical park.</figcaption></figure><p>The Sorcery Pack DLC also adds five brand new rides for you to introduce to your park, and naturally, you can customize them with the new magical scenery if you like (although you don't have to!).</p>

<p>Two new coasters, the Outmax LSM Raid Coaster and Bike and Sidecar attractions, offer "adrenaline-pumping excitement" and "explosive acceleration" respectively, while the new Vector child coaster gives the kids something to do.</p>

<p>The Flying Theater is a new "immersive simulation experience" that gives your guests the chance to experience "truly soaring through the air", while Gale Force is a pendulum flat ride that will make your guests "feel every twist and tilt".</p>

<p>You can check out a trailer for the Sorcery Pack DLC for&nbsp;<em>Planet Coaster 2</em>, which should give you a sense of what the DLC will bring to your park should you choose to buy it, right here.</p>




<p>The Sorcery Pack launches alongside&nbsp;<em>Planet Coaster 2</em>'s seventh major update, which brings a new Challenge Mode to test you to your theme park management limits, as well as improved path-building tools and lots more.</p>

<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Planet Coaster 2</em>, it's the sequel to Frontier's&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/planet-coaster" rel="nofollow">2016 theme park management sim</a>, and as you'd expect, it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/planet-coaster-2-announced" rel="nofollow">brings a number of new features</a>, including a focus on waterpark attractions, new themes, and a new event sequencer tool for maximum guest engagement.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Planet Coaster 2&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2688950/Planet_Coaster_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10009610" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/planet-coaster-2/9PK5WS0HXQKQ" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. The Sorcery Pack launches alongside Update 7 on September 16th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/planet-coaster-2-sorcery-pack-dlc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turns out Hollow Knight: Silksong does have another difficulty mode, just not the one you probably want]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/turns-out-hollow-knight-silksong-does-have-another-difficulty-mode-just-not-the-one-you-probably-want</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/turns-out-hollow-knight-silksong-does-have-another-difficulty-mode-just-not-the-one-you-probably-want.1292805/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong_XIi8oj7.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong_XIi8oj7.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong_XIi8oj7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong_XIi8oj7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong_XIi8oj7.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Golly, that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> is a bit hard, 'ey? I'm not here to feed into that discourse right now, you've probably seen enough of that on Bluesky and in the comments of YouTube videos about the top 10 things you missed in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-walkthrough">Silksong</a>. No, instead I'm here to tell you that things could be much, much worse apparently, as it turns out an entire difficulty mode is hidden within the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-metroidvania-games">metroidvania</a> for you to unlock.
</p>
<p>
That might be music to the ears of those of you who are struggling a bit with the game (no judgement here, the game's tough). Unfortunately, this one isn't your tune, as the hidden difficulty mode actually makes the game harder, almost impossibly so. It's called Steel Soul mode, and the rules are pretty simple: "No reviving. Death is permanent." Great! Exactly what I want from a game where I've already died 10,000 times.
</p>
<p>
Unlocking the mode is, as discovered by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1n8d1xc/cheat_code_discovery_not_joke/">Reddit user Buttnugtaster</a> (no relation), monumentally easy compared to the rest of the game. All you have to do is head into the Extras menu, then input the following: up, down, up, down, left, right, left, right. You'll get a flash on the screen, and if you try to start a new save file you'll find Steel Soul as an option. I've checked this myself and it does work, and no, I did not start a new save. My experience of this mode will be entirely limited to watching someone inevitably attempt it at Games Done Quick.
</p>
<p>
While there is no easy mode in the game, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/teamcherry">Team Cherry</a> did <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksongs-first-patch-makes-some-early-bosses-slightly-easier-out-now-in-steam-and-gog-beta">outline an upcoming patch earlier today</a> that promises to make a few bits of the game like a couple of boss fights a smidge more forgiving. At least those of us who beat Moorwing already have bragging rights.

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/turns-out-hollow-knight-silksong-does-have-another-difficulty-mode-just-not-the-one-you-probably-want]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pacific Drive DLC expansion ‘Whispers in the Woods’ announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/pacific-drive-dlc-expansion-whispers-in-the-woods-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pacific-drive-dlc-expansion-%E2%80%98whispers-in-the-woods%E2%80%99-announced.1292781/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Kepler Interactive [53 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kepler-interactive">Kepler Interactive</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Ironwood Studios [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ironwood-studios">Ironwood Studios</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Pacific Drive [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pacific-drive">Pacific Drive</a></em> downloadable content expansion “Whispers in the Woods.” It will launch in 2025. <span id="more-990746"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the content, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3594760/Pacific_Drive_Whispers_in_the_Woods/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Return to the Zone and witness the rise of a group of Anomaly-obsessed fanatics in this terrifying new expansion to <em>Pacific Drive</em>.</p><p>“Whispers in the Woods” is a brand new story for you and your trusty station wagon. Available at any point after the first few hours of the game, this expansion takes you deep within a new and mysterious part of the Olympic Exclusion Zone’s forests. Marked with strange symbols and effigies, these woods are filled with new dangers and mysteries to uncover. Find and experience the power of Artifacts, each adding bizarre and inexplicable new effects.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong><a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> Their Story</strong><ul><li>Dig into a eight to 12 hour story for you and your station wagon, playable from within a new or existing save.</li><li>Embark on a fully voiced journey filled with a new cast of characters and additional side narrative to discover.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Learn Their Ways, Uncover Their Secrets</strong><ul><li>They have come to the Zone and left their mark. Travel into the whispering woods of the OEZ – a disturbing vision of the once familiar forests.</li><li>Explore new maps and junction types filled with strange altars and unique resources.</li><li>Adorn your car with their designs of new parts and cosmetics.</li><li>Encounter new anomalies and anomaly behaviors hidden beneath the dark canopy.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Find Their Artifacts, Embrace the Unknown</strong><ul><li>Unlock the power—and peril—of Artifacts, a new gameplay system featuring objects that create mysterious changes and effects to you and the world around you.</li><li>Carrying Artifacts increases the challenge you and your car will face, but they’re instrumental to your <a title="Genres > Survival [454 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>. How much risk are you willing to take?</li></ul></li><li><strong>And More</strong><ul><li>New Garage Stations to aid on your journey.</li><li>New Route Modifiers that change how you play.</li><li>New Garage Cosmetics to find and collect.</li><li>New Original Score from composer Wilbert Roget II.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Pacific Drive</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,324 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,177 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1458140/Pacific_Drive/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/pacific-drive" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>DLC “Whispers in the Woods” Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Pacific Drive: Whispers in the Woods | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cXRk1pFRgOc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/pacific-drive-dlc-expansion-whispers-in-the-woods-announced]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Accessory maker will pay Nintendo after showing illicit Switch 2 mockups at CES]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/accessory-maker-will-pay-nintendo-after-showing-illicit-switch-2-mockups-at-ces/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/accessory-maker-will-pay-nintendo-after-showing-illicit-switch-2-mockups-at-ces.1292778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<p>Nintendo also accused Genki of "extensive use of Nintendo trademarks" in association with their unlicensed products, a move that "exploit[ed] and appropriate[d] for [Genki] the public goodwill associated with... Nintendo Switch marks."</p>
<figure>
    <div id="caption-2069738"><p>
              The Switch 2 mockup Genki showed in a CES video ended up matching very closely with the final console as released.
                              </p>
                          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      The Switch 2 mockup Genki showed in a CES video ended up matching very closely with the final console as released.

              <span>
          Credit:

                      <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/pages/ns2_accessories" target="_blank">
          
          Genki

                      </a>
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>The lawsuit also dealt in part with conflicting reports that Genki may have had "unauthorized, illegal early access to the Nintendo Switch 2," as Nintendo put it. <a href="https://www.numerama.com/tech/1877968-la-nintendo-switch-2-se-devoile-en-avant-premiere-au-ces-2025.html">Media reports around CES</a> quoted Genki representatives asserting that their 3D-printed case mockup was based on early access to a real Switch 2 console. But the company later publicly backtracked, <a href="https://x.com/GenkiThings/status/1879642103267164639">writing on social media</a> that "we do not own or possess a black market console, as some outlets have suggested."</p>
<p>In their settlement, Nintendo and Genki simply note that "Genki represents and attests that it didn't obtain any unreleased Nintendo property or documents before the system's official reveal."</p>
<p>The public settlement document doesn't go into detail on the confidential "payment in an agreed-upon amount" that Genki will make to Nintendo to put this matter to rest. But the settlement outlines how Genki is barred from referencing Nintendo trademarks or even parody names like "Glitch" and "Glitch 2" in its future marketing. Under the settlement, packaging for Genki accessories also has to "make clear to consumers Genki’s status as an unlicensed accessory manufacturer" and not mimic the color scheme of official Switch 2 hardware.</p>


          
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/accessory-maker-will-pay-nintendo-after-showing-illicit-switch-2-mockups-at-ces/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Of 2024's Best Games Is Getting A Huge Horror Expansion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-2024s-best-games-is-getting-a-huge-horror-expansion/1100-6534553/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-of-2024s-best-games-is-getting-a-huge-horror-expansion.1292775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534553">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">My personal pick for 2024 Game of the Year was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pacific-drive/" data-ref-id="5000-572027">Pacific Drive</a>, a game that is hard to describe briefly. It's a game in which you upgrade and repair a station wagon that you drive through a very strange stretch of forest roads in the Pacific Northwest, known in the game as the Olympic Exclusion Zone. It's a game that, at different times, gave me feelings of Stalker, The X-Files, and Remedy's Control, with SCP-like weirdnesses lurking on the roads or in the woods. It wasn't exactly a horror game before, but thanks to its upcoming expansion, Whispers in the Woods, it will be one soon.</p><p dir="ltr">Whispers in the Woods is Pacific Drive's upcoming 8- to 12-hour expansion that gives it a haunting overhaul. It's the game's first "true expansion," Ironwood Studios founder and creative director Cassandra Dracott told me, following a number of patches and content updates since the game debuted in February 2024. It'll be playable from within the base game and focuses on a group of "fanatics" who are obsessed with the game's many <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/pacific-drive-anomalies-enemies-guide/2900-5089/">anomalies</a>.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="470242860" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466325,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Pacific%20Drive%20-%20Whispers%20in%20the%20Woods%20Expansion%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:167,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/pacific-drive-whispers-in-the-woods-expansion-trailer\/2300-6466325\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466325\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466325\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466325\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466325&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466325,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6534553&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;pacific-drive&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,adventure,survival&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;kepler-interactive,teyon,ironwood&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466325},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466325\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4564395-1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/yhE840Wx.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1757433600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="yhE840Wx" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Pacific Drive - Whispers in the Woods Expansion Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Back when I reviewed the game, it definitely creeped me out, so I've always felt like it was a horror game, but I learned that wasn't everyone's experience.</p><p dir="ltr">"[Pacific Drive] is a story about you and your car, and for some people, driving around in the woods is a very scary experience. But we didn't do a lot to intentionally build on that horror. We just wanted to build on the atmosphere," Dracott said. But the team at Ironwood was influenced by "<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-pacific-drive-pulls-off-being-unnervingly-spooky-and-relaxingly-chill-all-at-once/1100-6523113/">how scary the game was for some people</a>," leading to them taking this expansion much farther down that path. "And it felt very natural as well. Like, we built a very atmospheric experience [...] Our game is built on the familiar, right? We have this car. It is your car. You have your garage. It's your space, right? And it's very easy to start to question the safety of, like, 'How alone are you right now?'"</p><p dir="ltr">Dracott explained how the expansion adds a gameplay element called Artifacts, which are "mysterious objects that are left behind by this enigmatic group" that build on top of each other to create new experiences with each trip outside of the warm light of your garage.</p><p dir="ltr">"So it could be something like when you jump, your car horn honks, and we tell you what it is right away. But then you may get another one later that says when the car horn honks, your car takes damage, and they're important for the progression of the expansion, so they play a critical role in how you're making your way through the new areas of the DLC. But holding too many of them causes bad things to happen, and can draw the attraction of some less-than-positive things out in the Zone. And so we want to present players with this choice of, 'Which artifact do I take? Which one interacts with the ones that I already have? Is this too many? Do I want to push my luck?'"</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4563721-witw_screenshot_02.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4563721" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4563721-witw_screenshot_02.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4563721"></a><figcaption>The motives of the expansion's shadowy group will be explored in the horror DLC.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4563721-witw_screenshot_02.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The thing about the original game's anomalies is that they could be harmful and disruptive, but they were more or less naturally occurring elements of the game's weird woods. I wondered if, in the expansion, those types of encounters are being altered to reflect something more like a traditional horror game, such as chase sequences or true "enemies," rather than anomalies that may spell doom, but did so without malice or intention.</p><p dir="ltr">"From a high level, we aren't changing up the structure of how we deliver narrative. So, you know, we are introducing new voiced characters into the game, but they are voices, right? Like that is the primary way that we communicate. We're not reinventing the wheel there--pardon the car pun. But, but there is something out there, and what that is and how alone you really are, I think that's something to leave to the players when they get a chance to check it out. But yeah, I think you're picking up on the right questions."</p><p dir="ltr">Given that some players played Pacific Drive like me--already a bit creeped out--Dracott explained how the team sought to lean into a new-ish genre without abandoning the core gameplay "verbs" of Pacific Drive.</p><p dir="ltr">"I've always been fascinated with any horror that takes something that is comfortable and shifts it," Dracott said. "Comfort is the thing you want to mess with when you start to introduce these elements that can make you nervous, make you afraid, make you not expect the thing that may happen. But at the same time, we do want to change up some of the systems, because we want the players to engage with the game slightly differently, but we're pretty careful about that."</p><p dir="ltr">Dracott said a new anomaly called Harvestmen is a good example of how Whispers in the Woods will walk that line between tweaking older systems and building in new ones.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4563722-witw_screenshot_bonus_04.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4563722" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4563722-witw_screenshot_bonus_04.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4563722"></a><figcaption>If, like me, Pacific Drive already creeped you out before, Whispers in the Woods should only be more unnerving.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4563722-witw_screenshot_bonus_04.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">"[Harvestmen] are part of the resource economy in the expansion, and so you <em>have </em>to go and engage with them," she said. "There is no other way to get the resources that they are connected to. We really did want to double down and focus on saying, 'Okay, let's create some anomalies where the player <em>has </em>to go and engage with them.' And so in that sense, we did change [the game's loop]. And that's a positive change because the car is a story generator. 'Did I forget to put it in park? Is it rolling down the hill?' But the anomalies are multiplicative on that. So, 'Is the abductor grabbing my car and pulling it along? Do I have a leech that is making my lights do funny things?' There are all kinds of different ways [it can go]. So by pushing the player towards anomalies directly, we spice that up. We add more opportunities for those stories."</p><p dir="ltr">Dracott left me to consider who those cloaked figures in the trailer may be, and the broader story implications of driving in the Olympic Exclusion Zone with the sudden emergence of threatening cultists, but I'm happy to make sense of that story myself when the expansion releases later this year. Pacific Drive <em>wasn't</em> a horror game, at least not definitively. <em>At least not until now.</em></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-2024s-best-games-is-getting-a-huge-horror-expansion/1100-6534553/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battle Suit Aces, The Latest From Battle Chef Studio Trinket, Launches Its Mecha Card Battle Action This October]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/09/09/battle-suit-aces-the-latest-from-battle-chef-studio-trinket-launches-its-mecha</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battle-suit-aces-the-latest-from-battle-chef-studio-trinket-launches-its-mecha-card-battle-action-this-october.1292772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>It's almost time to shuffle up and get in the robot. <em>Game Informer </em>can exclusively reveal that Battle Suit Aces, the new mecha card-battling game from Trinket Studios, will arrive on October 7 for PlayStation 5, Switch, and PC.</p><p>Trinket Studios made a splash with <a href="https://gameinformer.com/games/battle_chef_brigade/b/switch/archive/2017/11/20/battle-chef-brigade-review.aspx">2017's Battle Chef Brigade</a>, which mixed side-scrolling action with a match-3 puzzle system to portray a fantasy cooking competition. Similarly, Battle Suit Aces also blends several genres and concepts; in a card-fighting RPG, you follow the USS Zephyr and its crew through a planet-hopping voyage across the stars to try and stop a looming, universe-endangering threat.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZhKcqp1oxG4"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZhKcqp1oxG4" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Card battles play out on a board, where you can deploy your team of mechs, pilots, and drones to combat the enemy, trying to strike through their lines and destroy their base before they do the same. Between missions, you'll be able to recruit and get to know your crewmates, as well as upgrade their mech suits.</p><p>Trinket is planning numerous story missions driven by both the plot and your recruited cast of characters, as well as a story influenced by the factions you support and the relationships you build. Different Factions can also help you lean into your chosen playstyle, too, opting for specific methods of crushing your enemies with your small army of pilot pals and giant mecha.</p><p>No word on exact pricing just yet, but Trinket Studios has confirmed it will launch Battle Suit Aces on PlayStation 5, Switch, and PC via Steam.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/09/09/battle-suit-aces-the-latest-from-battle-chef-studio-trinket-launches-its-mecha]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Author Immortal Is A Metanarrative Isekai Comic That Explores The Messiness Of Separating The Art From The Artist]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/the-author-immortal-image-comics-interview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-author-immortal-is-a-metanarrative-isekai-comic-that-explores-the-messiness-of-separating-the-art-from-the-artist.1292769/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In “Planetary Consciousness,” Alan Moore’s introduction to the 2000s DC comic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planetary_(comics)" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Planetary</em></a> by Warren Ellis, the legendary author didn’t just herald a new era of comics—he forecasted a shift in their audience. “The underlying human tastes and audience demands on which we built the comic field have altered in the flux of things, within the readership if not within the books themselves. The way people think and see things has moved on. The massive scaffolding of values where the comic field was raised seems now deserted, seems redundant,” he wrote. Moore argued the medium’s evolution had stagnated, stuck in reverence for idols and stories that once redefined the 20th century. While many creators looked backward for answers, Moore praised <em>Planetary </em>as a rare comic book work that embodied the future by daring to interrogate the medium’s mythology while offering a blueprint for what storytelling could become in the new millennium.&nbsp;</p><p>Yet, hindsight, as it’s wont to do, complicates legacy.&nbsp;</p><p>Moore’s prolonged endorsement of <em>Planetary</em>—a comic nevertheless worthy of its accolades—sits uneasily beside the controversy surrounding its writer, Warren Ellis. In 2020, Ellis, who’d written for Marvel, DC Comics, and Netflix’s <em>Castlevania </em>series, was <a href="https://gizmodo.com/warren-ellis-responds-to-accusation-backlash-im-at-the-1847173837?utm_source=gizmodo.com&amp;utm_medium=link&amp;utm_campaign=share" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">accused</a> of a myriad of alleged sexual predatory behaviors by a group of<a href="https://somanyofus.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> 60 people</a>. Although Ellis later <a href="https://gizmodo.com/warren-ellis-accusers-respond-to-his-image-comics-retur-1847159513" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">returned to the comic book industry</a> the following year at Image Comics, the question still lingers: Can we truly separate the art from the artist when the art continues to shape us?</p><p>The conversation has shifted, as Moore predicted: Readers now struggle to separate the art from the artist as formative creatives like <a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/neil-gaiman-allegations-controversy-amanda-palmer-sandman-madoc.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Neil Gaiman</a> and <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/entertainment-arts-64729304" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">J.K. Rowling</a> spark debates. Former <em>Destiny </em>writer <a href="https://www.atlasincognita.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Frank Barbiere</a> (<em>Five Ghosts</em>) and <a href="https://morganbeem.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Morgan Beem</a> (<em>Swamp Thing: Twin Branches</em>) confront this tension head-on in their new Image Comics series, <em>The Author Immortal</em>.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Image Comics</span></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://imagecomics.com/press-releases/new-ongoing-fantasy-series-the-author-immortal-to-explore-the-legacy-impact-of-storytelling-this-october" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Author Immortal</em></a><em> </em>tells the tale of Hector Ramire, a failed writer who stumbles upon the chance to reboot a formative fantasy children's book as its co-writer after its original author, Vossler, mysteriously disappears. After discovering that the previous author was spirited away into his own fictional world, Hector and his child, Al, are pulled into the book <a href="https://gizmodo.com/studio-mappas-anime-about-making-anime-is-a-surprisingly-refreshing-isekai-2000546889?utm_source=gizmodo.com&amp;utm_medium=link&amp;utm_campaign=share" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">isekai-style</a>. While figuring a way out, they must reckon with the sprawling world of living characters who don’t want their stories changed.&nbsp;</p><p>In a world where A.I. threatens to hollow out the soul of storytelling, stories are treated as disposable content with the sole purpose of printing infinite money, and formative creators’ fall from grace forces readers to decide if the art is ever truly separate from them. Beem and Barbiere endeavour not to provide a tidy answer, unpacking artistic messiness one issue at a time. Aftermath spoke with Barbiere about how he and Beem went about approaching their new comic and exploring a subject looming over not just comic books, but every facet of creative works.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Penning <em>The Author Immortal</em> was a homecoming for Barbiere to the comic book industry after spending his time with games as a lead writer at Skydance Interactive, writing stories for <em>Darksiders Genesis </em>and <em>Ruined King: A League of Legends Story</em>. While writing a story about writing stories isn’t novel, Barbiere found himself compelled to find his own ground with a metafiction comic that moved him like Mike Carey's artist Peter Gross’ Vertigo comic, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Unwritten" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Unwritten</em></a>—one of his favorite books of all time—had. However, Barbiere didn’t want to settle for making a poor man’s version of <em>The Unwritten</em>, but to put a spotlight on the eroding trust of stories with readers.</p><p>“It really began with what I think is—forgive my grandiose wording—a generational wound around fallen or cancelled authors of my generation. There are certain people, obviously, <a href="https://aftermath.site/harry-potter-jk-rowling-cge-codenames-board-game" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">J.K. Rowling</a> is the biggest target, <a href="https://www.wired.com/2013/10/enders-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Orson Scott Card</a> was a big one as well for a lot of people, and presently Neil Gaiman,” Barbiere said. “This idea that these works that resonate so deeply with often smaller, queer communities who are typically not serviced by mainstream comics—especially when speaking of Gaiman—but also people who love fantasy and grew up with these books.</p><p>“Seeing the, quite honestly, heel turn and disgusting behavior of a lot of these people has created a huge rift, I think, in trust of fiction for my generation where it’s, ‘Oh my gosh, these books we believed in that we thought were organic and really spoke to the heart. If their writers are turning out to be these people, what does that mean for the work? What does that mean for me?’” Barbiere said.</p><p>Barbiere has no illusions that <em>The</em> <em>Author Immortal</em> will provide a catch-all solution to readers navigating these muddy waters. “The real goal for stories is for human beings to explore scenarios outside themselves to learn. Basically ‘virtual reality.’ It’s supposed to be a safe space where we can explore different feelings, personas—anything that is not real, and learn from it,” Barbiere said. “That really inspired but saddened me, considering how so many things have gone wrong and how little trusted stories are.”</p><figure><figcaption><span>Image Comics</span></figcaption></figure><p>Barbiere likened this current phenomenon to an <a href="https://comicbook.com/comicbook/news/surprisingly-honest-hobbit-featurette-explains-what-went-wrong/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">article headline</a> in which director Peter Jackson admitted that <em>The Hobbit</em> wasn’t his best work, which Barbiere called readers relishing tearing down the film trilogy as a validation for their distrust of the creator for being inauthentic and commercial. It’s a sentiment Barbiere senses has gotten all the more exacerbated by the pervasiveness of A.I. encroaching upon creative spaces.&nbsp;</p><p>“‘Can I even trust what I’m reading was written by a human?’That general anxiety led me to want to tell a story to reaffirm what stories are for, what they can do for you, how you can believe in them, and how they’re useful,” he said. “But, in doing so, we need to show the negative up front.”&nbsp;</p><p>Barbiere explains that <em>The Author Immortal</em> confronts its charged topics by showing how even a portal fantasy world isn’t immune to the corruption of real-world problems. Within this realm where teethy ink monsters menace on its readership, Hector and his nonbinary teen, Al, grapple with the lingering influence of stories whose narratives continue to shape their lives long after they’ve been bookended.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Image comics</span></figcaption></figure><p>This tension crystallizes around Hector’s co-writer on Vossler’s work, a popular author named Miss Luckwell who is a thinly veiled analogue of a cancelled author in the vein of Rowling. Hector’s offer, while a blank check out of poverty, is uncomfortably fraught for Al. Not only does Hector agreeing to work with Luckwell feel like it’s an endorsement of the Rowling-esque character’s invalidation of Al’s queer existence, as Al wastes no time to point out, but Al is named after Alethea, the protagonist of Vossler’s series that Hector is charged with rebooting.</p><p>“Hector is a character who named his kid after a [character]&nbsp; from a novel, and I'm just so taken by the amount of people I know who have named their kids <em>Game of Thrones</em> characters or, God forbid, <em>Harry Potter </em>characters now,” Barbiere said (making me grimace at my own flirting with naming my future child after Petrichor from <em>Saga</em>). “I was so fascinated by this mega fan who grows into an adult and [tries] to share with his kid his love for this thing that he names them after, and just the irony that [Al doesn’t] care.”</p><p>For Al, the whole arrangement is a personal affront and betrayal by their father, forcing them to confront the painful legacy of a story headfirst by being inside of it and proposing changes to its heroes, who don’t want to surrender control.</p><p>“The story explores the idea of what if you’re ready to move on from certain stories, but they’re not done with you yet,” Barbiere said. “I think we’ve got a little blatant in some of the marketing where it’ll be like ‘some stories will kill’ and very intense things like that, but it really does come from that generational anxiety I feel where we can’t trust people who’ve written works that affect us, and what that means for the future of storytelling.”&nbsp;</p><p>Much of the comic’s central tension is embedded in its title—a deliberate double entendre that Barbiere sees as both ironic and provocative. On one hand, it nods to the notion of “the death of the author,” questioning whether a work truly belongs to its creator once it’s released into the world. On the other hand, it interrogates the idea of artistic immortality itself. Can an author ever wholly vanish from their work, or will their presence linger, haunting its narrative, reception, and legacy long after they’ve passed—inversely allowing the author to live forever, even in infamy? Or perhaps a secret third thing where self and work are redefined by Hector and the characters in <em>The Author Immortal</em>, becoming the authors of their own stories.</p><p>No matter what readers take away from <em>The Author Immortal</em>’s title, Barbiere admits it still gives him a chuckle since it reminds him of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6kZBJs527-k&amp;pp=ygUTMzAgcm9jayBydXJhbCBqdXJvcg%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>30 Rock</em>’s “Rural Juror” gag</a>. He’s also grateful he locked in after a quick SEO search confirmed no one else had claimed it for a comic, so that designer <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/sievish.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sasha Head</a> could make a beautiful logo on the cover of their comic, and letterer<a href="https://leagueofcomicgeeks.com/people/27980/hassan-otsmane-elhaou" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Hassan Otsmane-Elhaou</a> could give the words that encompass its personality life.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Image Comics</span></figcaption></figure><p>On the subject of art design, Barbiere and Beem spoke highly of one another, with Barbiere calling Beem's art a constant inspiration and Beem, in turn, praising Barbiere’s ability to write flawed, real characters for her to play around with through her titular, dreamlike watercolor art throughout the comic. After reaching out to Beem, remembering her work on <em>Swamp Thing</em>, Barbiere’s idea for <em>The Author Immortal</em> expanded from a straight fantasy to a tale that more confidently explored a character-focused take on its premise. Along the way, Barbiere recalls answering Beem’s creative prayers coming off Sarah Miller’s YA book <em>You Belong Here</em>, to depart from drawing so many hallways and characters in an otherwise great book and “have some fun with monsters or something crazy.”</p><p>“Morgan's character acting on the page is phenomenal,” Barbiere said. “Some people struggle when they get into [comic book writing] because if they overly visualize, the art can look wrong to them. I love just being surprised and, without sounding narcissistic, so much of Morgan's acting makes me laugh on the page and makes me smile. She really brings it to life. It's been such a joy and inspiration to me. It really does help me find the characters when we see them, and I see their acting and how Morgan renders them, and just the amount of design she's doing on the page.”</p><p>Barbiere notes that many fellow <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creator_ownership_in_comics" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">creator-owned authors</a> fall into the trap of hastily jumping into action in the first issue trade, rather than allowing the story to develop and unfold naturally. With <em>The Author Immortal</em>, it was paramount for Barbiere to do justice to establishing its characters and world instead of blitzing toward its anime-esque isekai gimmick.&nbsp;</p><p>“There's a version of this book where they get isekai’d on page five and immediately thrust into the fantasy world,” he said. “I wanted to really take our time, set up the characters, but keep it urgent enough that it’s not just like ‘We see 10 years of their lives before we jump in.’”</p><p>Thankfully, <em>The Author Immortal</em>’s first issue being 40 pages, Barbiere says, allows him and Beem to give readers time to understand who the characters are without languishing in a setup before its big cliffhanger grabs readers to its story. Should the series catch fire, Barbiere assures prospective readers he and Beem have issue four already wrapped up to keep the story going for as long as folks want to read it.&nbsp;</p><p>“I’m very thankful that we have so much that we don’t even really get to in the first five issues that we’re ready to get to in the next arc—a lot of cool world building and history those first five pages flashing back to Vossler hint at,” Barbiere said. “We hope people are excited to find out about it.”&nbsp;</p><p>In a market flooded with legacy sequels and algorithm-friendly nostalgia, Barbiere and Beem’s book asks a bigger question: Who do stories truly belong to—the author’s catharsis or the reader’s transformation?</p><p>“‘What does it mean to have a story that changes your life?’” Barbiere said. “I think it’s something that people say very casually or talk about in hyperbolic ways, but we want to show characters who that actually happened for, for good and bad, and learn to recontextualize [those stories’ authors] in terms of ‘Am I doing damage with this? Is my obsession with trying to be famous or trying to leave behind work that is going to hopefully live beyond me a good thing or a bad thing? Have I indirectly blessed or cursed someone with it?’ And then, also fictionalizing it: ‘Can this be weaponized through magic? Can this be weaponized through the collective unconscious? What does that look like?’”</p><p>“That's the stuff that drives me as a creator and something that very much has been, I think, on everyone's mind. Looking at some of the modern thoughts on Death of the Author, what does it mean that we have work we want to divorce from creators? Do we abandon it? Do we continue it? What can we take from it? It’s different for every single person,” Barbiere said. “Our book does not offer answers to these difficult questions as much as explore them and, hopefully, characterize them, because it’s not gonna be me finger-wagging at you to act one way or another. But I think having that as the spine of our book and this idea of legacy in the dimension of creative work in children, in terms of how you affect the world you leave behind, is really fascinating.”&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Image Comics</span></figcaption></figure><p>Barbiere hopes that <em>The Author Immortal</em> will prove to be a work that signals a ripple effect, not just for the reader, but for the industry at large, which decides what stories get told and what stories get buried. As a creator who was burned out doing a lot of books, who was scripting video game narratives and comic book tales as dream projects before it all started to homogenize into a mechanical job where he’d have to pitch new ideas every four months, Barbiere said <em>The Author Immortal</em> was an opportunity for him to take a chance on writing something new that endeavors to tell a tale all his own without regurgitating the echoes from those that came before.</p><p>Barbiere compared the experience of writing a metanarrative tale about making art to that of a touring band’s second album, which often reflects the band's experiences on the road and the wildness of their lives. Barbiere hopes <em>The Author Immortal</em> comforts readers afflicted by how they should navigate appreciating or abandoning a work when the faults of their creators overshadow the merit of their creation’s messaging. All the better for it if it catches the eye of lapsed fantasy comic book readers in a sea of big-tent superhero legacy comic series.&nbsp;</p><p>“I hope the book succeeds, but I hope it shows that there's more space here, like that's what I love about working at Image and love a lot about smaller publishers who are taking a chance on genres that didn’t necessarily do as well in the direct market. There were years when people said you can't do sci-fi, you can't do westerns, or you can't do romance, but I think we've hopscotched past that,” Barbiere said. “I'm hoping that we can fill that void and live in that literary fantasy corner that a lot of mainstream books don't have, and certainly, don't do monthly anymore. Remind people that there's an audience for that, and, hopefully, capture some lapsed comic readers who maybe came in with <em>Saga </em>or <em>Monstress </em>back when Image was really bringing things out and give people an opportunity to come in on the ground floor.”</p><p><em>The Author Immortal</em> releases in local comic book shops as well as digital platforms on October 1.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/linda-bae-doona-gkids-james-iha"><h3>Linda Linda Linda Is Good Good Good</h3></a><p>Like a rat, I want to be beautiful, because there’s a kind of beauty that can’t be photographed</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-silksong-launch-gta-vi-elden-ring"><h3>All-Consuming Event Releases Like Silksong Are Growing Fewer And Further Between</h3></a><p>"Silksong and then GTA VI coming up are the two big launches that almost feel like the end of the big launch"</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/football-manager-26-fm26-sports-interactive-womens-league-wsl-nwsl"><h3>More Sports Games Should Take A Year Off</h3></a><p>It gives you the time to, for example, add around 35,000 new players to a game</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/play-for-peace-bundle-palestine-aid-fundraiser"><h3>10 Months In The Making, Play For Peace Bundle Launches To Raise Money for Palestinian Aid</h3></a><p>‘It was important that our charity's proceeds directly went to Palestinian relief efforts’</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/oxo-rapid-brewer-coffee-espresso-soup-shots"><h3>The OXO Rapid Brewer Is Great For Coffee And Better For ‘Soup’</h3></a><p>The OXO Brew Rapid Brewer is a fantastic portable coffee brewer. But coffee nerds are pushing it to its limit with 'soup' shots.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/the-author-immortal-image-comics-interview]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo's Pikmin Invade London This Month For A Special Trafalgar Square Mission]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/nintendos-pikmin-invade-london-this-month-for-a-special-trafalgar-square-mission</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendos-pikmin-invade-london-this-month-for-a-special-trafalgar-square-mission.1292751/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Bloomin' heck!</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Pikmin" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/d9754b95c5527/pikmin.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo / Niantic</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>London's Trafalgar Square will play host to some interactive Nintendo-themed fun this September 21st when <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/pikmin">Pikmin</a> arrive as part of the capital's <a href="https://japanmatsuri.com/">Japan Matsuri</a>, an annual celebration of Japanese culture in the UK.</p>
<p>Nintendo is encouraging any and all visitors to Japan Matsuri to bring along their phones and boot up <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pikmin_bloom">Pikmin Bloom</a> to take part in a special in-app challenge. Once at Trafalgar Square, a special <em>walking mission</em> will be activated in your game (well, that IS what the game is all about, after all), with the reward of an in-app Gold Seedling that'll net you a (semi-)exclusive Decor Pikmin for all your real-world efforts.</p>
<p>This is the first year that Nintendo has had a Pikmin booth at the event, and it'll also (according to the press release), offer "a variety of special Decor Pikmin seedlings, including a Mario Hat Pikmin and the elusive Fortune Pikmin normally available only near shrines and temples in Japan, which can be collected in app by walking to predefined areas within Trafalgar Square."</p>
<p>As well as the main walking challenge within Pikmin Bloom, the stall itself will also have an AR photobooth, where you get to capture a photo and video with some Pikmin for a digital souvenir. Hooray!</p>
<p>For those taken with the idea, Pikmin Bloom is free to download from both the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/pikmin-bloom/id1556357398">Apple App Store</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nianticlabs.pikmin&amp;pli=1">Google Play Store</a>, and leading into the London event from 9th-30th September, you can ‘Walk Together with Japan Matsuri’ in a Pikmin Bloom Party Walk in-game.</p>

<p>Oh, and before we go, the most important information! The Pikmin Bloom Special In-App Challenge will take place at the following place and time, so make sure to get to it if you want to take part:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Location: London Trafalgar Square, North Terrace</strong></li>
<li><strong>Date: Sunday September 21st, 2025</strong></li>
<li><strong>Time: 10am – 8pm</strong></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><em>Will you be heading to London for Japan Matsuri? Make sure to let us know!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-mobile/related-articles:169092,153483,134332 @ 1757435477 -->
</section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/nintendos-pikmin-invade-london-this-month-for-a-special-trafalgar-square-mission]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Circana Reveals Best-Selling PlayStation Games of All Time]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/circana-reveals-best-selling-playstation-games-of-all-time</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/circana-reveals-best-selling-playstation-games-of-all-time.1292748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It's the original PlayStation's 30th anniversary today (for the US release, at the very least), and US sales analysis firm Circana has compiled a list of the brand's best-selling games since 1995 by way of celebration.</p>

<p>As always, we have the ever-reliable Mat Piscatella to thank for sharing this data on social media platform <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lyftys4rhk2u" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Bluesky</a>, and the list he's compiled is an interesting one, although you probably won't be too surprised by a lot of the names you see.</p>

<p>Obviously, eternal moneyspinner&nbsp;<em>Grand Theft Auto V&nbsp;</em>tops the chart; it is, after all, a release that spans three PlayStation <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/grand-theft-auto-v-ps5-and-xbox-series-details-revealed" rel="nofollow">generations</a>, and given the massive popularity of&nbsp;<em>Grand Theft Auto&nbsp;</em>as a franchise (as well as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/grand-theft-auto-v-has-sold-over-195-million-units-red-dead-redemption-2-at-61-million" rel="nofollow">previously-reported sales figures</a> for the game),&nbsp;<em>GTA V</em>'s presence probably won't shock you.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/grand-theft-auto-v-playstation-top-selling-games-30th-anniversary.jpg?itok=ndeqnTh8 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/grand-theft-auto-v-playstation-top-selling-games-30th-anniversary.jpg?itok=FsekQJV6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Surprise surprise,&nbsp;<em>Grand Theft Auto V&nbsp;</em>is PlayStation's best-selling game of all time.</figcaption></figure><p>According to Piscatella's data, there are no games from the original PlayStation era on the top 20 list, and only three were released on the PlayStation 2. Two of those are&nbsp;<em>GTA&nbsp;</em>titles as well, namely&nbsp;<em>San Andreas&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Vice City</em>, while the third is&nbsp;<em>Guitar Hero III: Legends of Rock</em>.</p>

<p>All of the others are PlayStation 3 releases or later. In second place, it's <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/call-of-duty-modern-warfare" rel="nofollow">the 2019 version</a> of&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare</em>, with third place going to&nbsp;another Rockstar game in the form of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/red-dead-redemption-2" rel="nofollow"><em>Red Dead Redemption II</em></a>.</p>

<p>Places four through six are occupied by&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>releases as well, and blocky sandbox hit&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/minecraft" rel="nofollow">Minecraft</a>&nbsp;</em>is in seventh. Rounding out the top ten are&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Black Ops III</em>, then the aforementioned&nbsp;<em>San Andreas&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Guitar Hero III</em>.</p>

<p>It's worth noting that all of this is based on dollar sales; the unit sales column looks a little different, but there still aren't any original PlayStation games on it, and even fewer PS2 games appear on the unit sales list.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/red-dead-redemption-ii-playstation-top-selling-games.jpg?itok=ezPXSg0o 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/red-dead-redemption-ii-playstation-top-selling-games.jpg?itok=i8S4iXog 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Rockstar makes several appearances on Circana's PlayStation best-seller list.</figcaption></figure><p>It also happens to be the Sega Dreamcast's 26th birthday today, and to celebrate, Piscatella has compiled <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lyfu44xius2u" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a list</a> of that platform's top 20 best-selling games in the US as well.</p>

<p>Believe it or not, when it comes to dollar sales,<i>&nbsp;Sonic Adventure&nbsp;</i>doesn't top the chart (although it does top the unit sales list). That honor goes to&nbsp;<em>NFL 2K</em>, with successor&nbsp;<em>NFL 2K1&nbsp;</em>taking second place (followed by&nbsp;<em>Sonic Adventure</em>, naturally).</p>

<p>The Dreamcast may be dead, but many of the franchises on Piscatella's list, including&nbsp;<em>Sonic</em>,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/shenmue-iii-enhanced-announced" rel="nofollow"><em>Shenmue</em></a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/crazy-taxi-reboot-open-world-mmo" rel="nofollow">even&nbsp;<em>Crazy Taxi</em></a>, are still around today. Both lists are well worth a look if you want to take a trip down memory (card) lane.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/circana-reveals-best-selling-playstation-games-of-all-time]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost Of Yotei Studio Still ‘Hungover’ From Celebrating GTA 6 Delay]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gta-6-delay-ghost-yotei-cyberpunk-2-keanu-leak-2000624435</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-studio-still-%E2%80%98hungover%E2%80%99-from-celebrating-gta-6-delay.1292739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>How much champagne do you charge to the company credit card when <em>GTA 6</em> mercifully shifts out of your release window? Which celebrity will star in <em>Cyberpunk 2</em>? And what game are <em>Helldivers 2</em>‘s devs working on next? Welcome to another edition of Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku</em>‘s daily roundup of gaming news and culture.</p> <p>People are buzzing <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1757300/Jump_Space/">about <em>Jump Space</em></a>, the sci-fi co-op adventure about blowing up spaceships with friends. It comes to Early Access next week and already has an impressive <a href="https://x.com/KeepsakeGames/status/1965398533546160523">post-launch roadmap</a> of updates lined up. How many more cool ship games will we get before<em> Starfield</em>‘s <a href="https://nitter.poast.org/StarfieldGame/status/1963980745728229522#m">next expansion arrives</a>?</p> <h2>It was a good day in the Sucker Punch offices when <em>GTA 6</em> delayed</h2> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/ghost-of-yotei-tsushima-sony-ps5-state-of-play-1851786081"><em>Ghost of Yotei</em></a> is one of the biggest game releases of the fall, at least now that <em>GTA 6</em> has been delayed to May 2026. Creative director Nate Fox was asked about that moment in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ffOTS1CkZVg">new rapid-fire interview with <em>MinnMax </em></a>(via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/that-was-a-great-day-ghost-of-yotei-studio-screative%20director%20Nate%20Fox"><em>VGC</em></a>). “When<em> GTA 6</em> was delayed, did the entire studio pop some champagne?” host Ben Hanson asked. “We’re all still hungover. Multi-month hangover,” Fox responded. “That was a great day.”</p>

 <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/ghost-yotei-release-date-gta-6-collector-edition-1851777437"><em>Yotei</em>‘s October 2 release date</a> was announced before Rockstar revealed its delay, locking in its fate one way or the other. Fortune favors the bold. Now lots of games that were waiting to come out until 2026 to escape <a href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-aaaaa-silksong-next-gen-pc-devolver-digital-2000623190">the<em> GTA 6</em> gravity</a> well are faced with a new conundrum: get out ahead of it or come out later in the year and risk stumbling into a second <em>GTA 6</em> delay?</p> <h2 data-cy="article-headline"><em>Helldivers</em>&nbsp;studio’s next game will have a <em>Destiny</em>-style social hub</h2> <p>But what is it, exactly? Arrowhead CEO Shams Jorjani seemed to be speaking off the cuff when he responded to a fan in the game’s Discord who requested a place where <em>Helldivers 2</em> players can hang out in between drops. “It’s on the feature list for the next one,” Jorjani teased. What next one? <em>Helldivers</em> 3? Nope.</p>

 <p>“This was about our next game. Not <em>HD3</em>,” he added <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1nbmucr/comment/nd46h3l/">on Reddit</a>. Some fans are wondering if it’s a nod to the studio’s isometric fantasy multiplayer series <em>Magicka</em>. The studio has already confirmed that its next project, whatever it ends up being, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2025/05/15/helldivers-2-studios-next-game-will-be-free-from-playstation-partnership/">won’t be published by Sony</a>.</p> <h2>Fans think <em>GTA 6</em> parody website names have leaked</h2> <p>The open-world blockbuster is still over six months away, but in the meantime players may have some fresh teases to parse. What seem like in-game website names <a href="https://gtaforums.com/topic/1002286-gta-vi-general-speculation-discussion-vice-city-baby/page/51/#comment-1072587065">appear to have been registered</a> as real internet domains by Take-Two back in May. They include what-up.app, rydeme.app, and wipeoutcornskin.com. I don’t know if we’re ready for <em>GTA 6</em> in the post-internet, algorithmic slop phase of lampooning pop culture.</p>

 <h2>Will Johnny Silverhand return in <em>Cyberpunk 2</em>?</h2> <p>Because Keanu Reeves would be happy to do it if CD Projekt Red wants him back. “Absolutely,” he <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/johnny-silverhand-actor-keanu-reeves-says-he-absolutely-wants-to-be-in-cyberpunk-2">told<em> IGN</em></a> when asked about reprising the role. “I’d love to play Johnny Silverhand again.” Effectively a virtual ghost in the first game, there’s no reason Silverhand would need to come back in a sequel, but also nothing precluding it either. <em>Cyberpunk 2</em> is set to return to Night City but <a href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-orion-night-new-city-chicago-cdpr-1851781566">also take players to a new location</a> likened to “Chicago gone wrong.”</p> <h2>Satoru Iwata laughed when he heard about trying to sell <em>Animal Crossing</em> in America</h2> <p>Veteran Nintendo localizer Leslie Swan <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/features/interview-we-did-try-to-keep-forest-in-the-name-how-mario-64s-princess-peach-helped-bring-animal-crossing-to-the-west">told <em>Time Extension</em></a> that’s how the former president of the company reacted when she told him they were translating the cozy sim. “He just laughed and said, ‘I don’t know how you’re going to do this.’ And it’s true, just everything in that game was so specific to Japan,” she said.</p> <p>Long-time producer Takashi Tezuka was not confident either. “[Tezuka] basically said to me, ‘We’d like to have you localize it’ and I said, ‘Sure.’ But then he said, ‘No, Leslie, I’m not sure you understand, it’s going to be difficult.'” Swan recalled. “And I kept having to assure him that we would make it happen.” Decades later, the franchise is now one of the best selling in the world.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-difficulty-hard-damage-criticism-2000624031"><em>Silksong</em> is harder than <em>Hollow Knigh</em>t, but is that a problem?</a></p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/black-mirror-memecoin-crypto-web3-2000624006">Tech is beyond parody: even <em>Black Mirror</em> is getting a meme coin</a></p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/digimon-story-time-stranger-digifarm-hands-on-preview-2000624093"><em>Digimon Story: Time Stranger</em> might be the best JRPG of the fall</a></p> <h2>Watch this:</h2> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/gta-6-delay-ghost-yotei-cyberpunk-2-keanu-leak-2000624435]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lenovo Clears Out Its 4.8-Star Copilot AI Laptop (40GB RAM, 1TB SSD) at 73% Off, You Could Buy Several for the Price of One]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lenovo-clears-out-its-4-8-star-copilot-ai-laptop-40gb-ram-1tb-ssd-at-73-off-you-could-buy-several-for-the-price-of-one-2000624145</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lenovo-clears-out-its-4-8-star-copilot-ai-laptop-40gb-ram-1tb-ssd-at-73-off-you-could-buy-several-for-the-price-of-one.1292736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If you’re out there looking for a solid laptop that can handle basic, everyday tasks, then Lenovo is a manufacturer worth consideration. Maybe you’re a college student in need of something to build out documents and slideshow presentations for your classes. Maybe you’re a small business owner in need of something to, err, build out documents and slideshow presentations for your clients. Web browsing, email drafting, YouTube video watching. You know, computer stuff! Well, take a look at the Lenovo IdeaPad Slim 3. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3987/">Right now, Amazon has it on sale for 73% off. It’s listed at $2,999 but after the discount, the price comes to just $800. That’s a savings of $2,200.</a></p>
<p>Okay, but let’s hold our horses for just a moment. A $2,200 discount on a $2,299 laptop? Sounds too good to be true. So yeah, if we take a look at this items price history, we’ll see this listing has only existed on Amazon since the beginning of August. After about two weeks it dropped to the price it’s at now. It briefly went back up when September hit, but now it’s back down to $800.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3987/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>When we take a look at the specs on offer here, you can tell this is not a three thousand dollar machine. Lenovo’s own website has various builds of the IdeaPad Slim 3 in this $600 to $800 range. This listing is trying to trick you into thinking you’re saving a lot more than you are. And that’s a shame because these specs at this price point is a pretty good deal in its own right.</p>
<h2>Deep Dive</h2>
<p>What we have here is a 15.3-inch laptop capable of displaying in 1920 by 1200 HD. The anti-glare non-touch display has 300nits of brightness and a refresh rate of 60Hz. With DisplayPort 1.2 and HDMI 1.4, you can display on two additional monitors (three displays total including the laptop screen).</p>



<p>It’s got a built-in webcam that can record in 720p HD with a shutter so you can maintain privacy when not in use. For added connectivity, you have two USB-A ports and one USB-C port to transfer data or charge your other devices. Wi-Fi 6 and Bluetooth 5.2 are also supported.</p>
<p>The real story is its RAM and storage. <strong>It’s working with 40GB of memory and an SSD containing a full 1TB of storage space</strong>. Great for backing up photos and working with large file types like 4K video.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3987/">All and all, this Lenovo IdeaPad Slim 3 is a worthwhile laptop. At $2,999? Heck no. But at $800? Not bad.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3987/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lenovo-clears-out-its-4-8-star-copilot-ai-laptop-40gb-ram-1tb-ssd-at-73-off-you-could-buy-several-for-the-price-of-one-2000624145]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3D platformer Teeto to be published by Super Rare Originals]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/3d-platformer-teeto-to-be-published-by-super-rare-originals</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/3d-platformer-teeto-to-be-published-by-super-rare-originals.1292730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New demo now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Super Rare Originals [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/super-rare-originals">Super Rare Originals</a> will published <a title="Companies > Eat Pant Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/eat-pant-games">Eat Pant Games</a>-developed 3D <a title="Genres > Platformer [736 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Teeto" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/teeto">Teeto</a></em> for unspecified console(s) and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,177 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2783370/Teeto/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, the companies announced. A release date was not announced. A new demo is available now for PC. <span id="more-990737"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Super Rare Originals:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Teeto and Nory are going on an <a title="Genres > Action [3,015 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> packed <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,537 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>! Absorb ordinary objects from the world and harness their powers to fight the shadow corruption and assist a quirky cast of characters in a bright and colorful world.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Absorb and Transform</strong> – Teeto’s got a talent for absorbing all sorts of objects and turning them into wild new forms! Unlock unique abilities to outsmart enemies, solve puzzles, and discover hidden secrets.</li><li><strong>Team Up Together</strong> – Life’s better with a buddy and so is saving the world! Grab a friend and dive into split-screen <a title="Genres > Co-Op [324 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play, where you’ll absorb, transform, and explore together.</li><li><strong>Chaos Corruption</strong> – Chaos is spreading, and the shadow creatures are behind it! Teeto and Nory must use their unique powers to keep the world from tipping into complete disorder!</li><li><strong>Missing Michaels</strong> – It started with Nory’s first experiment, Michael. But Michael couldn’t stop multiplying and now there are too many Michaels for anyone to handle! Track them down, rescue them, and bring the tiny mischief-makers home.</li><li><strong>Lend a Hand</strong> – Teeto and Nory aren’t the only ones in need of help. Along the way, you’ll meet a colorful cast of quirky characters, each with their own oddball dilemmas!</li><li><strong>Dress the Part</strong> – Teeto’s got a wardrobe full of wild unlockable outfits, from stylish to downright ridiculous. Saving the world is important, but looking good while doing it is just as crucial.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Publisher Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Teeto | Super Rare Originals Publisher Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/olYY9vIUIrI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/3d-platformer-teeto-to-be-published-by-super-rare-originals]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Preorder Bonus Now Includes Four Legendary Weapons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc/1100-6532454/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-preorder-bonus-now-includes-four-legendary-weapons.1292727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532454">

            
            
      


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Borderlands 4's Gilded Glory Pack preorder bonus now includes four pieces of Legendary Gear. The additional content was <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1285190/view/543367724371282190" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announced by Gearbox</a> on September 9, just three days before the game's September 12 launch on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. If you haven't preordered your copy yet, two different physical editions are available: the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0FDBL8L41,B0FDBLDXN6,B0FKNLSFK8&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$70 standard edition</a> and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0FDBLLB34,B0FDBM9HPZ&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$130 Super Deluxe Edition</a>. The <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fcollectibles%2Fcollectors-boxes%2Fproducts%2Fborderlands-4-collectors-edition%2F426330.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GameStop-exclusive Echo-4 Collector's Bundle</a> is still up for grabs for $150. The bundle includes an Echo-4 statue with LED lights and numerous other collectibles, but it doesn't come with the game.</p><p>Xbox and PC players should also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/powera-borderlands-special-edition-wireless-controller-for-xbox/1100-6534540/" data-ref-id="1100-6534540">check out the officially licensed PowerA Special Edition Wireless Controller</a> that launches the same day as the game.</p><p>Borderlands 4's standard edition is also available to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Borderlands-4-Nintendo-Switch-2/dp/B0FKNLSFK8?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">preorder on Switch 2</a>, but Nintendo players will have to wait until October 3 to start playing.</p><h2>Borderlands 4 Preorder Bonuses</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4564479-borderlands4.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4564479" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4564479-borderlands4.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4564479"></a><figcaption>Borderlands 4 Gilded Glory Pack</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4564479-borderlands4.jpg"></figure><p>All Borderlands 4 preorders include the Gilded Glory Pack, and Gearbox just added a few extra pieces of DLC to the pack a few days before launch: one Vault Hunter Head that can be worn by all Vault Hunters and four pieces of Legendary Gear. Here's the full list of what's included.</p><ul><li>Vault Hunter Head</li><li>Vault Hunter Skin</li><li>Weapon Skin</li><li>Echo-4 Drone Skin</li><li>Legendary Gear:  <ul><li>Lvl 1 Maliwan SMG</li><li>Lvl 30 Ripper Grenade</li><li>Lvl 30 Torgue Ordnance</li><li>Max Lvl Daedalus Assault Rifle</li></ul></li></ul><p>You can also get an exclusive Ripper Mask cosmetic by preordering from GameStop.</p><div title="Borderlands 4 Preorders" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="3704" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="Borderlands 4 Preorders" data-collection="">                                                                                                                                          <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0FDBLLB34,B0FDBM9HPZ&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/stores\/page\/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0FDBLLB34,B0FDBM9HPZ&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0FDBLLB34,B0FDBM9HPZ&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20">Borderlands 4 Super Deluxe Edition</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0FDBLLB34,B0FDBM9HPZ&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/stores\/page\/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0FDBLLB34,B0FDBM9HPZ&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0FDBLLB34,B0FDBM9HPZ&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20">$130 | Releases September 12</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>The $130 Super Deluxe Edition is available for PS5 and Xbox Series X at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0FDBLLB34,B0FDBM9HPZ&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Dborderlands%2B4%2Bsuper%2Bdeluxe%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbestbuy.7tiv.net%2F55QXYj&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fs%3FsearchTerm%3Dborderlands%2B4%2Bsuper%2Bdeluxe&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Target</a>, and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fxbox-series-x%257Cs%2Fproducts%2Fborderlands-4-super-deluxe-edition---xbox-series-x%2F427191.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GameStop</a>. Along with two extra bundles of launch DLC--including extra missions, challenges, and bosses--the Super Deluxe Edition includes the Vault Hunter Pack. This is essentially the season pass, as it grants access to Borderlands 4's post-launch story expansions, new regions, additional Vault Hunters, and more.</p><ul><li>Bounty Pack Bundle  <ul><li>4 unique areas with new missions and bosses</li><li>4 Vault Cards with new challenges and rewards</li><li>New gear and weapons</li><li>New cosmetics</li><li>4 new vehicles and cosmetics</li></ul></li><li><span>Ornate Order Pack</span><ul><li>4 Vault Hunter Skins</li><li>4 Vault Hunter Heads</li><li>4 Vault Hunter Bodies</li></ul></li><li>Vault Hunter Pack - Post-launch DLC  <ul><li>2 new playable Vault Hunters</li><li>2 new Story Packs with new story and side missions</li><li>2 new map regions</li><li>Additional gear and weapons</li><li>New Vault Hunter cosmetics</li><li>New Echo-4 cosmetics</li></ul></li><li>Gilded Glory Pack preorder bonus</li><li>Firehawk’s Fury Weapon Skin</li></ul><p>Borderlands 4 also has a $100 Deluxe Edition with the Bounty Pack Bundle, Gilded Glory Pack bonus, and Firehawk's Fury Weapon Skin. The Deluxe Edition is only available in digital format.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fcollectibles%2Fcollectors-boxes%2Fproducts%2Fborderlands-4-collectors-edition%2F426330.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fcollectibles%2Fcollectors-boxes%2Fproducts%2Fborderlands-4-collectors-edition%2F426330.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fcollectibles%2Fcollectors-boxes%2Fproducts%2Fborderlands-4-collectors-edition%2F426330.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click">Borderlands 4 Echo-4 Bundle</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fcollectibles%2Fcollectors-boxes%2Fproducts%2Fborderlands-4-collectors-edition%2F426330.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fcollectibles%2Fcollectors-boxes%2Fproducts%2Fborderlands-4-collectors-edition%2F426330.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Borderlands+4+Preorder+Bonus+Now+Includes+Four+Legendary+Weapons&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-09+08%3A24%3A32&amp;fnarticle_id=6532454&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Pre-Order+Guides&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fcollectibles%2Fcollectors-boxes%2Fproducts%2Fborderlands-4-collectors-edition%2F426330.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fborderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc%2F1100-6532454%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook&amp;event_type=click">$150 | Exclusive to GameStop</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>GameStop has an exclusive "collector's edition" called the Echo-4 Bundle. Since the $150 bundle doesn't come with the game, this is more like a box with a handful of collectibles. We've seen multiple publishers release collector's editions without games in recent years, as it allows players to pick the edition they want for any platform.</p><ul><li>8-inch Echo-4 statue with LED lights</li><li>17-inch polyester map of Kairos</li><li>Vault symbol necklace</li><li>4 double-sided lithograph art prints (8 x 10 inches)</li><li>Shift Code for 5 Golden Keys</li></ul></div>                      </div>   </div><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4514481-20022975.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4514481" data-ratio="0.60590277777778" data-width="1152" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4514481-20022975.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4514481"></a><figcaption>Borderlands 4 Collector's Edition</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4514481-20022975.jpg"></figure><p>If you're interested in learning about the development of Borderlands 4 and its striking visuals, you may also want to check out the upcoming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-a-behind-the-scenes-look-at-borderlands-4-in-this-new-art-book/1100-6531707/" data-ref-id="1100-6531707">The Art of Boderlands 4 art book</a> that launches October 7. The 224-page hardcover book will feature concept art, illustrations, and behind-the-scenes production materials detailing the creation of the game. Preorders are available for $55 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1506748406?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">at Amazon</a>. There are also several new Borderlands novels, comics, and even a cookbook launching soon, as well.</p><hr><p><strong>Sign up for GameSpot's Weekly Deals Newsletter:</strong></p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/walmart-bricktember-exclusive-lego-bundle-deals-september-2025/1100-6534392/">Walmart Has Exclusive Lego Bundles This Month: Spider-Man, Star Wars, Disney, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-tactical-edition-free-dlc-collectors-edition-restock-buying-guide/1100-6524133/">Metal Gear Solid Delta Collector's Edition Restocked At Amazon (September 2)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/8bitdo-pro-3-wireless-controller-nintendo-switch-2-recommendation/1100-6533157/">8BitDo Pro 3 Controller For Switch 2 Gets First Price Cut, But It Won't Be Available For Long</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-deals-amiibo-figures-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-street-fighter-6/1100-6534260/">All Zelda And Street Fighter Switch 2 Amiibo Are On Sale For $20</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-shining-the-film-vault-special-edition-steelbook-4k-blu-ray-walmart/1100-6534223/">Preorder The Shining Film Vault Special Edition At Walmart Before It's Gone</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/discontinued-arcade1up-countercade-randomly-restocked-at-amazon/1100-6534222/">Discontinued Arcade1Up Countercade Randomly Restocked At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-super-mario-world-nintendo-adult-building-set-best-deal/1100-6525283/">Lego Super Mario World Pixel Art Model Gets Rare Price Cut At Amazon And Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-microsd-express-card-nintendo-switch-2-samsung-sandisk-walmart-amazon-restock/1100-6530578/">SanDisk 512GB MicroSD Express For Switch 2 Is Only $78 At Walmart</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        
  
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-preorder-buying-guide-ps5-xbox-switch-2-bonus-dlc/1100-6532454/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Fan Finds Rare Misprinted Game That May Be Worth Thousands]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-fan-finds-rare-misprinted-game-that-may-be-worth-thousands/1100-6534585/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-fan-finds-rare-misprinted-game-that-may-be-worth-thousands.1292724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534585">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In 1998, the first Pokemon games made their way to America as Pokemon Red and Pokemon Blue. Now, decades after the games were released, a Pokemon fan has discovered that they left Pokemon Blue unopened in their closet for decades, and it may be worth thousands.</p><p>Reddit user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gamecollecting/comments/1n60yut/found_my_old_sealed_pok%C3%A9mon_blue_for_gameboy/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sausagenpeppers</a> recently shared a photo of their unopened Pokemon Blue (via <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/pokemon-fan-discovers-rare-misprint-gameboy-title-in-their-closet-potentially-worth-thousands-of-dollars/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Automaton</a>), which still has a K-B Toys price tag on it.</p><p>That would have been an exciting find of its own, but when Sausagenpeppers shared a pic of the other side of the box, it revealed that this is a rare misprint of Pokemon Blue that has Pokemon Red's text on the back of the box.</p><p>Misprints like this one are highly sought after in the Pokemon community, and this game may turn out to be worth thousands of dollars if Sausagenpeppers decides to sell it. Pokemon's most devoted fans have shown a willingness to pay a lot of money even for unofficial merch, like the Charizard-Shaped Cheeto aka <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/charizard-shaped-cheeto-is-up-for-auction-and-already-at-an-astounding-price/1100-6529658/" data-ref-id="1100-6529658">Cheetozard, which sold for $72,000 earlier this year</a>. Last May, a UK man was arrested in possession of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/man-arrested-after-being-found-with-a-stolen-pokemon-card-haul-worth-over-300000/1100-6531563/" data-ref-id="1100-6531563">over $300,000 worth of stolen Pokemon cards</a>. And there are reports that the Japanese mob has been <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-cards-are-reportedly-being-used-to-launder-money-by-the-japanese-mob/1100-6528520/" data-ref-id="1100-6528520">using some Pokemon </a><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-cards-are-reportedly-being-used-to-launder-money-by-the-japanese-mob/1100-6528520/" data-ref-id="1100-6528520">cards to launder money</a>.</p><p>As for the primary franchise, its popularity shows no signs of slowing down. There's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-pokemon-tcg-expansion-is-coming-in-november/1100-6534534/" data-ref-id="1100-6534534">a new Pokemon TCG expansion</a> coming in November, and the next game in the series, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pokemon-legends-z-a/" data-ref-id="5000-619901">Pokemon Legends: Z-A</a>, is slated to arrive on Switch and Switch 2 on October 16. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pokemon-go/" data-ref-id="5000-449545">Pokemon Go</a> has also launched a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-tales-of-transformation-season-brings-fresh-content-in-september/1100-6534271/" data-ref-id="1100-6534271">Tales of Transformation season</a>, while Scopely has laid out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-august-2025-events-raid-bosses-spotlight-hours-community-day-and-more/1100-6534461/" data-ref-id="1100-6534461">the game's events for September</a>.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><p><i>Click the button below to add GameSpot as a preferred source on Google</i></p></div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-fan-finds-rare-misprinted-game-that-may-be-worth-thousands/1100-6534585/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Talking Point: Is Hollow Knight: Silksong Too Difficult?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-is-hollow-knight-silksong-too-difficult</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/talking-point-is-hollow-knight-silksong-too-difficult.1292700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="Silksong - Sweat" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/aabf7f18f0f77/silksong-sweat.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>The original <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hollow_knight">Hollow Knight</a> was no pushover, but it's safe to say that its sequel is hitting a whole new level of difficulty.</p>
<p>You only need look on social media to see that some folks have been struggling with their journey through Pharloom. A few are even going so far as to say that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Silksong</a> is <a href="https://x.com/CreatorCreepy_/status/1963848634807492623">"way too difficult to be enjoyable"</a> or <a href="https://x.com/n8nja538/status/1964047646298869769">"harder for the sake of being harder"</a>. Team Cherry is well aware of players' struggles, with an <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/hollow-knight-silksongs-upcoming-patch-will-nerf-the-difficulty-in-certain-areas">upcoming patch</a> looking to fine-tune the difficulty in key areas.</p>
<p>While we here at Nintendo Life are more or less in agreement that the game is significantly more taxing than its predecessor, we have varying thoughts on how this has affected our overall enjoyment so far (if at all).</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067rxhuow&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>834k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>So with that in mind, let's see what Team NL thinks about Silksong's difficulty so far...</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187623 @ 1757433831 -->
<h2>"a natural progression" (PJ O'Reilly, staff writer)</h2>
<p>I'm perhaps not as far into the game as most of the rest of the gang here, but I do think that, without the difficulty where it's at (and it does feel fairly tough compared to the first one, getting started), Silksong would lose quite a bit of what makes it so special, and so uniquely engrossing.</p>
<p>I wouldn't like to see anything get any easier, especially for long-term fans who are back and wanting to be challenged more than last time. It's a natural progression, really. I can see how it's frustrating and rage-quit-inducing for some, too, but no more so than most other serious contenders in this genre. Indeed, my faves of late, stuff like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/dead_cells">Dead Cells</a> and whatnot, are easily just as hard as anything I've approached here thus far.</p>
<p>It can be a little annoying even to me at times, mind, with some boss runbacks in particular irritating me as I have to trek a little too far through enemies to get back at it after a death.</p>
<p>That's all part of the fun, though, with these intense, and intensely clever, platformers. What's the point of an uphill battle without a good hill or any proper battles? Something like that, innit. And when death is my fault 99.9% of the time, it's all good.</p>
<h2>"struggle and persistence" (Alex Olney, video producer)</h2>
<p>I mean, it's certainly no secret that the game is hard, it's expected given how tough the previous game was. What I think is most jarring for a lot of players who were familiar with the original is that you're most likely coming from end-game The Knight to basic early-game Hornet, which is a marked difference. A big part of the game's identity is struggle and persistence, and I think it would be a disservice to fans to dilute that.</p>
<p>Having said that, so many enemies dealing two damage in a hit does perhaps feel a bit cruel. But if you're efficient with your traps and all the extra moves at your disposal, you should find that if you could get through Hollow Knight, you can get through Silksong.</p>
<figure><a title="Silksong Gameplay 01" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/70ad6c0935519/silksong-gameplay-01.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Team Cherry</em></figcaption></figure>
<h2>"masks of damage" (Alana Hagues, deputy editor)</h2>
<p>I'm deep into Act 2 now, and I may have gotten a <em>little</em> mad at this game a few times. But on the whole? I'm loving the difficulty.</p>
<p>It ramps up much quicker than it did in Hollow Knight, but almost every single boss fight (so far) has felt incredibly well designed and extremely fun to fight that I'm rarely, truly annoyed with any single fight — more just at myself for making a silly mistake.</p>
<p>As Alex said, some enemies (and most bosses) do two masks of damage. But there are also numerous little traps and punishing little tricks that Team Cherry has tucked away — Pharloom is dangerous, and I'm constantly surprised by the horrors and laughs it brings me. I also think the game expects you to <em>know</em> Hollow Knight. Even the platforming is trickier early on.</p>
<p>But the real trick is, if you're struggling, just walk away and explore. It's a Metroidvania, and there are Quests to complete, Tools to discover and buy, and ways to upgrade your health. As the world opens up, your options expand and I've already chopped and changed my progress multiple times because I know something would be easier if I had a different Tool or Art.</p>
<p>So yes, Silksong is tough, and it may bring out my awful stubbornness and frustration, but it's incredibly rewarding.</p>
<h2>"a few expletives" (Ollie Reynolds, staff writer)</h2>
<p>My time is often quite limited these days, so I have to admit that if a game is proving particularly taxing for me and I'm having to replay sections over and over, I'll sometimes put it down and do something else for a while. There's something about Silksong, however, that keeps me coming back for more.</p>
<p>It's definitely a lot more challenging than the first game. But it's all about learning patterns and recognising when might be the best opportunity to launch your attack. Once you've nailed that, then you're basically 99% of the way there. There have been a couple of moments where I've let out a few expletives at my inanimate electronic gaming device, mind you.</p>
<p>I expected Silksong to be difficult, and honestly, I'm quite glad it is. After such a long wait, I didn't want to just breeze through the game and forget about it after a single weekend. Team Cherry has crafted something that begs to be savoured, and if that means restarting from a bench every now and then, so be it.</p>
<figure><a title="Silksong Gameplay 02" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/b27ad33e0d525/silksong-gameplay-02.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Team Cherry</em></figcaption></figure>
<h2>"the right equipment" (Felix Sanchez, video producer)</h2>
<p>Personally I feel the difficulty has been great 18 hours in. I don't know if it's because I've already played Hollow Knight, but I never feel I'm stuck because of a tough fight. Sure, I'm dying quite a lot in some places, but I eventually learn the patterns, and I also think choosing the right equipment has a lot to say.</p>
<p>The design of the bosses and their phases are honestly maybe my favourite in any game. I'm excited to see what the rest of the game has to offer, but as for now, it's absolutely perfect!</p>
<hr>
<p><em>So that's what we reckon, but what about you? Be sure to vote in the poll above and leave a comment with your thoughts on Silksong's difficulty so far.</em></p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187338,187028 @ 1757433616 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-is-hollow-knight-silksong-too-difficult]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sucker Punch Was Elated When Grand Theft Auto VI Got Delayed, “That Was A Great Day,” Says Creative Director]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sucker-punch-elated-when-grand-theft-auto-vi-delayed-ghost-of-yotei/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sucker-punch-was-elated-when-grand-theft-auto-vi-got-delayed-%E2%80%9Cthat-was-a-great-day-%E2%80%9D-says-creative-director.1292697/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>When Rockstar announced that Grand Theft Auto VI would <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-may-26/">no longer be launching in 2025 and was instead pushed back to 2026</a>, it was a disappointing day for plenty of players, even though we all got a <a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-vi-trailer-2-breaks-all-time-24h-viewership-records-beating-deadpool-vs-wolverine/">nice trailer to pore over in the meantime</a>. A disappointing day for those hoping to play it as soon as possible though, was a day of celebration for developers across the industry planning to release a game in fall 2025, including for Ghost of Yotei developer, Sucker Punch. </p>



<p>In a recent rapid-fire interview with MinnMax, creative director at Sucker Punch, Nate Fox, was asked, "<em>When GTA VI was delayed into 2026, did the entire studio just like pop some champagne?," </em>to which Fox replied, "<em>We're all still hungover. Multi-month hangover. That was a great day," </em>with a sizeable smile on his face as he said it.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="125 Rapid-Fire Questions About Ghost of Yōtei With Sucker Punch's Nate Fox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ffOTS1CkZVg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>While Ghost of Yotei might have avoided having to go toe-to-toe with Grand Theft Auto VI when its launch arrives this coming October, any games planning to launch in May 2026 won't be so lucky, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/take-two-ceo-very-high-conviction-grand-theft-auto-vi-wont-be-delayed-again-rockstar/">Take-Two boss Strauss Zelnick has a "<em>very, very, high</em>" conviction </a>that the game's release date won't be moved again.</p>



<p>Sucker Punch recently confirmed that Ghost of Yotei had <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-has-already-gone-gold/">"<em>gone gold</em>"</a> ahead of its coming launch, and  PlayStation fans can look forward to its release on October 2, 2025.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/sucker-punch-elated-when-grand-theft-auto-vi-delayed-ghost-of-yotei/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Pro AMD FSR 4 Support Is Coming In First Quarter of 2026 – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-amd-fsr-first-quarter-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-pro-amd-fsr-4-support-is-coming-in-first-quarter-of-2026-%E2%80%93-rumor.1292694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/amd-fsr-4/">AMD FSR 4</a> support will come to <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/playstation-5-pro/">PlayStation 5 Pro</a> early next year, according to rumors circulating online.</p>



<p>In a new video shared a few days ago on YouTube, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MooresLawIsDead">Moore's Law is Dead</a> commented on when support for the new version of the AMD upscaling tech is expected to hit the system, saying that it should come in the first quarter of 2026, together with or shortly after support for RDNA 3 GPUs, which may come as early as in the final months of 2025.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="RX 9070 GRE 16GB Specs Leak, AMD FSR 4 on RDNA 3, Nvidia RTX 5080 &amp; 5070 SUPER | August Loose Ends" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HEdT4lCvWaY?start=462&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Although Moore's Law is Dead proved reliable regarding PlayStation leaks in the past few months being the first to reveal the AI-powered PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution upscaler, we have to take what was revealed in the video above with a pinch of salt. Lead System Architect Mark Cerny confirmed that <a href="https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr4-ps5-pro-2026-rdna5/">AMD FSR 4 support is indeed coming to PlayStation 5 Pro sometime in 2026</a>, however, so there's a very good chance that it is indeed coming in the first few months of the year as MLiD revealed.</p>



<p>While it is official that AMD FSR 4 is coming to PlayStation 5 Pro next year, very little is known about how the system will handle the upscaler and how games will benefit from some of its features, which include AI-powered super resolution and frame generation. Known AMD insider KeplerL2 revealed back in July that <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-can-t-run-amd-fsr-4-ai-model/">the system is not capable of running the same model used on RDNA 4 GPUs</a>, as the console lacks FP8 support, meaning that some work will have to be done for the console to run the full version of the tech. In addition, it seems like existing games will have to be patched, as the current version of PSSR doesn't allow system-level DLL swaps.</p>



<p>Even without AMD FSR 4 and with the sometimes average implementation of the PSSR upscaler, the PlayStation 5 Pro is still a worthy purchase for demanding console games that want to experience PlayStation 5 games at the very best. You can learn more about what the system has to offer by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/playstation-5-pro-hardware-the-next-gen-graphics-upgrade/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-amd-fsr-first-quarter-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead Reset Review – Gripping, Thrilling, and Simple]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/dead-reset-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dead-reset-review-%E2%80%93-gripping-thrilling-and-simple.1292691/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Dead Reset</h5><p><span>September 11, 2025</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC, PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X/S, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch</span>
						</p></div><div>
							<h5>Publisher</h5><p><span>Wales Interactive</span>
						</p></div><div>
							<h5>Developer</h5><p><span>Dark Rift Horror, Wales Interactive</span>
						</p></div></div></div>			
			<p>Dead Reset is the latest and 17th FMV game from Wales Interactive, a studio that has done just FMV titles, but it’s a well the studio draws from, more than it does from making more roguelike deckbuilders, survival FPS games, 2.5D auto-attack survival games, and VR titles, to name just a few of the ways the studio bounces around.</p>



<p>Not only is Dead Reset not the studio’s first time making an FMV game, but it’s also not the first time it’s done a horror-flavored FMV game. This is all to say that I have to believe Wales Interactive knows a thing or two about developing and executing on full-motion-video, or FMV, narratives. Or, that they’ve proven 16 times over now, they can make one successful enough to make another.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Cole backs up against a desk while hiding from the creature</figcaption></figure>



<p>I haven’t played their other FMV games, but I can believe that what was learned from them is what informs the best parts of Dead Reset. It’s a tightly paced story with strong performances that keep you locked into playing to find out what happens next. Scenes are tense, emotionally charged, and there’s enough atmosphere created through strong lighting and sound choices to carry the parts that aren’t as strong, like the over-the-top gore and messy creature design that hams everything up, or how, even if the actors are doing their best with the writing, the words they're told to say make them sound like a bad caricature.</p>



<p>When I checked out the first chapter of Dead Reset in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/dead-reset-hands-on-preview/">preview</a>, I came away disappointed, though that was mostly due to my own expectations not being met. I was hoping it would be more of a layered horror story, but it seemed more interested in trying to do a fun creature-feature to play through with a bowl of popcorn at your side. I’m all for that experience too, and when I had still only played the first chapter, I was hopeful Dead Reset would get better as it went along.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, now that I’ve seen every chapter multiple times, I feel let down again, knowing that Dead Reset doesn’t have the juice to be entertaining the whole way through.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Cole chooses between admitting his déjà vu and not.</figcaption></figure>



<p>What I mean by ‘the whole way through’ is getting to each of the four endings, because otherwise you can mop it up in less than three hours, and feel totally fine with whatever version of the story you got (unless you got the worst one). Play through it just the once, and you’ll probably walk away perfectly whelmed and reasonably entertained. It’s when you ‘reset’ your experience that suddenly, the plot beats I liked the first time around didn’t hit as hard, even with a new context between each character as I tried to make different choices each time. It quickly started to feel more like checking scenes off for the sole purpose of saying you’ve seen them and whatever alternatives they offer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some basics about Dead Reset. You play as Cole Mason, a former surgeon who can remember how to perform surgery, but not anything about what happened to him before a security guard named Slade picks him up and tosses him in front of a patient who has a ‘foreign mass’ in her lower abdomen. There are six core characters: Cole, Fearne, Weir, Cooper, Slade, and Magson.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><figcaption>Even in its earliest forms, the creature looks like a mess of bad looking prosthetics.</figcaption></figure>



<p>The mass is a creature that eats anything with a pulse and looks like someone made a mop out of intestines. It changes forms, but it unfortunately never really looks scary or even interesting, to be frank. In every form, it looks like a blob of flesh put together from the scrap pile of a prop studio’s prosthetics section. It’s even telling that you so rarely get a solid, long look at the creature, with most of the shots featuring it only showing a half-view, or a dimmed view while the lights only partially illuminate it. Almost like the production team knew it wasn’t worth highlighting.</p>



<figure><figcaption>You'll hear Cooper scream quite a bit depending on how many wrong turns you take.</figcaption></figure>



<p>While the creature isn’t interesting, what’s at least a little more fun to think about is the ability, or curse, depending on how you see it, that Cole bears. He's stuck in a time loop, with his starting point being determined by a power surge connected to a time machine chair that the Magson character has built, and his reset point being any time he dies. With each new power surge, his starting point moves forward in time, which is how you progress through the story.</p>



<p>There’s a menu that tracks how many of its 339 scenes you’ve witnessed, how many times you’ve died across all your playthroughs, how many of the endings you’ve found, and how many decisions you’ve made. There’s another that claims to track your relationships with the other characters, though it never seemed to give me any more information beyond who was still alive among the five characters you meet alongside Cole.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Dead Reset features plenty of scenes enhanced by its lighting and sound design choices.</figcaption></figure>



<p>There’s also a page that tracks different ‘tasks’ or objectives you can try to complete based on what paths you’ve taken. It’s all very bare bones and is only a little helpful for anyone wanting to do some achievement hunting.</p>



<p>Speaking of the choices you make, you can either have them countdown, or you can set it to 'Streamer Mode,' which pauses the action and lets you take however long you like to decide. Some of the choices, you realize, are meaningless. Plenty of them just pad out the experience so that Cole has the necessary information to move forward. Once you've played through to the end once, it's easy to spot which do and don't matter, another element that adds to the tedium of playing it a second, third, and fourth time to see all the endings.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Cole, Fearne, and Slade all get the most screen time.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Though I'd be remiss if I didn't mention that there is a meta-layer of fun to be had for veteran horror fans. If you're someone who loves the horror genre, and has seen all of its sides from the most intense to the most laid-back, comedy-focused stories and everything in between, then you can have a good time doing what I did on my first playthrough. Basically, with every choice I ran through all the horror and narrative tropes the genre carries in my head, and decided based on what I've always believed characters in other horrors should have done, instead of making bad, emotional decisions. As if I had a '<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@HowItShouldHaveEnded">How It Should Have Ended</a>' storyboard running through my head in real-time for Dead Reset. It was fun, and more than a little funny, how often it worked. Randy Meeks would've probably mopped up the whole game without dying unnecessarily once.  </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Dead Reset - Official Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SggmZx9CAgk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Ultimately, I'm walking away from my time with Dead Reset more disappointed than when I previewed it. At least then I had hope, because I hadn't played the full game. The naked truth of it is that despite good performances from the whole cast, some wonderful lighting and sound design work, well-paced scenes that kept the story moving with strong emotional beats at the wheel, it doesn't hold up on multiple replays. </p>



<p>It's not helped by the fact that when it's not dimly lit with the darkness of a secret research station (and even sometimes when it is), the set looks like it came out of a forgettable Doctor Who episode, while the creature looks like a mish-mash of rejected creature designs that came together the way it did because they ran out of time to do any better. The rest of its gore and prosthetic work subtract from the experience rather than add to it, cutting the intensity too much compared to how straight and serious the rest of the story is played. If there were more jokes made, then maybe it would've made sense. Instead, it just makes you laugh when you're supposed to be scared.</p>



<p><em>PS5 version tested. Review code provided by the publisher.</em></p>

				

						<div>
					
					
					<h2>Dead Reset</h2>
				</div>
			
						<section>
				<p>Dead Reset is worth experiencing for its performances, its tense atmosphere built on strong lighting and sound design choices, and well-paced story that makes you want to keep finding out what will happen next, but its entertainment value wanes after you've hit the credits. It's less enticing on replays or 'resets,' and its worst attributes don't help carry the experience beyond a single play through.</p>
				<div>
												<ul>
							<h6>Pros</h6>
							<li>Strong performances from the cast
</li><li>Tense atmosphere built by good lighting and sound design choices
</li><li>Gripping scenes that make you want to keep playing and find out what happens next</li>						</ul>
																		<ul>
							<h6>Cons</h6>
							<li>Hammed-up gore that cuts the intensity too much
</li><li>Poor creature design that really brings down the whole experience as a creature-feature horror story
</li><li>Writing that constantly failed the strong work the actors were putting in by making everyone sound like a caricature
</li><li>Bare-bones menu that doesn't provide meaningful insights into your playthroughs
</li><li>Its strongest story beats wane after the first playthrough, even if they play out differently under new circumstances</li>						</ul>
										</div>
				<a rel="sponsored nofollow noskim" href="">Buy for  from Amazon</a>
				<span>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may
					earn from qualifying purchases.</span>
			</section>
			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/review/dead-reset-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kpop Demon Hunters Fan Reimagines The Movie As A Video Game, And I Need It]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-video-game-rhythm-mod-idea-concept-2000624444</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kpop-demon-hunters-fan-reimagines-the-movie-as-a-video-game-and-i-need-it.1292679/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>There was a time when a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-best-worst-songs-soundtrack-ranking-2000616633"><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters</span></i></a> <span>tie-in video game would have been a given. Netflix would have partnered with a studio to create a probably terrible game based on the K-pop group Huntr/x’s music-powered demon-slaying adventures that kids could rent at their local Blockbuster for the weekend after they saw and became obsessed with the movie. Nowadays, movie studios are much more precious about quality control, so we don’t get waves of tie-in video games haphazardly dropping on the eShop or PlayStation Store. And yeah, it’s probably a good thing we don’t have a </span><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters </span></i><span>video game months after the musical blew up on Netflix, but I wouldn’t be surprised if someone at the streaming company has been considering throwing some money around to get one made. What such a game might look like down the line is anyone’s guess, but fans are already creating mock-ups of a </span><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters </span></i><span>game, and I hope one day a studio gets to make one a reality.</span></p> <p><span>JHN Studios is a YouTube channel that creates 8-bit versions of K-pop songs, and while most of their videos are reimaginings of tunes by real-world groups, they are now working their way through the </span><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters </span></i><span>soundtrack. Each of these arrangements is accompanied by retro-style animated videos of a hypothetical </span><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters </span></i><span>rhythm game that recreates the songs’ respective scenes from the movie. I’m obsessed with the excellent sprite work. I want the Rumi as a keychain or pin.&nbsp;</span></p>  <p><span>The actual rhythm gameplay of these mock-ups isn’t that complex, but it does make for a good proof of concept. A rhythm game seems like the obvious choice for a </span><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters </span></i><span>game, and the movie’s incredible tunes have already started worming their way into the mod scene for games like </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@thatboygro/video/7529646402599718175"><i><span>Beat Saber</span></i></a><span>, </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@vifalleniv/video/7543302663614598455"><i><span>Friday Night Funkin</span></i><span>’</span></a><span>, and </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@sleepiegoat/video/7528110760031997215"><i><span>Dead as Disco</span></i></a><span>. That being said, I also think the movie would be a natural fit for a retro-style beat-em-up like the projects coming out of Tribute Games, such as </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/scott-pilgrim-ex-netflix-tribute-games-anamanaguchi-1851783893"><i><span>Scott Pilgrim EX</span></i></a><span> and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-cosmic-invasion-preview-beat-em-up-tribute-games-1851784757"><i><span>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</span></i></a><span>. Give me a three-player co-op brawler that lets me and two friends smack around some demons while JHN Studios’ chip-tune arrangements play in the background.&nbsp;</span></p>  <p><span>While a game is probably still a pie-in-the-sky dream for the moment, it does sound like Netflix fully intends to capitalize on </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-streaming-box-office-numbers-netflix-2000622381"><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters</span></i><span>’ success</span></a><span> with </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-2-sequel-theories-questions-netflix-2000620717"><span>a sequel</span></a><span>. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-video-game-rhythm-mod-idea-concept-2000624444]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch modder owes Nintendo $2 million after representing himself in court]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/switch-modder-who-acted-as-his-own-lawyer-now-owes-nintendo-2-million/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-modder-owes-nintendo-2-million-after-representing-himself-in-court.1292676/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<p>Daly's <em>pro se</em> legal representation in the case was notable for its use of several novel affirmative defenses, including arguments that Nintendo's "alleged copyrights are invalid," that Nintendo "does not have standing to bring suit," and that Nintendo "procured a contract [with Daly] through fraudulent means." For the record, the judgment in this case reasserts that Nintendo "owns valid copyrights in works protected by the TPMs, including Nintendo games and the Nintendo Switch operating system."</p>
<p>In addition to $2 million in damages, Daly is specifically barred from "obtaining, possessing, accessing, or using" any DRM circumvention device or hacked console, with or without the intent to sell it. The judgment also bars Daly from publishing or "linking to" any website with instructions for hacking consoles and from "reverse engineering" any Nintendo consoles or games. Control of Daly's ModdedHardware.com domain name will also be transferred to Nintendo.</p>
<p>Nintendo's latest legal victory comes years after a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/11/hacker-will-pay-nintendo-4-5-million-in-team-xecuter-plea-bargain/">$4.5 million plea deal with Gary "GaryOPA" Bowser</a>, one of the leaders behind Team Xecuter and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/05/nintendo-goes-to-court-to-stop-sale-of-new-switch-hacking-tech/">its SX line of Switch hacking devices</a>. Bowser also <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/04/bowser-free-from-prison-still-owes-nintendo-14-5m-for-switch-hacking/">served 14 months</a> of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/02/bowser-sentenced-to-40-months-for-team-xecuters-console-hacking/">a 40-month prison sentence</a> in that case and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/02/after-14-5m-judgments-console-hacker-paid-nintendo-25-a-month-from-prison/">said last year</a> that he will likely be paying Nintendo back for the rest of his life.</p>


          
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/switch-modder-who-acted-as-his-own-lawyer-now-owes-nintendo-2-million/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Single-Player Campaign News Coming Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-single-player-campaign-news-coming-soon/1100-6534583/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-single-player-campaign-news-coming-soon.1292670/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534583">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The official show schedule for Tokyo Game Show 2025 has been <a href="https://tgs.cesa.or.jp/en/program" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announced</a>, and it was quickly noticed that EA is hosting an event of its own to reveal more about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6</a>'s campaign.</p><p>A <a href="https://tgs.cesa.or.jp/en/program" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">presentation on September 26 at 1 PM </a>local time in Tokyo (midnight EST) will include a new look at Battlefield 6's single-player campaign, featuring lead developers Philippe Ducharme and Roman Campos-Oriola, along with the game's English voice actors. This is <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/tgs-2025-official-live-stream-program-schedule-announced" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">according to Gematsu.</a></p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1084339183" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466208,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Battlefield%206%20-%20Official%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:129,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/battlefield-6-official-reveal-trailer\/2300-6466208\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466208\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466208\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466208\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466208&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466208,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6534583&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;battlefield-6&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466208},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466208\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4537708-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/2vOVIwZW.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1753370340,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="2vOVIwZW" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Battlefield 6 - Official Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Much of the focus of Battlefield 6 so far has been on the multiplayer element, so fans are eager to learn more about the campaign. EA Motive is developing the campaign, which <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6s-campaign-is-inspired-by-this-movie-and-tv-show/1100-6531514/" data-ref-id="1100-6531514">takes inspiration from the war movie Civil War and the Taylor Sheridan drama Lioness.</a></p><p>A Battlefield 6 trailer (above) spotlights the game's campaign, opening with the President of the US speaking to the American people about a "monstrous, unprovoked attack" and how "no country is safe." The trailer shows off a variety of locations around the world, including New York City.</p><p>Campos-Oriola <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6s-campaign-is-inspired-by-this-movie-and-tv-show/1100-6531514/" data-ref-id="1100-6531514">said</a> a guiding theme for the Battlefield 6 campaign is exploring the concept of "talented but ordinary people put in extraordinary situations."</p><p>"That creates a very interesting dynamic in terms of relationships with other people. These are elements we're looking to capture in the single player," the developer said.</p><p>EA Motive previously developed the 2023 Dead Space remake, and Ducharme said that game is "obviously very different" from Battlefield. However, the Ducharme said the idea was to explore the "curve of tension" of the "highs and the lows to keep players hooked."</p><p>Battlefield 6 launches on October 10 for PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. While you can't play Battlefield 6 yet, you can <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/upcoming-battlefield-2042-patch-offers-battle-pass-tier-skipping-and-more/1100-6534550/" data-ref-id="1100-6534550">earn rewards for it by playing Battlefield 2042 right now</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-single-player-campaign-news-coming-soon/1100-6534583/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Conan O'Brien's Clueless Gamer Is Back With Borderlands 4 To Support Charity]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/conan-obriens-clueless-gamer-is-back-with-borderlands-4-to-support-charity/1100-6534581/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/conan-obriens-clueless-gamer-is-back-with-borderlands-4-to-support-charity.1292667/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534581">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Comedian and host Conan O'Brien's "Clueless Gamer" segment is back, and the newest episode is all about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6529507/" data-ref-id="1100-6529507">Borderlands 4</a> and raising money for a good cause.</p><p>In this segment, O'Brien plays Borderlands 4 alongside the two people--Brian Long and Liz Day--who donated the most money in the <a href="https://www.charitybuzz.com/catalog_items/auction-join-conan-obrien-on-clueless-gamer-for-3163901" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">CharityBuzz auction</a> supporting the charity Next for Autism. O'Brien does what he does best in the episode, roasting the game and playing poorly. In particular, he makes fun of Claptrap for being so annoying and questions why such an absurd game needs any kind of story at all.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qLOA_F-H3QI" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qLOA_F-H3QI" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><a href="https://nextforautism.org/donate/?utm_source=google_ads&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=general_campaign&amp;utm_term=donation&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gad_campaignid=22666689497&amp;gbraid=0AAAAABJFgOKD5psZ2YApjbBJEtEuC10hH&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwoP_FBhDFARIsANPG24NPFrb4nuAdOrBha6FLNGk41O1cQg9X3hlFSzQn3Z1SbFQyp0wzsEEaAmapEALw_wcB" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Next for Autism</a> is a nonprofit that designs and launched programs to support people with autism. Long and Day donated the most money, winning the auction and a chance to play a game with O'Brien.</p><p>Clueless Gamer was a regular series that generated many millions of views across numerous installments, but went dark for a while. The latest episode prior to the Borderlands 4 installment <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/conan-obriens-clueless-gamer-returns-to-take-on-a-game-hes-already-in/1100-6527949/" data-ref-id="1100-6527949">came in 2024 with Death Stranding's director's cut.</a></p><p>One Clueless Gamer episode had Seth Rogen and Zach Efron <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/conan-obrien-plays-mario-kart-8-with-seth-rogen-an/1100-6439329/" data-ref-id="1100-6439329">draw a penis on O'Brien's face while playing Mario Kart 8</a>. The show was so successful that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/conans-clueless-gamer-is-becoming-a-series/1100-6446686/" data-ref-id="1100-6446686">TBS was considering a Clueless Gamer spin-off show</a>, but that never happened.</p><p>Borderlands 4 launches on September 12, but it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-release-times-revealed-heres-exactly-when-you-can-start-playing/1100-6534522/" data-ref-id="1100-6534522">actually unlocks starting at 9 PM PT on September 11</a>. For more, be sure to check out <a href="https://google.com/search?q=bl4+preorder+guide+gamespot&amp;rlz=1C5GCCM_en&amp;oq=bl4+preorder+guide+gamespot&amp;gs_lcrp=EgZjaHJvbWUyCQgAEEUYORigATIHCAEQIRigAdIBCDMxMTZqMGo3qAIAsAIA&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GameSpot's Borderlands 4 preorder guide.</a> The game launches this week for PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC, and comes to Switch 2 in October.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><p><i>Click the button below to add GameSpot as a preferred source on Google</i></p></div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/conan-obriens-clueless-gamer-is-back-with-borderlands-4-to-support-charity/1100-6534581/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>