<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:19:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Screamer Preview – How Milestone built their arcade racer for combat]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/17/screamer-preview-how-milestone-built-their-arcade-racer-for-combat/</link>
            <guid>1438315</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>You probably know Milestone best for their long lineup of motorcycle racing games, from MotoGP through Ride and on to Motocross, but that’s not where the studio started. No, the studio’s big break came in 1995 with the arcade-style racing game Screamer, which went toe-to-toe with Ridge Racer as a PC alternative. Over a trio of games in the 90s, the series drifted towards more rally racing, before petering out at another studio, but now in 2026? Screamer’s back, and it’s a refreshing new take on the arcade street racer.</p>
<p><iframe title="SCREAMER - Gameplay Reveal Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_mm2ljVET8A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The immediate and most obvious shift from the 90s is that the graphics are so very different. Obviously, they are massively higher fidelity, there’s none of the early 3D polygon wibble, and the gameplay is built around more nuanced physics and handling models… but the art direction has shifted towards anime cutscenes, and there’s a drama-filled story to sink into alongside.</p>


<p>Michele Caletti Creative and Development Director discussed the game’s blend of visual styles: “We took inspiration from things like Akira, from Ghost in the Shell, from Bubblegum Crisis, from Cyber City Oedo, from Cowboy Bebop, and many more, but one of the things that we had to take a very strong decision was not to make the game cel shaded.</p>
<p>It would have been the easy choice –  It’s an anime, so you make the game cel shaded – but if you do so, you have to oversimplify some details, you cannot go into fine details with cel shading. So the art direction was bold enough to try to blend the anime and the realistic or quite realistic rendition of the world. And then take some other moves like that there’s not onlythe city setting, there are many other settings that try to portray a different but familiar world.”</p>

<div id="attachment_469002"><p id="caption-attachment-469002">You know it’s anime sci-fi when you have a dog that can drive a car.</p></div>
<p>The Tournament is a long-running illegal street racing competition, but this latest edition is for a huge $1 billion prize, drawing in teams from all kinds of backgrounds. For the Banshee PMC, Hiroshi, Roisin and Frederick are looking for revenge on Anaconda Corp and their distinctly fascist-coded leader, Gabriel. The best way to get close is to enter the same tournament, with the possibility that Gabriel’s demise could be made to look like an accident… But it’s also a story that won’t take itself too seriously. I mean, there’s a dog that can drive a car, and whose owner has fitted it with the same universal translator that everyone else uses to communicate using their native tongues – “This is another choice that we made early,” Michele said, “because we wanted to have cultural melting pot of different characters, of different ethnicities and this was important to convey the fact that in this near future the culture is something like what we have today, but even more diverse, even more varied.”</p>
<p>They won’t be the only team that you race as, though, with five teams competing and the story hopping back and forth, putting you in control of various racers, cars and their specific abilities. Even in the opening few story chapters, there’s races where you just need to finish, where you’re driving as a team, where you’re regularly jumping via cutscenes between different cars.</p>
<p>“We wanted to go away from the pure racing focus and jargon and dialogue and always thinking, always about [winning].” Michele explained. “So you see the characters are not even dressed like drivers, because they are something else, then they are drivers. So their goal is to win, yes, but everyone has also another goal. So you will see that during the story, they’re focus shifts towards their inner goal. Then you’ll be playing in the role of all the characters of the game. So everyone has the goal to be first, yes, but from different perspectives.”</p>
<p>What’s particularly striking about the racing is how it reimagines the controls. The right and left trigger make you go and stop, of course, and the left stick is for turning, but drifting is on the right stick, you have a timing minigame for upshifts to give you boost charges, and those feed into a bull-rushing attack to destroy other competitor cars.</p>

<p>It’s quite a lot to get a handle on, and the way you can counter-steer while drifting felt a bit like rubbing my head and patting my tummy at the same time, so it makes sense that the story mode adds these concepts one at a time. When you wrap that around the mix of lavishly produced anime cutscenes and the character portrait dialogue scenes, though, that does lead to a pretty slow feeling rollout over the course of the opening hour or two. I was really waiting for it to give me all of the gadgets and toys to play with.</p>
<p>Michele admitted “The story takes you that slowly, yeah. It takes hours to get to all the mechanics in place, and the point is, you’re never thrown multiple things together to you.”</p>
<p>He continued, “We thought and we discussed a lot about how to lay out the default controls, how to favour the most intricate actions, because you might want to do strange stuff and we want to allow you to do so. I think we’ve reached the balance where it’s not overwhelming. Give yourself some time to get into the mechanics and it’s not about much about the fingers, but the strategy in order to understand and being in control of when to do things, not to overuse the systems.”</p>

<p>The macguffin that makes all of this possible is the ECHO, a device fitted to each and every car like a super sci-fi MGU-K from Formula 1. Fitted by Gage on behalf of the tournament’s enigmatic host Mr. A, it gradually accumulates Sync, both passively over time and when tapping the Active Shift to shift up a gear in time with the rev limiter –&nbsp;don’t worry, it’s still an arcade game and you won’t be asked to downshift at all. This builds up to grant you boost charges, which you can then deploy, and even strengthen by holding and releasing with another mini timing challenge.</p>
<p>As you Boost, this takes that energy and transfers it over to the second meter of the ECHO device, building up Entropy. This gives you charges to use defensively, to create a temporary shield for a few moments, or to unleash as a Strike, boosting forward again and destroying any car that you hit from behind. Save up the Entropy to fill out the meter, and you can enter into Overdrive, putting you in a much longer-lasting Strike boost that can blast multiple rivals into smithereens, and eventually leaves you vulnerable to destruction just from hitting a wall. You can technically outlast the Overdrive, but I would explode my car every time…</p>
<p>That’s where the ECHO’s final trick comes in, as destruction just respawns your car and body, and gets you racing again. There’s no moral quandary over whether or not this new car and person is the same as the one that died – Milestone seem to be leaving that philosophical debate to the Ship of Theseus and the Star Trek teleporter – and instead it’s just a canny way of keeping the action rampaging along.</p>
<p>“We didn’t want to have this pattern of side-striking the cars,” Michele said. “We tried different things like because the hot part is that it’s easy to strike on a straight, it’s harder to strike into a corner, so the more the intricate the trucks, the more it’s complicated to strike. But we experimented with many things like a semi-automatic strike that drives you toward your opponent, but it didn’t work. We tried something like a seeking missile, but it didn’t work. So we ended up with this where you’re still in control, so you if you hit, you feel like you’ve done it. If you miss, you understand what you have done wrong.”</p>

<p>It all blends into a rather unique take on the arcade racer. Combat is direct and to the point, with just the Strike as your only option for attack – no side-swiping and no missiles or energy abilities like in Wipeout or Blur – and there’s a technical depth to master with the drifting and boost timing, not to mention juggling energy.</p>
<p>In one race, I was able to break away in the lead, conserving my boosts in a way that meant I couldn’t be caught, but it felt much more likely to be caught in the middle of the pack and really have to scrap and fight. That ties in very well with the team race mode, with duos or trios battling for victory. This isn’t about the first across the line, and it’s not even just the combined finishing positions that determine the winning team, as every KO also awards points, so that the highest-placed racer might have finished eighth and outscore the winner that didn’t have a single KO to their name.</p>
<p>After adapting to its style of racing, Screamer really started to speak to me. I’m definitely curious to see how the game will blend together its anime narrative and single-player racing scenarios, but that combination of racing and combat? Well, it makes perfect sense for anyone who watched the F1 movie.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/17/screamer-preview-how-milestone-built-their-arcade-racer-for-combat/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: What's Your Favourite Gen 4 Pokémon?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-whats-your-favourite-gen-4-pokemon</link>
            <guid>1438312</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Sinnohs</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="1936f21dd03e1"><a title="Pokemon Diamond" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1936f21dd03e1/pokemon-diamond.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Jim Norman / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Pokémon turns 30 on 27th February, and in honour of this momentous anniversary, we're running a series of polls leading up to the big day, asking you to vote for your favourite Pokémon from each generation. The nine winners will then go head-to-head in a final poll at the end of the month.</p>
<p>We're covering a generation a day until we've ticked off all nine, leading up to the ultimate showdown. <strong>Each poll will be open for five days</strong>.</p>
<p>It's Day Four, which means fourth-Gen 'mon from Sinnoh and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_diamond_and_pearl">Pokémon Diamond, Pearl</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_platinum">Platinum</a>. Before we get down to it, let's see which under-the-radar Pokémon Team NL is considering before casting their vote.</p><div><figure data-videoid="Igg8EW7CDl0" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Igg8EW7CDl0?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><p><iframe id="ytIgg8EW7CDl0" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Igg8EW7CDl0?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Igg8EW7CDl0?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed395a12uimtpl&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe></p></figure></div>




<p>Let's crack on. A mere 107 new Pokémon this generation, listed in National Dex order - although you can use the search bar to quickly find a particular monster. And as ever, <strong>you can only choose one!</strong></p>

<hr>
<p><em>Thanks for voting! Keep an eye out for further generations in the coming days as we cruise towards Pokémon's 30th anniversary.</em></p>
<p><em>And if you missed Gens 1, 2, or 3, those polls are still live:<br></em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:197281,197283,197402,197536 @ 1771344006 --></section></article><div><p>Gavin first wrote for Nintendo Life in 2018 before joining the site full-time the following year, rising through the ranks to become Editor. He can currently be found squashed beneath a Switch backlog the size of Normandy.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/dartmonkey"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('dartmonkey');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-whats-your-favourite-gen-4-pokemon]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Relooted Review - Restoring Pride & Ownership To African Art History]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/relooted-review-restoring-pride-ownership-to-african-art-history</link>
            <guid>1438309</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>On the surface,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/relooted-is-unique-heist-game-for-2d-platforming-speedrun-fans" rel="nofollow"><em>Relooted</em> first appeared to be a very intriguing game</a> to be introduced to the industry, solely based on its overarching narrative. Since its reveal during the Day of the Devs showcase last year, there have been increased yet negative conversations regarding the controversial subject matter of cultural repatriation, rooted in misinformation and racism.</p><p>As such, one was quite cautious, maybe concerned about how nuanced developer Nyamakop will present its story and how it approached tackling this conversation, one that is still ongoing today.&nbsp;After hours of playtime,&nbsp;what&nbsp;it&nbsp;did was leave&nbsp;one feeling frustrated while raising some important questions regarding preservation and the future of modern museums&nbsp;regarding&nbsp;African art repatriation.</p><h2>Pulling Off Africa's Biggest Heist Of The Century</h2><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/relooted_review_screenshot-1261-rescuing_trevor_nyamakop_0.jpg?itok=t11yb_KU 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1337" height="752">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/relooted_review_screenshot-1261-rescuing_trevor_nyamakop_0.jpg?itok=ld48ELrs 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p>Nyamakop's 2D side-scrolling puzzle platformer,&nbsp;<em>Relooted</em>, is set in a semi-futuristic&nbsp;city&nbsp;of Johannesburg, South Africa, where&nbsp;we find&nbsp;the game's protagonist, Nomali,&nbsp;embarking&nbsp;on a&nbsp;dangerous mission to rescue her younger brother, Trevor.&nbsp;What follows is Nomali being convinced by her art historian grandmother,&nbsp;Professor Grace,&nbsp;to form a ragtag group of vigilante thieves in a high-stakes mission to reclaim stolen artifacts from the African continent and beyond in an effort to return them home.</p><p>Within the context of&nbsp;<em>Relooted</em> in&nbsp;the 21st century, the Transatlantic Returns Treaty has been&nbsp;put into power, operating as an intermediary body to ensure that African artifacts&nbsp;will be&nbsp;safely returned to their place of origin.&nbsp;As expected, there is one major caveat, largely due to some interesting phrasing, that this is only applicable to cultural artifacts that are being publicly displayed in museums globally.</p><p>As such, some Western museums have opted to quietly remove the artifacts in question and place them in secure vaults,&nbsp;while&nbsp;private collectors have&nbsp;continued&nbsp;to keep theirs behind locked doors in&nbsp;private&nbsp;collections.&nbsp;Sure, those museums aren't committing anything illegal, but morally, it's quite a heinous thing to do if one isn't planning on returning them.</p><p>This is where Nomali, Trevor, and their team come&nbsp;into play, as they've been tasked&nbsp;to&nbsp;"bypass" the&nbsp;Transatlantic Returns Treaty by acting outside the law and reclaiming those artifacts.&nbsp;From the many great heist films,&nbsp;like&nbsp;<em>The Thomas Crown Affair</em>,&nbsp;<em>The Italian Job</em>, the&nbsp;<em>Ocean's trilogy</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Inception</em> as examples, planning a heist&nbsp;looks&nbsp;almost&nbsp;near&nbsp;effortless with careful planning, reconnaissance work, and exceptional&nbsp;team building by using&nbsp;every member's strengths to their advantage.</p><p>In the case of&nbsp;<em>Relooted</em>, the&nbsp;team Nomali builds&nbsp;are not hardened criminals nor have criminal backgrounds, but are skilled in their respective areas of expertise, which adds a shade of unpredictability that gives&nbsp;<em>Relooted</em> that&nbsp;thrilling charm.&nbsp;As the game progressed, more members were added, but with these additions came a greater risk of carelessness, overexposure, and&nbsp;failure that jeopardized their plans, team morale, and overall mission of returning priceless cultural artifacts to their native homelands.</p><h2>Reclaiming Africa's Cultural History</h2><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/relooted_review_screenshot-1301-artifact_library_nyamakop.jpg?itok=mocdDFMY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/relooted_review_screenshot-1301-artifact_library_nyamakop.jpg?itok=6_Ls5F5R 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p><em>Relooted</em> looks and plays like a well-designed side-scrolling platforming game, but due to the immense amount of research into the game's development lies a game with plenty of heart, soul, and reverence. Relooted features 70 cultural artifacts from the African continent and a few from other cultures outside Africa.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.shacknews.com/article/144812/relooted-is-a-stylish-and-topical-heist-game-about-doing-crime-for-the-right-reasons" rel="nofollow">a Shacknews interview with Nyamakop's Creative Director Ben Myers</a>, the team employed full-time researchers who assisted and advised the development team with deciding which historical and cultural artifacts would be included in-game. <em>"Not a lot of people realize the scale of African artifacts that aren't in Africa,"</em> and as such, for the developers, <em>"a lot of the research was finding the most interesting stories, trying to find artifacts that had huge cultural [or] spiritual importance to the people they were taken from."</em></p><p>Within the context of <em>Relooted</em>, Nomali's art historian grandmother mentions that any and all African artifacts that are returned under the&nbsp;Transatlantic Returns Treaty are granted once a deal is brokered. However, much like in real life, where certain bodies and countries just outright decline to return these historical and cultural African artifacts back to their place of origin, the same situation is being played out in-game.</p><p>It has been publicly documented within the media over the last few decades that many African countries have pleaded with museums, private bodies, and organizations to return stolen artifacts to Africa. An example was 39 pieces that were returned to the Ugandan government by the University of Cambridge in 2024; however, the condition was that they were loaned back to the government for a three-year period, which can be extended,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/africa-stolen-artifacts-colonial-deaccessioning-repatriation/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">according to a news report from CBS News</a>.</p><p>Similarly, Germany has promised to return 1,130 artifacts to Nigeria in 2022, with 22 Benin Bronzes already back in the country, based on&nbsp;<a href="https://apnews.com/article/africa-germany-berlin-13e1a65da1b08644d3c5d5032d24e426" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">reporting from the Associated Press</a>. Sadly, not all requests have been approved, as in 2018, <a href="https://www.theartnewspaper.com/2018/01/12/pariss-dapper-foundation-stalls-talks-over-cameroonian-sculpture" rel="nofollow">the Dapper Foundation has stalled talks to return the&nbsp;Bangwa Queen</a>, which is featured in&nbsp;<em>Relooted</em>, and is still being held in France despite requests for it to be returned to Cameroon.</p><p>These cultural pieces still hold great religious significance in their respective countries in today's modern times, yet despite being looted as rewards for the violence invoked across the continent, the request for them to be returned is being denied on the basis that they best belong in the gilded halls of museums around the world. <em>Relooted</em> greatly emphasizes the need for increased dialogue surrounding cultural repatriation by placing&nbsp;a lot of care, dedication, and great detail into highlighting and restoring the historical significance of these artifacts.</p><p>Not only are the artifacts intricately recreated by talented 3D artists, but each artifact has well-researched descriptions and is accurately pronounced in the dialogue. <em>"And then we also had a woman who produced our pronunciation guide to make sure the way the artifacts and ethnicities are pronounced is correct and accurate, too,”</em> Myers explained in the&nbsp;Shacknews interview.</p><h2>Error Controls In The Planning Phase</h2><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/relooted_review_screenshot-1331-pre_planning_heist_heavy_heads_nyamakop.jpg?itok=lT2XBksb 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1483" height="834">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/relooted_review_screenshot-1331-pre_planning_heist_heavy_heads_nyamakop.jpg?itok=Sb_08UNi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p><em>Relooted</em> has many tremendous components to love and appreciate, especially given the great level of detail that went into the research and development of the game. While <em>Relooted</em> offers a new, fresh, and nuanced experience that one has never seen in the industry to date, the game is held back by some technical and creative issues that were annoying or confusing at times.</p><p>A combination of controller issues, gameplay bugs relating to the parkour movement and wall-jumping, and game crashes were the most prevalent technical issues that had one forcibly close the game before relaunching. Sadly, this meant having to backtrack on progress, as the auto-save feature didn't kick in to advance the game and its narrative.</p><p>Dealing with controller issues was annoying at times, as some incidents were isolated from other issues. However, it becomes&nbsp;frustrating when it snowballs&nbsp;with other problems, resulting in lost gameplay time and important saved progress if the auto-save wasn't triggered.</p><p>The game's platforming was quite an arduous experience, especially in certain locations like the House of Horrors and the Shiny Place heist locations, as timed jumps and speed boosts felt like they were on a delay or couldn't clear gaps with free-running and jumping distance. There were some hilarious ones to boot, like during the Maiden Voyage training session, where, during the Ndedi training session, smashing into a window left one in a glitched state and suspended mid-air, which surely was added to the <strong>"Funny Screenshot Moments"</strong> folder.</p><p>As an addendum, one noticed the disconnect between the planning phase and the heist itself, as many of the questions raised and inquiries asked didn't correspond to the plans that eventually unfolded in the subsequent heist mission, other than finding the artifacts and marking a path to the exit. It is certain that some technical issues are likely to be patched in the coming weeks; what could be slightly improved on is the disjointed character interactions and dialogue options during gameplay.</p><p>Some of the performances didn't feel compelling enough to care about certain characters, and there wasn't enough natural or organic chemistry where actors would play off of each other. This wasn't the case in a handful of the cutscenes, naturally, as the interactions were more convincing and well-performed, but the gameplay performances left more to be desired, which is not the fault of the actors but possibly the voice direction that was given.</p><h2><em>Relooted</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/relooted_review_screenshot-1281-nomali_scouting_nyamakop.jpg?itok=fSC7CXxn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1408" height="792">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/relooted_review_screenshot-1281-nomali_scouting_nyamakop.jpg?itok=ElpJjFRt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p>Undoubtedly, <em>Relooted</em> is a game unlike anything we've seen in today's gaming landscape, which is certainly needed. As a heist sidescrolling platformer, it checks most of the boxes, providing a decent platforming experience, albeit with some technical issues hindering it.</p><p>Where it shines the brightest is that it serves as a historical reminder of the continual aftermath of colonialism by illustrating the broad scale of the violent plundering of cultural artifacts by its oppressors. While some have made their way back home, there are still thousands of artifacts that are being withheld by museums, private collections, and other institutions.</p><p>In the end, the game recontextualizes the "treasure hunter" trope we see all too often by giving us, the players, the power to do the right thing in reclaiming artifacts and returning them home. This may be some kind of dream come true, but maybe, just maybe, getting to make history by writing a new chapter illustrating that taking back what belongs to them is the right and honorable thing to do.</p><hr><p><em><strong>Relooted</strong> was reviewed on PC via Steam, with a copy provided by the publisher over the course of 20 hours&nbsp;- all screenshots were taken during the review.</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/relooted-review-restoring-pride-ownership-to-african-art-history]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crusader Kings 3 devs Paradox are working with a mystery modder on spreadsheeting up the inbred monarch grind]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crusader-kings-3-devs-paradox-are-working-with-a-mystery-modder-on-spreadsheeting-up-the-inbred-monarch-grind</link>
            <guid>1438306</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Your castle might have columns already, but not like these ones</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crusader-kings-3-ledger-mystery-modder-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crusader-kings-3-ledger-mystery-modder-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crusader-kings-3-ledger-mystery-modder-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crusader-kings-3-ledger-mystery-modder-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crusader-kings-3-ledger-mystery-modder-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crusader-kings-3-ledger-mystery-modder-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crusader-kings-3-ledger-mystery-modder-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crusader-kings-3-ledger-mystery-modder-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crusader-kings-3-ledger-mystery-modder-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Paradox</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I wake up at 3AM. Do 50 pull-ups on a halberd wedged in the door frame. Do 50 push-ups on the cold stone floor. A servant hands me my protein mead and a wine frappamachiato. I violently double fist the two beverages. I don't eat breakfast, because food that isn't flavourless cup gruel is the enemy of productivity. Then, I'm dressed in my robes for the commute to the throne room. The magic starts. It's 5AM in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/crusader-kings-iii">Crusader Kings 3</a> and I'm on my medieval monarch grindset.</p>
<p>I pull out Paradox's <a href="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/developer-diary/dev-diary-192-spring-cleaning.1902372/">latest dev diary</a>. Oh, look at that, they're working with a mystery modder on bringing exactly the sort of big number tables to the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy game</a> that I need to tell at a glance whether I'm out-grinding my inbred wealth-creating cousins who rule other nations across the world.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>These big number tables are dubbed The Ledger, and once added to CK3 as part of the game's next major update, they'll give you a big spreadsheet to delve into if you're keen to look up certain aspects of your kingverse. For example, you can quickly check which ruler across the world has the most gold without having to click on them all, or see which of the current crop of wars has been running the longest.</p>
<p>Handy, and according to Paradox design manager Riad Deneche it's the product of some direct collaboration between the studio and a mystery modder whose identity will be revealed in a future dev blog. "Much of their work had already inspired us internally and influenced changes we’d made to the game," the developer wrote. "When I reached out, instead of assigning a predefined task, I asked a simple question: what would you like to work on? They came back with a list so large it genuinely shocked the team. Some of it overlapped with things already in our pipeline, but a lot of it made us collectively ask, 'How did we not think of this?'"</p><p>The Ledger was one of those ideas, and the initial version of it's set to include tabs covering characters, artifacts, ongoing Wars, and houses. All things you might want to sort through, compare or just check up on if you're loading up a save you've put a lot of hours into for the first time in a while. I can't say I've been playing CK3 long enough to have any properly ancient games to return to, but even a couple of weeks gap between checking on my weird Scottish co-monarchy can leave me struggling to remember off the top of my head what's going on.</p>
<p>The likes of counties, titles, holdings, faiths and cultures are also being considered for tabs of their own, and Deneche points out that modders will likely come up with ones the developers don't think to add. Quite frankly, I'll be happy if I can sort monarchs by their percentage of inbredness or courtiers by how much they hate me.</p>
<p>The update that'll bring the ledger and a number of other quality-of-life additions/fixes is currently slated to arrive at the start of Q2, which if my understanding of corporatese is right will put it around the beginning of April.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crusader-kings-3-devs-paradox-are-working-with-a-mystery-modder-on-spreadsheeting-up-the-inbred-monarch-grind]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come Deliverance II And The Witcher 3 Are Coming To Xbox Game Pass]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-witcher-3-xbox-game-pass-2000669707</link>
            <guid>1438285</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Two of the biggest, most popular and most utterly enormous RPGs of the recent era are coming to Xbox Game Pass in the next few weeks. First, on February 19, the Complete Edition of <em>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</em> arrives on Microsoft’s gaming subscription platform, followed by&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</em> on March 3. And that’s alongside a bunch of other games of note.</p> <p>February has already seen the arrival of a preview build of RTS <em>Menace&nbsp;</em>and the arrival of&nbsp;<em>Diablo II: Resurrected&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>High on Life 2</em> to Game Pass, which is hard to sniff at (until you remember that <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-price-hike-cod-2000632122">Microsoft increased the price</a> of the subscription from $20 to $30 a month last year). But the second half of the month is much more busy, starting today with the addition of&nbsp;<em>Aerial_Knight’s DropShot</em>, and Ubisoft’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisofts-avatar-game-is-so-much-better-than-fire-and-ash-2000659445">surprisingly great</a>&nbsp;<em>Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</em>. Additionally, Obsidian’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-xbox-pc-rpg-game-pass-skyrim-review-kotaku-1851761525">wonderful RPG</a>&nbsp;<em>Avowed</em> is brought down from Ultimate to Premium, to let more people in.</p>

 <p>Coming up in a couple of days is&nbsp;<em>Death Howl</em>, a deckbuilder that was already on PC Game Pass and is now spreading its spiritual wings to console, joined by last July’s <em>EA Sports College Football 26.</em> And then there’s the rather large matter of <em>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</em>‘s return to Game Pass after leaving way back in 2021. This time the CD Projekt RPG is in its updated Complete Edition form. (It’s worth noting you <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sub/124923/">can grab the same from Steam</a> for just $10 right now.)</p> <p>Another game preview arrives Feb 24 with&nbsp;<em>TCG Card Shop Simulator</em>, which hopefully won’t include regular break-ins from which to recover. The next day, PC Game Pass gets dice-rolling roguelike <em>Dice a Million</em>, and the day after that, on Feb. 26, action-RPG <em>Towerborne</em> comes out of early access as a fully finished release.</p>

 <p>Jump to March 3 (presumably February is just too short of a month to cram it all in) and two more big names get squished in. First is <em>Final Fantasy III</em>, and then the headliner, <em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</em>. Last year’s action-RPG from Warhorse was a smash hit, and despite the company’s CEO and director Daniel Vavra having been <a href="https://kotaku.com/my-e3-meeting-with-a-pro-gamergate-developer-1715511964">a consistently destructive</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/we-keep-having-the-same-video-game-arguments-and-its-dr-1841027051">voice</a> in the industry, the game somehow managed to piss off all the worst people for its more progressive values. Hooray!</p>

 <p>Anyway, if&nbsp;<em>Witcher 3</em> and&nbsp;<em>KCDII</em> aren’t enough to keep you busy on top of <em>High on Life 2</em> and&nbsp;<em>Avatar</em>, I dunno how to help you.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-witcher-3-xbox-game-pass-2000669707]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Things I Learned From Attending Pokémon EUIC 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/6-things-i-learned-from-attending-pokemon-euic-2026/</link>
            <guid>1438279</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Pokémon franchise is set for arguably the biggest year ever, with the 30th anniversary celebrations coming alongside major releases, significant changes to the competitive scene, and there’s likely to be even more on the horizon.</p>



<p>After the success of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/pokemon-legends-z-a/" id="2273" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> last year, a boom in the TCG hobby, and two releases already confirmed for the year ahead with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/pokemon-pokopia/" id="2965" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokopia</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/pokemon-champions/" id="2457" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon Champions</a>, 2026 is set to be a big one, and Pokémon EUIC displayed the very best that the franchise has to offer.</p>



<p>Across four action-packed days in London for Pokémon EUIC, here are the main takeaways I learned from the event.</p>







<h3 id="h-pokemon-s-growth-shows-no-signs-of-stopping">Pokémon’s Growth Shows No Signs of Stopping</h3>



<figure><figcaption>The boom continues. Image via The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p>Pokémon’s boom in the past decade, following the release of Pokémon Go, has been well-documented, and excitement for the franchise has reached fever-pitch levels heading into the 30th anniversary. However, it’s clear that this isn’t the height of the peak.</p>



<p>The attendance at Pokémon EUIC was over 17,000, including over 7,000 competitors, numbers that dwarf the Pokémon World Championships attendance from London 2022. Around a third of ExCel London was taken over by Pokémon, and there’s still plenty of room to grow.</p>



<p>With the VGC format moving to Pokémon Champions, lowering the barrier of entry as the title will also be available on mobile devices, and the Pokémon games venturing into new genres, Pikachu and the gang are here to stay.</p>



<h3 id="h-pokopia-could-be-the-next-pokemon-go-like-hit">Pokopia Could Be The Next Pokémon Go-Like Hit</h3>



<p>The release of Pokopia is now just a few weeks away, and the latest entry in the Pokémon franchise blew me away in my <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-pokopia-hands-on-preview/" id="176556" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hands-on preview</a>, showing it can have the same sort of momentum that Pokémon Go did a decade ago.</p>



<p>Pokémon Go was a title that spread like wildfire across the world, bringing new fans into the Pokémon franchise, and Pokopia has the ability to do the same. With an Animal Crossing-like approach and a clear cozy vibe, new gamers could be attracted, and diehard fans will also be thrilled with the experience.</p>



<p>The Pokémon Company has not been afraid to venture into new genres and try out new things in recent years, and fans can reap the benefits.</p>



<h3 id="h-lego-pokemon-sets-are-incredible">LEGO Pokémon Sets Are Incredible</h3>



<p>Ever since the first reveal of the debut <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-pokemon-scavenger-hunt-codes/" id="169235" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LEGO Pokémon</a> sets, it was clear that they were going to make waves, but having now seen the sets in person, they completely blew my socks off.</p>



<p>There are no stickers on the sets, with the eyes and any other accents all printed directly to the bricks, showing a more premium approach to the set. Of course, with the high prices of LEGO, fans will expect the very best, and this is exactly what they are getting.</p>



<p>It’s not long now until the LEGO Pokémon sets will arrive in the hands of fans worldwide, and I can’t wait to see what other sets are on the horizon this year.</p>



<h3 id="h-competitive-pokemon-is-much-tougher-than-i-imagined">Competitive Pokémon is Much Tougher Than I Imagined</h3>



<p>I’ve always been more of a collector in the world of Pokémon, both in the games, hunting down everything needed to fill out my Pokédex and in the world of the TCG, and I truly had no idea just how tough the competitive scene truly is.</p>



<p>The tactical approaches in the VGC scene were far beyond what I could envision, with competitors always trying to be two steps ahead, and my head was spinning with the knowledge those in the TCG had. Add in the quick reactions of those playing UNITE and Go, and it was incredible to witness.</p>



<p>Esports continues to grow and will have greater prominence in the years to come, and Pokémon will certainly have a big part to play.</p>



<h3 id="h-pokemon-world-championships-is-a-bucket-list-addition">Pokémon World Championships Is A Bucket List Addition</h3>



<p>The one major thought that stuck with me throughout the weekend at EUIC and since I returned home is that I need to attend a World Championship, and I’ve got my eyes on San Francisco in August.</p>



<p>I loved every single second of Pokémon EUIC, and attending such a huge event has immediately led to attending Worlds jumping into my bucket list.</p>



<p>I highly recommend that any Pokémon fan look to attend one of the major events, and to keep an eye out for Pokémon Play! Schedules, to meet other members of the community and have an experience you’ll remember for the rest of your lives.</p>







<p>There’s no denying there’s a lot of negativity often spread around Pokémon, particularly on the TCG side of things, and the difficulty getting your hands on sealed product, but there was zero sign of this at EUIC.</p>



<p>Instead, the weekend was filled with moments that show the very best of the Pokémon community. One parent of a competitor in the Junior TCG category told me about how other parents rallied to help create a replacement deck after an initial one was lost, ensuring they wouldn’t have to exit the tournament. While the original deck was found, the new deck, including cards from a variety of languages, showed the very best of the community.</p>



<p>Throughout the entire event, everyone I spoke to was welcoming, there was absolutely no gatekeeping, and every attendee was there to share their love of the Pokémon franchise.</p>







<hr>



<p>Did you attend Pokémon EUIC in London? What did you think about the event? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Pokémon, take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-euic-2026-schedule-scores/" id="175823" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all the winners from EUIC 2026</a>, and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-pokopia-switch-2-exclusive-all-platforms/" id="177280" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">platform details for Pokopia</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/6-things-i-learned-from-attending-pokemon-euic-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Piece by Piece for PC launches March 11]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/piece-by-piece-for-pc-launches-march-11</link>
            <guid>1438276</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New demo now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Cozy repair shop <a title="Genres > Simulation [939 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Piece by Piece [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/piece-by-piece">Piece by Piece</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,528 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3179050/Piece_by_Piece/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 11, publisher <a title="Companies > No More Robots [30 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/no-more-robots">No More Robots</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Gamkat [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gamkat">Gamkat</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3179050/view/603055190765994293" target="_blank">announced</a>. A Switch version is also <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/cozy-repair-shop-simulation-game-piece-by-piece-announced-for-switch-pc">planned</a>, but was not dated as part of today’s announcement. <span id="more-1027188"></span></p><p>A new demo is also available now, featuring updated textures, lighting, visual effects, and dialogues, a refreshed user interface, improved performance, additional customization items, and improved gameplay. It supports English, French, Spanish, German, Brazilian Portuguese, Simplified Chinese, and Japanese language options.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3179050/Piece_by_Piece/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Piece by Piece</em> is a cute repair shop simulator about helping forest animals fix up their broken gadgets and gizmos.</p><p>Are we for real? We absolutely are. Inherit your family’s repair shop, roll up your sleeves, and get to work fixing, painting, baking, planting, sweeping, mixing and piecing back together dozens of family heirlooms, toys, and beloved items from a variety of woodland creatures.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>If you think this’ll be a walk in the park, Piece by Piece is going to outfox you. Each day you’ll need to tidy up your store, attend to anyone who needs help, then throw a bunch of stuff on sale and see if you can make a tasty profit. Being a good Samaritan is great and all, but this fox needs to put food on the table!</p><p>Customize your shop with different colors and materials, grow plants and mix paint, spruce up the items that pass through the store, bake cookies for your neighbors, and listen to the latest gossip. There’s plenty to do in the world of Piece by Piece, and plenty of cute critters to share your story with.</p><p><strong>Key Featurse</strong></p><ul><li>Piece together antiques, heirlooms, and favorite mugs for your customers, each with its own puzzle!</li><li>Grow berries in your back garden to mix up into colorful paints, and paint up a storm</li><li>Customize your creations with a splash of color, then sell them for a profit</li><li>Keep your shop in check by cleaning up the floor, keeping the fire lit and the cookie jar full</li><li>Make your shop your own by picking out furniture, rugs and more!</li></ul></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/piece-by-piece-for-pc-launches-march-11]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision is shutting down Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/activision-is-shutting-down-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile</link>
            <guid>1438273</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-template="layout" data-theme="theme2"><nav data-module="navigation" aria-label="navigation"><div data-testid="header" data-component="informa-bar"><div data-testid="informa-bar-left-section"><p>Together, we power an unparalleled network of 220+ online properties covering 10,000+ granular topics, serving an audience of 50+ million professionals with original, objective content from trusted sources. We help you gain critical insights and make more informed decisions across your business priorities.</p></div><p>This site is operated by a business or businesses owned by Informa PLC and all copyright resides with them. Informa PLC's registered office is 5 Howick Place, London SW1P 1WG. Registered in England and Wales. Number 8860726.</p></div></nav><div data-testid="article-base-body" data-template="article"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr<!-- -->,</a><p><span data-testid="contributor-title">Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 17, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span data-testid="article-read-time-text">1 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Newsbrief:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Activision is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://support.activision.com/warzone-mobile/articles/warzone-mobile-service-changes">shutting down</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on April 17, 2026, after the shooter fell short of expectations.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The title had already effectively been laid to rest after being </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/activision-is-delisting-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-after-one-year">pulled from stores in May 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. At the same time, Activision confirmed it would be ending support in the form of seasonal content, social features, gameplay updates, and in-app purchases using in real currency.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Warzone Mobile</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> launched in March 2024 for iOS and Android after a number of delays. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.pocketgamer.biz/call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-ready-for-battle-with-50-million-players-on-board/">According to PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, it garnered 50 million pre-registrations prior to launch but has evidently failed to retain the interest of players.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div><div data-module="newsletter-signup-promo"><p>Daily news, dev blogs, and stories from Game Developer straight to your inbox</p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/activision-is-shutting-down-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embark Studios is cracking down on players who abused Arc Raiders' recent duplication exploit and other glitches]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/embark-studios-details-actions-against-exploits-and-glitches-abusers</link>
            <guid>1438270</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Arc-Raiders-deluxe-set.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Arc-Raiders-deluxe-set.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Arc-Raiders-deluxe-set.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Arc-Raiders-deluxe-set.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Arc-Raiders-deluxe-set.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Arc-Raiders-deluxe-set.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Arc-Raiders-deluxe-set.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Arc-Raiders-deluxe-set.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Arc-Raiders-deluxe-set.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> continues to enjoy tons of success, nearing <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-had-nearly-1000000-concurrent-players-last-month-and-thats-on-pc-alone">almost 1m concurrent players </a>on PC alone and pushing onwards with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-shared-watch-event-rewards-pve">events</a> and regular updates <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/roadmap-january-april-2026">planned out until April</a>. Its <em>actual health </em>hasn't been great in 2026 so far though.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, a <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/third-person-shooter/arc-raiders-latest-duplication-glitch-has-players-placing-hundreds-of-ziplines-and-trigger-nades-and-safe-to-say-its-scaring-everyone-i-hope-this-gets-addressed-soon/">massive duplication glitch</a> allowed cheeky players to double anything they were holding in their hands, which translated in maps littered with all sorts of traps and ziplines, among other things. Game balance issues aside, this was also bad for performance in especially crowded areas, so you can imagine why Embark Studios needed to act quickly on that whole mess.</p>
<p>Right after a hotfix was deployed to deal with the duplication glitch, another problem arose: <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/third-person-shooter/arc-raiders-immediately-suffers-an-infinite-ammo-exploit-after-embark-fixes-a-dupe-heightening-criticism-of-the-studios-soft-response-to-cheaters/">an infinite ammo exploit</a>. This one also affected magazine sizes and even gun durability, which completely demolished Arc Raiders' in-game economy and the loop of looting and making do with whatever you can scavenge and preserve. In the following weeks, Embark has been hitting the game hard with <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/1808500/allnews/">patches</a>, both small and large, ahead of <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/third-person-shooter/arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-update-arrives-next-week-embark-confirms-but-there-will-be-no-major-game-update-this-week-to-tide-you-over-until-then/">this month's 'Shrouded Sky' content update</a>.</p>
<p>Today, 17th February, the developers also confirmed <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/an-update-on-recent-exploits-and-corrective-actions">they'd finished conducting a large investigation</a> into how the recent exploits and glitches came to be and how to deal with offenders now and in the future. "Though these exploits stemmed from a design flaw on our part, the way they were used had a real impact on the game's economy and the way the community experienced ARC Raiders. It's on us to address that and work to restore balance," the article states before elaborating on why it's taken a while to see more substantial comms regarding all this drama.</p><p>Though the studios is supposedly better prepared for future events like these, the powers that be are warning they'll "be taking actions based on severity, intent, frequency, and impact." Warnings will be issued for "low-severity cases," coins obtained through these glitches will be deleted, and suspensions will be dished out for the "severe cases" that completely ruined other players' fun.</p>
<p>Embark is fully aware this won't be the last time it has to deal with rampaging exploits and whatnot, and is encouraging lawful raiders to share their findings through the game's <a href="https://discord.com/invite/arcraiders">official Discord sever</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/embark-studios-details-actions-against-exploits-and-glitches-abusers]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Pokopia Has The Best Approach To Multiplayer Possible, With One Caveat]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-ghost-pikachu-peakychu-cloud-island-2000669710</link>
            <guid>1438255</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-release-date-switch-2-multiplayer-ditto-2000660646"><i><span>Pokémon Pokopia</span></i></a> <span>is taking a page from </span><i><span>Minecraft </span></i><span>in how it handles shared worlds between players. Rather than taking the </span><i><span>Animal Crossing </span></i><span>approach where each island has a “host” player that must be present for you to access it, </span><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>is giving players persistent worlds that no one person has to be online for you to reach. That way, multiple players can cultivate one of its reinvigorated Pokémon towns without having to drag one person into the play session, though it will have some restrictions.</span></p> <p><span>In an interview with </span><a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202602/66124"><i><span>Famitsu</span></i></a><span> (translated by </span><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/simulation/pokemon-pokopia-follows-minecrafts-lead-in-featuring-persistent-private-servers-with-unlimited-member-caps-but-youll-have-to-swap-in-and-out-as-it-only-accommodates-four-at-once/"><i><span>GamesRadar</span></i><span>+</span></a><span>), </span><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>chief director Takuto Edagawa explained that the life sim will use a feature Koei Tecmo calls “cloud island,” which allows multiple players to access an island regardless of whether the island’s owner is present. However, only four players will be able to enter the island at the same time. So even though no one person has to be in the game at that moment, you can’t have dozens of players building all at once.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>“There is a different system that is unique to this game called the ‘cloud island,’” Edagawa said. “This is an island that everyone can create together, and even if the host (the island’s owner) is not online, everyone is free to join and play. If you can’t find the time to meet up and play together, you can still work together to build the island little by little in your free time.”</span></p> <p><span>So if you’ve got more than three friends who want to contribute to the island, they’ve gotta wait in line, which is a shame. I have a group of friends I’d love to make an island with, but it sounds like the game’s limitations will make that a more arduous process than in something like </span><i><span>Minecraft</span></i><span>.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000644026" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000644026"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000644026">© The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure> <p><span>While the presence of persistent islands is good news, the bad news is that we have more details on the ghost-like Peakychu, the white Pikachu who is one of the new forms with </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-post-apocalypse-snorlax-pikachu-fuschia-2000644400"><span>terrifying post-apocalyptic implications</span></a><span> that will show up in </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>. Speaking with </span><i><span>Famitsu</span></i><span> (once again translated by </span><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/adventure/pokemon-pokopias-new-pikachu-form-was-dubbed-unfortunate-pikachu-by-co-dev-koei-tecmo-but-it-comes-from-a-place-of-love-we-were-surprised-and-thrilled/"><i><span>GamesRadar+</span></i></a><span>), Edagawa said that Peakychu was dubbed “unfortunate Pikachu” by the team after they saw its design, which was created by </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>developer Game Freak, so if you were worried that Koei Tecmo was creating some kind of unsanctioned version of </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span>’s mascot, it sounds like Peakychu, the moss-covered Snorlax called Mosslax, and other alternate forms in </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span> are coming straight from the source. Edagawa says that Peakychu has a“temporal and melancholy feel,” which sure sounds like she’s a ghost of some kind. Is she dead? Is she dying? We’ll find out when </span><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>comes out on Switch 2 on March 5.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-ghost-pikachu-peakychu-cloud-island-2000669710]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clickout Media, Owner Of The Escapist, Pivots To AI, Holds Mass Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/clickout-media-owner-of-the-escapist-pivots-to-ai-holds-mass-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>1438252</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Clickout Media, owner of websites such as Esports Insider and The Escapist, has told its staff that they are being laid off. The layoffs come just a week after they began laying off freelancers and pausing all future freelance hires. </p>







<p>Insider Gaming understands that the company is making a heavy pivot to AI content, resulting in almost all of its editorial staff being let go.</p>



<p>It was said that Clickout Media will be maintaining a skeleton crew of “AI Editors.”</p>



<p><strong>“Sad to say that my role at The Escapist is up for redundancy, and that means a lot of things that I’m still not quite getting my head around,”</strong> The Escapist writer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/lloydcoombes_sad-to-say-that-my-role-at-the-escapist-is-activity-7429538899200270336--5Xj/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Lloyd Coombes wrote</a>, though he did not mention the AI pivot in his posting.</p>



<p>It’s also believed that employees being let go are being forced to sign an NDA from speaking publicly about the layoffs, at risk of not receiving their severance payouts. </p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Clickout Media for comment on the layoffs and AI pivot. As of publishing, a response has not been received. </p>



<p>This is a developing story and will be updated as more information becomes available.</p>







<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/six-games-ubisoft-canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">six games canceled at Ubisoft</a>&nbsp;when it announced its recent restructure. And for even more Insider Gaming delivered directly to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>



<p><em>Editor’s Note: Article edited for clarity</em></p>






        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/clickout-media-owner-of-the-escapist-pivots-to-ai-holds-mass-layoffs/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Marathon Have Crossplay? Cross-Platform Status, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/does-marathon-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained/</link>
            <guid>1438249</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/marathon/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/marathon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marathon</a> is almost ready to be shared with the world, with the multiplayer extraction shooter arriving on multiple platforms at launch. However, that poses the question: Will Marathon have crossplay and cross-progression?</p>







<p>It’s a common question when it comes to multiplayer titles, especially for scattered friend groups dispersed between the likes of PlayStation, Xbox and PC. Although it’s more common these days, not every title offers crossplay, so it’s important to check before deciding whether Marathon will be your next multiplayer game.</p>



<h2 id="h-does-marathon-have-crossplay">Does Marathon Have Crossplay?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Friend or foe? Image by Bungie.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Yes, Marathon does have Crossplay across all platforms, allowing you to team up with friends across PC, Xbox, and PlayStation.</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/bungie/" id="99" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bungie</a> is no stranger to multiplayer shooters, as it’s mastered the art of juggling multiple platforms with the likes of Destiny 2. It looks like that will translate directly to Marathon, as anyone on any platform can engage with one another directly from launch.</p>



<p>It will be turned on by default, and it works through Bungie, meaning you won’t need to be signed into any external accounts. However, if you prefer to stick to dealing with those on your platform, it will also be toggleable in the menu. </p>



<h2 id="h-does-marathon-have-cross-progression">Does Marathon Have Cross-Progression?</h2>



<p><strong>Yes, Marathon will also have cross-progression at launch, meaning your save data will transfer between any platform you decide to play on. </strong></p>



<p>If you decide to pick the game up on console, but change your mind and switch to PC, then fear not, as all of your saved data and progression will transfer right over to the new platform. </p>







<p>Bungie hasn’t yet revealed the full details on how this operates, but it’s likely that it will work similarly to how Destiny 2 handles cross-progression. It all revolves around your Bungie ID, which ties your saved data together. Just sign in to the same account, and everything should be right where you left it.</p>



<hr>



<p>What platform will you be picking Marathon up on? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" id="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<p>For more Marathon content, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-release-date-exact-start-times/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-release-date-exact-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exact release times</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-marathon-on-xbox-game-pass/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/is-marathon-on-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whether it’s available on Xbox Game Pass</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/does-marathon-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Announces Xbox Game Pass February 2026 Wave 2 Lineup, Including Witcher 3 and Kingdom Come Deliverance 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-february-2026-wave-2-lineup-including-witcher-3-and-kingdom-come-deliverance-2</link>
            <guid>1438243</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft has announced the Xbox Game Pass February 2026 Wave 2 lineup, which includes big hitters such as The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt (and in its Complete Edition, no less) plus Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As detailed in a post on <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/02/17/xbox-game-pass-february-2026-wave-2/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xbox Wire</a>, available today, February 17, are Aerial_Knight’s DropShot (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, Handheld, and PC) and Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, Handheld, and PC) for PC and Ultimate subscribers. Premium members also gain access to Avowed (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, and PC) — as detailed in the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-february-2026-wave-1-lineup">first wave of February Xbox Game Pass titles</a> announced several weeks ago.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Coming later this week on February 19 is Death Howl (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, Handheld, and PC), as well as EA Sports College Football 26 (Cloud and Xbox Series X/S for Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscribers). And then it's onto the big guns: The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt – Complete Edition (Cloud and Console) also becomes available on February 19 for Game Pass Ultimate and Premium subscribers. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">TCG Card Shop Simulator launches into Game Preview (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, Handheld, and PC) on February 24 for Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass subscribers. A day later, Dice A Million launches on PC, for PC and Ultimate subscribers. Towerborne's full game release then turns up (Console, Handheld, and PC)  a day after <em>that</em>, on February 26, for Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass subscribers. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Final Fantasy 3 (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, and PC) arrives on March 3 for Game Pass Ultimate, Premium and PC Game Pass members. Finally, Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, and PC) becomes available on March 3 for Game Pass Ultimate, Premium and PC Game Pass members.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The arrival of The Witcher 3 comes at an interesting moment, as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-3-expansion-reports-continue-now-with-discussion-of-a-possible-dune-style-location">rumors swirl of a third expansion for the title</a> that's expected to arrive later this year and potentially bridge the gap between it and CD Projekt's The Witcher 4 (which is due in 2027 at the earliest).</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/02/17/xbox-gamepass-announcement-16x9-02-17-2026-en-us-e7643a95212ef5aaa178-1024x576-1771338396618.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Microsoft's Xbox Game Pass February 2026 Wave 2 additions. Image credit: Xbox</figcaption></figure></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Xbox Game Pass February 2026 Wave 2 lineup:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/death-howl">Death Howl</a> — February 19 (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, Handheld, and PC) – Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/college-football-26">EA Sports College Football 26</a> — February 19 (Cloud and Xbox Series X/S) – Game Pass Ultimate</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</a><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt"> - Complete Edition</a> — February 19 (Cloud and Console) – Game Pass Ultimate, Premium</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tcg-card-shop-simulator">TCG Card Shop Simulator</a> (Game Preview) — February 24 (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, Handheld, and PC) – Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass</li><li>Dice A Million — February 25 (PC) Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tcg-card-shop-simulator">Towerborne (Full Game Release)</a> — February 26 (Console, Handheld, and PC) – Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy-iii">Final Fantasy 3</a> — March 3 (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, and PC) – Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a> — March 3 (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, and PC) – Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass
</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">As ever, whenever Microsoft giveth, it also taketh away. Leaving Game Pass on February 28 are Monster Train, Expeditions: A MudRunner Game, Injustice 2 and Middle Earth: Shadow of War — all of which are currently available for Cloud, Console, and PC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-february-2026-wave-2-lineup-including-witcher-3-and-kingdom-come-deliverance-2]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rogue Prince of Persia Outlines 2026 Roadmap, Includes New Elements, Difficulties, Weapon Affixes, Tools, Parkour, And Arenas]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-outlines-2026-roadmap-includes-new-elements-difficulties-weapon-affixes-tools-parkour-and-arenas</link>
            <guid>1438240</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">While the promise of a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake"><u>Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake</u></a> disappeared along with several other games earlier this year, Prince of Persia fans still have spin-off <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-rogue-prince-of-persia">The Rogue Prince of Persia</a> — and now its team has unveiled a sizable 2026 spring roadmap.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2717880/view/541130614987817395?l=english" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a>, developer Evil Empire wished its community a happy 2026, and confirmed the addition of a Flaming Horses tool as a nod to lunar new Year of the Horse. This tool unleashes a herd of flaming horses that "charge forward, leaving a burning trail behind them."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We’ve always wanted a burning tool that works like Altan’s Bracelets, and the year of the fire horse provided the perfect creative spark," the team teased. "Plus, when you talk about Persian culture, you have to talk about the horse! From the Nisean Horse and the Royal Road to the legendary Rakhsh from the Shahnameh, horses are legendary."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That's not all, though. The "Breathless" update is slated to arrive with a public beta at the end of March, promising a "quicker and more intense" experience. This includes a rework of the game's first hour, tighter pacing and improvements to when and how you unlock new game content and new mechanics, as well as changes to bosses' difficulty. "Reworks of the level design of the first few biomes will also highlight our iconic wall-run move and make each biome quicker and tougher," developer Evil Empire said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are changes for established players, too, including a new Freeze element, which is coming with a new weapon, the slingshot, arenas — "zones that lock you in, and the only way out is to defeat wave after wave of enemies!" — and weapon affixes which can "make each weapon that appears in your run much more interesting and varied, giving you some difficult choices to take…"</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/02/17/2d9cdf0b6bc05c8d97ac894ffe426dc6da0d6309-1771332292329.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2717880/view/541130614987817395" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">full update</a>:</p><blockquote>The <strong>“Breathless update”</strong> will arrive with a public beta around the end of March! As you can guess from its title, this update means making the whole experience quicker and more intense, leaving you... breathless!</blockquote><blockquote>We have done a big rework of the pacing of the <strong>first hour,</strong> including when and how you will unlock new game content and new mechanics, as well as the bosses’ difficulty. Reworks of the level design of the first few biomes will also highlight our iconic wall-run move and make each biome <strong>quicker and tougher</strong>.</blockquote><blockquote>For <strong>veteran </strong>players who have been looking forward to new toys to play with, don't worry, we've got you covered! First up, we're introducing a new element - <strong>freeze </strong>– which is coming with a new weapon, the slingshot!</blockquote><blockquote>Next on the list is the <strong>arenas </strong>– zones that lock you in, and the only way out is to defeat wave after wave of enemies!</blockquote><blockquote>Most importantly, <strong>weapon affixes </strong>are coming too!! These affixes will make each weapon that appears in your run much more interesting and varied, giving you some difficult choices to take...</blockquote><blockquote><strong>End Game Update</strong></blockquote><blockquote>That's it for the first update, let's quickly talk about the <strong>second one!</strong></blockquote><blockquote>We're planning for it to land in early May, and some of the content may change, but we know what we'd like to do... It will focus on the End Game, plus bringing more challenges like Speed Run mode and Daily Awakening.</blockquote><blockquote>You'll be able to really test your skill and push the limit with this update coming! Speed, precision, and strategy—show us what you've got.</blockquote><blockquote><strong>From 2025 to 2026</strong></blockquote><blockquote><strong>Looking back on 2025</strong>, it was a big year for The Rogue Prince of Persia. We finally graduated from Early Access and increased the game’s <strong>Steam review score from 70%</strong> upon Early Access release to 88% so far with your support and help!</blockquote><blockquote>Of course, we're not just on Steam, we’ve also successfully brought the game to Switch, Xbox, and Playstation! Right now, we are almost at the point of having<strong> 1 million people</strong> who've played our game!</blockquote><blockquote>Even though we are only in the second month of 2026, the game has already achieved something else: we have been included in the <strong>Bafta awards longlist and gained 4 nominations at the french game awards ceremony PEGASUS</strong>, including best game. We’re crossing all the fingers and toes we have until March.</blockquote><blockquote>Following the awards season, <strong>vinyl and physical collector editions</strong> are also on the way! We believe it will be a great year for the rogue prince of persia, and we can’t wait to make this game better with you guys in 2026!</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-cancels-6-projects-including-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-closes-2-studios-and-confirms-further-layoffs-in-major-company-restructure"><u>Ubisoft began this year by announcing a sizable company restructure, resulting in the cancelation of six games</u></a>, including its Prince of Persia: Sands of Time remake, and a delay to a further seven titles. Two Ubisoft studios will close completely as a result of the changes, while others are subject to further layoffs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Prince of Persia creator Jordan Mechner <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/having-a-project-killed-is-a-brutal-experience-prince-of-persia-creator-reacts-to-sands-of-time-remake-cancelation"><u>recently reacted to Ubisoft's cancelation of its Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake</u></a>, describing the loss of any project as a "brutal experience" for developers. "A cancelation so close to release can be particularly devastating for younger team members who don't have decades of past shipped titles on their resumé," he said. "It's tough to suddenly absorb that the past four years of hard work you were proud of, and looking forward to seeing out in the world as your new calling card, will now never see daylight."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-outlines-2026-roadmap-includes-new-elements-difficulties-weapon-affixes-tools-parkour-and-arenas]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Styx: Blades of Greed and Star Trek: Voyager – Across the Unknown Launch with NVIDIA DLSS 4 with Multi-Frame Gen Support]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-multi-frame-gen-styx-blades-of-greed-star-trek-voyager/</link>
            <guid>1438216</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Just as every week brings another <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-geforce-now-amazon-fire-tv-app-reanimal-kingdom-come-deliverance/">GeForce NOW Thursda</a>y, we also get an <strong>NVIDIA DLSS 4</strong> Tuesday, with <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/news/star-trek-voyager-styx-blades-of-greed-dlss-4-multi-frame-gen/">a new batch of games</a> adding support for NVIDIA's DLSS 4 with Multi-Frame Generation technology. </p>



<p>This week, two games are launching with support for NVIDIA DLSS 4:<strong> Styx: Blades of Greed</strong>, the return of the stealth-driven action adventure, and <strong>Star Trek: Voyager - Across the Unknown</strong>, a new strategy management game where you have to try to manage the crew of the U.S.S. Voyager and get the ship out of deep space and back to Earth.</p>



<p>Both games also arrive with support for NVIDIA Reflex and DLSS Super Resolution, which those with the NVIDIA app can upgrade to DLSS 4.5 Super Resolution. </p>



<p><strong>NORSE: Oath of Blood</strong> is another game that's launching this week with support for some of NVIDIA's DLSS technology, arriving with DLSS Frame Generation and DLSS Super Resolution. Once again, if you're using the NVIDIA app, you'll be able to upgrade to DLSS 4 with Multi-Frame Generation and DLSS 4.5 Super Resolution.</p>



<p>Styx: Blades of Greed arrives on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S later this week, though you can already check out <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/styx-blades-of-greed-review-a-sandbox-goblin-adventure/">Francesco De Meo's review of the goblin's return</a>, in which he gave the game a <strong>7.5/10</strong>, and also noted that while the game does suffer from a few technical issues, when you flip the switch for DLSS 4 with Mult-Frame Generation, those issues are smoothed out. </p>



<p>"<em>Despite the technical friction and a 20-hour runtime that becomes slightly repetitive toward the end, </em><em>Styx: Blades of Greed</em> is a <strong>solid stealth title</strong>. It doesn't revolutionize the genre, and it lacks a much-needed in-game map for its sandbox maps, but it compensates with <strong>excellent level design and immense heart</strong>. For fans of the series or those craving a pure stealth experience, <strong>Styx's hunt for Quartz it’s a journey worth taking</strong>," writes De Meo.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-multi-frame-gen-styx-blades-of-greed-star-trek-voyager/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crisol: Theater of Idols Review - Praise the Sun]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-praise-sun</link>
            <guid>1438213</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>is, at the very least, an aptly-named game. It really does feel like a theater of idols; in fact, it feels like a theater that pays tribute to two idols in particular, namely <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/bioshock" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="59ad10c9-4ae1-417e-a4af-d1ad3147da86" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>BioShock</em></a><em> </em>and <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/resident-evil-village" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="7d76fc24-612e-4e7e-9804-64ccee40af28" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Resident Evil Village</em></a>.</p><p>The DNA of both games can be found everywhere in developer Vermila Studios and publisher Blumhouse Games' horror shooter. Whether it's the gloomy, glitzy post-disaster setting of Tormentosa, a suspiciously familiar weapon upgrade system, or structural similarities that are hard to ignore, there's no denying the connections.</p><p>Of course, it's one thing to pay tribute to your idols and quite another to transcend those influences in order to create something truly original. <em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>knows what it likes, but it can't quite find a way to translate those heady origins into something new and compelling.</p><h2><em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>Is Atmospheric, but Uninvolving</h2><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-mediodia.jpg?itok=8vO7D-F8 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-mediodia.jpg?itok=hePN8ie8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>You will grow to loathe Mediodia.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><em>Crisol </em>tells the story of Gabriel, a religious soldier sent to the island of Tormentosa on a holy mission. In true <em>BioShock </em>fashion, Gabriel awakens on the coast of Tormentosa at the outset of his quest and journeys inland, encountering horrors aplenty as he goes.</p><p>It's clear that <em>Crisol </em>wants religion and dogma to be the central pillars of its narrative, but it lacks the courage to say anything meaningful about its subject matter.&nbsp;</p><p>What unfolds is not a tale of zealotry and the lengths to which religion will go to subjugate its victims; rather, it's a histrionic, uneven story that takes some pretty egregious logical leaps in attempting to deliver shocking twists.</p><p>I don't want to spoil anything, but I found <em>Crisol: Theater of Idols</em>' narrative to be equal parts uninvolving and baffling. Many of its key mysteries felt unresolved, and the conclusions of those that did receive some sort of closure felt unsatisfying and weak.</p><p>The problem lies chiefly with characters. Gabriel is about as stock a protagonist as you could hope to find, and his radio support companion Mediodia is intensely, desperately annoying (not to mention horribly animated).</p><p>Unfortunately, there aren't many other major characters to get to know; the enemies Gabriel comes across are generally stock characters indebted to their key influences. One major villain even directly paraphrases <em>BioShock </em>during a climactic moment, and it feels like a cheap reference rather than a sly wink.</p><p>It's a shame, because the atmosphere on display can be very effective indeed. The sound design here is excellent, capturing the feel of an abandoned city and its labyrinthine horrors perfectly.</p><p>When the moon hits a ramshackle dock or a glittering carnival just right, <em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>threatens to become immersive, but knowing there's another lame narrative twist around the corner derails that sense of tension.</p><p>Not only that, but <em>Crisol </em>is in deep with the yellow paint mob. Its largely linear environments are covered in these patronizing, obvious directional signals, and it lessens immersion even further. Who's painting the entrances of these tunnels? Who knows Gabriel's journey better than he does?</p><h2>Combat In <em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>Struggles With Repetition</h2><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-shooting.jpg?itok=1Lw3kZY9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-shooting.jpg?itok=AJyhwxp6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Get used to this enemy. You'll be seeing it a lot.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>During <em>Crisol</em>'s opening moments, Gabriel comes face-to-face with a creepy porcelain mannequin enemy, which wrenches itself off the wall and rushes him with nary a change of its painted expression.</p><p>It's a very effective opener, and the ways in which Gabriel can dismember the creature and even behead it without making a dent set up an adaptable, worryingly durable foe that will take smarts and perseverance to overcome.</p><p>Sadly, this is another area in which <em>Crisol </em>disappoints. These mannequins will form the vast bulk of the enemies you'll face throughout a roughly 10-12-hour playthrough; I reckon about 90% of the enemy encounters are made up solely of these guys.</p><p>Over the course of my time with <em>Crisol</em>, I counted four distinct enemy types. One, a sort of goblin creature that crawls between paintings, isn't really a combat encounter; it and its friends infinitely respawn, meaning it's much more worth your time to sprint to your goal rather than engage the monster.</p><p>The best survival horror games constantly wrong-foot you with new enemy types and changes to existing enemies, meaning you're never quite able to relax. <em>Crisol </em>absolutely fails on this front; its encounters are so repetitive that they're almost comforting.</p><p>Your weapons themselves feel...fine. It's a pretty bog-standard lineup - think pistol, shotgun, rifle - but bullets land with a satisfying enough thud. That's only half of the equation, though, and when enemies are this boring to fight, even <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/doom-eternal" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1cbdb0ce-87bb-479c-9216-3442b390a2cf" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Doom Eternal</em></a>'s gunplay wouldn't suffice.</p><h2>There's Simply No Scarcity in <em>Crisol: Theater of Idols</em></h2><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-doorway.jpg?itok=t4aYXHw7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-doorway.jpg?itok=B2rsaZR6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption><em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>can't manage scares or tension at any point.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I bring up survival horror because <em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>explicitly bills itself as such, and judged on these terms, it's an abject failure.</p><p><em>Crisol </em>revolves around a rather neat little mechanic whereby blood serves as ammunition, so if you want to keep yourself stocked up, you'll have to sacrifice health to do so.</p><p>Blood can be recovered by draining animals (and, sometimes, humans) throughout your environment, as well as by using consumable syringes. As such, <em>Crisol </em>clearly wants you to constantly be asking whether it's worth draining that last scrap of health to give yourself a fighting chance in a battle.</p><p>It's unfortunate, then, that <em>Crisol </em>suffers from an almost total lack of scarcity. There was not a single point during my playthrough when I struggled for resources. I was awash with blood, drowning in corpses, carrying a bag bulging with syringes.</p><p>Ironically enough for a horror game, <em>Crisol </em>seems terrified of alienating you or frustrating you, so its levels are absolutely chock-full of health pickups. I was constantly ignoring syringes or using them with 95% of my health remaining just so I could pick up more.</p><p>Without scarcity, a survival horror game can no longer deliver on dread. If you're constantly well-prepared for whatever's coming around the next corner, then it won't surprise you or terrify you.</p><p>Combined with the terminal lack of enemy variety, any chance that <em>Crisol </em>can provide a tense or scary experience is gone.</p><p>The problem, though, is this: if <em>Crisol </em>doesn't work as a survival horror shooter, and its enemies are nowhere near varied enough for a serviceable action-horror game, then what, exactly, do we have before us?</p><h2><em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>- Final Thoughts</h2><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-building.jpg?itok=bikUq4y1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-building.jpg?itok=Rbypttfo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Sometimes, <em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>looks nice. It's not enough to save it.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It pains me to say it, given the obvious ambition on display, but <em>Crisol: Theater of Idols </em>just...doesn't work.</p><p>Its survival horror elements are undone by a total lack of scarcity, thus making resource management a complete non-issue, and its enemy encounters are stultifyingly repetitive, thus kneecapping any chance of high-octane and exciting combat.</p><p><em>Crisol </em>just feels like it keeps getting in its own way. Its atmosphere is moody and compelling, but undone by overbearing yellow paint guidance. Its guns feel weighty, but the enemies you'll use them on are too boring to provide catharsis.</p><p><em>BioShock </em>worked because it had a message, and <em>Resident Evil Village </em>worked because it constantly kept you guessing. <em>Crisol </em>does neither, and as such, it's a safe skip, even if you love its influences.</p><hr><p><em><strong>Crisol: Theater of Idols</strong> was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the developer over the course of 12 hours of gameplay. All screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/crisol-theater-of-idols-review-praise-sun]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[G.I. Joe Snake Eyes Game Dev Reportedly Shut Down, but Game Is Still Coming]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gi-joe-snake-eyes-studio-shut-down-game-not-canceled</link>
            <guid>1438210</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new report has emerged which claims that Hasbro has closed down Atomic Arcade, the developer of the company's upcoming <em>G.I. Joe Snake Eyes </em>game, but that the game itself is still in the works.</p><p>As spotted by <a href="https://wccftech.com/hasbro-wizards-of-the-coast-reportedly-shut-down-g-i-joe-snake-eyes-game-makers-atomic-arcade/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Wccftech</a>, a LinkedIn <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/dominicbraun_opentowork-activity-7429184370877345793-37wz/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">post</a> by former Atomic Arcade software engineer Dominic Braun makes reference to "Hasbro's and Wizards of the Coast's decision to close Atomic Arcade", which Braun says means there are now "a lot of really great people" looking for work.</p><p>A Hasbro representative subsequently told Wccftech that the <em>G.I. Joe Snake Eyes </em>game itself is "not canceled", and that Hasbro and Wizards of the Coast are "currently taking time to evaluate the path forward for the game".</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/g.i-joe-snake-eyes-atomic-arcade-shut-down-blade.jpg?itok=LbsfEgy_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/g.i-joe-snake-eyes-atomic-arcade-shut-down-blade.jpg?itok=ZKb2CR4s 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption><em>G.I. Joe Snake Eyes </em>developer Atomic Arcade appears to have been closed down.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The two companies say that no decisions about the game's future have yet been "finalized", but that updates will be provided "as soon as [they're] able".</p><p>This <em>G.I. Joe </em>game may or may not be the same one that was first <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-gi-joe-game-in-developer-at-wizards-of-coast" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="209153fc-2cb7-4d27-98f3-9cc0ea45c91e" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">announced all the way back in 2021</a>, but if it is, it's an ignominious end for a studio that's been working on the game for at least the last five years.</p><p>Unfortunately, Atomic Arcade isn't the first studio to be shut down in the last few months. Back in January, Ubisoft <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-halifax-shutdown" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="5c381dd9-8d80-4d19-ac2f-5c64bbb6ef55" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">closed down its Halifax wing</a> just weeks after it unionized, and other developers to have met with the axe recently include <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/boss-fight-entertainment-netflix-shutdown" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="9711bede-314c-4ee1-8135-fe8d85504170" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Squid Game: Unleashed </em>studio Boss Fight</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-hellsinger-the-outsiders-shut-down-funcom" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="7586356a-08b1-450a-a88c-9b10c217225a" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Metal: Hellsinger </em>outfit The Outsiders</a>.</p><p>If the <em>G.I. Joe Snake Eyes </em>game has indeed avoided cancellation, it's lucky to have done so; high-profile projects like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ashes-of-creation-layoffs-canceled-report" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1b59358e-2c0a-4543-a759-154075e27078" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">MMO <em>Ashes of Creation</em></a><em> </em>(reportedly, at least) and Ubisoft's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-canceled" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="91d63675-e1f4-4624-a716-79db888eb3c6" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time </em>remake</a> haven't been so fortunate.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ashes-of-creation-report-canceled.jpg?itok=Sq6BFVc- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ashes-of-creation-report-canceled.jpg?itok=AZ9aQv7J 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption><em>Ashes of Creation </em>is just one of a number of games that have apparently been canceled recently.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>We'll have to wait and see what happens to the <em>G.I. Joe Snake Eyes </em>game in the future, but presumably, Hasbro and Wizards of the Coast will make an announcement relating to it soon. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gi-joe-snake-eyes-studio-shut-down-game-not-canceled]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15 Tips If You’re Coming Back To Stardew Valley In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/stardew-valley-tips-tricks-beginner-2000669702</link>
            <guid>1438201</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It’s been almost a decade since the release of the legendary farming sim <em>Stardew Valley</em>, and it’s easy to be daunted by its massive reputation and dedicated player community. Fortunately, the game is all about chilling out, and isn’t too tough on newcomers. That being said, going in totally blind can be a bit overwhelming in a game so packed with information. So, whether you’re a brand new player or it’s been so long you’ve forgotten the ropes, here are 15 tips for starting a fresh <em>Stardew Valley</em> save in 2026.</p> <h2>Choose the Four Corners, Standard, or Forest Farm</h2> <p>There are eight different farm maps to choose from, but not all are created equal. Be sure to make an informed decision — you can’t change your mind later!</p> <p>The Four Corners farm is described as being ideal for multiplayer, but it’s my favorite for single player, too. Four Corners’ structured layout is great for planning how you want to organize your base later on, and each corner has a different perk to it.<br> The Standard farm is another solid choice since it gives you the most space for raising animals and farming crops. The Forest farm also works well; it doesn’t offer a lot of farming space, but it’s great for foraging, which is a crucial skill in the early game.<br> The other farms make starting out more challenging, and <em>Stardew</em> is already overwhelming enough without adding extra hurdles. I would know; my first ever farm was on the Riverland map (because it’s the prettiest), but I got so frustrated I abandoned the save.</p>

 <h2>Take it easy</h2> <p>It’s inevitable that you’re gonna make a mistake. Whether you can’t get home before 2 a.m., or you give someone a present they don’t like, or you miss out on farming a particular crop before the season changes, don’t beat yourself up about it. <em>Stardew Valley</em> is a game about going at your own pace—it’s not possible to play it “wrong,” so long as you’re having fun. It isn’t the end of the world if you accidentally sell something you need later on. Find the joy in stumbling as you learn.</p> <h2>Plan ahead for the Community Center</h2> <p>That being said, if you do want to strategize, the best thing you can do is keep track of what you’ll need to finish rebuilding the Community Center. I like to keep a physical list of all the stuff I need to complete the Community Center handy for quick reference.</p>

 <h2>Watch TV every day</h2> <p>Flicking through the TV when you wake up will reward you with helpful intel from a variety of channels. The content on every channel changes daily, so make a habit of TV surfing before you head out each morning.</p> <h2>Keep one of every item</h2> <p>As a general rule, I like to keep at least one of every item I stumble upon stored at my base. Odds are the stuff you think is worthless now will turn out to be useful later on.</p>

 <h2>Start a tree farm</h2> <p>You’re gonna need a lot of wood in this game. Trees take forever to grow, so set up a designated area for trees on your farm as early as you can.</p> <h2>Don’t plant too many seeds</h2> <p>Believe it or not, there is such a thing as too much farming. Watering your plants costs energy, which you have a limited amount of each day. There’s much more to explore beyond your farm, so don’t spend all your time trying to till every square inch of your land—keep it manageable.</p>  <h2>Go fishing</h2> <p>Fishing is one of the best things you can do in the early game. Not only is it a quick and easy way to earn some cash, you also have a chance of fishing up rare treasure. Upgrading your rod as soon as you’re able is also a good move.</p>

 <h2>Fish where you see bubbles</h2> <p>If you see bubbles in the water, make sure to cast your line there. Fish are way quicker to bite in bubble spots and you’re less likely to catch trash.</p> <h2>Dig for worms</h2> <p>When you’re walking around, keep an eye out for any grass tiles that have three little worms wriggling on them. Using a hoe on that tile will yield valuable items.</p> <h2>Place chests in key locations</h2> <p>Remember that you can place chests anywhere so long as they aren’t on NPC walking paths. It’s easy to run out of inventory space while spelunking, so having a chest right outside the elevator in the mines is super helpful. I also like to keep chests on the beach and by the river for fishing.</p> <h2>Build a silo ASAP</h2> <p>Silos automatically store all the grass you cut. Constructing one before you start on any other buildings is a good idea because it’ll give you a big reserve of hay for when you do get animals.</p>

 <h2>Pet your animals</h2> <p>Once you get livestock on your farm, right-click to pet them! If you make a daily habit of it, you’ll be rewarded with higher quality animal goods—plus a cute heart animation. It’s my favorite part of the daily farm routine (no I will never buy the auto petters).</p> <h2>Prepare for winter with heaters</h2> <p>Winter is tough. Your farmland is rendered barren and your animals can’t go outside, so you’ll have to rely on resource reservoirs and animal produce to survive. Make sure your animals have a siloful of hay to munch on and a heater in every barn/coop so they don’t go cold.</p>

 <h2>Press and hold right-click to save time</h2> <p>Most repetitive actions can be done en masse by holding down the right mouse button. It makes harvesting crops, petting animals, and collecting items from machines way faster.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/stardew-valley-tips-tricks-beginner-2000669702]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's the next batch of Xbox Game Pass games for February]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-the-next-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-games-for-february</link>
            <guid>1438189</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2! Final Fantasy 3! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Death-Howl-artwork-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlaid.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Death-Howl-artwork-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlaid.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Death-Howl-artwork-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlaid.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Death-Howl-artwork-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlaid.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Death-Howl-artwork-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlaid.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Death-Howl-artwork-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlaid.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Death-Howl-artwork-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlaid.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Death-Howl-artwork-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlaid.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Death-Howl-artwork-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlaid.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Microsoft has revealed the next batch of games coming to its Xbox Game Pass subscription service this February, and into next month.</p>
<p>Along with the already announced <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/here-are-our-xbox-game-pass-games-for-february">Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora and Avowed</a>, which are available from today (17th February), Game Pass subscribers can look forward to the following games making their way onto the service:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Aerial_Knight's DropShot</strong> (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, Handheld, and PC) – 17th February via Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li>
<li><strong>Death Howl</strong> (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, Handheld, and PC) – 19th February via Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass</li>
<li><strong>EA Sports College Football 26</strong> (Cloud and Xbox Series X/S) – 19th February via Game Pass Ultimate</li>
<li><strong>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</strong> – Complete Edition (Cloud and Console) – 19th February via Game Pass Ultimate, Premium</li>
<li><strong>TCG Card Shop Simulator</strong> (Game Preview) (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, Handheld, and PC) – 24th February via Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass</li>
<li><strong>Dice A Million</strong> (PC) – 25th February via Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li>
<li><strong>Towerborne</strong> (Full Game Release) (Console, Handheld, and PC) – 26th February via Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass</li>
<li><strong>Final Fantasy 3</strong> (Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, and PC) – 3rd March via Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass</li>
<li><strong>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 </strong>(Cloud, Xbox Series X/S, and PC) – 3rd March via Game Pass Ultimate, Premium, PC Game Pass</li>
</ul>
<p>I am quite intrigued by Death Howl, which is a soulslike deck builder.  The game is described as a "poignant tale of grief, healing, and resilience", and follows the journey of hunter Ro as she leaves her tribe and ventures into a disturbingly realised realm of the spirits in the hope of reuniting with her deceased son.</p><p>Kingdom Come Deliverance 2, meanwhile, garnered a lot of love for its dedication to toil and turmoil in Bohemia, told through the eyes of Henry of Skalitz. A hardy combat system and eager embrace of vulgarity come together in a compelling RPG well worth playing.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Microsoft</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As with every month, with new games coming to Game Pass, it does mean a selection of others will be leaving. On 28th February, the following with be leaving the service:</p>
<ul>
<li>Monster Train (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Expeditions: A MudRunner Game (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Injustice 2 (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Middle Earth: Shadow of War (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
</ul>
<p>For everything else in Microsoft's subscription service, you can check out our handy <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-game-pass-games-list-this-month-price-6400">Xbox Game Pass guide</a> detailing the many titles available.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-the-next-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-games-for-february]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What If Red Dead Redemption But It's Just A Bear Driving A Train]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/bumpy-ride-steam-demo/</link>
            <guid>1438183</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      <p>In 2024 I wrote about <em>A Short Trip</em>, a tiny hand-drawn game where a cat drives a train. Well now I’m back with <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3056840/A_Bumpy_Ride/?ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>A Bumpy Ride</u></em></a>, a Western game where a bear (I think?) drives a train. I’m not sure why we’re seeing a boom in the animal-drives-a-train genre, but I’m into it.</p><p><em>A Bumpy Ride </em>is being developed by Cosmoporium Games; its Steam demo recently got an update that includes a tutorial and unlimited in-game days of play. During those days, you pick up various animal passengers from one station and drive them to another. In addition to wanting to get to their destination on time, the animals like it when you obey train traffic signs, like going slow when a sign says to go slow or sounding your train whistle when a sign says to sound your train whistle.</p><figure><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V2JZH8mAgvI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" title="OUR NEW DEMO IS LIVE! 🚂 A Bumpy Ride, Demo Update!"></iframe></figure><p>The tracks you follow are set into a sprawling desert landscape that, even rendered cartoonishly, really evokes a 19th century developing West. Wooden towns appear among the tumbleweeds and cacti, from little outposts of only a few houses to relatively sprawling metropolises set among cliffs or along rivers. Some paths in the demo are blocked off by boulders that the game says requires TNT to clear, and though you can’t do this in the demo I did enjoy rolling into a TNT depot and imagining chugging around with a bunch of dynamite. The weather changes, as does the time of day, with the sky becoming an endless expanse of stars that reminded me of being alone in the wilderness in <em>Red Dead Redemption</em>.</p><p>While there isn’t all that much to do in the demo mechanically, what you <em>can</em> do is very satisfying thanks to the game’s chunky interface. You control the train with a lever on the right side of your screen, pulling it to speed up, slow down, stop, and reverse. The whistle is controlled with a pull-down tab at the top of the screen that I spent a lot of time pulling just for fun. Track directions are switched with a pop-up interface that’s equally satisfying, and also often sent me frantically checking my map to make sure I was headed the right way, especially when I was first unveiling which directions are available and wasn’t sure where a set of tracks would take me. You also have to keep your train topped up with water, stopping in just the right spot at towers placed around the map to let water pour into the right car of your train.</p><figure><figcaption><span>I wish I could explore the town (Cosmoporium Games/Aftermath)</span></figcaption></figure><p>Satisfied passengers pay you money, and you can use this to upgrade to a new train, buy more seats for passengers, or install a bar car that makes passengers a bit more cheerful. I definitely did not satisfy all my passengers, especially when I was first learning the map and took them on long, scenic tours into the night instead of getting them to their destinations. But once I knew where I was going, <em>A Bumpy Ride</em> was a simple, lovely experience of chugging along following traffic laws and watching the landscape roll past, listening to the jaunty music and admiring the landscape.</p><p>Cosmoporium plans to release the game later this year, and the Steam page promises more areas, train cars, and a level-up system that will include “new upgrades, staff, and skins.”</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/short-trip-impressions-review/"><div><p>Short Trip Is A Tiny Game Where A Cat Drives A Train - Aftermath</p><p>And also rings the bell</p><p><span>Riley MacLeod</span></p></div></a></figure>
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/bumpy-ride-steam-demo/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>