<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 20:16:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft: Midnight Is Officially Launching on March 2, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/world-of-warcraft-midnight-officially-launching-march-2-2026/</link>
            <guid>1365844</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Blizzard Entertainment has just confirmed that <a href="https://wccftech.com/world-of-warcraft-midnight-qa-housing-long-term/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">World of Warcraft: Midnight</a>, the eleventh expansion pack for the most popular subscription-based MMORPG, will be released on Monday, March 2, 2026 at 3:00 PM Pacific Time.</p>



<p>An earlier rumor from leaker billbil-kun <a href="https://wccftech.com/world-of-warcraft-midnight-to-launch-february-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mentioned</a> a February 26, 2026 date. It appears that Blizzard has finally settled on taking a few more days, though it really is a nearly insignificant delay compared to the date listed in that report.</p>



<p>World of Warcraft: Midnight is the middle chapter of the trilogy known as the <a href="https://wccftech.com/world-of-warcraft-worldsoul-saga-the-war-within-midnight-the-last-titan-expansions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Worldsoul Saga</a>. This narrative was conceived by returning writer Chris Metzen, who <a href="https://wccftech.com/chris-metzen-blizzard-retires/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">left Blizzard in 2016</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/warcraft-christ-metzen-returning-lead-franchise-wow-next-generation-of-adventures/">returned in 2023</a>. Following the events of the previous expansion, The War Within, Xal’atath, the so-called Harbinger of the Void, returns to Azeroth and unleashes utter chaos in her wake. The ensuing invasion strikes at the heart of the Blood Elf homelands in Eversong Woods. Meanwhile, the looming Voidstorm threatens to extinguish all light and cover the world in darkness as it arrives over the ancient elven kingdom of Quel'thalas.</p>



<p>As mentioned <a href="https://wccftech.com/world-of-warcraft-midnight-deep-dive-housing-early-access-december-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in my previous Deep Dive article</a>, the expansion introduces player housing through the so-called Neighborhoods, the new opt-in Prey bounty hunting system, the new Haranir Allied Race, the new Devourer specialization for the Demon Hunter class, four explorable zones (the Eversong Woods, which have been merged with the Ghostlands; Zul'Aman; Harandar; and the Voidstorm), eleven Delves, eight Dungeons, three Raids, new PvP content (a new Battleground and the Training Grounds as a permanent mode), a reimagined Silvermoon City that now hosts the Horde and Alliance both, and other improvements to User Interface and transmogrification. In the campaign storyline, players will have the option to choose which of multiple paths to complete first.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Midnight Arrives 3.2.26 | World of Warcraft" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oK_-6glk2MM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>While you'll have to wait for early March to play most of the content in World of Warcraft: Midnight, player housing is actually being made available in early access starting next Tuesday, on December 2, for those players who pre-purchased the expansion. To celebrate the arrival of this long-requested feature, Blizzard crafted a range of special rewards across all its games for players who move into their first home and earn the new 'Welcome Home' achievement in World of Warcraft.</p>



<p>Overwatch 2 players can look forward to the following in-game unlocks:</p>



<ul>
<li>Xal’atath Symmetra Legendary Skin</li>



<li>Xal’atath Symmetra Spray</li>



<li>Xal'atath Symmetra Name Card</li>



<li>Dark Heart Player Icon</li>
</ul>



<p>Hearthstone players will unlock the Hearth &amp; Home Card Back. Furthermore, separate from the WoW achievement, the collectible card game now hosts a new, limited-time in-game event, 'Welcome to the Neighborhood!', featuring an earnable Epic event card.</p>



<p>Lastly, in StarCraft II, players will be able to show their allegiance in every match with the new Horde and Alliance StarCraft II skins. Weirdly, there won't be any Diablo IV tie-in unlocks.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/world-of-warcraft-midnight-officially-launching-march-2-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 is already 24 percent off for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/gadgets/830040/battlefield-6-black-friday-deal-sale-2025</link>
            <guid>1365841</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Njg3NzE5"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Brandon Russell</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a commerce writer covering deals and buying guides. Previously, he was a freelance writer for Popular Mechanics, Men’s Health, and Esquire.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Electronic Arts’ <em>Battlefield 6</em> is still relatively hot off the presses, having just <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/795232/ea-battlefield-6-hit-launch-deal">launched in October</a>. But thanks to Black Friday, you can pick up a copy on the PlayStation 5 for just $52.99 ($17 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FJHS8TH5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>. The price has also dropped at Best Buy to $59.99 ($10 off) for <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fproduct%2Fbattlefield-6-standard-edition-playstation-5%2FJ7CYFSSSPW%2Fsku%2F6642408" rel="sponsored">PS5</a> and <a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fproduct%2Fbattlefield-6-standard-edition-xbox-series-x%2FJ7CYF9YZ4F" rel="sponsored">Xbox Series X</a>, giving you more ways to shop.</p><p>With a lot on the line for EA, <em>Battlefield 6</em> is off to a pretty good start, becoming the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/825171/battlefield-6-had-a-big-launch-month">best-selling title</a> in the franchise’s history. Considering how fiercely competitive the online shooter space is, that’s good news after 2021’s <em>Battlefield 2042</em> failed to meet expectations. While reactions to <em>Battlefield 6’s</em> single-player campaign have been lukewarm, the multiplayer component is the real draw. One of the biggest focuses this year is on environmental destruction, which adds to the chaos of large-scale battles.</p><p>Beyond <em>Battlefield 6</em> proper, EA has also <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/807720/ea-battlefield-6-battle-royale-redsec">launched <em>Battlefield Redsec</em></a><em>,</em> a separate free-to-play battle royale mode, which takes place on a huge map called Fort Lyndon. In addition, EA has sketched out <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/battlefield/battlefield-6/news/battlefield-6-season-1-roadmap-preview">ambitious plans</a> for <em>Battlefield 6</em>, Season 1, which includes additional content like a new map, a new 4v4 multiplayer mode, and a new vehicle, among other updates. EA says it is also launching a Winter Offensive update on December 9th, which will include special seasonal themed content.</p><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Njg3NzE5"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Brandon Russell</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/gadgets/830040/battlefield-6-black-friday-deal-sale-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nier Automata's 2B remains in crossover prison, this time relegated to Final Fantasy 7: Ever Crisis]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nier-automatas-2b-remains-in-crossover-prison-this-time-relegated-to-final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis</link>
            <guid>1365838</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Something new or bust, I say</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-nier.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-nier.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-nier.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-nier.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-nier.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-nier.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-nier.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-nier.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-nier.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Square Enix</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Look, ok, I get it Square Enix. I understand why you put 2B in absolutely everything. She is a character with particular qualities that certain audiences found very appealing! But I am begging you… stop putting her in things. I'm sick to death of seeing her everywhere, her blindfolded eyes somehow still staring directly into my soul, begging me to spend money on endless gacha rolls, but this time in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis">Final Fantasy 7: Ever Crisis</a>, the next game she's set to appear in.
</p>
<p>
It's even easier to understand why she's in this one, it's another Square Enix game after all, they don't even have to do any annoying brand deals. On this particular occasion, rather than as a playable character (presumably because her fighting Sephiroth was too much for even Square Enix), 2B will be a boss fight you can take on. Which means that really, the main draw will be the outfits for a few <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/final-fantasy-vii">Final Fantasy 7</a> characters.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="FINAL FANTASY VII EVER CRISIS | YoRHa No.2 Type B Intercept - Encounter in the City Ruins Crossover!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ed-Z-AsI0C4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>FINAL FANTASY VII EVER CRISIS | YoRHa No.2 Type B Intercept - Encounter in the City Ruins Crossover!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ed-Z-AsI0C4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Ed-Z-AsI0C4?autoplay=1" title="FINAL FANTASY VII EVER CRISIS | YoRHa No.2 Type B Intercept - Encounter in the City Ruins Crossover!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ed-Z-AsI0C4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
The two graced and/or cursed depending on how you look at it with such outfits are everyone's favourite ninja Yuffie, puppy-boy Cloud, and the more predictable choice out of the two, Tifa. I fear for what this might do to Clerith shippers that think this is a sign that Square Enix has a preference, but I digress.
</p><p>
More than anything, I would just like Square Enix to let Yoko Taro either make or, if they are working on one, announce a new… anything, honestly, but a fresh entry into <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nier">Nier</a>'s world would be nice. The poor moon-shaped head lad can't seem to catch a break at the moment, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nier-creator-yoko-taro-would-like-you-to-know-he-has-been-working-on-games-they-just-keep-getting-cancelled">what with him saying games he's been working on keep getting cancelled</a>. We're quickly approaching Automata's 10th anniversary! Let the endearing oddball get on with it.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nier-automatas-2b-remains-in-crossover-prison-this-time-relegated-to-final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another Long-Time Game Studio Is On The Chopping Block]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/another-long-time-game-studio-is-on-the-chopping-block-2000647684</link>
            <guid>1365832</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Longtime English studio <a href="https://kotaku.com/transformers-reactivate-canceled-splash-damage-layoffs-1851735308">Splash Damage</a> is facing an uncertain future as it begins a consultation process that will affect all staff and likely lead to layoffs.</p> <p>On November 26, Splash Damage publicly announced online that the studio was entering a “studio-wide consultation process” that would involve all employees across all roles and disciplines. This follows the London-based studio being acquired in September by a private equity investor after being sold by its previous owner, Chinese conglomerate Tencent.</p> <p>“This was a difficult step for us to take,” said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/splash-damage_an-update-from-splash-damage-activity-7399486098588196864-pz0I/">Splash Damage via a message shared on LinkedIn</a>. “But we believe it is necessary so Splash Damage can remain agile and adaptable in what has been a very challenging market. We know this kind of change is emotionally tough, and we will do what we can to guide our people through this process with honesty and care. We’re committed to exploring every option to retain talent and making sure those affected have meaningful support throughout.”</p>

 <p>Splash Damage already suffered layoffs earlier this year after the <a href="https://kotaku.com/transformers-reactivate-leak-footage-gameplay-canceled-1851736122"><em>Transformers</em> game it was working on was canceled</a>. The last game the studio shipped was 2020’s <em>Outcasters</em> for Google’s now-defunct Stadia game streaming service. Before that, the studio, which was formed in 2001, had developed various popular multiplayer games, including <em>Wolfenstein: Enemy Territory, Brink,</em> and helped Xbox as a support studio on <em>Halo </em>and <em>Gears of War</em> titles. It also developed <em>Gears of War Tactics.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>It is the latest round of bad news for the video game industry as developers <a href="https://kotaku.com/tag/layoffs">continue to be laid off and studios closed as publishers tighten their belts</a> and begin<a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-ai-fps-temmates-genai-nfts-gameplay-snowdrop-reveal-2000646251"> investing more into AI generation tools</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/another-long-time-game-studio-is-on-the-chopping-block-2000647684]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Souls + Morrowind + The Doom Engine = One Of 2025’s Coolest Shooters]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dark-souls-morrowind-doom-engine-mohtra-review-pc-steam-fps-boomer-shooter-2000647667</link>
            <guid>1365829</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>In first-person shooters, <a href="https://kotaku.com/wrath-is-a-retro-shooter-done-right-1841067258">especially older games or retro-inspired boomer shooters</a>, the first gun you get tells you a lot about the game. And in <em>Mohrta</em>, your first weapon is a powerful, accurate, hard-hitting revolver that makes the<a href="https://youtu.be/jRrommJ5V9w"> famous M1-Garand “ping” noise</a> every time you reload it. This is just one of the many reasons why I adore <em>Mohrta,</em> which is out now on Steam.</p> <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2881610/Mohrta/"><em>Mohrta</em>, which launched last month</a>, is a non-linear first-person shooter built in GZDoom that has big <em>Morrowind</em> and <em>Dark Souls</em> vibes. And yes, I know mentioning<em> Dark Souls</em> in a blog or article about video games risks mockery,&nbsp; but the way this game’s save shrines work and the pacing of each of the worlds you visit, plus its challenging boss fights, create <em>very </em>similar vibes to a FromSoftware RPG. Except you have a shotgun. <a href="https://youtu.be/e_HT14h35eg">Wait, actually, FromSoftware did that, actually</a>. Huh…anyway, I mentioned <em>Morrowind</em> because <em>Mohtra’s</em> strange dark fantasy universe has similar aesthetics to Bethesda’s popular RPG, too. But again, with more guns.</p>

  <p>In <em>Mohrtra</em>, you play as an undead knight-like machine-man who is determined to clean up all the nasty, strange creatures and oddities infesting the land while tracking down someone important. To save the lands and find this person, you’ll need to explore various worlds that ramp up in difficulty, but which can be completed in any order you desire. You start with a powerful sword and badass revolver and grow your arsenal with a shotgun, a bizarre grenade launcher, an SMG that fires bones, and some other really odd weapons I won’t spoil here. All of the weapons feel great, and because the game is built in GZDoom, <a href="https://kotaku.com/doom-gzdoom-source-port-graf-zahl-ai-chatgpt-2000636055">a modern source port of id’s classic ’90s FPS</a>, gameplay feels snappy, fast, and punchy.</p>

 <p>You also have a small talking doll that can heal you and a vulture on your shoulder that provides light when exploring dark caverns or ruins. <em>Mohtra</em> is weird if you haven’t got that yet. But I love it. Returning from levels to the large market hub world is always a treat. The strange denizens of this world are always willing to chat and trade with you, letting you upgrade your gear and guns, making future missions in new worlds easier.</p>

 <p>All of this is drenched in gorgeous retro-inspired textures and effects. Forests are foggy and gloomy. Lava-filled caves are dark and foreboding. Ancient ruins look deserted and lonely. Immaculate vibes going in this one. <a href="https://kotaku.com/selaco-gzdoom-engine-fps-steam-review-early-access-1851513067">Who needs 4K raytracing when you got the <em>Doom</em> engine?</a></p> <p>If you are craving a five-to-seven-hour oddball boomer shooter that isn’t just about running through corridors and killing soldiers or zombies,<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2881610/Mohrta/"> I’d hop over to Steam and check out <em>Mohtra</em></a>, one of the best FPS games released this year. And tell me how you think <em>Mohtra</em> is pronounced.&nbsp; I’ve been saying “mow-CH-ru.” But I heard someone say “MAHT-ra.” I don’t know, I’m too busy shooting creepy skeleton men with my bone gun to worry about that kind of stuff.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dark-souls-morrowind-doom-engine-mohtra-review-pc-steam-fps-boomer-shooter-2000647667]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Stocking Stuffers for Gamers]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/stocking-stuffers-for-gamers-2025/</link>
            <guid>1365826</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-160454">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>If you have a gamer in your life, shopping for things like holiday stocking stuffers can be a bit frustrating. Most things a gamer would like are usually either a game, something large, or something expensive. But what if you could give them something that costs less and they’ll actually use?</p>



<p>Stocking stuffers are supposed to be where you have the most fun with what you give. There’s no need to overthink any of it. If you really can’t decide, however, the check out the list that’s been put together of small holiday gaming gifts that all cost $25 or less. </p>







<p>These gifts range from table-top dice to headphone stands to even cleaning supplies and candles. In fact, there’s likely something here for any type of gamer. </p>



<p>Check out the gifts below and leave ideas that might have been missed either down in the comments or over in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>. For even more holiday shopping guides, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/holiday-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming’s Holiday 2025 hub</a>&nbsp;for the best deals available.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-stocking-stuffers">Best Stocking Stuffers</h2>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Stocking Stuffer</th><th>Price</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/colorcoral-cleaning-gel-universal-dust-cleaner-for-pc-keyboard/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ColorCoral Cleaning Gel Dust Cleaner</a></td><td>$5.94</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/eurpmask-rotating-headphone-stand/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EURPMASK Rotating Headphone Stand</a></td><td>$7.69</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/1985-games-mystery-dice-dnd-dice-set-of-7-polyhedral-dice/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">1985 Games Mystery Dice</a></td><td>$8.99</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/keyboard-cleaning-kit-laptop-cleaner/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Keyboard Cleaning Kit Laptop Cleaner</a></td><td>$12.68</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/uno-super-mario-card-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">UNO Super Mario Card Game</a></td><td>$11.47</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/kanoodle-original-3d-brain-teaser-puzzle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kanoodle – Original 3D Brain Teaser Puzzle</a></td><td>$9.99</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/super-bros-mini-question-block-night-lights/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Super Bros Mini Question Block Night Lights</a></td><td>$15.99</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/double-sided-decision-maker-coin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Double Sided Decision Maker Coin</a></td><td>$11.99</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/diamond-waterproof-black-playing-cards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Diamond Waterproof Black Playing Cards</a></td><td>$7.19</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/gamer-grip-stops-sweat-on-hands-feet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gamer Grip Sweat Stopper</a></td><td>$13.99</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/d20-dice-ice-mold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">D20 Dice Ice Mold</a></td><td>$19.98</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/anker-usb-c-hub/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Anker USB-C Hub</a></td><td>$18.99</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/adults-food-dice/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Food Dice</a></td><td>$8.99</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/table-top-mini-bowling-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tabletop Mini Bowling Game</a></td><td>$8.49</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/funny-video-game-candle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“Video Game Rage” Candle</a></td><td>$16.99</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/bluetooth-speaker-waterproof/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Waterproof Bluetooth Speaker</a></td><td>$18.98</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/the-legend-of-zelda-link-christmas-ornament/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Super Mario Yoshi Christmas Ornament</a></td><td>$9.77</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/gamer-chair-phone-stand/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gamer Chair Phone Stand</a></td><td>$9.99</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/20-nintendo-eshop-gift-card/">Nintendo eShop Gift Card</a></td><td>$20 or more</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/xbox-gift-card-20-loaded/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Gift Card</a></td><td>$20 or more</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/playstation-gift-card-25-loaded/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Gift Card</a></td><td>$25 or more</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<hr>



<p>What are you looking to pick up as a stocking stuffer for the gamer in your life this year? Leave your picks down in the comments and join us over at the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<p><em><strong>NOTE:</strong>&nbsp;Insider Gaming may earn affiliate commission if you purchase items through links on Insider Gaming. Read more about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/privacy-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">affiliate commission here</a>.</em></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-xbox-series-x-games-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-xbox-series-x-games-2025/">
                                Best Xbox Series X Games to Gift 2025                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Explore the best Xbox Series X games to gift this holiday season for any gamer.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-november-26-899/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-november-26-899/">
                                NYT Connections Hints Today (#899)—Clues and Answers for Wednesday, November 26                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It’s time for a bit of midweek madness; hopefully, your streak can keep up with today’s NYT Connections puzzle! Here are the hints you need.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-xbox-ally-accessories-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-xbox-ally-accessories-2025/">
                                Best ASUS ROG Xbox Ally X Accessories: Holiday 2025                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>With the 2025 holiday shopping season here, check out the best ASUS ROG Xbox Ally X accessories and add-ons to protect your investment.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-ranked-play-release/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-ranked-play-release/">
                                Black Ops 7 Ranked Play Release Period, Explained                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ranked Play will bring a competitive edge to Black Ops 7 that many in the community desperately want, and a release period is known.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/stocking-stuffers-for-gamers-2025/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Save On Sony's Noise-Canceling Headphones & Earbuds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-noise-canceling-headphone-deals-bf2025/1100-6536517/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1365823</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536517">

            
            
    


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sony's noise-cancelling wireless headsets have been popular since they were first introduced, and for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/black-friday/">Black Friday</a>, you can save nearly 40$ on the tthe <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony WH-1000XM5 headphones,</a> which are on sale for $49 (was $400). These offer high-quality audio, strong battery life, and are comfortable to wear all day. You can choose from four colors for this deal: <a href="https://amazon.com/dp/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Black</a>, <a href="https://amazon.com/dp/B0BXYCS74H?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Midnight Blue</a>, <a href="https://amazon.com/dp/B09XSDMT4F?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Silver</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DDV3FRHR?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Smoky Pink</a>, and as an added bonus, you'll also get $30 Amazon credit with the black version. Amazon has similar deals on several other Sony headphone models, including the WH-1000XM6, WH-CH720N, and XM5 Earbuds, all of which are discounted and come with a bonus 60-day Audible subscription. Beyond Amazon's offerings, you can also save a whopping $190 on the Sony WH-1000XM4 wireless headphones at Best Buy, dropping them to just $160 (normally $350). We've outlined all of the best Black Friday deals on Sony wireless headphones below. And for even more savings on tech, video games, and beyond, be sure to check <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/black-friday/">GameSpot's Black Friday Deals Hub</a>.</p><div title="Sony WH-1000XM5 Headphones Black (BF2025)" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="5122" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="Sony WH-1000XM5 Headphones Black (BF2025)" data-collection="{&quot;collection&quot;:[]}">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free\/dp\/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">Sony WH-1000XM5 Wireless ANC Headphones</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free\/dp\/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">$248 (was $400) | Includes $30 Amazon credit</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>Sony’s WH-1000XM5 features Auto NC Optimizer technology that adapts noise cancellation to your environment. It also sports a sleek matte black design with built-in controls on the earcups. The left cup houses physical buttons for noise-cancelling and ambient modes, while the right cup offers touch controls for playback, volume, and calls. The headphones support wireless Bluetooth pairing or wired connections via 3.5mm or USB-C. Battery life is roughly 30 hours with ANC enabled (or 40 hours with ANC off), and it supports fast charging to restore hours of playback time in just a few minutes on the charger. The headphones ship with a soft-shell carrying case and a USB-C cable.</p><p>Amazon's deal knocks the price on the Sony WH-1000XM5 Wireless ANC Headphones down to just $248 (was $400), and you'll get a free $30 Amazon Gift card as part of your purchase.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Save+On+Sony%27s+Noise-Canceling+Headphones+%26+Earbuds&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A23&amp;fnarticle_id=6536517&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbestbuy.7tiv.net%2Fc%2F1804712%2F614286%2F10014%3Fu%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.bestbuy.com%252Fproduct%252Fsony-wh-1000xm4-wireless-noise-cancelling-over-the-ear-headphones-black%252FJ7XSRH44JK%26partnerpropertyid%3D1423009&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsony-noise-canceling-headphone-deals-bf2025%2F1100-6536517%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Save+On+Sony%27s+Noise-Canceling+Headphones+%26+Earbuds&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A23&amp;fnarticle_id=6536517&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbestbuy.7tiv.net%2Fc%2F1804712%2F614286%2F10014%3Fu%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.bestbuy.com%252Fproduct%252Fsony-wh-1000xm4-wireless-noise-cancelling-over-the-ear-headphones-black%252FJ7XSRH44JK%26partnerpropertyid%3D1423009&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsony-noise-canceling-headphone-deals-bf2025%2F1100-6536517%2F&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Save+On+Sony%27s+Noise-Canceling+Headphones+%26+Earbuds&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A23&amp;fnarticle_id=6536517&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbestbuy.7tiv.net%2Fc%2F1804712%2F614286%2F10014%3Fu%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.bestbuy.com%252Fproduct%252Fsony-wh-1000xm4-wireless-noise-cancelling-over-the-ear-headphones-black%252FJ7XSRH44JK%26partnerpropertyid%3D1423009&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsony-noise-canceling-headphone-deals-bf2025%2F1100-6536517%2F&amp;event_type=click">Sony WH-1000XM4</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Save+On+Sony%27s+Noise-Canceling+Headphones+%26+Earbuds&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A23&amp;fnarticle_id=6536517&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbestbuy.7tiv.net%2Fc%2F1804712%2F614286%2F10014%3Fu%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.bestbuy.com%252Fproduct%252Fsony-wh-1000xm4-wireless-noise-cancelling-over-the-ear-headphones-black%252FJ7XSRH44JK%26partnerpropertyid%3D1423009&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsony-noise-canceling-headphone-deals-bf2025%2F1100-6536517%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Save+On+Sony%27s+Noise-Canceling+Headphones+%26+Earbuds&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A23&amp;fnarticle_id=6536517&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbestbuy.7tiv.net%2Fc%2F1804712%2F614286%2F10014%3Fu%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.bestbuy.com%252Fproduct%252Fsony-wh-1000xm4-wireless-noise-cancelling-over-the-ear-headphones-black%252FJ7XSRH44JK%26partnerpropertyid%3D1423009&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsony-noise-canceling-headphone-deals-bf2025%2F1100-6536517%2F&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Save+On+Sony%27s+Noise-Canceling+Headphones+%26+Earbuds&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-11-26+11%3A54%3A23&amp;fnarticle_id=6536517&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbestbuy.7tiv.net%2Fc%2F1804712%2F614286%2F10014%3Fu%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.bestbuy.com%252Fproduct%252Fsony-wh-1000xm4-wireless-noise-cancelling-over-the-ear-headphones-black%252FJ7XSRH44JK%26partnerpropertyid%3D1423009&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsony-noise-canceling-headphone-deals-bf2025%2F1100-6536517%2F&amp;event_type=click">$160 (was $350)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>While Amazon's deal on the Sony WH-1000XM5 headphones is great, Best Buy has its own exclusive deal on the previous generation model, the Sony WH-1000XM4 headphones. These are very similar to the WH-1000XM5 in form factor, features, and sound quality. While they aren't quite as powerful as the XM5 model, the XM4 headphones still offer excellent playback quality and noise cancellation. Battery life last up to roughly 30 hours, and the support quick-charge via the included charging cable. They also include handy features like touch playback controls, AI audio upscaling, and multipoint Bluetooth pairing so you can connect them to multiple devices simultaneously.</p><p>Thanks to Best Buy's Black Friday doorbuster deal, you can grab these for just $160 (normally $350), making this the biggest Black Friday discount we've seen for Sony's headphones so far. However, unlike Amazon's deals, there are no extra bonuses.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM6-Headphones-Microphones-Studio-Quality/dp/B0F3PQHWTZ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-WH-1000XM6-Headphones-Microphones-Studio-Quality\/dp\/B0F3PQHWTZ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM6-Headphones-Microphones-Studio-Quality/dp/B0F3PQHWTZ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">Sony WH-1000XM6 Wireless ANC Headphones</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM6-Headphones-Microphones-Studio-Quality/dp/B0F3PQHWTZ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-WH-1000XM6-Headphones-Microphones-Studio-Quality\/dp\/B0F3PQHWTZ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM6-Headphones-Microphones-Studio-Quality/dp/B0F3PQHWTZ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">$398 (was $460) | Includes 60 days of Audible</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>If you'd like to check out the newest model in Sony's WH-1000XM line, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM6-Headphones-Microphones-Studio-Quality/dp/B0F3PQHWTZ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the Sony WH-1000XM6</a> headphones are discounted to $398 (was $460). These offer improved ANC performance, Bluetooth 5.3 support, and a foldable design. The WH-1000XM6 is equipped with a QN3 processor and 12 microphones, further refining its voice capture and noise-cancellation capabilities. Along with the  You'll also get a 60-day Audible subscription with your purchase.</p>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Canceling-Wireless-Headphones-Comfortable/dp/B0CWVX1GNX?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-Canceling-Wireless-Headphones-Comfortable\/dp\/B0CWVX1GNX?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Canceling-Wireless-Headphones-Comfortable/dp/B0CWVX1GNX?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">Sony Ult Wear Over-Ear Noise Canceling Bluetooth Headphones</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Canceling-Wireless-Headphones-Comfortable/dp/B0CWVX1GNX?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-Canceling-Wireless-Headphones-Comfortable\/dp\/B0CWVX1GNX?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Canceling-Wireless-Headphones-Comfortable/dp/B0CWVX1GNX?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">$148 (was $250)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>Amazon's other Black Friday deals for Sony headphones include the Sony Ultra Wear Over-Ear Noise-Canceling Bluetooth Headphones. While they're not quite on par with the tech in the WH-1000X line, they're still a solid choice for mid-range active noise cancellation. Note that this is the only Sony headphone deal at Amazon that does not include a bonus gift card or Audible subscription.</p>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-CH720N-Canceling-Headphones-Microphone/dp/B0BS74M665?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-WH-CH720N-Canceling-Headphones-Microphone\/dp\/B0BS74M665?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-CH720N-Canceling-Headphones-Microphone/dp/B0BS74M665?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">Sony WH-CH720N</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-CH720N-Canceling-Headphones-Microphone/dp/B0BS74M665?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-WH-CH720N-Canceling-Headphones-Microphone\/dp\/B0BS74M665?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-CH720N-Canceling-Headphones-Microphone/dp/B0BS74M665?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">$88 (was $171) | Includes 60 days of Audible</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>If the above headphone models are outside your price range, you might want to check out the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-CH720N-Canceling-Headphones-Microphone/dp/B0BS74M665?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">budget-friendly WH-CH720N</a>, which are down to $88 (was $171). This is another pair of wireless noice-cancelling headphones, and though they lack some of the premium features of the other models we've covered, they also won't break the bank. You'll also get a complimentary 60-day Audible subscription along with the discounted price if you grab these at Amazon.</p>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C33XXS56?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0C33XXS56?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C33XXS56?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">Sony XM5 Earbuds</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C33XXS56?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0C33XXS56?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C33XXS56?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">$228 (was $248) | Includes 60 days of Audible</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>For something more compact, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C33XXS56?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Sony XM5 Earbuds are on sale for $228</a> (was $248). These offer the same noise-cancelling features as the XM5, just in a true wireless earbud form factor. The earbuds use Bluetooth wireless connectivity and offer up to 8 hours of battery life, which can be extended to 24 hours with the included charging case. Like the other Sony XM headphone deals at Amazon, the retailer is including a free 60-day Audible subscription with your purchase.</p>                      </div>   </div><p>If you'd like to check out the newest model, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM6-Headphones-Microphones-Studio-Quality/dp/B0F3PQHWTZ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the Sony WH-1000XM6 </a><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM6-Headphones-Microphones-Studio-Quality/dp/B0F3PQHWTZ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">headphones </a>have been discounted to $398 (was $460). There are a few key differences with the latest model, as it adds more articulation to the headphones for increased foldability, supports Bluetooth 5.3, and improves on noise-cancelling. The WH-1000XM6 is equipped with a QN3 processor and 12 microphones, further refining its audio quality and noise-cancelling functions. You'll also get a 60-day Audible subscription with your purchase.</p><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Canceling-Wireless-Headphones-Comfortable/dp/B0CWVX1GNX?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Ultimate Ears headset </a>for $143 (was $250)</p><p>For something even more compact, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C33XXS56?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Sony XM5 Earbuds are on sale for $228</a> (was $248), and these offer the same noise-cancelling features as the XM5. The Bluetooth earbuds have a battery life of up to 8 hours, which can be extended to 24 hours with the charging case.</p><p><strong>Sign up for GameSpot's Weekly Deals Newsletter:</strong></p><hr><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-first-ps5-pro-deal-in-six-months-is-up-for-grabs-for-a-limited-time/1100-6526406/">The First PS5 Pro Deal In Six Months Is Up For Grabs For A Limited Time</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-ps5-slim-bundles-and-collectors-edition-get-huge-discounts/1100-6534326/">Ghost Of Yotei PS5 Slim Bundles And Collector's Edition Get Huge Discounts</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/8bitdo-ultimate-2-switch-2-pc-controller-review-best-deals-at-amazon/1100-6529695/">Save Big On 8BitDo's Stellar Ultimate 2 Controllers In Amazon's Black Friday Sale</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/evercade-exp-r-tomb-raider-cartridge-bundle-retro-gaming-amazon-black-friday-deals/1100-6534530/">Evercade Retro Handhelds &amp; Cartridges Get Rare Price Cuts In Amazon's Black Friday Sale</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide/1100-6534089/">Kirby Air Riders Buying Guide: Release-Day Delivery Still Available At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/meta-quest-3s-vr-headset-best-black-friday-deals/1100-6532962/">Meta Quest 3S Black Friday Deal - Save Up To $70 And Get $50 Amazon Credit</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-gamecube-third-party-controller-switch-2-pc-amazon-holiday-deal/1100-6532458/">Grab A Wireless GameCube-Style Controller For Switch 1/2 &amp; PC For Only $40</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lunar-remastered-collection-amazon-exclusive-physical-edition-deal-switch-playstation-xbox/1100-6528818/">Amazon-Exclusive Lunar Remastered Collection Gets First Price Cut</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

    
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-noise-canceling-headphone-deals-bf2025/1100-6536517/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Of Warcraft's Midnight Expansion Launches In March 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-midnight-expansion-launches-in-march-2026/1100-6536536/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1365817</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536536">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-midnight-beta-details-shared-by-blizzard/1100-6535837/" data-ref-id="1100-6535837">World of Warcraft: Midnight</a>, the eleventh expansion in the long-running MMO and the second chapter of the Worldsoul Saga, is set to launch on March 2, 2026. Positioned between The War Within (2024) and the future expansion The Last Titan, Midnight marks a major return to one of Azeroth's most iconic settings while pushing the overarching saga toward its cosmic climax. Revealed during this past summer and <a href="https://google.com/search?q=gamespot+gamescom+warcraft&amp;udm=14" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">showcased heavily at Gamescom</a>, the expansion signals a dramatic escalation in the war between Light and Void.</p><p>Set in a fully rebuilt and reimagined Quel'Thalas, Midnight centers on a massive Void invasion led by Xal'atath, whose manipulations during The War Within left Azeroth vulnerable to the voidlord Dimensius. The Void now seeks to claim the Sunwell--a source of potent magical energy--and plunge the world into terror. Players will work to reunite the fractured elven tribes, forge alliances with ancient powers, and ultimately join the Light's armies in a desperate effort to repel the Shadow once and for all. Zones such as Eversong, Zul'Aman, Harandar, and the Voidstorm will be heavily featured for the campaign. </p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oK_-6glk2MM" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/oK_-6glk2MM" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Midnight introduces several major gameplay features and progression updates, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-player-housing-finally-arrives-december-2-after-decades-of-waiting/1100-6536160/" data-ref-id="1100-6536160">including player housing</a>, a long-requested addition to the game. The expansion also debuts a new Allied Race, the Haranir, an ancient, root-dwelling people from the hidden zone of Harandar whose flora-grown architecture evokes the natural magics of early Azeroth. Players will be able to choose their zone progression order after completing Eversong, offering additional flexibility in how the campaign unfolds. Alongside returning lore heavyweights such as Wrathion, Khadgar, and Alexstrasza, the story pushes deeper into the tumult of the Worldsoul Saga.</p><p>Onboarding systems for both new and returning players are being refreshed as well. Beginners will now flow from <a href="https://worldofwarcraft.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24226733" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Exile's Reach directly into a streamlined "story mode"</a> version of Dragonflight, complete with narrative versions of raid finales, ending at level 70. Returning players can take a guided recap tour through Arathi Highlands with Jaina or Thrall, unlocking gear scaled to their level and covering core gameplay essentials like skyriding and interrupts. There will also be a War Within catch-up--designed to hit the expansion's major story beats in just a few hours--that helps new and returning players progress smoothly from level 70 to 80 as they enter Midnight and continue the Worldsoul Saga.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-midnight-expansion-launches-in-march-2026/1100-6536536/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splash Damage Facing More Layoffs Two Months After Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/splash-damage-layoffs-after-sale/</link>
            <guid>1365790</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Splash Damage, the studio behind games like Gears Tactics and Star Wars: Hunters, is facing layoffs that could impact the entire company.</p>



<p>These new layoffs are happening just two months after Splash Damage was sold by former parent company Tencent to an unknown group of private equity investors. </p>







<h2 id="h-splash-damage-layoffs-are-studio-wide">Splash Damage Layoffs Are “Studio-Wide”</h2>



<p>In a post on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/splash-damage_an-update-from-splash-damage-activity-7399486098588196864-pz0I/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">social media</a> on Wednesday, it was announced that the company was <strong>“entering a studio-wide consultation process affecting all roles.”</strong> This consultation, they say, was a <strong>“difficult step” </strong>for the company, but it’s one that they believe is <strong>“necessary so Splash Damage can remain agile and adaptable in what has been a very challenging market.”</strong></p>



<p>This is the second time this year that Splash Damage has faced layoffs. After the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/transformers-reactivate-cancelled-splash-damage-to-lay-off-developers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cancelation of Transformers: Reactivate</a>, the studio said that it needed to scale down in order to <strong>“refocus our efforts on other projects.”</strong></p>



<p>Those efforts included Star Wars: Hunters, a game that released on mobile in June 2024. In January 2025, the game released in Early Access on Windows, but was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-hunters-is-shutting-down-in-october/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">canceled just two months</a> later with the game shutting down fully on October 1, 2025.</p>







<p>The company’s statement on Wednesday ended with a promise to “explore every option” in order to retain as many employees as possible, while giving support to those who will be let go.</p>



<p><strong>“We know this kind of change is emotionally tough, and we will do what we can to guide our people through this process with honesty and care,”</strong> they said.</p>



<p>Formed in 2001, Splash Damage has worked on a mix of its own games while also co-developing other titles. Games on its resume include Gears of War 4 and 5, Halo: The Master Chief Collection, and Doom 3. Currently, the studio is working on an open-world survival game called “Project Astrid”. That game was announced back in 2023, but no updates have come since. </p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to ask if the sale had anything to do with the layoffs. Should a response be received, it will be added to this story.</p>



<p>What do you think of Splash Damage having more layoffs just two months after being sold? Leave your thoughts down below and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pc-ram-prices-have-soared-by-up-to-250/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PC RAM prices rising by as much as 250%</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/splash-damage-layoffs-after-sale/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega Suggests Expectations for 'Definitive Editions' Could be Behind Disappointing Launch Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sega-suggests-expectations-for-definitive-editions-could-be-behind-disappointing-launch-sales</link>
            <guid>1365784</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sega is pointing to consumer expectations for “definitive editions” as one potential cause behind lower-than-expected sales for some of its recent games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As spotted by <a href="https://gamebiz.jp/news/416531" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>GameBiz</u></a>, the Sonic the Hedgehog and Persona company opened up about its performance throughout the last few months during a Q2 financial briefing Q&amp;A session with shareholders yesterday. The conversation (via <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/sega-is-aware-its-past-definitive-version-releases-could-be-deterring-players-from-buying-games-at-launch/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Automaton</u></a>) saw Sega address the thought process behind why sales for its new premium and free-to-play games failed to meet expectations despite generally positive reviews from critics and fans.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Sega says a number of elements could be contributing to disappointing returns, including competition from other releases within the same genre, as well as launch prices. The gaming publisher also suggested gamers could be passing on purchasing games at launch due to an expectation they will eventually be able to purchase “definitive editions” of those same titles further down the line.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Definitive editions, which typically encompass video game re-releases with relatively minor visual upgrades and additional content, have become a popular tactic for publishers to utilize throughout the last decade. Sega is no stranger to the idea either, especially when it comes to Persona and Shin Megami Tensei developer Atlus.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The studio has a history of pushing re-releases for games like Persona 4 and 5, which received <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/persona-4-golden">Golden</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/persona-5-royal">Royal</a> versions a few years after their initial launches. There’s also Shin Megami Tensei V, which originally released in 2021 and went on to come to more platforms with its Vengeance counterpart in 2024. Atlus’ latest, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metaphor-refantazio"><u>Metaphor: ReFantazio</u></a>, released for PC, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S late last year.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Sega didn’t specifically call out any game or franchise when pointing to its definitive edition theory. The company also generally seems hesitant to directly place the blame on any one factor for now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“While we haven’t been able to pinpoint a precise cause of [the lower-than-expected sales performance], we believe the problem also lies in our marketing, which wasn’t able to sufficiently convey the appeal of our games to users,” a Sega spokesperson told investors.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s unclear if Metaphor: ReFantazio or any other Sega series will receive a definitive edition or equivalent re-release in the future. For now, fans are eagerly awaiting any news Atlus may have to share about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-6-everything-we-know-so-far"><u>Persona 6</u></a>. A <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/persona-3-reload"><u>Persona 3 remake</u></a>, subtitled Reload, launched early last year, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/persona-4-revival"><u>Persona 4 Revival</u></a> set to<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/p-studio-director-confident-persona-4-revival-will-be-fresh-and-surprising"> <u>give its sequel the same treatment</u></a> sometime in the near future. Sega is also continuing to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-racing-crossworlds-finally-has-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition-release-date-and-its-not-too-far-away">roll out new content</a> for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/sonic-racing-crossworlds">Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</a>, which launched in September.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>If you're hunting for the best offers this week, we're actively rounding up the strongest Black Friday deals on video games, tech, and more. You can find all our top picks and price drops in our full </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2025-predictions-and-latest-news"><em>Black Friday hub</em></a><em>, or check out our relevant pages for </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-black-friday-sale-is-officially-live-2025"><em>PlayStation</em></a><em>, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-black-friday-sale-is-officially-live-2025"><em>Nintendo</em></a><em>, and </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-xbox-predictions-what-to-expect-2025?_cache=pass"><em>Xbox</em></a><em> deals.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/sega-suggests-expectations-for-definitive-editions-could-be-behind-disappointing-launch-sales]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2: Renegades Presents a Much-Needed Refresh With a Star Wars Twist]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/destiny-2-renegades-presents-a-much-needed-refresh-with-a-star-wars-twist</link>
            <guid>1365778</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">As Destiny 2 gets closer to its tenth anniversary, the shared world action-RPG is currently at something of a crossroads. Following the end of The Final Shape, many players struggled to keep up with the steep power grind and evolving saga set up by The Edge of Fate. It's hard to deny those clear stumbles with Destiny 2 in 2025, but there's still so much potential for strong storytelling and slick action within the growing universe of Bungie's satisfying online RPG.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And that's what makes the upcoming Renegades expansion an interesting next step for Destiny 2. It not only seeks to realign the ascent to greater power for players but also expands the universe with a pulpy, sci-fi storyline that leans right into the influence of Star Wars. After getting an early hands-on experience with Destiny 2: Renegades, I got to appreciate the way that developer Bungie is rethinking Destiny 2's power grind, and how they're getting players to embrace the scoundrel's life as they navigate the shifting battle zones of the new Lawless Frontier.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Destiny 2: Renegades – Weapons Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Renegades picks up after the events of The Edge of Fate, with The Drifter warning the Guardians of a threat led by a new Cabal faction known as the Barrant Imperium and a mysterious fallen guardian named Bael. Embarking on a new mission without support from the Vanguard, The Drifter and other returning allies will form alliances with the growing network of syndicates within the new Lawless Frontier – all to take on the Barrant Imperium, fight back against the fallen guardian, and uncover the larger conspiracy that The Nine are working towards. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It's not so much the Star Wars universe invading Destiny 2, a la Fortnite, but rather Destiny 2 leveraging its own lore for its take on a Star Wars story.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">What's interesting about the story with Renegades is that it's simultaneously the next phase of Destiny 2's ongoing Fate saga – setting up changes to the galaxy's power dynamics – yet it's also an expansion that pays deep homage to the Star Wars series. It's not so much the Star Wars universe invading Destiny 2, a la Fortnite, but rather Destiny 2 leveraging its own lore for its take on a Star Wars story. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Destiny 2: Renegades – Gear Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">According to game director Tyson Green, Destiny 2: Renegades taps into a similar conceit to the Forsaken expansion and its space western revenge plot. But the opportunity to collaborate with Lucasfilm on a Star Wars crossover allowed them to take it further with a compelling crossover for the Renegades expansion. "One of the advantages that the new release model gave us, which is two expansions a year, means you can experiment more within those individual expansions – you can try different things," Green said. "So we saw what we wanted to do with a 'space western' revenge story, and we figured, let's do it in that one, let's aim for this. So we took the idea of Star Wars as total inspiration and built a Destiny expansion around it; that's kind of how we always do it. In this case, I think it comes through much more richly, because it's being more deliberate with its influences and style, but it's still fundamentally a Destiny expansion."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the surface, it can come off as an extended series of cheeky references, and it initially took me some time to get used to the visual homages to Star Wars iconography – such as a near one-to-one recreation of the opening of A New Hope, complete with movie-accurate sound effects. But I got more into it as it went on, and I appreciated the attempt at trying to make a front-facing mash-up of sorts. I especially had a blast hopping into a giant walker to mow down foes. So far, it feels like a good fit, and honestly, much of the Star Wars aspect fits, given that Destiny and most modern sci-fi and fantasy media already have Star Wars DNA baked in. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Destiny 2: Renegades – Environments Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In keeping with the Star Wars connection, Renegades also introduces the Blaster weapon variant, and just like Han Solo's and Chewbacca's guns from the movies, the Blasters hit hard and can fire quickly. They're essentially laser weapons that require venting to avoid overheating, which is a fair tradeoff considering how useful they can be in a fight. To be clear, these aren't totally new weapon archetypes, but rather new guns with a twist, some of which are variants of older guns like the Sweet Business exotic. But the added wrinkle of venting guns in between downtime does change up firefights a bit, and it can be super satisfying to tear into enemies with a Gatling Blaster rifle that feels right out of The Clone Wars.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">By far the most unique weapon to acquire is the exotic Praxic Blade, Destiny 2's take on the lightsaber. Though similar to Destiny 2's existing power swords, the Praxic Blade is an exotic special weapon that deals heavy damage and grants guardians the ability to deflect incoming enemy fire, and can even be thrown like a boomerang to deal ranged damage. It's a very satisfying weapon to use, and the exotic quest to acquire it was a strong mission that made me feel like I was taking on a trippy Jedi challenge. I don't use swords too often in Destiny 2, but I ended up using the Praxic Blade a lot more than I thought I would, given how useful it was against crowds. Also, playing as my Warlock really allowed me to live out that Jedi fantasy within Destiny.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Destiny 2: Renegades – Lawless Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Unlike The Final Shape and The Edge of Fate, the primary campaign of Renegades takes a less guided approach and doesn't steer you into the core missions to make progress. Outside of the key story missions that will take you to bespoke locales, the majority of the action in Renegades focuses on building up your reputation within the Lawless Frontier, where you'll take on various missions ranging from smuggling, sabotage, and bounty hunts of key targets. Your new home base is the Tharsis Cantina on Mars. In this social space, you and other guardians will build up your reputation with the different syndicates vying for power within the Lawless Frontier. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The majority of the action in Renegades focuses on building up your reputation within the Lawless Frontier.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, the expansion doesn't introduce a new destination to explore. It instead focuses on building up the Cantina social space and the excursions into the new battle zones across Mars, Europa, and a remixed Venus in the Lawless Frontier activities. This does make for a smaller scope, but I felt more engaged with how I could take my time before jumping into new activities, which focus on solo or fireteam missions fighting rival syndicates. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the new systems in the Cantina is the Syndicates, three factions vying for control of territory across the Lawless Frontier. In keeping with the scoundrel fantasy, you'll have to decide which of them you'll work with to build up a reputation and unlock rewards. My favorite faction was the Tharsis Reformation, a Vex sect that broke away from the machine hivemind and gained its own sentience – and it also wears its own jackets to showcase its individuality. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The syndicates are an interesting addition, and it really helped to showcase the Cantina as a fully realized den of scum and villainy – and you can even bribe characters within the social space to get tips on secrets within the Lawless Frontier. But what I really liked about the Syndicates in particular is that they felt like a more developed version of the Faction system from Destiny 1. In Renegades, you're actually helping these syndicates amass power within the Lawless Frontier, which will unlock bonus Renegade abilities to use in the field and more specialized gear. This especially comes into play with some missions that focus on contested territories, which require you to take on priority contracts to help your chosen syndicate secure them.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking with core creative director Ben Womack, he stated that a valuable lesson learned was that it's necessary to think beyond boundaries and try to expand upon the usual structure and tone when necessary. The opportunity to make a Star Wars-themed Destiny 2 expansion helped the team rethink elements of the game's signature style and structure.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I think my big lesson that I learned is that when you're making something new, you often have a bunch of conventions and boundaries that you have to consider, especially for games that have been around for a long time like Destiny," Womack said. "It's tempting to stick to those conventions as being the boundaries of the rules, but the truth is that you need to re-examine all of them every single time when trying to really create something special and make a splash. This is especially true when having a partnership with Lucasfilm. We looked at how we made the sandbox stuff we've done, we now have blaster weapons that will stay with us going forward, seeing how the Praxic Blade turned out, and we have the various new syndicates that turned out well. There are things that we definitely wouldn't have done, but we had to accept and push past those usual boundaries to do these things, and as long as it's still fun and people are responding to it, and the feel is there, then it's the right decision."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I was really impressed with how chaotic and exciting the Lawless Frontier jobs were. These PvE-focused missions feel like stepping behind enemy lines, where you have to complete dynamic objectives. It really kept my team constantly on the move, and once the job was complete, we had to make one last sprint to the exfil to complete the mission, or else suffer the consequences. One of the big twists with these missions is that you can activate new Renegade abilities to call in support drops. I was able to summon a vex shield for protection, call in an aerial bombardment, or even activate battle armor to dish out to help even the odds. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I was really impressed with how chaotic and exciting the Lawless Frontier jobs were.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Depending on what difficulty you're playing on, the challenge can really ramp up quickly, especially when playing on a mission that allows for enemy player invasions. Much like the Gambit mode, a lone rival player can step into your squad's game and take you out to earn rewards for their syndicate. You can opt out of missions with invasions. Still, it does present a fascinating and unnerving twist to the missions, and you're not totally punished for getting wiped out by a particularly devious player who can get the jump on you. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, gaining power and earning the new gear to develop your guardians is the big drive for playing Destiny 2. Unfortunately, players struggled to keep up with The Edge of Fate's shifting power levels and steep grind, leading many longtime players to move on. During our hands-on, the developers were candid about how they handled that approach in the previous expansion, and one of the larger updates coming with Renegades is realigning the game's power approach so it won't require as many hurdles to overcome.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Along with a refocused loot pool that will be a bit more generous and balanced with getting players powered, there are also new and refreshed activities and pinnacle ops for players to take on, which include more difficulty tuning options for players who want to maximize their chances for gaining solid loot. Along with 300 new storage slots in the vault, the portal menu and its variety of noteworthy missions to tackle will also see a refreshed version of the Seasonal Hub, which offers additional rewards for players to acquire by completing daily and weekly challenges that will give more incentive to dive into the activities of the hubs. This system was introduced in The Edge of Fate, but Renegade's updated version is easier and more inviting to engage with.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">According to the game director, they took the criticism to heart following the release of The Edge of Fate and have been steadily releasing updates to make the next expansion one that keeps players engaged and not frustrated by the grind.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We looked at the problem that we had and we said, 'We think there's a route here,' which is leaning into more systems of pursuit, getting new tiers of gear, armor sets, and power progression, and things like challenge customization," Green said. "These things that can allow a core audience of players to really say, like, I'm really gonna take this game and put it through its paces, and get good rewards for it. It sounds great on paper, but it didn't work. I think we've been taught a bunch of hard lessons about what our players want, and there are really two kinds of live games: there are live games that listen to the players and respond to them, and then there are dead ones.  And we don't want to be a dead live game, we want to keep building Destiny. So we're listening to our players, and what our players are telling us is that they don't want to chase a simple number that goes up, they want real rewards."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Though I wasn't able to get a sense of the larger pursuit of power with my limited hands-on time, I did appreciate that Destiny 2: Renegades feels a bit more generous with its loot quality and ways to move up. Those pain points in Edge of Fate made the progression a slog, but with Renegades, I found myself getting a lot more into the flow – plus I really liked that it allowed me to get the Praxic Blade fairly early on. However, I do worry that D2's new direction with the Portal hub continues its menu-heavy focus. It's convenient, for sure, but it's also a bit of a headache to navigate, and it lessens the motivation to visit the various social spaces and destinations.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So far, Destiny 2: Renegades feels like a proper step forward for the live-service pioneer's next chapter, making for a more player-conscious experience. It's certainly not looking to reinvent Destiny 2 with a new sprawling campaign, but rather, realign its approach to getting players back into the right flow that doesn't feel like a drag. Along with the new Star Wars-inspired campaign that taps into it, it could end up being the right kind of course correction that Destiny needs – plus it's fun to see a Star Wars story play out in the Bungie’s universe.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/destiny-2-renegades-presents-a-much-needed-refresh-with-a-star-wars-twist]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Is Down Along With A Number Of Other Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-is-down-along-with-a-number-of-other-games/1100-6536537/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1365775</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536537">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>As America heads into a long holiday weekend for Thanksgiving, one of the most popular games on the planet, Fortnite, is encountering some significant issues. Epic Games has acknowledged server struggles for Fortnite, with players unable to get into the game at all.</p><p>"Our team is investigating the issue and we'll follow up once the issue has been resolved," it said. GameSpot attempted to access Fortnite around 2:10 PM ET and could not get into the Epic launcher, let alone access Fortnite.</p><p>As usual with any outage, your mileage may vary. But the issues today with Fortnite were severe and prolonged enough for Epic to release a statement addressing the matter.</p><p>The issues appear to be related to a log-in bug affecting the Epic Games Store and games that utilize Epic Online Services. "We'll provide an update ASAP as we have more info, and the issue is fixed," the company <a href="https://x.com/EOSStatus/status/1993746004676624805" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said.</a></p><p>Reports have also pointed to issues today with other games and gaming services, including Xbox Live, Apex Legends, and Battle.net, among others.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><blockquote><p dir="ltr">⚠️ We’re aware of players being unable to login to Fortnite.<br>Our team is investigating the issue and we'll follow up once the issue has been resolved.</p>  — Fortnite Status (@FortniteStatus) <a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteStatus/status/1993739293689536842?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 26, 2025</a></blockquote>


  






  </div><p>The Fortnite server issues are cropping up just ahead of the end of the current Simpsons collaboration and the start of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-7-start-date-new-map-and-everything-we-know-so-far/1100-6536068/" data-ref-id="1100-6536068">Chapter 7</a> on November 29.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-6-finale-live-event-everything-you-need-to-know-about-zero-hour/1100-6536400/" data-ref-id="1100-6536400">Fortnite Zero Hour event </a>that kicks off Chapter 7 takes place on Saturday, November 29, at 11 AM PT / 2 PM ET / 7 PM GMT. Then on November 30 at the same time, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-get-a-free-kill-bill-fortnite-skin/1100-6536515/" data-ref-id="1100-6536515">The Lost Chapter: Yuki's Revenge</a> will begin in Fortnite. This is the Quentin Tarantino collaboration regarding a previously untold Kill Bill story.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7h1aMVdBEk" data-width="854" data-height="480" data-video-start="15">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/x7h1aMVdBEk?start=15" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>We will update this post with more information about Fortnite's server status as it becomes available.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-is-down-along-with-a-number-of-other-games/1100-6536537/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Let's Compare All Three Versions Of Dragon Quest VII, Including Reimagined]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/11/26/lets-compare-all-three-versions-of-dragon-quest-vii-including-reimagined</link>
            <guid>1365772</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</a> is the latest game to grace <a href="https://gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2025/10/21/cover-reveal-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">the cover of <em>Game Informer</em></a>, and you can read all about that here. If you're familiar with the history of this specific Dragon Quest entry, then you likely already know Reimagined is the second time Square Enix has remade Dragon Quest VII.&nbsp;</p><p>It released the original Dragon Quest VII in 2000 on PlayStation in Japan and a year later as Dragon Warrior VII in the U.S. Square Enix remade it for the Nintendo 3DS, launching Dragon Quest VII: Fragments of the Forgotten Past in 2013 in Japan before releasing it in the West in 2016. Now, Square Enix is remaking it a second time, with Reimagined launching next year on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, Switch 2, Switch, and PC.&nbsp;</p><p>It's rare to see a single entry get this many remakes, so we've created two galleries to show you the differences between the original Dragon Quest VII, the 3DS remake, and Reimagined, using the same spot across the years.&nbsp;</p><h2>Gallery 1: Original vs. 3DS Remake vs. Reimagined</h2><h2>Gallery 2: Original vs. 3DS Remake vs. Reimagined</h2><p>As you can see, the differences are pretty stark due to hardware limitations and varying visual styles and aesthetics. We're excited for Reimagined, though, and you can read about why in the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/11/04/adventure-doesnt-wait"><em>Game Informer </em>cover story here</a>, and if you aren't already a subscriber, be sure to <a href="https://gameinformer.com/subscribe">subscribe here</a>.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Which visual style for Dragon Quest VII do you like best? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/11/26/lets-compare-all-three-versions-of-dragon-quest-vii-including-reimagined]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digital Foundry Dives Into Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition's "Big Downgrades" On Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/digital-foundry-dives-into-tomb-raider-definitive-editions-big-downgrades-on-switch-2</link>
            <guid>1365760</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>

<p>Our good friends over at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2_9EQ02fVA8">Digital Foundry</a> have delivered their tech review of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/tomb-raider-definitive-edition">Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition</a>, which shadow dropped onto Switch 1 and 2 last week, and it's something of a mixed bag.</p>
<p>Starting on a positive note, the Switch 2 version of the game sets out to hit 60fps, and it does so <em>c</em><em>onsistently</em>. DF's Thomas Morgan notes that he noticed "barely any drops" when playing in either handheld or docked modes, so that's a big bonus for fans of smoothness.</p>
<p>What's more, the Switch/Switch 2 'Definitive Edition' boasts many of the re-release 'pros' over the PS3 original — upgraded textures, foliage placement, colour grading, etc. — and renders at 1920x1080p resolution in docked (similarly hits 1080p in handheld). Nice.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, there are some pretty glaring visual omissions in the Switch version to get things running at the specs outlined above. Shadow density is pulled way back, foliage thickness is reduced, the advanced TRESSFX for Lara's hair is MIA, and many of the cutscenes' cinematics are dialled down for simplicity.</p>
<p>It falls behind the Definitive Edition's PS4 release, in this instance, but strangely, there are select points where the Switch 2 version is even a step back from the PS3 original. There are no screen-splat rain effects, the geometry is more simplistic, and even shadow coverage is a bit of a downgrade. It should be noted that these cutbacks <em>also</em> apply to the PS4 re-release, but, as the DF video states, "the drawbacks are disappointing, given the multi-generational divide between the systems".</p>
<p>For those wondering about the Switch 1 version, the older system runs things at 30fps (sometimes dipping into the 20s in demanding cutscenes), with a "surprisingly respectable" 864p-900p. Many of the visuals are matched between the systems, and while Switch 1 does see a further drop in shadow quality, it "holds up much better than you might expect," according to DF.</p>
<p>You'll find the full Digital Foundry tech review in <a href="https://www.digitalfoundry.net/reviews/tomb-raider-definitive-edition-painful-downgrades-on-switch-2">written form</a>, as well as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/tomb-raider-definitive-edition">our thoughts</a> on Lara's latest, down below.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194042,194383 @ 1764186304 -->
<p><em>What do you make of Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition on Switch (2)? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2_9EQ02fVA8" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2_9EQ02fVA8">youtube.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/a83b6c329ed02daf79f5ff949ee33012 @ 1764185837 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/digital-foundry-dives-into-tomb-raider-definitive-editions-big-downgrades-on-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Eclipses 35 Million Copies Sold, Work on Cyberpunk 2077 Sequel Continues to Scale Up]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-eclipses-35-million-copies-sold-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-scales-up/</link>
            <guid>1365754</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>CD Projekt RED reported its latest financial results today with its <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/pl/wp-content/uploads-pl/2025/11/prezentacja-wynikowa-q3-2025-en.pdf">third-quarter 2025 earnings report</a>. The report included a couple of notable updates on the studio's ongoing projects and a significant update about the studio's most infamous release, Cyberpunk 2077. </p>



<p>After what no one will deny was an absolutely disastrous launch, true to its word and commitment to try and right its wrongs, CD Projekt RED has overhauled and patched Cyberpunk 2077 to the point where the game has now sold <strong>35 million copies</strong> since it launched in December 2020. </p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Cyberpunk-2077-Hit-35-Million-Copies-Sold-Nov-2025.png"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: CD Projekt RED</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>This announcement comes almost exactly a year to the day after CD Projekt RED announced Cyberpunk 2077 <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-has-sold-over-30-million-units-says-cdpr/">had reached 30 million copies sold</a>. </p>



<p>No one will soon forget how, in 2020, CD Projekt RED withheld PS4 and Xbox One copies of Cyberpunk 2077 from reviewers ahead of launch, only handing out PC copies pre-release in an attempt to mask how poorly it ran on those previous-gen consoles and protect its pre-orders, and the backlash that followed. </p>



<p>That said, now that we're almost five years out from that disaster, even though it took CD Projekt RED three years to release the <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-2-0-update-release-date/">Cyberpunk 2077 2.0 patch</a>, we're arguably at the point where we can say CD Projekt RED has earned the ability not to be forever judged for Cyberpunk 2077's 2020 launch.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="[PL/EN] Grupa CD PROJEKT - wyniki finansowe za III kwartał 2025 r. | KOMENTARZ" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z0ENiOGmcic?start=3&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Though the real test of whether players can really trust CD Projekt RED again will come with the release of its next major title, The Witcher 4. Its launch will likely be the difference maker between whether players entirely abandon CDPR or start to really trust the developer again.</p>



<p>Speaking of The Witcher 4, work on the return of CDPR's other major franchise has continued to be the company's main focus, with 447 developers all working on it. Meanwhile, the percentage of developers working on the Cyberpunk 2077 sequel continues to scale up, with 135 developers now spread out between the studio's Vancouver, Warsaw, and Boston branches, <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-will-do-better-justice-to-its-settings-americana-thanks-to-the-new-boston-studio-says-cdpr/">the latter of which was opened specifically to work on the Cyberpunk 2077 sequel</a>.</p>



<p>Once The Witcher 4 is out the door, we can expect to see more of the company move to working on Project Orion, which is the given code name for the Cyberpunk 2077 sequel, which CDPR has also begun calling "<em>Cyberpunk 2</em>."</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/CD-Projekt-RED-Q3-2025-Report-1.png"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: CD Projekt RED</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>"<em>We are very happy and satisfied with the fact that - despite the passage of time - Cyberpunk 2077 remains such a well performing title and continues to attract new players</em>," said Michał Nowakowski, joint chief executive officer of CD Projekt RED in today's presentation. "<em>Sales of the game have exceeded 35 million copies, which testifies to the franchise's enduring power and enables us to be even more audacious about charting its future</em>."</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-eclipses-35-million-copies-sold-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-scales-up/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fighting Fantasy Set 2 Kickstarter is a Crowdfunding Critical Success]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/fighting-fantasy-set-2-kickstarter-is-crowdfunding-critical-success</link>
            <guid>1365751</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Today, the <em>Fighting Fantasy</em> Set 2 Kickstarter campaign went live. The campaign aims to reprint five more of the iconic solo adventuring book series. It has already reached its initial funding goal.</p>

<h2>The <em>Fighting Fantasy</em> Set 2 Kickstarter Campaign</h2>

<p>As the <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/sjgames/fighting-fantasy-solo-adventure-gamebooks-back-in-print" rel="nofollow">campaign page</a> states, the <em>Fighting Fantasy</em> Set 2 Kickstarter goal is to release updated versions of books 6-10 in the <em>Fighting Fantasy</em> series. This campaign is part of a <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/fighting-fantasy-solo-adventure-rpg-series-returns-to-us-through-steve-jackson-games" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">publishing agreement</a> signed by series co-creators Sir Ian Livingstone and Steve Jackson with Steve Jackson games to reprint the books in the United States.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/fighting-fantasy-set-2-book-display.jpg?itok=Rjn5pTab 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/fighting-fantasy-set-2-book-display.jpg?itok=dqxGFUPM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The campaign even opens with Steve Jackson Games applauding the fan response to their first Kickstarter campaign for reprinting set 1, saying it was the most successful crowdfunding campaign in the company's history.</p>

<p>But <em>Fighting Fantasy</em> Set 2 isn't just a reprint of the original 1980s books. The books will still feature the original artwork, but the formatting has been updated and the text size has been increased for easy reading. Finally, each book has a unified design, complete with numbered spines. Each book is around 224-384 pages and is approximately&nbsp;5.0625" x 7.8125", emulating the UK's B-format size.</p>

<p>The pledge tiers for <em>Fighting Fantasy</em> Set 2 are small and straightforward. If you want a single book from Set 2, it will cost you $15. If you want the full five-book set, that is $60. For the most pristine version, there is the slipcase set for $80. The campaign also includes several add-ons including books from <em>Fighting Fantasy</em> Set 1, and similar books from other series like <em>Choose Cthulhu</em>, and <em>The Fantasy Trip</em>.</p>

<p>At the time of writing, the <em>Fighting Fantasy</em> Set 2 Kickstarter campaign has raised&nbsp;<span><span>$106,836, more than four times its initial funding goal of $25,000. The campaign ends December 31 and books are expected to ship on July 2026.</span></span></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/fighting-fantasy-set-2-kickstarter-is-crowdfunding-critical-success]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Sales Now at 35m as Sequel Development Ramps Up]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cyberpunk-2077-sales-35m-sequel-work</link>
            <guid>1365745</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>CD Projekt Red has revealed that its open-world action RPG&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em>has hit a new sales milestone, and that work on the sequel is ramping up in earnest.</p>

<p>As part of its latest Q3 financial results presentation, the Polish studio says that&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em>sales have now passed 35 million, a figure that includes standalone sales and those racked up as part of the Ultimate Edition bundle (which includes the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty-release-date-revealed" rel="nofollow"><em>Phantom Liberty&nbsp;</em>expansion</a>).</p>

<p>The new figure means that&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em>has sold another five million copies <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cyberpunk-2077-sales-witcher-production" rel="nofollow">since November last year</a>, which is a pretty impressive achievement for a game that was released five years ago (although CD Projekt Red clearly very much considers the game a going concern).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cyberpunk-2077-sales-35m-bike.jpg?itok=usilwnmp 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cyberpunk-2077-sales-35m-bike.jpg?itok=pYos0TMt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em>has hit 35 million sales, and it's still going strong.</figcaption></figure><p>The presentation also reveals that CD Projekt Red has allocated another 19 staffers to work on&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2&nbsp;</em>since July this year, and that a number of new staff have been added in areas like localization and motion capture across the company as well.</p>

<p>Work on the new&nbsp;<em>Witcher&nbsp;</em>game also continues in earnest, although only three more developers have been hired to work on that project since July. It's likely to be a while before we hear more about&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/witcher-4-official-reveal" rel="nofollow"><em>The Witcher 4</em></a>, although whether that or&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2&nbsp;</em>will be officially unveiled first remains to be seen.</p>

<p>Across the company, sales are up when compared to the same period last year, mainly driven by increased sales of&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>; franchise sales for&nbsp;<em>The Witcher&nbsp;</em>have fallen since then, although the release of the Switch 2, along with its&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em>port, probably <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-third-party-game-launch-sales-report" rel="nofollow">helped in that area</a>.</p>

<p>Profits are up as well, and when looking at the year to date as a whole, CD Projekt Red's numbers are looking pretty healthy. Whether the company can sustain that health remains to be seen, however, especially with no new games imminently on the horizon.</p>




<p>We'll probably have to wait a while for new info about&nbsp;<em>The Witcher 4&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2</em>, but in the meantime, you can check out CD Projekt's full financial presentation for the third quarter of its fiscal year <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/pl/wp-content/uploads-pl/2025/11/prezentacja-wynikowa-q3-2025-en.pdf" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cyberpunk-2077-sales-35m-sequel-work]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Almost Twenty Years On, Beyond Good and Evil 2 Is Still in Development as New Job Listings Emerge]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/beyond-good-and-evil-2-new-job-postings</link>
            <guid>1365742</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ubisoft has posted several new job listings for&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil 2</em>, which means that almost twenty years after its original announcement, the long-awaited action-adventure game is still in development, although probably no closer to release.</p>

<p>As spotted by <a href="https://frvr.com/blog/ubisoft-is-still-working-on-beyond-good-and-evil-2-as-new-job-listings-pop-up-after-years-of-development-hell/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">FRVR</a>, new job listings on the Ubisoft <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/company/careers/search?query=beyond%2520good%2520and%2520evil%25202" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">website</a>&nbsp;are calling for a lead quest designer, a VFX artist, and a technical lead network programmer, among others, to work on the company's beleaguered sequel.</p>

<p>According to the listings,&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil 2&nbsp;</em>is still being built in the Voyager engine, which, as far as we know, hasn't yet been used for any other Ubisoft games. It was developed as a proprietary engine for use within&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil 2&nbsp;</em>itself.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/beyond-good-and-evil-2-job-listings-gameplay.jpg?itok=0x7f52Ga 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/beyond-good-and-evil-2-job-listings-gameplay.jpg?itok=QL_oWnKG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Beyond Good and Evil 2&nbsp;</em>is still in development...somehow.</figcaption></figure><p>The last time Ubisoft provided an update on&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil 2&nbsp;</em>was in <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/beyond-good-and-evil-2-gets-new-creative-director" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">October last year</a>, when a new creative lead, Fawzi Mesmar, stepped in to replace Emile Morel, who sadly passed away in 2023 of unknown causes.</p>

<p>It's been a very long and very strange journey for&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil 2&nbsp;</em>thus far. The project was originally announced during E3 in 2008, but subsequently underwent a lengthy period of radio silence before being <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-e3-2017-beyond-good-and-evil-2" rel="nofollow">reintroduced in 2017</a>.</p>

<p>Ubisoft subsequently drip-fed more information about the game in the ensuing years, including info about its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/beyond-good-and-evil-2-devs-show-off-ships-staff-combat" rel="nofollow">combat</a>, details about its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/beyond-good-and-evil-2-livestream-shares-new-world-details" rel="nofollow">world</a>, and confirmation that since it had seamless multiplayer elements, the game would <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/beyond-good-and-evil-2-q-reveals-online-connection-required-for-game" rel="nofollow">require an online connection</a> to play.</p>

<p>Since then, however, things have been very quiet on the&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil 2&nbsp;</em>front; original lead Michel Ancel departed not only the project, but video games as a whole <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/beyond-good-and-evil-2-lead-michel-ancel-leaves-video-games" rel="nofollow">back in 2020</a>, although Ubisoft said at the time that he hadn't been "directly involved" with the game for some time upon his departure.</p>




<p>Whether these job listings amount to a new announcement anytime soon remains to be seen, but for now, there's no indication that Ubisoft is even remotely ready to re-re-re-announce&nbsp;<em>Beyond Good and Evil 2</em>. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/beyond-good-and-evil-2-new-job-postings]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EcoFlow Decided Profit Doesn’t Matter, 1800W Power Station Hits New All-Time Low for Winter Backup]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ecoflow-decided-profit-doesnt-matter-1800w-power-station-hits-new-all-time-low-for-winter-backup-2000647635</link>
            <guid>1365715</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Winter power outages strike more frequently than most people realize with ice storms, heavy snow and equipment failures leaving homes without electricity for hours or days at critical moments. Having backup power transforms these emergencies from stressful crises into manageable inconveniences by keeping essential appliances running.</p>
<p>EcoFlow specializes in portable power stations that bridge the gap between small battery banks and expensive whole-home generators and delivers practical backup capacity without professional installation. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5693/">At $349, down from $699, the Delta 2 has hit a record-low price</a> on Amazon for Black Friday while <strong>being EcoFlow’s bestselling model across several years</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5693/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The 1800W Output Powers Real Appliances</h2>
<p>The<strong> constant 1800W AC power with an accompanying surge power of 2700W</strong> enables the operation of genuine household electronics such as full-sized refrigerators, microwave ovens, space heaters, and medical electronics, beyond the capability of smaller power stations. The power offered here almost competes with the power offered by conventional gas-generators whose use has long been hamstrung by the need for gas tanks, the resultant air pollution, and the lack of quiet operation.</p>



<p>In the event of power outage during the cold seasons, the Delta 2 can power a furnace blower motor, light a refrigerator in order to save the food, and recharge mobile and laptop collections all at the same time. The <strong>use of all the available 15 outlets, ranging from the AC, USB-A, USB-C, and DC ports</strong>&nbsp;enables the operation of all the needed electronics.</p>



<p>The <strong>Delta 2 takes only 50 minutes to charge from empty to 80%</strong> and this has changed the way you now prepare in advance when there are forecasts of storms and unexpected power outages. Conventional portable power stations need 6-8 hours to fully recharge, and this means you could be left in the dark when there are forecasts of storm power outages and when the brief periods offered when the power may be restored are not sufficient for recharging.</p>
<p>The lithium-ion battery chemistry, LiFePO4, has an extraordinary lifespan<strong>, boasting 3000+ charge cycles and retention levels over 80% capacity</strong>, estimated at about 10 years. Another advantage the LiFePO4 battery chemistry boasts over other lithium-ion batteries is increased safety. The battery management system constantly monitors voltage, current, and temperatures in all the cells and <strong>protects against overcharge, over-discharge, overcurrent, and short-circuit conditions.</strong></p>
<p>While the EcoFlow Delta 2 normally costs $349, you can get this power solution with 1800W, 50-minute fast charging and long-lasting LiFePO4 battery technology at an unbelievable price this Black Friday.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5693/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ecoflow-decided-profit-doesnt-matter-1800w-power-station-hits-new-all-time-low-for-winter-backup-2000647635]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Charlie Cox Still Isn’t Ready To Take Credit For His Award-Nominated Clair Obscur Performance Because Game Performances Are Complicated]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/charlie-cox-clair-obscur-expedition-33-gustave-game-awards-2000647664</link>
            <guid>1365709</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-rpg-review-in-progress-1851777402"><i><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></i></a> <span>looks primed to </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/game-awards-2025-goty-nominees-categories-clair-obscur-2000644825"><span>take several awards home at The Game Awards next month</span></a><span>. Sandfall Interactive’s turn-based RPG has </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/indie-game-awards-iga-igf-gdc-clair-obscur-expedition-33-2000644070"><span>several nominations across multiple categories</span></a><span>, including the big one: Game of the Year. One category it is most represented in is Best Performance, which features three members of its English voice cast, one of whom has sparked a surprising conversation about how we recognize performances in video games.</span></p> <p><i><span>Daredevil </span></i><span>actor Charlie Cox, the voice behind </span><i><span>Clair Obscur</span></i><span>’s gunslinging false protagonist, admits that he wasn’t as involved in the game as other members of the cast. He spent a few hours in the booth and was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-charlie-cox-gustave-voice-1851784940"><span>surprised to hear just how much people loved his character</span></a><span>. Back in July, he </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/charlie-cox-clair-obscur-expedition-33-gustave-actor-1851786701"><span>admitted he still hadn’t played the game yet, either</span></a><span>. Now that his performance as Gustave has been nominated for an award, Cox seems hesitant to take any of the credit.</span></p>

 <p><span>During a Q&amp;A segment at the La Conve 64 event in Mexico, Cox said that any credit he gets for his voice performance should be given to Gustave’s motion capture actor.</span></p> <p><span>“I’m thrilled for this nomination,” Cox said. “I’ve said this before, and I think it’s important to say, there’s an amazing French actor by the name of Maxence Cazorla who did almost all of the motion capture for that role in that game. So any nomination or any credit I get, I really have to give to him because I kind of believe that the performance of that character is really down to him, and my voice is just part of that process.”</span></p>

   <p><span>Cazoria has since responded to Cox’s sentiment on his </span><a href="https://x.com/maxence_cazorla/status/1993339680608465405?s=20"><span>X account</span></a><span>, saying that the actor’s words were appreciated, but bringing Gustave to life was a team effort.</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thank you for all the messages these past few days.<br>Charlie’s words were incredibly generous, and I’m truly grateful 🙏<br>Bringing Gustave to life was a team effort, and I’m honored to have played my part in it.<br>Thank you all so much for the love and support 🌹🤍<br>Tomorrow comes ✨</p> <p>— Maxence Cazorla (@maxence_cazorla) <a href="https://twitter.com/maxence_cazorla/status/1993339680608465405?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 25, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>Notably, Cazoria was also the motion capture for Renoir and Verso. Ben Starr, who provided the English dub for Verso, is also nominated in the Best Performance category, as well as Jennifer English for her role as Maelle. Cazoria may not be the name many English-speaking players associate with these characters, but as Cox points out, the motion capture artists deserve credit for helping bring these characters to life.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Is there a future where The Game Awards recognizes motion capture actors separately from voice actors? Some industry professionals, like </span><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3 </span></i><span>performance director Aliona Baranova, sure hope so.</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">yup, i think we should have a motion capture category at awards shows <a href="https://t.co/6vYaLwXU7X">https://t.co/6vYaLwXU7X</a></p> <p>— Aliona Baranova (@alionabaranova1) <a href="https://twitter.com/alionabaranova1/status/1993588077508673841?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 26, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>I would be surprised if The Game Awards bothers to make that distinction. The show already has a propensity to imperfectly lump categories together, such as discontinuing the Best Shooter category to put those games in the Best Action Game pile. But maybe as the industry becomes more aware of how many moving parts make up a whole character like Gustave, award shows will find ways to recognize everyone involved, rather than just the person behind the voice.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/charlie-cox-clair-obscur-expedition-33-gustave-game-awards-2000647664]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 10 Best Kirby Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-kirby-games</link>
            <guid>1365706</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Kirby has been so many different things since he first floated into our lives in 1992. Besides his dozens of transforming copy abilities, he’s been split into four differently-colored Kirbys, turned into yarn, warped into a ball we controlled on the DS touch screen, and so much more. And now that he’s hopped back on the Warp Star with the release of Kirby Air Riders on Nintendo Switch 2, we thought it was the perfect time to look back at the history of the pink puffball. Here are IGN’s top ten Kirby games of all time.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">10. Kirby and the Amazing Mirror</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/26/kirby-and-the-amazing-mirror-1764139672803.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Two iconic Nintendo heroes were split into four different versions of themselves on the Game Boy Advance: Link in The Legend of Zelda: Four Swords and Kirby in Kirby and the Amazing Mirror. The latter is a 2004 GBA platformer that took advantage of the system’s link cable functionality to allow four players to adventure together, calling each other on a cellphone to regroup if they ever got split up. Just make sure the batteries don’t run out! And even if you played Amazing Mirror on your own, it stands out thanks to its lite Metroidvania setup. Rather than adventure through linear levels like pretty much every other Kirby platformer, Amazing Mirror’s branching paths let players explore levels in different orders at their own pace. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">9. Kirby’s Dream Land 2</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/26/kirbys-dream-land-2-1764139873589.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Before becoming an industry celebrity thanks to the Super Smash Bros. series, Masahiro Sakurai directed the humble Kirby’s Dream Land on Game Boy. Back in those days, Kirby was white instead of pink (at least on the North American box art), and he didn’t have copy abilities! But the 1995 Game Boy sequel, Kirby’s Dream Land 2, improved on everything the first game set up, bringing Kirby Adventure’s copy abilities into the fold, and introducing the iconic rideable animal friends like Rick the hamster. It’s a classic example of a bigger, better sequel, and our pick for the best game in Kirby’s original Dream Land trilogy, even though we really love the pastel art style of Dream Land 3 on Super Nintendo.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">8. Kirby: Triple Deluxe</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/26/kirby-triple-deluxe-1764139983972.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Kirby’s debut outing on 3DS took full advantage of the handheld’s screen, as Kirby: Triple Deluxe (a wordier way to say Kirby: 3D) sees Kirby platforming in the foreground and background in very unique ways. Its main hook is the Hypernova ability, which makes Kirby suck harder than he’s ever sucked before, essentially turning his stomach into a black hole. This is used in all sorts of clever puzzles, including one level where Kirby eats an entire train like it’s a light snack. It also introduced one of my favorite subgames in the series: Dedede’s Drum Dash, a rhythm game where Kirby’s best frenemy bounces to the beat in stages set to familiar Kirby tunes.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">7. Kirby: Nightmare in Dreamland</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/26/kirby-nightmare-in-dreamland-1764140118083.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Kirby’s Adventure is an important entry in the franchise, as it’s responsible for introducing copy abilities. And it wasn’t just two or three; Adventure came out swinging with more than 20 different powers for Kirby to steal from enemies, setting the blueprint for every Kirby game to come. It also established both minigames and Kirby’s longtime rival, Meta Knight, as staples for the series. This NES classic got remade as Kirby: Nightmare in Dream Land on the GBA in 2002, which we’re picking as the definitive version because of its improved controls and additional content it brought with it, like the bonus Meta Knightmare mode, where you can play the whole campaign as Meta Knight — another new wrinkle that would become commonplace in future Kirby games,. But shoutout to the NES Kirby’s Adventure cover, where Kirby is literally eating the box art and revealing the endless void that lies underneath.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">6. Kirby’s Epic Yarn</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/26/kirbys-epic-yarn-1764140224078.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Kirby’s Epic Yarn is probably the easiest game on this list – which is saying a lot, given the general approachability of almost all of the Kirby series – but it’s also one of the most charming. Developed by Good-Feel instead of series steward HAL Laboratory, Kirby’s Epic Yarn transforms the pink sphere into, you guessed it, yarn, completely changing the aesthetic and overall gameplay. There aren’t traditional copy abilities – instead, this Kirby simply morphs himself into a yarn submarine, car, or parachute as he travels with the adorable Prince Fluff through an arts and crafts-themed world. It’s relaxing, beautiful, and fits in right alongside the best Kirby games despite being so different.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">5. Kirby Air Riders</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/13/kirbythumbono-1763069064246.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Kirby Air Riders is only a few days old, but it’s already one of the all-time franchise greats. After more than two decades away, Masahiro Sakurai returned to the franchise he created to take another crack at Kirby Air Ride, which was a fun but somewhat underbaked experiment back on the GameCube. And Sakurai didn’t let any part of this second chance go to waste, creating a definitive sequel that feels like the ultimate realization of its simplistic one-button racing formula. Air Riders is packed with modes, unlockables, and tons of little details that show how much love and attention went into its development. The racing is frantic and fun, but the star of the show is still City Trial; the battle mode / collectathon hybrid that’s a wonderful throwback to local multiplayer modes from the N64 and GameCube days. Its unconventional controls aren’t going to be for everyone, but if you go along for the ride, you’ll find a fantastic Kirby game that’s brilliantly unique.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">4. Kirby’s Return to Dreamland Deluxe</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/26/kirbys-return-to-dreamland-deluxe-1764140399062.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Return to Dreamland on Wii was the first traditional home console Kirby platformer since Kirby 64: The Crystal Shards (which we love but narrowly missed out on our top 10). It delivered the classic Kirby adventuring fans were craving, but introduced fun new copy abilities like Leaf and Water, had multiple well-hidden collectibles to track down in each level, tasked players with mastering every copy ability in its challenge rooms, and a lot more. Most importantly, it’s a blast in local multiplayer, allowing up to four friends to play the entire campaign together as either Kirby, King Dedede, Meta Knight, or Bandana Waddle Dee. Return to Dreamland got a fantastic deluxe treatment on Nintendo Switch, adding a bonus epilogue and a ton of returning subgames from across the series, complete with dozens of achievements to chase, so we’ve gone with that version here.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">3. Kirby Super Star Ultra</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/26/kirby-super-star-ultra-1764140526170.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Sakurai is known for stuffing his games full of side modes that all build around the same gameplay foundations, and that tradition started in Kirby Super Star, the Super Nintendo classic that hosted a small handful of bite-sized adventures to run through. These were repackaged and expanded upon in the excellent DS remake, Super Star Ultra, which brought everything back and added even more, continuing the tradition of a Meta Knight campaign established in Nightmare in Dreamland. Super Star’s biggest strength, though, is its sheer variety: collecting every last treasure in The Great Cave Offensive, racing to eat more treats than Dedede in Gourmet Race, or infiltrating the Halberd as terrified crewmates discuss the best way to stop Kirby. Every mode offers its own flavor, and it all comes together to create the strongest game of Kirby’s early days.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">2. Kirby and the Forgotten Land</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/26/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-1764140743065.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Every game series takes a different approach when transitioning from 2D to 3D, and fittingly for this franchise, Kirby kept things delightfully simple by keeping its formula largely intact as it made the jump. Kirby and the Forgotten Land is a fantastic realization of classic Kirby platforming in a 3D space. Kirby hops, floats, and dodges just like you’d think he would, and the upgradeable copy abilities work seamlessly. Its most memorable new addition is Mouthful Mode, which lets Kirby wrap his enormous mouth around a car, staircase, or even a vending machine, making for fun puzzle platforming that proves this isn’t just a retread of Kirby’s greatest hits. The Forgotten Land also takes some inspiration from the 3D platforming greats, such as Super Mario and Banjo-Kazooie, by sprinkling hidden collectibles and secret objectives across every level, and it’s a joy for completionists to hunt down every last Waddle Dee to send back to town. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">1. Kirby Planet Robobot</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/26/kirby-planet-robobot-1764140874873.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The best Kirby game of them all is Kirby: Planet Robobot, an unassuming sequel to Triple Deluxe on 3DS that turned out to be his finest adventure. That’s largely thanks to the Robobot armor, a hulking mech suit Kirby pilots across the campaign, complete with its own unique copy abilities. While Triple Deluxe’s Hypernova and Return to Dreamland’s Super abilities felt more like gimmicks relegated to setpiece moments, the Robobot armor is seamlessly integrated into the stages, leading to fantastic puzzles with the most depth, variety, and challenge in the series, especially if you’re trying to collect everything. Robobot expands upon Triple Deluxe’s foreground and background platforming and features some of the coolest settings in the series, as a mechanized Planet Popstar is just a great idea that ties each world together. Robobot is an absolute treat, and we can only hope that Nintendo rereleases it on Switch or Switch 2 sometime soon so more people can experience the best Kirby game of them all.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There you have it – IGN’s top ten Kirby games of all time. Would you inhale this list, or spit it out? Are we leaving off your favorite? Drop a comment and let us know. For more Kirby, check out our review of Kirby Air Riders, or our Nintendo Voice Chat podcast that posts new episodes every Friday on the IGN Games YouTube channel and your favorite podcast app. And for everything else Nintendo, stick with IGN.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Logan Plant is the host of Nintendo Voice Chat and IGN's Database Manager &amp; Playlist Editor. The Legend of Zelda is his favorite video game franchise of all time, and he is patiently awaiting the day Nintendo announces a brand new F-Zero. You can find him online @LoganJPlant.</em>
</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-kirby-games]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>