<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:44:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kojima "happy" with Death Stranding 2 critical reception, spurring fans to "fight and battle" against war and climate change]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/kojima-happy-with-death-stranding-2-critical-reception-spurring-fans-to-fight-and-battle-against-war-and-climate-change</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kojima-happy-with-death-stranding-2-critical-reception-spurring-fans-to-fight-and-battle-against-war-and-climate-change.1232583/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Caroline Polachek and Chvrches performed at London World Tour event.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Kojima Production / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/hideo-kojima">Hideo Kojima</a> is "happy" with the critical reception of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/death-stranding-2">Death Stranding 2</a>: On The Beach, and has spurred on fans to fight back against war and climate change.</p>
<p>Speaking at the London leg of the Death Stranding 2 World Tour that Eurogamer attended, Kojima was asked by host <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/geoff-keighley">Geoff Keighley</a> for his final thoughts on the evening's events, which included performances from Caroline Polachek and Chvrches.</p>
<p>"We have a lot of things right now," said Kojima. "We have war, we have climate change, we have a lot of earthquakes, we had the pandemic, we have a lot of things. And we have maybe a dark future a little bit. But today, if we gather like this and if we are going to be connected, we can fight and battle all these things."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Death Stranding 2: On the Beach Review" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PDgRQ9ZCRmE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach Review</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PDgRQ9ZCRmE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PDgRQ9ZCRmE?autoplay=1" title="Death Stranding 2: On the Beach Review">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach Review<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PDgRQ9ZCRmE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Kojima dedicated the evening - also attended by actors Norman Reedus and Léa Seydoux - to the memory of Low Roar lead singer Ryan Karazija, who passed away in 2022 due to complications of pneumonia. Low Roar's music was a key part of the first game's identity and Kojima had wanted to use more of the band's music in the sequel.</p>
<p>"When I was creating Death Stranding 2, I wanted to contact him and there was Covid so he couldn't come to Japan to perform so I was trying to write an email," explained Kojima. "But then I got this sad message that Ryan passed away and that was so tragic when I first heard that. I also heard from his relatives that he does have some new songs and I decided to put in his new songs in Death Stranding 2.</p>
<p>"So I think he's watching us somewhere. In Death Stranding 2 there's this line 'death is not the end, it does not separate us'. I still feel connection with Ryan so I'm going to cherish this relationship with Ryan. And I hope everyone will feel that way too."</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Singer Caroline Polachek, meanwhile, performed the game's title song On The Beach for the first time at the event.</p>
<p>"I am always terrified the first time I perform songs, but I've gotta say I've never sung a song that feels more like playing a video game than that song," she said. "It has so many rollercoaster dips in it."</p>
<p>Kojima was introduced to Polachek's music by the team at KindaFunny, which eventually led to the pair collaborating on the song. "If I hadn't received that CD, this connection would never have happened," said Kojima.</p>
<p>Polachek explained more about the writing process for On The Beach. "I often keep special songs in a treasure chest for when they have the right moment, and this was one of them," she said.</p>
<p>"Hideo explained to me the concept of Death Stranding 2 and I was so taken by the ethical conflict in the story and also how far that carries back into Death Stranding 1 as well. This idea of: is extinction a good idea, is it a bad idea? And how provocative that is, actually. One of the things that's special about this song is the verses are really evil and looming and then the chorus is so innocent and has this feeling of being saved. And I really liked the match between the song and these ideas. He sends me a synopsis of the game and I take it away and study it. And about a month later we had the song."</p>
<p>The lyrics to On The Beach are a riddle, though the singer didn't want to give it away. "In this case I wanted to pick up the gauntlet that Hideo threw down, which is how many strands of the game can you put into the song but in a way people won't necessarily be able to read until they've played it," she said.</p>
<p>Polachek also admitted she was "so nervous" to send Kojima her first recording of the song, and Chvrches later mirrored this sentiment after their performance of the title track from the first game. This was the first performance from Chvrches in two years, with the band confirming they've been back in the studio for six months writing a new album.</p>
<p>In a previous interview, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hideo-kojima-isnt-interested-in-appealing-to-the-mass-market-but-death-stranding-2-playtests-proving-popular">Kojima stated he's not interested in "appealing to the mass market"</a> and, despite playtests of Death Stranding 2 proving popular, he wished it "was a bit more controversial".</p>
<p>The reaction would suggest otherwise. While sales figures haven't been released, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/death-stranding-2-topples-mario-kart-world-from-uk-physical-sales-top-spot-but-still-some-way-from-beating-the-original">Death Stranding 2 did top the UK physical charts last week</a>. And with such a strong critical reaction, it's no wonder Kojima is feeling "very happy".</p>
<p>"A busier, louder, and more emotionally resplendent take on this singular hiking sim," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-review">Death Stranding 2 review</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/kojima-happy-with-death-stranding-2-critical-reception-spurring-fans-to-fight-and-battle-against-war-and-climate-change]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals: Get 5% Off Nintendo eShop Credit & Switch 2 Games In Our Summer Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/deals-get-5percent-off-nintendo-eshop-credit-and-switch-2-games-in-our-summer-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deals-get-5-off-nintendo-eshop-credit-switch-2-games-in-our-summer-sale.1232580/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Discounted eShop credit, subs, and games</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Nintendo Life Summer Sale" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/271ebee4e17ab/nintendo-life-summer-sale.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Summer has arrived in the northern hemisphere, and what better way to enjoy it than sitting in the shade with a glass of something cool — possibly with a novelty straw sticking out the top — and relaxing with a Switch?</p>
<p>Whether you're still rocking the OG Switch or you've got your hands on the new hotness with Switch 2, there's plenty to play over the warmer months, and we've got a discount on Switch eShop credit which might pique your interest, too.</p>
<p>You can get 5% off Nintendo eShop credit and digital games through <a href="https://codes.nintendolife.com/">our code store</a> until 14th July. Depending on your region, that 5% discount is available on eShop credit, Switch Online subscriptions, and lots of top digital Switch (2) games.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067slinom&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>825k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>This means you can save even more on Nintendo's official discounts, as there's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/97-games-you-should-pick-up-in-nintendos-switch-eshop-summer-sale-north-america">a Switch eShop summer sale</a> running in North America until 10th July. So you can grab some discounted credit from us, then spend it on those sale games for double savings. Every little helps!</p>
<p>You can browse all of our deals below – just use code <strong>NINTENDOLIFE5</strong> at checkout to get your 5% off. If you're visiting the store from a European country other than the UK, we'd recommend heading directly to <a href="https://codes.nintendolife.com/">our store's homepage</a>. And if you're in the southern hemisphere? Well, what better time than winter to curl up inside with some video games? Everyone's a winner!</p>
<nav><ul><li><span title="On This Page"></span></li></ul>
</nav>
<p>Please note that some external links on this page are affiliate links, which means if you click them and make a purchase we may receive a small percentage of the sale. Please read our <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/advertising">FTC Disclosure</a> for more information.</p>
<h2 id="nintendo-life-deals-us-andamp-canada">Nintendo Life Deals - US &amp; Canada</h2>
<p>Our US store includes eShop credit and games (no subscriptions), while Canada gets the lot. Reminder: Get 5% off your chosen amount below using code <strong>NINTENDOLIFE5</strong>. And remember that you can stock up on several discounted codes at a time if you want to add plenty of reduced credit to your eShop account.</p>
<p>Please note that some of these games may be currently available at better prices in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/97-games-you-should-pick-up-in-nintendos-switch-eshop-summer-sale-north-america">Nintendo's own Summer sale</a>.</p>
<h3 id="eshop-credit">eShop Credit</h3>
<h4 id="us">US</h4>


<h4 id="canada">Canada</h4>


<h3 id="switch-online-subscriptions">Switch Online Subscriptions</h3>
<h4 id="canada-2">Canada</h4>


<h2 id="nintendo-life-deals-ukeurope">Nintendo Life Deals - UK/Europe</h2>
<p>And here's the UK selection! Remember to use code <strong>NINTENDOLIFE5</strong> once you've added everything to your basket!</p>
<p>If you're visiting from a European country other than the UK, <a href="https://codes.nintendolife.com/">click here to go directly to the store</a>!</p>
<h3 id="eshop-credit-2">eShop Credit</h3>


<h3 id="switch-online-subscriptions-2">Switch Online Subscriptions</h3>


<h3 id="switch-2-games">Switch 2 Games</h3>
<p>First up, the Switch 2 games! The code NINTENDOLIFE5 will get you 5% off the usual eShop price for all games and Upgrade Packs listed below.</p>


<h3 id="switch-games">Switch Games</h3>
<p>And now the Switch 1 selection. Remember, Switch 2 is backwards compatible with the vast majority of original Switch games, so you'll be able to play all of these on NS2.</p>


<h3 id="dlc">DLC</h3>


<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:128963,174635 @ 1751367606 -->
<p>If you decide to treat yourself to any of the discounts above, we hope you enjoy and thank you for supporting the site.</p></section></article><div><p>Growing up with a ZX Spectrum and a Sega Master System and his exhaustive knowledge in the fields of SEO and digital marketing, Darren's organisational prowess helps steer Hookshot's portfolio in the right direction.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Dazza"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Dazza');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/deals-get-5percent-off-nintendo-eshop-credit-and-switch-2-games-in-our-summer-sale]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam’s updated PC performance monitor is quietly clever, and not just because it digs into frame generation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steams-updated-pc-performance-monitor-is-quietly-clever-and-not-just-because-it-digs-into-frame-generation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam%E2%80%99s-updated-pc-performance-monitor-is-quietly-clever-and-not-just-because-it-digs-into-frame-generation.1232577/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Valve</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The latest <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/steam">Steam</a> update includes a new, heavily upgraded performance monitor, stacking readouts for framerate, CPU, GPU, and memory usage data on top of the previously basic FPS overlay. It’s "a first step," <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/500576552635859540">so say Valve</a>, "towards helping Steam users more easily understand their game and system performance," and as such includes some counters and metrics that you won’t see even on game-math classics like MSI Afterburner.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The most straightforward of these is the option to separate framerate counts by both traditionally rendered frames and any extras that might be served up by frame generation tech such as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nvidia-dlss-4-explained">DLSS 4</a> or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-fsr-3-demystified-how-the-next-gen-upscaler-could-upgrade-performance-on-any-gpu">FSR 3</a>. Existing hardware monitors can usually measure either the raw, un-generated frame count or the combined total, but to my knowledge, Steam’s the first to keep track of both separately – allowing you to see precisely how much of that on-screen smoothness is down to 'real' frames versus the generated ones. Handy stuff.</p>
<p>This new overlay (which, by the way, can be customised to show varying degrees of details, similar to the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-games">Steam Deck</a>/SteamOS performance monitor) offers some other convention-breaking counters too. The CPU usage monitor is one: in addition to a standard, percentage-based figure showing average CPU core usage, it can also display a second percentage that denotes the current busiest core, specifically how much it’s working relative to its base clock speed. Hence why it sometimes reads above 100% - that’s when the core is running at its higher 'boost' clock speed, to get more done when thermal headroom allows it to.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>Idris approves. | <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Valve/CD Projekt Red</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This is useful info, not because anyone secretly wants to sit an arithmetic exam when they sit down to play games, but because average core usage doesn’t give the full picture when a game perhaps isn’t taking advantage of CPU cores like it should. Showing, in real time, that the busiest core is in fact working its little silicon arse off could help diagnose performance problems that may not otherwise have a clear cause.</p>
<p>There’s a similar troubleshooting benefit to how the Steam monitor counts VRAM availability, which takes into account the amount of system RAM that temporarily holds graphics data. Some monitors, and the VRAM counters you often see in graphics settings menus, only consider the GPU’s own memory alone, so if the Steam overlay says you’re maxing out your supply, you can be more sure that you really have squeezed out every last gigabyte of possible memory. That’s my understanding, anyway. I’m still just a humanities graduate, and this thing makes an awful lot of numbers.</p>
<p>Having played around with the monitor myself, I have noticed one bug, which you can see for yourself in that header screenshot: the generated frames counter sometimes doesn’t show in full, so what should be a count of three-hundred-and-something frames looks like 30. I sort-of fixed this by switching DLSS Multi Frame Generation from 4x to 2x and back again, but hopefully a more permanent amendment is due. Already, though, this is another mostly-great feature that Steam has almost nonchalantly slotted into itself. A repeat of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-record-game-clips-with-steam">Game Recording</a> launch, but for helping when things break, rather than showing off.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steams-updated-pc-performance-monitor-is-quietly-clever-and-not-just-because-it-digs-into-frame-generation]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4's New Planet Features One Huge Improvement Over Borderlands 3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4s-new-planet-features-one-huge-improvement-over-borderlands-3/1100-6532862/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4s-new-planet-features-one-huge-improvement-over-borderlands-3.1232571/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532862">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It's been nearly six years since <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/borderlands-3-review-six-sirens-one-god-queen/1900-6417293/" data-ref-id="1900-6417293">Borderlands 3</a> debuted during the previous console generation. This fall, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6529507/" data-ref-id="1100-6529507">Borderlands 4</a> is taking advantage of the power of the current consoles by thrusting players into a large "seamless world" that doesn't need many loading screens during the long hours it will take to explore it all. That's a major improvement over Borderlands 3's Pandora, which had enough loading screens to test the players' patience. </p><p>While speaking with <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/preview/2025/06/30/the-seamless-open-world-of-borderlands-4" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Game Informer</a>, senior project producer Anthony Nicholson noted that the Borderlands 4 team didn't initially set out to make Kairos an open-world environment. However, the power of Unreal Engine 5 "gave us other advantages to be able to do things and kind of went into being able to make a seamless world and things of that nature."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1371458371" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466145,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Borderlands%204%20-%20Official%20Story%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:127,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/borderlands-4-official-story-trailer\/2300-6466145\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466145\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466145\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466145\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466145&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466145,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6532862&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;borderlands-4&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,first-person,shooter&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc,nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;2k-games,take-two-interactive&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;borderlands&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;borderlands&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466145},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466145\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4519082-22.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/j0EtbPbu.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1750684860,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="j0EtbPbu" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Borderlands 4 - Official Story Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>World-building director Jason Reiss added that there are "a lot more 360 combat areas where players can enter into spaces from any direction, including from the air--and we have to account for that now with all these crazy movement abilities. It's been all about, 'Let's create a large, dynamic, awesome place where players can feel like badasses.'"</p><p>In this expanded world, enemies can be spotted from further away, and they aren't just waiting around to fight players. Instead, an effort was made to make the enemies "be alive and doing things from... far away, where they need to look like they're naturally a part of their environment whenever you're looking at them through your scope from a mile away," said lead game designer Josh Jeffcoat.</p><p>One of the side missions will involve players helping Claptrap recover some of his mementos from previous adventures, while others will vary between story-based missions to specific activities related to Kairos' various regions.</p><p>Gearbox recently debuted <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-borderlands-4-story-trailer-shows-off-the-sinister-timekeeper-and-claptrap/1100-6532590/">a new story trailer</a> that put the spotlight on the game's villain, the Timekeeper. The Borderlands 4 team also revealed that there are<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-has-more-skills-per-character-than-the-last-two-main-games-combined/1100-6532628/" data-ref-id="1100-6532628"> more skills per-character</a> than the last two main games combined. In part because of the sheer amount of new content in the game, Gearbox boss Randy Pitchford has warned that it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dont-expect-borderlands-4-to-hit-game-pass-or-be-dirt-cheap-for-many-years/1100-6532782/" data-ref-id="1100-6532782">may be several years before Borderlands 4 has a significant drop in price</a>.</p><p>Borderlands 4 will hit PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC on September 12. It will also be released on Switch 2 at a later date.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4s-new-planet-features-one-huge-improvement-over-borderlands-3/1100-6532862/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Key Fairy is a "hand-drawn, pacifist, folkloric bullet-hell",  and its demo actually lives up to how interesting that description is]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/key-fairy-is-a-hand-drawn-pacifist-folkloric-bullet-hell-and-its-demo-actually-lives-up-to-how-interesting-that-description-is</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/key-fairy-is-a-hand-drawn-pacifist-folkloric-bullet-hell-and-its-demo-actually-lives-up-to-how-interesting-that-description-is.1232568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>The eels of creation awaken</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Owl Machine</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>To overcome the first enemy you meet in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/key-fairy">Key Fairy</a> (a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bugles_(snack)">Bugle</a> with big eyes and bat wings), you zip around the woods with a grapple, avoiding its circling and collecting the stars it dispenses. When you collect three, it turns friendly and apologises for attacking you. "Worry not, little bird", I reply from a set of dialogue options. "My cloak is thick." The next screen is inhabited by three cyclopean worms chanting about the "eels of creation". I like it here very much.</p>
<p>Brought to life with spacious, enchanting and playfully layered electronic music and hand-drawn art  (you can change the colour palette to something cooler or monochrome if you wish), Key Fairy's forest is a place I want to live, and I'm very grateful for even a short opportunity to spend time in it.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Key Fairy - Official Demo Trailer | Frosty Games Fest 2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JCGbzhOJ3a0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Key Fairy - Official Demo Trailer | Frosty Games Fest 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JCGbzhOJ3a0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JCGbzhOJ3a0?autoplay=1" title="Key Fairy - Official Demo Trailer | Frosty Games Fest 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JCGbzhOJ3a0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>You'll find the demo on Key Fairy's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2878580/Key_Fairy/">Steam page</a>, which also has one of the loveliest descriptions of making things I've read in a while:</p>
<blockquote><p>"An adventure made just for you! We forged this forest out of blood, and ink, and thought. Come, join us for a while, we are only small, and there is space enough to share."</p></blockquote>
<p>"The Forest Contains…"</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Dozens of unique monsters</li>
<li>Fast paced, frenetic engagements</li>
<li>Trinkets by the bagful, for you to collect</li>
<li>Whimsy</li>
<li>hundreds of hand-crafted rooms</li>
<li>People, with hopes and dreams</li>
<li>Sounds (if you walk softly, you may hear them)</li>
<li>The truth</li>
<li>An ungodly quantity of keys</li>
<li>Pages and pages of hand-drawn art</li>
<li>A sword! (not to be used as a weapon)</li>
<li>No secrets. we promise there are no secrets in the forest...</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>The full game's release is still to be announced. Do visit the forest if you get a chance. It's a marvellous place.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/key-fairy-is-a-hand-drawn-pacifist-folkloric-bullet-hell-and-its-demo-actually-lives-up-to-how-interesting-that-description-is]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Ghost Recon Game Will Shortly Move Into Internal Alpha Testing, Says New Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/new-ghost-recon-game-will-shortly-move-into-internal-alpha-testing-says-new-report</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-ghost-recon-game-will-shortly-move-into-internal-alpha-testing-says-new-report.1232565/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Could be out 2026.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The next mainline <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tom-clancys-ghost-recon-breakpoint"><u>Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon</u></a> game is moving into internal alpha testing in the coming months.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That's according to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-recon-mainline-alpha/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Insider Gaming</u></a>, which claimed the shooter, codenamed 'Over' internally, will commence alpha testing in the Fall (Q3). With testing thought to take around 12 months, IG estimated Ghost Recon may release Fall 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">News of a new Ghost Recon broke around the time the developer/publisher confirmed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-recon-breakpoint-final-support"><u>it was ceasing all new development on 2019's Ghost Recon Breakpoint</u></a>. It has reportedly been in development at Ubisoft <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-recon-sequel-reportedly-in-development"><u>since then</u></a>, although at the time, it was clear the series was undergoing a full reset, which would necessitate a lengthy development cycle. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a statement to IGN, an Ubisoft representative said: "We do not comment on rumour or speculation."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tom-clancys-ghost-recon-breakpoint-review"><u>IGN's Ghost Recon Breakpoint review returned a 6/10</u></a>. We wrote: "Breakpoint offers initial fun following Ubisoft's open-world structure as gospel, but a lack of variety and conflicting pieces leave it devoid of personality."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/embattled-ubisoft-forms-subsidiary-for-ips-like-assassins-creed-far-cry-and-rainbow-six-with-the-help-of-116-billion-tencent-investment"><u>Ubisoft created a subsidiary company based on its Assassin’s Creed, Far Cry, and Tom Clancy’s Rainbow Six brands, with a €1.16 billion (approx. $1.25 billion) investment from Chinese megacorp Tencent</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The news came hot on the heels of the launch of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows"><u>Assassin's Creed Shadows</u></a>, which <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-now-up-to-3-million-players-but-still-no-sales-figure-from-ubisoft"><u>just passed the 3 million player mark</u></a>. Ubisoft suffered a number of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-admits-star-wars-outlaws-underperformed"><u>high-profile flops</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-cuts-45-jobs-in-its-us-offices"><u>layoffs</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-is-discontinuing-xdefiant-in-2025-new-purchases-disabled"><u>studio closures</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-says-delays-cancellations-were-because-it-was-making-too-many-games-at-once"><u>game cancellations</u></a> in the run up to Assassin's Creed Shadows' release, and there was enormous pressure on it to succeed after the company's share price hit an historic low.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In 2022, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-has-officially-stopped-development-on-ghost-recon-frontline">Ubisoft canceled development on Ghost Recon Frontline</a> a year after it was announced. It was meant to be a free-to-play battle royale spin-off with 102-players, but never saw the light of day.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/new-ghost-recon-game-will-shortly-move-into-internal-alpha-testing-says-new-report]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Street Fighter 6 collab with K-pop group Aespa announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/01/street-fighter-6-collab-with-k-pop-group-aespa-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/street-fighter-6-collab-with-k-pop-group-aespa-announced.1232550/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Capcom has announced that is doing a collaboration with K-pop group Aespa, along with virtual idol Naevis. The collaboration with Aespa will consist of a new outfit for Juri which will release on July 4th. This outfit will be only be available for a limited time, with that timeframe being a year. After that it will be gone. You can see the the outfit and hear some of Aespa’s Whiplash track in the trailer below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Street Fighter 6 x aespa Special Collab with naevis Announce Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NNXmO0LLsjQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Naevis is a virtual idol that began as a sidekick for the group Aespa, before being spun off to be a solo artist. Naevis’ has been confirmed as a real time commentator. It is worth mentioning that being a virtual idol means that Naevis is not a real person, and has been created using generative AI. The option to use Naevis as a real time commentator in Street Fighter 6 will also be available from July 4th.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/05/30/street-fighter-6-review/">Street Fighter 6 Review</a></h2>
<p>In our Street Fighter 6 review, Nick said, “Street Fighter 6 doesn’t need recommending to hardcore fighting fans – you all already know how incredible it is – but do I recommend it for more casual players? Street Fighter 6 has a real sense of community, welcoming all players old and new, teaching new tricks and providing something for those that just want a bit of fun. This is truly a fighting game for everyone.”</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NNXmO0LLsjQ">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/01/street-fighter-6-collab-with-k-pop-group-aespa-announced/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Devs to Host Performance Talk Amid Ongoing Efforts to Improve Stability]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-devs-talk-optimization/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-devs-to-host-performance-talk-amid-ongoing-efforts-to-improve-stability.1232547/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>To everyone's surprise, members of the Monster Hunter Wilds development team will give a talk on performance optimization later this month while the game continues to be affected by all sorts of technical issues.</p>



<p>As confirmed on the <a href="https://cedec.cesa.or.jp/2025/timetable/detail/s67ad32469773b/">CEDEC 2025 official website</a>, programmer Yuichi Ito and AI Engineer Takanori Nakamura will host a talk on July 24 during this year's edition of Japan's largest annual conference for game developers regarding the challenges of optimizing the latest entry in the series and how the team reportedly managed to <em>"maintain stable operation"</em> while realizing the game's core features, a statement many will inevitably find funny, at the very least, considering how the game doesn't run well on anything other than the very top end PC hardware and with upscaling and frame generation on top.</p>



<p>A few months since launch, Monster Hunter Wilds' performance is just as disappointing as it was back in February. <a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-2-nvidia-dlss-4-amd-fsr-4/">Title Update 2</a>, which went live yesterday, introduced some VRAM utilization improvements but has not addressed the many issues the game still has on this front. The new update also introduced some stability issues that are causing crashes on a variety of system configurations, but these, at least, will be addressed soon with a new 1.020.01.00 patch announced today. The patch will also address another issue in the PC version of the game that may cause unstable performance when equipping ranged weapons.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Monster Hunter Wilds is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S. You can learn how the game still manages to be a great new entry in the series despite the performance issues by checking out my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/monster-hunter-wilds-peak-hunting/">review</a>.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-devs-talk-optimization/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Fallout 4 quest mod has you investigating alien abductions for an iconic Elder Scrolls voice actor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-fallout-4-quest-mod-has-you-investigating-alien-abductions-for-an-iconic-elder-scrolls-voice-actor</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-fallout-4-quest-mod-has-you-investigating-alien-abductions-for-an-iconic-elder-scrolls-voice-actor.1232544/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Its creation has raised over $5,000 for the US Alzheimer's Association</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Kinggath</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A new <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-4">Fallout 4</a> mod put together over the course of a 40 hour-long charity modathon will see you beamed up by aliens you're investigating on behalf of a quirky conspiracy theorist. Its creation alone has <a href="https://donate.tiltify.com/9bfd5162-8a13-4012-908f-e64b4598976d/details">raised over $5,800</a> (about £4.2k) for the American <a href="https://www.alz.org/">Alzheimer's Association</a> so far.</p>
<p>We <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-elder-scrolls-voice-actor-is-teaming-up-with-top-fallout-4-modders-to-livestream-a-48-hour-modding-jam-for-charity">wrote about the plans to livestream this mod's creation</a> last month. The team behind Fallout 4's popular <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/21872">Sim Settlements mod</a> are behind it, having teamed up with Wes 'Sheogorath' Johnson, a number of other voice actors and a group of prominent Fallout modders to make a cool thing with a bunch of moving parts in one weekend.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Their creation, <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/fallout4/mods/94745?tab=description">Transmission Zeta</a>, is now available to download via Nexus Mods. It looks like a fun time, though you might not dig the questline it offers if you're not down for plenty of silliness and Fallouty meta humour.</p>
<p>In line with what viewers voted for during a <a href="https://x.com/simsettlements/status/1932626360859820127">June 14th planning stream</a>, that questline is all about aliens. The Zetans from the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-3">Fallout 3</a> Mothership Zeta DLC have returned to The Commonwealth to get up to some abduction antics, along with various other cameos from across the Fallout series. You'll investigate with the aid of Clark, a zany conspiracy theorist voiced by Johnson, and the mod's fully-voiced follower, a vault dwelling con artist called Arlen.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>The 40 hour Modathon is over, and you raised just shy of 10k across our events - and there's still one more to go!</p><p>Amazing work from all the modders who poured themselves into this!</p><p>Join <a href="https://twitter.com/GopherGaming?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GopherGaming</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/WesJohnsonVoice?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WesJohnsonVoice</a> tomorrow to watch the reveal of what we've assembled! <a href="https://t.co/c7CsW4Xb63">pic.twitter.com/c7CsW4Xb63</a></p></div>— simsettlements (@simsettlements) <a href="https://twitter.com/simsettlements/status/1939538383539417571?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 30, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>As you play through the quests and explore a new dungeon, one of which is called "V.A.T.S in Spaaace!", you'll gain some custom alien-themed weapons and armour made by modders Neeher and Niero. There's also a player home in the form of a houseboat with its own robot butler that modder Elianora's cooked up.</p>
<p>In order to start the mod's questline once it's installed, the modders write that you'll need to "simply pass through any load screen by fast traveling or entering and exiting a building", at which point a strange new radio station will pop up on your Pip-Boy. If you're not in the mood for modding or just want to get a taste of what you're in for, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d0v7JSrvqB8">YouTuber Gopher</a> has livestreamed a playthrough of Transmission Zeta as part of the modathon.</p>
<p>If you are planning on playing the mod, you'll need version 1.10.163.0 or greater of Fallout 4 and all of its DLC aside from Far Harbor and the high-res texture pack.</p>
<p>Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm going to investigate this weird blue light that's just begun beaming down from the heavens outside my house.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-fallout-4-quest-mod-has-you-investigating-alien-abductions-for-an-iconic-elder-scrolls-voice-actor]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2: On the Beach – Make Stealth and Combat Way More Enjoyable With This One Game-Changing Trick]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-make-stealth-and-combat-way-more-enjoyable-with-this-one-game-changing-trick/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-%E2%80%93-make-stealth-and-combat-way-more-enjoyable-with-this-one-game-changing-trick.1232535/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><span>Although&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-review-in-progress-one-more-for-the-road/" target="_blank">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a>&nbsp;is not focused on combat, the new entry in the series by Kojima Productions introduces new tools and a slew of improvements that make </span>it more fun and convenient to take on all sorts of enemies, ranging from human enemies to BTs. Stealth has been likewise been improved, and the game now provides you with so many tools to clear enemy camps without getting spotted by the enemy.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, it doesn't take long to notice how fighting enemies and sneaking around still feels  a little cumbersome. Sam's mobility is still quite limited, and is only partially improved by equipping a Battle Skeleton, and enemies seem to be able to spot the porter no matter how careful you are, often turning camp clearing into a head-on combat affair, which doesn't feel great for the same reason sneaking doesn't. As such, you will eventually start avoiding enemy camps completely.</p>



<p>However, there's <strong>a way to make stealth and combat way more enjoyable in Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</strong>, and it's so game-changing that it's really surprising to see how the game doesn't highlight this during what essentially is the long tutorial sequence in Mexico. This trick improves things to much that it makes the game feel more like the sequel to Metal Gear Solid V: The Phantom Pain that we never got.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Before infiltrating an enemy camp, find a safe spot some distance away, <strong>hold the Triangle button to drop your entire backpack</strong>, and try moving around. You will instantly notice how agile Sam is without cargo encumbering him. The difference is really night and day: you can now sprint and slide faster, and consistently double jump after sprinting if you have a Battle Skeleton equipped. Not having cargo on your back also makes it harder for enemies to spot you, meaning that you will have a much easier time sneaking into camps and taking enemies down one by one without getting spotted.</p>



<p>One may argue that dropping the backpack will leave you with a limited number of items that you can use, as only those Sam is carrying in his suit will be available, but this is hardly a problem. The contrary. If you have infiltrated an enemy camp already, you will have noticed how many resources, tools and weapons can be found scattered around, and you can just pick them up on the spot and use during your current infiltration. In many ways, this mirrors the premise of the Metal Gear Solid games where Snake has to procure almost everything he needs to complete his mission on site.</p>



<p>While leaving your backpack behind doesn't help a lot against BTs, as they rely on sound to spot Sam and taking them on directly doesn't reward you in any significant way, leaving your cargo behind helps a lot during boss battles. The increased mobility makes it easier to dodge enemy attacks, and Sam's evasive maneuver, which can be used while aiming, becomes way more useful. As such, always drop your backpack before fighting most enemies, and you will have a much better appreciation of the mechanics of <a href="https://www.kojimaproductions.jp/en/death-stranding-2">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a>, and a much better time overall.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/how-to/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-make-stealth-and-combat-way-more-enjoyable-with-this-one-game-changing-trick/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Alters Dev Releases Statement After Accusations Of Undisclosed AI Use]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-alters-dev-releases-statement-after-accusations-of-undisclosed-ai-use/1100-6532860/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-alters-dev-releases-statement-after-accusations-of-undisclosed-ai-use.1232526/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532860">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-alters/" data-ref-id="5000-566112">The Alters</a> developer 11 Bit Studios has found itself in hot water after players discovered evidence of generative AI in the game. The studio has now released a statement to explain why AI chatbot prompts can be found in multiple parts of the introspective survival game.</p><p>After The Alters was released in mid-June, screenshots started to emerge on social media showing evidence that certain content had been generated by AI chatbots--despite the game lacking the AI disclosure that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-developers-will-need-to-disclose-ai-use-on-steam/1100-6520235/" data-ref-id="1100-6520235">Steam now requires from developers</a>.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="11632999" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466137,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;The%20Alters%20GameSpot%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:482,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/the-alters-gamespot-review\/2300-6466137\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466137\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466137\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466137\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466137&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466137,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6532860&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;the-alters&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,adventure,survival&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;11-bit-studios,silver-lining-interactive&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466137},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466137\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4518262-review_thealters_v1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/CBzqsYRM.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1750425600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="CBzqsYRM" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> The Alters GameSpot Review</p>
      </div>
<p>One <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheAlters/comments/1lhbpox/did_the_alters_captain_use_a_little_bit_of_ai/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Reddit user</a> shared an image of an in-game data screen where the text appears to have an AI prompt included, reading: "Sure, here's a revised version focusing purely on scientific and astronomical data." Another <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:o7fzbrxgcaoek5sjkxq3acq3/post/3lsm3lzvb3s2b" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">player posted</a> a more egregious example where the chatbot prompt agreeing to translate text to Brazilian Portugese was left visible in the subtitles.</p><p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fans-slam-the-alters-after-discovering-evidence-of-undisclosed-gen-ai-in-images-text-and-translation" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Eurogamer reports</a> that errors were present in subtitles in other languages too, all appearing in the same section of the game. Handong Ryu, who was responsible for the majority of the game's Korean translation, said that "the same section of the Korean localisation shows clear signs of having been run through an LLM without proper editing," and that it was "a part of the game I had no control over."</p><p>11 Bit Studios has now posted a statement on Bluesky explaining how the sloppy AI inclusions made it into the final game, alongside a screenshot showing exactly where the AI-influenced asset can be found.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/altersgame/status/1939707458152448118" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">We’ve seen a wide range of accusations regarding the use of AI-generated content in The Alters, and we feel it’s important to clarify our approach and give you more context. AI-generated assets were used strictly as temporary WIPs during the development process and in a very… <a href="https://t.co/Me9oyABOrZ" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/Me9oyABOrZ</a></p>  — The Alters | OUT NOW 🐑 (@altersgame) <a href="https://twitter.com/altersgame/status/1939707458152448118?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 30, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The AI-generated translations, it says, were because that section of the game was added late in the development process. "A few licensed movies that the alters can watch in the social area of the base were added at the final stage of development," the statement reads. "While those were externally produced, our team was not involved in the creative process, and these required additional last-minute translations. Due to extreme time constraints, we chose not to involve our translation partners and had these videos localized using AI to have them ready on launch."</p><p>"The alternative was to release those specific dialogues in English only, which we believed would be a worse experience for non-English-speakers," the statement continues. "In hindsight, we acknowledge this was the wrong call. Even more so, no matter what we decided, we should have simply let you know."</p><p>11 Bit says both instances are being rectified now, and that the intention was always to replace the AI-generated translations in a post-launch localization hotfix.</p><p>Despite 11 Bit's admission that it used AI in the development process, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1601570/The_Alters/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Alters' Steam page</a> still appears to be lacking the AI disclosure required by Valve.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-alters-dev-releases-statement-after-accusations-of-undisclosed-ai-use/1100-6532860/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The "official scoop" on what's happening with Halo will arrive this October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-official-scoop-on-whats-happening-with-halo-will-arrive-this-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-official-scoop-on-whats-happening-with-halo-will-arrive-this-october.1232523/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Halo Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The team over at Halo Studios will be giving us the "official scoop" for what it's been working on this October.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Halo Studios - née 343 Industries - laid out further details for this year's Halo World Championship event. Here, the developer addressed the "fair amount of speculation" that has been making the rounds recently regarding what it has been working on.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Halo Infinite Campaign Gameplay - IT'S TIME TO START THE FIGHT!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nLa3nAjF1MY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Halo Infinite Campaign Gameplay - IT'S TIME TO START THE FIGHT!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nLa3nAjF1MY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nLa3nAjF1MY?autoplay=1" title="Let's Play Halo Infinite Campaign Gameplay - IT'S TIME TO START THE FIGHT!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Let's Play Halo Infinite Campaign Gameplay. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nLa3nAjF1MY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We don't usually comment on such matters, but this time we want to enter the chat and share a little more perspective for Halo fans who might be on the fence about whether to attend this year's event," the <a href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/news/halowc25-june">post on Halo Waypoint reads</a>.</p>
<p>The studio went on to confirm that, while speculation can be "fun" at times, those looking to get the official word of what is going on "won't want to miss this year's Halo World Championship". That is taking place in Seattle, between 24th - 26th October.</p>
<p>In the same post, Halo Studios noted during last year's event <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/halo-developer-343-industries-rebrands-confirms-multiple-new-games">it introduced Project Foundry</a>, its experimental look at how the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-halo-on-unreal-engine-5-means-for-ps5">Xbox flagship franchise will look developed in Unreal Engine 5</a>.</p>
<p>As for what the studio could be working on right now, the latest blog post affirmed multiple projects were in the pipeline. One of those projects may well indeed be the rumoured Halo Combat Evolved remaster, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-a-new-trailer-for-gears-of-war-reloaded">which even Xbox head Phil Spencer teased last month</a>. Then there was the chatter earlier in the year that<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-reportedly-getting-halo-and-another-big-xbox-game-with-microsoft-set-to-be-a-very-big-supporter"> Xbox was planning on bringing Halo to Switch 2 at some point</a>.</p>
<p>Who can say for sure. For now, we will just have to sit tight, and wait to see what October's Halo World Championship event has in store for us all. Stay tuned!</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-official-scoop-on-whats-happening-with-halo-will-arrive-this-october]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Dead Online Suddenly Gets New Zombie Themed Content]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/red-dead-online-gets-new-zombie-content/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/red-dead-online-suddenly-gets-new-zombie-themed-content.1232520/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It seems like Red Dead Online is suddenly getting some new content, and it's also zombie-themed. The update set to go live later today at 5 AM Eastern Time will <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/RedDeadOnline/comments/1logs5w/monthly_discounts_and_bonuses_july_1st_to_august/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">include</a> the so-called Strange Tales of the West, a set of four new Telegram missions where players will aid author Theodore Levin in investigating the unknown. They'll be able to track down undead plagues, rogue automations, swamp beasts, and more by collecting Mr. Levin’s letter from any Post Office or their Camp’s Lockbox, or simply by launching Telegram Missions from the Player Menu.</p>



<p>Telegram Missions, including the new Strange Tales of the West, are paying out 3X Gold, RDO$, and XP. Naturalists also reap rewards with 3X RDO$ and XP on Sample Sales, 3X Role XP and XP on Legendary Animal Sighting Missions, and 2X RDO$ and XP on Wildlife Photography. Here's a full list of the Red Dead Online bonuses planned for the month of July:</p>



<p><strong>3X Gold, RDO$, and XP</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Telegram Missions</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>3X RDO$ and XP</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Naturalist Sample Sales&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>3X Role XP and XP</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Legendary Animal Sighting Missions</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>2X RDO$ and XP</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Wildlife Photography&nbsp;</li>



<li>Featured Series&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-discounts">Discounts</h2>



<ul>
<li>Naturalist Sample Kit – 10 Gold Bars off&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>50% off</strong> </p>



<ul>
<li>Novice and Promising Naturalist Role Items</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>40% off</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Sedative Varmint Cartridge Pamphlet</li>



<li>Legendary Animal Pheromone Pamphlet</li>



<li>Potent Herbivore Bait Pamphlet</li>



<li>Potent Predator Bait Pamphlet</li>



<li>Gus’ Store Clothing</li>



<li>Gypsy Cob and War Horses</li>



<li>Ammo</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>30% off</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Pistols and Pistol Style Customizations</li>



<li>Hats, Coats, and Gloves</li>
</ul>



<p>Red Dead Online never really took off as much as GTA Online did. Arguably, the much slower pace worked well for the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/red-dead-redemption-2-living-outlaw-life/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">single player masterpiece that is Red Dead Redemption 2</a>, but not nearly as well in online multiplayer. It's been three years since Rockstar openly <a href="https://wccftech.com/red-dead-online-support-seemingly-slowing-down-to-focus-on-gta-vi-and-gta-online/">acknowledged</a> that they would focus more on making content for the much more successful GTA Online, and it's been a while since RDO got anything new, which is why its fans are now positively surprised. Plus, the zombie theme certainly appears to be a nod to Undead Nightmare, the acclaimed expansion released for the first Red Dead Redemption game.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/red-dead-online-gets-new-zombie-content/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto and Red Dead Redemption writer's new novel is about ill-fated game development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-and-red-dead-redemption-writers-new-novel-is-about-ill-fated-game-development</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-and-red-dead-redemption-writers-new-novel-is-about-ill-fated-game-development.1232517/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Take-Two Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>"Mark Tyburn dreams of building the perfect video game," reads the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BETTER-PARADISE-One-Aftermath/dp/B0FCYSK8VD">sales blurb</a> for Rockstar co-founder Dan Houser's novel A Better Paradise: Volume One: An Aftermath, a title so resplendent with drive-by colons that you could easily guess this man spent thirty years working in videogames. "Kurt Fischer dreams of being a rich and successful executive. Daisy Tyburn dreams of having the ideal father. John Tyburn Smith dreams of fitting in. NigelDave just dreams of becoming human."</p>
<p>PleaseDon'tLetThatBeATypo, I immediately prayed to every god I knew the name of, and a few I made up on the spot. <em>Please let NigelDave be real</em>.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="A BETTER PARADISE • NigelDave" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wox25hPeF8Y?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>A BETTER PARADISE • NigelDave</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wox25hPeF8Y?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Wox25hPeF8Y?autoplay=1" title="A BETTER PARADISE • NigelDave">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wox25hPeF8Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>NigelDave is real. He's some sort of sentient AI, I think. And without really knowing anything about the setting, I actually quite like the idea of an AI picking two blokey first names in a sort of Ford Prefect, nicely inconspicuous way. He only wants to be loved, he says.</p>
<p><em>
I</em> love you, NigelDave.</p>
<p>A Better Paradise is Houser's multimedia project, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dan-houser-a-better-paradise-video-game-novel-grand-theft-auto-writer/1100-6532850/">note Gamespot</a>. Produced by his company Absurd Ventures, it's got its own <a href="https://www.absurdventures.com/abetterparadise/audiofiction">audiofiction series</a> starring Human Traffic's (and The Walking Dead's) Andrew Lincoln. Absurd Ventures also <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockstar-co-founder-dan-housers-new-studio-is-making-an-open-world-action-adventure-game">announced last year</a> they were making an "<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world</a> action-adventure" set in the same universe.</p>
<p>A few of the novel's other characters also have voiced intro videos online. Here's a quote from Daisy Tyburn who, may I remind you, "dreams of having the ideal father". <em>The statistically perfect dad</em>. What's the Bechdel test but for before the character has spoken?</p>
<p>"<a href="https://youtu.be/sGLPNgVSpYQ">I watch the people</a>, and the people are like robots and the robots are like people. People watch their screens and the screens watch people."</p>
<p>Gods, it's like reading Candide all over again. No one man should have access to such a dangerous combination of wit and prescience.</p>
<p>"Set in the near future, A Better Paradise tells the story of the ill-fated development of an ambitious but addictive video game project that goes very wrong," continues the blurb. "As the software they developed starts to produce unexpected and disturbing results, the project is shut down and abandoned. Until now."</p>
<p>The book is out this year, October 14th. Here's a <a href="https://youtu.be/7GGKr1uCFAc">13 minute analysis of Grand Theft Auto 6's beer bottles</a> to keep you going in the wait for that game's release, currently slated for May 26th, 2026.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-and-red-dead-redemption-writers-new-novel-is-about-ill-fated-game-development]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Fans Rejoice, New Switch Icons Are Now Available Just For You]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/metroid-fans-rejoice-new-switch-icons-are-now-available-just-for-you</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metroid-fans-rejoice-new-switch-icons-are-now-available-just-for-you.1232496/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Play to unlock</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Metroid Fusion" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/c7dc67aedaf6b/metroid-fusion.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo has added two new batches of Switch Online icons from the <strong>Metroid</strong> series – specifically <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/super_metroid">Super Metroid</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/metroid_fusion">Metroid Fusion</a>.</p>
<p>You'll need to boot up and play both games in order to unlock the icons. Super Metroid is part of the SNES app on Switch, and Metroid Fusion is part of the GBA app. The latter will require a membership to Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack, so make sure you're all signed up if you're particularly keen on these.</p>
<p>The Super Metroid icons include Samus herself alongside iconic enemies like Ridley, Kraid, and the Metroid. Meanwhile, the Fusion icons include Samus in her lovely blue and yellow Fusion Suit, flanked by enemies like the X Parasite and the Core X.</p>
<p>Bizarrely, Nintendo has opted not to include S-AX in any of its forms, which seems a bit odd to us, but never mind.</p>
<p>This is nice little treat for fans while we await more news on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a>, that's for sure. The game is scheduled to launch this year, but we've yet to receive a specific date. A recent blunder saw Nintendo install a giant poster in the London Underground stating that Beyond was "Out Now", but this <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/nintendo-fixes-its-metroid-prime-4-blunder-and-its-no-longer-out-now">has since been replaced</a>.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:184338,180447 @ 1751366784 -->
<p><em>Will you be picking up any of the new Metroid icons for NSO? Let us know with a comment in the usual place.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/metroid-fans-rejoice-new-switch-icons-are-now-available-just-for-you]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Just Confirmed the New Techmarine Class, the Power Axe, a New Chaos v Chaos Mode, and Much More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-just-confirmed-the-new-techmarine-class-the-power-axe-a-new-chaos-v-chaos-mode-and-much-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-just-confirmed-the-new-techmarine-class-the-power-axe-a-new-chaos-v-chaos-mode-and-much-more.1232487/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Praise the Omnissiah.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> is set for a second year of DLC, and we have the first details on its huge 10.0 update.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Breakout hit Space Marine 2 has sold 7 million copies, so it’s no surprise to see Year 2 support confirmed by publisher Focus Entertainment and developer Saber Interactive. In a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2183900/view/500577186633221225" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">community update</a>, the companies said Year 2 will bring new PvE missions, enemies, weapons, and more unannounced content.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Space Marine 2 came out in September 2024, and as part of its first anniversary, a “large-scale” update is planned to release in September. Patch 10.0 sounds like a big one for Space Marine 2, but it’s worth noting that Patch 9.0 is due out beforehand. 9.0 was meant to add a new PvP mode, but that’s now delayed to 10.0, which means 9.0 will add only balance changes.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">We do know a little about this new PvP mode, however. The twist here is it’s Chaos vs Chaos set on a new map, and, most interesting of all, you’ll be able to take control of the Helbrute. The Helbrute, for the uninitiated, is a variant of the Chaos Dreadnought, an evil death-dealer piloted by a Chaos Space Marine trapped within its plated metal chest. You might remember the Helbrute from the Space Marine 2 campaign, where it came off worse in a scrap with the Ultramarines’ Brother Valtus. Alongside this new Chaos-themed PvP mode are new Chaos armours, which are much-requested by fans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, 10.0 adds the new Power Axe melee weapon, which has its own moveset and execution animations. We have a first look below:</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/01/b9d4da70b5f382d137a5fc2c8a7c87556b8e5053-1751353725644.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Space Marine 2's upcoming Power Axe. Image credit: Focus Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ahead-of-warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-patch-8-fans-believe-datamines-have-revealed-everything-from-the-new-class-to-a-new-much-wanted-melee-weapon-and-a-surprising-new-gun">Datamines had suggested the Power Axe</a>, which makes sense in the context of Games Workshop’s ongoing Space Wolves push for the Warhammer 40,000 tabletop game. And let’s remember, in December, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/space-marine-2-modders-put-the-axe-from-secret-levels-warhammer-40000-episode-into-the-game"><u>IGN reported on Space Marine 2 modders who put the axe from Secret Level’s Warhammer 40,000 episode into the game</u></a>.</p><blockquote data-media-max-width="560" data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>THIS is why I’m a fan of Warhammer 40k! Hats off to <a href="https://twitter.com/PrimeVideo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@PrimeVideo</a> for producing Secret Level: And They Shall Know No Fear. Watch it here: <a href="https://t.co/Gf0i2d0Rus" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/Gf0i2d0Rus</a></p><p>I highly recommend giving the entire 19 min episode a watch. It’s immersive and awesome. It’s a happy grim dark ray of… <a href="https://t.co/iuYxprAo2J" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/iuYxprAo2J</a></p></div>— MiniWarGamer Dave (@MWGdave) <a href="https://twitter.com/MWGdave/status/1866570193708913144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">December 10, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">And finally — and perhaps most exciting of all — we now know the new class for use across PvE and PvP: the Techmarine. We don’t have a first look yet, but it’s advanced enough in development to be announced. Expect more on the Techmarine in the next community updates.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Techmarine perhaps doesn’t come as a huge surprise given it was also strongly hinted at in datamines (the files mentioned a perk called ‘shoulder gun bolter,’ which is a clear indication that Techmarines are finally in play). For the uninitiated, a Techmarine is a Space Marine engineer-type class who's a big fan of the Cult Mechanicus as well as their Chapter. They’re big on technology and specialize in fixing and maintaining vehicles and other big stuff, such as Dreadnoughts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s a lot of new Space Marine 2 content coming down the line, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-3-announced-development-officially-begins-at-saber-interactive"><u>despite the surprise announcement that development of Space Marine 3 development had begun</u></a>. In the shorter term, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-siege-mode-launches-alongside-game-changing-patch-8">Patch 8.0 just launched with Siege Mode</a>, Space Marine 2's take on a Horde mode.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-just-confirmed-the-new-techmarine-class-the-power-axe-a-new-chaos-v-chaos-mode-and-much-more]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo announces price changes for original Switch in Canada]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/01/nintendo-announces-price-changes-for-original-switch-in-canada/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-announces-price-changes-for-original-switch-in-canada.1232463/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Nintendo has announced that prices of original Nintendo Switch systems and associated products in Canada will change on 1st August 2025, “based on market conditions.” The <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> line up is unaffected.</p>
<p>While they don’t say so in quite so many words, the implication is that prices are rising for the previous generation of Nintendo console – they wouldn’t pre-announce a price drop like this.</p>


<p>This looks like a full readjustment of pricing in Canada, including <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/10/06/nintendo-switch-oled-review-it-all-comes-down-to-the-screen/">Nintendo Switch – OLED Model</a>, Nintendo Switch, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/09/19/nintendo-switch-lite-review/">Nintendo Switch Lite</a>, physical and digital Nintendo Switch games and Nintendo Switch accessories. Amiibo and Nintendo Switch Online will also see price changes.</p>
<p>A lot of this could be put down to the fallout from trade wars and disputes with Canada’s closest neighbour, the United States of America. Since the start of the current administration, Canada has repeatedly tussled with Trump over tariffs, with new levies being announced, paused, pulled back, reannounced and more. That’s in addition to the global tariffs that Trump put in place as well. This uncertainty has had a huge impact on pricing around the world, but while <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/01/xbox-series-xs-console-prices-are-jumping-up-around-the-world-games-to-hit-80-this-winter/">Microsoft</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/14/ps5-price-increases-hit-uk-eu-aus-nz-but-at-least-the-disc-drive-is-getting-cheaper/">Sony</a> announced price increases earlier this year, Nintendo has avoided making similar changes in the run up to the Switch 2’s launch – not least because of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/24/nintendo-switch-2-edition-game-upgrade-prices-set-at-8-and-17-depending-on-the-game/">how much criticism they took</a> over pricing the new console, games and upgrades.</p>

<p>Could this herald more price increases for other countries? Certainly, and we’ll just have to wait and see what these price changes actually end up being.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-ca/whatsnew/nintendo-switch-pricing-update/">Nintendo</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/01/nintendo-announces-price-changes-for-original-switch-in-canada/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Removed Its Products from Amazon US Due to Disagreement on Unauthorized Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-removed-products-amazon-us/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-removed-its-products-from-amazon-us-due-to-disagreement-on-unauthorized-sales.1232460/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>If you regularly browse Amazon US, you might have noticed that some Nintendo products sold directly by Amazon have seemingly disappeared from the online store. Now, Bloomberg has <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-30/amazon-lost-right-to-sell-nintendo-switch-2-amid-sales-dispute?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc1MTMzNDU2NiwiZXhwIjoxNzUxOTM5MzY2LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTWURHWDRUMEFGQjQwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJBRDcxOUY5NDBGRTk0MzNBOERCNzI2OEJDOTY3NzY3QyJ9.E71nPDnc5HCRuSL_hpDTIu53pBJ6k8Jxef68-H6UgOs&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">published</a> a report on why that's happened.</p>



<p>According to Bloomberg's sources, the issue presented itself when Nintendo noticed that certain third-party sellers on Amazon were undercutting official products. They would essentially purchase the products in Southeast Asia, where they were presumably cheaper, and then sell them in the United States via Amazon.</p>



<p>In an attempt to reassure Nintendo, Amazon offered to attach labels to products to guarantee their authenticity. However, the proposal wasn't deemed enough of an assurance to Nintendo, and the Japanese company ultimately decided to remove its products from Amazon in the US.</p>



<p>When Bloomberg asked Amazon for a comment prior to publishing the story, a spokesperson simply commented, “The claims made by Bloomberg regarding our relationship with Nintendo are inaccurate,” without providing any further details on the subject.</p>



<p>Whatever the case, the fact remains that the issue prevented Amazon from participating in the launch of the Nintendo Switch 2, which turned out to be the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-debuts-with-3-5-million-units-sold-in-4-days/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fastest-selling console in history</a> with its over 3.5 million units sold in the first four days since the launch date (June 6), going <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-nintendo-switch-2-is-selling-twice-as-fast-as-the-og-switch/">twice as fast</a> as the original Switch when considering the same timeframe. </p>



<p>What's perhaps even more impressive is that even without selling directly on Amazon US, by far the biggest online store in the country, the Nintendo Switch 2 still <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-set-another-record-by-selling-1-1-million-units-in-its-launch-week-in-the-us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sold</a> 1.1 million units across the United States in the launch week, beating the record previously established by Sony's PlayStation 2 in October 2000. By the way, Nintendo products (Switch 2 included) are regularly available in several countries, such as Japan itself, the United Kingdom and Canada. However, Amazon US makes up two-thirds of the store's global sales.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-removed-products-amazon-us/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Builder Garage Fan-Made 'Direct' Reveals New Creations Alongside Switch 2 Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/game-builder-garage-fan-made-direct-reveals-new-creations-alongside-switch-2-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-builder-garage-fan-made-direct-reveals-new-creations-alongside-switch-2-update.1232421/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The Switch title received a free update last month</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>Alongside Switch 2's launch last month, Nintendo rolled out multiple free Switch game updates. One of these was for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/game_builder_garage">Game Builder Garage</a> – which not only included visual optimisations but also added Joy-Con 2 mouse support.</p>
<p>Now, timed in with this update and the game's fourth anniversary, the Game Builder Garage community has held its very own "fan-made Nintendo Direct" <a href="https://youtu.be/4XpotaYRQRY">hosted by VideoDojo on YouTube</a> (<em>thanks for the heads up, Giovani Vitti</em>).</p>
<p>It showcases 20 minutes of community-made games (and demos) available now and coming soon, and even features an entire segment dedicated to Game Builder Garage creations made by the game's community in Japan.</p>
<p>Some of the games here channel Nintendo's IP and there's even a recreation of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> and many other fan-made surprises. You can see just how far the community has pushed this game-maker in the full video above.</p>
<p>And here's a quick list highlighting some of these games. You can find out more about each project by scanning the QR codes displayed throughout the presentation.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>DOOM: The Garage Ages</strong></li>
<li><strong>Super Kirb RPG</strong></li>
<li><strong>Crumble Crew</strong></li>
<li><strong>HajiPro Direct</strong></li>
<li><strong>Printo Golfing!!!</strong></li>
<li><strong>Kuno</strong></li>
<li><strong>Shackled II: Bloodbound</strong></li>
<li><strong>Undertale: Quest of the Depths</strong></li>
</ul>
<figure><a title="Captain Toad" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/57e162b03f263/captain-toad.large.jpg"></a></figure>

<figure><a title="Mario Kart" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ce0680e61281c/mario-kart.large.jpg"></a></figure>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:182454,115758 @ 1751369079 -->
<p>Have you returned to Game Builder Garage on the Switch 2? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://youtu.be/4XpotaYRQRY" rel="noopener" href="https://youtu.be/4XpotaYRQRY">youtu.be</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/3fdfb7d259cd632267e9acd4c0e8b79b @ 1751367994 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/game-builder-garage-fan-made-direct-reveals-new-creations-alongside-switch-2-update]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Incredible Sonic The Hedgehog Rubber Duck Plushies Hit New Low Prices]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tubbz-rubber-duck-plush-sonic-the-hedgehog-amazon-deals/1100-6532858/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/incredible-sonic-the-hedgehog-rubber-duck-plushies-hit-new-low-prices.1232412/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532858">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sonic the Hedgehog fans can <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DFM7B6TJ,B0DFM7YD7V&amp;tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">save on two of the cutest and silliest collectibles</a> featuring Sega's iconic mascot and his archenemy Doctor Eggman. Amazon has the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7B6TJ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sonic the Hedgehog Rubber Duck Plush</a></strong> discounted to a new all-time low of $18.60 (was $25). Meanwhile, <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7YD7V?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Doctor Eggman's Rubber Duck Plush</a></strong> is up for grabs for $21.10 (was $25), which is also the best price yet for this arguably zanier plushie.</p><p>Check out both Sonic characters and more popular heroes and villains as rubber duck plushies below.</p><div title="[Various] Sonic the Hedgehog Tubbz Duck Plush" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="3792" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="[Various] Sonic the Hedgehog Tubbz Duck Plush" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7B6TJ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DFM7B6TJ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7B6TJ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">Sonic the Hedgehog Tubbz Duck Plush (9 Inches)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7B6TJ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DFM7B6TJ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7B6TJ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">$18.60 (was $25)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>This 9-inch Sonic the Hedgehog-Duck plush is officially licensed by Sega and modeled after the hero's classic appearance.</p><p>Each Tubbz duck has a weighted base, so that it can be displayed upright as shown above. But while Sonic makes for a funny display piece, it's also soft enough to cuddle like any other plush. If you're buying this as a gift for a younger Sonic fan, you'll be pleased to learn that it's machine washable.</p><p>Amazon doesn't have an end date listed for the Sonic deal, but this model has only received a few price cuts since its launch last November. It was also sold out for several months after launch and wasn't readily available again until April.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7YD7V?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DFM7YD7V?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7YD7V?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">Doctor Eggman Tubbz Duck Plush (9 Inches)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7YD7V?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DFM7YD7V?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7YD7V?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">$21.10 (was $25)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>This is the first time the Doctor Eggman Rubber Duck Plush has been priced lower than its $25 MSRP. Amazon has this one marked as a limited-time deal with a set number of units available.</p><p>Like Sonic, Doctor Eggman was sold out for a few months following its launch last holiday before being restocked in March.</p></div>                      </div>   </div><p>Collectible company Tubbz has made a name for itself with its zany lineup of vinyl rubber ducks featuring characters like <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Gandalf-Collectible-Rubber-Figure/dp/B0C9YMHN61?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Gandalf</a> from Lord of the Rings, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-First-Raider-Survival-Cosplaying/dp/B0DKP3S6DB?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lara Croft</a> from Tomb Raider, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Metal-Collectible-Rubber-Figurine/dp/B08GKN1HYD?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Solid Snake</a> from Metal Gear Solid, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Boxed-Shining-Torrance-Cosplaying/dp/B0DQ8RFVQ5?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Jack Torrance</a> (with an axe) from The Shining, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Hannibal-Lecter-Collectible-Rubber/dp/B0CDLCC769?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hannibal Lecter </a>from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Silence-Lambs-Criterion-Collection-Blu-ray/dp/B077HP1DSS?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Silence of the Lambs</a>, multiple <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Sub-Zero-Collectible-Rubber-Figure/dp/B0CN9MR12B?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Mortal Kombat fighters</a>, and even <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Knight-Astora-Collectible-Rubber/dp/B0C9YMFS3D?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Solaire of Astora</a> from Dark Souls, who is, of course, praising the sun.</p><p>And yes, Tubbz also has rubber duck vinyl figures of numerous Sonic the Hedgehog characters, including <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-NS4878-Sonic-Plush/dp/B0CRS346QK?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sonic</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Boxed-Collectible-Rubber-Figure/dp/B0CRS4C744?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tails</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Boxed-Collectible-Rubber-Figure/dp/B0CRS3G1G5?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Knuckles</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Boxed-Collectible-Rubber-Figure/dp/B0CRS488SX?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Shadow,</a> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Boxed-Collectible-Rubber-Figure/dp/B0D7CKCTP6?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amy Rose</a>, and more.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4523965-tubbzrubberduckplushies.png" data-ref-id="1300-4523965" data-ratio="0.38461538461538" data-width="1300" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4523965-tubbzrubberduckplushies.png" data-ref-id="1300-4523965"></a><figcaption>Batman | Gandalf | Joker</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4523965-tubbzrubberduckplushies.png"></figure><p>There aren't nearly as many plushies as vinyl figures in the Tubbz collection, but there are a bunch of cool ones outside of the Sonic the Hedgehog franchise. Sticking with video game-themed plushies, Destiny fans can pick from a few different characters, including <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Destiny-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0CLVNL9Y7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Cayde-6</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Zavala-Collectable-Rubber-Plushie/dp/B0CLVQVLY6?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Zavala</a></strong>. After selling out earlier this year, <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DQYFD63T?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Vault Boy from Fallout</a></strong> is back in stock at Amazon.</p><p>Amazon also recently started selling plushie versions of <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Gandalf-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DQ8KM73L?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Gandalf the Grey</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Baggins-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DQ8JD22K?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Frodo from Lord of the Rings</a></strong> as well as <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Batman-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0F1FYS4QQ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Batman from The Dark Knight</a></strong>. The Batman plush is on the verge of selling out, though, so fans should snag it while they can. You can display the Caped Crusader next to the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Batman-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0F1FZJLBL?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Joker Rubber Duck Plush</a></strong> based on the villain's appearance in The Dark Knight.</p><hr><p>Horror fans can get creepy/adorable duck plushie spins on <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Chucky-Collectable-Rubber-Plushie/dp/B0CLVQGLY3?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Chucky from Child's Play</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-NS4983-IT-Plush-Pennywise/dp/B0DD48BXSD?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Pennywise from Stephen King's It</a></strong>. Chucky is on sale for only $15, while Pennywise is a few bucks off. Pennywise is holding his signature red balloon, but even if he keeps telling you that "we all float down here," you should know that Tubbz plushies are not designed to be brought in the bathtub.</p><p>We've put together a list of the Tubbz Rubber Duck Plushies we found on Amazon. Several of the characters below have received limited-time discounts similar to Doctor Eggman, including the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-NS5107-Avatar-Plush-Turtleduck/dp/B0DFM76CG6?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">turtle duck from Avatar: The Last Airbender</a></strong>.</p><h2><a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DFM7B6TJ,B0DFM7YD7V,B0DD48BXSD,B0CLVQGLY3,B0F1FYS4QQ,B0F1FZJLBL,B0DFM76CG6,B0F1G1P2CS,B0F1FZ4W6N,B0CLVNV9QW,B0CLVNL9Y7,B0CLVQF592,B0CLVQVLY6,B0DQYFD63T,B0CLVQG3FR,B0DFM8MM8K,B0DFM9ZY4C,B0CLVPXC9W,B0DQ8JD22K,B0DQ8KM73L,B0DQYDF29G,B0DHY8S4KC,B0DG2TJG3M,B0DG2MR2F1,B0DT4RD9JW,B0DT4QYJH4,B0CLVPN4J8&amp;tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tubbz Rubber Duck Plushies</a></h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-NS5107-Avatar-Plush-Turtleduck/dp/B0DFM76CG6?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Avatar - Turtleduck</a> -- $21.10 (<del>$25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Future-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0F1G1P2CS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Back to the Future - Doc Brown</a> -- $25 | Releases July 22</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Future-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0F1FZ4W6N?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Back to the Future - Marty McFly</a> -- Sold out</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Chucky-Collectable-Rubber-Plushie/dp/B0CLVQGLY3?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Child's Play - Chucky</a> -- $15 (<del>$25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Batman-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0F1FYS4QQ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Dark Knight - Batman</a> -- $25</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Batman-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0F1FZJLBL?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Dark Knight - Joker</a> -- $25</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Collectable-Rubber-Duck-Plushie/dp/B0CLVNV9QW?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Despicable Me 4 - Bob the Minion</a> -- Sold out</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Destiny-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0CLVNL9Y7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny - Cayde-6</a> -- $25</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Eris-Collectable-Rubber-Plushie/dp/B0CLVQF592?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny - Eris Morn</a> -- $30</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Zavala-Collectable-Rubber-Plushie/dp/B0CLVQVLY6?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny - Zavala</a> -- $24 (<del>$25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DQYFD63T?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout - Vault Boy</a> -- $25</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Bruce-Collectable-Rubber-Plushie/dp/B0CLVQG3FR?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Jaws - Bruce</a> -- Sold out</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Jurassic-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DFM8MM8K?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Jurassic Park - Velociraptor</a> -- $20 (<del>$25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Dilophosaurus-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DFM9ZY4C?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Jurassic Park - Dilophosaurus</a> -- $29</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Jurassic-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0CLVPXC9W?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Jurassic Park - T-Rex</a> -- Sold out</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Baggins-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DQ8JD22K?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Lord of the Rings - Frodo</a> -- $25</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Gandalf-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DQ8KM73L?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Lord of the Rings - Gandalf the Grey</a> -- $25</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-NS4983-IT-Plush-Pennywise/dp/B0DD48BXSD?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Pennywise from Stephen King's It</a> -- $22.36 (<del>$25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Resident-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DQYDF29G?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Resident Evil - Claire Redfield</a> -- $33</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Resident-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DHY8S4KC?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Resident Evil - Leon Kennedy</a> -- Sold out</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Grinch-Duck-Figurine-Merchandise/dp/B0CLVPN4J8?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Santa Claus</a> -- Sold out</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-NS4878-Sonic-Plush/dp/B0DFM7B6TJ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sonic the Hedgehog</a> -- $18.60 (<del>$25)</del></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DFM7YD7V?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sonic the Hedgehog - Doctor Eggman</a> -- $21.10 (<del>$30</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DG2TJG3M?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Star Trek - James T. Kirk</a> -- $25</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Star-Trek-Plush-Spock/dp/B0DG2MR2F1?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Star Trek - Spock</a> -- $25</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Yakuza-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DT4RD9JW?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yakuza - Kazuma Kiryu</a> -- $29</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/TUBBZ-Plush-Yakuza-Cosplaying-Collectible/dp/B0DT4QYJH4?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yakuza - Goro Majima</a> -- $29</li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-criterion-collection-best-movie-deals-amazon-blu-ray-sale/1100-6532794/">The Criterion Collection 50% Off Movie Sale - Here Are The Best Deals</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/little-nightmares-3-preorder-guide-amazon-exclusive-edition-bonuses-release-date/1100-6532712/">Little Nightmares 3 Amazon-Exclusive Mirror Edition Is Up For Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/legos-first-visual-history-for-adults-is-60-off-in-early-prime-day-deal/1100-6532717/">Lego's First Visual History For Adults Is 60% Off In Early Prime Day Deal</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-earth-dancer-limited-edition-nintendo-switch-2-restock/1100-6526172/">Amazon Restocks Rune Factory: Guardians Of Azuma Earth Dancer Edition</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-four-discontinued-donkey-kong-lego-sets-restocked-at-amazon/1100-6532560/">All Four Discontinued Donkey Kong Lego Sets Restocked At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-collector-edition-launch-buying-guide/1100-6530003/">Death Stranding 2 Collector's Edition Is In Stock Ahead Of Tomorrow's Launch</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-preorder-nintendo-switch-2/1100-6530595/">Donkey Kong Bananza Game &amp; Amiibo Bundle Available At Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-spider-man-magic-the-gathering-trading-card-restock-amazon-preorder/1100-6529819/">Marvel's Spider-Man Magic: The Gathering Preorders Restocked At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tubbz-rubber-duck-plush-sonic-the-hedgehog-amazon-deals/1100-6532858/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Harvest Moon's New "Cozy" Bundle Slightly Delayed For Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/harvest-moons-new-cozy-bundle-slightly-delayed-for-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/harvest-moons-new-cozy-bundle-slightly-delayed-for-switch.1232394/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"Hate to make you wait"</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Harvest Moon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/5b895a5217908/harvest-moon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Natsume</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Natsume previously announced it would be releasing a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/harvest_moon_the_lost_valley_and_harvest_moon_skytree_village">Harvest Moon</a> double pack on the Switch at the beginning of this month, but it seems there's been a slight delay.</p>
<p>Instead of the 3rd July 2025 release, it seems farming and life simulation fans will now have to wait until <strong>31st July 2025</strong> for this game to arrive. Natsume didn't reveal the reason behind the delay but did <a href="https://x.com/Natsume_Inc/status/1939746378286039510">issue an apology on social media</a>.</p>
<p>Here it is in full:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Hi, farmers. We are very sorry to share that Harvest Moon: The Lost Valley &amp; Skytree Village will now be released on July 31. We are very excited to bring these 3DS titles to the Switch and hate to make you wait. Thank you for your patience and understanding!"</p></blockquote><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067slinom&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>825k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>As mentioned, this two-in-one bundle will contain <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/harvest_moon_the_lost_valley_and_harvest_moon_skytree_village">The Lost Valley</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/harvest_moon_the_lost_valley_and_harvest_moon_skytree_village">Skytree Village</a>, which originally debuted on the 3DS. These new versions on Switch will be "optimized" for the system and each game includes the DLC.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:181744,183745,143372 @ 1751367615 -->
<p>Will you be checking out this bundle when it launches on Switch? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/harvest-moons-new-cozy-bundle-slightly-delayed-for-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>