<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:07:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 players are escaping death by performing aerial salutes and hugs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-players-are-escaping-death-by-performing-aerial-salutes-and-hugs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-players-are-escaping-death-by-performing-aerial-salutes-and-hugs.922434/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-players-are-escaping-death-by-performing-aerial-salutes-and-hugs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
According to the wikihow page <a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Fall-Safely">“how to fall safely”</a>, the best thing way to minimise injury while falling is to stay loose, keep your arms and legs bent, and roll on impact. According to ragdoll-prone shooter <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a>, however, it’s better to stand to attention in mid-air and perform a crisp salute. It’s long been known that the game’s emotes confer unexpected defensive advantages, with emergency hugs sometimes shielding you against artillery fire, but now, one redditor has proven via careful scientific experimentation that they also protect you against the force of gravity.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
The redditor in question is the heroic 21471824781, whose doings have been passed along by <a href="https://www.vg247.com/helldivers-2-players-dont-want-arrowhead-to-patch-out-lifesaving-salutes">VG247</a>. As the below clip demonstrates, saluting or, if you’re more of a lover than a patriot, hugging the air while falling will reduce the red-tinting on impact. Other redditors speculate that this is due to Helldivers 2’s unexpectedly in-depth simulation systems, with damage to your head counting for more than damage to other body parts. Spreading your arms or sticking out your elbow rather than ragdolling means that you’re less likely to strike the floor headfirst.</p>
<p>On this count, at least, Helldivers 2 is in broad agreement with Wikihow (which advises falling people to protect their heads, albeit not in a patriotic way). On the other hand, it could be that developers Arrowhead have applied a general damage nerf while emoting so that emoting under fire is slightly more practical. Whatever the answer, it's an enjoyable quirk for a game that has "diving" in the title.
</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1dxr2bu/attention_helldivers_using_an_emote_midfall_may/">Attention Helldivers, using an emote mid-fall may SAVE YOUR LIFE!</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/21471824781/">u/21471824781</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/">Helldivers</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>
There’s a rich tradition of people using emotes in videogames for tactical gain, though I can’t think of anything else quite like this. Personally, I use them as tools of misdirection in PvP shooters – attempting to confuse and charm an attacking player with a hearty Cheer emote only to callously gun them down the second they return the gesture. In Dark Souls 3, meanwhile, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sL99DrR5lhg">you can use the Curl Up emoji to dodge boss attacks</a> if you want to sabotage all sense of theatre and make poor Pontiff Sulyvahn look like an absolute prize fool. Do you have any similar examples to share? In other news, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-developers-have-big-opaque-plans-for-galactic-war-and-that-black-hole-you-made">Arrowhead are making ominous noises about the game's recently added black hole</a> that possibly augur the reveal of the game's long-speculated-about <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-updates-could-bring-back-the-first-games-sneaky-teleporting-illuminate-faction">Illuminate faction</a>.</p>




        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nike And Tekken 8 Are Tag-Teaming Up For Foamposite One Shoe Collaboration]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/07/09/nike-and-tekken-8-are-tag-teaming-up-for-foamposite-one-shoe-collaboration</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nike-and-tekken-8-are-tag-teaming-up-for-foamposite-one-shoe-collaboration.922431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/07/09/nike-and-tekken-8-are-tag-teaming-up-for-foamposite-one-shoe-collaboration<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Nike and Bandai Namco are teaming up to release a <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/tekken-8">Tekken 8</a>-inspired shoe that will be available for purchase this September. Dubbed "Tekken 8 x Nike Air Foamposite One Fist," these shoes will be available through Nike, SNKRS, and select retailers in-store and online for $250, as reported by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.soleretriever.com/news/articles/tekken-8-nike-air-foamposite-one-premium-fist-release-date-2024"><em>Sole Retriever</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="91d9866f-4a0e-4802-9c9a-dfb25cf007c9" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p>The shoes themselves are inspired specifically by Tekken 8's primary antagonist, Kazuya Mishima, as the colorway of the shoe is basically a spin on his outfit in-game.&nbsp;<em>Sole Retriever&nbsp;</em>describes the shoes as featuring an iridescent Foamposite material across the design's upper region in armory navy, with a faux crocodile skin texture across the Foamposite material, and black hues over the leather eyestays, shoe collar, and tongue.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Check out the Tekken 8 x Nike Air Foamposite One Fist&nbsp;</strong><strong>shoes for yourself below:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>As you can see, the shoes also feature the Tekken logos, a Fist logo with Tekken's signature lighting, and a nice box to hold the shoes.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Sole Retriever&nbsp;</em>reports that a second colorway in this lineup is on the way and it will reference Jin Kazama, although there's no images of what it will look like yet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>These Tekken 8 x Nike Air Foamposite One Fist shoes will cost you $250 when they release this September. For more, read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/tekken-8/aggressively-absurd"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>Tekken 8 review</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>[Source: <a href="https://www.soleretriever.com/news/articles/tekken-8-nike-air-foamposite-one-premium-fist-release-date-2024">Sole Retriever</a>]</em></p>

<hr><p><em>Are you going to pick these shoes up this September? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Paramedic action drama’ Neo Harbor Rescue Squad announced for PS5, PS4, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/paramedic-action-drama-neo-harbor-rescue-squad-announced-for-ps5-ps4-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98paramedic-action-drama%E2%80%99-neo-harbor-rescue-squad-announced-for-ps5-ps4-and-pc.922428/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/paramedic-action-drama-neo-harbor-rescue-squad-announced-for-ps5-ps4-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Featuring over 50 farcade-style minigames.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>Home</em> and <em>Alone With You</em> developer <a title="Companies > BancyCo" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bancyco">BancyCo</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Neo Harbor Rescue Squad" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/neo-harbor-rescue-squad">Neo Harbor Rescue Squad</a></em>, a “paramedic <a title="Genres > Action [1,996 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> drama” featuring over 50 <a title="Genres > Arcade [53 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a>-style minigames. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,426 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,913 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,618 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2342780/Neo_Harbor_Rescue_Squad/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2024. <span id="more-897819"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://www.bancy.co/games/rescuesquad/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">official website</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A paramedic action drama with frantic minigames and a wild, funny story!</p><p>Prove yourself as a rookie paramedic as you juggle waves of patients with an inventive triage system. Master dozens of treatments to win the city’s recognition from the egotistical fire department.</p><p>Stabilize patients with fast, funny, arcade-style minigames—perform CPR, stop a nosebleed, seal a wound, use a defibrillator, bandage an arm—and so much more! Features over 50 minigames with multiple difficulty variations, allowing for hundreds of combinations.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Use our triage system to quickly monitor patients’ health, how much damage they’re taking, if they’re critical, and learn to prioritize treatment.</li><li>Quickly switch between different views to manage multiple patients across a variety of complex scenes.</li><li>Use shields to temporarily protect your patients from damage, giving you some breathing room to strategize.</li><li>Aim for a high rank with each emergency; be graded based on speed, skill, and the condition of your patients.</li><li>Make dialogue choices to deal with the public, advance the story, and get to know your squadmates.</li><li>Laugh through a story of teamwork and friendship (and dolphins), inspired by real paramedic stories in Asia.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Neo Harbor Rescue Squad - Official Announcement Trailer (4K)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PMFicJOCIxU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/09/zenless-zone-zero-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-review.922413/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/09/zenless-zone-zero-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/genshin-impact">Genshin Impact</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/honkai-star-rail/">Honkai Star Rail</a> were both games that proved that free-to-play doesn’t mean lightweight and frivolous. While you can question the business model of their ‘gacha’ style setup, miHoYo’s differing gameplay styles across both games have hit home with players. Zenless Zone Zero is the latest title from the developer, and once again gameplay is the star of the show, though at times it doesn’t make enough of the standout parts of it.</p>
<p><iframe title="Zenless Zone Zero Official Release Teaser | The Person You Are Calling Is in a Hollow" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KGOynaQoofc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Zenless Zone Zero is set in the futuristic city of New Eridu. This world has been beset by Hollows – areas of frozen time that are polluted with Ether, a substance that’s capable of mutating people into terrifying monsters known as Ethereals – but which have also proven to hold substantial wealth, if you have the means to collect it.</p>


<p>You play as a Proxy, choosing between the siblings of Wise and Belle. Proxies can send their consciousness into the Hollows within a Bangboo – a strange combination of Rabbid, Pokémon and a robot – and from there direct teams of Hollow Raiders who can fight off the Ether monsters on their way to whatever target they’ve been set. It’s a suitably sci-fi/anime setting that draws in and builds successfully on ideas we might have seen or heard before, but Zenless Zone Zero does an incredible job of selling them via its stellar presentation.</p>


<p>Put simply, Zenless Zone Zero looks and sounds incredible. I might be a sucker for anime-styled games, but the art style and overarching design of New Eridu and its inhabitants is simply breathtaking. It looks like a comic that’s come to life, and at points, it actually is a comic, with cutscenes and dramatic moments told via pages of a graphic novel. Beyond that, interactions between characters are often fully voiced, and as you spend more and more time with them you’ll come to love them, especially the opening trio made up of the emotionless Anby, street-smart Nicole and the Deadpool-lite Billy. You unlock new team members via the different gacha machine-style mechanics, each with their own personality as well as unique weaponry and appearances, virtually guaranteeing that you’ll find a favourite amongst them.</p>
<p>Zenless Zone Zero is much smaller scale than Genshin Impact, and where that aped <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2017/03/02/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-review/">Breath of the Wild</a> and its sprawling landscape, ZZZ is closer to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/07/26/neo-the-world-ends-with-you-review/">NEO: The World Ends With You</a>, with its central elements happening across a much more limited area. It’s more approachable to newcomers, and makes more obvious sense on mobile as well as console or PC, placing it firmly between miHoYo’s expansive Genshin Impact and the smaller-scale Honkai Star Rail.</p>

<p>While it might sit somewhere between the two gameplay-wise, it shares the same ‘gacha’ elements as both its forebears, meaning it’s built to try and make you spend actual money. You’ll likely know whether this business model works for you, but this is a game that is fundamentally fully playable without spending anything. You do, however, rely on RNG to gift you the most powerful versions of each character, and their equipment, so if you want to maximise your chances you have to spend some cash. I’ve spent 99p though, and the game is certainly worth more than that.</p>
<p>The thing that shines brightest of all here, and the element that’s worth a pretty penny, is Zenless Zone Zero’s combat. Entering a Hollow sees you choosing a team of three Hollow Raiders, and then fighting off an increasingly dangerous set of Ethereals. Hack-and-slash combat is built around standard and special attacks, but the game’s <em>coup de grace</em> is the ability to switch between all three members of your team on the fly. If you time it so you dodge an incoming attack you’ll perform a more powerful switch attack, and you can chain these together, creating a spectacular anime battle in real-time. It feels powerful and natural, and the visuals back it all up wonderfully. This is the consistent highlight of the game, and it does not wear thin.</p>

<p>What might wear thin is that you’re not always involved in that delicious combat. At the moment, the weakest elements of Zenless Zone Zero lie in its focus away from the exciting and vibrant battles, especially in the board game sections that seem to stand in your way for very little reason other than to have you do something before hopping back into the fray. These happen within the proxy’s HDD computer, with you exploring a route tile by tile, collecting information, different materials and currency while facing whatever foes you can’t avoid. The thing is, you won’t want to avoid these enemies, because that gets you back to the best bit.</p>
<p>Depending on the type of person you are, you can get heavily involved in the levelling up, unlocking and collecting of each character’s equipment. As a free-to-play title you’ll probably be familiar with the fact that literally everything has a notification next to it, and you can complete challenges at an impressive pace, gaining more and more material to pile into every possible slot. miHoYo are masters of this art, and I rarely found it getting in the way, especially when I was enjoying it as much as I was.</p>

<p>At launch, there are little quality-of-life things that we can hope miHoYo implement, like your characters having an auto-speech option during cutscenes, which would make everything feel just that little bit smoother, and improving or minimising the amount of loading or updating it does every single time you start the game. Still, as a free-to-play title, this is a generous and hugely enjoyable package that will hopefully grow into another success for the company.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spooky free-to-play open worlder Once Human is out today, and the devs have some crash and performance tips]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spooky-free-to-play-open-worlder-once-human-is-out-today-and-the-devs-have-some-crash-and-performance-tips</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spooky-free-to-play-open-worlder-once-human-is-out-today-and-the-devs-have-some-crash-and-performance-tips.922410/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spooky-free-to-play-open-worlder-once-human-is-out-today-and-the-devs-have-some-crash-and-performance-tips<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>No controller, Steam Deck or DLSS support right now</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_fI4wL6Y.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Starry Studio</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
From <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/zenless-zone-zero">Zenless Zone Zero</a> to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant</a>, we seem to be experiencing a free-to-play explosion. Despair, ye time-constrained adults, for your carefully engineered shortage of pocket money offers no bulwark against the onslaught of games that want a slice of your evening or weekend. Today's big release, Once Human, at least features a giant schoolbus on monster legs, together with a less exciting but customisable van that just has wheels. In this <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world</a> survival shooter, you are a "Meta-Human" making your way around a landscape corrupted by Stardust, which has warped the scenery and will slowly drive you nuts. 
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Once Human | Official Release Date Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XTwOAAGhLCk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Once Human | Official Release Date Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XTwOAAGhLCk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XTwOAAGhLCk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XTwOAAGhLCk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
You'll get to chop down trees, build bases and craft/obtain weapons of colour-coded rarities. It's a familiar blend, but I'm intrigued by the touches of Control-esque and Ghostwire-adjacent monster and level design in the trailers. I'm going to try the game out this evening. I'm hoping it'll be a bit like The Division 2's Dark Zones but New Weird. On which note, developers Starry Studio have done <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2139460/view/4230650600757463064?l=english">a launch FAQ</a> in advance of the probably inevitable release day bugs.
</p>
<p>
Let me pack it down for you: at launch, you only get one character per account. Once Human is cross-platform, but not on Steam accounts, for the moment, "due to their inherent limitations"; the developers suggest using NetEase's Loading Bay launcher instead, which I don't have much experience with myself. The game also doesn't officially run on Steam Deck right now. More vexingly, it doesn't yet support controllers either. "Our development team is actively working on changes to bring controller support as soon as possible," the FAQ promises. "We expect to complete this by August."
</p>
<p>
Once Human will get seasonal updates with new scenarios offering different rules and environments, with players able to carry resources between seasons via their "personal domain" at Eternaland, which sounds like the name of a web3 Second Life rip-off but is seemingly just a customisable base. There will be separate PvE and PvP servers at launch, with a tiny quantity of PvE stuff exclusive to the PvE server. 
</p>
<p>
Now then, how about some system requirements! The below are apparently what you'll need to run Once Human at 1080p. 
</p>
<blockquote><p>
<strong>Minimum</strong>:
</p>
<p>
OS: Windows 10 (64-bit)
</p>
<p>
CPU: Intel Core i5-4460
</p>
<p>
RAM: 8GB RAM
</p>
<p>
GPU: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 750 Ti, 4 GB or AMD Radeon R9 270
</p>
<p>
DirectX: Version 11
</p>
<p>
Available Storage Space: 60GB
</p>
<p>
<strong>Recommended</strong>:
</p>
<p>
OS: Windows 10 (64-bit)
</p>
<p>
CPU: Intel Core i7-7700
</p>
<p>
RAM: 16GB RAM
</p>
<p>
GPU: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1060, 6 GB or AMD Radeon RX 580
</p>
<p>
DirectX: Version 11
</p>
<p>
Available Storage Space: 70GB SSD
</p>
<p>
<strong>For 60 fps performance</strong>:
</p>
<p>
OS: Windows 10 (64-bit)
</p>
<p>
CPU: Intel Core i5-12400F
</p>
<p>
RAM: 16GB RAM
</p>
<p>
GPU: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 3060 or AMD Radeon RX 6650 XT
</p>
<p>
DirectX: Version 11
</p>
<p>
Available Storage Space: 70GB SSD
</p></blockquote>
<p>
Sound a bit demanding? The developers are aware. "Once Human offers a high-quality audiovisual experience," the FAQ explains. "This requires a large amount of storage space for HD images, textures, sound effects, and map files. Additionally, as an MMO survival game, we aim to render long viewing distances so that players can see structures in the world as far as possible. We are continuously working to optimize the game for the best possible experience."
</p>
<p>
On a similar note, Once Human doesn't yet support DLSS "due to the ongoing optimization and integration of certain features". It does support DirectX 12, but this might cause "a slight frame drop" compared to DirectX 11.
</p>
<p>
Starry Studio have also put together some elementary tips to improve performance - in particular, lowering the resolution, lowering texture quality and special effects, and lowering the rendering quality. The developers further note that if you do try to plug in a controller - including "pedals and gearbox controls for driving games, or joysticks for flying games" - there may be compatability errors that lead to crashes.</p>
<p>If you are reading this in a distant future of a few hours from now, after Once Human goes live, I hope the advice has helped. Past experience of free-to-play launches suggests that there will be many a gremlin to exorcise. And beyond that, who knows? Once Human was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-next-fext-2024s-most-popular-demos-include-goblin-maid-sims-horror-shooters-and-a-chinese-game-about-an-unmarried-no-lifer">the most popular demo during Steam Next Fest 2024</a>. Again, there's no shortage of competition right now in the loot-ridden realm of F2P, but perhaps it'll be another one of this year's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/palworld">breakout</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/manor-lords">hits</a>.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shadow of the Erdtree Has Been Beaten with a Dance Pad]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-has-been-beaten-with-a-dance-pad/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadow-of-the-erdtree-has-been-beaten-with-a-dance-pad.922404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-has-been-beaten-with-a-dance-pad/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>MissMikkaa has done it again, beating Shadow of the Erdtree on the dance pad, and some players need help to pass the first boss using a standard controller. </p>



<p>Miss Mikka’s Shadow of the Erdtree journey lasted seven days, with 325 deaths (69 of them were thanks to all the falls). The last boss, Radahn, Consort of Miquella, was the biggest hurdle in her dance padding escapades, taking 52 tries and seven hours of dancing to take him down finally.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>I DID IT! ALL bosses of my dance pad Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree run have been deFEETed!</p><p>The last boss fell after 52 tries and 7 hours of dance-padding (my feet hurt). DLC took me 7 days in total with 325 deaths; 69 of them to gravity, nice.</p><p>I hope Miyazaki is proud of me. <a href="https://t.co/DqbgLxTCXz">pic.twitter.com/DqbgLxTCXz</a></p></div>— MissMikkaa (@MissMikkaa) <a href="https://twitter.com/MissMikkaa/status/1810415598108581941?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>MissMikka isn’t unfamiliar with the Elden Ring scene and has done several dance pad challenges with FromSoftware’s open-world RPG. The most notable was the <a href="https://x.com/MissMikkaa/status/1611104473698701313" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ultimate Challenge Run</a>, where she played two Elden Ring games simultaneously, one with a controller and the other with a dance. She had to kill bosses on the same try for both games, which was the most difficult aspect of this challenge. However, Miss Mikka could best Malena 3 days and 199 tries later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Players should know that Shadow of the Erdtree is no piece of cake. Players from all around have been complaining about difficulty, with the DLC feeling much more challenging than the base game. This makes beating the DLC with a dance pad much more astonishing and a testament to MissMikkaa’s perseverance. Now we wait for other players to finish their alt runs for Shadow of the Erdtree.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you found this run interesting, check out how this player beat Shadow of the Erdtree’s final boss <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtrees-final-boss-was-defeated-with-a-saxophone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">with a saxophone</a>. Also, a streamer is attempting to beat the game <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-streamer-brainwaves/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">using her brainwaves</a>. Can you beat Shadow of the Erdtree with a dance pad? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/piranha-bytes-senior-devs-form-new-studio-pithead-studio/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new studio formed by former Piranha Bytes senior devs</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroidvania game Frontier Hunter: Erza’s Wheel of Fortune launches July 26 for PS5, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/metroidvania-game-frontier-hunter-erzas-wheel-of-fortune-launches-july-26-for-ps5-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metroidvania-game-frontier-hunter-erza%E2%80%99s-wheel-of-fortune-launches-july-26-for-ps5-pc.922401/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/metroidvania-game-frontier-hunter-erzas-wheel-of-fortune-launches-july-26-for-ps5-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently in Early Access for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Metroidvania [156 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/metroidvania">Metroidvania game</a> <em><a title="Games > Frontier Hunter: Erza's Wheel of Fortune" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/frontier-hunter-erzas-wheel-of-fortune">Frontier Hunter: Erza’s Wheel of Fortune</a></em> will leave Early Access and launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,426 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,618 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1429500/Frontier_Hunter_Erzas_Wheel_of_Fortune/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/frontier-hunter-erzas-wheel-of-fortune" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/frontier_hunter_erzas_wheel_of_fortune" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOG</a> on July 26, developer <a title="Companies > IceSitruuna" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/icesitruuna">IceSitruuna</a> announced. <span id="more-897799"></span></p><p><em>Frontier Hunter: Erza’s Wheel of Fortune</em> first launched in Early Access for PC on December 15, 2022.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via IceSitruuna:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Frontier Hunter: Erza’s Wheel of Fortune</em> is a genuine Metroidvania game. Compared to our last work, <em>Tower Hunter: Erza’s Trial</em>, <em>Frontier Hunter: Erza’s Wheel of Fortune</em> has fuller stories, content, monsters, more exquisite scenes, smoother <a title="Genres > Action [1,996 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s, and a more diversified, personalized cultivation system. We’ll do our best to make the game construction more thorough and stable. Also, we’ll add more featured experience, gameplay, and content in future updates.</p><p>Two years ago, Erza obtained the legendary hunter license and became a rising star in the imperial force. Under the rule of the wise and able emperor, the empire grows steadily. As one of the core forces in the expansion, Erza has won many military exploits.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In this fantasy world of swords and magic, Erza will lead an exploration team and start an epic <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,606 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>. She will fight unknown monsters and solve mysteries of the world. Why would the fiend become a hair clip? You’ll find the answer in the game.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Classic <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [707 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> levels with steadier, smoother gameplay. Jump and dash can interrupt other actions’ recovery to get smoother responses.</li><li>During your exploration in the game world, you may find secret passages between the two main areas or accidentally enter unknown chambers with hidden stories.</li><li>Improved cartoon rendering makes the characters more lifelike.</li><li>Real <a title="Genres > Beat 'Em Up [98 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/beat-em-up">beat ’em up</a> combat system. Enemies have more ways to act after hit.</li><li>You’ll depend more on tactics when it comes to BOSS fights—learn their routines and act swiftly. Seize the chance to hit while keeping a distance.<br>With the character change and support system, Erza won’t be fighting alone.</li><li>2.5D exquisite scenes will surely make an impression on you. The ultimate skills are made in 3D, which enables cool shows that 2D can’t do.</li><li>With a more diversified, personalized cultivation system, you can choose your favorite way to raise characters and find more possibilities.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Frontier Hunter: Erza’s Wheel of Fortune Launch Trailer | PS5 &amp; STEAM &amp; EPIC &amp; GOG" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bd1YqXZnDD0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Retro-style adventure RPG Veritus for PC launches July 22]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/retro-style-adventure-rpg-veritus-for-pc-launches-july-22</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/retro-style-adventure-rpg-veritus-for-pc-launches-july-22.922398/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/retro-style-adventure-rpg-veritus-for-pc-launches-july-22<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Uncover the secrets hidden within the castle of Veritus.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Retro-style <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,606 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> <a title="Genres > RPG [16,413 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Veritus" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/veritus">Veritus</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,618 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2513580/Veritus/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 22 for $6.99, developer <a title="Companies > Colorgrave" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/colorgrave">Colorgrave</a> announced. <span id="more-897807"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Colorgrave:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Veritus</em> is a colorful adventure with the pixel-perfect aesthetic of a <a title="Platforms > Game Boy [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/game-boy">Game Boy</a> Color title. Journey into the dark chambers of the god of shadows, Veritus, and uncover the secrets hidden within his castle.</p><p>Face monsters and mysteries lurking around every corner as you collect resources and equipment to survive. Prepare to leave camp, navigate the castle’s lonely halls, and reveal the secrets dwelling within the throne room.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Explore the Castle</strong> – Discover the mysteries of the god of shadows. Navigate the treacherous corridors and chambers of Veritus’ forgotten castle and find key fragments to unlock secrets within the throne room.</li><li><strong>Puzzles and Combat</strong> – Overcome numerous dangers lurking in every corner of the castle’s hallowed walls. Use the weapons and tools at your disposal to defeat monsters and decipher puzzles that hinder your quest.</li><li><strong>Regroup</strong> – Set up camps in safe havens deep within the castle. Prepare for each adventure by equipping a variety of weapons and tools, going on expeditions with companions, and resting after each encounter.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Veritus - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O_sF3Yg-5lM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends’ new Battle Pass plans promise greater rewards, but for more of your real-world money]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-battle-pass-plans-promise-greater-rewards-but-for-more-of-your-real-world-money</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends%E2%80%99-new-battle-pass-plans-promise-greater-rewards-but-for-more-of-your-real-world-money.922380/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-battle-pass-plans-promise-greater-rewards-but-for-more-of-your-real-world-money<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>No more Apex Coin freebies</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Apex-Legends-season-20-Legend-Upgrades-Gameplay.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Ever since the hat was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tf2s-classless-udpate-hats-maps">invented by Valve Corporation in 2009</a>, mankind has grappled with questions of fairness, worthiness, and pride – at least as they pertain to microtransations in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-free-pc-games">free-to-play</a> games. Shooty battle royale  <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-best-guns-tier-list-weapon-stats">Apex Legends</a> is the latest to posit an answer, that being "the Battle Pass should cost more money".</p>
<!--more-->
<p>In a <a href="https://www.ea.com/en-gb/games/apex-legends/news/battle-pass-update">post</a> detailing BP-specific changes to expect in Apex’s upcoming Season 22, publishers EA announced that the Premium Battle Pass will, from Season 22 onward, only be sold for $10 in real-world cash – a major change from previous passes, that were buyable with in-game currency that could be earned through play. There’ll also be two separate Premium Battle Passes per season, taking the total cost per-season to $20. Cue outrage, the game’s <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/apexlegends/comments/1dyblr3/apex_legends_battle_pass_updates_season_22/">subreddit</a> filling in minutes with players announcing their immediate uninstall.</p>
<p>In fairness to the <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disgusted_of_Tunbridge_Wells">Disgusted of Tunbridge Wells</a> crowd, this change could represent a major price hike for regular players when Season 22 launches on August 6th. Previous Premium Battle Passes cost 950 Apex Coins, the aforementioned in-game currency, but by progressing through the pass’s tiers, you could eventually earn that amount back in rewards. Which could then be spent on the next season’s Battle Pass, and so on, potentially daisy-chaining BP purchases without ever needing to buy a fresh pile of Apex Coins with real money.</p>
<p>Now that the Premium Battle Pass is going cash-only, that self-funding cycling is broken, and what replaces it ain’t cheap. At $10 a pop, with two per season and usually four seasons in a year, that’s an annual cost of $80 – just four bucks shy of a standard Netflix sub. For skins and taunts. Yeesh.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, EA’s post argues that the new system will in fact "up the value" for players. While each individual Premium Battle Pass will only have 60 levels apiece, down from 110, when completed they’ll fork over more crafting materials and Apex Pack loot crates than previous passes did. And since there’ll be twice as many passes per season, one per 'split' (basically each half of the season), the total per-season haul of potential unlocks is effectively doubled. In the first two weeks of season 22, there’ll also be the one-off chance to unlock the first split’s Premium Battle Pass rewards for free, by completing "a set of challenges".</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/apex-legends-aerith-skin.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>EA/Respawn Entertainment</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>That’s cool and all – more crafting materials is a good way to gain the specific unlockables you want, offsetting the randomness of Apex Packs – but even as someone whose interest in Apex Legends was only <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-season-20s-skill-trees-see-the-battle-royale-take-a-surprising-moba-turn">recently rekindled</a>, I wouldn’t pay ten quid for even twice as many cosmetics. Not when I’ve spent the past five years getting Battle Passes who what felt like nada.</p>
<p>Such reticence has, it must be said, likely been calculated by EA. Like January’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-crossover-arrives-on-january-9th">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth crossover</a> event, and its $360 deathbox skin, this whole thing smacks of an appeal to <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0306460321000368">whales</a> – dedicated big spenders who’ll pay up regardless. Meanwhile, more numerous but also more frugal players are considered acceptable losses. Which from a purely business-y standpoint, is a logical enough plan for F2P games that are already facing a dwindling playerbase.</p>
<p>From a player standpoint, though... hmmmmm. We can get as snooty as we want about the cosmetic-based concept of Battle Passes, but it’s a fact that they incentivise play, through the simple pleasures of seeing a level counter tick up as much as the desire for the cosmetics themselves. Erecting a higher paywall for them can and will remove this source of progression, and with it, the ability to feel like you’re getting wins even when you’re eating shit in the actual arena. That’s surely not good for Apex Legends’ health, even if it does prove good for its coffers.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom blamed for 40% drop in US hardware sales this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-blamed-for-40-drop-in-us-hardware-sales-this-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-blamed-for-40-drop-in-us-hardware-sales-this-year.922377/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-blamed-for-40-drop-in-us-hardware-sales-this-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Ghost of Tsushima best-selling US game in May.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tears-of-the-Kingdom-Link-holds-the-Master-Sword.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nintendo</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Video game hardware spending in the US was down 40 percent in May compared to 2023, numbers company Circana reports.</p>
<p>Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S sales all saw "double-digit percentage declines year-on-year" comparing figures up to May, "with Switch showing the most significant drop", according to the company's boss and industry analyst Mat Piscatella.</p>
<p>PlayStation 5 was the top selling console in units and dollar sales in May. The console's unit sales lead those of PlayStation 4 by eight percent.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FQg2NCp1bQU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The decline wasn't just for hardware sales. Spending on game "content" - ie. games and in-game currency and items - also fell three percent compared to a year ago. Meanwhile, spending on gaming accessories also dropped eight percent compared to last year. PlayStation Portal was the best selling accessory in May. </p>
<p>Ghost of Tsushima was the best selling game in the US for May. Previously a PlayStation console exclusive, its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-df-weekly-ghost-of-tsushima-on-pc-is-another-excellent-nixxes-port">PC port launched</a>, and quickly became <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ghost-of-tsushima-is-playstations-fourth-biggest-pc-launch-to-date">PlayStation's biggest single-player PC launch in terms of concurrent players</a>.</p>
<p>Fortnite has maintained its popularity, with the free-to-play game boasting the highest number of active users across PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S in May. A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/70-of-developers-concerned-about-sustainability-of-live-service-games-new-study-suggests">recent study highlighted the prevalence of free-to-play games and their sustainability</a>, with these new sales figures proving their continued popularity above new full releases.</p>
<p>"Projected US total spending on video game hardware, content and accessories fell six percent in May 2024 when compared to a year ago," Piscatella said.
</p>
<p>According to Piscatella, this comparative yearly decline can be attributed - at least in part - to last year's arrival of The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom, released on Nintendo Switch in May 2023. On its launch, Tears of the Kingdom sold over 10m units worldwide in just three days, making it the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-fasted-selling-game-in-series-over-10m-units-sold-worldwide-in-three-days">fastest selling Zelda release to date</a>.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">May 2024 U.S. Video Game Market Highlights from Circana - Projected U.S. total spending on video game hardware, content and accessories fell 6% in May 2024 when compared to a year ago, to $4.0 billion. Year-to-date 2024 spending was 2% higher than a year ago, at $22.8 billion. <a href="https://t.co/QtKko05BoI">pic.twitter.com/QtKko05BoI</a></p>— Mat Piscatella (@MatPiscatella) <a href="https://twitter.com/MatPiscatella/status/1810377988434964526?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Nintendo, Sony and Microsoft are all set to launch new hardware in the not too distant future.</p>
<p>Last month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-reveals-three-new-xbox-console-variants">Microsoft revealed three new Xbox console variants</a> with increased storage capacity, which will be available at the end of the year in select markets. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-df-weekly-new-ps5-pro-gpu-details-emerge-including-a-235ghz-max-boost-clock">Sony is also reportedly planning to release a PS5 'Pro' console</a>, which will run games at 60fps with ray-tracing.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Nintendo has said it will announce the Switch's successor - dubbed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-everything-we-know">Switch 2</a> - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-makes-first-switch-2-announcement">later this financial year</a>, before March 31st 2025. It's expected to be actually <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-release-date-now-q1-2025-report">released at some point in 2025</a>.</p>
<p>Each platform has a number of bigger video game releases still to come this year, as well, with the likes of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-finally-playable-in-the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom">Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom arriving on Switch</a> this September, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-announces-new-astrobot-game">Astro Bot coming to PS5 also in September</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indy-heads-to-the-himalayas-in-new-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-teaser">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle slated for a 2024 debut</a> on Xbox and PC.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball Kakarot Next DLC Name Discovered In Game’s Latest Update]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dragon-ball-kakarot-next-dlc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-kakarot-next-dlc-name-discovered-in-game%E2%80%99s-latest-update.922374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dragon-ball-kakarot-next-dlc/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The name of the next Dragon Ball Kakarot DLC has been discovered in the game files, revealing how it will be based on the next iteration of the franchise.</p>
<p>As reported by Josou Kitsune on<a href="https://x.com/Josou_Kit/status/1810164580615590381" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> X/Twitter</a>, the game's latest update, which introduced a new side quest, includes in its files references to its next DLC expansion. Unlike what most expected, the next expansion won't be based on Dragon Ball GT or Dragon Ball Super, but on Dragon Ball Daima, a new anime series, and Akira Toriyama's last work, which is set to release this Fall.</p>
<p>Dragon Ball Kakarot proved to be rather successful on the market, so much so that Bandai Namco decided to continue supporting the game well past its first round of DLC expansions. Even without additional content, the game is well worth the time of any fan of the series, despite some issues, as it is an accurate recreation of the Dragon Ball Z story, as we highlighted in our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dragon-ball-z-kakarot-authentic-ambitious-adequate/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot is a mixed bag. If you're a Dragon Ball fan, this game will offer so many nice moments and make you occasionally beam from ear to ear. But then during exploration and combat, things quickly become tedious. At full price, it's hard to recommend this game, but when it becomes affordable in a sale, it'll be hard for fans to resist.</em></p>
<p>Dragon Ball Kakarot is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Descendant Hotfix Will Add Much-Requested Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-hotfix-will-add-much-requested-feature</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-descendant-hotfix-will-add-much-requested-feature.922368/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-hotfix-will-add-much-requested-feature<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant</a> developer Nexon has signaled the game will get one of the most-requested features since launch.</p><p>The free-to-play co-op focused looter shooter has progression systems that fuel a deep-rooted grind that in turn encourages players to jump into repeatable missions on hard mode in order to have a better chance of obtaining materials.</p><p>Currently, the only hard mode content with no matchmaking is Infiltration Operations. Hard mode on these Infiltration Operations offers an improved drop chance for certain loot, which means players are inclined to play them on hard rather than normal difficulty. But without matchmaking, you're forced to play Infiltration Operations on hard mode solo, which for some players isn't doable or, at the least, slows them down.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/09/gsarayta8aafvf5-1720519652185.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Infiltration Operations are repeatable dungeons that currently do not have matchmaking on hard mode. Image credit: Nexon.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Now, Nexon has said a hotfix is incoming that includes "matchmaking for public Infiltration Operation (Dungeon) on Hard Mode." The news has certainly gone down well with fans who have praised the developer for acting quickly on feedback. “Kudos to the dev team, brilliant decision,” said redditor <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheFirstDescendant/comments/1dyqxfh/comment/lcas3ic/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sufficient_Theory534</a>. “This will increase the longevity of the game exponentially.”</p><p>While Nexon is adding this much-requested feature, it has remained quiet on a number of controversies that have hit The First Descendant since it came out. For example, the company has yet to address <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-enjoys-big-player-numbers-on-steam-despite-microtransaction-hell">The First Descendant’s ultra aggressive monetization</a>, nor has it explained <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-hit-with-destiny-icon-plagiarism-accusations-but-theres-seemingly-more-to-the-story">the remarkable similarities between icons used in The First Descendant and Bungie’s rival looter shooter, Destiny</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The First Descendant Screenshots </h3></div></output><p>Still, The First Descendant is pulling in players, with a peak Steam concurrent player count of 264,860 so far — enough to break into the top five most-played games on Valve’s platform. Microsoft and Sony do not provide player numbers for PlayStation and Xbox. Check out IGN's <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-first-descendant"><u>The First Descendant review in progress</u></a> to find out what we think of the game so far.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Descendant Hit With Destiny Icon Plagiarism Accusations — but There’s Seemingly More to the Story]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-hit-with-destiny-icon-plagiarism-accusations-but-theres-seemingly-more-to-the-story</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-descendant-hit-with-destiny-icon-plagiarism-accusations-%E2%80%94-but-there%E2%80%99s-seemingly-more-to-the-story.922365/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-hit-with-destiny-icon-plagiarism-accusations-but-theres-seemingly-more-to-the-story<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Licence to steal.</h2></div><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant</a>, a free-to-play co-op focused looter shooter from Korean games company Nexon, is blowing up across PC and console with big player numbers on Steam specifically. But as players debate the rights and wrongs of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-enjoys-big-player-numbers-on-steam-despite-microtransaction-hell">its ultra aggressive monetization</a>, another controversy has hit the game.</p><p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/07/07/the-first-descendant-is-using-barely-changed-destiny-2-icons/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Forbes</a> reported that The First Descendant “is using barely-changed” Destiny 2 icons, and pointed to the remarkable similarities between icons used by developer Bungie for its veteran looter shooter and those used by Nexon for its new looter shooter challenger.</p><p>Certainly, the similarities are hard to ignore. One Bungie icon artist tweeted to say it “feels like a great day to mention that Bungie icon artists are a super-crew of talented folks with original ideas and sharp instincts.” But what’s actually happened here?</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">‘The First Descendant’ Is Using Barely-Changed ‘Destiny 2’ Icons via <a href="https://twitter.com/Forbes?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@forbes</a> <a href="https://t.co/rGdbfKNfJX" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/rGdbfKNfJX</a> <a href="https://t.co/gGKfoTkLk9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/gGKfoTkLk9</a></p>— Paul Tassi (@PaulTassi) <a href="https://twitter.com/PaulTassi/status/1809996852391293440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 7, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>While Nexon is under pressure to explain itself (IGN has asked for comment but has yet to hear a response), fans have unearthed evidence to suggest the root of the problem can be found in an icon database that seems to misunderstand the concepts of personal and commercial use of assets.</p><p>Iconduck bills itself as a “free and open-source” database of hundreds of thousands of icons, illustrations, emojis, logos, and flags, and includes a number of Destiny icons Nexon may have lifted for use in The First Descendant.</p><p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/third-person-shooter/the-first-descendant-contains-icons-from-destiny-2-and-one-theory-about-how-they-got-there-is-a-reminder-that-not-everything-on-the-internet-is-what-it-purports-to-be/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PC Gamer</a>, Iconduck has a <a href="https://iconduck.com/sets/destiny-icons" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Destiny Icons set</a> that includes 204 icons, all open sourced with a Creative Commons Zero v1.0 Universal license. “All icons can be used for personal and commercial purposes,” Iconduck claims.</p><p>This icon set was designed by Tom Chapman, who made the Bray.tech websites among others for Destiny 2. In a <a href="https://x.com/BraytechHelp/status/1810114495936864717" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet</a>, Chapman said most of the icons in the set were “ripped from the font files created by Bungie and its designers.”</p><p>“Most of the remainder are designed by Bungie and recreated by me or whoever contributed them to that repo,” Chapman added, before casting doubt on Iconduck itself: “I've come to hate open source…  I don't want @iamiconduck to use my work like this.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The First Descendant Screenshots </h3></div></output><p>It’s worth pointing out that Iconduck also makes available icons from the Pokémon franchise, including Pikachu and Poké Balls, Marvel Avengers icons, famous Batman icons, and plenty more images you’d imagine Iconduck wouldn’t have the rights to make available for people to use for commercial purposes.</p><p>There are many other icon databases that include similar sets and make similar claims of their use. Nexon may well have used icons from one of these websites, such as Iconduck, and tweaked them slightly for The First Descendant, but the company has yet to explain its process. If it did, Nexon would then face pressure to explain <em>why</em> it did. Again, IGN has asked for comment.</p><p>The First Descendant rekindles memories of <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/palworld">Palworld</a>, Pocketpair’s controversial ‘Pokémon with guns’ survival and crafting game that has been accused of “ripping off” ‘Pokémon, but has also been compared gameplay wise to all sorts of titles in the survival and crafting genre.</p><p>Generally speaking, The First Descendant is a mash-up of mechanics from various looter shooters already in the market. There’s more than a whiff of Destiny about The First Descendant’s design, systems, and mechanics, but then there’s also a lot of Warframe about it, too. Check out IGN's <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-first-descendant"><u>The First Descendant review in progress</u></a> to find out what we think of the game so far.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 3 mod adds character customisation and magic-wielding sorceress class]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-3-mod-adds-character-customisation-and-magic-wielding-sorceress-class</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-3-mod-adds-character-customisation-and-magic-wielding-sorceress-class.922356/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-3-mod-adds-character-customisation-and-magic-wielding-sorceress-class<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Finally, playable Yennefer!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/yennefer-witcher3-closeup.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>CD Projekt Red</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
An impressive new mod for The Witcher 3 lets players customise their own character and even wield magic as a sorceress.
</p>
<p>
Modder nikich340 has been working on the <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/witcher3/mods/5940">Custom Player Characters mod</a> for two-and-a-half years and it's now available on NexusMods (thanks <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/witcher-3-mod-lets-you-play-as-fully-customizable-witcher-or-sorceress-with-new-magic-combat-system">IGN</a>).

</p>
<p>
The mod allows players to create a custom character instead of protagonist Geralt, choosing between a Witcher, a Witcheress, and even a Sorceress with a new magic combat system and questline.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FQg2NCp1bQU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>

While it's not a full character creator in the traditional sense, the mod essentially takes body elements from all NPCs and allows players to mix and match to style their own character.
</p>
<p>
Players can then choose between three classes. The Witcher will play the same as Geralt, while the Witcheress is the same but with a female character. So yes, you could re-skin the character as Ciri for the entire game, or a more custom character.
</p>
<p>
Perhaps most interesting, though, is the Sorceress class, which not only includes a brand new magic combat system but a unique questline to unlock skills. Yes, that means you can finally play through The Witcher 3 as Yennefer (or Triss, if you really must).
</p>
<p>
Oh, and on top of blasting enemies with lightning, you can transform into a cat!
</p>
<p>
Animations have been tweaked for female characters, plus - through a separate mod - female voice lines can be added in.
</p>
<p>
In short, it's a very cool mod that will satisfy wish fulfilment for some players looking for a Geralt alternative. You can see it all in action in the video below.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Witcher 3 &quot;Custom Player Characters&quot; Mod" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yCDwEWKvDoA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Witcher 3 "Custom Player Characters" Mod</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yCDwEWKvDoA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/yCDwEWKvDoA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Witcher 3 "Custom Player Characters" Mod<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yCDwEWKvDoA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The mod arrives shortly after the release of REDkit, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/witcher-3-mod-editor-gets-official-steam-release-this-month">The Witcher 3's official mod editor that's now available for all on Steam</a>.

</p>
<p>
As for what's next from The Witcher team, CD Projekt Red confirmed the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cd-projekt-red-confirms-new-witcher-medallion-is-a-lynx">medallion in its tease of the next game is from the Lynx School</a> - but what could that mean?


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Gaming for Amazon Fire TV Launches Today]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-gaming-for-amazon-fire-tv-launches-today/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-gaming-for-amazon-fire-tv-launches-today.922353/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-gaming-for-amazon-fire-tv-launches-today/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Microsoft has announced that Xbox Gaming is now available on Amazon Fire Sticks through the Xbox TV App. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-gaming-is-coming-to-amazon-fire-tv-devices-in-july-2024/">A few weeks ago</a>, Xbox announced that it would bring cloud gaming to select Fire Sticks in limited counties for Xbox Game Pass Ultimate members. </p>



<p>The service is live in 25 countries, and users with Fire TV Stick 4K Max (2023) and Fire TV Stick 4K (2023) can now download the app on their devices. Learn how to set up Xbox TV App on your Amazon Fire TV stick and fire up your games.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-setting-up-xbox-gaming-on-amazon-fire-tv">Setting Up Xbox Gaming on Amazon Fire TV</h2>



<p>If you have an Amazon Fire TV, you can download the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/apps/xbox-app-for-tv?ocid=Platform_soc_omc_xbo_tw_Video_lrn_7.8.1#asterisk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox TV </a>app from the store. Sign in with your Microsoft account and ensure you have an active Xbox Game Pass Ultimate Membership. Then, connect a wireless controller. You can use the Xbox Wireless Controller, Xbox Adaptive Controller, PlayStation DualSense, or DualShock 4 controller.</p>



<h2 id="h-games-you-can-try-first">Games You Can Try First </h2>



<p>Once you’re all set up, you’ll have access to a wide range of games through the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-IN/xbox-game-pass/ultimate" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Game Pass Ultimate </a>membership. Whether you’re into action-packed adventures like Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II, open-world exploration in Starfield, high-speed racing in Forza Horizon 5, or the post-apocalyptic thrill of Fallout 76 and Fallout 4, there’s something for everyone. Plus, free-to-play games like Fortnite are also on the menu.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Xbox TV app on the Amazon Fire Stick provides an economical and convenient means to enjoy your preferred games. The stick’s compact size makes it an excellent choice for on-the-go gaming, as long as you have a reliable internet connection and a display available. Furthermore, you can instantly start playing without downloading games onto the device.</p>



<p>In other news, Amazon is giving away <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazon-free-games-prime-gaming/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">15 free games for Prime Day</a>. Also, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-activision-august/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Activision Games</a> are arriving on Xbox Game Pass next month. Are you going to try out Xbox Gaming on Amazon Fire TV? Let us know in the comments. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, read what&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sketch-confirms-of-leaks-real-stream/">Sketch said about the recent OnlyFans leaks</a>&nbsp;and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends Season 22 is doubling up on paid battle passes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/09/apex-legends-season-22-is-doubling-up-on-paid-battle-passes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-season-22-is-doubling-up-on-paid-battle-passes.922350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/09/apex-legends-season-22-is-doubling-up-on-paid-battle-passes/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a> Season 22 is bringing big changes to how battle passes and rewards are doled out to players, with developer Respawn Entertainment announcing that each season will now have two shorter battle passes in place of one, and that they’re removing the ability to use the premium in-game currency to buy them. As you’d expect, the community is in uproar over the effective price hike to premium battle passes for the free-to-play shooter.</p>
<p>From Season 22 in August, Apex Legends will now have two half-season battle passes, one of which will be available at the start of the season and the second then at the season’s “split” in the middle. Each will have 60 levels of rewards for a total of 120, which is an increase to the previous system’s 110 rewards, and will mean that there’s a reduced grind to reach the end-tier rewards and the most special skins.</p>


<p>However, this comes at a cost. There will still be a free battle pass reward track, but each half-season premium battle pass will cost $9.99 USD in real currency, effectively doubling the price where a premium battle pass previously cost 950 Apex Coins. Those were available as part of a 1000 coin bundle priced at $9.99 USD, or could be earned through playing and completing a previous battle pass, making it a reward for your continued engagement and keeping the servers stocked with players.</p>
<p>In addition to a standard premium pass, the new ‘Premium+’ tier will replace the existing ‘Premium Bundle’. This costs $19.99, has 10 level skips and double the Exotic Shards, as well as special Premium+ character skin variants and grants access to all characters through a battle pass’s duration. Over the course of a full season that works out to $40 compared to 2800 Apex Coins (coin bundles available in 2150 for $20 or 4350 for $40), though Respawn are saying that “The decision to move from AC to real-world currency is not one that we made lightly, but it does allow us to decrease the price of Premium+ for our community.”</p>
<p>Yes, a “decrease”.</p>

<p>One element that’s not clear is how long battle passes will be available for. Will the first pass of a season expire at the “split”, or be valid through to the end of a season? Each pass has roughly half the rewards, but there’s also potentially half the amount of time in which to complete them, which will mean there’s still that&nbsp;fear of missing out (FOMO) and grinding to reach the final tier rewards.</p>
<p>This has obviously gone down like a lead balloon with the fanbase, in large part for effectively doubling the cost, but it has also called into question how healthy Apex Legends is as a game, if EA is resorting to this kind of tactic. It’s equivalent to how Netflix, Disney+ or PS Plus have increased price over time, as their ability to draw in new subscribers has tapered off, as a way to boost quarterly revenues. EA will be gambling that having more battle passes will mean that devout players will spend more, making up for any players that are pushed away from spending or playing by this decision.</p>
<p>There’s another side to this, though, which is that having more shorter battle passes in general (free and paid) shortens the cadence of play and engagement that seasonal structures have. Instead of having that big refresh every 3 months, it’s now ever 1.5 months, which they will hope will help to even out the peaks and troughs that they might currently be seeing.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/news/battle-pass-update">Apex Legends</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Go fans in China celebrate as game briefly available - before the country is blocked again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-fans-in-china-celebrate-as-game-briefly-available-before-the-country-is-blocked-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-go-fans-in-china-celebrate-as-game-briefly-available-before-the-country-is-blocked-again.922347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-fans-in-china-celebrate-as-game-briefly-available-before-the-country-is-blocked-again<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Apparent glitch also saw Russia gameplay return.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pokemon-Go-Inbound-From-Ultra-Space-Header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Niantic</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Chinese and Russian Pokémon Go players have reported a brief window of regular gameplay this week - despite long-standing geo-blocking that typically makes the game inaccessible across most of these regions. 
</p>
<p>
Reports collated on top Pokémon Go reddit <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheSilphRoad/comments/1dxy6x6/pogo_in_mainland_china_so_pogo_got_ungeoblocked/">TheSilphRoad</a> show players able to send in-game postcards from Beijing's Tiananmen Square, site of the 1989 student protest and massacre now subject to strict censorship by the country's government. 
</p>
<p>
For years, Pokémon Go has been unplayable in large swathes of China - and various tourists have recorded their experiences trying to load the smartphone game when visiting. No Pokémon will appear to catch, and no locations will appear on the map.
</p>
<p>
This changed, briefly, on Sunday evening, as an apparent glitch brought the game back to life across the country. 
</p>
<p>
In Russia, where developer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-will-suspend-gameplay-in-russia-belarus">Niantic suspended Pokémon Go gameplay in March 2022</a>, the same glitch saw gameplay return there too. 
</p>
<p>
Intriguingly, in-game locations remain in Niantic's database for both of these countries - although it seems unlikely either will return normally any time soon. 
</p>
<p>
"We stand with the global community in hoping for peace and a rapid resolution to the violence and suffering in Ukraine," developer Niantic wrote in a statement published via X in 2022.
</p>
<p>
"Niantic's games are no longer available for download in Russia and Belarus, and gameplay will also be suspended there shortly."
</p>
<p>
Niantic declined to comment on Sunday's brief window of gameplay when contacted by Eurogamer. 
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-looks-to-be-adding-fuse-mechanic-as-necrozma-confirmed-for-go-fest">Pokémon Go's biggest event of the year, Go Fest 2024</a>, is scheduled for this weekend - with the general release of Mythical Pokémon Marshadow one of its rewards. Beyond that, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-looks-set-to-add-gen-8s-dynamax-mechanic">game looks set to finally go big on Pokémon's eighth generation of monsters</a>, including the likely arrival of Dynamax.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swedish game industry wants video games recognised as 'cultural canon']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/swedish-game-industry-wants-video-games-recognised-as-cultural-canon-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/swedish-game-industry-wants-video-games-recognised-as-cultural-canon.922341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/swedish-game-industry-wants-video-games-recognised-as-cultural-canon-<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Swedish video game trade association, Dataspelsbranschen, has selected 15 titles it believes should be added to the country's "cultural canon" to improve recognition of the artform.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The list includes classic and contemporary titles such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Stugan</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>BackPacker</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ground Control</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minecraft</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Amnesia: The Dark Descent</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">,</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> It Takes Two,</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sayonara Wild Hearts</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It was curated by a panel of expert historians, industry leaders, and academics following hundreds of nominations from the general public. Dataspelsbranschen has released the list after Sweden's minister for culture Parisa Liljestrand laid out plans to develop an official culture canon.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Although Liljestrand didn't specific which artforms would be included in that canon, Dataspelsbranschen began developing one for video games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Games should be recognised as culture for several reasons: games are culture to the players, who relate to them similar ways as audiences in other art forms," said Dataspelsbranschen spokesperson Per Stromback.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Games are culture to the game developers who have the same drivers as other creators: the will to express, create something new and communicate with their audience. Games are also culture to society as they reflect the world we live in and have a rich history which is now being recognised by museums and other institutions. Also games are unique in that they are interactive. For these reasons, we think it is fitting that games have a canon too."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Dataspelsbranschen noted its list has been released at a time when national game industries are fighting for economic and cultural recognition, and calls for video game preservation growing ever louder.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The full list can be found below:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Stugan, Developed by: Kimmo Eriksson, Viggo Kann, Olle E Johansson, 1978/1986</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">BackPacker, Developed by: Tati Mixedia, 1995</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Europa Universalis, Developed by: Paradox Interactive, 2000</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ground Control, Developed by: Massive Entertainment, 2000</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Battlefield 1942, Developed by: DICE, (Digital Illusions CE) 2002</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Amnesia–The Dark Descent, Developed by: Frictional Games, 2010</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Minecraft, Developed by: Mojang, 2011</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Toca Tea Party, Developed by: Toca Boca, 2011</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Candy Crush Saga, Developed by: King, 2012</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Star Stable Online, Developed by: Star Stable Entertainment, 2012</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Goat Simulator, Developed by: Coffee Stain Studios, 2014</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Battle of Polytopia, Developed by: Midjiwan, 2016</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Budget Cuts, Developed by: Neat Corporation, 2018</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sayonara Wild Hearts, Developed by: Simogo, 2019</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It Takes Two, Developed by: Hazelight, 2021</span></p></div></li></ul></div></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embracer reportedly close down cult RPG maker Piranha Bytes, creators of Gothic, Risen, and Elex]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embracer-reportedly-close-down-cult-rpg-maker-piranha-bytes-creators-of-gothic-risen-and-elex</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/embracer-reportedly-close-down-cult-rpg-maker-piranha-bytes-creators-of-gothic-risen-and-elex.922335/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embracer-reportedly-close-down-cult-rpg-maker-piranha-bytes-creators-of-gothic-risen-and-elex<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Former head opens a new studio</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/pirahna-bytes-studio-gothic-closed-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>THQ Nordic</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>The studio-killing fallout of Embracer's acquisition frenzy continues to fall like ash on the industry. The publishing giant has reportedly closed Piranha Bytes, the studio known for cult RPGs like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/gothic">Gothic</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/risen">Risen</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elex">Elex</a>, according to a worker who spoke to Polish games site <a href="https://www.cdaction.pl/newsy/piranha-bytes-zamkniete-to-koniec-tworcow-gothica">CD-Action</a>. The studio's existence had been under threat since early this year, after being targeted in Embracer's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embracer-group-to-close-studios-and-cancel-games-as-part-of-restructuring">purgatorial studio massacre</a>. At that time the German studio were hopeful to avoid being closed down, insisting <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/piranha-bytes-devs-of-gothic-and-elex-are-next-on-embracers-chopping-block">"don't write us off yet!"</a> Unfortunately, it looks like those who worked at the studio have since been laid off.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The former head of Piranha Bytes, Björn Pankratz, confirmed the news on a Discord server for Pithead Studio, a newly established games company co-founded with his wife, Jenny Pankratz.</p>
<p>"As you sure noticed, the gaming industry was not doing well last year," says a message in the Discord,  as spotted by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/embracer-has-reportedly-closed-elex-developer-piranha-bytes-as-former-creative-director-announces-a-new-indie-studio/">PC Gamer</a>. "This was also the case for the Embracer Group, to which THQ Nordic and Piranha Bytes belong. A lot of studios had to close, thousands of people in the gaming industry worldwide lost their jobs. Sadly, Piranha Bytes was also affected by this."</p>
<p>Images in the CD-Action report also show the <a href="https://www.cdaction.pl/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.cdaction.pl%2Fimages%2F2024%2F07%2F08%2F47e10678-9580-460e-8a37-46151afd5289.jpeg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75">Piranha Bytes offices</a> in a state of relative abandonment, with unused desks, chairs and lamps piled up in a room. </p>
<p>The RPGs of Piranha Bytes were known for being somewhat janky but spirited. Gothic was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gothic-retrospective">more believable than modern RPGs</a>, according to Sin. The Risen games had <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/risen-2-review">"heart and soul"</a> even if they were sometimes wobbly, said Alec once upon a time. And although Elex II was not Alice B's cup of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elex-ii-prevew-a-weird-science-fantasy-rpg-that-doesnt-care-about-you-at-all">sci-fi lizard battering</a>, she could still clearly see why people would gel with it. </p>
<p>As brands, Gothic, Risen and Elex still belong to publisher THQ Nordic (owned by Embracer), according to another message on the Pithead Studio Discord. But it's hard for even those who spent their lives working on these games to know whether the franchises will continue in any meaningful way in the future.</p>
<p>"All we know is that Alkimia Interactive from [Spain] is working on [a] Gothic Remake," say Pithead. "We are not included in the making of the remake in any form, and therefore have no influence on it."</p>
<p>The closures brought about by Embracer have greatly impacted the industry, putting a huge number of people out of work, and killing dead a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-embracers-cuts-killed-a-potential-red-faction-sequel-and-gutted-a-promising-studio">potential Red Faction sequel</a>. They say <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embracer-say-their-restructure-is-over-but-its-too-early-to-start-acquiring-studios-again">their "restructuring programme" is over</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark strategy game Anoxia Station is Dwarf Fortress for oil drillers with a squirming helping of body horror]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dark-strategy-game-anoxia-station-is-dwarf-fortress-for-oil-drillers-with-a-squirming-helping-of-body-horror</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-strategy-game-anoxia-station-is-dwarf-fortress-for-oil-drillers-with-a-squirming-helping-of-body-horror.922332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dark-strategy-game-anoxia-station-is-dwarf-fortress-for-oil-drillers-with-a-squirming-helping-of-body-horror<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_4KUfwoG.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Abylight Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>I gaze with alarm and approval upon the recent phenomenon of "dark <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy</a>" or "horror strategy" games, a devilish parade of top-down drag-clickers, from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-fabulous-fear-machine-out-today-is-a-strategy-game-of-engrossing-evil">The Fabulous Fear Machine</a> to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/out-now-in-early-access-the-tribe-must-survive-is-frostpunk-for-people-who-love-being-afraid-of-the-dark">The Tribe Must Survive</a>, that strive to find the fear in a genre that typically places you at a managerial remove. The best-known is probably <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/frostpunk">Frostpunk</a>, with its perpetual raging against the dying of the light, its ceaseless scrape for coal and wood as the temperature falls. Anoxia Station, announced this month, is similarly driven by the gathering of fossil fuels, and similarly shaped by questions of worker death and morale, but it takes you deep underground - into a sumptuous, brutal world of quartz crystals, salt caves, magma lakes, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moonmilk">moonmilk</a> rivers, swirling gases and, judging from the below trailer, enormous maggots and centipedes. Larva lakes, amirite.</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Anoxia Station reveal teaser trailer | Coming 2025" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/W0z4EoMuTHQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Anoxia Station reveal teaser trailer | Coming 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/W0z4EoMuTHQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/W0z4EoMuTHQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W0z4EoMuTHQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Anoxia Station is set in 1988, but not the 1988 you may remember. The Earth's surface has been devastated by a supervolcano and, in a shocking display of wildcard speculative world-building, humanity is now dependent on petroleum for survival. You take charge of a group of Terranauts, sent into the guts of a festering world in search of a fabled ocean of oil. You'll excavate a path to this mega-deposit, sector by sector. Along the way, you'll need to extract smaller pockets of oil for the benefit of the world above, expand your mining facilities and keep your (irreplaceable) crew alive, sane and at peace with each other. </p>
<p>This is easier said than done, because this is 1988, the height of the Cold War, and your miners hail from different sides of various Iron Curtains - there are people from the Soviet Union, the United States, the German Democratic Republic and Japan, among others. Some are enemies within who have hidden agendas, others just hate each other instinctively. You'll have to look after all of them, regardless. "Crewmen might become despicable, but if they fall, entire production lines might be extinguished, spelling hardship, if not death for the whole mission," explains <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2924310/Anoxia_Station/">the Steam page</a>. Sounds challenging! And that's before we start talking about those massive insectile lifeforms, which look like they've wriggled out of the catacombs of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/scorn">Scorn</a>. The Steam page trails off ominously here.</p>
<p>Anoxia Station has "a uniquely isometric style grounded in real physical processes", with audio design that consists of "a mix of the deafening roars of shifting rock, the harsh sounds of mining and welding, the distant clicking of something clearly inhuman, and a familiar scream". It's the work of Yakov Butuzoff, whose other works include visual novel Loretta, with Abylight Studios publishing. There's no release date yet.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twitch streamer MissMikkaa completes Elden Ring DLC Shadow of the Erdtree on a dance mat]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/twitch-streamer-missmikkaa-completes-elden-ring-dlc-shadow-of-the-erdtree-on-a-dance-mat</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/twitch-streamer-missmikkaa-completes-elden-ring-dlc-shadow-of-the-erdtree-on-a-dance-mat.922329/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/twitch-streamer-missmikkaa-completes-elden-ring-dlc-shadow-of-the-erdtree-on-a-dance-mat<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"I hope Miyazaki is proud of me."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ER_SOTE_screenshot-(9).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Twitch streamer MissMikkaa has completed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-tips-and-tricks">Elden Ring DLC</a> Shadow of the Erdtree with a dance mat controller.
</p>
<p>
Fans of the streamer won't be surprised by this news, after Mikkaa previously not only <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/twitch-streamer-dancing-through-elden-ring-with-a-dance-pad">completed the base game on a customised dance mat</a>, but played <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/twitch-streamer-defeats-elden-rings-malenia-in-dance-pad-and-controller-simultaneous-challenge-run">two games simultaneously on dance mat and controller</a>.

</p>
<p>
Of course, the release of Shadow of the Erdtree means she's back at it. And, after a week of dancing, she's completed the DLC. There's a video of the feat below so <strong>spoiler warning</strong>.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ELDEN RING Shadow of the Erdtree | Official Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bGFvUgQyJ00?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ELDEN RING Shadow of the Erdtree | Official Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bGFvUgQyJ00?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bGFvUgQyJ00?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree launch trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bGFvUgQyJ00" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>

"I did it! ALL bosses of my dance pad Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree run have been deFEETed!" she posted on X, formerly Twitter.
</p>
<p>
"The last boss fell after 52 tries and 7 hours of dance-padding (my feet hurt). DLC took me 7 days in total with 325 deaths; 69 of them to gravity, nice. I hope Miyazaki is proud of me."
</p>
<p>
A video alongside the post shows the streamer defeating the final boss, so <strong> final spoiler warning</strong>. "I'm so tired," she says at the end, collapsing to the ground. I'm not surprised.
</p>
<p>And when so many players are debating whether the DLC is too difficult, here's a streamer finishing perhaps the ultimate challenge. A true expert!</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>I DID IT! ALL bosses of my dance pad Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree run have been deFEETed!</p><p>The last boss fell after 52 tries and 7 hours of dance-padding (my feet hurt). DLC took me 7 days in total with 325 deaths; 69 of them to gravity, nice.</p><p>I hope Miyazaki is proud of me. <a href="https://t.co/DqbgLxTCXz">pic.twitter.com/DqbgLxTCXz</a></p></div>— MissMikkaa (@MissMikkaa) <a href="https://twitter.com/MissMikkaa/status/1810415598108581941?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>

As we previously reported, the release of Shadow of the Erdtree has meant <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/streamers-continue-to-play-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-in-weird-and-wonderful-ways">the return of streamers playing the game in weird ways</a>. That includes Perrikaryal who's playing through the game with mind control - she's now defeated Messmer, which is hugely impressive.

</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>WE FINALLY DID IT </p><p>Shadow of the Erdtree boss, Messmer the Impaler, DEFEATED with mind control, and ZERO HANDS. </p><p>This took so long and it was SO hard; I've never had such good training for the EEG game controller.</p><p>If you have any questions, look at the full VOD below - I do… <a href="https://t.co/izLiQfPMu7">pic.twitter.com/izLiQfPMu7</a></p></div>— Perri (@perrikaryal) <a href="https://twitter.com/perrikaryal/status/1809272601497215457?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 5, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>
In other Elden Ring news, you may have been <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-scadutree-is-not-pronounced-the-way-you-think-it-is">pronouncing Scadutree Fragments wrong</a>. And has author <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-writer-george-rr-martin-tells-us-nothing-and-everything-about-a-live-action-spin-off">George R. R. Martin teased a film or TV spin-off</a>?



</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gorgeous Fallout Unreal Engine 5 Prototype Provides a Glimpse at Future Possibilities]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fallout-unreal-engine-5-prototype/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gorgeous-fallout-unreal-engine-5-prototype-provides-a-glimpse-at-future-possibilities.922326/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fallout-unreal-engine-5-prototype/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A fan recently created a Fallout Unreal Engine 5 prototype, providing a glimpse at what possibilities the future holds for the popular series by Bethesda.</p>
<p>The prototype, which was made by Milwaukee Games, takes advantage of the latest version of the game engine by Epic to recreate the atmosphere the series is known for. The moment the Vault opens, in particular, looks great, as do the open wasteland and the recreation of the iconic Pip-Boy.</p>
<p><iframe title="I Made a Fallout Prototype in Unreal Engine 5 (Gameplay)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SQK1VjUL3l4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It has been a while since the release of Fallout 4, so this Fallout Unreal Engine 5 is definitely making us hunger for another proper new entry in the series even more. A statement from Xbox head Phil Spencer suggested the success of the Amazon Prime Video TV Show may have <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-5-release/">sped up plans for a new game</a>, but Todd Howard later confirmed that <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-fallout-games-wont-be-rushed-says-howard-bethesda-game-studios-had-25-million-players-last-month/">new entries in the series won't be rushed out</a> just to take advantage of the franchise's current popularity.</p>
<p>The latest entry in the series is Fallout 76, now available on PC and console. The game is currently available for a very low price as part of the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1151340/Fallout_76/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam Summer Sale</a>, so there's no better time than now to join the many Vault Dwellers roaming post-nuclear America and experience the largest and most dynamic world created for the franchise.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parasol Stars: The Story of Bubble Bobble III Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/09/parasol-stars-the-story-of-bubble-bobble-iii-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/parasol-stars-the-story-of-bubble-bobble-iii-review.922320/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/09/parasol-stars-the-story-of-bubble-bobble-iii-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/09/parasol-stars-the-story-of-bubble-bobble-iii-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Parasol Stars: The Story of Bubble Bobble III Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Tuffcub">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-07-09">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-07-09">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The launch of Parasol Stars: The Story of Bubble Bobble III on PlayStation means that for the first time in many, many years, all three Bubble Bobble games are available on one platform. Both <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/EP8908-CUSA46390_00-HAMPRDC000000001">Rainbow Islands</a> and <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/EP8908-CUSA03943_00-HAMPRDC000000001">Bubble Bobble</a> were released as part of the Arcade Archives series, direct ports of the arcade games, but Parasol Stars has had a few extra tweaks thanks to developers ININ and this one is actually published by the original arcade machine manufacture, Taito.</p>
<p><iframe title="Parasol Stars - The Story of Bubble Bobble III Launch Teaser" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sHhXUfVmwD8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The game – also confusing known as Rainbow Islands II even though there are no rainbows – features the same elements as the previous two instalments but with an added twist. The basic gameplay is still the same, with mostly single screen levels that have a bunch of enemies moving in fairly predictable paths, where one touch from any of them will cause you to lose a life. The twist here is that Bub and Bob (still in human form) have parasols which they can use&nbsp; in a number of ways.</p>


<p>Get close to an enemy and flourish you parasol and you can stun the creature, pick it up and throw at other enemies. You can also use the parasol to block incoming attacks, and collect bubbles that drop from the ceiling. Throw a single bubble and it will knock out an enemy, but collect five and it will turn into a super weapon – either a pool of fire, an electric bolt, or a torrent of water – which you can use to knock out multiple bad guys at once.</p>


<p>Like all the Bubble Bobble games the premise is quite simple, and unlike it’s predecessors, Parasol Stars is actually much easier and you can breeze through the first couple of levels without much thought. However, thinking is exactly what you need to do if you want to score the big points.&nbsp; Hitting multiple enemies at once brings showers of point giving fruit, and there many secrets hidden in the levels, just throwing a bubble in a certain direction may produce enough ice creams and eclairs to keep anyone happy. As the enemies always start in the same position and you have just a brief second before they start moving, the key is to work out the best path through the level, hitting as many enemies at once and uncovering all the delicious goodies.</p>
<p>At the end of each of the eight levels you will face a boss fight and the mechanics change. Now you can spawn bubbles by floating around, charge up a super burst and hit the boss. There are also two hidden bonus levels that can be unlocked… if you know how.</p>

<p>As mentioned this isn’t a direct port of the arcade game, and while the core game is exactly the same ININ have tweaked a few things. The control scheme has been modified for our modern controllers and I have to say it works like a dream, so much better than the controls from the previous games. The graphics, while still in the 16-bit pixel glory, are superbly crisp and colourful and make Rainbow Islands look rather washed out in comparison. The colours also help make the game look a lot less dated; it could be an indie game from 2024.</p>
<p>The game also has the usual modern features including a rewind button, load and saves, and filters. There’s also options for those who are colour blind and a hilarious if totally useless feature to change the screen size to the original GameBoy version, which results in the game running in a 3cm square in the middle of a 4K screen.</p>
<p>The jewel in the crown is the two player mode, as unlike the previous games you can work together, or be a dick. Do you help the second player, giving them a boost up on your brolly and working together to clear the screen, or do you hide on your side and throw enemies at your pal, stunning them so they can’t move and get smacked in the face by a sentient trombone?</p>

		
		

<p>So the big question, is as good as the the other two games? Well yes and no. It’s still a brilliant game but perhaps lacks the “one more go” factor of Rainbow Islands, but if you have two players then this is by far the best in the series.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		A superb, crisp version of the arcade classic with plenty of replayability and tonnes of secrets to uncover. An absolute must for fans who want to complete the trilogy. 	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>A faultless version of the classic game</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Superbly crisp and bright graphics</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Fight or cooperate two player mode</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Lacks that "one more go" factor</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Don’t Need an Xbox to Play Xbox, Says New Fire TV App Ad]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/you-dont-need-an-xbox-to-play-xbox-says-new-fire-tv-app-ad/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-don%E2%80%99t-need-an-xbox-to-play-xbox-says-new-fire-tv-app-ad.922308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/you-dont-need-an-xbox-to-play-xbox-says-new-fire-tv-app-ad/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Starting yesterday, the newly released <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09MVCQJBJ/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox app</a> for the Amazon Fire TV stick allows users to play Xbox games on the go, even without the console. Of course, you will need an active Game Pass Ultimate subscription, as that's the only way to access cloud gaming for Xbox - unless all you want to play is Fortnite, which can be checked out for free.</p>
<p>The app is initially available on the <a href="https://amzn.to/3LBrJ7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fire TV 4K Max (2023)</a> and <a href="https://amzn.to/3VWvQ2D" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fire TV Stick 4K (2023)</a>, with pricing starting at $49.99. A Bluetooth-enabled wireless controller, such as Xbox Wireless Controller, Xbox Adaptive Controller, PlayStation DualSense, or DualShock 4, is also needed to play.</p>
<p><iframe title="No Xbox? Have no fear with Amazon Fire TV Stick" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xiVHc3UBJFk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>To celebrate the occasion, Microsoft also released a dedicated ad where the phrase 'you don't need an Xbox to play Xbox' can be heard - something that would have been unthinkable mere years ago. Of course, it is no news that Microsoft is pushing beyond the limited confines of the console space. Partly, that is because sales aren't great (in fact, <a href="https://wccftech.com/activision-boosts-microsot-q3-gaming-revenue-xbox-consoles-sales-collapse/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">they have been declining for a while now</a>), but it's also because Microsoft's ambitions are much bigger than the total addressable market for consoles could ever allow. There are only a few hundred million users interested in console gaming, whereas Microsoft <a href="https://wccftech.com/nadella-xbox-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wants to reach up to three billion gamers</a> wherever they may wish to play.</p>
<p>That includes PC gaming (all Xbox first-party titles have launched on PC for several years now), other consoles (as we've seen with the ports of Sea of Thieves, Pentiment, Grounded, and Hi-Fi Rush to PlayStation 5/Nintendo Switch), TVs (<a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-and-samsung-partnership-brings-xbox-app-to-samsung-gaming-hub-on-2022-smart-tvs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there's been an app on Samsung televisions</a> for two years now), and mobile devices, the real deal, with Microsoft <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-to-launch-mobile-store-via-web-in-july-microsoft-sees-tremendous-growth-in-cloud-gaming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ready to launch a dedicated store later this month</a>. The Amazon Fire TV stick app is just a stepping stone on a path to bring Xbox games to every possible device.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atlas Fallen Is Reportedly Coming Soon to Game Pass]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/atlas-fallen-reportedly-coming-to-game-pass-soon/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atlas-fallen-is-reportedly-coming-soon-to-game-pass.922290/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/atlas-fallen-reportedly-coming-to-game-pass-soon/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://x.com/eXtas1stv/status/1810470552731095545?t=VNOHCe8Wbww2sHiGT0Ge7w&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">According to Spanish leaker extas1s</a>, Deck13's action RPG Atlas Fallen is coming soon to Microsoft's Game Pass subscription service. The leaker did not specify any specific date, but chances are it will happen alongside the upcoming launch of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/atlas-fallen-gets-enhanced-with-free-reign-of-sand-update-on-august-6/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">big free Reign of Sand update</a>, scheduled for August 6.</p>
<p>Atlas Fallen launched in August 2023 to slightly mixed reviews. The game earned a 7 out of 10 score <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/atlas-fallen-god-of-sand/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in Wccftech's review</a>:</p>
<p><em>Before release, Atlas Fallen looked like an intense action game that could rival the best titles released in the past few years. The execution, however, relegates Deck13's latest game to be nothing more than a decent title that can be fun if one is willing to look past its shortcomings. With a little more polish, the game could have been great, but in its current state, it will eventually become a faint memory like the world that was covered in sand by the God Thelos.</em></p>
<p>Deck13 is known mostly for its Soulslike games (the first Lords of the Fallen and the two The Surge titles). With Atlas Fallen, they tried to switch genres, but they didn't find commercial success, either, as publisher Focus Home Interactive <a href="https://wccftech.com/atlas-fallen-was-a-financial-disappointment-but-an-enhanced-version-and-new-content-is-coming-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> in December 2023.</p>
<p>However, they set on trying to improve the game. The Reign of Sand update will introduce some brand new voice acting by the award-winning actor Ben Starr (who voiced Clive Rosfield, the protagonist in Square Enix's Final Fantasy XVI), a new area, new enemies, 25 new Essence Stones, new progression mechanics, quality of life improvements (mostly to the camera, but also to balancing and onboarding), the highly requested New Game Plus mode, and a new difficulty mode called Nyaal's Nightmare.</p>
<p>It only makes sense to ensure as many people as possible check out this improved version of Atlas Fallen through Game Pass. After all, as KeokeN's Koen Deetman <a href="https://wccftech.com/deliver-us-home-qa-keoken-talks-studio-layoffs-kickstarter-campaign-and-life-as-a-small-indie/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told Wccftech in our fresh Deliver Us Home interview</a>, Game Pass is a great discovery tool that is sure to boost a game's visibility for a while.</p>
<p>We'll keep an eye on the official announcement, which will probably happen soon.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Console US Spending Declines; Ghost of Tsushima Resurgence Validates Sony’s PC Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/console-us-spending-declines-ghost-of-tsushima-resurgence-validates-sonys-pc-strategy/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/console-us-spending-declines-ghost-of-tsushima-resurgence-validates-sony%E2%80%99s-pc-strategy.922287/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/console-us-spending-declines-ghost-of-tsushima-resurgence-validates-sonys-pc-strategy/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://x.com/MatPiscatella/status/1810377988434964526">Hardware spending in the US declined by 40%</a> in May on a year-on-year comparison, according to Circana (formerly NPD). This includes popular consoles such as the Nintendo Switch and PlayStation 5. The main culprit is the tough comparison with May 2023, which saw the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">release of The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a>, a masterpiece and massive commercial success for Nintendo that drove lots of sales of Switch hardware.</p>
<p>This May, Sony's PlayStation comes out on top. Ghost of Tsushima was the best-seller in May 2024, surging back from rank #71 in the chart thanks to the game's <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-tsushima-sets-new-concurrent-player-peak-record-for-sonys-single-player-games-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">successful release on PC</a>. During this time, Nintendo also saw the release of the Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door remake. However, Sony remained on top with better sales in physical and digital media from Ghost of Tsushima.</p>
<p>Also, Helldivers 2 was a massive release for Sony, and it can be played only on PC or PlayStation 5. The large number of sales accrued with these two games shows that Sony's strategy of bringing its exclusives to PC is incredibly successful, being able to tap into a whole new market.</p>
<p>As the years go by, we see more and more PlayStation exclusives, such as The Last of Us, Ghost of Tsushima, Horizon Zero Dawn, and many more, be ported to PC. As this happens, Sony's sales skyrocket as it adds a new layer of accessibility to the game for fans who may not be able to afford a PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>Circana also notes that May 2024 saw a 3% dip in all content spending, compared to a 13% growth in mobile content spending. As more games are put on mobile (including <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-7-biohazard-coming-to-iphone-ipad-and-mac-on-july/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CAPCOM's Resident Evil series</a>), new audiences can discover them, and they can usually get them for cheaper than they may get on another console.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch is seeing the biggest drop in sales, which could be related to the upcoming announcement of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-higher-resolution-steam-deck/">Nintendo Switch 2</a>. Many players avoid buying a new Nintendo Switch because they don't want to have outdated technology, and a new era of future games could be exclusive to the Nintendo Switch 2. Then again, most users who wanted a Switch probably already have one by now.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Logitech’s $80 supercapacitor gaming mouse is the most versatile it’s ever made]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/9/24194631/logitech-g309-gaming-mouse-powerplay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/logitech%E2%80%99s-80-supercapacitor-gaming-mouse-is-the-most-versatile-it%E2%80%99s-ever-made.922281/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/9/24194631/logitech-g309-gaming-mouse-powerplay<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I haven’t thought about charging my Logitech wireless gaming mouse in two and a half years <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23005435/magic-mouse-apple-logitech-powerplay">because I have a magic mousepad</a> that does it automatically. But Logitech mice that work with the Powerplay mousepad are <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/5/23043644/logitech-g-pro-x-superlight-2-gaming-mouse-price-release-date-specs">expensive</a>, heavy, or both, and none of them double as a Bluetooth mouse so I can wirelessly pair them to my laptop, handheld, or phone.</p><p>Today, Logitech is changing that with <a href="https://logitech.cfzu.net/c/482924/499820/8585?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.logitechg.com%2Fen-us">the Logitech G309</a>, an $80 mouse that almost does it all. It’s the first Powerplay mouse this inexpensive, the first with Bluetooth, the first that lets you use an AA battery when you’re on the go — and the first Logitech wireless mouse with a supercapacitor inside so you don’t <em>necessarily</em> need a battery at all. </p><p>Even without Powerplay, the G309 is a dual-mode wireless gaming mouse that promises up to 300 hours of battery life using its Lightspeed wireless dongle or up to 600 hours over Bluetooth, while you’re slinging around its 86-gram frame. </p><p>But if you’ve got that $120 Powerplay pad, you can remove the AA battery to reach a total mouse weight of <em>just 68 grams</em>, nearly as light as the 60-gram $160 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/5/23043644/logitech-g-pro-x-superlight-2-gaming-mouse-price-release-date-specs">Logitech G Pro X Superlight 2<em> </em>that gave me serious mouse envy</a> last year. It’s possible because the supercapacitor acts as a tiny battery constantly being wirelessly charged by the Powerplay mousepad underneath. “It’s never going to die at all; it’s endless battery life,” promises Logitech senior global product manager Nicolas Métral.</p><p>It’s not the first wireless gaming mouse to test the waters with a supercapacitor — but <a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/1/9/16867292/razer-wireless-charging-hyperflux-mamba-firefly-mouse-pad-ces-2018">when Mad Catz and Razer tried that in 2018</a>, those pricey wireless power mice didn’t have any <em>other</em> way to charge. You had to use them on their bundled pad or with a wired cord. Until now, Logitech’s used internal rechargeable lithium cells to let you make its Powerplay mice somewhat portable; here, an AA battery picks up the slack. </p><p>Despite being on the budget end of Logitech’s gaming mice, the G309 also has the same Hero 25K sensor and hybrid optomechanical switches the company’s been <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/8/30/23328970/logitech-g502-x-lightspeed-plus-gaming-mouse-mice-optical-buttons-usb-c">shipping in premium mice for a while</a>, both of which might be welcome upgrades over the $60 G305 mouse it’s based on. </p><p>But it’s still missing the one Logitech mouse feature I’d have a hard time doing without: the company’s dual-mode ratcheting / free-spinning scroll wheel that I’m constantly using to zip through documents and webpages when I’m using my gaming mouse for work. Among gaming mice, that’s still exclusive to its G502 and G903, from what I can tell. </p><p>And it’s a bit of a shame Logitech still sells its Powerplay mousepad for $120 with only the rarest and smallest of discounts. If the company really wants to fulfill the G309’s promise of “Wireless Play for All” — that’s Logitech’s tagline — I’d recommend making the complete package more affordable.</p><p>Logitech says it will keep selling the G305 alongside the G309. The G309 can also share a single Lightspeed wireless dongle with a bunch of Logitech’s wireless keyboards, including <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/25/24185020/logitech-keyboard-mx-keycaps-gaming">the new G515 TKL</a>, G715, G915, G915 TKL, Pro X 60, and Pro X TKL.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beautiful Toy Story Unreal Engine 5 Concept Shows What a Current-Gen Installment Could Look Like]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/beautiful-toy-story-unreal-engine-5-concept-shows-what-a-current-gen-installment-could-look-like/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beautiful-toy-story-unreal-engine-5-concept-shows-what-a-current-gen-installment-could-look-like.922272/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/beautiful-toy-story-unreal-engine-5-concept-shows-what-a-current-gen-installment-could-look-like/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A beautiful new Toy Story Unreal Engine 5 concept video shows what a current-gen Toy Story installment could look like.</p>
<p>Created by digital artist '<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nn5VUsxmoaI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TeaserPlay</a>', this fan concept video shows a Toy Story imagining within Epic's latest game engine on a modern-day setup. Of course, as with most concept videos from this YouTuber, this is only a teaser video and we likely won't be seeing a modern new Toy Story title anytime soon. Still, there are many fans out there who will likely appreciate this Unreal Engine 5 imagining of Toy Story. Check out the video below and judge for yourself.</p>
<p><iframe title="Imagining TOY STORY™ Realistic Game" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nn5VUsxmoaI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Since the release of the popular Toy Story movies in 1995, we've seen multiple videogame adaption based on the franchise, including titles for the original PlayStation, Dreamcast, Nintendo 64 and PC. The latest main entry in the series is 2010's Toy Story 3 from Disney Interactive Studios. This title was released for the PS3, Xbox 360, Wii, and PC.&nbsp; As you can imagine, fans have been hoping for a new game in the series following the release of the 2019's Toy Story 4 movie. We've included a part of the official Toy Story 3: The Video Game press release from 2010 below.</p>
<p>"“Toy Story 3: The Video Game addresses a fact understood by every kid: imagination is what truly brings toys to life,” said John Blackburn, vice president and general manager of Avalanche Software. “That’s really what a toy box is about. We remember that kind of play from our own childhood, and it’s where we began as game designers. With this title, we want to encourage and reward creativity in others.”</p>
<p>“With Toy Story 3: The Video Game, audiences will have multiple ways to experience and enjoy the Toy Story world,” said Craig Relyea, senior vice president of global marketing, Disney Interactive Studios. “Story Mode follows the film’s story and adventures, while Toy Box Mode gets to the playful heart of the Toy Story franchise. By combining the power of imagination with the Toy Story universe, the game appeals to the joy of play in all of us.”</p>
<p>What are your thoughts about this video? Do you like what you're seeing? Would you like to see a new entry on modern-age platforms? Hit the comments below.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hellblade II Hit Woeful Sales Records in May]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hellblade-ii-woeful-sales-in-may-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hellblade-ii-hit-woeful-sales-records-in-may.922269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/hellblade-ii-woeful-sales-in-may-2024/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II was released on May 21 following years of teasers and trailers. It was first announced in 2018 and was penned as being one of the most visually advanced games ever made – and to give the game credit, it hits that target just fine. However, it’s a testament to the fact that visuals aren’t everything, as recent sales data has revealed that the game performed terribly during May 2024.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-sacrificing-senua">Sacrificing Senua</h2>



<p>Hellblade II is a fairly short game that offers an immersive, impactful story mixed up with groundbreaking visuals, and it performed fairly well in reviews when it was released. Presently, it sits on Metacritic with a score of 80, which isn’t awful.</p>



<p>However, US sales data published by Circana has revealed how poorly Hellblade II performed when it was released, with the game coming in 37th place overall in the charts for full-game dollar sales. On Xbox, it ended up in 21st place. In terms of player count, it fell behind the likes of Fallout 76, and on Steam, it peaked at just 3,892 players. </p>



<p>In the <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/ea-sports-fc-24-and-gta-5-top-european-charts-in-tough-may-european-monthly-charts" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">European sales charts</a>, it was revealed that Hellblade II failed to break into the top 100 games in May. On streaming platforms, Hellblade II crashed pretty quickly. It reached a peak of 110,193 viewers on Twitch on launch day, but by the second day on the market, that number had dwindled by 90%, and by the following week, a peak of just 900 users was recorded. </p>



<p>It’s hardly a flash in the pan, but it’s a short-lived, short-form game that only offers a few hours of entertainment, and once you’re done, you’re <strong>done</strong>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, read what <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sketch-confirms-of-leaks-real-stream/">Sketch said about the recent OnlyFans leaks</a>&nbsp;and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Score a 2TB PS5 SSD for Only $104.99 Ahead of Amazon Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/score-a-2tb-ps5-ssd-for-only-105-ahead-of-amazon-prime-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/score-a-2tb-ps5-ssd-for-only-104-99-ahead-of-amazon-prime-day.922266/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/score-a-2tb-ps5-ssd-for-only-105-ahead-of-amazon-prime-day<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><p>SSD prices are trending upward for 2024, but there are still some excellent deals to be found if you're vigilant. Ahead of Prime Day, Amazon is currently offering the PS5-compatible <a href="https://zdcs.link/Y0382?content_id=424538be-8b3a-4bb7-8d50-5fe3eb96fe61&amp;pagetype=article" target="_blank">TEAMGROUP</a> 2TB PCIe Gen4 x4 M.2 Solid State Drive (SSD) for only $110. You'll need to supply a heatsink, but you can easily get a <a href="https://zdcs.link/OGrjj?content_id=424538be-8b3a-4bb7-8d50-5fe3eb96fe61&amp;pagetype=article" target="_blank">PS5 heatsink for under $10</a>.  All of the other <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ps5-ssd">best PS5 SSDs</a> cost $140 or more.</p><h2>TEAMGROUP 2TB SSD (PS5-Compatible) for $110</h2><div id="202985" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Teamgroup MP44Q 2TB PCIe Gen4 x4 M.2 SSD (up to 7400MBps)</h3></p></div><p>The PS5 is an outstanding gaming console, but the 1TB SSD is a real bottleneck. Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3, for example, can <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/activision-explains-huge-call-of-duty-modern-warfare-3-file-sizes">exceed 200GB alone</a>. NBA 2K23 weighs in at 150GB and even older games like God of War: Ragnarok and Horizon Forbidden West require 90GB of space. Future games like Grand Theft Auto VI will undoubtedly demand even more space. The advantage of a PS5 console over the Xbox Series X is that the SSD slot is not proprietary; you can install most third-party PCIe Gen4 x4 SSDs as long as they are fast enough. Slower drives WILL work, but they may bottleneck the original SSD.</p><p>Although TEAMGROUP isn't as well-known of a brand as SanDisk or Samsung, this brand has been around for a while and is a legitimate manufacturer of flash-based storage. This particular model has plenty of good reviews on Amazon. This particular SSD meets all the requirements for your PS5 upgrade. This is a PCIe Gen4 x4 SSD with an M.2 2280 form factor and transfer speeds of up to 7,400MB/s read and 6,500MB/s write which is well above the 5,500MB/s minimum threshold. It also makes an excellent boot drive for your gaming PC, especially with its 2TB storage capacity.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Willing to pay more for another brand? Check out all of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-ps5-ssd-deals-for-2024">best PS5 SSD deals today</a>.</p></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 9, 2024 4:25 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sketch Confirms OF Leaks Are Real During Emotional Stream]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sketch-confirms-of-leaks-real-stream/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sketch-confirms-of-leaks-are-real-during-emotional-stream.922257/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sketch-confirms-of-leaks-real-stream/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Earlier this week, images emerged online showing popular streamer, Kylie ‘Sketch’ Cox, performing explicit acts – and it was alleged that the images were screengrabbed from an old OnlyFans account. The surfacing of the images led to Sketch being bombarded on social media with homophobic abuse, prompting many of his peers to speak up in support of him amid an unplanned outing. </p>



<p>He went live just hours ago with an explanation that led to him confirming that the images are real and that they were taken from a ‘dark time’ in his life and he has since ‘changed’.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-we-move-on">We Move On</h2>



<p>Sketch might not be everyone’s cup of tea and he’s one of the more zany characters on Twitch, but there’s no discrediting the rampant growth that the streamer has experienced in the last few months. In March 2024, he blew up, amassing more than 350,000 followers in a single month, and he now sits at 1.1 million followers on the top-tier streaming platform.</p>



<p>Earlier this week, images appeared on social media showing Sketch engaged in a sexual act with another man, which prompted an ignorant portion of the gaming community to unleash a tirade upon him. He was dragged through the wringer, and during <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2192642945" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">an emotional appearance on stream</a> last night, he revealed that the revelation hitting the air almost ended him:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Yeah, it came out. And I have a lot of people to credit for… I’ll be honest, Plan A was – and I will say candidly – was to probably eat a — well, probably to call it quits, if this ever came out. But some people saved me. Shout out Banks, shout out my parents, shout of y’all. I f***ed up, but I’m changed.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s widely assumed Sketch was about to say he would have to ‘eat a bullet’ if this came out. His reference to Banks is a nod to FaZe Banks, who was supportive of Sketch when the news dropped online. Following his explanation, Sketch suggested he might be taking a break from streaming to get his head in the right space – but there’s still a chance he might quit, he said.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, read about&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-3-character-creator-mod/">awesome new Witcher 3 mod</a>&nbsp;and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>