<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:22:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov is Getting Easier For The First Time in a Decade]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-getting-easier-first-time-decade/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-from-tarkov-is-getting-easier-for-the-first-time-in-a-decade.1354222/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>If you’ve ever played Escape from Tarkov from a fresh, uninitiated perspective, you’ll know that it’s <strong>not </strong>a welcoming game. It’s one of the most challenging shooters ever developed, and fans of the spearhead extraction title love to lord it over other gamers when they become <strong>cracked </strong>at Escape from Tarkov.</p>



<p>As the game hits 1.0 tomorrow, Battlestate Games is planning something that will, for the first time in a decade, make Escape from Tarkov <strong>easier for new players to understand</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-escape-from-tarkov-is-getting-a-tutorial">Escape from Tarkov is Getting a <em>Tutorial</em></h2>



<p>Escape from Tarkov has been pretty rough for years. You buy it, create a basic character, and are thrown into the game to figure out for yourself how the core mechanics work. The first tasks put to you are simple, but you have zero guidance, no map markers, and little in the way of any indication of where to go.</p>



<p>The game’s core mechanics were never explained, tactics were never outlined, and functions like healing, inventory management, and weapon handling were left up to the player to discover and master.</p>



<p>That’s why it comes as a surprise to learn what Escape from Tarkov has planned for the 1.0 release, which is dropping tomorrow after more than a decade of development.</p>



<p>When new players enter the fight in Escape from Tarkov from tomorrow, they’ll be met <a href="https://www.escapefromtarkov.com/news/id/363" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">with a <strong>tutorial</strong></a> designed to help them learn the ropes. But it doesn’t end there. Beyond the tutorial, Battlestate Games has outlined step-by-step progression guides, building on the scattering of guides it introduced over the last year or so.</p>



<p>Escape from Tarkov has never had a strict tutorial, only ‘more basic’ starter missions that were designed to ease players into the brutal game world, but even they were often sticking points early on in every ‘reset’ (read: wipe).</p>







<p>The tutorial arrives with a non-linear story campaign and end-game content, a new map, new mechanics and weapons, improvements across the audio and graphics suite in the game, and <strong>more than 1,000 improvements </strong>across the board.</p>



<p>Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> if you’re excited about Tarkov 1.0.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-splinter-cell-ubisoft-canceled/">Ubisoft canceled a new Splinter Cell game</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-getting-easier-first-time-decade/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Canceled A Splinter Cell Game, And It Morphed Into The Ill-Fated XDefiant - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-canceled-a-splinter-cell-game-and-it-morphed-into-the-ill-fated-xdefiant-report/1100-6536236/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-canceled-a-splinter-cell-game-and-it-morphed-into-the-ill-fated-xdefiant-report.1354219/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536236">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Ubisoft was working on a new Splinter Cell game that was going to embrace games-as-a-service before it shifted to become XDefiant, a game that the publisher shut down not long after release. This is according to Nick Herman, a developer who worked on the game before leaving to start AdHoc Studios, the team that just launched the episodic game Dispatch to great success.</p><p>"I was so excited to be a part of this and help revitalize it, because it's been dormant for a while," Herman said told <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-11-14/the-turbulent-seven-year-saga-behind-hit-game-dispatch" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloomberg</a>. "And we thought we could tell a great story and do something the fans would love."</p><p>The game was in development "for a few months," Bloomberg reported, and Herman confirmed that Ubisoft wanted to have it feature games-as-a-service elements.</p><p>"We tried," Herman said. "Let's make a narrative GAAS game. We were trying to make that make sense, and a lot of cool prototypes were made."</p><p>The report said "Ubisoft had lost interest" in this Splinter Cell game and shifted to pursue a project that could attempt to compete with Call of Duty. This became XDefiant, a game directed by former Call of Duty boss Mark Rubin. The game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xdefiant-shuts-down-in-june-2025-ubisoft-closes-two-offices/1100-6528210/" data-ref-id="1100-6528210">shut down after a year and developers were laid off. </a></p><p>"We thought we were going to be able to make something really great," Herman said. "And then you realize that all of the things you care about, they don't anymore. It's a common thing in games."</p><p>While that Splinter Cell game is not coming to market, a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/splinter-cell-remake/">Splinter Cell remake is now in the works</a>. Outside of games, the Splinter Cell TV show Deathwatch debuted in October on Netflix and has already been renewed for a second season. A live-action movie was in the works, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/splinter-cell-movie-sneaks-back-to-the-shadows-after-being-canceled/1100-6527785/" data-ref-id="1100-6527785">apparently no longer is.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-canceled-a-splinter-cell-game-and-it-morphed-into-the-ill-fated-xdefiant-report/1100-6536236/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How The New Voice Over Affected Dragon Quest VII Reimagined]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2025/11/14/how-the-new-voice-over-affected-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-the-new-voice-over-affected-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined.1354216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</a> is the first version of Dragon Quest VII to feature in-game voice acting, meaning characters like Sir Mervyn, Aishe, Maribel, Prince Kiefer, and even Ruff, will be voiced. Neither the original PlayStation release of Dragon Quest VII nor the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/dragon-quest-vii-fragments-of-the-forgotten-past">2016 3DS remake</a> featured voice acting, so I asked Reimagined lead scenario writer if this changed how the team approached redesigning the story.&nbsp;</p><p>Unsurprisingly, it did.&nbsp;</p><p>"Knowing that it was going to have voice over certainly did change the approach of the way I wrote the narrative here," Sayaka Takagi tells me within Square Enix's Shibuya offices in Tokyo, Japan. “The original release on PlayStation didn’t have any voiceovers, and it was written [out]. So certainly, the way we wrote the language of the dialogue [in Reimagined] needed to be changed to be more realistic and more modern for modern audiences.”&nbsp;</p>



<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="0ccdbf19-1393-48d4-8f94-bead78ce4b9b" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="image:responsive_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;responsive_image_style&quot;:&quot;content_body&quot;,&quot;image_loading&quot;:{&quot;attribute&quot;:&quot;lazy&quot;},&quot;image_link&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
          <picture>
                  <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/body_default/public/2025/09/24/01d5baf1/372_dqvii_04.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 851px)" type="image/webp" width="800" height="450">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/09/24/01d5baf1/372_dqvii_04.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 315px) and (max-width: 450px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/09/24/01d5baf1/372_dqvii_04.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (max-width: 314px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
                  

  </picture>


  
  
  
</article>

<p>She says colloquialism played a significant factor in writing Reimagined’s dialogue, because everything needs to sound natural for the various included voice-over options.</p><p>I hear first-hand one of these changes when I encounter eventual party member Sir Mervyn at the top of The Tallest Tower dungeon while playing the game. After I awaken him from a special stone to defeat the flying Chimaera surrounding the tower, he does just that before gracefully landing beside my party. It's here I hear his voice, and it sounds like that of a medieval knight – this isn't too shocking, considering how he looks.&nbsp;</p>



<article alt="Sir Mervyn" title="Sir Mervyn" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="097ea367-8eea-43a9-ae5b-51912419b8c4" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="image:responsive_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;responsive_image_style&quot;:&quot;content_body&quot;,&quot;image_loading&quot;:{&quot;attribute&quot;:&quot;lazy&quot;},&quot;image_link&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;Sir Mervyn&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
          <picture>
                  <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/body_default/public/2025/11/05/3d4efe47/mervyn_7.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 851px)" type="image/webp" width="800" height="450">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/11/05/3d4efe47/mervyn_7.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 315px) and (max-width: 450px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/11/05/3d4efe47/mervyn_7.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (max-width: 314px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
                  

  </picture>


  
  
      <p>Sir Mervyn</p>
  
</article>

<p>But in Japanese, he talks like a feudal samurai, Reimagined producer Takeshi Ichikawa, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2025/11/05/who-is-takeshi-ichikawa-the-producer-of-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">who you can read more about here</a>, says. Another example of this colloquialist effect present in Reimagined comes from Bulgio, an extremely wealthy man who gives Hero the special stone that houses Sir Mervyn. In English, Bulgio mixes Italian words into his English, reflecting the multicultural inspiration present throughout the world of Reimagined. In Japanese, however, that's not the case – instead of mixing English and Italian, his dialogue instead reflects his character rather than a nationality.&nbsp;</p><p>"He's supposed to be this rich, arrogant guy, and that's reflected in the dialogue," Takagi says on the differences between the Japanese localization and the English version, noting her work is focused on the former while other teams handle the latter. "At least for the Japanese version, we didn't necessarily write dialogue in a way that you can tell what these specific cultural backgrounds are for each character, but we did write dialogue in a way that it's immediately understandable what kind of personality that character has."&nbsp;</p><p>Takagi adds, "The world of Dragon Quest VII, as you know, is comprised of many different islands, and obviously the dialects on each of those islands tends to differ, so it is a very important part of the story of Dragon Quest VII to ensure that the residents of those islands can reflect the uniqueness and individuality of each of those islands and the cultures they have."&nbsp;</p><p>We'll get to hear more of these new voices when Dragon Quest VII Reimagined launches on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, Switch 2, Switch, and PC on February 5, 2026.&nbsp;</p><p>In the meantime, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/digital-issue/2025/11/04/the-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-digital-issue-is-now-live">check out this article</a> breaking down everything in the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2025/10/21/cover-reveal-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined issue of <em>Game Informer</em></a>, and be sure to <a href="https://gameinformer.com/subscribe">subscribe here</a> if you haven't yet so you can access the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/11/04/adventure-doesnt-wait">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined cover story</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/11/04/the-history-of-dragon-quest-as-told-by-creator-yuji-horii">our deep dive into Dragon Quest history</a> with creator Yuji Horii, and so much more. Here are some other stories to check out:</p><ul><li><a href="https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/11/04/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-will-have-a-new-never-before-seen-conclusion">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined Will Have A New Never-Before-Seen Conclusion</a></li><li><a href="https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2025/11/05/who-is-takeshi-ichikawa-the-producer-of-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">Who Is Takeshi Ichikawa, The Producer Of Dragon Quest VII Reimagined?</a></li><li><a href="https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2025/11/05/heres-how-the-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-team-streamlined-its-main">Here's How The Dragon Quest VII Reimagined Team Streamlined Its Main Scenario</a></li></ul><hr><p><em>Whose voice are you most excited to hear in Dragon Quest VII Reimagined? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2025/11/14/how-the-new-voice-over-affected-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Splinter Cell Was In Development Until Ubisoft Spiked It To Make A Live-Service Game]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/a-new-splinter-cell-was-in-development-until-ubisoft-spiked-it-to-make-a-live-service-game-2000644414</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-new-splinter-cell-was-in-development-until-ubisoft-spiked-it-to-make-a-live-service-game.1354201/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p data-component="paragraph">In 2017, some former Telltale developers were working on a <em>Splinter Cell</em> sequel that eventually, due to Ubisoft’s focus on live-service games, morphed into the now-dead free-to-play FPS<em> XDefiant.</em></p> <p data-component="paragraph"><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-11-14/the-turbulent-seven-year-saga-behind-hit-game-dispatch?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc2MzE0MzM2NiwiZXhwIjoxNzYzNzQ4MTY2LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUNVFBMDdHUEZIUlYwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.fNOncm0D1BfbWI9RAgwCB6j8SI8mW9RhRD76EEz1TYo&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall">In a <em>Bloomberg</em> story published on November 14</a> about the development of the recently released narrative-focused superhero adventure game <em>Dispatch</em>, we learn a little bit about a previously unknown-to-the-public <em>Splinter Cell</em> game that was being developed by Ubisoft San Francisco around eight years ago.</p> <p data-component="paragraph">Adhoc Co-Founder Nick Herman told <em>Bloomberg</em> that in early 2017, he and a few colleagues left Telltale after working on <em>Tales from the Borderlands</em> and landed at Ubisoft San Francisco. They were tasked with developing a new entry in the tactical stealth franchise, <em>Splinter Cell.</em> At that point, it had been about four years since the last game, <a href="https://kotaku.com/splinter-cell-blacklist-the-kotaku-review-1126859452"><em>Blacklist</em>, had been released in 2013</a>.</p>

 <p data-component="paragraph">“I was so excited to be a part of this and help revitalize it, because it’s been dormant for a while,” Herman told the outlet. “And we thought we could tell a great story and do something the fans would love.”</p> <p data-component="paragraph">However, after working on the new <em>Splinter Cell</em> sequel for a few months, Ubisoft executives started disrupting development. This was when the publisher was becoming more and more focused on live-service games that could be updated for years and years, like <em>Rainbow Six Siege </em>and <em>The Division 2. </em>Ubisoft reportedly wanted all of its in-development games to include live-service elements and monetization, including the new <em>Splinter Cell.&nbsp;</em></p>

 <p data-component="paragraph">“We tried,” Herman told <em>Bloomberg</em>. “Let’s make a narrative [live-service] game. We were trying to make that make sense, and a lot of cool prototypes were made.” But it apparently became clear to those working on the doomed game that Ubisoft was no longer interested in <em>Splinter Cell.&nbsp;</em>According to<em> Bloomberg</em> and Herman, the project changed and evolved many times, and eventually became <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-xdefiant-shut-down-ending-call-of-duty-cod-june-1851712899"><em>XDefiant,</em> aka that short-lived live-service shooter Ubisoft killed back in June.&nbsp;</a></p> <p>“It was exciting to go to work for the first six months because we thought we were going to be able to make something really great,” Herman said. “And then you realize that all of the things you care about, they don’t anymore. It’s a common thing in games.”</p> <p>Ubisoft hasn’t completely given up on <em>Splinter Cell. </em><a href="https://kotaku.com/new-splinter-cell-trailer-netflix-deathwatch-chaos-theory-ending-john-wick-2000626077">There’s an animated series that recently arrived on Netflix</a> that I’m guessing you didn’t know about. And <a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/4adJLuhgYrPboHAPRfK7Oz/splinter-cell-remake-begins-development-at-ubisoft-toronto">in 2021, the company confirmed Ubisoft Toronto was developing a remake</a> of the first game. We’ve not heard much about that project since it was first revealed. Hopefully, it doesn’t morph into some <em>Call of Duty</em> clone.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/a-new-splinter-cell-was-in-development-until-ubisoft-spiked-it-to-make-a-live-service-game-2000644414]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Says It's Not Prohibiting Third-Party Switch 2 Docks After Players Report Bricking Issues]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-says-its-not-prohibiting-third-party-switch-2-docks-after-players-report-bricking-issues/1100-6536233/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-says-its-not-prohibiting-third-party-switch-2-docks-after-players-report-bricking-issues.1354198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536233">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>While the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-and-switch-get-new-system-updates-and-they-add-more-than-just-stability/1100-6536122/" data-ref-id="1100-6536122">latest firmware update for Switch and Switch 2</a> included several quality-of-life improvements, one consequence appears to be that many third-party docks have been rendered useless. According to Nintendo itself, such a consequence was unintentional.</p><p>In a statement, Nintendo spelled out the obvious, saying: "Nintendo Switch 2 outputs audiovisuals once it detects that it is docked into a Nintendo Switch 2 Dock. Nintendo Switch does the same, outputting audiovisuals once it detects that it is docked into a Nintendo Switch Dock."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1048623944" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466522,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;11%20Minutes%20of%20Metroid%20Prime%204%3A%20Beyond%20Gameplay&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:634,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/11-minutes-of-metroid-prime-4-beyond-gameplay\/2300-6466522\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466522\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466522\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466522\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466522&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466522,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536233&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466522},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466522\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1862\/18620770\/4602300-10minofgameplay.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/payJBFR2.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1763128800,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="payJBFR2" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> 11 Minutes of Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Gameplay</p>
      </div>
<p>More importantly, the company claimed that it "does not have any intention to hinder or invalidate legal third-party dock compatibility." It is unclear what Nintendo considers to be a "legal" dock.</p><p>When version 21.0.0 arrived on November 11, some Switch 2 owners took to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Switch/comments/1ou7lo8/psa_switch_2_v2100_disables_third_party_docks/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Reddit</a> and other forums to share their struggles with using third-party docks after the patch. Other users have noted that their docks remain functional, and manufacturers such as <a href="https://hagibis.bbscloud.com/info/570fc56f2e5c480cbda88a6638ebed89?csr=1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hagibis</a> and <a href="https://support.jemdogame.com/firmware_update_dock_20251112/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Jemdo</a> have since deployed firmware updates to their docks to ensure compatibility with the latest Switch patch.</p><p>Regardless of Nintendo's intention, the sample size of users who experienced issues with their third-party docks certainly demonstrates that the latest Switch firmware update had some sort of impact on compatibility. Based on Nintendo's statement, it doesn't appear that the company is eager to remedy the situation, and it may fall on the dock makers themselves to push out their own fixes.</p><p>Switch owners may own a third-party dock for various reasons, including the desire to have docks in multiple locations within their home or for portability. Unfortunately for third-party hardware makers, Nintendo made the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/report/695915/switch-2-usb-c-third-party-docks-dont-work-authentication-encryption" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Switch 2's USB-C port a lot more restrictive</a> and harder to work with.</p><p>Many third-party Switch 2 docks found online range from $20 to $50. In comparison, <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/nintendo-switch-2-dock-set-123791/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo's official Switch 2 dock set</a>, which include the official dock, an ultra-high-speed HDMI cable, a USB-C cable, and an AC adapter, costs $125 USD.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-says-its-not-prohibiting-third-party-switch-2-docks-after-players-report-bricking-issues/1100-6536233/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite is coming to the Xbox PC store]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/821177/fortnite-xbox-on-pc-app-store-epic-games-play-anywhere-crew-game-pass</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-coming-to-the-xbox-pc-store.1354189/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Fortnite</em> is going to be available on the Xbox on PC app beginning November 18th. Right now on PC, you have to launch the game from the Epic Games Launcher, but if you prefer the Xbox on PC app, that’s going to be an option.</p><p>The game is also joining the Xbox Play Anywhere program, meaning “your progress and purchases will seamlessly follow you across Xbox consoles, PC, and supported gaming handhelds,” <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/11/14/fortnite-crew-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-pc-play-anywhere/">Microsoft says</a>. That could make it easier to play on Xbox Ally and Xbox Ally X, if you want to get in some drops on one of the handhelds.</p><p>On November 18th, Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscribers will get Epic’s <em>Fortnite</em> Crew subscription as an additional perk, too. With a Crew subscription, you get a new skin and 1,000 V-Bucks every month as well as access to all of <em>Fortnite</em>’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/28/24282075/fortnite-streamlining-battle-passes-music-lego-festival">various battle passes</a> so you can earn items to use in the game’s many modes.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/821177/fortnite-xbox-on-pc-app-store-epic-games-play-anywhere-crew-game-pass]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Splinter Cell Was In Development, But Ubisoft Canceled It]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-splinter-cell-ubisoft-canceled/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-new-splinter-cell-was-in-development-but-ubisoft-canceled-it.1354183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Ubisoft was working on a new entry in the Splinter Cell franchise, but Ubisoft decided to cancel it before it was ever announced.</p>



<p>In a recent interview with Bloomberg’s Jason Schreier, AdHoc Studio co-founder Nick Herman spoke about how Dispatch came to be and an interesting situation that led to the studio’s formation.</p>







<p>Herman was hired in 2017 by Ubisoft, along two other AdHoc cofounders Pierre Shorette and Dennis Lenart, and moved to work in Ubisoft’s San Francisco office. Upon arrival, they were put on the new Splinter Cell project.</p>



<p><strong>“I was so excited to be a part of this and help revitalize it, because it’s been dormant for a while,”</strong> Herman <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-11-14/the-turbulent-seven-year-saga-behind-hit-game-dispatch?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc2MzE0MzM2NiwiZXhwIjoxNzYzNzQ4MTY2LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUNVFBMDdHUEZIUlYwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.fNOncm0D1BfbWI9RAgwCB6j8SI8mW9RhRD76EEz1TYo&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall">told Schreier</a>. <strong>“And we thought we could tell a great story and do something the fans would love.”</strong></p>











<p>Unfortunately, the game didn’t get very far. After just months of work, Ubisoft started making pivots on its plans. It seemed like the writing was on the wall for the game. </p>



<p>“<strong>It was exciting to go to work for the first six months because we thought we were going to be able to make something really great,” </strong>Herman said. <strong>“And then you realize that all of the things you care about, they don’t anymore. It’s a common thing in games.”</strong></p>







<p>Herman, Shorette, and Lenart would leave Ubisoft after the project was cancelled and form AdHoc Studio along with Michael Choung in 2018. </p>



<p>Despite no new game in the franchise since Splinter Cell: Blacklist in 2013, Splinter Cell isn’t dead. Ubisoft is currently working on a remake of the original game that, as of late 2024, was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-update-on-splinter-cell-remakes-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">still planned for a 2026 release</a>. Since then, however, it’s been quite silent on its status. </p>



<p>Recently, Ubisoft has moved into a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-is-forming-a-new-subsidiary-with-tencent-valued-at-4-3-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">partnership with Tencent</a>, started <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisofts-new-company-officially-launches-today/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new subsidiary</a>, and even <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-delays-earnings-report-halts-share-trading/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">delayed reporting its earnings</a> just minutes before they were scheduled to release.</p>



<p>What do you think of Ubisoft cancelling a new Splinter Cell game? Leave your thoughts down in the comments and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-delays-earnings-report-halts-share-trading/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft delaying their earnings report</a>&nbsp;and suspending stock trading just minutes be for it was scheduled to release. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-splinter-cell-ubisoft-canceled/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord Lives Again As Fan-Made Project Unveils Gameplay Test Videos]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concord-lives-again-as-fan-made-project-unveils-gameplay-test-videos/1100-6536235/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-lives-again-as-fan-made-project-unveils-gameplay-test-videos.1354180/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536235">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The story of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/concord/" data-ref-id="5000-589443">Concord</a> is a cautionary tale in the age of live-service games. Years of development and millions of dollars went into the game, only for it to fail at launch and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-shuts-down-concord-permanently-shutters-dev-firewalk-studios/1100-6527460/" data-ref-id="1100-6527460">get canceled by Sony weeks later</a>. However, Conord had some fans, and a trio of them worked very hard to bring the game back to life on a server.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://thegamepost.com/sony-concord-playable-again-custom-servers/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Game Post</a>, Concord's partial resurrection is due to reverse engineering by a user called Red, a rebuild of the game's backend API by open_wizard, and an additional assist from a programmer called gwog. The team shared a pair of a gameplay videos to demonstrate their achievement, but noted that Concord is still somewhat buggy.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ahpUW5Gbfi0" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ahpUW5Gbfi0" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The trio successfully tested their ability to load the game, pick their characters, and run a full Clash Point match.</p><p>"The project is still WIP, it's playable, but buggy," wrote Red. "Once our servers are fully set up, we'll begin doing some private playtesting."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nNHdoS_LC6Q" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nNHdoS_LC6Q" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>When Concord launched in 2024, it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concord-has-sold-about-25000-copies-and-should-have-launched-as-a-free-game-analysts-say/1100-6526227/" data-ref-id="1100-6526227">debuted to only 25,000 players</a>. Sony subsequently shut down the game's developer, Firewalk Studios. In the aftermath, Sony <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-re-commits-to-live-service-games-says-bungies-marathon-wont-suffer-concords-fate/1100-6532419/" data-ref-id="1100-6532419">recommitted to live-service games</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-talks-concord-failure-and-the-hard-lessons-learned-from-it/1100-6527647/" data-ref-id="1100-6527647">shared some of the hard lessons</a> it learned from the ordeal. Sony Interactive Entertainment chief executive of studio business Hermen Hulst <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concords-failure-led-to-increased-oversight-says-sony-exec/1100-6534243/" data-ref-id="1100-6534243">attributed its failure to a lack of oversight</a>.</p><p>Concord's fate was recently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/uk-government-cites-concord-during-debate-about-consumer-protections-for-gamers/1100-6535897/" data-ref-id="1100-6535897">cited in a debate</a> in the United Kingdom's House of Commons about the preservation of video games. That session also addressed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-addresses-the-stop-killing-games-movement/1100-6533318/" data-ref-id="1100-6533318">the Stop Killing Games movement</a>, but lawmakers were unconvinced of the necessity to create laws that prevent games from being taken offline.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concord-lives-again-as-fan-made-project-unveils-gameplay-test-videos/1100-6536235/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP's Switch 2 Upgrade Gets Last-Minute Delay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/lollipop-chainsaw-repops-switch-2-upgrade-gets-last-minute-delay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lollipop-chainsaw-repops-switch-2-upgrade-gets-last-minute-delay.1354165/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Was due in November</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="7693829e5141b"><a title="Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/7693829e5141b/lollipop-chainsaw-repop.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Dragami Games</em></figcaption></figure><p>Fans of extremely bloody, sugary sweet violence were likely excited to get their hands on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a> later <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-is-getting-a-sweet-switch-2-edition-upgrade-this-november">this month</a>. Unfortunately, you'll have to wait a little bit longer, as Dragami Games have announced a last-minute delay. The game will now be launching in <strong>early 2026</strong>.</p>
<p>But there's actually a good reason for the delay this time around — "While the title was initially planned to be released as a digital-only version, we received many requests for a physical edition following the announcement" the developer states <a href="https://x.com/Dragami_Games/status/1989252238347567413">on social media</a>.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067vmwqjl&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>838k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>"In response, and with the cooperation of multiple publishing partners, we are now able to prepare physical releases for multiple regions." The delay is to allow both the digital and physical versions to release at the same time.</p>

<p>So, we think we can all wait just a few more months to get the game on a cartridge, right? At least, we assume it'll be a full physical release.</p>
<p>We hope the Switch 2 Edition improves some of our issues with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/lollipop_chainsaw_repop">Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP</a> on the Switch, which suffered from rough performance. It's not the <em>best</em> game in the world, but it's a cult hit with many, so <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/lollipop-chainsaw-repop">we were disappointed with the rerelease</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Will you be grabbing Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP physically next year? Let us know in the usual spot.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:176339 @ 1763148616 -->
</section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://x.com/Dragami_Games/status/1989252238347567413" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/Dragami_Games/status/1989252238347567413">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/e9ffae2c398ca5610bc46e3f50df5831 @ 1763148616 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/lollipop-chainsaw-repops-switch-2-upgrade-gets-last-minute-delay]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Fallout Season 2 trailer shows us more of New Vegas]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/14/the-fallout-season-2-trailer-shows-us-more-of-new-vegas/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-fallout-season-2-trailer-shows-us-more-of-new-vegas.1354162/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Amazon had dropped a new trailer for season two of Fallout, based on the Bethesda franchise of the same name.&nbsp; We get to see more Lucy (Ella Purnell) and The Ghoul (Walton Goggins) as they travel to&nbsp; New Vegas, plus our first look at two of the new additions to the cast,&nbsp; Macaulay Culkin and Kumail Nanjiani.</p>
<p>The Fallout Season 2 trailer also reveals Moisés Arias returns as Lucy’s brother Norm and it will be interesting to see where his story goes, as at the end of Season 1, he discovered the real purpose of the Vaults.<br>
Fan favourite Mr. House will join the show, played by Justin Theroux, Barb Howard, the Ghouls wife from his previous life, is also shown a long with other returning characters such as Woody Thomas (Zach Cherry) and Lucy’s dad, Overseer Hank MacLean who is played by Kyle MacLachlan.</p>
<p><iframe title="Fallout Season Two | Official Trailer | Prime Video" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dS6q36IyKpk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Amazon previously announced that Season 2 of Fallout will drop an episode a week, rather than all at once, which is how Season One arrived. The second season, which was commissioned just a week after the first had aired.</p>
<p>The logline for season two does not reveal anything,&nbsp; “The new season will pick up in the aftermath of season one’s epic finale and take audiences along for a journey through the wasteland of the Mojave to the post-apocalyptic city of New Vegas.”</p>

<p>If you missed the first series, then we highly recommend it. You<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/04/11/fallout-season-1/">&nbsp;can check out my review here.</a> Season 3 has already been commissioned, so the story will continue. The Fallout television series is canon within the franchise so Fallout 5, whenever that gets round to being made, may incorporate characters and locations from the show.</p>
<p>“Fallout is one of the greatest game series of all time,” said&nbsp; Jonathon Nolan during <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/07/02/fallout-tv-series-teased-by-amazon-studios-and-kilter-films/">the show’s 2020 announcement</a>. “Each chapter of this insanely imaginative story has cost us countless hours we could have spent with family and friends. So we’re incredibly excited to partner with Todd Howard and the rest of the brilliant lunatics at Bethesda to bring this massive, subversive, and darkly funny universe to life with Amazon Studios.”</p>
<p>The first episode of Fallout Season 2 will be released on Amazon Prime video on 17th December 2025, with a new episode following on the same day for the next seven weeks.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7TsP09cZA7o">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/14/the-fallout-season-2-trailer-shows-us-more-of-new-vegas/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov 1.0 Launch Q&A – ‘We Are Aware of Our Significance, and We Have Very Big Plans’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/escape-from-tarkov-1-0-launch-qa-we-have-big-plans/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-from-tarkov-1-0-launch-q-a-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98we-are-aware-of-our-significance-and-we-have-very-big-plans%E2%80%99.1354159/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Saturday isn't usually a day of game releases, and yet it is the day that developer Battlestate Games <a href="https://wccftech.com/escape-from-tarkov-release-date-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has chosen to release version 1.0 of its highly popular game Escape from Tarkov</a>. Tomorrow, the game will officially exit early access and become available for the first time <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3932890/Escape_from_Tarkov/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on Steam</a>, Valve's premier global PC gaming platform.</p>



<p>We first covered the game over nine years ago, <a href="https://wccftech.com/escape-tarkov-interview-truly-hardcore-first-person-shooter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">with an interview conducted at Gamescom 2016</a>. The game then followed an unusual development pattern: Battlestate <a href="https://wccftech.com/escape-from-tarkov-closed-beta-start/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">soft-launched it with the Closed Beta</a>, which became available on July 28, 2017, granting access to all pre-order customers and dropping the Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA) so that players could freely discuss the game on the Internet.</p>



<p>Since then, the studio slowly but surely expanded and improved the game, which gained a large following of players and became the de facto ancestor of a new shooter subgenre: the extraction shooter, where players enter a zone, scavenge it for loot, and fight against AI and player-controlled enemies in a dangerous bid to extract with those precious resources intact.</p>



<p>This type of game is so popular nowadays that its mechanics are even spilling into other genres, as we're seeing with extraction RPGs like <a href="https://wccftech.com/project-pantheon-qa-a-post-apocalyptic-fantasy-extraction-arpg-from-the-makers-of-wolcen/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Project Pantheon</a> (now known as Gods, Death &amp; Reapers), <a href="https://wccftech.com/mistfall-hunter-is-a-dark-fantasy-soulslike-extraction-rpg-coming-to-pc-and-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mistfall Hunter</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/legacy-steel-sorcery-pvpve-extraction-arpg-gets-alpha-demo-for-steam-next-fest/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Legacy: Steel &amp; Sorcery</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/blizzard-veteran-finds-funding-innsmouth-mysteries-lovecraft-co-op-extraction-rpg/">Innsmouth Mysteries</a>, just to name a few.</p>



<p>Still, Escape from Tarkov remains as alluring as ever with its hardcore, realistic, and uncompromising extraction military first-person shooter experience. With mere hours left separating us from the long-awaited 1.0 release, here's our exclusive chat with Game Director Nikita Buyanov, in which we discussed the road to launch, what's in it (and what's not), the studio's opinion on the burgeoning genre, and what's next for Escape from Tarkov.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>The 1.0 release is, of course, a very large-scale update. It contains a massive amount of new content. The story alone is a huge part – players will finally get the chance to escape from Tarkov. If I'm not mistaken, preparing, developing, and integrating the release content took over 2 years. So yes – it's very large-scale.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>It's been over 8 years since you first released Escape from Tarkov to pre-order players. How would you describe this long journey with your community?</strong></p>



<p>This wasn't just a long journey; it's been a part of our lives—mine and everyone at the studio. We grew up ourselves, and along with us, an entire generation of players grew up. It's been a very interesting, exciting, and challenging journey.</p>



<p><strong>Were you aware that it would take such a long time to get the game to version 1.0, or did you expect to launch earlier?</strong></p>



<p>That's a very good question. Of course, we planned to release it sooner. But creating a game, especially one with almost a decade of background, is a very complex process. We faced numerous obstacles in the form of various subsystems; some things we rewrote from scratch, other things we were the first to do, things no one had ever done before us. I think we would have released Tarkov sooner if we could predict the future and knew what we would face. We knew what we were doing, but at times we didn't know how to do it.</p>



<p><strong>Escape from Tarkov is arguably the forefather of extraction shooters. How does it feel to see it gain such popularity, and what do you think about the genre's latest success, <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-has-sold-4-million-units-nexons-most-successful-global-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Embark's ARC Raiders</a>?</strong></p>



<p>We are aware of our significance: we managed to create not just a game, but an entire subgenre – the extraction shooter. And when we see games that find their audience, like ARC Raiders, which you mentioned, we are only happy about it. After all, the more good games, the better. Unfortunately, not everyone views us the same way and sees us as a competitor; everyone strives to proclaim themselves the "Tarkov killer" and tries to "knock Tarkov off its pedestal." We never had the goal of climbing onto that pedestal. We are simply making a game. A game that we ourselves enjoy, and which, in its uniqueness, is suited specifically for hardcore players. That's all.</p>



<p><strong>Will the 1.0 release's content be as substantial as previous large updates (e.g., Reserve or Streets)?</strong></p>



<p>The 1.0 release is, of course, a very large-scale update. It contains a massive amount of new content. The story alone is a huge part – players will finally get the chance to escape from Tarkov. If I'm not mistaken, preparing, developing, and integrating the release content took over 2 years. So yes – it's very large-scale.</p>



<p><strong>Will there be a heat map or death cam feature in version 1.0?</strong></p>



<p>No, these features will not be in the release version, but we still plan to implement them in the future.</p>



<p><strong>What’s the roadmap for expansions or content updates after 1.0?</strong></p>



<p>The first DLC players can expect after release is "Scav Life." Players will dive into the story of the Scavs and see them from a different perspective. They will have their own little Hideout, as well as progression opportunities. In fact, we have a very broad planning horizon – there will be new locations and major events. Tarkov hasn't been fully explored and still holds many secrets.</p>



<p><strong>Where do you think the game is when it comes to anti-cheat measures? Are you looking to make further enhancements?</strong></p>



<p>The release version carries many changes aimed directly at combating cheaters. We have done a tremendous amount of work in this area and sincerely hope that things will be good on this front. Nevertheless, we certainly don't plan to stop here and will continue to improve our anti-cheat mechanics. We have a very large department at the studio working exclusively on this problem.</p>



<p><strong>What improvements will be made to server stability and matchmaking?</strong></p>



<p>I must point out that server stability isn't 100% within our control. However, the aspects that are our responsibility, including matchmaking, have undergone many changes, and we expect significant improvement.</p>



<p><strong>Will there be further improvements in Quality of Life (QoL) for usability and user interface?</strong></p>



<p>Yes, this is also one of the important points that has our attention. We will continue to improve Quality of Life (QoL) and the User Interface (UI), both at release and after it.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>Yes, we are considering the possibility of porting the game to consoles. I think when we start working on it, we will implement full controller support. It's a very serious and interesting game design challenge – to create comfortable controls while accounting for all of Tarkov's unique mechanics.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>How are the narrative/story modes progressing? Is there anything you can share about that?</strong></p>



<p>The story consists of a chain of story quests. A clear storyline. It's not a narrative mode in the traditional sense. Answering your question, I can only say that players will finally have the opportunity to thoroughly understand what happened to the city and to escape from Tarkov.</p>



<p><strong>Are there plans to improve AI behavior, especially for Scavs and bosses?</strong></p>



<p>Of course, the Black Division alone is a significant addition. But the AI and the game as a whole have undergone a huge number of changes.</p>



<p><strong>Escape from Tarkov does not currently support controllers; however, a substantial number of PC players regularly utilize this control system in other games. Are you planning to add it in the future? Also, are you thinking about console ports?</strong></p>



<p>Yes, we are considering the possibility of porting the game to consoles. I think when we start working on it, we will implement full controller support. It's a very serious and interesting game design challenge – to create comfortable controls while accounting for all of Tarkov's unique mechanics.</p>



<p><strong>What else does the future hold for Battlestate Games now that a decade-long project is concluding?</strong></p>



<p>We have very big plans. We plan to expand and do even more – to continue developing and deepening Tarkov, and to expand the universe. You will all see it soon.</p>



<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/escape-from-tarkov-1-0-launch-qa-we-have-big-plans/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sims-Style Indie Life Sim Paralives Delayed to May Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paralives-delayed-may-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sims-style-indie-life-sim-paralives-delayed-to-may-next-year.1354156/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Alex Massé has announced that upcoming&nbsp;<em>Sims</em>-style indie life sim&nbsp;<em>Paralives&nbsp;</em>is being delayed, and it's a pretty hefty delay at that, so you won't be playing this one for a while, unfortunately.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/ParalivesGame/status/1989347579856113871" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">message</a> on social media, Massé announces that&nbsp;<em>Paralives&nbsp;</em>will now be launching on May 25th next year, having been previously <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paralives-december-early-access-release-date" rel="nofollow">slated for an Early Access release next month</a>.</p>

<p>Massé says that although the&nbsp;<em>Paralives&nbsp;</em>team was confident the game would be ready for December, expanding playtesting beyond the initial player base showed that the game "isn't up to the standard [the team] wanted it to meet for release".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/paralives-delayed-early-access-workout.jpg?itok=_3Is5cSx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/paralives-delayed-early-access-workout.jpg?itok=gx47yT4K 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Paralives&nbsp;</em>won't be launching in December after all.</figcaption></figure><p>According to Massé, those who have tried out&nbsp;<em>Paralives&nbsp;</em>are still enjoying the "flexibility and customization" of the game's Paramaker and Build Modes, but the Live Mode is still playing host to "impactful bugs", and on top of that, there's "a lack of activities" in&nbsp;<em>Paralives</em>' main town.</p>

<p>Massé goes on to explain that life sims of this kind, which he calls "doll-house life simulation" games (among which games like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/inzoi-release-date-delayed" rel="nofollow">Krafton's&nbsp;<em>inZoi</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em>and the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paradox-profits-life-by-you-canceled" rel="nofollow">now-canceled&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paradox-profits-life-by-you-canceled" rel="nofollow">Life by You</a>&nbsp;</em>mingle), are "really three games in one": a building game, a character creator, and a simulation.</p>

<p>The build mode and character creator are in a place Massé and his team are happy with, but the simulation element requires "a bit more time" for polish, ensuring that&nbsp;<em>Paralives&nbsp;</em>offers "a great first experience" for those who decide to check it out.</p>

<p>It's not all bad news, though; on November 25th, a 45-minute "uninterrupted Live mode gameplay" stream will be happening on the&nbsp;<em>Paralives&nbsp;</em>YouTube channel, so more info is on the way.</p>




<p>If you want to keep up with&nbsp;<em>Paralives&nbsp;</em>as development continues ahead of its new May Early Access release date, you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1118520/Paralives/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">wishlist the game on Steam</a> right now. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/paralives-delayed-may-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision Responds To Call Of Duty: Black Ops 7‘s AI-Generated Artwork]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-ai-art-activision-statement-blops7-steam-ps5-2000644397</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-responds-to-call-of-duty-black-ops-7%E2%80%98s-ai-generated-artwork.1354138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Stop me if you’ve heard this one before: The latest <em>Call of Duty</em> game seems to contain AI-generated art that doesn’t look very good, and people aren’t happy about it. This time, it’s the newly released <a href="https://kotaku.com/cod-blops-7-campaign-coop-always-online-pause-co-op-xp-challenges-2000644358"><em>Black Ops 7.</em></a></p> <p>On November 14, <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em> launched across consoles and PC. And within a few hours, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CODBlackOps7/comments/1owqr38/so_these_calling_cards_are_definitely_ai/">players online were sharing screenshots of artwork</a> within the game that they believe is AI-generated slop. And it’s hard not to agree.</p> <p><a href="https://x.com/Kumesicles/status/1988984517823197541">Looking at some of this artwork</a>, including in-game player banners, I notice the telltale signs of AI imagery, including at least one cartoon character that appears to have <a href="https://x.com/Kumesicles/status/1989327996126126344">six fingers</a>. Eyelines also don’t match up, and some objects seem vaguely defined. And almost all of it just looks really bland. Keep in mind, these are rewards you get for completing challenges, which makes it even more depressing; gee, thanks, some machine-vomited “art.”</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Almost every single campaign and endgame calling card in bo7 is like Grok Ai generated images its so insane <a href="https://t.co/5bCGNJQmgn">pic.twitter.com/5bCGNJQmgn</a></p> <p>— Kume (@Kumesicles) <a href="https://twitter.com/Kumesicles/status/1988984517823197541?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 13, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Other players have shared screenshots of what looks like AI-generated artwork within<em> Black Ops 7’s</em> campaign, which this year is online-only and designed around multiplayer. Of course, we can’t know for sure which pieces of art in the latest<em> Call of Duty</em> were created by humans, which were generated by a machine, and which are a combo, with humans touching up crappy generated imagery.</p>

 <p>But we do know for a fact that <em>Black Ops 7</em> has AI art in it, as confirmed by the game’s Steam store page: “Our team uses generative AI tools to help develop some in-game assets.” This is the same disclaimer found on <a href="https://kotaku.com/black-ops-6-ai-calling-card-loading-screen-blops-6-cod-1851766313"><em>Black Ops 6′</em>s store page, which was added in February</a>.</p>

 <p><em>Kotaku</em> contacted Activision about the AI art in <em>Black Ops 7 </em>and was sent this statement:</p> <blockquote><p>“Like so many around the world, we use a variety of digital tools, including AI tools, to empower and support our teams to create the best gaming experiences possible for our players. Our creative process continues to be led by the talented individuals in our studios.”</p></blockquote> <h2><em>Black Ops 7</em> and <em>Black Ops 6</em> both use AI art</h2> <p>If that sounds familiar, it’s because this is similar to what Activision and Treyarch said about <em>Black Ops 6</em> earlier this year, following months of players accusing the devs of using AI slop. In an interview with <em>IGN</em> in August, <a href="https://kotaku.com/black-ops-7-generative-ai-call-duty-gamescom-2025-slop-2000618833">Treyarch associate creative director Miles Leslie talked about using AI art</a> in <em>Black Ops 7.</em></p>

 <p>The developer claimed that “everything that goes into the game is touched by the team a hundred percent,” but did admit that AI tools are used to “help.” As to why some clearly AI-generated art that was seemingly not fixed up by a human slipped into <em>Black Ops 6,</em> Leslie told <em>IGN</em> it was an “accident.”</p> <p data-cy="paragraph">“That was never the intention,” said Leslie. “We’ve come out and been very clear that we use these as tools to help the team, but they do not replace any of the fantastic team members we have that are doing the final touches and building that content to put it in the game. So everything you play: human-created and touched. AI tools in the world we live in: it’s how do we streamline it? That’s really the goal. Not replace, but streamline.”</p> <p data-cy="paragraph">And with players discovering bland AI-generated images in <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em> and Activision openly confirming it and embracing it, it seems this is&nbsp;just how it works now, I guess.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-ai-art-activision-statement-blops7-steam-ps5-2000644397]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fans Think The Pokémon Animal Crossing Game May Be Set In A Post-Apocalypse]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-post-apocalypse-snorlax-pikachu-fuschia-2000644400</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fans-think-the-pok%C3%A9mon-animal-crossing-game-may-be-set-in-a-post-apocalypse.1354135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-animal-crossing-switch-2-nintendo-direct-2000625331"><i><span>Pokémon Pokopia</span></i></a> <span>is Omega Force’s swing at a cute and cozy </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>life sim in the vein of </span><i><span>Animal Crossing </span></i><span>or </span><i><span>Stardew Valley</span></i><span>. You play as a Ditto that transforms into a human and helps cultivate a new home for the local Pokémon wildlife, and though it’s a little unnerving seeing the beady-eyed human running around, it seems like a fun enough premise to support </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>’s life-sim gameplay. However, the more we see of the game, the more it seems like there might be a dark truth lurking beneath the surface, and fans are running wild with theories.</span></p> <p><span>Though it’s unclear how the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>world may have gotten to this point, the prevailing theory is that the world of </span><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>may take place in some kind of post-apocalyptic timeline where humans and Pokémon have been separated for many years after some kind of disaster. There are clues hinting at this possibility dating as far back as the original reveal trailer from September. Ditto is shown escaping its Poké Ball in a cave that looks like it was, at one point, occupied by its trainer. The ‘mon looks at a Pokédex on the ground that is covered in dirt, and transforms into the trainer seen in a photo on the device. The fact that the dex has clearly been exposed to the elements for some time is concerning on its own, but there are more hints that something is amiss in </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>’s world than that.</span></p>

 <p><span>Yesterday, Nintendo released an extended </span><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>trailer that revealed a few new Pokémon variants, all of which seem to reflect the passage of time and lack of human interaction. A Snorlax is shown covered in moss, as if having slept long enough for nature to have overgrown its massive body. A Smeargle in the game is covered in paint, as if it has been painting without stopping or cleaning itself up. Then, there’s the biggest surprise: a white Pikachu named Peakychu who seems to be sickly, or even ghost-like. Could she be a specter of a long-dead Pikachu? Perhaps.</span></p>

  <p><span>The most explicit confirmation we get that humanity has been gone for a while is in Professor Tangrowth. This vine-covered Pokémon appears to be greying a bit and wears a broken TM machine like a doctor’s head mirror, as if it scavenged it in the rubble. In the trailer, we see Tangrowth tell Ditto that humans and Pokémon once lived in this place, but now that its buildings are destroyed and plants withered, he hasn’t seen anyone else in “quite some time.” He says this as he’s literally rummaging through the remains of what looks like a Pokémon Center that is now crumbled and covered in overgrowth. Whatever happened here that drove people and Pokémon away happened a long time ago. Some fans point out that what we see of the town’s layout looks similar to that of </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@slantedgaming/video/7572354779658161463"><span>Fuchsia City</span></a><span> from </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue</span></i><span>, and given that </span><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>seems to take place near a collection of islands, it’s not out of the question that this is a post-disaster version of the coastal city.</span></p> <p><span>Whatever is going on, it’s clear that something terrible happened to this place that we’ll be sprucing up in </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>. </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>loves to delve into dark, life-or-death situations from time to time; I’m just surprised it might be doing so in its foray into the genre that’s supposed to be about feel-good vibes. We’ll know more when the game comes to Switch 2 on March 5.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-post-apocalypse-snorlax-pikachu-fuschia-2000644400]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision Responds To Black Ops 7 AI Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/activision-responds-black-ops-7-ai-claims/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-responds-to-black-ops-7-ai-claims.1354132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-157940">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Activision has responded to claims regarding the use of generative AI to create calling cards in Call of Duty: Black Ops 7.</p>



<p>The response comes in the form of an email statement sent to Insider Gaming by an Activision spokesperson. In the statement, which you can read below, the company says that it uses a “variety” of tools, “including AI tools” for their development.</p>







<p><strong>“Like so many around the world, we use a variety of digital tools, including AI tools, to empower and support our teams to create the best gaming experiences possible for our players,”</strong> the statement reads, which was first given to <a href="https://xboxera.com/2025/11/14/activision-responds-on-genai-use-in-black-ops-7/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Era</a> before the rep responded to Insider Gaming’s request. <strong>“Our creative process continues to be led by the talented individuals in our studios.”</strong></p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out for more specific clarification as to what assets were generated by AI. Should that get a response, it will be published on Insider-Gaming.com and in the new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/insider-gaming-mobile-app-membership-tiers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming App</a>.</p>







<p>What are your thoughts on Activision’s statement regarding the use of AI in Black Ops 7? Leave your thoughts down in the comments and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-delays-earnings-report-halts-share-trading/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft delaying their earnings report</a>&nbsp;and suspending stock trading just minutes be for it was scheduled to release. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards/">
                                Activision Accused of Using Generative AI Art For Black Ops 7 Calling Cards                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Activision has been accused of using generative AI art for assets like calling cards in Call of Duty: Black Ops 7.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-hellrunners-zombie-game-never-made-it/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-hellrunners-zombie-game-never-made-it/">
                                EXCLUSIVE: Dying Light: Hellrunners—The Zombie Game That Never Made It                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Dying Light: Hellrunners would have represented a sudden genre pivot for Techland, but the game never saw the light of day.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-isnt-the-only-horizon-multiplayer-game-coming/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-isnt-the-only-horizon-multiplayer-game-coming/">
                                Horizon Steel Frontiers Isn’t the Only Horizon Multiplayer Game Coming                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Horizon Steel Frontiers isn’t the only multiplayer game coming for the franchise; Guerrilla Games has something in the works as well. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-enhanced-version-is-still-coming-insider-reveals/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-enhanced-version-is-still-coming-insider-reveals/">
                                Red Dead Redemption 2 Enhanced Version is Still Coming, Insider Reveals                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The release of Red Dead Redemption’s current-gen port doesn’t ‘negate’ the development of Red Dead Redemption 2’s Enhanced Version. </p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/activision-responds-black-ops-7-ai-claims/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Buy Just Dropped the Best Meta Quest 3S VR Headset Deals for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-just-dropped-the-best-meta-quest-3s-vr-headset-deals-for-black-friday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-buy-just-dropped-the-best-meta-quest-3s-vr-headset-deals-for-black-friday.1354129/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Up to $100 off in savings, plus get two free games.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">As part of its early Black Friday Doorbuster Sale, Best Buy just dropped the best deals we may see this entire month on the <a href="https://zdcs.link/zEJ1yo?object_uuid=97e13d21-56b7-4e99-996c-30bf2d7a9f7a&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Meta Quest 3S VR headset</a>. Not only do you get $50-$70 off in instant discounts ($249 for the 128GB model and $329 for the 256GB model), you also get a bonus $50 Best Buy gift card with your purchase. That's basically getting a Quest for as low as $199. This is the best deal I've seen this year on a Quest 3S headset with warranty. Recently we've seen deals on refurbished models, but in this case the advantage of buying new is that you also get a couple of free games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Note: </strong>The 128GB model includes two games, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/batman-arkham-shadow-review-meta-quest-3">Batman: Arkham Shadow</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-walking-dead-saints-and-sinners-review">The Walking Dead: Saints and Sinners</a>. The 256GB model includes one game, Batman: Arkham Shadow.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Meta Quest 3S Starting at $249 Plus $50 Best Buy Gift Card</h2><div id="207786" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="46006467-4f90-4d47-ad0b-ab15ae567c6a"><div><p>$50 Best Buy Gift Card With Purchase</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Meta Quest 3S 128GB VR Headset</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes Batman: Arkham VR and The Walking Dead: Saints and Sinners games.</p></div></div><div catalogid="46006467-4f90-4d47-ad0b-ab15ae567c6a" id="222595"><div id="222595" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>$50 Best Buy Gift Card With Purchase</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Meta Quest 3S 256GB VR Headset</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes Batman: Arkham VR game.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Meta Quest 3S is the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-vr-headset">best standalone consumer-oriented VR headset under $300</a>. It costs 40% less than the Quest 3 and yet retains most of its hardware and functionality, including the Snapdragon XR2 Gen 2 processor, Touch Plus controllers with inside-out tracking, and mixed reality passthrough. However, whereas the Quest 3 has been updated with a new pancake lens design, the Quest 3S retains the Fresnel optics of the Quest 2. Although obviously not as good as the Quest 3, the Quest 3S still very much offers an immersive visual experience that is sure to impress. I myself logged in hundreds of hours on the Quest 2 before I moved on to the Quest 3. For newcomers who want to try out VR gaming without investing tons of money, of for people who want to give this as a gift to someone who's never tried VR, I would recommend the Quest 3S over the Quest, especially at this price.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>TL;DR Quest 3S vs Quest 3:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Same </strong>Snapdragon XR2 Gen 2 processor</li><li><strong>Same </strong>Touch Plus controllers</li><li><strong>Same </strong>120Hz refresh rate</li><li><strong>Same </strong>Mixed reality passthrough functionality</li><li><strong>Same</strong> tetherless and tethered functionality</li><li>Quest 3 has <strong>sharper </strong>resolution (2064x2208 vs 1832x1920)</li><li>Quest 3 has <strong>better </strong>lens array (pancake vs fresnel)</li><li>Quest 3 has <strong>lower </strong>FOV (104°/96° vs 96°/90°)</li><li>Quest 3 has <strong>higher </strong>storage capacity (512GB vs 128GB)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric Song is the IGN commerce manager in charge of finding the best gaming and tech deals every day. When Eric isn't hunting for deals for other people at work, he's hunting for deals for himself during his free time.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 14, 2025 5:50 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-just-dropped-the-best-meta-quest-3s-vr-headset-deals-for-black-friday]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7 Developers Used AI Tools, But Creative Process Is Led By Humans, Activision Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-7-developers-used-ai-tools-but-creative-process-is-led-by-humans-activision-says/1100-6536232/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-7-developers-used-ai-tools-but-creative-process-is-led-by-humans-activision-says.1354126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536232">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Activision has once again confirmed that AI tools were used in the development of Call of Duty: Black Ops 7, which is in keeping with tradition for the franchise, as Black Ops 6 utilized AI tools as well. In a statement, Activision said the creative process is handled by humans, with AI tools helping out. Back in August, Activision explained that developers working on Black Ops 7 used generative AI, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-dev-embraces-ai-but-not-to-replace-humans/1100-6534113/" data-ref-id="1100-6534113">"none of that goes in-game."</a></p><p>"Like so many around the world, we use a variety of digital tools, including AI tools, to empower and support our teams to create the best gaming experiences possible for our players. Our creative process continues to be led by the talented individuals in our studios," the company said.</p><p>Black Ops 7 launched today, November 14, and people quickly noticed that a number of Calling Cards that appear to use the "Ghibli-style" anime look, with <a href="https://frvr.com/blog/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-is-littered-with-ai-art-slop-because-your-70-means-nothing-anymore/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">people theorizing</a> that Activision used AI to create these images.</p><p>The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3606480/Call_of_Duty_Black_Ops_7/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Black Ops 7 Steam page</a> discloses that, "Our team uses generative AI tools to help develop some in-game assets." The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2933620/Call_of_Duty_Black_Ops_6/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">same exact language</a> is featured on Black Ops 6's Steam page. Activision has not clarified exactly what content in Black Ops 7 was made with the help of AI tools.</p><h2><strong>Call of Duty's past use of AI</strong></h2><p>An anonymous source within Activision <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/ai-is-already-taking-jobs-in-the-video-game-industry/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">told Wired in 2024</a> concept artists working on Call of Duty were "forced to use AI to aid in their work." The report added that "a lot of 2D artists" got laid off in early 2024 as part of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-cuts-650-more-gaming-jobs-but-no-studios-closed-or-games-canceled/1100-6526439/" data-ref-id="1100-6526439">Microsoft's wider job cuts</a>, though whether or not this had anything to do with AI is unknown.</p><p>Activision has said its plan for AI tools is to use them to help "streamline" game development and not replace humans.</p><p>If content created at least in part by generative AI tools has made its way into past Call of Duty games, that was "by accident," Treyarch's Miles Leslie said. He may be referring to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-uses-generative-ai-for-some-content-activision-admits/1100-6529691/" data-ref-id="1100-6529691">multiple instances of AI-generated content in Call of Duty that fans have spotted over the years.</a></p><p>Leslie also stressed that Treyarch's use of AI tools is for efforts that "help the team" but not as a means to "replace any of the fantastic team members" who are building content for Call of Duty.</p><h2><strong>What other developers think of AI</strong></h2><p>A survey of game developers globally found that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/study-finds-majority-of-game-dev-companies-use-generative-ai-already-despite-worker-concerns/1100-6528919/" data-ref-id="1100-6528919">a majority of studios are using AI technologies to build games, despite concerns from workers.</a> Recently, Embark's popular PvPvE game Arc Raiders caused a stir in some circles <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-sparks-debate-over-ai-voice-acting-in-games/1100-6536146/" data-ref-id="1100-6536146">regarding its use of AI voice lines.</a> Call of Duty's main competitor in the FPS space, Battlefield, returned this year with Battlefield 6, and the developers <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/genai-is-very-seducing-battlefield-6-boss-says/1100-6535356/" data-ref-id="1100-6535356">did not use generative AI.</a> However, a top Battlefield boss said EA's development teams use generative AI in the early development cycle, and the tools are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/genai-is-very-seducing-battlefield-6-boss-says/1100-6535356/" data-ref-id="1100-6535356">"very seducing."</a></p><p>AI has been a controversial topic in video games and beyond, in part over fears about job losses. Electronic Arts CEO Andrew Wilson has said the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-ceo-on-how-ai-will-impact-video-games-and-the-people-who-make-them/1100-6513969/" data-ref-id="1100-6513969">rise in AI will lead to job losses in the short term</a> but will ultimately create more jobs total, just like what happened with previous labor revolutions.</p><p>Microsoft recently laid off thousands, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-xbox-games-cancelled-and-studios-closed-in-microsofts-latest-mass-layoffs/2900-6726/" data-ref-id="2900-6726">including deep cuts at Xbox</a>. One affected studio was Candy Crush developer King, with some affected staff saying <a href="https://mobilegamer.biz/laid-off-king-staff-set-to-be-replaced-by-the-ai-tools-they-helped-build-say-sources/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">they were replaced by the AI tools they helped design.</a></p><p>Black Ops 7 is out now for PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, and PC. It's also playable via Xbox Game Pass, and you don't have to pay the new, higher rate, as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-sign-up-best-deal-available-now/1100-6535504/" data-ref-id="1100-6535504">most major retailers have not adopted Microsoft's 50% Game Pass price hike.</a></p><p>For more, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-review/1900-6418441/" data-ref-id="1900-6418441">Black Ops 7 campaign review</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-tips-for-multiplayer/2900-7104/" data-ref-id="2900-7104">tips for multiplayer</a> in the gallery below.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-7-developers-used-ai-tools-but-creative-process-is-led-by-humans-activision-says/1100-6536232/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond The Stars]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/podcasts/beyond-the-stars/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beyond-the-stars.1354123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
      
    

<div data-post-info="">
      <p><span>Published:</span>
        <time datetime="2025-11-14T01:31:33">November 14, 2025, 1:31 pm</time>
      </p>
    </div>
    <article>
      <p>On this week's Aftermath Hours, Chris, Riley, and Gita raise our heads above the water of Aftermath’s <a href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-relaunch-announcement/" rel="noreferrer">relaunched website</a> to talk, excitingly, about things that aren’t relaunching a website. To start, Chris and Gita talk about the movie <em>Bugonia</em>, a remake of 2003’s <em>Save the Green Planet</em>. We talk about how it’s different from the original, for better and worse, and what it says about class, society, and whether or not humanity is a failed experiment.</p><p>Then we talk about <em>Breaking Bad</em> creator Vince Gilligan’s new Apple TV show <a href="https://aftermath.site/pluribus-is-an-apocalypse-story-for-people-who-go-to-therapy/" rel="noreferrer"><em>Pluribus</em></a><em>.</em> We’re a bit divided on it, with some of us liking the tough exterior of its main character and others not quite sold yet. We discuss where we hope the show goes–no “Carol learns to love,” please!--and, if the point of art is to communicate with others, whether or not art can exist in the show’s world.</p><p>Last, Chris pitches us all on how great <em>Lumines Arise </em>is before we move on to the mailbag, where we appreciate the newly-announced <a href="https://aftermath.site/steam-machine-steam-frame-steam-controller-good-choices/" rel="noreferrer">Steam Machine</a>, discuss what games it should launch with, and talk about where we find a respite from staring at the news all day. </p><p>You can find this week's episode below and on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/7qtlX6MNeEoyNuHBU0chUJ?si=a2f12b75911f43cb&amp;ref=aftermath.site">Spotify</a>, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/aftermath-hours/id1727407094?ref=aftermath.site">Apple</a>, or wherever else you prefer to listen to podcasts. If you like what you hear, make sure to leave a review to tell the rest of the hivemind how much you like it.</p>
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->

<!--kg-card-end: html-->

    </article>

        

      

          

  
  
  
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/podcasts/beyond-the-stars/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Had No "Intention To Hinder Or Invalidate" Third-Party Docks For Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/nintendo-had-no-intention-to-hinder-or-invalidate-third-party-docks-for-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-had-no-intention-to-hinder-or-invalidate-third-party-docks-for-switch-2.1354093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Manufacturers are working on updates to their docks</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="63d4585372042"><a title="Nintendo Switch 2 with S3 MAX TV Dock Station by Antank" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/63d4585372042/nintendo-switch-2-with-s3-max-tv-dock-station-by-antank.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Gavin Lane / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Following reports that some Switch 2 owners are having issues with third-party docks, Nintendo has addressed the issue.</p>
<p>In a response to <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/video-games/nintendo/nintendo-says-it-has-no-intention-of-blocking-third-party-switch-2-docks-following-firmware-update-that-stopped-them-from-working-accessory-makers-scramble-to-deploy-workaround">Tom's Hardware</a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-just-blocked-third-party-switch-2-docks-and-it-sucks-2000644081">Kotaku</a>, a representative told the outlets that "Nintendo does not have any intention to hinder or invalidate legal third-party dock compatibility."</p>
<p>The issue of third-party compatibility <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Switch/comments/1ou7lo8/psa_switch_2_v2100_disables_third_party_docks/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=post_embed&amp;utm_content=post_body&amp;embed_host_url=https://www.tomshardware.com/video-games/nintendo/nintendo-says-it-has-no-intention-of-blocking-third-party-switch-2-docks-following-firmware-update-that-stopped-them-from-working-accessory-makers-scramble-to-deploy-workaround">cropped up earlier this week</a> after the Nintendo Switch 2 Version 21.0.0 update dropped. Many who have updated their consoles to the latest version have found that their third-party docks are no longer working with the console.</p>
<p>Some have even said that the official Switch 2 dock also stopped working after the update, but a quick restart has fixed this.</p>
<p>While not all third-party docks are affected, and some manufacturers have managed to put out hotfixes, it seems like the issues caused by the latest update are completely unintentional. Still, some manufacturers are suggesting Switch 2 owners to hold off on updating their console <em>until</em> they've managed to get a fix going.</p>

<p>"Nintendo Switch 2 outputs audiovisuals once it detects that it is docked into a Nintendo Switch 2 Dock," the representative explained, reiterating that the original Switch works similarly.</p>
<p>The Switch 2 dock situation has been a little tenuous in the early months of the console's life. Reports from July this year suggest that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/switch-2-usb-c-chip-might-be-breaking-compatibility-with-third-party-docks">the USB-C chip may be responsible</a> for some other compatibility issues. These issues are unrelated to the latest update.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Have you been having dock issues with your Switch 2? Glad to see Nintendo acknowledge this? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193896 @ 1763148900 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.tomshardware.com/video-games/nintendo/nintendo-says-it-has-no-intention-of-blocking-third-party-switch-2-docks-following-firmware-update-that-stopped-them-from-working-accessory-makers-scramble-to-deploy-workaround" rel="noopener" href="https://www.tomshardware.com/video-games/nintendo/nintendo-says-it-has-no-intention-of-blocking-third-party-switch-2-docks-following-firmware-update-that-stopped-them-from-working-accessory-makers-scramble-to-deploy-workaround">tomshardware.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://kotaku.com/nintendo-just-blocked-third-party-switch-2-docks-and-it-sucks-2000644081" rel="noopener" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-just-blocked-third-party-switch-2-docks-and-it-sucks-2000644081">kotaku.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/69b1d31e4a00cdde809c26b29239ba08 @ 1763151293 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/nintendo-had-no-intention-to-hinder-or-invalidate-third-party-docks-for-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What We Played – Forestrike, Black Ops 7 & Anno 117]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/14/what-we-played-forestrike-black-ops-7-anno-117/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-we-played-%E2%80%93-forestrike-black-ops-7-anno-117.1354090/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>There’s been a very different tone to the games news this week, with the juggernaut of Call of Duty feeling like it’s lost a step in the face of some serious competition. Battlefield 6 is out there doing a straight up war shooter, Arc Raiders has made an extraction shooter love-in, and now here’s Black Ops 7, where there’s just a baffling direction for the campaign.</p>
<p>It takes some of the psychological mish-mash of Black Ops 3’s story, which people hated back in the day, the open world missions of Modern Warfare III, which people hated a couple years ago, practically makes co-op mandatory, and then has an Endgame post-campaign thing that will have to compete for attention with both the main Zombies mode and Dead Ops Arcade. It’s barmy, especially compared to the strengths of last year’s game.</p>
<p>The multiplayer does feel pretty good, though, which is the bulk of what people will play.</p>

<p><strong>Aran</strong> chimed in first, having played Forestrike and Umami for review. You’ll have to wait for the latter, but barring some snags, he enjoyed the puzzle-like take on the martial arts brawler in Forestrike.</p>

<p>As we continue through the busy season, <strong>Jim’s</strong> had to put Battlefield 6 on the back burner. He picked up a copy of Metal Gear Solid Delta in time for the Fox Hunt multiplayer, which is “a surprisingly competent online shooter”, and I dragged him into the Black Ops 7 single player with me, but in the main he’s “swapped body armour and boot laces for a fresh white toga for Anno 117: Pax Romana – it’s a series I’ve always been interested in playing but never got around to biting the bullet. Thoroughly enjoying my time as a governor in Ancient Rome, crafting city districts that not only perform well but look fab.”</p>

<p>Another conscript for Black Ops 7 was <strong>Miguel</strong>, who was about as baffled by some of the design choices as I was. Much clearer was playing some time with Tekken 8 and having fun with the King vs. Armour King matches. He’s also played the Atelier Ryza Deluxe trilogy pack, and went delved into his “niche weird Japanese action game” catalogue for D3 Publisher’s 2020 anime-girl-zombie-fighting action game OneeChanbara Origin. Sounds about right!</p>
<p><strong>Laura</strong> has continued to juggle Jurassic World Evolution 3 and Silent Hill 2 remake, getting some tonal whiplash from creepy nurses trying to kill her and being a proud park-building surrogate mum when the Megalodons brought a baby Megalodon into the world. Bless ’em!</p>
<p>Another genre juggler was <strong>Steve</strong>, going between the new SpongeBob SquarePants game and the classic horror of Tormented Souls 2, “which has been delayed somewhat after some bad ammo management put me in an impossible situation – what’s known in the trade as ‘Code Veronica-ing yourself’.” He’s also been a bit disappointed by the Sacred 2 Remaster.</p>

<p><strong>Ade</strong> has had the “fifty-something runs” which sound nasty until you realise he’s talking about Hades 2, where he reckons he’s nearing the end credits and would like to recommend it very highly.</p>
<p>And finally, <strong>Tuffcub</strong> played more Arc Raiders, “which is a lovely cuddly hug that reminds that despite how rubbish the world is, there are decent people in it.”</p>
<p>Now then, what have you played?</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/14/what-we-played-forestrike-black-ops-7-anno-117/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Against All Odds, Concord Is Playable Again]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/concord-servers-delisted-shutdown-revive-fan-modders-2000644390</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/against-all-odds-concord-is-playable-again.1354084/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i><span>Concord</span></i><span>’s shutdown was one of the highest-profile failures in not just video games, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/concord-sony-biggest-flop-failure-box-office-1851676475"><span>but all of entertainment last year</span></a><span>. Sony </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/concord-shutting-down-closing-servers-refunds-ps5-1851638566"><span>pulled the plug</span></a><span> on its </span><i><span>Guardians of the Galaxy</span></i><span>-esque hero shooter days after its PS5 and PC launch failed to bring in players, and then subsequently </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/concord-firewalk-studios-relaunch-ps5-sony-playstation-1851652811"><span>shut down its developer, Firewalk Studios</span></a><span>. It was a highly publicized mess of mismanagement and callous corporate calculus, and it was also a damn shame because the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/concord-ps5-toxic-haters-heroes-shutdown-1851646309"><span>game was actually pretty alright</span></a><span>. Although the game seemed lost to time, some fans have taken it upon themselves to try and bring it back with fan-made servers, so if you wanted to see what all the fuss was about, you may have the chance.</span></p> <p><span>A group of fan modders has been working to rebuild </span><i><span>Concord</span></i><span>’s backend and create new servers (thanks, </span><a href="https://thegamepost.com/sony-concord-playable-again-custom-servers/"><i><span>TheGamePost</span></i></a><span>), and have officially played a match of the game once thought lost to time.&nbsp;</span></p>  <p><span>Red, one of the modders leading the project alongside Real, open_wizard, and Gwog, posted an update on Discord letting folks know the group had managed to play a match, though there are still a lot of bugs to iron out before they’re ready to open it up to more players.</span></p> <blockquote><p><span>After a long time of reverse engineering &amp; server development, we just managed to play a match of </span><i><span>Concord</span></i><span>! This is the match I played with open_wizard (don’t mind my horrible aim, I spend so much time reverse engineering that I no longer have the time to actually play games)</span></p> <p><span>The project is still WIP, it’s playable, but buggy. Once our servers are fully set up, we’ll begin doing some private playtesting, if anyone here wants to join those playtests, let me know (include what region/time zone you are in for convenience).</span></p></blockquote> <p><span>I still consider </span><i><span>Concord</span></i><span>’s fate</span> <span>to be a consequence of Sony’s terrible fumbling of its ill-advised live service pivot, but it’s always a bad thing when games are wiped from existence by their owners. A lot of people worked hard on </span><i><span>Concord</span></i><span>, and it deserves the dignity of being playable, even if Sony isn’t supporting it. So shoutout to fans for picking up the torch.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/concord-servers-delisted-shutdown-revive-fan-modders-2000644390]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision Accused of Using Generative AI Art For Black Ops 7 Calling Cards]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards.1354081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><strong>Update: </strong>Activision has issued the following statement to Insider Gaming.</p>



<blockquote>
<p><em>Like so many around the world, we use a variety of digital tools, including AI tools, to empower and support our teams to create the best gaming experiences possible for our players. Our creative process continues to be led by the talented individuals in our studios.</em></p>
</blockquote>







<hr>



<p><strong>Original: </strong>Activision has been known to use generative AI in Call of Duty in the past, but now there are accusations of it being used in a new way within Call of Duty: Black Ops 7.</p>



<p>Many have taken to social media to show examples of what looks to be generative AI art in Black Ops 7 calling cards.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-possibly-ai-in-black-ops-7">What Is Possibly AI In Black Ops 7?</h2>



<p>First shared by <a href="https://x.com/Kumesicles/status/1988982194916999619" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kume on Twitter</a>, the ones being called out specifically come from challenges like “Over Here Buddy”, “Peekaboo”, “Reeled In”, and more. The cards in question use Studio Ghibli art style, which has been easy to generate in most AI art programs. </p>



<p>The use of AI is disclosed on the game’s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3606480/Call_of_Duty_Black_Ops_7/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam store page</a>. However, it doesn’t say what was done. Instead, it simply reads, “Our team uses generative AI tools to help develop some in game assets.” So, seeing things like calling cards be, possibly, the work of AI shouldn’t come as <a href="https://x.com/MikeStrawMedia/status/1865107470751834402" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">much of a surprise</a>. That said, it still might not sit well with players. </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Activision for comment on the claims. As of publishing, no response has been received, but should one come, it will be added to this story.</p>



<p>If that doesn’t bother you, Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/black-ops-7-loaded-xbox-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">is available now</a> for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/black-ops-7-amazon-us-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation 5</a>, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, and PC.  </p>



<p>What do you think of the possibility of generative AI being used for things like calling cards in Black Ops 7? Leave your thoughts down in the comments and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/after-pivot-ai-first-krafton-voluntary-resignations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Krafton offering employees voluntary resignations</a> just weeks after announcing its pivot to being an “AI first” company. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>



<p><em><strong>NOTE:</strong> Insider Gaming may earn affiliate commission if you purchase items through links on Insider Gaming. Read more about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/privacy-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">affiliate commission here</a>.</em></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BROK: The Brawl Bar coming to PS5, PS4, Xbox One, and Switch on December 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/brok-the-brawl-bar-coming-to-ps5-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-december-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/brok-the-brawl-bar-coming-to-ps5-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-december-2.1354078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A standalone release on consoles.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > COWCAT [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cowcat">COWCAT</a> will release <em><a title="Games > BROK: The Brawl Bar" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/brok-the-brawl-bar">BROK: The Brawl Bar</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,847 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,532 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,307 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,979 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on December 2 for $9.99 / €9.99, the developer announced. <span id="more-1007127"></span></p><p>The game, an off-beat spin-off to the <a title="Genres > Point-and-Click [80 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/point-and-click">point-and-click adventure game</a> / <a title="Genres > Beat 'Em Up [165 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/beat-em-up">beat ’em up</a> hybrid <em><a title="Games > BROK the InvestiGator [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/brok-the-investigator">BROK the InvestiGator</a></em>, was initially released for the PC version of the game as <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2931330/BROK_the_InvestiGator__The_Brawl_Bar/" target="_blank">paid downloadable content</a>. For the console release it will be available as a standalone game. A bundle will also be available for $24.99 / €24.99.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via COWCAT:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Brok, a former boxer turned detective, stumbles upon an underground bar hidden deep in the Slums. Old instincts kick in, and he jumps headfirst to prove he’s still top dog! (or…gator.)</p><p>Solo or with a friend in <a title="Genres > Co-Op [348 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play, take on creative challenges inspired by “Event matches” of platform fighters, taken to the next level with original addictive mechanics and variety. In this gritty-yet-humorous bar, meet unforgettable characters and uncover surprises around every corner as the story unfolds.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>This game is part of the <em>BROK the InvestiGator</em> universe.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Over 60 varied challenges, with unique mechanics.</li><li>Six playable characters, each offering distinct abilities.</li><li>Local cooperative play for up to four players.</li><li>Creator mode: Build your own challenges.</li><li>Additional modes: <a title="Genres > Survival [482 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a>, Versus, Support, Daily, and Bonus Challenges.</li><li>Multiple difficulty levels.</li><li>In-game achievements to unlock.</li><li>Text localized in 12 languages.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Consoles Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="BROK: THE BRAWL BAR - Consoles Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lA5olRoO5eI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/brok-the-brawl-bar-coming-to-ps5-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-december-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astroneer coming to PS5 on November 20]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/astroneer-coming-to-ps5-on-november-20</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/astroneer-coming-to-ps5-on-november-20.1354075/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A free upgrade from the PlayStation 4 version.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > System Era Softworks [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/system-era-softworks">System Era Softworks</a> will release a <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,847 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> version of interplanetary exploration game <em><a title="Games > Astroneer [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/astroneer">Astroneer</a></em> on November 20, the developer announced. It will be a free upgrade from the PlayStation 4 version. <span id="more-1007116"></span></p><p>The PlayStation 5 version will run in native 4K resolution at 60 frames per second, and feature DualSense support.</p><p><em>Astroneer</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/361420/ASTRONEER/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on December 16, 2016, followed by a full release across Xbox One and PC on February 5, 2019, PlayStation 4 on November 15, 2019, and Switch on January 13, 2022.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via System Era Softworks:</p><blockquote><p>In <em>Astroneer</em> you can:</p><p>Reshape the ground under your feet as though it were made of clay. In <em>Astroneer</em>, players use their deform tool to dig, collect, shape and build anything they wish.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Survive on and explore carefully crafted planets that can be entirely deformed and traversed. Our vast solar system includes 7 wondrous planets that players can travel between and explore every inch of, from the entire spherical surface, through treacherous layers of caves, all the way down to mysterious the core.</p><p>Snap together components and objects to build bases and vehicles. Items that Astroneers craft and find in the world can all be snapped and connected together to create unique creations for any situation. Customize and decorate your bases, vehicles, and Astroneer.</p><p>Play with friends in four-player online drop-in / drop-out <a title="Genres > Co-Op [348 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play. <em>Astroneer</em> is better with friends. Group up with other players and work together to create massive industrial bases or to create fun games in the extensive creative sandbox.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PlayStation 5 Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="ASTRONEER PS5 Version Coming November 20th!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K9tcMmdmO9g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/astroneer-coming-to-ps5-on-november-20]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Creative May Be Going Pay-To-Win Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-creative-may-be-going-pay-to-win-soon/1100-6536230/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-creative-may-be-going-pay-to-win-soon.1354072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536230">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Epic Games is gearing up for its biggest shake-up to Fortnite Creative since the introduction of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/epic-announces-unreal-editor-for-fortnite-arriving-next-week/1100-6512398/" data-ref-id="1100-6512398">Unreal Editor for Fortnite</a>. Soon, Epic will allow developers who use UEFN to make Fortnite Creative modes, or "islands," to sell in-game items using V-Bucks, the game's real-money currency.</p><p dir="ltr">The news, which Epic announced during the Veteran's Day holiday in the US, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortniteCreative/comments/1ouht3b/ive_got_a_feeling_this_could_ruin_fortnite/" rel="nofollow ">was not met with much excitement from fans</a>. The way the Fortnite Creative ecosystem is currently crammed with clones of tycoon, boxfight, and platforming islands, it's easy to see how adding microtransactions to any of the typical island types could be a bad thing. And it becomes much more difficult to see any possible upside when Epic's example idea is to <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/tools-for-in-island-transactions-now-available-to-fortnite-developers?lang=en-US" rel="nofollow ">sell people a better shovel for 300 V-Bucks</a>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1757/17577455/4602590-fortnitecreativemicrotransactions.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4602590" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1757/17577455/4602590-fortnitecreativemicrotransactions.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4602590"></a><figcaption>Fortnite will allow UEFN developers to sell gameplay items for money soon.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1757/17577455/4602590-fortnitecreativemicrotransactions.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">But the reality is actually pretty murky, because V-Buck transactions are a wildcard that could completely shake up the Fortnite Creative ecosystem and encourage creators to try new things. We've got a digital Wild West here, in a sense. Let's try to understand the situation a little better, and get a better sense of where it may lead us, by taking a deep dive into the details.</p><h2 dir="ltr">What's actually happening with V-Bucks and Fortnite Creative</h2><p dir="ltr">Right now, creators can use UEFN to make islands that use the V-Buck mechanic, but they cannot publish these islands yet. The most important detail to understand here is that UEFN developers will not be able to sell any of the same types of things Epic sells--meaning purely cosmetic items are not allowed. That means no skins, no pickaxes, no kicks, and no original cosmetic types. Likewise, you can't sell XP gains, since Epic sells account levels in the shop. Random loot crates are allowed but will automatically be disabled in the many countries where that predatory practice is banned.</p><p dir="ltr">These restrictions mean, essentially, that anything sold in a Creative island must have a gameplay purpose. So in the current Creative ecosystem, the most obvious options are pay-to-win mechanics, like selling better-quality guns in a boxfight map, or some kind of bonus to your gains in a tycoon. Most of the available options are the kinds of things players generally dislike.</p><p dir="ltr">But since the current Creative ecosystem is currently geared entirely toward earning payouts from Epic through engagement and playtime, these V-Buck transactions probably aren't being added for the sake of most existing islands. Most current islands would drive people away if they started charging for things that used to be free, and those island creators will be able to keep earning those same playtime payouts in the same way they have been anyway. In other words, those maps can keep making money the same way they have been, so they may not want to bother with V-Buck shenanigans that could mess up their current streams of revenue.</p><p dir="ltr">Instead, adding V-Buck transactions to Creative is at least partially about encouraging UEFN developers to try new things. And it's also about capitalizing on Steal the Brainrot, specifically.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Steal the Brainrot and your V-Bucks</h2><p dir="ltr">Steal the Brainrot is the most popular Fortnite Creative island ever, with tens of thousands of players at any given moment and hundreds of thousands at peak times on the weekend. Steal the Brainrot is unique in that it's actually a licensed port of a popular Roblox game. It has no direct competition in Fortnite, because unlicensed copycat islands have faced legal action, and the Roblox version has a number of real-money transactions that are, thus far, absent from the Fortnite version.</p><p dir="ltr">Kids can use Robux to buy money, items, or Lucky Blocks that contain a random Brainrot--with the best Lucky Block going for $30. The mode also sells access to an "admin panel" that offers the ability to mess with your opponents for $50 or more, depending on the day's prices. We should expect these sort of predatory mobile-style, pay-to-win mechanics to be added to the Fortnite version once Epic allows creators to update their islands with the new microtransaction types.</p><p dir="ltr">It's not hard to figure, then, that Steal the Brainrot will be the first major beneficiary of these V-Buck transactions. But that doesn't mean you should expect to see that sort of thing everywhere in Fortnite.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Are Fortnite Creative and UEFN islands about to be filled with microtransactions?</h2><p dir="ltr">While Steal the Brainrot is a prime candidate for V-Buck transactions, that's not the case for most of the rest of the current Fortnite Creative ecosystem, which is largely built on folks ripping each other off. If one of 500 identical boxfight Pit maps tried selling better guns for V-Bucks, people would just switch to one that didn't do that. And it would be the same story with any of the other common Creative archetypes we currently have. You might see V-Buck donation boxes pop up, but you won't see many paywalls added to existing islands.</p><p dir="ltr">As it is now, there's a decent chance that Epic is adding V-Buck transactions to Fortnite Creative specifically to capitalize further on Steal the Brainrot, and there may not be much of an audience for them in the current ecosystem. But the ecosystem will change as a result of Epic offering this new way to monetize maps. You can expect a lot of creators to try the same old exploitative mobile game-style monetization tricks that we're all too familiar with by now, but there actually is some (hypothetical) good news in all this.</p><h2 dir="ltr">The possible upside to Fortnite Creative V-Buck transactions</h2><p dir="ltr">There certainly could be some decent outcomes from this. Right now, creators can only monetize based on their engagement stats, and that's led to a lot of trend-chasing as creators keep trying to make "better" versions of things that simply exist to waste your time rather than be particularly enjoyable. While plenty of predatory monetization could come with this, the upside is that it should encourage creators to try new types of games.</p><p dir="ltr">For example, this scheme would allow a developer to create an experience within a "paid area" and charge V-Bucks for permanent access--selling a video game within Fortnite, essentially. When devs have more ways to monetize, they're more likely to make more unique things.</p><p dir="ltr">But for now, all this is speculative. Aside from those Brainrots, we don't really know what kind of stuff will sell in this ecosystem. This is one of those situations where nobody, including Epic, really knows how it'll shake out, because it's going to be up to UEFN developers, and their players, to decide what works.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-creative-may-be-going-pay-to-win-soon/1100-6536230/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 3 Almost Left Out This Important Romance Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-witcher-3-almost-left-out-this-important-romance-feature/1100-6536229/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-3-almost-left-out-this-important-romance-feature.1354069/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536229">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Anyone who plays through The Witcher 3: The Wild Hunt is invited to make a choice between the two great loves of Geralt of Rivia: Yennefer of Vengerberg or Triss Merigold. That decision even informs the game's farewell to Geralt. However, CD Projekt Red has recently disclosed that players didn't always get to choose between Geralt's lovers.</p><p>CD Projekt Red co-CEO Adam Badowski told <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/the-witcher-3-didnt-originally-make-you-choose-between-romancing-yennefer-or-triss-this-decision-was-made-pretty-late/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC Gamer</a> that the option to romance Triss was added late in the game. Until then, the team had been focusing on Geralt's relationship with Yennefer. But adding Triss back into Geralt's heart gave the game more personality .</p><p>"[The romance with Triss] wasn't [there] from the beginning," recalled Badowski. "But at some point we understood that this lack of conflict, personal conflict... There was a lack of something... This decision was made pretty late, but it was great. It was a great decision."</p><p>The Witcher video games take place beyond the original stories by author Andrzej Sapkowski, and CD Projekt Red didn't bring Yennefer or Ceri into the narrative until the third game. Conversely, Triss had a much bigger role in the first two Witcher games and she was one of Geralt's primary romance options. If the possibility of romancing Triss had been absent from The Witcher 3, it would have been a missed opportunity to continue that romantic thread.</p><p>Although the game celebrated its 10th anniversary this year, CD Projekt Red is planning <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-witcher-3s-last-patch-is-delayed/1100-6535045/" data-ref-id="1100-6535045">one final patch for The Witcher 3</a> that will introduce mod support for the game's console ports. CD Projekt Red is also currently developing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-witcher-4/" data-ref-id="5000-561041">The Witcher 4</a>, as well as a remake of The Witcher. Both titles will be built using Unreal Engine 5, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-witcher-4-tech-demo-wasnt-actually-the-game-says-cd-projekt-red/1100-6532043/" data-ref-id="1100-6532043">The Witcher 4's tech demo</a> offered a glimpse at how that may look when the game is eventually released.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-witcher-3-almost-left-out-this-important-romance-feature/1100-6536229/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>