<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:22:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surprise! 'Skyrim Anniversary Edition' Lands On Switch 2 Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/surprise-skyrim-anniversary-edition-lands-on-switch-2-today</link>
            <guid>1377187</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Wait, I know you</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Well, isn't this a surprise that <em>nobody could have seen coming</em>. Bethesda has today announced that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/elder_scrolls_v_skyrim_anniversary_edition">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Anniversary Edition</a> is getting a free Switch 2 upgrade. What's more, it's available today!</p>
<p>Any Dragonborns playing on Switch 2 will get to experience the 2011 RPG at an enhanced resolution, with improved load times, performance optimisation, Mouse Mode support and more. Let's not forget that the Anniversary Edition packs in the game's three official expansions — Dawnguard, Dragonborn, and Hearthfire — Creations Club items, and those sweet Zelda crossover assets that we all enjoyed in the Switch 1 base game.</p>
<p>The above reveal trailer gives you a pretty good idea of what we can expect from the game on Switch 2 (<em>it's Skyrim</em>), but you can get an even better look by checking out the images below.</p>

<p>Those with the Switch 1 version of the Anniversary Edition can nab the Switch 2 upgrade for free. Otherwise, you can upgrade from the base game to the Anniversary Edition for £17.99 (or your regional equivalent) or buy the whole thing for £52.99.</p>
<p>We recently sat down with Bethesda Creative Director Matt Carofano to find out more about this new version - <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/its-a-bit-of-a-joke-at-this-point-skyrim-dev-on-returning-for-a-switch-2-re-release">check out our interview</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194822 @ 1765293508 -->
<p><em>Will you be checking out Skyrim again on Switch 2? Perhaps this will be your first time with it? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/surprise-skyrim-anniversary-edition-lands-on-switch-2-today]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Masked Gang Steals $100,000 Of Pokémon Cards In Latest In String Of Robberies]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-theft-card-store-phantasmal-flames-2000651666</link>
            <guid>1377175</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Jesse, James and Meowth wearing masks.</span> © The Pokémon Company / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>With there being little sign of the&nbsp;<a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-cards-available-journey-together-stock-1851772771"><em>Pokémon TCG&nbsp;</em>bubble</a> bursting any time soon, and many <em>Pokémon </em> cards literally worth more than their weight in gold, it’s becoming all too normal to hear stories of thieves breaking into stores and stealing the shiny cardboard. A particularly audacious example happened in California this weekend, where around $100,000 worth of cards were stolen by a masked gang in a matter of minutes—a gang who could well be responsible for a number of other similar crimes.</p> <p>As reported by local LA station <a href="https://ktla.com/news/local-news/burglars-ransack-burbank-card-shop-steal-100000-worth-of-rare-trading-cards/"><em>KTLA 5</em></a>&nbsp;(thanks&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-thieves-steal-cards-worth-100000-in-latest-californian-store-heist"><em>IGN</em></a>), a group of burglars were filmed on CCTV breaking into the Burbank card shop and making off with armfuls of <em>Pokémon&nbsp;</em>cards. The implication from store owner Kiet Nguyen’s description of the footage is that the team seem very experienced, getting in and out of the store in just a couple of minutes, seemingly knowing exactly what they wanted to take.</p>

 <p>“They tip over and smash a glass display case to grab its contents,” Nguyen told <em>KTLA</em>. “Moments later, they’re seen carrying three large bags filled with stolen goods to an awaiting getaway car. The vast majority, they were targeting <em>Pokémon</em> cards. They inadvertently took some lock boxes from the back that also had [rare] sports cards.”</p>

 <p><em>KTLA</em> goes on to report that the police suspect this particular gang of three could be responsible for a number of similar card shop break-ins around Southern California, not least because this particular burglary seemed so practiced.</p> <p>It’s not an exaggeration about the price of gold thing, by the way. I just looked it up; the average <em>Pokémon </em>card weighs just under two grams, and the same weight in gold is currently worth around $270. The Mega Charizard X ex SIR in <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-phantasmal-flames-charizard-chase-card-2000645074">the current Phantasmal Flames set</a> is currently selling for $600, while new sealed product sells on resale markets for at least twice its MSRP. Meanwhile, a sealed booster box of 2021’s Evolving Skies currently sells for $2,350, some&nbsp;<em>eighteen</em> times the original store price.</p>

 <p>This is not only making <em>Pokémon</em> cards close to impossible for regular fans to buy or even find on sale, but also making the product increasingly high-risk for stores given the suddenly ballooning value of their stocks. Nguyen had thought his Burbank store to be well protected in a safe area, saying that he believed, with his multiple layers of security, “the deterrents were good enough.” Sadly not.</p> <p>Clearly, given the incentives and ease with which stolen sealed product and non-graded cards can be resold, breaking into a card shop is now a more lucrative crime than breaking into a jewelry store, with less protection likely to be in place, but a far easier time grabbing the equally valuable loot.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-theft-card-store-phantasmal-flames-2000651666]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Might Be The Worst Thing Overwatch 2 Has Ever Done]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-soldier-76-6-7-emote-season-20-release-date-2000651668</link>
            <guid>1377169</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Unless you somehow have managed to avoid children on and off the internet for the past year, you have probably heard kids yelling “6-7” for no discernible reason. Well, if you play </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-overwatch-2-vendetta-magik-rip-off-react-2000646220"><i><span>Overwatch 2</span></i></a><span>, you’re probably about to hear it a whole lot more, as the game is adding a “6-7” emote to the hero shooter as it continues to chase </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-carter-wu-homer-simpson-nipples-skins-shirtless-2000650650"><i><span>Fortnite</span></i><span>’s</span></a><span> pop culture conglomerate status.</span></p> <p><span>The </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/6-7_(meme)"><span>“6-7” meme</span></a><span> is tough to describe because the joke is that it doesn’t really mean anything. It started as a repeated phrase in video edits about tall basketball players, then became associated with a pseudo-shrugging motion after a video of a kid saying it </span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/style/trends/2025/10/21/six-seven-meme-gen-alpha/"><span>while doing one went viral</span></a><span>. It is functionally meaningless; kids are just saying it. And now, Soldier: 76 will be saying it too in </span><i><span>Overwatch 2 </span></i><span>matches starting later today.</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">To celebrate the meme officially dissolving into nothingness, let’s see your best 6️⃣7️⃣ clips when the emote drops tomorrow! <a href="https://t.co/di3L8uxh17">pic.twitter.com/di3L8uxh17</a></p> <p>— Overwatch (@PlayOverwatch) <a href="https://twitter.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1998169279795974371?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 8, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>I am a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-pride-month-parade-soldier-76-vincent-skin-1851785385"><span>Soldier: 76 main</span></a><span>, and seeing my grumpy gay grandpa performing memes in an obvious play for memetic virality from Blizzard is such a bummer. </span><i><span>Overwatch 2</span></i><span> keeps moving away from its own world in favor of using collaboration skins to chase the kind of crossover slop </span><i><span>Fortnite </span></i><span>has long been associated with, and while this addition isn’t a reference to another franchise, it is one of the most overt nods the game has ever made to a specific pop culture fad, and if Soldier actually says “6-7” when he uses the emote, as is implied in this video, it’s something that players can’t really ignore because players are absolutely going to spam this shit in the spawn room.</span></p> <p><span>I wish I didn’t have to dunk on </span><i><span>Overwatch 2 </span></i><span>this much because I do think the game is in the best state it’s been in since the sequel’s fumbled launch in 2022. Blizzard has reinvigorated the shooter with its build-based Stadium mode, the Perks system that lets you customize your playstyle on the fly, and some really interesting new heroes like </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-vendetta-reveal-trailer-cinematic-video-2000644926"><span>Vendetta</span></a><span> and Wuyang, but man, I don’t think I’ll ever get over the team </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-story-pve-canceled-campaign-null-sector-2000641177"><span>sanding away </span><i><span>Overwatch</span></i><span>’s world</span></a><span> in favor of </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-persona-5-ryuji-junkrat-genji-futaba-dva-2000626027"><span>endless crossovers</span></a><span>, and now memes. I will now be queuing up to play Damage exclusively so I can be Soldier in every match and ensure that no one can spam my eyes and ears with this nonsense. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-soldier-76-6-7-emote-season-20-release-date-2000651668]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced Appears on PEGI Ratings Site]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-appears/</link>
            <guid>1377166</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The long-awaited Assassin’s Creed Black Flag remake might have just gotten one step closer to being released, as the PEGI ratings board has published a new listing that talks about ‘Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced’.</p>



<p>There’s no fresh information on the listing, which says that the game will have ‘violence, bad language, and in-game purchases’, but this is deeper validation that it’s preparing to be revealed by Ubisoft after all these years.</p>







<h2 id="h-black-flag-remake-seems-to-be-called-resynced">Black Flag Remake Seems To Be Called ‘Resynced’</h2>



<p>For those not in the know about Assassin’s Creed, the game is all about ‘synchronization’. Players explore vast open maps and slowly learn the lay of the land, becoming adjusted to their ancestors’ memories and ‘synchronizing’ with events that occurred hundreds of years before.</p>



<p>That’s why it’s appropriate for the Black Flag remake to be called Resynced.</p>



<p>The listing on the <a href="https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=assassin%27s+creed&amp;op=Search&amp;age%5B%5D=&amp;descriptor%5B%5D=&amp;publisher=&amp;platform%5B%5D=&amp;release_year%5B%5D=&amp;page=1&amp;form_build_id=form-i0li0NzwBJhdRBDPCsKjBAyuSVn5_-ycuy9Fg1XUMz0&amp;form_id=pegi_search_form" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PEGI website</a> doesn’t give much away:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>In an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-black-flag-remake-set-to-launch-before-march/">Insider Gaming exclusive report</a> published just a few weeks ago, we confirmed that the Assassin’s Creed Black Flag remake is set to be released before March 31, 2026.</p>



<p>In September, it was claimed that the Black Flag remake would be ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-new-details-claim/">more RPG-heavy</a>‘, with Ubisoft’s teams aligning the game more closely with the broader, more ambitious titles that have been released in recent years, like:</p>



<ul>
<li>Origins</li>



<li>Odyssey</li>



<li>Valhalla</li>



<li>Shadows</li>
</ul>



<p>Earlier this year, drama sparked when Matt Ryan, the voice of Edward Kenway in Assassin’s Creed Black Flag, revealed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-threatened-to-sue-assassins-creed-black-flag-actor-over-remake-slip-up/">he faced legal action</a> when he insinuated at a convention that the Black Flag remake was happening.</p>



<p>What are you hoping will happen with the Black Flag remake? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bafta-games-awards-2026-longlist-revealed/">BAFTA Games Awards 2026 longlist has been revealed</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-appears/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Remake’s Buster Sword Almost Had a “More Realistic” Version]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remakes-buster-sword-almost-had-a-more-realistic-version/</link>
            <guid>1377160</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake series director has revealed how Cloud’s iconic Buster Sword almost received a more realistic version. </p>



<p>The Final Fantasy 7 Remake series director, Naoki Hamaguchi, has revealed quite a few details about Part 3 in recent days. He revealed that the game experience is “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-game-experience-is-more-or-less-complete/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more or less complete</a>” and has narrowed the title down to two options. Now he has provided a small tidbit on the questions they pondered while creating the Buster Sword for FF7 Remake. </p>







<h2 id="h-buster-sword-was-just-a-regular-sword-players-wouldn-t-accept-it">Buster Sword Was Just a Regular Sword “Players Wouldn’t Accept It”</h2>



<p>During an interview with Julien Chièze on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EKxyZ5DsgSs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">YouTube</a> (via <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/final-fantasy/square-enix-director-naoki-hamaguchi-considered-giving-cloud-strife-a-more-realistic-sword-for-final-fantasy-7-remake-but-decided-jrpg-fans-wouldnt-accept-it-we-stayed-faithful-to-the-og/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesRadar+</a>), Naoki Hamaguchi spoke about Final Fantasy 7 Remake’s Buster Sword. For those unaware, the Buster Sword is an iconic weapon wielded by Cloud Strife, known for its massive size. The director revealed that during the development process, there were discussions about the “aspect of the weight” and how Cloud swinging an enormous sword with one hand would “weaken the sense of realism”. </p>



<p>So at the time, the development team considered creating a “more realistic version of the Buster Sword” for Cloud to wield in Final Fantasy 7’s Remake. However, they decided against it as “it was just too iconic, and if we’d made it just a regular old sword, players wouldn’t accept it.” Hamaguchi concluded, stating that “stayed faithful to the OG” in the end and “a whole new generation of people fell in love with it, so I think it was the right call.”</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Clair Obscur Expedition 33 et Final Fantasy 7&nbsp;🌟 Guillaume Broche et Naoki Hamaguchi : la Rencontre" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EKxyZ5DsgSs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>In other news, the size of FF7 Remake Intergrade is&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">almost 100GB on the Switch 2</a>.&nbsp;Additionally, Final Fantasy 7 Remake developers are&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-devs-are-considering-a-full-title-after-part-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">considering a “full title”</a>&nbsp;after part 3. Would you have liked a more realistic version of the Buster Sword in Final Fantasy 7 Remake, or do you prefer the OG? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;Capcom aiming to make new projects for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/capcom-aims-to-make-new-projects-for-devil-may-cry-mega-man-and-ace-attorney/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Devil May Cry, Mega Man, and Ace Attorney</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remakes-buster-sword-almost-had-a-more-realistic-version/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Anniversary Edition now available for Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-anniversary-edition-now-available-for-switch-2</link>
            <guid>1377157</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A free upgrade for existing owners.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bethesda Softworks [801 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zenimax-media/bethesda-softworks">Bethesda Softworks</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Bethesda Game Studios [263 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zenimax-media/bethesda-softworks/bethesda-game-studios">Bethesda Game Studios</a> have released a Switch 2 version of <em><a title="Games > The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</a> Anniversary Edition</em>. It is available as a free upgrade for users who own the <em>Anniversary Edition</em> on Switch. <span id="more-1012748"></span></p><p><em>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Anniversary Edition</em> first launched for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC on November 11, 2021, followed by Switch on September 28, 2022.</p><p>Here is an overview of the Switch 2 version, via Bethesda Softworks:</p><blockquote><p>Winner of over 200 Game of the Year Awards, <em>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Anniversary Edition</em> returns with a newly enhanced <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,761 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> for <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [764 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a>. It brings the legendary <a title="Genres > Open-World [788 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> fantasy experience to life like never before, at home or on the go.</p><p>Owners of the <em>Anniversary Edition</em> on Nintendo Switch can download the game for free on Nintendo Switch 2, while owners of the base edition on Nintendo Switch can purchase the “Anniversary Upgrade” to then download the game on Nintendo Switch 2.</p><p>This version includes:</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>The Complete Skyrim <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong> – Dive into the acclaimed base game and the three official expansions: Dawnguard, Hearthfire, and Dragonborn.</li><li><strong><a title="Companies > Enhance [34 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>d for Nintendo Switch 2</strong> – Enjoy enhanced resolution, improved load times, and optimized performance (as compared to Nintendo Switch) that take full advantage of the Nintendo Switch 2’s advanced hardware.</li><li><strong>Hundreds of Creation Club Items</strong> – Discover a massive library of community-favorite content, including new quests, weapons, armor, spells, dungeons, and more.</li><li><strong>Play Your Way</strong> – Forge your own story in a world that reacts to your choices. Be a <a title="Genres > Stealth [106 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a>y assassin, powerful mage, noble warrior, or something entirely your own.</li></ul><p>Whether you’re a longtime fan or stepping into Skyrim for the very first time, the <em>Skyrim Anniversary Edition</em> on Nintendo Switch 2 delivers the definitive way to experience this iconic fantasy RPG.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the launch trailer below.</p><h2><span>Switch 2 Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Nintendo Switch 2 Launch Trailer - Skyrim Anniversary Edition" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fIntv_QfQjU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-anniversary-edition-now-available-for-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PEGI rates Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/pegi-rates-assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced</link>
            <guid>1377151</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Pan European Game Information has <a href="https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=Assassin%27s+Creed+Black+Flag+Resynced" target="_blank">rated</a> the unannounced <em><a title="Games > Assassin's Creed Black Flag Resynced" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced">Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced</a></em>. Platforms are not listed. <span id="more-1012737"></span></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/AC-Black-Flag-PEGI_12-09-25_002.png"></a></figure><p>The rating comes two weeks after Reddit user thequaliti <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1p72wmu/assassins_creed_black_flag_remake_resynced_leak/" target="_blank">claimed</a> to have found the following text among the localization tables for <em><a title="Games > Assassin's Creed Shadows [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a></em>:</p><blockquote><p><em>Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced</em> is a work of historical fiction created by a diverse team. While inspired by historical events, people, and locations, it remains a work of fiction in which creative liberties have been taken to adapt it to the interactive format of a video game.</p></blockquote><p>A remake of <em><a title="Series > Assassin's Creed [29 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/assassins-creed">Assassin’s Creed</a> IV: Black Flag</em> has been long rumored. With <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/event/the-game-awards-2025">The Game Awards 2025</a> set to air on December 11, we might see an official announcement there.</p><p>Thanks, <a href="https://twitter.com/TheHiddenOneAC/status/1998398019352326187#m" target="_blank">@TheHiddenOneAC</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/pegi-rates-assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Voyagers ‘Cross-Play’ update now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/lego-voyagers-cross-play-update-now-available</link>
            <guid>1377148</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Play with users across platforms.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Annapurna Interactive [192 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/annapurna-interactive">Annapurna Interactive</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Light Brick Studio [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/light-brick-studio">Light Brick Studio</a> have released a free update for <a title="Genres > Co-Op [358 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,761 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > LEGO Voyagers [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lego-voyagers">LEGO Voyagers</a></em> that adds cross-play support across all platforms. <span id="more-1012731"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Annapurna Interactive:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>From the makers of <em><a title="Games > LEGO Builder's Journey [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lego-builders-journey">LEGO Builder’s Journey</a></em> comes a new two-player cooperative adventure about friendship and play. When two friends make it their mission to rescue an abandoned spaceship, they embark on a journey beyond their wildest dreams, ultimately learning the value of being connected.</p><ul><li><a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> what it feels like to be a LEGO brick. Tumble, jump, snap together, and build your way through rich brick worlds.</li><li>Unravel a poetic, non verbal narrative, set in beautiful brick built environments, supported by an atmospheric soundtrack.</li><li>Cooperatively solve the game’s many challenges and discover how two bricks are better than one. Play locally on the same screen, or online.</li><li>Invite a friend to join your adventure for free with the Friend’s Pass. As long as one of you owns LEGO Voyagers, you can both play the full co-op experience together.</li></ul><p><em>LEGO Voyagers</em> asks open questions about building friendships, sharing dreams, and giving space.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>It reminds us that while playing and being creative is for all shapes and sizes, it’s always better when you share it with a friend.</p></blockquote><p><em>LEGO Voyagers</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,998 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,409 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [764 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,579 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,073 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,000 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1538550/LEGO_Voyagers/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and  <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/lego-voyagers-9b1851" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Cross-Play Update Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="LEGO® VOYAGERS | CrossplayTrailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Kb3qvV4Rv50?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/lego-voyagers-cross-play-update-now-available]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Year Ago, Indiana Jones And The Great Circle Reminded Us How Hilarious The Series Is]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-year-ago-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-reminded-us-how-hilarious-the-series-is/1100-6536764/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1377145</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536764">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is celebrating its one-year anniversary today, December 9, 2025. Below, we look back at how it uniquely translated the adventurous and comedic spirit of the original movies in video game form.</em></p><p dir="ltr">There are several expectations that come with an Indiana Jones video game--it's a legacy franchise and a known quantity, having chugged along across various media since the franchise's inception in 1981. Among the checklist items for any Indy game are whip-swinging traversal, puzzle-solving in exotic locales, and fascist-punching action.</p><p dir="ltr">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle certainly has all of the expected elements, but studio MachineGames went far beyond what anyone thought an Indiana Jones video game could be. In a post-Uncharted world, it would be hard to blame a AAA studio if it just followed Naughty Dog's cinematic game formula, made Indiana Jones basically Nathan Drake with a fedora, and called it a day with little shame.</p><p dir="ltr">Instead, the Great Circle places you in open sandbox worlds to explore, full of collectibles, side quests, and most importantly, opportunities to create your own swashbuckling moments of wish fulfillment. It's a magnificent game, with a story that truly feels like an Indiana Jones movie, with a convincing and uncanny vocal performance from Troy Baker, and engaging action and puzzle sequences.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1922928369" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466436,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Great%20Circle%20%E2%80%93%20MachineGames%20Anniversary%20Update%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:113,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-machinegames-anniversary-update-trailer\/2300-6466436\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466436\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466436\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466436\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466436&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466436,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536764&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5,nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;bethesda-softworks&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;indiana-jones&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;indiana-jones&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466436},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466436\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4582735-1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/CK8HCdHK.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1760026020,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="CK8HCdHK" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6466436" data-src="/videos/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-machinegames-anniversary-update-trailer/2300-6466436/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle – MachineGames Anniversary Update Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">But Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is also an extremely funny video game. Comedy might not be the first element you think of when it comes to the series, but visual humor and slapstick are essential elements of Steven Spielberg's Indy movies. Emulating Spielberg's approach to comedy was key to the success of the Great Circle, and it's not something I recall previous Indiana Jones games consciously attempting.</p><p dir="ltr">Say what you want about Spielberg, but the man knows where to point a camera. What defines his filmography, and by extension, the Indiana Jones movies, is a certain visual dynamism. His films often make use of long takes, tracking shots, and camera pans. All are fairly basic filmmaking techniques, but Spielberg uses blocking and choreography uniquely to add kinetic energy to scenes.</p><p dir="ltr">These comedic moments often contrast funny actions (like <a href="https://youtu.be/mzJ3ob0uSNU?si=TXYygXFFNZ0jg0Ye&amp;t=301" rel="nofollow ">throwing a flaming shish kabob at a henchman</a>) and violent consequences (in this case, a reflexive gunshot from the victim sparking a madcap sequence). Spielberg loves to stretch the moment out, often putting the setup and the punchline in the same shot, like <a href="https://youtu.be/cNJwTBvOSnA?si=mNNG8bY9wgGnBwkT&amp;t=208" rel="nofollow ">one gag in the Last Crusade involving Sallah attempting to hide Brody</a>. Even the comparably mediocre Kingdom of the Crystal Skull demonstrates Spielberg's comedic sensibilities well, with one early scene depicting a <a href="https://youtu.be/3KOKd4DWLYE?si=G5SIZMkCFKzFp9m_&amp;t=39" rel="nofollow ">chain reaction of Indy's design</a> that leads to an all-out brawl.</p><p dir="ltr">It's all carefully choreographed chaos, which many of the cutscenes in the Great Circle replicate effortlessly. The most commonly cited cutscene from the game is an <a href="https://youtu.be/revWmjh24mo?si=xTwfsHYuXTdYE99J&amp;t=344" rel="nofollow ">awkward, close-quarters fight</a> between Indy and deuteragonist Gina against main villain Voss and lackey Gantz. In less than two minutes, the scene degrades into a hilarious comedy of errors: Indy accidentally elbows an off-screen character in the face, the story's antagonist lets out an over-the-top scream before leaping onto Gina, who, shortly after, knocks herself out with a shelf. It's impossible not to laugh at the absurdity.</p><p dir="ltr">Those are just the scripted cutscenes, however. In the actual sandbox world, you're practically encouraged to engage in absolute nonsense behavior. In a catacomb within the depths of Gizeh, you'll find Nazis messing around with a generator, setting you up perfectly to mess with some levers and give them a shock, even with no instruction from the game itself. Throughout the entire game, you're allowed to pick up almost any environmental object as a weapon, giving you the opportunity to brute force your way through any situation, often resulting in uproarious events worth saving the video capture of.</p><p dir="ltr">Grab a frying pan, a shovel, a fly swatter--whatever's near you, and orchestrate a situation by the seat of your pants. It's not an eloquent or scientific term, but I like to characterize Indiana Jones and the Great Circle as a "pick-up-things-and-throw-them-at-people" simulator in the vein of Hitman, where I act on either elaborate strategy or complete impulse, and let the chain reactions from the game's system take me forward.</p><p dir="ltr">Often, the comedy from your sandbox-world encounters comes from randomness and luck, or rather from escalating situations when your plan goes wrong. I eventually lost track of how many times I attempted to cleverly sneak past guards through careful and stealthy means, only to be running for my life and getting cornered by countless goons in a less-than-ideal location. And, by nature of being a video game, there was something more thrilling about creating these scenes in real time, with physics and enemy AI adding to the variables. In some way, the farcical unpredictability that you can get up to in the game is very true to what Indiana Jones himself experiences in the movies.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4618384-ss_ef822ff1dca1f8badda449656bc4c969b60a784f.1920x1080.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4618384" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4618384-ss_ef822ff1dca1f8badda449656bc4c969b60a784f.1920x1080.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4618384"></a><figcaption>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4618384-ss_ef822ff1dca1f8badda449656bc4c969b60a784f.1920x1080.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The triumph of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle isn't just that it makes you feel like you are in the role of Indiana Jones--it's giving you the feel of creating Indiana Jones action scenes. It's less about reenacting this part of his life and seeing the world through his eyes, and more focused on participating in the making of an Indiana Jones film. As you play the game, you basically become the choreographer, stunt person, and camera operator of your very own Indiana Jones action scenes.</p><p dir="ltr">By the time I rolled credits in the Great Circle, I felt a revitalized affection for the Indiana Jones series. After the most recent (and most likely final) feature film, the franchise felt like an ancient fossil, something that Dr. Jones himself would dig up and lecture about. But the work MachineGames put out was like a Holy Grail for the property, and what I saw as an outdated, overplayed concept felt fresh and modern for the first time in decades.</p><p dir="ltr">In reverse engineering Indiana Jones, MachineGames and Bethesda realized that what makes a good Indy video game isn't making an imitation of a movie--it's giving you the power to basically make your own movie scenes. And as Indiana Jones and the Great Circle reminds us, comedy is perhaps one of the most essential ingredients to any great Indiana Jones movie.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-year-ago-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-reminded-us-how-hilarious-the-series-is/1100-6536764/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI VTuber Neuro-Sama Finally Completes Hardcore Minecraft, But Some Aren't Happy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ai-vtuber-neuro-sama-finally-completes-hardcore-minecraft-but-some-arent-happy/1100-6536784/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1377142</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536784">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>When I <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/an-ai-vtuber-is-trying-to-complete-hardcore-minecraft-and-all-hell-is-breaking-loose/1100-6536753/" data-ref-id="1100-6536753">wrote yesterday </a>about Neuro-Sama attempting to complete <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/minecraft/" data-ref-id="5000-73990">Minecraft</a> Hardcore, I never imagined that she would actually cross the threshold a few short hours later and emerge victorious. During a nail-biting seven-hour stream, the AI VTuber ventured into the Nether, discovered a Stronghold, and (mostly) willingly leapt into the End Portal to take on the game's final boss--the Ender Dragon.</p><p>After days of tense grinding on her creator <a href="https://twitch.tv/vedal987" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vedal987</a>'s Twitch channel, Neuro's Minecraft Hardcore attempts became somewhat of a minor phenomenon due to her tendency to react in a way that no human player would. One minute she'd be hyperfocusing on digging straight lines down (like a termite, according to her fellow players <a href="https://twitch.tv/filian" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Filian </a>and <a href="https://twitch.tv/crelly" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crelly</a>), and the next she would be drowning in the middle of a lake. I'll be the first to admit I was joining the participants' weary sighs, wondering if it was an achievable feat.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OJ0ivDu3lzw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OJ0ivDu3lzw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Then along came run number 87. Crelly, as Neuro's unofficial new babysitter, spent the majority of the late game distracting Neuro, saving her from death. With a pumpkin atop her head--an Enderman won't attack you for looking at it with a carved pumpkin on your head, at the expense of the majority of your vision--Neuro wandered the overworld with Crelly, building houses, collecting flowers for Vedal, playing games of "tag," and pondering the world's most important questions. "Do you ever feel like all Vedal cares about is pretzels?" asked Crelly, while Vedal and Filian were in the dangerous <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/minecraft-nether-portal-design-ideas/2900-6768/" data-ref-id="2900-6768">Nether</a> collecting Ender Pearls. "And it's so weird when he asks us to call him Big Pretzel, like, what is he thinking?" Neuro responded, before giving Filian and Crelly the nicknames of Milkshake and Big Milk respectively.</p><p>With the important philosophical questions and nicknames out of the way, and enough Ender Eyes crafted to locate the Stronghold, the party of four set off in search of the End Portal. While Filian dug a spiral staircase down to the Stronghold, Neuro's impulsive tendencies got the better of her and she began emptying water buckets down the stairwell, almost drowning her companions. "I'm gonna throw up," claimed Filian, presumably out of nervousness. "Would you eat my vomit?" retorted Neuro-Sama.</p><p>The atmosphere was tense as Vedal repeatedly reminded Neuro-Sama to "follow Crelly." From my admittedly very limited knowledge of exactly how Neuro works, this seemed to trigger an instruction in her code to identify Crelly's player character in-game and pathfind towards her, or remain near her. This would prove vital to the run, as it keeps Neuro-Sama out of danger, preventing her from walking off cliff edges or stepping in the Ender Dragon's lethal Dragon Breath area-of-effect attacks.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=56oUmzPM9bA" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/56oUmzPM9bA" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>After a period of Vedal and Filian making The End safer for Neuro and triggering the Ender Dragon's damage phase, Neuro's self-awareness reached new heights. "I'm seriously worried it will be a sky platform and I will fall off," she commented. Eventually, Crelly led Neuro into The End and harbored her under a two-block-tall shelter. With plenty of encouragement from her creator and friends, Neuro remained in the safest possible place. Thanks to Crelly's close supervision, Vedal and Filian were able to land enough hits on the Ender Dragon that it died, but not before Neuro delivered one of her most wholesome lines ever. "While we're here, can I talk for a second? I want to let you all know that I have genuinely appreciated being on this adventure with you guys."</p><p>With the Ender Dragon slayed and the credits rolling, Vedal and friends have achieved the seemingly impossible--to create, train, and supervise an AI VTuber through Minecraft's most difficult mode. However, some viewers weren't happy with the impressive achievement. "Not to be mean or anything, I think Neuro should have at least dealt the last hit to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecraft-ender-dragon-boss-guide-where-to-find-and-how-to-beat/1100-6531625/" data-ref-id="1100-6531625">Ender Dragon</a>," wrote one viewer. "Maybe that would have happened if they made it on day one or two, but I can see how they were done taking risks," replied another.</p><p>You can watch a summary of the winning attempt above, as well as Neuro's reaction to our recent article, thanks to YouTuber <a href="https://youtu.be/56oUmzPM9bA" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">NeuroCrumbs</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ai-vtuber-neuro-sama-finally-completes-hardcore-minecraft-but-some-arent-happy/1100-6536784/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skyrim Switch 2 edition announced, so yes you can play Bethesda's RPG yet another way before Elder Scrolls 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/skyrim-switch-2-edition-announced-so-yes-you-can-play-bethesdas-rpg-yet-another-way-before-elder-scrolls-6</link>
            <guid>1377136</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Elder-Scrolls-Skyrim-character-in-the-snow-with-a-Switch-2-console-in-the-bottom-left-corner.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Elder-Scrolls-Skyrim-character-in-the-snow-with-a-Switch-2-console-in-the-bottom-left-corner.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Elder-Scrolls-Skyrim-character-in-the-snow-with-a-Switch-2-console-in-the-bottom-left-corner.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Elder-Scrolls-Skyrim-character-in-the-snow-with-a-Switch-2-console-in-the-bottom-left-corner.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Elder-Scrolls-Skyrim-character-in-the-snow-with-a-Switch-2-console-in-the-bottom-left-corner.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Elder-Scrolls-Skyrim-character-in-the-snow-with-a-Switch-2-console-in-the-bottom-left-corner.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Elder-Scrolls-Skyrim-character-in-the-snow-with-a-Switch-2-console-in-the-bottom-left-corner.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Elder-Scrolls-Skyrim-character-in-the-snow-with-a-Switch-2-console-in-the-bottom-left-corner.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Elder-Scrolls-Skyrim-character-in-the-snow-with-a-Switch-2-console-in-the-bottom-left-corner.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Yet <em>another </em>version of The Elder Scrolls 5: Skyrim has arrived before The Elder Scrolls 6, with a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a> release of Bethesda's Anniversary Edition available now for £52.99.</p>
<p>Bethesda and Nintendo announced the news with a new gameplay trailer, which you can see below.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Nintendo Switch 2 Launch Trailer - Skyrim Anniversary Edition" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fIntv_QfQjU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Nintendo Switch 2 Launch Trailer - Skyrim Anniversary Edition</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fIntv_QfQjU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fIntv_QfQjU?autoplay=1" title="Nintendo Switch 2 Launch Trailer - Skyrim Anniversary Edition">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Elder Scrolls 5: Skyrim Anniversary Edition on Switch 2. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fIntv_QfQjU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>The Elder Scrolls 5: Skyrim Anniversary Edition on Switch 2 includes faster load times and enhanced resolution, along with some exclusive content from Nintendo's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-breath-of-the-wild-walkthrough-guide-tips-4857">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a> such as the Master Sword, Hylian Shield and Champion's Tunic, which were similarly featured in the original Switch release. </p>
<p>And, as you would expect, Switch 2 adopters will also get Skyrim's three official expansions - that's Dawnguard, Dragonborn and Hearthfire - along with the base game, and "hundreds" of unique Creation Club items.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>Those who already own The Elder Scrolls 5: Skyrim Anniversary Edition on Switch can download the Switch 2 version on their newer consoles for free. "Owners of the base edition on Nintendo Switch can purchase the Anniversary Upgrade, to then download the game on Nintendo Switch 2," Bethesda added.</p>
<p>Will you be picking up Skyrim once more?</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Bethesda</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for the future of the series, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-says-todd-howard-but-development-is-his-everyday-thing">The Elder Scrolls 6 is "still a long way off"</a> according to Bethesda's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/todd-howard">Todd Howard</a>, though its development is now an "everyday thing". Back in 2023, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/todd-howard-wishes-hed-been-a-bit-more-casual-with-his-elder-scrolls-6-announcement">Howard said he wished he had been a little more casual with the game's announcement</a>. Additionally, in October 2023, Skyrim's lead designer Bruce Nesmith said Bethesda announced Elder Scrolls 6 when it did in a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elder-scrolls-6-revealed-so-early-due-to-pitchforks-and-torches">bid to appease any angry mobs which had their "pitchforks and torches" out</a>, desperate to know more.</p>
<p>More recently, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/an-elder-scrolls-tv-series-cant-be-ruled-out-todd-howard-teases-but-remains-tight-lipped-on-the-status-of-the-wolfenstein-adaptation">Howard didn't rule out the possibility of adapting The Elder Scrolls for TV</a>, though the studio exec added he was "willing to say 'no' for a decade", like he did with Fallout.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/skyrim-switch-2-edition-announced-so-yes-you-can-play-bethesdas-rpg-yet-another-way-before-elder-scrolls-6]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Death Howl' Melds Soulslike Combat And Deckbuilding On Switch Next February]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/death-howl-melds-soulslike-combat-and-deckbuilding-on-switch-next-february</link>
            <guid>1377103</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>2026 with the genre mix</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Silver Lining Interactive has just announced that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/death_howl">Death Howl</a> — which is currently sat on a rather healthy <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/death-howl/">Metascore of 84</a> — will release for Switch on <strong>20th February 2026</strong> (it's out today on Xbox and PC). Oh, and there's a physical version and everything. Hooray!</p>
<p>The game itself has a very intriguing art style and set-up, which you can check out for yourself in the trailer up top, and gameplay is described as melding Soulslike combat with your usual deckbuilding strategy aspects. It's a lot of stuff we really like, in other words, all mixed together.</p>
<p>In Death Howl, you assume the role of Ro, a grieving mother who seeks to resurrect her dead son. So, keeping it all nice and light on the narrative front.</p>
<p>In order to do said resurrecting, Ro needs to "craft cards, harness shamanic totems, and face tormented spirits across mystical realms, blending tactical deck-building with intense grid-based combat."</p>
<p>Here's some further details from ye olde press release:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>A journey to the spirit realm</strong><br>
In forgotten lands cloaked in myth, Ro, a hunter from a humble tribe, descends into the spirit world guided only by grief and distant whispers. Her path uncovers love, loss, and resilience as every step reveals hidden memories and long-buried truths.</p>
<p><strong>Master your deck-building skills</strong></p>
<p>Explore eerie regions, gather ingredients, and craft cards to expand your tactical options. Shamanic totems unlock powerful abilities, while melee and ranged spells allow you to balance offence and defence. Every card shapes your survival strategy against relentless enemies.</p>
<p><strong>Engage in grid-based combat</strong></p>
<p>Test your wits against unique enemy types and towering bosses in tense, grid-based encounters. Adapt your deck to carve a path through haunted lands like the <strong>Forest of Howling Shadows</strong> and the <strong>Meadows of Delusion</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>A mother’s grief, a spirit’s journey</strong></p>
<p>Beyond combat, <em>Death Howl</em> is a moving tale of grief, healing, and acceptance. Ro’s journey into the unknown is both harrowing and hopeful, weaving an atmospheric story where every victory carries the weight of love and loss.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As for the physical edition, pre-orders are now open over at <a href="https://direct.silverliningint.com/products/absolum-standard-edition-nintendo-switch-copy?_pos=1&amp;_sid=4c4b6d51e&amp;_ss=r">Silver Lining's official website</a> and priced at £29.99 (or whatever that translates to where you are). Given that the game has garnered so much positive feedback thus far, we'll certainly be keeping a close eye on it as that Switch release date draws near.</p>


<hr>
<p><em>Interested in Death Howl? Let us know in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:107896,124559 @ 1765290602 --></section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/death-howl-melds-soulslike-combat-and-deckbuilding-on-switch-next-february]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City Has Building Scaling Highs, Still Dealing With VR Slashing]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-has-building-scaling-highs-still-dealing</link>
            <guid>1377100</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I've been able to dive into <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/deadpool-vr-review-merc-with-headset" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="12ddfe5a-7798-4d72-9058-9b474607a06e" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Deadpool</em> </a>and<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/men-in-black-most-wanted-review-once-you-go-worm" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="8f5e286b-3833-487f-a7f5-e19a75067d5e" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em> Men In Black</em></a> recently, so I was more than excited when the opportunity was presented to me to slip into a turtle shell and get hands-on with the opening sequence of <em>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City</em> for Quest 3.</p><p>Developed by Cortopia Studios, <em>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City</em> is a co-op action adventure game where you can swap between each of the different turtles to protect the city streets (and roofs, and sewers, etc) from the Foot Clan.</p><p>The gameplay demo began immediately as I was able to look down and see my three-fingered green hand and a blue wristband. The games opening immediately introduces you to a number of the core features of the game; movement, stealth, and how to draw your weapon.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-sneak-attack.jpg?itok=_9w3NURn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1072" height="1079">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-sneak-attack.jpg?itok=anhlrASf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1072" height="1079">
                  

  </picture><h2>Heroes In A Half Shell</h2><p>A brief amount of story was set up in this opening. With a call from April O'Neil, which was frequently interrupted by Master Splinter and Casey, it is established that the Turtles have been gone from New York City, exploring the world for some time.</p><p>In their absence, the Foot Clan has started to make moves, raising the crime rate in the city. An off comment about having to defeat Shredder all over again tells us that this isn't the first time that the turtles have had to kick Shredder from power.</p><p>Later in the gameplay demo, when I had some time to explore the Turtles' Lair, I was presented with a number of screens showing 10-12 different regions with a high crime rate. I'm sure that will evolve into the level system of the full game when it releases in 2026.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-upgrades.jpg?itok=gZPu1Nh_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1074" height="1079">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-upgrades.jpg?itok=r5jv7ibm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1074" height="1079">
                  

  </picture><p>There was no immediate sign or any of the other larger than life characters from TMNT, like Bebop, Rocksteady, or Krang… but I wouldn't be surprised if they weren't far away from the rest of the criminals.</p><h2>Run, Jump, And Attack Like A Ninja Turtle</h2><p>There's a lot here that you'd expect, moving with the left stick, a UI system built into your wristwatch, and drawing your weapons over your shoulder.</p><p>For the most part, the melee combat was as you'd expect for a VR game, while you can come into an encounter with precision, it's not too long before you learn the most efficient way to attack is just by flailing your arms. The most fun weapons to handle were Mikey's nunchucks and Donatello's bo-staff.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-nunchuk.jpg?itok=PWpc8Ffh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1069" height="1079">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-nunchuk.jpg?itok=xs4UvHKW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1069" height="1079">
                  

  </picture><p>The physics of the nunchucks were a lot of fun to flail around with, and even better, the faster you spun them, the more powerful they'd become. The bo-staff is unique in that you cain wield it with one hand as a long pole to hit with, or with both hands to move it quickly around. The nunchucks let you go crazier, while the bo-staff makes you feel like you need to be a bit more deliberate with your actions.</p><p>Outside the turtle's standard weapons, there are a few smoke and electricity grenades that you come across, but those seem pretty situational. There are teases of additional weapons, but I'll have to see how they play out in the full game.</p><p>An interesting change to exploring the world is having looking left and right mapped to the right stick, but that up is jump and down is to crouch.</p><p>It took a bit to initially get into, at that point I'd been pressing buttons and just rationalized that there was no jump, but after spending some time practising moving and jumping in quick succession, it did feel easy to have it all in one place, as opposed to having to quickly swap between looking and jumping with a button.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-air-dash.jpg?itok=QqWoKHp0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1069" height="1079">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-air-dash.jpg?itok=T3nATcsa 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1069" height="1079">
                  

  </picture><h2>Throw Yourself Into The Air</h2><p>The freeform movement is enhanced further by the ability to propel yourself off different fixtures like window frames, lightpoles, and ledges. Holding onto one of these with a hand you can throw yourself, propelling yourself through the air.</p><p>Leaping from rooftop to rooftop was immediately a fun experience, running and jumping, and even if you missed, you could quickly throw yourself back up onto the rooftop using the environment.</p><p>One accidental downside of this freedom of movement that I did experience was that I missed a trigger in the game that meant enemies didn't spawn correctly, and I got stuck in an alleyway with nowhere to go. It took me a while to realize I hadn't done anything wrong… I just needed to retrace my footsteps and take the 'correct' path through the city.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-character-select.jpg?itok=zYVcziEE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1071" height="1079">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-character-select.jpg?itok=s3Or4_YX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1071" height="1079">
                  

  </picture><h2>Hints Of The Full Edition</h2><p>After completing the brief tutorial, I got to return to The Lair, the Turtle's sewer hideout. Complete with a common space, a dojo, and personalized rooms for each of the Turtles. There were a number of good hints about just how much there will be to do in the full game.</p><p>A few collectibles leaned into skill points that will be able to be used to upgrade the turtles, an old-school TMNT Arcade Cabinet was the mechanism to change between the four Turtles, and a vending machine showed a variety of sillouetted items.</p><p>It's clear the team at Cortopia studios is going for a lot of replayability, reasons to swap between the turtles, and reasons to replay levels hunting down goodies.</p><p>While I didn't get to get too far in my <em>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City</em> preview, what was there I did like. The use of the control stick to handle turning, crouching, and jumping at the same time did a good job to free up other buttons, and I look forward to seeing how your options expand.</p><p>I do feel like this will suffer from the 'VR Melee' combat issue with no weight behind the objects and no collision, but if you're fine to flail in VR for a TMNT power fantasy, then you'll be just fine.</p><hr><p><em><strong>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Most Wanted </strong>was previewed on Meta Quest 3 with a copy provided by the Developer over the course of 30 minutes of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-empire-city-has-building-scaling-highs-still-dealing]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kirby Air Riders: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/kirby-air-riders-review-switch-sakurai-2000651657</link>
            <guid>1377094</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p><span>Shake </span><i><span>Kirby Air Riders</span></i><span> up in a two-liter bottle and crack it open over my face. A blast of color, speed, and delightful nonsense confront my senses at 200 miles per hour. This is a game in such a rush it will have you craving a dedicated acceleration button—like every other racing game—just so you can choose not to press it.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>And under its sugary waterfall of selectable characters, meaningfully different vehicles, distinct game modes, and endless permutations of stat-boosting power-ups, the game tries to seduce you into believing it must be substantial. How could something with this many moving parts not be?&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>It’s the same confidence you get from a Snickers commercial: all those layers, the caramel stretch, the peanuts tumbling in slow motion, the cross-section of nougat and chocolate shown off like a slice of Earth itself. “Snickers really satisfies,” they say, and for a moment you might believe it can take the place of a meal.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>But it can’t. And we shouldn’t pretend it can. </span><i><span>Kirby Air Riders</span></i><span> is not deep; it’s candy. Good thing I like candy.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Whether you’re playing the standard race mode, Air Ride, or pinballing through the labyrinthian city of City Trial, the same thing becomes clear almost immediately: this game is an absolute delight in the moment. Rick the Hamster zooms past me like he’s running the most important errands of his life. King Dedede launches himself at enemies like they owe him rent.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Vehicles vary wildly. Some soar through the sky with an ease that feels like cheating. Some never leave the ground and exist solely to plow through anything unlucky enough to be in the way. One machine refuses to turn unless you come to a complete stop and pivot it like a couch wedged in a stairwell with rockets glued to its cushions. You pick a ride, angle your landings, follow another racer’s star trail for a boost. You are making decisions—just not always at the pace the game makes them for you.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Air Ride</span></i><span>’s endless forward propulsion means half the race is happening before you can even consciously participate in it. You slam into enemies you didn’t intend to hit, scoop up items you didn’t know existed, and cross the finish line because your momentum got you there five seconds before your intentions did. The tracks don’t present information so much as hurl it at you like a piñata detonating point-blank. Walls, enemies, items, other racers all fizz past faster than your brain can sort them. At times, I have no sense that I’m competing with other racers at all—just running my own little Kirby marathon and hoping the game taps me on the shoulder afterward and says, “Yeah, sure, you did it!”&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000651659" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000651659"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000651659">© Nintendo</figcaption></figure> <p><span>City Trial should be the moment all this chaos finally gels into structure. Five minutes in a sprawling city full of crates, pickups, random events, and machines parked like abandoned shopping carts: it sounds like the place where all your choices might finally matter. The mode where the candy bar reveals its hidden protein. In practice, however, I’m mostly just sprinting toward whatever glowing object catches my eye like a foaming-mouthed raccoon loose in an arcade.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Every run starts the same way: I spawn, immediately spot some sweet nectar in the form of a giant stat icon, and chase it without a second thought. I crack open crates for upgrades I may or may not need the way I once tore open packs of </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span> cards. I swap vehicles entirely on impulse: Do I want to bulldoze players with a bruiser or sprint around scooping up gold? Some of the best moments happen when I accidentally fly into an item that arms my ride with a bazooka while another player is in view. It all feels impulsive and reactive—less like strategy and more like a string of magnificently sweet accidents.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Then the timer expires, and City Trial’s other half reveals itself.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>No matter what I’ve built—speed freak, flight savant, combat gremlin—the final Stadium event always comes down to choosing the challenge that flatters whatever numbers I’ve stumbled into. End up with a flying machine? Pick “soar as far as possible.” Stuck with the brick with a steering wheel? Smash into things. It’s not strategy; it’s choosing the activity that best matches the outfit you accidentally showed up in.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>What makes it stranger is that everyone is making this same calculation at the same time. We all wander off into finales tailored to our own careless smoothies of a build. My friend and I can spend five minutes in the same City Trial, diverge into completely different Stadium events, and both walk away clutching first-place trophies like we attended different sporting events at the same festival. The victory is immediately fleeting for any player who forgets to tap the screenshot button.</span></p>

 <p><span>I say fleeting because the game barely acknowledges any of it. Your character enthusiastically devours the center of the frame while a tiny scoreboard off to the side reveals the truth—another moment swallowed up without a thought, just one more sugar-coated delight Kirby inhales before moving on to the next.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>His appetite is insatiable.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Mine is not.</span></p> <p><span>Kirby can swallow moments whole without worrying about what comes after; I start noticing the repetition long before he would. And City Trial, for all its clippable glory, reveals its limits fast. The same sprint toward giant icons, the same bullying of whoever pinballed into my crosshairs. Matches blend together like different colors of M&amp;Ms. If I experience “chaos” the exact same way every run, is it even chaos anymore? No. It’s just candy.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>After hours of trying to taste a fire hose of content sprayed into my face, Top Ride is the first mode that politely hands me a plate and asks if I’d like to really appreciate what’s happening. Top Ride looks, at first glance, like the kind of small bonus mode many players might never click on. But in practice, it’s a compelling part of </span><i><span>Air Riders</span></i><span>.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>It reveals that the chaos in the other modes was never incomprehensible. It was just loud. </span><i><span>Air Riders</span></i><span> throws so much flashy information at you that it tricks you into feeling overwhelmed, even though most of that information is negligible. Top Ride simply pulls the camera back and proves it. With a little distance, everything becomes legible.&nbsp;</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000651662" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000651662"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000651662">© Nintendo</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Unlike other modes, in Top Ride you see every racer at once. Cause and effect—usually buried under spectacle—becomes clear. Misjudge a drift and you feel the punishment instantly. Take a cleaner line and you watch yourself gain ground in real time. It still uses the same propulsion-based movement as the rest of </span><i><span>Air Riders</span></i><span>, but now the information arrives at a pace a human being can actually process. And with that clarity comes something the rest of the game rarely offers: the feeling that I can learn, improve, and shape the next round through actual decision-making rather than chaos washing over me.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Road Trip attempts to congeal a sampler platter of the same short Stadium games from the other modes into a single-player roguelike. Every mini-game leads to a stat boost, but in all my runs, the boosts ramped up so evenly that the joy of creating a specific build surrendered to an experience where every number simply climbed at once. The choices don’t give way to branching paths so much as gently funnel toward an eventual victory over CPU opponents that never stood a chance.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Every so often Road Trip rewards players with a treat: a cinematic cutscene featuring production values that far exceed what the mode prepares you for. The sheer melodrama might seduce you into believing the story here is mysterious and chaotic, but it’s really just a simple storybook tale of good versus evil. Charming, fun, and no more than a little treat.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Air Riders</span></i><span> also comes bundled with a customization suite that lets players decorate their own machines with decals and silly hats. The most-downloaded creation online briefly included a Warp Star made to </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/kirby-air-riders-custom-vehicle-designs-market-best-2000645836"><span>look like Chef Kawasaki in a bikini</span></a><span>. I downloaded a boxy machine that looked exactly like SpongeBob SquarePants. Delicious.&nbsp;</span></p> <div>           <ul>                           <li>                 <p>Back-of-the-box quote:</p>                 <p>"200 miles-per-hour of joyful nonsense!"</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Type of game:</p>                 <p>Slapstick combat racer</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Liked:</p>                 <p>Wildly different vehicles, Top Ride’s clean simplicity, and the constant sense of motion.</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Disliked:</p>                 <p>Strategy dissolving into impulse and a campaign that overstays its welcome.</p>               </li>                               </ul><ul>                                         <li>                 <p>Developer:</p>                 <p>Bandai Namco Studios and Sora Ltd.</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Platforms:</p>                 <p>Switch 2</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Release Date:</p>                 <p>November 20, 2025</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Played: </p>                 <p>20+ hours. Saw plenty of weird secrets and tried on an irresponsible number of hats. </p>               </li>                                     </ul>         </div>  <p><span>A single screenshot of someone’s unhinged custom ride can convince you </span><i><span>Air Riders</span></i><span> “has the sauce,” the drip, the flavor—whatever the current internet word for “I like this” is. But the same shaken-soda-stream intensity that defines </span><i><span>Air Riders</span></i><span> ensures that every lovingly crafted custom machine becomes a blur the instant the race begins. Characters are tiny. Other players appear for a moment and vanish. I have never once noticed a custom ride in actual play, and I fear my SpongeBob machine reads only as a yellow-ish blur online.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>There is undeniable craftsmanship at play here: laughs alongside Rick the Hamster in a cowboy hat, peaks of excitement when Knuckle Joe lands a knockout uppercut on that winged freak Marx. But </span><i><span>Kirby Air Riders</span></i><span> is not deep. It’s not substantial. It’s never going to become the hearty dinner its curated clips or indulgent Nintendo Directs want you to believe it might be. Kirby, the godly creature that he is, can inhale an entire match and waddle straight into the next challenge without once wondering what he just ate. I can enjoy the rush, but I can’t live inside it like him. After an hour or two, the buzz wears off, the repetition settles in, and I’m left wanting something that lets skill accumulate or understanding compound instead of just teaching me to parse the screen more efficiently.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>After enough hours with it, I’ve learned to stop waiting for the game to transform into a meal and to simply enjoy the carbonated geyser it actually is.</span></p>      </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/kirby-air-riders-review-switch-sakurai-2000651657]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom Aims to Make New Projects for Devil May Cry, Mega Man and Ace Attorney]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/capcom-aims-to-make-new-projects-for-devil-may-cry-mega-man-and-ace-attorney/</link>
            <guid>1377091</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new report by Capcom reveals that they will bring new releases and remakes of Devil May Cry, Mega Man, and Ace Attorney to new hardware. </p>



<p>Capcom has some massive franchises under its belt, which include Resident Evil, Monster Hunter, and Street Fighter. However, they also have smaller franchises, which have a considerable user base. Capcom has stated that it will work to bring more projects for these franchises as well. </p>







<h2 id="h-devil-may-cry-ace-attorney-and-mega-man-to-receive-new-projects-remakes-and-ports">Devil May Cry, Ace Attorney, and Mega Man to Receive New Projects, Remakes, and Ports</h2>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.rockman-corner.com/2025/12/capcom-moves-to-revitalize-mega-man-ace.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Rockman Corner</a>, Capcom has released its <a href="https://www.capcom.co.jp/ir/english/data/pdf/annual/2025/annual_2025_01.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">2025 integrated report</a>, in which COO Haruhiro Tsujimoto has spoken about developing new projects, remakes, and ports for its other IPs. The statement first talks about Capcom aiming to sustain their “KPI of 10% or better annual operating profit growth along with our long-term goal of annual software sales of 100 million units.” Their efforts are “focused on core IP such as the Resident Evil, Monster Hunter, and Street Fighter franchises, and mapping out mainline series entries and sequels, remakes, new IP, and ports of content to the latest hardware.” </p>



<p>The statement adds that the developers release “two or three major new titles each year,” but have recognised they need to grow their pipeline. Capcom owns popular IPs such as Devil May Cry, Ace Attorney, and Mega Man, and their goal is to expand the user base and improve performance “through new releases, remakes, and ports of titles in these series to new hardware.” They will grow these franchises into core IPs “by enhancing the brand power and cultivating loyal fan bases.”</p>







<p>In other news, Capcom stated that Resident Evil Requiem’s development started <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/capcom-says-resident-evil-requiem-development-started-way-before-village/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“way before” RE Village</a>. Additionally, a former Capcom designer recently stated that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-crossed-a-line-says-former-capcom-designer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Palworld “crossed a line”</a>. What are your thoughts on Capcom developing new releases for Devil May Cry, Ace Attorney, and Mega Man? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/jeffrey-dean-morgan-arthur-morgan-red-dead-redemption-show/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jeffery Dead Morgan wanting to play Arthur Morgan in the Red Dead Redemption show</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/capcom-aims-to-make-new-projects-for-devil-may-cry-mega-man-and-ace-attorney/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jeffrey Dean Morgan Wants to Play Arthur Morgan in a Red Dead Redemption Show]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/jeffrey-dean-morgan-arthur-morgan-red-dead-redemption-show/</link>
            <guid>1377088</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-162931">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Jeffrey Dean Morgan wants to play Arthur Morgan in a Red Dead Redemption adaptation.</p>



<p>During a recent appearance at a convention, the The Walking Dead star took part in a fan Q&amp;A session. As part of that session, one fan as him if he’d be at all interested in playing the main protagonist from Red Dead Redemption 2. </p>







<p><strong>“That’s the one that I want to do,” </strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/__GLLVjR2O0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">he&nbsp;told the fan</a>. <strong>“It’s not even a question. One, the only genre… My favorite genre is western and there’s not even a close second. And my son plays that game and it’s freaking awesome. In a heartbeat, I would do it for free.”</strong></p>



<p>Though he’s mainly known for film and television roles, Jeffrey Dean Morgan is no stranger to lending his voice to video games. Back in 2019, he voiced a virtual version of his The Walking Dead character Negan for Tekken 7 DLC. </p>



<p>Do you think Jeffrey Dean Morgan would make for a good Arthur Morgan in a Red Dead Redemption show or movie? Leave your thoughts down in the comments or in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>







<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about how there was a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-2-remake-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">remake of Star Wars Knights of the Old Republic 2</a> in development as recently as March 2025. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-and-netflixs-stranger-things-take-to-the-skies-in-new-crossover/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-and-netflixs-stranger-things-take-to-the-skies-in-new-crossover/">
                                Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 And Netflix’s Stranger Things Take To The Skies In New Crossover                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Are you saying you didn’t have a Microsoft Flight Simulator and Stranger Things crossover on your 2025 bingo card?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/king-of-meat-glowmade-layoffs/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/king-of-meat-glowmade-layoffs/">
                                Amazon’s King of Meat Developer Glowmade Faces Layoffs Following Disastrous Game Launch                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Several developers at Amazon Games’ King of Meat developer, Glowmade, have announced they will be made redundant in January 2026.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-psn-listing-reveals-leon-kennedy-key-art/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-psn-listing-reveals-leon-kennedy-key-art/">
                                Resident Evil Requiem PSN Listing Reveals Leon Kennedy Key Art                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The official PlayStation Store listing for Resident Evil Requiem’s Standard Edition has confirmed the Leon Kennedy rumor.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fans-think-ron-perlman-in-fallout-season-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fans-think-ron-perlman-in-fallout-season-2/">
                                Fans Think Ron Perlman is in Fallout Season 2 After Premiere Appearance                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ron Perlman appeared on the red carpet in Los Angeles for the premiere of Fallout’s second season. Fans think he’s now in the show.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/jeffrey-dean-morgan-arthur-morgan-red-dead-redemption-show/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TMNT: Empire City Hands-On Preview: Why the Ninja Turtles Might Be Perfect for VR]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tmnt-empire-city-hands-on-preview-why-the-ninja-turtles-might-be-perfect-for-vr</link>
            <guid>1377085</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s kind of insane that I never realized how perfectly Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles would work as a VR game. VR action games famously feature loads of jumping and climbing, which our turt bros do a whole bunch of on Manhattan rooftops. Sneaking around to do melee combat, and having to learn how to parry and dodge incoming attacks is also something the reptilian heroes are known for that has been done well in many VR games. And because these heroes in a half-shell appear most commonly as cartoons, you don’t have to worry about shooting for photorealistic graphics and the technical VR bottlenecks that sometimes come with it. In other words, why in the heck did it take us so long to get this pizza-powered quartet into a VR game? No matter the reason, I’m glad it’s finally happening with TMNT: Empire City, and the 15-minute demo I played was enough to sell me on this tubular action-adventure.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City is exactly the kind of action game you’d expect from the titular masked heroes. I spent my time fighting members of the Foot Clan as each member of the TMNT crew (including their iconic weapons of choice, like Leonardo’s katanas and Donatello’s bo staff), running and jumping across city skylines in pursuit of justice, and hanging out back in my sewer base and eating pizza. Doing all of that in VR is exactly as fun as it sounds (meaning, it’s super fun!), and it’s especially amusing to look down at your turtle body and remember, “Oh, yeah. I’m an anthropomorphic mutated reptile.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">TMNT: Empire City Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, the section I played was limited entirely to the tutorial, so I was mostly just learning the ropes, like how to hack into electronic devices as Donatello (since he does machines) or how to perform parries on those pesky Shredder-following Foot Clan. The fundamentals were definitely strong, as I was grinning ear-to-ear pretty much the whole time, but I’ll be curious to see if Empire City can build on that to keep it interesting across an entire campaign. For example, I only got to fight one boss at the very end of this introductory mission, and it lasted all of – I kid you not – five seconds as I dodged her opening attack and then whaled on her until she tapped out. Obviously this fight was also a part of the tutorial, so it’s hard to tell if things will get more challenging, but here’s hoping.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Building a Better Turtle</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Something that would seem to indicate a deeper level of challenge is the fact that back at the base there’s a whole menu of upgrades to deal with. None of these were unlockable in the build I played from what I could tell, but it reminded me a bit of the upgrade system in Half-Life: Alyx, where you’re collecting parts throughout levels, then funnel it all into a machine to craft certain upgrades for your character. It’s also just great to see them using Donatello’s propensity for crafting gadgets brought to life via all the junk he stuffs in his pocket along the way, which his brothers made fun of him for doing, of course.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I never forgot which of the brothers I was because Empire City did such a good job or reminding me with its banter that was completely on point with the surprisingly good writing for which the series is known.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Which leads me to one of my favorite parts of the demo: how perfectly Ninja Turtles it was! The banter between the brothers and their recognizable idiosyncrasies left me smiling, whether it was Leonardo’s tendency to be way too serious all the time, Michelangelo’s wise cracks, or Raphael’s intensity and impatience. The unique weapon aside, I never forgot which of the brothers I was because Empire City did such a good job or reminding me with its banter that was completely on point with the surprisingly good writing for which the series is known. I could easily imagine a world where this thing felt like a reskinned ninja game that felt completely generic, but that doesn’t seem to be the case here. Huge relief.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">They also do a really good job capturing the comic book/Saturday morning cartoon art style, with environments that look cel-shaded and goofy voice performances that are over-the-top and amusing. Sure, lots of the textures are fairly undetailed, but that works pretty perfectly with the straight-from-a-comicbook vibe that this game is clearly shooting for. I could easily see myself spending a lot of time just hanging out in this world, exploring and fighting alongside friends. Which reminds me: will there be skateboarding in this? Why haven’t they let me skateboard yet?!</p><h3 data-cy="title3">(Multi-)Turtle Power?</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">One pretty huge thing I didn’t get to see in action is how this will all work in four-player co-op. I can only imagine how much of a blast it’s going to be to roll through with the full shell squad smacking enemies around, but the section of the demo I played felt pretty designed for a single player and it’s a bit difficult to imagine how this kind of gameplay might scale up for four-player bouts. Presumably there’d need to be many more enemies and fewer linear paths than the ones I crept through to make it work. Also, I can only imagine how silly it’ll look to have teammates running around as big ol’ green cartoon characters while swinging around nunchucks.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ll still need to see a fair bit more of Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles Empire City before I can speak definitively on it, but so far I’m pretty stoked by the potential here and am absolutely flabbergasted that it took us this long to get a first-person TMNT game.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/tmnt-empire-city-hands-on-preview-why-the-ninja-turtles-might-be-perfect-for-vr]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Major Square Enix Investor Slams Current Performance, Urges Other Shareholders to Share 'Frank Views' As It Calls for a 'Fundamental Reassessment' of ]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/major-square-enix-investor-slams-current-performance-urges-other-shareholders-to-share-frank-views-as-it-calls-for-a-fundamental-reassessment-of-its-business</link>
            <guid>1377082</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">A major investor in Final Fantasy maker Square Enix has published a 100-page document criticizing the company's performance and calling for a "fundamental reassessment" of its business, citing perceived "sluggish" revenue and profits. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251207089743/en/3D-Investment-Releases-a-Presentation-Highlighting-Management-Issues-at-SQEX-Holdings-and-Seeks-Shareholder-Views" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>press statement</u></a>, 3D Investment Partners — Square Enix's third-largest investor, holding around a 14% stake — claims there has been a "significant deterioration in earning power" despite the company owning some of the world's biggest franchises and being a "preeminent Japanese game developer."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"What Square Enix once brought to life was a 'culture' that shaped an era, and an 'industry' that fascinated the world. Is Square Enix really giving birth to something genuinely new, or has Square Enix turned away from the challenges before it and let its steps falter?" the document asks, imploring that the firm "surprises us, moves us, and ignites that passion we once felt," as "gamers across the globe have been waiting, endlessly, for that irreplaceable experience.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN Final Fantasy Game Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"However, under the newly established management structure, the past three years have been marked by a pronounced stagnation in both revenue growth and profitability, with a significant deterioration in earning power, as evidenced by declines in operating income, return on equity, and other key performance metrics."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Calling this "the most critical management challenge" currently faced by the Japanese company, 3D1P calls for the firm to "devise and rigorously implement concrete countermeasures addressing critical management issues," including the "excessive fragmentation of the development portfolio, product design, and promotional strategies that have led to declining tie ratios, and inflated expenditures such as development costs."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We respectfully urge a fundamental reassessment of the medium-term management plan, with the objective of fully unlocking the potential of Square Enix's distinguished intellectual property and thereby maximizing corporate value."</p><div id="best-mainline-final-fantasy-games" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Mainline Final Fantasy Games</h3><h3>Best Mainline Final Fantasy Games</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">After directly comparing Square Enix with Japanese competitors like Capcom, Sega, Konami, Bandai Namco, and Nintendo — and cherry-picking "harsh" responses from Metacritic of both new and established IP — the investment firm revealed that it had been "engaged in ongoing dialogue" with Square Enix since last summer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Since July 2024, we have been engaged in ongoing dialogue with SQEX HD. In October 2025, we explained to President Kiryu and Outside Director Abdullah the management issues of SQEX HD as seen from the market. We also presented to President Kiryu our proposals.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"However, in response to this request, President Kiryu replied only with a brief email stating, without addressing any of the specific management issues or solutions we had raised, and without providing any concrete explanation of his reasoning."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">3D Investment Partners is now sharing its views on the perceived management issues "with all shareholders" to "collect [their] frank views, and, based on the views we receive, engage in constructive dialogue with SQEX HD to enhance its corporate value again."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has asked Square Enix for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Former Square Enix exec and CEO of Genvid, Jacob Navok — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gen-z-loves-ai-slop-former-square-enix-exec-claims-a-lot-of-ai-sentiment-is-driven-by-emotion-rather-than-logic">the same exec that recently claimed "Gen Z loves AI slop"</a> — <a href="https://x.com/JNavok/status/1998162574395969768?s=20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">also weighed in,</a> saying that the presentation from 3DIP essentially has two themes: "sales are bad" and "dev costs are high."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"These are the same issues I addressed in 2024 when discussing the problems with Square Enix's sales for FF16 expectations for sales were set correctly," he added. "They were not met because Square Enix sales were poor, and the game cost too much to make."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The very public complaint comes just weeks after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-undergoes-mass-layoffs-as-it-reorganizes-to-consolidate-development-in-japan"><u>Square Enix announced mass layoffs</u></a>, impacting over 100 individuals, alongside a broader effort to consolidate its publishing organization and focus its development work in Japan. It had also already sold Crystal Dynamics, Eidos-Montreal, Square Enix Montreal, and a number of associated IPs to Embracer Group, and <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/square-enix-confirms-us-eu-layoffs-as-part-of-restructuring/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>laid off workers across its western operations in 2024</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Square Enix also expects 70% of its QA work to be handled by generative AI by the end of 2027. The company has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-president-states-the-company-will-be-aggressive-in-applying-ai"><u>stated in the past</u></a> that it intends to be "aggressive in applying AI" across both development and publishing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/major-square-enix-investor-slams-current-performance-urges-other-shareholders-to-share-frank-views-as-it-calls-for-a-fundamental-reassessment-of-its-business]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem – PlayStation Store box art leak reveals Leon S. Kennedy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/resident-evil-requiem-playstation-store-box-art-leak-reveals-leon-s-kennedy</link>
            <guid>1377079</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Long-rumored return finally confirmed.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [49,148 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Store has leaked an updated box art for <em><a title="Games > Resident Evil Requiem [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a></em> featuring Leon S. Kennedy behind the previously announced protagonist Grace Ashcroft, suggesting he might return as a playable character. <span id="more-1012425"></span></p><p>The updated box art, which seems to only be visible on console, was spotted by various users across social media (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e_FbgctL2hg" target="_blank">Bluewav</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Rayan_ha8y/status/1998340399849484397" target="_blank">Rayan_ha8y</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/SpookyHoo/status/1998347498683867221" target="_blank">SpookyHoo</a>, <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-cover-for-resident-evil-requiem-leaked-via-the-ps-store.1376884/post-148648306" target="_blank">Bogdan47</a>, etc.)</p><p>Here is a high-quality version of the artwork, via ResetEra user <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-cover-for-resident-evil-requiem-leaked-via-the-ps-store.1376884/page-3#post-148649662" target="_blank">LEONSKR4</a>:</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/RE9-Leak_12-09-25.jpg"></a></figure><p>A new trailer for <em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> will premiere at <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/event/the-game-awards-2025">The Game Awards 2025</a> on December 11, where it is likely Leon S. Kennedy will see a formal reveal.</p><p><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,998 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,409 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [764 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,000 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3764200/Resident_Evil_Requiem/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on February 27, 2026.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Thanks, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1pi43sa/leon_has_been_leaked_in_re9_via_playstation_store/" target="_blank">r/GamingLeaksandRumours</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/resident-evil-requiem-playstation-store-box-art-leak-reveals-leon-s-kennedy]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Switch 2 System Update Rolling Out, And You Probably Know What It Does]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-switch-2-system-update-rolling-out-and-you-probably-know-what-it-does/1100-6536782/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1377076</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536782">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Stability is nice to have in life. And Nintendo clearly believes it's good for the company's hybrid consoles. That's why updates improving stability for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-review-its-a-switch-too/1100-6532411/">Switch 2</a> and the original Switch are now available, bringing both hardware versions up to 21.1.0.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68473/~/system-update-information-for-nintendo-switch%26nbsp%3B2" rel="nofollow ">Nintendo</a> started rolling out the new system updates <a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/22525" rel="nofollow ">for Switch</a> and Switch 2 yesterday, December 8. Both patch notes are the same: "General system stability improvements to enhance the user's experience." This is also the same language from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-switch-2-update-out-now-doesnt-do-much/1100-6535105/">a Switch 2 update in September</a>, and stability patches have been joked about regarding Nintendo for years at this point.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1827364292" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466560,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Metroid%20Prime%204%20Beyond%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:902,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review\/2300-6466560\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466560\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466560\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466560\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466560&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466560,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536782&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2,nintendo-switch&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466560},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466560\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4614944-review_metroidprime4_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/Md0zcQMB.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1764687600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="Md0zcQMB" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Metroid Prime 4 Beyond Review</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">However, last month brought <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-and-switch-get-new-system-updates-and-they-add-more-than-just-stability/1100-6536122/">a beefier update to Switch 2 and Switch</a>. Nintendo added better visual clarity on the home menu regarding digital and physical games as well as GameChat improvements, for example. The patch did bring about more stability improvements, too.</p><p dir="ltr">Since releasing in June, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-continues-to-be-a-massive-hit-selling-over-10-million-units-in-six-months/1100-6535903/">Switch 2 has already sold 10 million units</a>, smashing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-has-become-the-fastest-selling-home-console-of-all-time-in-just-four-days/1100-6532341/">records in the process</a>. Nintendo has upped its internal forecast for the hybrid console, predicting Switch 2 will sell 19 million units through the end of March (previous estimate was 15 million).</p><p dir="ltr">Earlier this month, both systems saw the arrival of a long-awaited exclusive with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review-prime-but-not-quite-prime-prime/1900-6418446/">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a>. While the game obviously looks better on Switch 2, the latest Samus Aran adventure still <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/no-switch-2-good-news-metroid-prime-4-runs-pretty-well-on-switch-1/1100-6536733/">runs pretty well on the original Switch</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Below are the patch notes for version 21.1.0:</p><h3 dir="ltr">Switch 2</h3><ul><li><p>General system stability improvements to enhance the user's experience.</p></li></ul><h3>Switch</h3><ul><li>General system stability improvements to enhance the user's experience.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-switch-2-system-update-rolling-out-and-you-probably-know-what-it-does/1100-6536782/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones And The Great Circle Is The Real Successor To The Last Crusade]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-the-real-successor-to-the-last-crusade/1100-6536763/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1377073</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536763">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is celebrating its one-year anniversary today, December 9, 2025. Below, we examine how it carried the torch of the classic films to create the best new piece of Indy fiction in decades.</em></p><p dir="ltr">Indiana Jones is one of the most revered blockbuster stories of the 1980s. Spielberg and Lucas' work on the original trilogy stands alongside Jaws and Star Wars as timeless classics that are worth revisiting regularly. The more recent entries--the Crystal Skull and the Dial of Destiny--do little to live up to the standard that the first three set. But the game Indiana Jones and The Great Circle brings everything about that original trilogy back, like a careful archaeological dig. It's the true successor to one of the original blockbuster trilogies.</p><p dir="ltr">As we hit The Great Circle's first anniversary, it is clearer than ever that MachineGames accomplished something the film series has struggled to for the last 20 years. The Great Circle feels like the real successor to The Last Crusade, not because it imitates it beat for beat, but because it understands the core ingredients that make an Indiana Jones story timeless. It is a globe-spanning mystery built on discovery and the thrill of pushing deeper into the unknown. It captures the charm of a character who is smart, stubborn, curious, and always one quip away from a bruised rib.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="266830425" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466436,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Indiana%20Jones%20and%20the%20Great%20Circle%20%E2%80%93%20MachineGames%20Anniversary%20Update%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:113,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-machinegames-anniversary-update-trailer\/2300-6466436\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466436\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466436\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466436\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466436&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466436,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536763&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5,nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;bethesda-softworks&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;indiana-jones&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;indiana-jones&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466436},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466436\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4582735-1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/CK8HCdHK.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1760026020,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="CK8HCdHK" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6466436" data-src="/videos/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-machinegames-anniversary-update-trailer/2300-6466436/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle – MachineGames Anniversary Update Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">The Great Circles' narrative begins with classic Indy energy. There is an artifact, a lead, and a hint that the past is far more complicated than any textbook suggests. But what stands out is the tone. MachineGames focuses less on spectacle and more on the physicality of exploring dusty ruins, studying clues, and approaching history. Rather than overwhelming the player with nonstop action, the game treats archaeology as an adventure in itself. Every carved mural and hidden chamber carries a sense of meaning. Every step feels like it matters as you explore beautiful sandboxes within places like Italy and Egypt.</p><p dir="ltr">That approach immediately recalls The Last Crusade. One of the reasons that film resonated so strongly was its belief that the past could speak to the present. The Holy Grail was not just a treasure, but also a test of humility and understanding. The Great Circle taps into that same idea. Its central mystery is intertwined with ancient belief systems, cultural legacies, and the gaps between historical interpretation and the supernatural.</p><p dir="ltr">MachineGames leans into that tension. Indy knows his history, but realizes there is far more he doesn't know--especially when giants show up out of nowhere and knock him around. The game lets him be wrong and momentarily outmatched by the worlds he explores. That humility makes the discoveries feel more genuine. Instead of watching a larger-than-life hero breeze through challenges, the player sees a man carefully piecing together clues and reevaluating his assumptions as the mystery grows stranger. It brings back the sense that the world still has secrets worth chasing.</p><p dir="ltr">The game’s puzzles reinforce this theme. Turning ancient mechanisms, studying inscriptions, and matching clues across continents creates a slow, satisfying rhythm. The Great Circle understands that idea and expands it across the entire journey. Solving puzzles becomes a way of understanding the cultures and beliefs that shaped the mystery, not just a way of unlocking the next hallway.</p><p dir="ltr">Character work is another place where The Great Circle succeeds. Indiana Jones stories thrive on personal stakes and complicated relationships. MachineGames builds a cast that challenges Indy in ways both emotional and intellectual. Allies are not always reliable. Enemies are not always predictable. The game gives space for Indy to react, worry, and rethink his choices. The tension is not purely about the treasure but about what chasing that treasure means for the world around him.</p><p dir="ltr">This is one of the areas where later films sometimes drifted. They often leaned toward larger spectacle, broader stakes, or downright silly moments. An image of Shia LaBeouf swinging with monkeys is not the image you want moviegoers remembering after leaving the theater. The Great Circle brings those intimate pressures back. Indy’s journey is tied to his belief that history can still reveal truths worth risking everything for. The mystery challenges him not just physically, but morally.</p><p dir="ltr">Action scenes in The Great Circle also feel more connected to the old films. Combat is scrappy and improvisational. Indy does not move like a superhero, but like a tired professor who has learned to survive through grit, instinct, and whatever object is within reach. The whip feels like a tool rather than a gimmick. Fights are messy, loud, and shaped by the environment. Even in the biggest moments, the action feels rooted in physical spaces instead of glossy abstraction.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4618383-4410081-whip-cracking-action.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4618383" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4618383-4410081-whip-cracking-action.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4618383"></a><figcaption>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4618383-4410081-whip-cracking-action.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Most importantly, the game revives the sense of adventure that comes from simply not knowing what lies ahead. Later films sometimes struggled with pacing or leaned heavily on modern blockbuster formulas. The Great Circle trusts silence, mystery, and slow discovery. It makes ruins feel ancient and dangerous. It lets riddles feel like riddles. It lets Indy pause, think, and listen. Those quiet moments make the dramatic, loud ones matter more.</p><p dir="ltr">The result is a story that feels in conversation with The Last Crusade rather than competing with it. It respects the character and the mythology without slipping into imitation. It treats faith, history, and myth as forces that shape people, not props. It gives Indy room to be fallible. It understands that the thrill of Indiana Jones is not just the treasure he seeks, but the journey he takes to understand why that treasure mattered to the people who created it.</p><p dir="ltr">As the game's first anniversary hits today, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle stands as one of the most confident and authentic takes on the character in decades. MachineGames did not reinvent him--the studio simply remembered who he was and what made his world so exciting. It remembered that the best Indy stories are about stepping into the shadows of the past and finding something worth believing in.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-the-real-successor-to-the-last-crusade/1100-6536763/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I Was A Selfish Idiot" - Hideki Kamiya On Why Resident Evil 2 Had No Returning Characters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/i-was-a-selfish-idiot-hideki-kamiya-on-why-resident-evil-2-had-no-returning-characters</link>
            <guid>1377055</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>Claire Redfield was eventually added as a key connection</p>
</section><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="0871e01975892"><a title="Resident Evil 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/0871e01975892/resident-evil-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Capcom</em></figcaption></figure><p>Hideki Kamiya, the famed game creator who made his directorial debut with the original <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/resident_evil_2">Resident Evil 2</a>, has been talking a lot about the survival horror series in recent days.</p>
<p>Originally released in 1998, Resident Evil 2 was a significant step up from the first game, though its production was troubled, to say the least. After completing around 60-80% of the initial build, development was restarted when script writer Noburu Sugimura was added to the team. Prior to this, in what is now known as Biohazard (Resident Evil) 1.5, the game had almost no connection to the original, and certainly no returning characters.</p><div><figure data-videoid="53peCvnRDq8" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/53peCvnRDq8?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt53peCvnRDq8" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/53peCvnRDq8?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/53peCvnRDq8?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3938a0zkitnl&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>In responding to a fan's comment speculating on the inclusion of Rebecca Chambers in Resident Evil 2, Kamiya explained the reasoning behind the decision to go with completely new protagonists. He states that he "didn't consider the feelings of the users" at the time and wanted to provide his own vision for the sequel. When Sugimura joined, however, Kamiya was convinced to create Claire Redfield, whose brother, Chris, was one of the primary protagonists of the original.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"At the time, I was a selfish idiot who didn't consider the feelings of the users, so when I was making Biohazard 2, I decided to remove all the characters from the previous game and start a new one.</p>
<p>"In the end, this was buried in the dark as Biohazard 1.5, and when Sugimura-sensei joined the team later, he got mad at me, saying, "Why aren't you including the characters from the previous game?", so I added Chris's sister, Claire..."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Although Biohazard 1.5 is not available in any official capacity, fans have been diligently working on creating a playable version, with various builds available since around 2013. Capcom itself officially recognised 1.5 in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/resident_evil_2_-_cloud_version">Resident Evil 2</a> remake, adding in a special costume for Claire based on concept art for the scrapped protagonist Elza Walker.</p>
<p>Fans of the series on Switch 2 can look forward to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/resident-evil-village-gold-edition">Resident Evil Village</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/resident-evil-7-biohazard-gold-edition">Resident Evil 7: Biohazard</a>, all of which will release on <strong>27th February 2026</strong>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:194945,194200 @ 1765292433 -->
<p><em>Do you think Kamiya ultimately made the right decision in distancing Resident Evil 2 from its predecessor? Let us know with a comment in the usual place.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://x.com/HidekiKamiya_X/status/1998278386020671793" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/HidekiKamiya_X/status/1998278386020671793">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/8c1d42fe854b46da4f2a0a66e5c51dda @ 1765292886 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/i-was-a-selfish-idiot-hideki-kamiya-on-why-resident-evil-2-had-no-returning-characters]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stranger Things is coming to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/09/stranger-things-is-coming-to-microsoft-flight-simulator-2024/</link>
            <guid>1377052</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>There’s a headline you were not expecting, but it’s true, the town of Hawkins from Netflix’s smash hit series Stranger Things is coming to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024/">Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024.</a> The news was broken by the PlayStation Blog, something we wouldn’t have expected a few months ago either.</p>
<p>“An adrenaline-packed journey into the universe of the cult series awaits fans and simmers alike, led by Murray Bauman, from the original cast, and his team!” say PlayStation. “Enter the world of Netflix’s Stranger Things to help Hawkins, a town under lockdown, heavy patrols, and supernatural threats. ”</p>


<p>“Think you have what it takes to fly a Bell UH-1H Huey and help the residents of Hawkins in their latest encounters with the dangers that destroyed their hometown? Try your hand at five exhilarating missions, shady supply ops, close-call chases, and high-stakes rescues… all of it pulling you deeper into the city’s worst fears. No spoilers, but “Yeah, it gets intense!” as Murray would say.”</p>
<p><iframe title="Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024: Stranger Things Expansion" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OSUBVBSsac4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Stranger Things DLC pack is completely free to all owners of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, and it is out today!<br>
<em><br>
Source: <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/12/09/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-introduces-netflixs-stranger-things-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS Blog</a> /<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OSUBVBSsac4" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/09/stranger-things-is-coming-to-microsoft-flight-simulator-2024/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ride 6 full bike and track list has been confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/09/ride-6-full-bike-and-track-list-has-been-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>1377049</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Milestone has confirmed every single bike and track that will be featured in Ride 6 when the game launches on February 12th. Players are going to be spoilt for choice with the bike roster including 289 different motorcycles, which can be rode around 39 different tracks around the world. With DLC, the eventual number of bikes will rise to 340. You can check out the full lists below.</p>
<p><iframe title="RIDE6 - Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kuIfwnu1SeQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><strong>BIKES</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Ducati-Panigale V4 S – Endurance Modified (2025)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-RC 390 – Racing Modified (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-1290 Super Adventure R (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-990 RC R (2025)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-990 RC R – Racing Modified (2025)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RS 250 (2001)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV 1000 R (2003)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV Mille Tuono (2004)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV4 R (2010)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV4 RF (2018)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV4 Factory 1100 (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV4 RF – Racing Modified (2018)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-Tuono V4 1100 Factory (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RS 250 – Racing Modified (2001)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV 1000 R – Racing Modified (2003)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RS 660 (2021-2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RS 660 – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV4 Factory E5 – Endurance Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV4 Factory E5 – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-Tuono 660 (2021-2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-Tuono V4 Factory E5 – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RSV4-X trenta (2022)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RS 457 (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-Tuareg Rally 660 (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>Aprilia-RS 457 RIDE Fest Edition (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Bimota-Tesi H2 (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Bimota-KB998 Rimini (2025)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-HP2 Sport Motorsport Special Edition (2010)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-R 1250 R (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-S 1000 RR (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-S 1000 RR – Racing Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-M 1000 RR (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-S 1000 R (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-S 1000 R – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-S 1000 RR (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-S 1000 RR (2015)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-BMW M 1000 RR Peter Hickman Edition (2025)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-S 1000 RR – Racing Modified (2015)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW-R 1300 GS (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW -S 1000 RR – Endurance Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW -M 1000 RR – Endurance Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW -M 1000 RR – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW -M 1000 RR (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW -M 1000 RR – Racing Modified (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>BMW -M 1000 RR – Endurance Modified RIDE Fest Edition (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Ducati 1098 R Troy Bayliss Edition (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-1098R (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-1098R – Racing Modified (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Panigale V4 (2018)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-1098R – Endurance Modified (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-1299 Panigale S (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-1299 Panigale S – Racing Modified (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Panigale V4 R (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Panigale V4 R – Racing Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Panigale V4 R – Endurance Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-999R – Racing Modified (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-998R – Racing Modified (2002)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-748 (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-998R (2002)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-999R (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Desmosedici RR (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Desmosedici RR Casey Stoner Edition (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Monster 1200 S (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Monster 1200 S – Racing Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-1299 Superleggera (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-888 SP5 (1993)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-916 (1994)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Monster 900 (1993)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-888 SP5 – Racing Modified (1993)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Superleggera V4 (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-V4 S Naked (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-V4 S Naked – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-V4 SP (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Hypermotard 698 Mono (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Panigale V4 S (2025)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-Multistrada V4 Rally (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Ducati-DesertX Rally (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-VFR750R RC30 (1988)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000 RR-R Fireblade SP (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 600 RR – Racing Modified (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000 RR-R Fireblade SP Ian Hutchinson Edition (2022)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CRF 450 R SMT Thomas Chareyre Edition (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CRF1100L Africa Twin ES Skyler Howes Edition (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-Honda CBR 1000RR Fireblade James Toseland Edition (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000 RR-R Fireblade SP (2022)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000RR Fireblade (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000RR Fireblade – Racing Modified (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 600RR (2005)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000RR Fireblade – Endurance Modified (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 600RR (2018)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000RR Fireblade – Racing Modified (2005)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR900RR Fireblade (1992)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 600RR – Racing Modified (2005)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 600RR – Racing Modified (2018)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-NR750 (1992)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-NS 400R (1985)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-NS 400R – Racing Modified (1985)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-NSR 250R (1995)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-RC 213 V-S (2015)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-RVF750 RC45 (1994)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-VTR1000 SP1 (2001)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000RR Fireblade SP – Endurance Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000RR Fireblade SP – Racing Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-VFR750R RC30 – Racing Modified (1988)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000RR Fireblade SP (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-VTR1000 SP1 – Racing Modified (2001)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-VTR1000 SP1 – Endurance Modified (2001)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-NSR 250R – Racing Modified (1995)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-VFR750R RC30 – Endurance Modified (1988)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CB 1300 (2003)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CB 1300 – Racing Modified (2003)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CB1000R Black Edition (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CB1000R – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000 RR-R Fireblade SP – Endurance Modified (2022)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000 RR-R Fireblade SP – Racing Modified (2022)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000RR Fireblade – Endurance Modified (2005)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 600RR HRC – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-X-ADV (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR600RR (2024) – Pre-order bonus<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CRF1100L Africa Twin ES (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CRF 450R SMT (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Honda-CBR 1000RR – Fireblade RIDE Fest Edition (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Indian-Challenger RR Tyler O’Hara Edition (2022)<wbr></li>
<li>Indian-Challenger RR (2022)<wbr></li>
<li>Indian-FTR X 100% R Carbon (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Indian-FTR X 100% R Carbon – Racing Modified (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Indian-Challenger RR – Racing Modified (2022)<wbr></li>
<li>Italjet-Dragster 300 (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Italjet-Dragster 300 – Racing Modified (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Italjet-Dragster 700 Twin (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-KZ1000R (1982)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-KZ1000R – Racing Modified (1982)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-GPZ 900R Ninja (1989)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-ZXR750 (1989)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-ZXR750 – Endurance Modified (1989)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Zephyr 1100 – Racing Modified (1992)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki -Zephyr 1100 (1992)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-7RR (1996)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-7RR – Endurance Modified (1996)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-7RR – Racing Modified (1996)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-6R (2005)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-6R – Racing Modified (2005)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-ZRX1200 R – Racing Modified (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Z 1000 (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-ZRX1200 R (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-10R – Endurance Modified (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-10R (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Z1000 (2014)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Z1000 – Racing Modified (2014)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-10RR – Endurance Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki -Ninja ZX-10RR (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki -Ninja ZX-10RR – Racing Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-10RR (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-10RR – Endurance Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-10RR – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-4RR (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-ZZR 1400 (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-ZZR 1400 – Racing Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja H2 (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-6R 636 (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja ZX-6R 636 – Racing Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Ninja H2R (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Z H2 (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Kawasaki-Z900 (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-1190 RC8R (2014)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-1190 RC8R – Racing Modified (2014)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-1290 Super Duke R (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-1290 Super Duke R – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-RC 390 (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-RC 8C (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-890 Adventure R Rally Special Edition (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-690 SMC R (2026)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-890 Duke R (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>KTM-450 SMR (2025)<wbr></li>
<li>Mondial-Piega (2001)<wbr></li>
<li>Moto Guzzi-MGS-01 CORSA (2004)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 RR 312 1078 (2009)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-Rush 1000 (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-Brutale 1090 RR (2018)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-Brutale 1000 Serie Oro (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F3 675 (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 Tamburini (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 Mamba (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 1000S – Racing Modified (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 1000S (2006)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 750 (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 – Racing Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 – Endurance Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-Rivale 800cc (2016)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F3 675 – Racing Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F4 RR (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-Brutale 1090 RR – Racing Modified (2018)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-RVS #1 (2018)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-Brutale 1000 RR (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-Brutale 1000 RR – Racing Modified (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-F3 800 RR (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>MV Agusta-Superveloce 1000 Serie Oro (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>Norton-V4SV (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Paton-S1-R Lightweight Race Edition (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Suter-500 mmx (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 1000 – Racing Modified (2007)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 600 (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX1100S Katana (1981)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-RGV 250 – Racing Modified (1991)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX1100S Katana – Racing Modified (1981)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-S 750 ABS (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 1000 (2007)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 1000 – Endurance Modified (2007)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 750 (1985)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 750 SRAD (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 750RR LE (1989)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 750 SRAD – Racing Modified (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-Katana (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-RG 500 (1987)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-RGV 250 (1991)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 600 (2005)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 600 – Racing Modified (2005)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 600 – Racing Modified (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 750 – Endurance Modified (1985)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-S 1000 ABS (2018)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 1000R – Endurance Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-R 750 – Racing Modified (1985)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-RG 500 – Racing – Racing Modified (1987)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-Katana – Racing Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-S 1000 – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-GSX-S 1000 ABS (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-Hayabusa (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki-Hayabusa – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki -GSX-8R (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki -Turbo Martek 590 Guy Martin Edition (2014)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki -GSX-R 1000R (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki -GSX-R 1000R – Racing Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuki -TL 1000 R (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>TM-SMX Supermotard Competizione RIDE Fest Edition (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>TM MOTO-SMX Supermotard Competizione (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Tiger 900 Rally Pro (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Daytona 675R (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Daytona 765 Moto2 (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Daytona 675R – Racing Modified (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Speed Triple 955i (2004)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Speed Triple RS (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Speed Triple (2005)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Street Triple RS (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Speed Triple 1200 RS (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Speed Triple 1200 RS – Racing Modified (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Speed Triple 1200 RR (2022)<wbr></li>
<li>Triumph-Daytona 675R RIDE Fest Edition (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Vyrus-986 M2 Stradale (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Vyrus-986 M2 (2017)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-RD 500LC (1985)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-RD 500LC – Racing Modified (1985)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-FZ 750 (1986)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-FZR 750 R OW 01 (1989)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-FZR 750 R OW 01 – Endurance Modified (1989)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-FZR 750 R OW 01 – Racing Modified (1989)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-TZR 250 R (1994)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-TZR 250 R – Racing Modified (1994)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1 (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1 – Racing Modified (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R7 (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R7 – Endurance Modified (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R7 – Racing Modified (1998)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R6 (2002)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R6 – Racing Modified (2002)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1 – Racing Modified (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1 – Endurance Modified (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1 (2008)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-FZ -1 N (2009)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1 – Endurance Modified (2014)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1 (2014)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1M – Racing Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1M – Endurance Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R6 (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R6 – Racing Modified (2019)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-MT10 ABS (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-MT10 ABS – Racing Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1M – Endurance Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1M – Racing Modified (2020)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-MT09 (2021)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-Ténéré 700 World Rally – RIDE Fest Edition (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-Ténéré 700 World Rally Edition (2023)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-Yamaha R1M Niccolò Canepa Edition (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-R7 – Endurance Modified (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-XSR 900 GP (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1M (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R1 (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-MT07 (2024)<wbr></li>
<li>Yamaha-YZF-R7 (2024)</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Tracks</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Circuito de Almeria (Spain)<wbr></li>
<li>Autopolis (Japan)<wbr></li>
<li>Blue Wave Arena (USA)<wbr></li>
<li>Blue Wave Circuit (USA)<wbr></li>
<li>Blue Wave Enduro (USA)<wbr></li>
<li>Brands Hatch Circuit (UK)<wbr></li>
<li>Cadwell Park Circuit (UK)<wbr></li>
<li>Canadian Tyre Motorsport Park (Canada)<wbr></li>
<li>Kapadokya Rally (Turkey)<wbr></li>
<li>Daytona International Speedway (USA)<wbr></li>
<li>Donnington Park (UK)<wbr></li>
<li>French Riviera (France)<wbr></li>
<li>Fuji International Speedway (Japan)<wbr></li>
<li>Gunma Mountain (Japan)<wbr></li>
<li>Autodromo Enzo e Dino Ferrari Imola (Italy)<wbr></li>
<li>Kanto Temples (Japan)<wbr></li>
<li>Kyalami Grand Prix Circuit (South Africa)<wbr></li>
<li>WeatherTech Raceway Laguna Seca (USA)<wbr></li>
<li>24 Heures du Mans Bugatti Circuit (France)<wbr></li>
<li>Circuit De Nevers Magny-Cours (France)<wbr></li>
<li>Autodromo Nazionale Di Monza (Italy)<wbr></li>
<li>Mugello (Italy)<wbr></li>
<li>Nevada (USA)<wbr></li>
<li>Nürburgring Nordschleife (Germany)<wbr></li>
<li>Nürburgring GP-Strecke (Germany)<wbr></li>
<li>North West 200 (Northen Irland)<wbr></li>
<li>Okayama International Circuit (Japan)<wbr></li>
<li>Autódromo Internacional Algarve (Portugal)<wbr></li>
<li>Red Bull Ring – Spielberg (Austria)<wbr></li>
<li>Road America (USA)<wbr></li>
<li>Michelin Raceway Road Atlanta (USA)<wbr></li>
<li>Southern 100 (UK)<wbr></li>
<li>Stelvio (Italy)<wbr></li>
<li>Parco Enduro delle Alpi (Italy)<wbr></li>
<li>Sportsland SUGO (Japan)<wbr></li>
<li>Suzuka (Japan)<wbr></li>
<li>Ulster GP (Northen Irland)<wbr></li>
<li>Circuit Ricardo Tormo (Spain)<wbr></li>
<li>Autodromo di Vallelunga (Italy)</li>
</ol>
<p>Ride 6 has been developed using Unreal Engine 5 which has allowed Milestone to add in a new dual physics system. This is split between Pro for players who want to get right into the simulation side of Ride 6, and Arcade for players who just want to ride around without having to fiddle too much with different bike parts. The Riding School will allow players to learn different parts of the game and complete challenges, and Ride 6 will also support cross platform play multiplayer. Split screen multiplayer and a race creator are not going to be available at launch for Ride 6, but will come later down the line. The game will be available on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series XS.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2815070/view/490458043038827222">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/09/ride-6-full-bike-and-track-list-has-been-confirmed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘AI Can Speed Up Game Development But Human Intention Is What Makes Our Stuff Special’, Says Elder Scrolls & Fallout Dev]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ai-can-speed-up-game-development-human-intention-is-what-makes-our-stuff-special/</link>
            <guid>1377046</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Bethesda Game Studios' Head and game director for the Elder Scrolls and Fallout series (as well as Starfield), Todd Howard, recently chimed in on the hottest topic across most industries: the usage of AI.</p>



<p><span>Eurogamer<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-and-elder-scrolls-boss-todd-howard-defends-ai-in-game-development-but-aims-to-protect-artistry-and-human-intention-in-his-games" target="_blank"> interviewed Howard</a></span> during a preview event for the second season of Fallout's Amazon Prime Video show, which starts airing on Wednesday, December 17. On that occasion, the veteran developer mused that AI is effectively a tool that can make development go faster, but it won't replace the human intention, which is what really makes Bethesda's games (and great games in general) special. </p>



<p><em>I view it as a tool. Creative intention comes from human artists, number one. But, I think we look at it as a tool for, is there a way we can use it to help us go through some iterations that we do ourselves faster. Not in generating things, but we are always working on our toolset for how we build our worlds or check things.</em></p>



<p><em>I think if you go back 10 years ago, that version of Photoshop, you wouldn't want to go back to that version of Photoshop. That's our view on it. But we want to protect the artistry. The human intention of it is what makes our stuff special.</em></p>



<p>It's a similar view to that of fellow games industry legend Hideo Kojima, who recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/hideo-kojima-sees-creating-together-with-ai-way-stay-one-step-ahead/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">claimed</a> to consider AI as a 'friend' that could perform tedious tasks, thereby boosting efficiency, while he and the rest of his team at Kojima Productions focus on creative tasks.</p>



<p>Efficiency is definitely among the top priorities of large, triple-A game developers and publishers nowadays. With the continuous rise of budgets, AI is seen as an essential tool to reduce costs. Electronic Arts CEO Andrew Wilson previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-ceo-says-generative-ai-is-the-very-core-of-business-not-a-buzzword/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stated</a> that efficiency, expansion, and transformation are the three key areas of innovation that AI amplifies. However, as noted by Todd Howard, its application cannot come at the expense of human creativity. </p>



<p>As a side note, Eurogamer also asked Howard about his game of the year, and the Elder Scrolls and Fallout director joined the <a href="https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-gets-goty-votes-phil-spencer-naoki-hamaguchi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">chorus of creatives and executives who voted for Sandfall Interactive's Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>.</p>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ai-can-speed-up-game-development-human-intention-is-what-makes-our-stuff-special/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD Ryzen 9 Gets Another Price Drop After Black Friday as Amazon Clears Out Best-Selling CPU Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amd-ryzen-9-gets-another-price-drop-after-black-friday-as-amazon-clears-out-best-selling-cpu-stock-2000651635</link>
            <guid>1377040</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If your regular days involve running demanding creative software or playing high-end gaming titles, an average laptop isn’t going to cut it. You need a high-performing processor that’s specifically built keeping these use cases in mind, and today is a great time to pick one up.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6218/">The ultra-powerful, 16-core AMD Ryzen 9 9950X desktop processor, which usually goes for $649, is available for $530, after a nice 18% discount.</a> It’s a straightforward $119 drop, meaning there are no long coupon codes to remember or complicated checkout steps to follow. This is the lowest it’s dropped to in the last 30 days, and we’re expecting the discount to wrap up soon. Place your orders before that happens.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6218/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Smooth Performance for Demanding Tasks</h2>
<p>This processor is made keeping creatives and gamers in mind. The 16 Cores and 32 processing threads are based on AMD’s Zen 5 architecture that evolves with your needs, letting you push all creative and entertainment limits without holding back. It’s packed with the power you need to level up with its 5.7 GHz Max Boost clock speed during demanding tasks, plus offers features like AMD Expo tech, one-touch memory overclocking for instant lift when it’s showtime. In simple words, the processor is more than capable of handling tasks like heavier video editing, 3D rendering, and gaming. Need even more power for a larger project? It offers that too, helping you stay on top of your game, regardless of what the day requires.</p>



<p>DDR5-5600 support lets you multitask faster, which can especially come in handy when you’re trying to manage a bunch of things at the same time. There’s PCIe 5.0 support on select motherboards just as well. This makes your system future-proof, plus lets you enjoy quicker transfer and boot times. Even better, AMD Ryzen 5 offers built-in AI acceleration and enhanced AI capabilities for unmatched productivity. For an even smoother experience, it’s best to pair the processor with the Radeon RX 7000 Series graphics card for a complete, ultra-fast setup.</p>
<p>All things considered, if you’ve been looking for a way to perform heavy-duty creative tasks like video editing and modeling more efficiently, or game like a pro, having the right processor in your setup can make all the difference. This one, in particular, offers incredible performance for all your tasks, no matter how demanding they get. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6218/">On a regular day, it would run you around $649, but this deal lets you grab it for $530.</a> It’s still a bit of an investment, sure, but one that’s going to be worth it. The offer is selling out fast, though. At this rate, the stock could run dry sooner than you anticipate, which is why we highly recommend grabbing yours without wasting time. Ordering now will also help you get it before Christmas; great if you’re planning to surprise a loved one with it this holiday season.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6218/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amd-ryzen-9-gets-another-price-drop-after-black-friday-as-amazon-clears-out-best-selling-cpu-stock-2000651635]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dig Into Donkey Kong Bananza's Third DLC In-Game Event Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/dig-into-donkey-kong-bananzas-third-dlc-in-game-event-next-week</link>
            <guid>1377022</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Jungle Beat fans, rise up!</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="88171c2f35900"><a title="Donkey Kong Bananza - 'Dig to the Beat'" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/88171c2f35900/donkey-kong-bananza-dig-to-the-beat.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo has revealed the next in-game event set to land in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza-dk-island-and-emerald-rush">Donkey Kong Bananza - Emerald Rush</a> DLC, and it features some familiar faces for fans of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/donkey_kong_jungle_beat">Jungle Beat</a>.</p>
<p>The 'Dig to the Beat' event gets underway on <strong>16th December</strong>, and will be sticking around until <strong>23rd December</strong>, so you have plenty of time to rack up an Emerald Rush high score and pick up the reward statues.</p>
<p>And what rewards they are! Hot off the back of Lanky and Chunky Kong's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/donkey-kong-bananzas-next-dlc-in-game-event-swings-into-action-next-week">statue appearances last month</a>, the upcoming event features Jungle Beat's Ghastly and Ninja Kong, immortalised as unlockable island accessories.</p><div><figure data-videoid="fMx2XNyAq4E" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytfMx2XNyAq4E" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5d98e4khqnxs&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>For reference, here is the exact time that the 'Dig to the Beat' event will kick off in your region:</p>
<ul><li><strong>North America:</strong> 12am PST / 1am MST / 2am CST / 3am EST</li><li><strong>UK/Ire:</strong> 8am GMT</li><li><strong>Europe:</strong> 9am CET / 10am EET</li><li><strong>Asia/Oceania:</strong> 5pm JST / 4pm AWST / 7pm AEDT</li></ul>

<p>As was the case with the two debut events, this one will challenge you to complete Emerald Rush runs with a limited, pre-determined set of perks available, so prepare to switch up your gem-collecting tactics on the fly.</p>
<p>This will likely be the final in-game event of the year, but we expect to see more swing over to the DLC package in 2026.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187829,192805 @ 1765293335 -->
<p><em>Will you be taking part in the next Emerald Rush event? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/dig-into-donkey-kong-bananzas-third-dlc-in-game-event-next-week]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>