<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 12:56:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Itch.io taken down by collectible maker Funko and AI tool Brand Shield]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/itch-io-taken-down-by-collectible-maker-funko-and-ai-tool-brand-shield</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/itch-io-taken-down-by-collectible-maker-funko-and-ai-tool-brand-shield.1055586/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/itch-io-taken-down-by-collectible-maker-funko-and-ai-tool-brand-shield<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Indie game marketplace itch.io was seemingly torpedoed over the weekend by collectible maker Funko.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/itchio/status/1866017758040993829">According to an X post from the official itch.io account</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the platform was taken down by Funko (maker of the immensely popular Funko Pop! figurines) and its AI-powered brand protection software, Brand Shield.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"[Brand Shield] created some bogus phishing report to our registrar, iwantmyname, who ignored our response and just disabled the domain," said itch on social media, but not before taking a moment to brand the software as "trash."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Also, for transparency, we did take the disputed page down as soon as we got the notice because it's not worth fighting stuff like that. Regardless, our registrar's automated system likely kicked to disable the domain since no one read our confirmation of removal."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Itch.io appears to be back online at the time of writing. The company noted its servers weren't impacted by the situation and said it reached out to iwantmyname to ask "WTF is going on."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Itch decided to hold tight before taking any drastic measures, such as putting up a new domain, but did offer a workaround. "There are implications with third party services that make [switching domains] not a trivial swap. In the meantime, if you know how to tweak your hosts file use: 45.33.107.166," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/itchio/status/1866049560411566495">the company added in a follow-up post.</a></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"If you do edit your hosts file, please remember to remove all the lines after domain is restored. Although we typically hold an IP for a while, it can change if we update our back-end infrastructure. If the downtime exceeds 8 hours then we'll likely prioritize deploying a new domain. Hopefully things are able to get sorted out before then."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Brand Shield, Funko, and Itch.io for more information.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deathstroke kicks off Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League's final announced season]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/deathstroke-kicks-off-suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-leagues-final-announced-season</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deathstroke-kicks-off-suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-leagues-final-announced-season.1055583/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/deathstroke-kicks-off-suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-leagues-final-announced-season<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league">Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</a>'s fourth season starts tomorrow, marking the beginning of the end for Rocksteady's current roadmap.</p>
<p>From 10th December, players will be met with DC supervillain Deathstroke. The developer shared news of his debut with an image on social media platform X, although further details on the upcoming season for now remain pretty thin for now.</p>
<p>Rocksteady has thus far only committed to four seasons of content for Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League. It shared its <a href="https://x.com/suicidesquadRS/status/1749494429768146999/photo/1">2024 roadmap back in January</a>, promising new weapons, environments, gear and more. Things kicked off with the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squads-first-post-launch-season-includes-playable-elseworlds-joker">arrival of The Joker in March</a>, before <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squads-second-season-adds-frozone-esque-mrs-freeze">Mrs. Freeze joined in the summer</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League - IS IT A QUINNER OR A SINNER?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aZS4HXe3-_E?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League - IS IT A QUINNER OR A SINNER?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aZS4HXe3-_E?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/aZS4HXe3-_E?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Let's Play Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League - IS IT A QUINNER OR A SINNER? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aZS4HXe3-_E" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>More recently, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-season-three-debuts-to-less-than-300-steam-players">Zoe Lawton joined for Kill the Justice League's third season</a>. However, her debut didn't particularly spark much enthusiasm among players. Perhaps Deathstroke will have better luck.</p>
<p>Then, after season four comes to an end, who knows what is going to happen with Suicide Sqaud: Kill the Justice League. It is fair to say the game failed to take off the way Rocksteady and publisher Warner Bros. had hoped.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(489).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rocksteady</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Back in February of this year, Warner Bros. Discovery's chief financial officer Gunnar Wiedenfels said <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-fails-to-meet-warner-bros-expectations">Rocksteady's release had "fallen short" of its expectations</a>. Warner Bros. went on to attribute a $200m revenue loss to Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League.</p>
<p>A report then followed in July, which stated a culture of perfectionism, an ill-suited genre pivot, and a constantly shifting vision were <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squad-flopped-due-to-perfectionism-and-ill-suited-genre-pivot-report">key reasons for the live-service game's failure</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demon Slayer: The Hinokami Chronicles sequel announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/demon-slayer-the-hinokami-chronicles-sequel-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demon-slayer-the-hinokami-chronicles-sequel-announced.1055580/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/demon-slayer-the-hinokami-chronicles-sequel-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>With roster of over 40 characters.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Demon-Slayer--Kimetsu-no-Yaiba--The-Hinokami-Chronicles-2-Announce-(11).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sega</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sega has announced a sequel to its official Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba game, based on the popular manga and anime series.</p>
<p>Demon Slayer -Kimetsu no Yaiba- The Hinokami Chronicles 2 will arrive next year across PC via Steam, PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, and the "Nintendo Switch family of systems".</p>
<p>Like the first game, this will be an arena fighter with a story mode continuing where the original left off. It follows teenage protagonist Tanjiro Kamado and promises fans will be able to "relive many of the exciting moments from 'Entertainment District Arc', 'Swordsmith Village Arc', and 'Hashira Training Arc'".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Demon Slayer -Kimetsu no Yaiba- The Hinokami Chronicles 2 | Game Trailer #1" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CDVfumgZSFI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Demon Slayer -Kimetsu no Yaiba- The Hinokami Chronicles 2 | Game Trailer #1</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CDVfumgZSFI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CDVfumgZSFI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Demon Slayer -Kimetsu no Yaiba- The Hinokami Chronicles 2 | Game Trailer #1<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CDVfumgZSFI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Over in VS mode, the game will have a huge roster of 40 characters, including a return of all characters in the original game, its free post-launch updates, and paid DLC.</p>
<p>The nine Hashira (the highest rank of the Demon Slayer Corps) will also join in the sequel, including Muichiro Tokito and Mitsuri Kanroji.</p>
<p>Demon Slayer: The Hinokami Chronicles has sold over 4m units worldwide following its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-demon-slayer-game-heads-west-in-october">release in 2021</a>, so there's certainly an appetite for this sequel.</p>
<p>The games are developed by CyberConnect2, the Japanese studio known for other anime and manga adaptations like <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dragon-ball-z-kakarot">Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/naruto-ultimate-ninja">Naruto: Ultimate Ninja</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam, Path of Exile 2, and Marvel Rivals All Broke Records This Weekend]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/steam-path-of-exile-2-and-marvel-rivals-all-broke-records-this-weekend/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-path-of-exile-2-and-marvel-rivals-all-broke-records-this-weekend.1055568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/steam-path-of-exile-2-and-marvel-rivals-all-broke-records-this-weekend/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been another weekend of records on Valve's Steam. Yesterday at 14:00 UTC, Steam itself broke a new concurrency record of 39.2 million users, over 12 million of whom were playing a game.&nbsp; Valve's platform continues to grow at an astonishing rate. In January, it <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-sets-new-top-concurrent-player-number-record-nearing-34-million-connected-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reached</a> 33.6 million users; the 34 million threshold was <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-sets-new-record-with-over-34-million-concurrent-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">broken</a> in early March and quickly surpassed by two new records (35 and <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-sets-another-record-with-36-million-concurrent-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">36 million</a>). The 37 million milestone was <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-achieves-37-2-million-concurrent-players-breaking-all-previous-records/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reached</a> in August, while the following Steam <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-hits-all-time-record-38-3-million-pc-players/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">surpassed</a> 38 million concurrent online users. Of course, these new peaks usually happen whenever big games are released, driving users to engage with the platform. That was the case this past weekend with Grinding Gear's Path of Exile 2 and NetEase's Marvel Rivals.</p>
<p>The action RPG sequel launched into early access this past Friday and it's doing amazing numbers for a premium game (this early access phase is paid, while the full launch will be free to play) with a Steam player peak <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2694490/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">registered</a> at 578K around fourteen hours ago. So far, user reviews are also quite positive (82%), aligning with <a href="https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-early-access-hands-on-the-arpg-that-could-rule-them-all/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Francesco De Meo's early access preview on Wccftech</a>:</p>
<p><em> The Early Access version made it clear how Grinding Gear Games has a very strong idea of how to evolve the formula of its predecessor to deliver an experience that is, undoubtedly, very fun at all skill levels. Considering how the game manages to be both extremely welcoming and extremely deep at the same time, I have no doubt that Path of Exile 2 will only get better from here on out, having the potential to become one of the best action role-playing games ever released.</em></p>
<p>The game is performing well on all platforms,&nbsp;<span><a href="https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-early-access-redemptions-top-1-million-queues-over-the-weekend-are-expected/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">surpassing</a></span>&nbsp;a million users in total. In fact, the developers were forced to enable temporary server queues.</p>
<p>Marvel Rivals also had a strong launch, <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-launches-with-a-bang-thanks-to-444k-concurrent-users-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">registering</a> a peak of 444K concurrent users on Steam during the week and then <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2767030/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">breaking</a> it with 480K users fourteen hours ago. However, the game has even more success on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series S|X - <a href="https://x.com/MarvelRivals/status/1865909229070016851" target="_blank" rel="noopener">according to NetEase</a>, the team-based PvP superhero shooter has registered over 10 million players in the first three days. Of course, it has the advantage of being already free-to-play.</p>
<p>Are you playing Path of Exile 2 or Marvel Rivals? Let us know in the comments.</p>

				

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Michel Ancel Says Beyond Good and Evil 2 Issues Were Caused by Problems Between Managers]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/beyond-good-and-evil-2-development-issues/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/michel-ancel-says-beyond-good-and-evil-2-issues-were-caused-by-problems-between-managers.1055562/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/beyond-good-and-evil-2-development-issues/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a rare interview, Michel Ancel said that problems between management caused Beyond Good and Evil 2’s development issues.</p>



<p>The new interview came from French outlet <a href="https://www.superpouvoir.com/entretien-avec-michel-ancel-le-createur-de-rayman-et-beyond-good-evil-se-confie-sur-sa-nouvelle-vie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Superpouvoir</a>, where Ancel answered elaberated on the development issues of Beyond Good and Evil 2 and where he believes some of the accusations of toxic management, of which he denies, originates.</p>



<p>“On&nbsp;BGE2, for example, there were too many problems between managers. The artistic director wanted to redo everything constantly, <span>and the&nbsp;game director&nbsp;wanted to make a game of generated dungeo</span>ns. I dreamed of a space adventure. We could not agree and the&nbsp;game director&nbsp;took the project in other directions,” he said. </p>



<p>Ancel continued, “In this type of situation, teams find themselves tossed around and don’t even know who’s in charge and making decisions. The producer is supposed to sort things out, but that didn’t happen.&nbsp;Yves Guillemot&nbsp;even had to go down to Montpellier to get things back on track, but that wasn’t enough and the&nbsp;<em>game director</em>&nbsp;continued in his stubbornness. When I read in Libé that I was the one directing the game and asking for changes, I thought I was going to choke.&nbsp;<em>BGE2</em>&nbsp;is the game on which I don’t think I’ve ever questioned a decision.”</p>



<p>Michal Ancel left Ubisoft in 2020 to spend time in a wildlife sanctuary following burnout while working on games. One week later, though, accusations of toxic leadership by Ancel began to circulate, which Ancel firmly denied and continues to do so.</p>



<p>As of the time of writing, Ubisoft’s Beyond Good and Evil 2 is still in development. After nearly two years of development, it finally found its footing in early 2017. Speaking with sources, the game is still a couple of years out, though. We’ll share some exclusive details on the game later this week.</p>



<p>What do you think of the issues surrounding Beyond Good and Evil 2? Do you think it will ever be released? &nbsp;Let us know how it’s going on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-ballistic-esports-operating-model/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the reveal of Fortnite Ballistic</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple and Sony Partnering Up for Vision Pro Controllers, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/apple-and-sony-partnering-up-for-vision-pro-controllers-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apple-and-sony-partnering-up-for-vision-pro-controllers-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1055559/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/apple-and-sony-partnering-up-for-vision-pro-controllers-its-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-72743">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Per a recent report, Apple and Sony are collaborating to bring third-party controller support for the Vision Pro.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2024-12-08/apple-sony-talk-playstation-vr-ps-vr2-hand-controller-support-for-vision-pro" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Bloomberg</a>, Apple approached Sony at the beginning of 2024 to bring support for PlayStation VR 2 controllers for the Vision Pro. Moreover, Apple has also had conversations with other third-party developers about featuring third-party controller support for their games on the VR platform. The controllers will not only be a valuable addition for gaming on the Vision Pro but also provide more control over the entire operating system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report adds that Apple and Sony had planned to announce PlayStation VR 2 controller support for the Vision Pro “weeks ago”; however, the announcement was postponed due to an undisclosed reason. Also, Sony has another hurdle to cross: selling their VR controllers as standalone accessories, as right now, they can only be acquired by purchasing the PlayStation VR 2 console. When the announcement does come, players will seemingly be able to grab the PS VR 2 controllers from Apple’s retail and online stores.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-was-exclusive-to-playstation-because-sony-was-worried-about-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA was exclusive to PlayStation</a> because Sony was worried about Xbox. Also, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-releases-new-playstation-30th-anniversary-thank-you-video/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation’s 30th Anniversary ‘Thank You’ video</a>. What are your thoughts on Apple and Sony partnering up to bring third-party support for the Vision Pro?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-has-changed-how-pal-spheres-work-in-the-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Palworld changing how Pal Spheres work in the game</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-has-changed-how-pal-spheres-work-in-the-game/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-has-changed-how-pal-spheres-work-in-the-game/">Palworld Has Changed How Pal-Spheres Work in the Game</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>While battling Nintendo’s patent infringement lawsuit, Palworld has changed the behaviour of Pal Spheres in its latest update. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-new-all-time-high-user-count/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-new-all-time-high-user-count/">Steam Just Hit Another All-Time High Peak User Count</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Steam has secured another all-time high peak user count, notching up almost 40 million online users at the same time this weekend.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/grand-theft-hamlet-awards-success/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/grand-theft-hamlet-awards-success/">Grand Theft Hamlet Continues to Turn Heads and Win Awards</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Grand Theft Hamlet is a legitimate, award-winning production recorded entirely within the confines of GTA Online.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hatsune-miku-fortnite-crossover-confirm/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hatsune-miku-fortnite-crossover-confirm/">Hatsune Miku Coming to Fortnite in 2025, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Hatsune Miku is rumoured to be appearing in Fortnite in early 2025. These claims come from prominent Fortnite leakers on social media.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond Good & Evil 2's troubled development due to "passionate managers" not getting along, says creator Michel Ancel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/beyond-good-evil-2s-troubled-development-due-to-passionate-managers-not-getting-along-says-creator-michel-ancel</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beyond-good-evil-2s-troubled-development-due-to-passionate-managers-not-getting-along-says-creator-michel-ancel.1055553/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/beyond-good-evil-2s-troubled-development-due-to-passionate-managers-not-getting-along-says-creator-michel-ancel<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>And why WiLD was cancelled.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Beyond-Good-and-Evil-2-Trailer---BGE2-Trailer-from-E3-2018-1-32-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2's troubled development was due to "passionate managers" not getting along, the series' creator Michel Ancel has said.</p>
<p>The sequel to the cult classic adventure has been in development for almost 20 years (the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/beyond-good-evil-2-overtakes-guinness-record-holder-duke-nukem-forever-as-game-longest-in-development">longest in history</a>), and has continued despite <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rayman-creator-michel-ancel-quits-video-games-industry-to-work-on-wildlife-sanctuary">Ancel leaving Ubisoft back in 2020 due to retirement</a>. His departure <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/new-report-says-michel-ancel-left-ubisoft-amid-investigation-into-his-toxic-behaviour">followed an investigation into allegations of toxic leadership</a> by French newspaper Libération.</p>
<p>Ancel has not spoken publicly about the game's development since, but in a new interview with French outlet <a href="https://www.superpouvoir.com/entretien-avec-michel-ancel-le-createur-de-rayman-et-beyond-good-evil-se-confie-sur-sa-nouvelle-vie/">SuperPouvoir</a> he has now discussed some of the tensions and accusations made against him.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="New Beyond Good and Evil 2 Trailer - BGE2 Trailer from E3 2018" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CDdyhkBEi9g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>New Beyond Good and Evil 2 Trailer - BGE2 Trailer from E3 2018</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CDdyhkBEi9g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CDdyhkBEi9g?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>New Beyond Good and Evil 2 Trailer - BGE2 Trailer from E3 2018<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CDdyhkBEi9g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Passion is a "fabulous energy", said Ancel, but can also lead to clashes. For BG&amp;E2, he stated how the game's art director had wanted to redo everything over and over, that the game's director had wanted a game of generated dungeons, while he "dreamed of a space adventure".</p><p>The trio were unable to agree on a direction, with the development team left not knowing who was ultimately in charge. Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot even visited the Montpellier studio, Ancel said, but it wasn't enough and "the game director continued in his stubbornness", said Ancel.</p>
<p>"When I read in Libé that I was the one who was directing the game and asking for changes, I thought I was choking," Ancel said. "BG&amp;E2 is the game on which I think I have never questioned a decision.</p>
<p>"In the end, it is all a matter of passionate managers who have not gotten along. I believe that for some time now, these people have been let go and the project has found a certain balance with new leaders."</p>
<p>Ancel added there's a "huge difference" between developing BG&amp;E2 with new technology, and a project with established technology. This complexity "exceeded many people at Ubisoft".</p>
<p>He surmised there was no "single big villain" but multiple concerns left unresolved with managers. "I have my share of responsibility and I should have defended the project better, been more present and more conciliatory with the employees," he concluded.</p>
<p>According to the Libération report into Ancel's toxic leadership, his management of the project resulted in constant changes and fluctuations in scope, leading to "an unusual amount of [staff] exhaustion, depression, and burnout".</p>
<p>Ancel also discussed the end of WiLD, the project from his Wild Sheep studio originally announced in 2014 that was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-exclusive-prehistoric-open-world-adventure-wild-has-reportedly-been-cancelled">reported as having been cancelled in 2021</a>.</p>
<p>Though a playable version had been established in 2018, Ancel said the studio chose to upgrade the game from PS4 to PS5. However, despite Sony offering double Ubisoft's budgets to take on the game as publisher, it was turned down and remained with Ubisoft.</p><p>This was during Ancel's burnout and subsequent departure from the industry. Without him there to defend the game, he said, it was "crushed" by Ubisoft due to changes made "without really playing the game", which Ancel described as "a real scandal". The game was later abandoned in 2020 due to no longer matching the original vision.</p>
<p>He added the "editorial department was in full explosion" at this time due to Ubisoft's internal <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-exec-tommy-francois-leaves-company">investigation into former editorial vice president Tommy François</a> who had overseen development of WiLD, who was reportedly then fired.</p>
<p>Ancel joked 2018 was therefore "the beginning of the end" for both WiLD and BG&amp;E2, in his eyes.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/beyond-good-evil-2-still-in-development-now-with-new-creative-director">Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 remains in development</a>, it was confirmed again in October this year, with a new creative director once again at the helm.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld Has Changed How Pal-Spheres Work in the Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-has-changed-how-pal-spheres-work-in-the-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-has-changed-how-pal-spheres-work-in-the-game.1055547/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-has-changed-how-pal-spheres-work-in-the-game/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-72739">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>In their latest update, Palworld developers have changed the behaviour of Pal Spheres while battling Nintendo’s patent infringement lawsuit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Pal Spheres work like Pokeballs and capture and summon Pals in Palworld. However, after <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1623730/view/4477236636060484669" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">version v0.3.11 </a>(spotted by <a href="https://nichegamer.com/palworld-removes-pal-sphere-summons/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NicheGamer</a>), the Pal Spheres will have a different activation. Now, whenever a player uses a Pal Sphere, their Pal will be summoned near the player without them needing to throw the sphere. Also, the new update will display a reticle while aiming.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-lawsuit-palworld-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest developments</a> on Nintendo’s lawsuit against Palworld, the former has alleged that the latter has infringed three different patents and is seeking damages of 10 million Yen (approximately USD 66,000). Pocket Pair replied, stating they “will continue to assert our position in this case through future legal proceedings” in the lawsuit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Palxworld is getting its biggest island yet in December, which is about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-december-dlc-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">six times bigger than Sakurajima</a>. Also, Palworld has finally launched for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-finally-launches-for-ps5-in-japan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PS5 consoles in Japan</a>. What are your thoughts on Palworld changing how Pal Spheres work in the game?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-new-all-time-high-user-count/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam breaking its all-time player peak count again</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-new-all-time-high-user-count/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-new-all-time-high-user-count/">Steam Just Hit Another All-Time High Peak User Count</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Steam has secured another all-time high peak user count, notching up almost 40 million online users at the same time this weekend.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/grand-theft-hamlet-awards-success/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/grand-theft-hamlet-awards-success/">Grand Theft Hamlet Continues to Turn Heads and Win Awards</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Grand Theft Hamlet is a legitimate, award-winning production recorded entirely within the confines of GTA Online.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hatsune-miku-fortnite-crossover-confirm/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hatsune-miku-fortnite-crossover-confirm/">Hatsune Miku Coming to Fortnite in 2025, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Hatsune Miku is rumoured to be appearing in Fortnite in early 2025. These claims come from prominent Fortnite leakers on social media.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Is a Smash Hit With 10 Million Players in Just 3 Days]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-is-a-smash-hit-with-10-million-players-in-just-3-days</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-is-a-smash-hit-with-10-million-players-in-just-3-days.1055541/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-is-a-smash-hit-with-10-million-players-in-just-3-days<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvel-rivals">Marvel Rivals</a> just hit an impressive milestone: 10 million players in three days.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">NetEase’s free-to-play superhero team-based PvP shooter launched on December 6 across PC via Steam and the Epic Games Store, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S. While Sony and Microsoft do not make PlayStation or Xbox player numbers public, Steam makes Valve stats available, and it’s there that Marvel Rivals is enjoying a particularly massive launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marvel Rivals peaked over its launch weekend with 480,990 concurrent players, which was enough to put it in Steam’s top five most-played games. It’s the 20th highest concurrent player number ever seen on Steam, ahead of the likes of Helldivers 2, Grand Theft Auto 5, and Destiny 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On Steam, Marvel Rivals has a ‘mostly positive’ user review rating, with 76% of the 35,000 reviews tagged as positive. Check out IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-review"><u>Marvel Rivals Review in Progress</u></a> to find out what we think.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Marvel Rivals - Character Skins Gallery</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">For NetEase, it will be hoping not only to keep Marvel Rivals’ player count as high as possible for as long as possible (something that’s proved particularly tricky for live service games of late), but to make enough money from players to meet the company’s internal revenue projections. To that end, Marvel Rivals sells a battle pass and premium skins, but are they convincing players to open their wallets? Early signs suggest they are — Marvel Rivals is the second top-selling game on Steam by revenue, behind only Grinding Gear Games’ action RPG <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/path-of-exile-2">Path of Exile 2</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marvel Rivals launched alongside Season 0, dubbed Dooms’ Rise. This month-long kick-off season starts with a total of 33 heroes, all available to play for free, eight maps for Quick Match and Competitive modes, a Conquest map, and a Practice Range. Dooms' Rise serves as the opening chapter “for the chaos caused by each of Doctor Dooms’ time experiments colliding and unleashing the Timestream Entanglement,” NetEase said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s a Twitch Drops event for Season 0, as you’d expect from a live service game of this type, an 'Entangled Moments' seasonal event to unlock spray rewards, gallery card rewards, and stories for completing tasks, and a global launch gift: a special code for a free Iron Man costume.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Hinokami Chronicles 2 launches in 2025 for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles-2-launches-in-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-%E2%80%93-the-hinokami-chronicles-2-launches-in-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.1055538/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles-2-launches-in-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Fight your way through the events of the Entertainment District, Swordsmith Village and Hashira Training arcs.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba - The Hinokami Chronicles 2 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles-2">Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Hinokami Chronicles 2</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,498 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,447 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,514 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,663 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,401 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,901 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam in 2025, publishers <a title="Companies > Aniplex [260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-music-entertainment-japan/aniplex">Aniplex</a> and <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,632 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a>, and developer <a title="Companies > CyberConnect2 [600 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cyberconnect2">CyberConnect2</a> announced. <span id="more-932398"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via SEGA:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Forge bonds, slay demons!</p><p><em>Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Hinokami Chronicles 2</em> is coming in 2025! </p><p><strong>Hashira Joins as Playable Characters</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>All nine Hashira, the highest-ranking Demon-Slayer swordmen: Giyu Tomioka (Water Hashira), Kyojuro Rengoku (Flame Hashira), Tengen Uzui (Sound Hashira), Muichiro Tokito (Mist Hashira), Shinobu Kocho (Insect Hashira), Mitsuri Kanroji (Love Hashira), Obanai Iguro (Serpent Hashira), Sanemi Shinazugawa (Wind Hashira), and Gyomei Himejima (Stone Hashira) have been made into playable characters.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_932411"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Story Mode</strong></p><p>Continue where Tanjiro’s journey left off in the first <em><a title="Games > Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba - The Hinokami Chronicles [78 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles">Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Hinokami Chronicles</a></em>.</p><p>Fight your way through the events of the Entertainment District Arc, Swordsmith Village Arc, and Hashira Training Arc from the anime adaptation!</p><p><strong>VS Mode</strong></p><p>Select from a wide array of brand-new characters to play as, such as Muichiro Tokito and Mitsuri Kanroji, the two Hashira who take on an Upper Rank demon in the Swordsmith Village Arc. The full roster includes the eighteen characters from the original <em>Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Hinokami Chronicles</em>, the demons added in the free update, and the characters from the Entertainment District downloadable content packs.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles-2/december-9-2024/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website here: <a href="https://asia.sega.com/kimetsu_hinokami2/en/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">English</a> / <a href="https://game.kimetsu.com/hinokami2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Japanese</a>.</p><h2><span>Trailer #1</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Demon Slayer -Kimetsu no Yaiba- The Hinokami Chronicles 2 | Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nJ7S0H_WRsM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="家庭用ゲーム「鬼滅の刃 ヒノカミ血風譚2」第1弾PV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zeGbrb_o9Xo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phantom Brave: The Lost Hero post-launch DLC schedule announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/phantom-brave-the-lost-hero-post-launch-dlc-schedule-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phantom-brave-the-lost-hero-post-launch-dlc-schedule-announced.1055535/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/phantom-brave-the-lost-hero-post-launch-dlc-schedule-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Six scenarios, eight playable characters, and five handy adventuring items.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Nippon Ich Software has announced the post-launch downloadable content schedule for strategy <em><a title="Games > Phantom Brave: The Lost Hero [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/phantom-brave-the-lost-hero">Phantom Brave: The Lost Hero</a></em>, which includes six additional scenarios and eight playable characters from previous <a title="Companies > Nippon Ichi Software [1,093 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nippon-ichi-software">Nippon Ichi Software</a> games. <span id="more-932375"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ Season Pass</strong> (4,900 yen / 5,390 yen with tax)</p><p>A bundle including all six additional scenarios and eight playable characters characters, as well as the five handy adventuring items. As a bonus, users who purchase the Season Pass will also receive the bonus downloadable content “Grunt Pirate Costume” for the Sailor, Healer, and Chef general character classes.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Phantom-Brave-The-Lost-Hero_DLC_2024_12-10-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>■ Scenarios and Characters</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>February 6, 2025</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Scenario: “Siblings from Parallel Worlds”</strong><ul><li><strong>Characters:</strong> Castile and Walnut (<em>Phantom Brave</em>)</li><li><strong>Price:</strong> 1,400 yen (1,540 yen with tax)</li></ul></li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Phantom-Brave-The-Lost-Hero_DLC_2024_12-10-24_003.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>February 13, 2025</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Scenario: “Heroes of the Past”</strong><ul><li><strong>Characters:</strong> Scarlet and Sprout (<em>Phantom Brave</em>)</li><li><strong>Price:</strong> 1,400 yen (1,540 yen with tax)</li></ul></li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Phantom-Brave-The-Lost-Hero_DLC_2024_12-10-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>February 20, 2025</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Scenario: “The Pirate and the <a title="Games > Wanderer [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wanderer">Wanderer</a>“</strong><ul><li><strong>Characters:</strong> Samayoi, the Wanderer (<em><a title="Games > Bar Stella Abyss [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bar-stella-abyss">Bar Stella Abyss</a></em>)</li><li><strong>Price:</strong> 700 yen (770 yen with tax)</li></ul></li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Phantom-Brave-The-Lost-Hero_DLC_2024_12-10-24_005.jpg"></a></figure><ul><li><strong>Scenario: “The Liar Princess and the Lost Prince”</strong><ul><li><strong>Characters:</strong> Princess (<em>The Liar Princess and the Blind Prince</em>)</li><li><strong>Price:</strong> 700 yen (770 yen with tax)</li></ul></li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Phantom-Brave-The-Lost-Hero_DLC_2024_12-10-24_006.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>February 27, 2025</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Scenario: “The Girl Who Summoned a Ghost”</strong><ul><li><strong>Characters:</strong> Kotomo (<em>Yomawari</em>)</li><li><strong>Price:</strong> 700 yen (770 yen with tax)</li></ul></li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Phantom-Brave-The-Lost-Hero_DLC_2024_12-10-24_007.jpg"></a></figure><ul><li><strong>Scenario: “The Rat Feared by the Devil”</strong><ul><li><strong>Characters:</strong> Mad Rat &amp; Heart (<em>Mad Rat Dead</em>)</li><li><strong>Price:</strong> 700 yen (770 yen with tax)</li></ul></li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Phantom-Brave-The-Lost-Hero_DLC_2024_12-10-24_008.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>■ Handy Adventuring Items</strong></p><p><strong>January 30, 2025</strong></p><ul><li><strong>BOL Sack</strong> (100 yen / 110 yen with tax) – Grants 100,000 BOL (in-game currency).</li><li><strong><a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a> Sack</strong> (100 yen / 110 yen with tax) – Grants 50,000 mana to use when upgrading items.</li><li><strong>Boost Ticket 100%</strong> (100 yen / 110 yen with tax) – A ticket that increases BOL, mana, and EXP earned in battle by 100 percent.</li><li><strong>Boost Ticket 400%</strong> (100 yen / 110 yen with tax) – A ticket that increases BOL, mana, and EXP earned in battle by 400 percent.</li><li><strong>Boost Ticket 900%</strong> (100 yen / 110 yen with tax) – A ticket that increases BOL, mana, and EXP earned in battle by 900 percent.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Phantom Brave: The Lost Hero</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,498 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,514 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,401 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on January 30, 2025 worldwide, followed by <a title="Platforms > PC [21,901 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3049990/Phantom_Brave_The_Lost_Hero/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in spring 2025.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life is Strange developer Deck Nine confirms another round of layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/life-is-strange-developer-deck-nine-confirms-another-round-of-layoffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/life-is-strange-developer-deck-nine-confirms-another-round-of-layoffs.1055529/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/life-is-strange-developer-deck-nine-confirms-another-round-of-layoffs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Life is Strange: Double Exposure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Deck Nine Games has laid off an undisclosed number of employees.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Studio CEO Mark Lyons confirmed the news in a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/deckninegames_activity-7270953893927239680-BKYc/">post on Linkedin</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Today, we are sad to share the news that we must say goodbye to some of our talented team members," he wrote, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/keyword/layoffs">echoing the chorus of studios that have downsized in 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "This was an extremely difficult decisions and reflects the challenging times many companies in our industry are facing."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The news comes shortly after the release of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Double Exposure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which launched on October 29 and continues the narrative that began in the original </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Life is Strange</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This is the second round of layoffs Deck Nine has made in 2024. The company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/deck-nine-games-lays-off-20-percent-of-staff">made 20 percent of its workforce redundant in February</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and blamed "worsening marketing conditions."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio also </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/life-is-strange-dev-deck-nine-games-hit-with-staff-layoffs">laid off 30 people in May 2023</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> but didn't provide any explanation for the move. It did, however, state those impacted "did nothing wrong."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Lyons has asked fans for "support and understanding" while the studio regroups following the latest round of layoffs. It's unclear how projects such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Double Exposure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will be impacted by the decision.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Deck Nine for more information.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle first update adds full ray tracing on PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-first-update-adds-full-ray-tracing-on-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-first-update-adds-full-ray-tracing-on-pc.1055526/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-first-update-adds-full-ray-tracing-on-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Indy-in-Indiana-Jones-and-the-Great-Circle-in-the-Temple-of-Doom-outfit.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bethesda/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The first update for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-developers-super-thrilled-its-headed-to-playstation">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> is here, available across PC and Xbox.</p>
<p>Along with a variety of fixes, this update has notably added full ray tracing (with path tracing) for Nvidia GPUs on PC. The Indy team said you will need to have a minimum of 12GB VRAM to get the most out of this feature, however.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Review. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ASn8vBoC0X4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Other PC-specific fixes include improved performance on larger game levels for those players using an 8GB VRAM video-card, and a fix for torch or lighter flames flickering when playing the game at a high refresh rate.</p>
<p>More generally, across platforms, photos that Indy takes when out and about should now appear more quickly when inspecting them from the journal. On the UI side of things, the Adventure Book list will now get updated immediately after unlocking a new book.</p><p>There are also a fair smattering of mission fixes, however I won't go into specifics here to avoid spoilers. If you want the full breakdown of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle's first patch, you can <a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/ZKn6jyPTe2ElFSJ0yZ2WA/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-tm-update-1?linkId=100000316950846">check out the notes here</a>.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/c21f4959-47c1-4941-90c8-4eee8fff78a5.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Bethesda/Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is available now for PC and Xbox. It will be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-confirmed-for-playstation-5">coming to PlayStation 5 in the spring of next year</a>.</p>
<p>We awarded Indiana Jones and the Great Circle five stars on its release. "Indiana Jones really feels like he comes full circle (sorry) in this latest adventure. At long last, there's an Indy game that nails both the puzzles and the kind of action we know so well from the films, and it does so with wit, charm and a real eye for spectacle," our Katharine wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">Eurogamer's Indiana Jones and the Great Circle review</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Darktide on PS5 – Another standout Warhammer 40K shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/09/darktide-ps5-review-warhammer-40k/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/darktide-on-ps5-%E2%80%93-another-standout-warhammer-40k-shooter.1055514/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/09/darktide-ps5-review-warhammer-40k/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The wait for <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/warhammer-40000-darktide">Warhammer 40,000: Darktide</a> on PS5 was made a little more bearable for 40K fans earlier this year with the release of <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2">Space Marine 2</a>. Saber Interactive’s surprise sequel to the 2011 hack n’ slash/shooter hybrid has achieved phenomenal success, and is certainly a tough act to follow.</p>
<p>However, Darktide is a markedly different kind of game, hailing from the same school of shooter as <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/left-4-dead">Left 4 Dead</a> and indeed developer Fatshark’s flagship title, <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/warhammer-end-times-vermintide">Warhammer: Vermintide</a>. No doubt seeing how popular their co-op action series has grown, the Swedish studio applied a similar template to Game Workshop’s gritty sci-fi universe.</p>
<p><iframe title="Warhammer 40,000: Darktide - PlayStation &amp; Grim Protocols Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MqQH6IJgpSA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>For the most part, it’s a great fit. Darktide delves deep into the dark underbelly of 40K, far away from the warring Space Marines and their xenos rivals, instead focusing on the spreading corruption of Chaos within the Hive City of Tertium. Here, hiding within a labyrinth of habitat zones, factories, and pleasure districts, sedition manifests in the form of mutant cults who have turned their backs on the Emperor, seeking salvation instead from dark and ancient deities.</p>
<p>One major difference between Darktide and Vermintide is the shift away from named playable heroes. Instead, you create your own avatar, choosing from one of four classes that each have their own distinct weapon loadouts and abilities though all are equally capable in combat. As you’d expect, the hulking Ogryn is a bullet sponge who excels in taunting foes and pulling aggro away from squishier squadmates such as the magic-wielding Psykers. Although Darktide gives you the tools to customise your own grimdark misfit, this isn’t to say they’re devoid of any character. In fact, there’s plenty to be gleaned about the 40K universe from the banter, barbs, and exchanges between heroes as they go about their Chaos-thumping crusade.</p>


<p>We won’t do a complete retread of our original <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/12/19/warhammer-40000-darktide-review/">Darktide review</a>, though what we praised about the game at launch still rings true. There’s an immense amount of joy to be had shooting and pummelling huge waves of enemies as you steadily push along each gauntlet-like stage, completing objectives. On the lowest rung of the difficulty ladder it can be presented as mindless fun though there’s plenty of challenge to be had, pressing even the most coordinated of strike teams to work together.</p>
<p>One common critique of Darktide is also still true. Repetition is pretty much baked into the core experience, encouraging players to rerun stages over and over, gradually dialling up the difficulty while earning experience points, as well as new weapons and abilities. This is a game about perfecting your ideal loadout rather than seeing a concise narrative unfold from beginning to end. Thanks to various updates and major content drops – including the recent <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/02/cry-havoc-let-loose-the-grim-protocols-of-warhammer-40000-darktide/">Grim Protocols</a> – Darktide gives players much more to see and do while expanding the previously limited character progression system.</p>

<p>Through two years of toil and improvements, PlayStation fans get to experience Warhammer 40,000: Darktide at its very best complete with system-specific features such as DualSense haptics and a PS5 Pro performance boost. Online crossplay is another big boon, allowing you to matchmake with Xbox and PC players (something that was disappointingly absent from Vermintide 2). Speaking of which, Fatshark’s Skaven-stomping sequel is now long in the tooth and tail yet remains an ongoing success story within the blighted realm of live service video games – one that Darktide is looking to emulate.</p>
<p>Die hard fans have already managed to wring plenty of value from the game so far and there’s plenty of room to expand, though we doubt Fatshark will want to fragment its matchmaking pool by introducing premium maps. Having launched on all platforms, we’re eager to see what’s next as we go into 2025 and beyond, whether it’s new playable classes, enemies, and endgame modes.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[itch.io reportedly taken down by “bogus phishing report” by Funko]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/09/itch-io-reportedly-taken-down-by-bogus-phishing-report-by-funko/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/itch-io-reportedly-taken-down-by-%E2%80%9Cbogus-phishing-report%E2%80%9D-by-funko.1055511/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/09/itch-io-reportedly-taken-down-by-bogus-phishing-report-by-funko/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p><strong>Update 11AM 09/12</strong> – It looks like itch.io is back online, hopefully for good.</p>
<p><em>The original story follows.</em></p>


<hr>
<p>Popular indie game marketplace itch.io has been taken offline, the company blaming “bogus phishing reports” submitted AI brand protection used by Funko. Yeah. The plastic toys company…</p>
<p>Taking to <a href="https://x.com/itchio/status/1866017758040993829">social media</a>, the company explains:</p>
<p>I kid you not, itch.io has been taken down by [Funko] because they use some trash “AI Powered” Brand Protection Software called [BrandShield] that created some bogus Phishing report to our registrar, iwantmyname, who ignored our response and just disabled the domain. […]
</p><p>Also, for transparency, we *did* take the disputed page down as soon as we got the notice because it’s not worth fighting stuff like that. Regardless, our registrar’s automated system likely kicked to disable the domain since no one read our confirmation of removal.</p>

<p>This is potentially a major headache for all the developers who rely on the platform. While itch.io is often a compliment to hosting and selling games on Steam in particular, it also has other opportunities that Steam doesn’t necessarily accommodate – it can host game jams, it’s great for prototyping and it’s DRM free.</p>
<p>Hopefully this is able to be resolved quickly, though itch.io say they will try to get a new domain if downtime lasts longer than 8 hours.</p>
<p>We’re probably going to wait this one out. We considered putting up a new domain but there are implications with third party services that make it not a trivial swap. In the meantime, if you know how to tweak your hosts file use: 45.33.107.166</p>
<p>It’s a situation that highlights the flaws of both “AI powered” automation and online copyright claims, which can often be used indiscriminately or extra-judiciously by large companies to take down things they don’t like, whether they have an actual case or not. Adding AI to the mix without human hands as a check and balance doesn’t exactly help the situation…</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://x.com/itchio/status/1866017758040993829">itch.io twitter</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals opening weekend sees 10m players join in]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-rivals-opening-weekend-sees-10m-players-join-in</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-opening-weekend-sees-10m-players-join-in.1055508/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-rivals-opening-weekend-sees-10m-players-join-in<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Well shatter my Infinity Stones. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/free-to-play-hero-shooter-marvel-rivals-off-to-heroic-start-on-steam">Marvel Rivals' supercharged start</a> has now seen an astonishing 10 million players assemble over the game's opening weekend. 
</p>
<p>
A free-to-play six-on-six team shooter from Chinese giant NetEase, Marvel Rivals launched last Friday for PC via Steam and the Epic Games Store, on PlayStation 5 and on Xbox Series X/S. 
</p>
<p>
As of midnight last night, NetEase <a href="https://x.com/MarvelRivals/status/1865909229070016851">announced</a> that 10 million players had joined in across the game's various platforms. Excelsior!
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Marvel Rivals | Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-b0veB7q9P4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Marvel Rivals | Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-b0veB7q9P4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-b0veB7q9P4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Marvel Rivals launch trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-b0veB7q9P4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Marvel Rivals' roster of current and upcoming characters includes Marvel Cinematic Universe stalwarts such as Iron Man, Hulk, Scarlet Witch, Black Widow, Wolverine and Groot, along with other fan favourites such as Iron Fist, Cloak and Dagger and, of course, Squirrel Girl. (Seriously, when is she getting her MCU debut?)
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>🎉 In just 72 hours, we’ve reached an incredible milestone of 10 million players worldwide! 🎉</p><p>We want to extend our heartfelt thanks to each and every one of you. 🫶</p><p>Let’s ignite the battle together! 💖<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MarvelRivals?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MarvelRivals</a> <a href="https://t.co/5njTulx24e">pic.twitter.com/5njTulx24e</a></p></div>— Marvel Rivals (@MarvelRivals) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarvelRivals/status/1865909229070016851?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 9, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
As for how it plays, well, Marvel Rivals has been compared to Blizzard's hero shooter <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/overwatch">Overwatch</a>. 
</p>
<p>
Indeed, over the weekend, Blizzard's former boss - the ever-chatty Mike Ybarra - suggested Marvel Rivals was as much of an Overwatch copycat as the widely-discussed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tencents-horizon-clone-light-of-motiram-also-coming-to-ps5-of-all-platforms">Horizon Zero Dawn clone Light of Motiram</a>. 
</p>
<p>
Unfortunately, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-blizzard-boss-blasts-marvel-rivals-similarity-to-overwatch">Ybarra also seemed to suggest Marvel Rivals had copied Overwatch's character of Widowmaker</a> for Black Widow. The character - played by Scarlett Johansson in the MCU - was created by Marvel legend Stan Lee in 1964.
</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Bogus phishing report" from Funko takes indie game platform itch.io offline]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/bogus-phishing-report-from-funko-takes-indie-game-platform-itchio-offline</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bogus-phishing-report-from-funko-takes-indie-game-platform-itch-io-offline.1055505/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/bogus-phishing-report-from-funko-takes-indie-game-platform-itchio-offline<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Every minute is lost revenue."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/itchio-logo-header-textless_9X029em.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Itch.io</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Indie game platform itch.io has been taken offline after Funko allegedly logged a "bogus phishing report" to the website's registrar.</p>
<p>In a brief message posted this morning to Bluesky, the itch.io team said that Funko used "trash" AI-powered brand protection system Brand Shield and despite responding to challenge the phishing report, the site's domain has instead been disabled.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Is Sony buying FromSoftware's parent company the next big games industry acquisition?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qvqusIyhV2M" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"I kid you not, itch.io has been taken down by Funko of 'Funko Pop' because they use some trash 'AI Powered' Brand Protection Software called Brand Shield that created some bogus Phishing report to our registrar, iwantmyname, who ignored our response and just disabled the domain," the message said.</p>
<p>"I hope you're all having a nice Sunday evening."</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiginvwbfjau6624ym5ouawvkcd5fzvcud5atr7dfj6p5okm5cxvqa" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:oy37ivqnriw6nx3lrbcht2u3/app.bsky.feed.post/3lcu6h465bs2n"><p lang="en">I kid you not, @itch.io has been taken down by Funko of "Funko Pop" because they use some trash "AI Powered" Brand Protection Software called Brand Shield that created some bogus Phishing report to our registrar, iwantmyname, who ignored our response and just disabled the domain</p>— itch.io (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oy37ivqnriw6nx3lrbcht2u3?ref_src=embed">@itch.io</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:oy37ivqnriw6nx3lrbcht2u3/post/3lcu6h465bs2n?ref_src=embed">December 9, 2024 at 7:13 AM</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>"Sue them," <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/leafytail.bsky.social/post/3lcugqbsfek2o">said</a> one respondent. "Every minute is lost revenue. As someone who hosts games on itch.io I'm pissed at this nonsense."</p>
<p>"Itch should sue Funko, their registrar, and the BrandShield for loss of business on behalf of their own interests and the interest of their users, developers, and buyers," added <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alexvallimusic.bsky.social/post/3lcue2fp3qs2w">another</a>. "Because this is something that not only affects itch, but also everyone that hosts jams and releases software and games on there."</p>
<p>At the time of writing, itch.io remains offline.</p>
<p>Itch.io recently announced that it now <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indie-game-platform-itchio-now-requires-developers-to-tag-ai-content">requires developers to disclose whether generative AI has been used in their work.</a></p>
<p>In a statement, the platform detailed its new tagging requirement, specifying it is a required field for asset creator pages "to ensure buyers are aware of the origins of the material they are obtaining".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Itch.io is currently offline due to a ‘trash AI-powered’ phishing report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24316882/itch-io-offline-domain-registration-funko-report</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/itch-io-is-currently-offline-due-to-a-%E2%80%98trash-ai-powered%E2%80%99-phishing-report.1055490/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24316882/itch-io-offline-domain-registration-funko-report<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Indie game storefront&nbsp;<a href="http://itch.io/">Itch.io</a> is currently offline because of what it describes as a bogus phishing report. While the game store’s servers are still online, the domain for the website is currently pointing towards IP addresses that itch.io doesn’t own — making it inaccessible for most people.</p><p>Itch.io blames pop culture collectibles company Funko for the issues in a <a href="https://x.com/itchio/status/1866017758040993829">post on X</a>, “because they use some trash ‘AI-powered’ Brand Protection Software called Brand Shield that created some bogus Phishing report to our registrar.”</p><p>While the disputed page has been taken down, itch.io’s domain registrar, <a href="https://iwantmyname.com/">iwantmyname</a>, still disabled the domain likely due to automated systems. According to a <a href="https://x.com/itchio/status/1866022784222245305">post on X</a>, the indie game marketplace is now waiting on the domain registrar to respond and re-enable its domain.</p><p>If you know how to tweak your hosts file that maps hostnames to IP addresses then you can use the 45.33.107.166 IP address in the meantime, but you’ll need to remove the entry once the domain is restored. <a href="https://x.com/itchio/status/1866049795724648524">Itch.io is hoping</a> the problems will be resolved in a matter of hours so it doesn’t have to deploy a new domain name instead.</p><p>The domain issues come just days after itch.io <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295998/you-can-now-use-your-itch-io-url-as-your-username-on-bluesky">started allowing its users</a> to use its domain name for Bluesky accounts. If you have spent $10 on the platform then you have the option to use your itch.io profile URL on Bluesky, but the current domain issues mean anyone who switched to the custom itch.io URLs has an “invalid handle” error on Bluesky until the main itch.io domain is back online.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Michel Ancel Explains What Went Wrong with Beyond Good & Evil 2 and WiLD]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/michel-ancel-explains-what-went-wrong-with-beyond-good-evil-2-and-wild/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/michel-ancel-explains-what-went-wrong-with-beyond-good-evil-2-and-wild.1055475/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/michel-ancel-explains-what-went-wrong-with-beyond-good-evil-2-and-wild/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Video game designer Michel Ancel is primarily known for his work on Rayman, Beyond Good &amp; Evil, and Rabbids, although he also became infamous for two big failed projects attached to his name: Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 and WiLD.</p>
<p>Ancel <a href="https://wccftech.com/michel-ancel-retires-from-the-industry-wild-and-beyond-good-and-evil-2-development-to-continue/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">retired</a> from the games industry in September 2020, following <a href="https://wccftech.com/beyond-good-and-evil-2-development-disarray-michel-ancel-toxic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">allegations of toxic management</a>. Since then, he's been busy with something entirely different: an ecological project for the preservation of nature. However, French website <a href="https://www.superpouvoir.com/entretien-avec-michel-ancel-le-createur-de-rayman-et-beyond-good-evil-se-confie-sur-sa-nouvelle-vie/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Superpouvoir</a> (which tipped us about the article) managed to score an interview with him to discuss the aforementioned unsuccessful game projects.</p>
<p>When it comes to Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2, Michel Ancel cited issues with the other key figures in the studio at Ubisoft Montpellier. Apparently, they couldn't agree on a singular vision for the game.</p>
<p><em>On BGE2, there were too many problems between managers. The artistic director wanted to redo everything constantly, the game director wanted to make a game of generated dungeons and I dreamed of a space adventure. We simply could not agree and the game director took the project in other directions.</em></p>
<p><em>In this type of situation, teams find themselves tossed around and don't even know who's in charge and making decisions. The producer is supposed to sort things out, but that didn't happen. Yves Guillemot even had to go down to Montpellier to get things back on track, but that wasn't enough and the game director continued in his stubbornness. When I read in Libé that I was the one directing the game and asking for changes, I thought I was going to choke. BGE2 is the game on which I don't think I've ever questioned a decision. I'd be happy to discuss this topic with any potential detractors.</em></p>
<p><em>In the end, all this is a matter of passionate managers who did not get along. I believe that for some time now, these people have been thanked and the project has found a certain balance with new managers. These management concerns are of course very damaging for the teams. All this shows that indeed, it is not simple: a lot of egos and a lot of issues with clearly improvable human management.</em></p>
<p><em>There is a huge difference between developing a BGE2 that requires new technology and a project with known tech and gameplay. I believe that for a long time, the complexity of such a project was beyond many people at Ubisoft… and also in the press that did not hesitate to take shortcuts to sell paper at the time of the Parisian affairs.</em></p>
<p><em>There was not a single big bad guy but a sum of key concerns, unresolved at the level of the managers, of which I was one. I have my share of responsibility, and I should have defended the project better, been more present and more conciliatory with the collaborators.</em></p>
<p>Meanwhile, Michel Ancel had also founded his own studio, Wild Sheep, which was working on the PlayStation exclusive <a href="http://wccftech.com/ancel-working-hard-ps4-exclusive-wild/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WiLD</a>, a survival game set in a procedurally generated Neolithic world. It was announced at Gamescom 2014 and shown once again at Paris Games Week 2015, but then the studio went silent for a long time. The development reportedly continued after Ancel retired, but a few months ago, creative director Steven ter Heide <a href="https://x.com/StevenTerHeide1/status/1818716603942400382?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> that the project is no longer being actively worked on.</p>
<p>In the interview, Ancel explained why this project also had what he described as a 'very unfortunate fate':</p>
<p><em>In 2018, we had a very nice playable version, but we took time to upgrade the game on PS5, which slowed down production. On the Sony side, there were big management changes and the game was stopped. Ubisoft offered to take it back, and shortly after, Sony decided to take it back by even offering to double the budgets! Unfortunately, the contracts with Ubisoft were well advanced and we refused Sony's proposal. What a shame!</em></p>
<p><em>It was during this period that I had my burnout and, unfortunately, the game fell into the hands of the Ubisoft editorial department in Paris, itself in full chaos. I was no longer there to defend the game, which was literally crushed by people from this department who asked for all sorts of changes without really playing the game. A real scandal. After two years of wandering, the game was abandoned on the pretext that it no longer corresponded to the initial game... You have to understand that at this time, the editorial department was in full explosion following the internal affairs surrounding Tommy François, who was also in charge of WiLD.</em></p>
<p>Michel Ancel also revealed that he doesn't really have much time to play anymore. He did not completely shut down the door to a return to the industry, although he clarified the context would have to be 'optimal'.</p>

				

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s worth downloading the demo for uncanny horror Eclipsium just to stare at your hands]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-worth-downloading-the-demo-for-uncanny-horror-eclipsium-just-to-stare-at-your-hands</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it%E2%80%99s-worth-downloading-the-demo-for-uncanny-horror-eclipsium-just-to-stare-at-your-hands.1055472/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-worth-downloading-the-demo-for-uncanny-horror-eclipsium-just-to-stare-at-your-hands<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The only sound that greets you upon booting up <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/eclipsium">Eclipsium</a> is a loudly throbbing heart. As one must when encountering <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a> media, the game and I immediately enter a spiritual staring contest, each of us knowing the<em> real</em> game here was it trying to freak me out. "It’s fine", I decided. "It’s just a heart! I’ve got a heart. It’s actually very useful. Nothing to be scared of". Thing is, Eclipsium’s menu heart is actually massive and sits, like The Eye Of Sauron, atop a giant obelisk. “Ah. That’s definitely a horror thing, that” I was forced to admit. "If my heart was on a giant obelisk, I’d be proper shaken up, I reckon."</p>
<p>So starts Eclipsium’s very first bit of aggressive disorientation, and it basically just escalates from there. I obviously can’t describe the vibes without slightly spoiling the vibes, so do pop over to Steam for a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2419670/Eclipsium/">demo if you’re curious</a> and, oh, there’s a potted plant, the sound of its rustling mixed in such a way that it sort of sounds like it’s shrieking at me. Well.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Eclipsium: Demo Release Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eSguFOtf9V8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Eclipsium: Demo Release Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eSguFOtf9V8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/eSguFOtf9V8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eSguFOtf9V8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The first thing I really honed in on with Eclipsium is its use of the first person perspective, and specifically the hands. Your right hand is permanently held out, palm facing forward, as if to clamber through darkness or prepare to bop a potentially aggressive dog on the nose with the heel. Your fingers move slightly as you look about, and there’s an extra layer of unnerving presence in the hand posture being very similar to the one I use for my ergonomic mouse. One idle animation has you briefly flex it into the claw. It all contributes one of the most effective and unique horror game tricks I’ve seen in a hot minute. There’s an utter vulnerability to at once being reminded your character has a physical body, and is also completely lacking a shotgun.</p><p>You start the game in a cabin, and as you explore, your hand will automatically stretch out at interactable objects. A globe. The shrieking plant. A key. The cabin is lit warmly in warped orange hues, and utterly depressing classical music plays. I unlock the door, step out into the woods, and turn around to ascertain the dimensions of the cabin. It is now dark, the music has stopped, and all the furnishings are gone. You’re trying to horror me up, aren’t you, Eclipsium? You’re trying to rustle my shirt buttons, and it’s absolutely working.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eclipsium-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Housefire</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The midnight woods are lit by a bright red blood sky, and I get lost quite quickly, finding a strange mushroom in the woods that makes my vision go even more fuzzy than it already was. As is customary, I stare at my hands for a bit until the effects fade. The woods eventually offer up their greatest bounty: an axe, which I use to chop down a tree to make a bridge across a ravine. This breaks the axe. As I cross the tree, I think back to all the good times I had with the axe. A truly wonderful four seconds, it was. Now I am axe-less, and the woods are very threatening.</p>
<p>I will not tell what lay in the cave I found at the end of that path, but I will say that Eclipsium’s atmosphere is so thick and frightening you could cut it with, well, a deceptively sturdy axe. Here are some solid oak Steam facts:</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Explore over a dozen vivid and surreal environments</li>
<li>Multiple carefully crafted full-motion video cutscenes</li>
<li>Intuitive and atmospheric puzzles</li>
<li>Painstakingly created hand animations</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>They did not lie about the hand animations, I’ll tell you that.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The demo for Oolo offers up a magical metroidvania with hints of classic Zelda]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-demo-for-oolo-offers-up-a-magical-metroidvania-with-hints-of-classic-zelda</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-demo-for-oolo-offers-up-a-magical-metroidvania-with-hints-of-classic-zelda.1055469/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-demo-for-oolo-offers-up-a-magical-metroidvania-with-hints-of-classic-zelda<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/oolo-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Riddle Master Productions</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>“Hang on a sec. Haven’t I seen this exact genre of little guy before?” was my reaction upon encountering the yellow-eyed, hat-shrouded mage of isometric <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-adventure-games">adventure</a> Oolo. Some quick internet sleuthing turned up <a href="https://wintesm.tumblr.com/post/120149267193/an-old-2013-ish-hexafusion-of-vivi-from-final">this lovely bit of art</a> featuring <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/final-fantasy-ix">Final Fantasy 9</a>’s Vivi, Journey’s Traveller, and He-Man’s Orko. It’s a great feeling to begin your week identifying an archetype of diminutive magician, and I hope it becomes a regular occurrence. Another pleasant  discovery was Oolo itself, which you can discover yourself through the shrouded magic of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2819920/OOLO/">this link</a> to it’s free demo.</p>
<p>(Do I need to keep writing ‘free demo’, by the way? I tend to alternate. It’s obviously redundant but I feel writing ‘free’ gives it a certain gravitas. Free tax rebate. Free sunrise. Free oxygen. It makes things sound <em>better</em>.)</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Oolo is, I gather, the name of your purple wizard. The Steam page promises a sort of homage to isometric adventures of yore, and this moony yore-gazing is immediately apparent in a couple of nice ways. Firstly, the goal of the demo is to find a glowy green trinket named the ‘earth key’. Love that. Love not needing to worry about absent love ones or societal threats and just setting out to find a bloody lovely shiny key.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/oolo-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Riddle Master Productions</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The second is the music, starting with a few plaintive key plucks before growing into some rushy, synthy brass that evokes two dudes with opposite vocal ranges shouting the word ‘adventure!’ at you really fast in either ear, layered over with some hobbity strings. Adventure it is!</p><p>The music gets ever lovelier as you start to explore, ambling your way through one isometric room at a time. You hop around, with a deeply satisfying thud when you fall off high ledges, and solve a few jumping puzzles. These feel a little tricky with the viewpoint, but the game lets you tilt rooms and switch between movement control schemes for precision. Soon, you collect a pair of gauntlets that let you push blocks. It’s all very classic Zelda in its flourishes, with hints of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-metroidvania-games">metroidvania</a> through the multiple paths and ever-expanding map.</p>
<p>I manage to die after falling on to some spikes after a bit, upon which the game informs me that “the world flame” has burnt out. Nothing’s ever simple is it? I knew it couldn’t just be a key! Still, world-saving labour or not, I’m quite smitten by Oolo, which is clearly a labour of love. Here are some touted features:</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Explore a vast world with over 400 interconnected rooms!</li>
<li>Venture through dark forests, subterranean crypts, deadly swamps, and more.</li>
<li>Find new artifacts that change the way you move and interact with the world.</li>
<li>Move blocks, ride enemies, and jump your way to exciting new areas.</li>
<li>Non-violent fun for the entire family!</li>
<li>Scour the land for the six elemental keys that will unlock the portal to the World Flame.</li>
<li>Secret areas and hidden powers await the heartiest adventurers.</li>
<li>Discover memories of keepers who rekindled the flame in generations past to give you hints for your journey!</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>I would argue that Oolo falling on those spikes <em>suggests</em> violence, but only if you think about too hard. Otherwise, a fine entry in the pantheon of yellow-eyed conjurers.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Royal Ravens On Top Following First Week of the CDL 2025 Season]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/royal-ravens-on-top-cdl-2025-season/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/royal-ravens-on-top-following-first-week-of-the-cdl-2025-season.1055466/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/royal-ravens-on-top-cdl-2025-season/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The first week of the CDL 2025 season has wrapped and it’s the Carolina Royal Ravens that sit atop the standings. With a record of 2 – 0 and a win/loss of 6 – 2, the Royal Ravens outpaced the other eleven teams in the CDL this past weekend. First, the team handed a smackdown to Team Falcons, and that was followed up with an unexpected win over LAG M8.</p>



<p>The power players are getting well-established quite early on this year, with LAT, Rokkr, and Toronto Ultra all bursting out of the gate without a single loss this week.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-miserable-elsewhere">Miserable Elsewhere</h2>



<p>Uncharacteristically, Atlanta FaZe sits near the bottom of the CDL standings after the opening weekend of play. The squad failed to secure a point, being beaten down by both LAT and Toronto Ultra. The LAT match was a burner, though – almost every round (except the opening Hardpoint, oof) went down to the wire.</p>



<p>Cloud9, Vegas Falcons, and LAG M8 all also failed to secure any CDL points, with C9 NY putting up the worst record – just one single map won out of seven played, tieing the squad with Team Falcons, which many predict will be the worst-performing org this season.</p>



<p>Out of the twelve teams in the CDL 2025 season, the ones to watch have been made clear.</p>



<p>LAT’s combination of Scrap, HyDra, Envoy, and Ghosty is a nasty one. Scrap and HyDra are running wild slaying out (props to HyDra’s 40-bomb), while Ghosty’s IGL role and Envoy’s veteran support bolsters the squad immeasurably. It could be LAT’s year, and it’s well deserved, given how much Nadeshot has poured into the organisation this time around.</p>



<p>Ultra had a great weekend, too. They dealt a massive blow to Atlanta FaZe and followed that up by taking Surge down a peg. The Canadian side made some major changes heading into the new season, picking up Beans and JoeDeceives to flesh out the EU-dominant roster that includes long-timers Insight and CleanX.</p>



<p>This was a fantastic weekend of play all round, and a few technical blips didn’t do too much to mar the entertainment. It’s no big secret that viewership could have been better, but co-streams and watch parties will undoubtedly do bits for the CDL this year.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest esports news</a>, stay tuned to Insider Gaming</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>