<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 18:20:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TP-Link’s first Wi-Fi 7 gaming router costs $600]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/27/24187362/tp-link-router-wifi-7-ge800-be19000-gaming</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tp-link%E2%80%99s-first-wi-fi-7-gaming-router-costs-600.913632/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/27/24187362/tp-link-router-wifi-7-ge800-be19000-gaming<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The TP-Link Archer GE800 Wi-Fi 7 tri-band gaming router was first <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/11/14/23458207/tp-link-wifi-7-archer-be900-ge800-gaming-deco-be95-be85-mesh-routers">announced in late 2022</a> before making appearances at CES 2023 and <a href="https://www.tp-link.com/us/press/news/20921/">CES 2024</a>, alongside a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/11/24033022/wi-fi-7-laptops-gaming-ces-2024-lenovo-alienware-razer-msi-asus">bunch of Wi-Fi 7 laptops</a>. It’s finally <a href="https://www.tp-link.com/us/home-networking/wifi-router/archer-ge800/">available starting today</a> for $599.99, although those excited to upgrade immediately can save $100 as part of a “limited-time launch promotion.”</p><p>Designed to take full advantage of the broader 6GHz wireless spectrum that Wi-Fi 6E first had access to, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23902812/wi-fi-7-explained">Wi-Fi 7 further increases speeds</a> by doubling the maximum channel bandwidth from 160MHz to 320MHz, allowing more data to be transmitted.</p><p>The Wi-Fi 7 spec also allows connections to span multiple bands with a feature called Multi-Link Operation (MLO). For example, a file can be downloaded on the 6Ghz band at 1Gbps and on the 5GHz band at 500Mbps, resulting in combined download speeds of 1.5Gbps. TP-Link boasts the new tri-band Archer GE800 can achieve wireless speeds up to 19Gbps by spreading data across the 6, 5, and 2.4GHz bands simultaneously.</p><p>Just keep in mind that you’ll need a Wi-Fi 7-compatible device like the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23912370/google-pixel-8-pro-review-camera-assistant-magic-editor-best-take-audio-eraser">Google Pixel 8</a>, the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24053907/samsung-galaxy-s24-ultra-review-ai-screen-camera-battery">Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra</a>, or recently announced laptops like the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/8/24025680/razer-blade-14-16-18-cpu-ai-display-updates-usb-c-dock">Razer Blade 16</a> or <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/8/24030533/lenovo-ces-laptops-legion-thinkpad-thinkbook">Lenovo Legion 7i</a> to take full advantage of those speeds. None of the current crop of gaming consoles support Wi-Fi 7.</p><p>The Archer GE800 also features a pair of 10Gbps ethernet ports and four 2.5Gbps ports, with one serving as a dedicated gaming port that prioritizes network traffic from a connected console, although the Xbox Series X / S and PS5 only include gigabit ports. And because every piece of gaming hardware needs to put on an elaborate light show, the GE800 features multicolor lighting that can be controlled from a desktop app panel that also provides insights on router performance and the status of the network.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Payday 3's latest update adds "solo mode", but it still requires an initial internet connection]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/payday-3s-latest-update-adds-solo-mode-but-it-still-requires-an-initial-internet-connection</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/payday-3s-latest-update-adds-solo-mode-but-it-still-requires-an-initial-internet-connection.913629/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/payday-3s-latest-update-adds-solo-mode-but-it-still-requires-an-initial-internet-connection<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>A step in the right direction</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/payday-3-b.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Starbreeze</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/payday-3">Payday 3</a> launched last year to dismal reviews, due to bugs and features from Payday 2 that were absent in the sequel. One such piece of missing functionality was the ability to play alone or offline, but an update coming today makes some progress towards fixing that with the addition of "Solo Mode".
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Solo mode lets people play any of Payday 3's heists alone by hosting the match on their own computer. Y'know, like all games used to let you do. The downside is that Payday 3's solo mode still requires an initial internet connection to access, so it's not a completely offline solution. Not yet, anyway - Starbreeze describe the mode as a "beta".
</p>
<p>Payday 3's servers are offline for around eight hours in order to implement the feature, which is just one part of a larger set of changes in what's called the Boys In Blue update. It also includes bug fixes, art improvements, and both free and paid items including weapons and cosmetics.
</p>
<p>The 'always online' nature of Payday 3 was an issue right from launch, as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/payday-3s-launch-is-another-great-advert-for-not-making-your-game-always-online">players faced long waits to connect to servers</a>. Starbreeze immediately made changes to make it <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/payday-3-to-go-offline-temporarily-as-starbreeze-work-to-make-it-less-dependent-on-online">less dependent on those overburdened servers</a>. Unfortunately players didn't much like what they played of the game when they did connect, from its enemy AI, gun feel, level design, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/starbreeze-will-rework-payday-3s-progression-and-xp-system-after-player-backlash">and especially its progression system</a>. Starbreeze formed a strike force to begin working through those issues, as part of a series of updates <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/payday-3s-first-operation-medic-bag-patch-includes-300-fixes-and-an-unready-button">they've been calling Operation Medic Bag</a>. Alas, sales have been lower than expected, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/payday-3-developer-starbreeze-have-switched-ceo-six-months-after-disastrous-launch">the CEO of the studio has been replaced</a>, and its Steam reviews remain mostly negative.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oh, Hey, Halo Infinite Works On PCs With Nvidia Graphics Cards Again]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/halo-infinite-wont-start-nvidia-driver-update-1851564447</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oh-hey-halo-infinite-works-on-pcs-with-nvidia-graphics-cards-again.913626/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/halo-infinite-wont-start-nvidia-driver-update-1851564447<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="bbb14215d612ff8dca2c229cfb112c0d" data-recommend-id="image://bbb14215d612ff8dca2c229cfb112c0d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Spartan runs forward while firing a Battle Rifle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Spartan runs forward while firing a Battle Rifle." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->343 Industries / Claire Jackson / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bbb14215d612ff8dca2c229cfb112c0d" data-recommend-id="image://bbb14215d612ff8dca2c229cfb112c0d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Spartan runs forward while firing a Battle Rifle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>It ain’t perfect, but damn do I love <em>Halo Infinite</em>. So naturally, I wasn’t all too thrilled when it suddenly kept crashing before it even reached the main menu and nothing seemed to fix it. Verifying the game’s file integrity, reinstalling it, restarting Windows, casting spells and rituals in the forest. Nothing! Turns out, the problem for me and many other players was that we were using Nvidia driver 555.99.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195371" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Long-Lost Halo Demo Comes To Life" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="109" data-playlist="195371,195840,196163" data-current="195371"><div><p>Long-Lost Halo Demo Comes To Life</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195371/195371_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195371/195371_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195371/195371_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195371/195371_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20829.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Released on June 4, 2024, Nvidia Game Ready and Studio Driver 555.99 caused quite a bit of havoc for many fans of <em>Halo Infinite</em> as it rendered the game unplayable for most who had an Nvidia card and were timely with their driver updates. The workaround, of course, was to roll back to driver version 555.85. <em>Halo </em>developer 343 Industries acknowledged the issue early on. It released a statement via the official <em>Halo</em> Support X account stating that it was working with Nvidia to be sure the issue wouldn’t persist into the next driver update. Thankfully, driver version 556.12 was released on June 27 and lets <em>Halo Infinite</em> launch and run without issue. </p><h2 id="h6254"><a id=""></a>How to update your Nvidia driver to play <em>Halo Infinite</em></h2><p>Odds are if you found your way to Nvidia driver 555.99, you probably know how to update your system to the latest version to get back into some <em>Halo</em>. If not, you can download the driver via Nvidia’s GeForce Experience app (which is how I prefer to manage my drivers), or by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nvidia.com/Download/Find.aspx?lang=en-us&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nvidia.com/Download/Find.aspx?lang=en-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">downloading the driver directly from Nvidia’s website</a></span>. The latter is a handy way to locate past drivers should you run into any other issues. </p><hr><p><br>While rolling back to the previous driver was the solution to playing <em>Halo Infinite</em> on a PC with an Nvidia card, it’s usually preferable to keep your machine’s drivers as up-to-date as possible. But now that 556.12 fixed the <em>Halo</em> issue, I have a can of Monster energy, an aggressively frantic metal playlist, and endless rounds of Husky Raid with my name on them.   </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord Devs Respond To Everyone Hating On The Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/concord-dev-respond-reveal-trailer-backlash-playstation-1851564299</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-devs-respond-to-everyone-hating-on-the-trailer.913623/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/concord-dev-respond-reveal-trailer-backlash-playstation-1851564299<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Earlier this month, during PlayStation’s most recent State of Play, the world was formally introduced to team-based FPS <em>Concord </em>via a story trailer. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/concord-playstation-5-pc-state-of-play-reaction-reddit-1851516496&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/concord-playstation-5-pc-state-of-play-reaction-reddit-1851516496">The reception was... not great</a></span>! But the devs behind the game are still excited for players to see more of <em>Concord </em>and finally play it later this year.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196909" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Actor Alan Tudyk On Game Adaptations &amp; Voicing Hapless Halo Characters" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="112" data-playlist="196909,195840,196049" data-current="196909"><div><p>Actor Alan Tudyk On Game Adaptations &amp; Voicing Hapless Halo Characters</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196909/196909_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196909/196909_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196909/196909_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196909/196909_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22467.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ps5-showcase-spider-man-2-metal-gear-solid-3-trailer-1850471595&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-showcase-spider-man-2-metal-gear-solid-3-trailer-1850471595"><em>Concord </em>was first revealed in 2023</a></span> with a vague sci-fi teaser featuring a sniper rifle. We didn’t know what it was until May’s State of Play, where the sci-fi shooter opened the show and took up a large portion of the event. The game’s first big story trailer flopped online, with many unfavorably comparing it to <em>Guardians of the Galaxy</em>. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/concord-ps5-firewalk-release-date-trailer-1851510445&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/concord-ps5-firewalk-release-date-trailer-1851510445">Some gameplay shown during the event</a></span> also didn’t go over well, with people online unsure if the world needs yet another 5v5 class-based hero shooter. And now, the devs at Firewalk Studios have responded to the backlash. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/70pbGDAh4oA&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/70pbGDAh4oA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In an interview with <em>VGC</em></a></span> during a preview event for the game, <em>Concord’s </em>director of IP Kim Kreines reflected on the reaction to the trailer and how it’s just a “tiny slice” of the full game.  </p><p> “Yeah, that trailer, that moment is such a tiny slice of everything that we’ve been working on for years and years,” said Kreines. “We’re excited for the game and for the IP, and for the game to be in people’s hands and the IP to be in people’s minds.” </p><p>Kreines further explained that players will be able to learn more about this world via the Galactic Guide and weekly updates that will add new cutscenes and lore to the game. And according to the developer, all of that couldn’t be included in a short debut trailer. </p><p>“You’ll start to fall in love with the depth of the characters,” said Kreines. “That’s something that you learn week to week. Their personalities will unfold, their relationships will unfold for you, their backstories. None of that is something you can get in a tiny little slice.”</p><p>Still, she was excited that people watched the trailer and that there was a reaction to it, adding: “ I can’t wait for them to see more. To see everything that is there.”</p><p> Jon Weisnewski, lead character designer on <em>Concord</em>, seemed less interested in the initial reaction to the trailer and thinks players will be won over by the combat and gameplay. </p><p>“We have a team that is uniquely skilled at building very immersive and fluid gameplay that just feels tremendous in the player’s hands,” said Weisnewksi. </p><p>“The second they pick up the controller the game just comes to life. Like every action is responsive. And I’ve been a player of these games my whole life, these games are what I love to play, and I know that it’s all about how does it play, right. I want players to come into the beta, if they don’t like it after the beta that’s fine, but I think, yeah the the initial reaction is all about like, how does it actually play in your hands.”</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/concord-price-leak-astro-bot-60-40-hero-shooter-f2p-ps5-1851522161&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/concord-price-leak-astro-bot-60-40-hero-shooter-f2p-ps5-1851522161"><em>Concord</em> launches on August 23 for PS5 and PC with crossplay</a></span>. The game will cost $40. It will include cosmetic microtransactions, but the devs say all story and gameplay content will be added for free via updates. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/27/concord-beta-dates-announced-beta-early-access-launching-july-12/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/27/concord-beta-dates-announced-beta-early-access-launching-july-12/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Concord’s </em>closed beta starts July 12</a></span> for those who pre-order the game. Its open beta arrives on July 18. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[College Football 25: EA Sports Reveals the Best Defensive Teams]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-best-defensive-teams</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/college-football-25-ea-sports-reveals-the-best-defensive-teams.913620/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-best-defensive-teams<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Hours after revealing <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-best-offensive-teams-revealed">the best offensive teams</a>, EA Sports has revealed the best defensive teams available in <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/college-football-25">College Football 25</a>. </p><p>EA Sports revealed the top 25 best defensive teams available in its long-awaited return to the college football video game franchise. Like the top-ranking offensive teams, EA Sports factored in several parameters when compiling this list, such as vetting thousands of players, "years worth of game film," and viewing a slew of statistics when compiling this list. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>College Football 25 Official Reveal Trailer Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>The top-ranking defensive team in College Football 25 is The Ohio State University, with an overall rank of 96. Led by head coach Ryan Day and defensive coordinator Jim Knowles, Ohio State has been consistently a good team overall, with recent years showing its dominance as a defensive powerhouse. Last season, the Buckeyes went 11-2 record, losing the last two games in its season. The first loss was to longtime rival and the eventual 2023 national champions, the Michigan Wolverines, and the second was in the Cotton Bowl to the Missouri Tigers.</p><p>Georgia, Oregon, Alabama, and Clemson are some other top-ranking defenses in College Football 25. The full list of the top 25 defensive teams, as well as each team's overall offensive ranking in College Football 25 will be available below</p><p>College Football 25 <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-release-date">is out on July 19</a> or July 16 if you buy the Deluxe Edition or MVP Bundle. For more information, check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-ea-sports-details-the-immersion-created-by-college-sights-sounds-and-tradition">yesterday's Sights and Sounds gameplay deep dive</a>, the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-toughest-places-to-play">top 25 toughest places to play</a>, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-preview-more-than-just-a-madden-clone">our hands-on preview</a>. </p><h2><u><strong>Top 25 Defensive Teams in College Football 25</strong></u></h2><ol data-cy="list"><li>Ohio State - (96 OVR)</li><li>Georgia - (94 OVR)</li><li>Oregon - (90 OVR)</li><li>Alabama - (90 OVR)</li><li>Clemson - (90 OVR)</li><li>Notre Dame - (90 OVR)</li><li>Michigan - (90 OVR)</li><li>Texas - (88 OVR)</li><li>Penn State - (88 OVR)</li><li>Utah - (88 OVR)</li><li>Florida State - (88 OVR)</li><li>Oklahoma - (88 OVR)</li><li>Iowa - (88 OVR)</li><li>Virginia Tech - (86 OVR)</li><li>Wisconsin - (86 OVR)</li><li>USC - (86 OVR)</li><li>Auburn - (86 OVR)</li><li>LSU - (84 OVR)</li><li>Texas A&amp;M - (84 OVR)</li><li>Colorado - (84 OVR)</li><li>Oklahoma State - (84 OVR)</li><li>Louisville - (84 OVR)</li><li>North Carolina - 84 OVR</li><li>Kansas State - (84 OVR)</li><li>Florida - (84 OVR)</li></ol><p><em>Taylor is a Reporter at IGN. You can follow her on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/TayNixster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@TayNixster.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord Early Access And Open Beta Set To Kick Off In July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concord-early-access-and-open-beta-set-to-kick-off-in-july/1100-6524569/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-early-access-and-open-beta-set-to-kick-off-in-july.913614/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concord-early-access-and-open-beta-set-to-kick-off-in-july/1100-6524569/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524569">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Firewalk Studios' upcoming 5v5 hero shooter, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/concord/">Concord</a>, will enter beta early access on July 12 via a special early access event that ends on July 14. An open beta is scheduled for the following weekend, starting on July 18 and ending on July 21. Both PlayStation 5 and PC users can participate.</p><p dir="ltr">Players who pre-order the game will automatically be invited to the early access beta weekend, and will also get five codes for the event--one code for the player, and four to share with their friends.</p><p dir="ltr">Following the July 12-14 beta early access weekend, all PlayStation and PC users will gain access to the July 18-21 open beta. Even better, players can squad up together regardless of which platform they're playing on.</p><p dir="ltr">"No matter what platform you play on, the Concord Beta Early Access and Open Beta will allow you to team up with friends on either PS5 or PC through optional cross-play support," reads <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/27/concord-beta-dates-announced-beta-early-access-launching-july-12/" rel="nofollow ">a recent post</a> on the official PlayStation blog.</p><p dir="ltr">Concord is scheduled for release on August 20, and can be preordered now.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A game called One Million Checkboxes has sparked a terrible online war]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-game-called-one-million-checkboxes-has-sparked-a-terrible-online-war</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-game-called-one-million-checkboxes-has-sparked-a-terrible-online-war.913596/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-game-called-one-million-checkboxes-has-sparked-a-terrible-online-war<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/checkboxes.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nolen Royalty</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>I’m getting into the bad habit of posting just after the end of work. In this case, I’m doing it because the whole affair might be over and done with when I return to my desk. New York-based Nolen Royalty, creator of <a href="https://eieio.games/">impish experimental games</a> about bouncing DVD logos and staring contests, has made another one that consists of <a href="https://onemillioncheckboxes.com/">a website with one million checkboxes</a>. It's the best thing I've played all year, possibly.</p><!--more-->
<p>You are free to check and uncheck any box you please, and any box you check will appear checked for any other visitor to the site, with the game keeping a running total of checked boxes in the top-right corner. There is no reward for your efforts. The whole thing is entirely pointless, an idle clicker without even the gratification of unlocking a picture of a cookie or similar. And yet. And yet. Look at all those strangers on the other side of the internet, busily checking boxes, working their way down the page like locusts munching through a massive ream of bubble-wrap. Now, notice how that running total shoots up and down at the behest of an opposing army of uncheckers. Which are you?</p>
<p>In the course of five minutes with One Million Checkboxes, I have deduced the existence of several broad classes of checker or unchecker. Firstly, there are the Frontliners, fighting tooth and nail over every square, clicking on each other's clicks as though treading on heads in the scrum. Then there are the Artillery Checkers, who use the search field in the bottom right to punt themselves way ahead of the running total, crashing down into an unspoilt fastness of unfilled boxes.</p>
<p>Their counterparts among the uncheckers are the Saboteurs, who use the search functionality in reverse, burrowing back through the landscape of checks, opening up seams of white in the middle of all that slanted blue as though bleaching out the heart of a coral reef. And fourthly, there are each side’s Clean-up Crews, who follow behind the frontline polishing off stray squares here or there, as though knifing the wounded. It’s a brutal business, truly, the checking of squares.</p>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>I made a website. it's called "one million checkboxes dot com". it has one million checkboxes on it.</p><p>checking a box checks it for everyone.</p><p>that's it. have fun! <a href="https://t.co/KBF4UqCMJc">pic.twitter.com/KBF4UqCMJc</a></p></div>— nolen (@itseieio) <a href="https://twitter.com/itseieio/status/1805986839058079896?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 26, 2024</a></blockquote></div> <p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>As of these words, 525939 boxes have been checked. It was 820552 a couple of minutes ago.  It's not entirely clear what might happen when all the boxes are checked or unchecked. Perhaps we'll find out in 30 seconds. Perhaps we'll never know. Going by the developer's tweets, they weren’t expecting people to be quite this obsessed with the checking of boxes. Here’s <a href="https://x.com/itseieio/status/1806217752656351305">a communique from a few hours ago</a>: “alright i have been firefighting to keep the site up for like 14 hours straight, it's 3am, i am going to try to get some sleep. everyone just...don't check too many checkboxes for the next few hours ok”. Me posting this article definitely isn’t going to help with that. Sorry, Nolen. Neat game concept though!</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You’ve only got 6 months left to buy the best Forza Horizon game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24187156/forza-horizon-4-delisted-best-forza-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you%E2%80%99ve-only-got-6-months-left-to-buy-the-best-forza-horizon-game.913593/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24187156/forza-horizon-4-delisted-best-forza-game<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="w6uaKI">Playground Games and Microsoft <a href="https://forza.net/news/forza-horizon-4-delisting">have announced</a> that <a href="https://www.polygon.com/game/forza-horizon-4-2/40436"><em>Forza Horizon 4</em></a> will be delisted on Dec. 15. From then on, the 2018 open-world racing game and its additional content will no longer be available for purchase from the Xbox Store, the Microsoft Store, or Steam, and it’ll be removed from Game Pass. It will remain playable for people who own a digital or physical copy, and online features will still be available.</p>
<p id="IvLywm">Delisting older games is an increasingly common practice, and a worrying one for game preservation. In the world of racing games, however, it’s nothing new. The genre depends heavily on licensing deals with car manufacturers (and often music publishers). These deals typically have a built-in expiry date that requires the games be removed from sale after a set period of time. Indeed, Playground noted that <em>Forza Horizon 4</em>’s delisting was “due to licensing and agreements with our partners.”</p>
<p id="WN6pV6">There’s not much to be done about that, but it still sucks that many historically important or just plain brilliant racing games are difficult to buy and play today. It particularly sucks that this fate has befallen <em>Forza Horizon 4</em>, which is generally considered the high point of Playground’s freewheeling racing series.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719509025_2941_175284" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25508470,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eCv-lXP7EwlVvBndl4GpePjCMMs=/0x0:3840x2160/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KuBoWhhF60foEe5KqgZA2OUjUKw=/0x0:3840x2160/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b_Kd9DNRVYyephS1BgbQRhKwJp4=/0x0:3840x2160/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DV84rIgL2QxxDykZhDzRqM40VAQ=/0x0:3840x2160/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HE6YRJc9T7tKeMGkCgPrqSbB-98=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/24PunZK4vQZs3upZmyMZ5VlxdT4=/0x0:3840x2160/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Pq-RizLBKZ4aojXtkYhbm0uqts0=/0x0:3840x2160/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fNWjhmdIoO6cJTUn9VHnO84EwyE=/0x0:3840x2160/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R70aTvdOZaOe-RrTgg_SPkCD6kg=/0x0:3840x2160/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508470/forza_horizon_4_house.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Playground Games/Xbox Game Studios</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="Q4Ze71">In truth, there’s no such thing as a bad Forza Horizon game. I’m fond of all of them — including the current, Mexico-set entry, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/22762645/forza-horizon-5-review-xbox-game-pass-series-x-pc"><em>Forza Horizon 5</em></a>. Forza Horizon started as a spinoff of the Gran Turismo-style circuit racing series Forza Motorsport but has now fully eclipsed it. That’s thanks to the Horizon games’ joyful festival vibe, and the inherent accessibility and fun of exploring large, beautiful maps based on real-world tourist destinations in a range of cool, exotic, and even eccentric cars.</p>
<p id="RUogai">But there’s one reason why the fourth entry sets itself apart — or rather, one reason that feeds into many others. <em>Forza Horizon 4 </em>is set in Britain. As a Brit, perhaps I’m biased. But the point is that Playground Games is also British, so it’s biased, too. You can sense that added level of familiarity with and love for the British landscape and British car culture in every corner of the game.</p>
<p id="ZnCWew">The game’s gorgeous map is a compressed tour of the island of Great Britain that transitions smoothly from the honey-colored villages of the Cotswolds, through the eerie moorland and coastal castles of Northumberland, to the majestic Scottish highlands, stopping to take in the granite spires of the Scottish capital, Edinburgh — making its first appearance in a racing game since Bizarre Creations’ excellent <em>Project Gotham Racing 2</em>. (<em>Horizon 4</em> creative director Ralph Fulton, now leading development of the new <em>Fable</em>, is a proud Scot, which is evident from playing the game.)</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719509025_7082_175285" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25508471,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pHrkex-AnaY29WIEMYegffrAOpU=/0x0:3840x2160/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4q2vUHDFc0TZ6H0hv51DxJvm-_A=/0x0:3840x2160/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/22pvwX2mNQTR0pZI1gAcYccx1Wc=/0x0:3840x2160/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wz7AOB6rd1v5jkX7TpEnl64pK9U=/0x0:3840x2160/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1BMRiuwEQ2mIzOkH8U851c7qZL8=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/idM2CQcbBrPLMnUfCkFwwyIWK74=/0x0:3840x2160/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yC7IYYQySeXcY554hECRnSIVxoA=/0x0:3840x2160/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SozEKvkPZUvWW9ZoCndeyh7bwf0=/0x0:3840x2160/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NLgIzFQ8k_ceo8E_wbgfdT7BERs=/0x0:3840x2160/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25508471/forza_horizon_4_edinburgh.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Playground Games/Xbox Game Studios</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="qbqWW2">The changeable British weather also led to the inspired addition of seasons, which transform the map (and the terrain physics and vehicle handling) through spring, summer, fall, and winter. You’ve never seen overcast British skies, or the sun wanly shining through spring showers, rendered so well in a video game. Seasons returned in <em>Forza Horizon 5</em>, but although the Mexican climate allows for some spectacular weather effects, it doesn’t allow for whole-map transformations as effective as <em>Forza Horizon 4</em>’s blanket of snow.</p>
<p id="a7Pgol">The U.K.’s proud automotive history is on full display in <em>Forza Horizon 4</em>, too, highlighted in some of the game’s story events in which you get to drive the likes of Minis, London black cabs, Land Rovers, sleek 1960s Jaguars, and the unstoppable, supercharged 1931 Bentley.</p>
<p id="Md7FSL"><em>Forza Horizon 4</em> marked a shift toward ongoing, live-service-style content in the series, and Playground has come up with a reasonable plan for winding this down now that the game is being delisted. The game’s final Festival Playlist series will begin July 25 and end on Aug. 22. Some daily and weekly challenges will continue after this date, and all previously Playlist-exclusive reward cars will be made available via the Backstage Pass system. A few Festival Playlist-themed achievements will be impossible to earn after Aug. 22.</p>
<p id="Ou600X">Unlike some other racing game series, where content accumulates over time and tracks are recycled from one entry to the next, the open-world map for each edition of Forza Horizon lends it a unique flavor. For that reason alone, <em>Forza Horizon 4</em> is well worth having in your library — where else are you going to get to blast down Edinburgh’s Royal Mile and up Arthur’s Seat at 100 miles per hour? </p>
<p id="61KD5x">Microsoft will be offering deals on the game through its eventual delisting in December; it’s currently <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1293830/Forza_Horizon_4/">80% off on Steam</a>, with the Ultimate Edition coming in at just $19.99. If you’ve any interest in racing games, you should snap it up while you still can. </p>



  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Fans Debate Whether Malenia Has Been Dethroned As Hardest Boss After DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-hardest-boss-messmer-radahn-1851564300</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-fans-debate-whether-malenia-has-been-dethroned-as-hardest-boss-after-dlc.913590/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-hardest-boss-messmer-radahn-1851564300<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Like most of FromSoftware’s games, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-goty-2022-dlc-fromsoftware-dark-souls-1849925353&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-goty-2022-dlc-fromsoftware-dark-souls-1849925353"><em>Elden Ring</em></a></span><em> </em>is built around its exceptionally challenging bosses. Some of them are so infamous for their difficulty that community figures like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-malenia-cheese-let-me-solo-her-katana-waterf-1848794716&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-malenia-cheese-let-me-solo-her-katana-waterf-1848794716">Let Me Solo Her</a></span> have spawned for the singular purpose of defeating them. That hasn’t changed in the RPG’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-expansion-review-1851545505&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-expansion-review-1851545505"><em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em></a></span><em> </em>DLC, but with a new pantheon of iconic fights, fans are now conflicted about who the ultimate boss challenge is in <em>Elden Ring</em>.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195502" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="307" data-playlist="195502,195624,196773" data-current="195502"><div><p>The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20979.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><figure id="" data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Before <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>, Malenia, the final boss of the Legacy Dungeon Miquella’s Haligtree, was widely considered to be <em>Elden Ring</em>’s fiercest foe. Statistically, she was the enemy that defeated the most players, coming in with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-malenia-rock-sling-shadow-erdtree-dlc-1850243803&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-malenia-rock-sling-shadow-erdtree-dlc-1850243803">329 million kills as of March 2023</a></span>. Now, newcomers in the DLC, like Messmer the Impaler and Promised Consort Radahn, are giving her a run for her money. As is the case with any RPG that lets you have wildly varied builds, different <em>Elden Ring</em> players are encountering different challenges throughout <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>. It’s fascinating to see the gap in what some players consider hard compared to others.</p><p>If you scroll through <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dkzecz/hardest_boss_in_the_dlc/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dkzecz/hardest_boss_in_the_dlc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the <em>Elden Ring </em>subreddit</a></span>, you’ll find players debating who the hardest fight is in <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>, and while Messmer and Radahn are recurring answers, it seems folks are having trouble with just about everyone.</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>“[Frenzy Lord] was hard as fuck,” HEMANFTWETERNIA wrote. “Weird thing, when he leaps into the air, if you look at him, he will move closer to you and you can’t block his attack.”</p><p>“Haven’t finished [the DLC] yet, but Romina,” Last12u wrote. “She sucks so much ass.”</p><p>“Commander Gaius seemed kinda hard for me,” Emergency_Work6066 said.</p></blockquote><p>The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dl3c0z/malenia_vs_messmer_in_terms_of_difficulty_final/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dl3c0z/malenia_vs_messmer_in_terms_of_difficulty_final/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">big debate</a></span> right now is if Messmer, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-let-me-solo-her-him-messmer-shadow-erdtree-1851563743&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-let-me-solo-her-him-messmer-shadow-erdtree-1851563743">Let Me Solo Her’s new nemesis</a></span>, has ascended to the throne of hardest <em>Elden Ring </em>boss. The vicious, two-stage boss battle has been giving players a lot of trouble, and it has players wondering if he has overtaken Malenia’s title.</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>“Messmer is the hardest fight I have faced yet (I just finished the Shadow Keep),” Duelz_96 wrote. “Messmer took me 144 attempts Malenia took me 118 attempts Both are ridiculously hard. I’m just processing cause I just beat Messmer right now. Completely shaking still.”</p><p>“Malenia feels like a fair duel once you know the moves,” Klutzy-Call9328 wrote. Messmer always feels like you’re being crushed under his boot regardless of how well you know his moveset.”</p><p>“Personally, I would say Messmer is slightly harder,” L-man6151 said. “His tax feel like they have significantly more range, he closes distance, much quicker and his regular attacks hit harder I find. Plus he’s got that wombo combo, that not only does physical damage (specifically piercing damage, which is the best type of physical damage in the game) but a lot of fire damage too. I think he’s a lot harder to try to heal off of.”</p></blockquote><p>While Messmer is universally considered to be a tough-as-nails fight, not everyone agrees that he’s more challenging than Malenia. Some mention that play style can play a key role in who is harder for you.</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>“I beat just beat Messmer (LFG) and it took me around 6 hours of nonstop fighting,” Feisty_Bass6200 wrote. “I haven’t beat Malenia yet without summoning... something about her just wrecks me.”</p><p>“I think he’s pretty easy compared to Malenia and really fun to play against after you learn his moves,” Friendly_Industry_74 said.</p><p>“Blind fight: Malenia harder. Over-levelled: Malenia harder. Under-levelled: Messmer harder. No hit: Messmer harder,” iBlack92O said. “For someone like me who spends my first dozen attempts learning a move-set, bosses that have far too much visual clutter will always be much more of an issue.”</p></blockquote><p>One other challenger for the throne is Promised Consort Radahn. The final boss of <em>Shadow of the Erdtree </em>(<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dl4bcw/does_any_one_else_think_that_final_boss_fight_is/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dl4bcw/does_any_one_else_think_that_final_boss_fight_is/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">though some loreheads think the character’s reappearance feels like fanservice</a></span>) is at the top of lists of the most difficult DLC boss fights for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-hardest-bosses-ranked&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-hardest-bosses-ranked" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>IGN</em></a></span><em> </em>and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://dotesports.com/elden-ring/news/10-hardest-bosses-in-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-ranked&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://dotesports.com/elden-ring/news/10-hardest-bosses-in-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-ranked" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Dot Esports</em></a></span>. <em>IGN</em>’s Matt Kim describes Radahn’s reappearance as “relentless,” with his second phase feeling “downright impossible” thanks to his fast speed effectively making the dodge roll maneuver useless.</p><p>“It will take frame-perfect movement, guile, and maybe more than a little luck to get through this two-part boss fight,” Kim writes. “But I promise the feeling afterward will be worth it.”</p><p>Ultimately, just how difficult <em>Elden RIng </em>bosses are comes down to playstyle just as much as skill level. Certain builds are more effective than others at handling enemies that fight at close range vs. long range. Some can take a few more hits if they don the right armor or have spec’d into defense and survivability. Not to mention that summoning other players to take on a boss alongside you and using Spirit Ashes to bring an AI-controlled companion into the fight can tip the scales in your favor. But sometimes there are just universally challenging foes that have a response to any strategy you might have up your sleeve. It sounds like that hasn’t changed in <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>. Hopefully, FromSoftware will release stats that show us who is killing players the most in the coming weeks.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord Beta Dates Announced For PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/concord-beta-dates-announced-for-ps5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-beta-dates-announced-for-ps5.913587/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/concord-beta-dates-announced-for-ps5/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>After getting a full reveal during the PlayStation State of Play at the end of May, <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/27/concord-beta-dates-announced-beta-early-access-launching-july-12/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">developer Firewalk has announced</a> the dates for the Concord beta in July.</p>



<p>Starting July 12-14, those that pre-order the game will get beta access along with four extra codes to provide to friends to try the game. After the early access period, there will be an open beta for Concord from July 18-21.</p>



<p>The beta will be available to players on both PlayStation 5 (PS5) and PC. Those who play on PC will need a PlayStation Account in order to play.</p>



<p>As far as what’s in the Concord beta, players will have access to all 16 Freegunners to play as well as four game modes across five maps. The four game modes coming to the beta are:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Trophy Hunt:</strong> Kill members of the other team to collect bounty cards and earn points. Similar to Kill Confirmed.</li>



<li><strong>Cargo Run: </strong>Work with your team to retrieve the “Blue Buddy robotic package delivery system”. There are no respawns.</li>



<li><strong>Clash Planet</strong>: Another no-respawn mode, this mode sees your team fight to control a single zone on the map.</li>



<li><strong>Area Control: </strong>Releasing during the open beta, this mode has you fight to control multiple zones on the map.</li>
</ul>



<p>Concord launches on August 23 for PS5 and PC. Firewalk also promises updates to the game post launch that will see the game grow “at no additional cost”.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you going to check out the Concord beta now that we have the dates? For more Insider Gaming, read what Rockstar co-founder <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rockstar-games-co-founder-never-wanted-a-gta-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dan Houser had to saw about making a GTA movie</a>, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here Are The Best Offenses And Defenses In EA Sports College Football 25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/here-are-the-best-offenses-and-defenses-in-ea-sports-college-football-25/1100-6524566/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here-are-the-best-offenses-and-defenses-in-ea-sports-college-football-25.913584/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/here-are-the-best-offenses-and-defenses-in-ea-sports-college-football-25/1100-6524566/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524566">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">This week, EA Sports has been offering multiple new updates on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523761/" data-ref-id="1100-6523761">College Football 25</a>, which is the publisher's return to the college football gridiron after an 11-year hiatus, on the official CFB 25 website. Today's update unveiled the top 25 schools on offense and defense, and there are few surprises on either side of the ball.</p><p dir="ltr">The Georgia Bulldogs and Oregon Ducks are tied at the top of the offensive list with a 94 overall rating each, while the Ohio State Buckeyes sit alone at number one on defense with a 96 overall rating. The top five on offense include Alabama (91 overall), Texas (91 overall), and Ohio State (89 overall), while the defensive top five is rounded out by Georgia--again at 94 overall--and three teams at 90 overall: Oregon, Alabama, and Clemson.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4325893-psu.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4325893" data-ratio="0.56492890995261" data-width="3165" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4325893-psu.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4325893"></a><figcaption>We Are...#12 on offense and #9 on defense!</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4325893-psu.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">Best offenses in EA Sports College Football 25</h2><ol><li dir="ltr">Georgia - 94 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Oregon - 94 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Alabama - 91 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Texas - 91 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Ohio State - 89 overall</li><li dir="ltr">LSU - 89 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Miami - 89 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Colorado - 89 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Missouri - 89 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Clemson - 87 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Utah - 87 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Penn State - 87 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Ole Miss - 87 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Kansas - 87 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Arizona - 87 overall</li><li dir="ltr">NC State - 87 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Notre Dame - 85 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Texas A&amp;M - 85 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Memphis - 85 overall</li><li dir="ltr">SMU - 85 overall</li><li dir="ltr">UCF - 85 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Florida State - 83 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Oklahoma - 83 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Virginia Tech - 83 overall</li><li dir="ltr">USC - 83 overall</li></ol><h2 dir="ltr">Best defenses in EA Sports College Football 25</h2><ol><li dir="ltr">Ohio State - 96 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Georgia - 94 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Oregon - 90 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Alabama - 90 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Clemson - 90 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Notre Dame - 90 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Michigan - 90 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Texas - 88 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Penn State - 88 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Utah - 88 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Florida State - 88 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Oklahoma - 88 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Iowa - 88 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Virginia Tech - 86 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Wisconsin - 86 overall</li><li dir="ltr">USC - 86 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Auburn - 86 overall</li><li dir="ltr">LSU - 84 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Texas A&amp;M - 84 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Colorado - 84 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Oklahoma State - 84 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Louisville - 84 overall</li><li dir="ltr">North Carolina - 84 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Kansas State - 84 overall</li><li dir="ltr">Florida - 84 overall</li></ol><p dir="ltr">EA Sports College Football 25 launches July 19 for Xbox Series X|S and PlayStation 5. Those who <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-preorder-guide-ps5-xbox-series-x/1100-6523506/" data-ref-id="1100-6523506">preorder the deluxe edition</a> can access the game three days early on July 16.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve launches new Steam chart for top-played Steam Deck games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/valve-launches-new-steam-chart-for-top-played-steam-deck-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-launches-new-steam-chart-for-top-played-steam-deck-games.913581/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/valve-launches-new-steam-chart-for-top-played-steam-deck-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Valve is expanding its Steam charts, with a brand new one focused on the most-played games on its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/steamdecktopplayed">Steam Deck</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> handheld.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The list will updated on a daily basis, and cover additional metrics such as weekly, monthly, and yearly numbers. However, it doesn't feature specific numbers, so you'll still have to go to SteamDB for that information.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Before this, Valve would reveal the top-played Steam Deck games on a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/hades-ii-ascends-to-become-steam-deck-s-most-played-may-game">monthly</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> basis. The new list builds upon that, and expands on it by revealing the top 100 games rather than the top 20.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Who's on Steam's new charts, and what does that mean?">Who's on Steam's new charts, and what does that mean?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">At time of writing, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">is at the top of the list, with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Stardew Valley </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Balatro </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">in second and third place. Rounding out the top five are </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Baldur's Gate 3 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Hearts: HD 1.5 &amp; 2.5 Remix.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">While the first four games are no real surprise, given their well-publicized success in recent months, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Hearts </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">is another matter. The series finally </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/after-two-years-on-the-epic-games-store-the-kingdom-hearts-series-is-finally-releasing-on-steam/">came to Steam</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in June after previously being relegated to the Epic Games Store for three years.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Hearts 3 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">is also on the list at #92, but unlike the previous game, it's not deemed Steam Deck-ready. The majority of the games in the complete list are fully Steam Deck verified, while some are simply marked "playable" or not at all.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/playground-games-will-delist-forza-horizon-4-in-december">Forza Horizon 4</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">is notably at #26. While simply "playable" on the Deck, it's currently 80 percent off, and reached a new player peak of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://steamdb.info/app/1293830/charts/">71,600 concurrent players</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which can be owed to its upcoming delisting in mid-December.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If Only I Could Give You The World, My Houseplants]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/houseplant-care-why-how-what</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/if-only-i-could-give-you-the-world-my-houseplants.913554/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/houseplant-care-why-how-what<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I own a bunch of plants. They are nice to own, and they make me happy, and I like to think they do a little to combat how abysmal I am at decorating because someone might come over and say, “Oh, look at all your plants!” instead of “Wow, what a small kitchen” or “I like how you get around only having one closet via all these strategic heaps.” The trouble with houseplants is that when they have problems, the solution is… everything?</p><p>Over the years, my plants have done OK. I’m not too fussy with them, which has mostly worked out. I owned a <a href="https://www.thesill.com/blog/how-to-care-for-calathea" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">calathea</a> for a while, a charming plant that folds up at night because it has a bedtime like a person, but the minute the heat went on in my apartment it threw a fit and never recovered. I knelt close to it as it expired like the door scene in <em>Titanic</em>, watching it brown and crisp and be basically too delicate for this world, or at least the aggressive world of New York City radiator heat. A few summers ago I grew food plants on my fire escape, and despite a war with aphids and birds, I got a ton of jalapenos and mint out of the deal. I would have gotten parsley, but a caterpillar ate it, which would have been annoying if it wasn’t so fucking cool.</p><div><figure><div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I bought the caterpillar a new parsley because it ate the ENTIRE old one, and look at this extreme sports shit it got up to <a href="https://t.co/XMo8dOVCIM">pic.twitter.com/XMo8dOVCIM</a></p>— Riley MacLeod (@rcmacleod) <a href="https://twitter.com/rcmacleod/status/1542955023088377857?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 1, 2022</a></blockquote></div></figure></div><p>During my time in DC, my plants took a turn, growing yellow and leggy and miserable. I have a couple theories: their soil was old and needed changing, which I neglected. They went from my north- and east-facing NYC windows to the full blast of my DC south-facing ones, and weren’t suited for all that abundant, inescapable light. The water in DC <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/washingtondc/comments/x3r7ii/do_you_drink_dcs_tap_water_unfiltered_if_no_why/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sucks</a>. They were picking up on my own unhappiness in town, their sad state reflecting my own. When I moved back to New York, I salvaged the good stems of my <a href="https://www.joyusgarden.com/monstera-adansonii-care-swiss-cheese-vine-growing-tips/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">monstera</a> and <a href="https://extension.sdstate.edu/pothos-devils-ivy-golden-pothos-house-plant-how" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pothos</a> to water propagate, and sent the others on ahead in their pots. I carried the cuttings with me on the train alongside my ukulele like I was cosplaying Zooey Deschanel, ready to start a new plant life.&nbsp;</p><p>Of course, some of that new life involved compulsively buying new plants, because I moved back to Brooklyn in the spring, when plants pour out of hardware stores and garden centers and plant sales. I added a tiny <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/grow-chamaedorea-indoors-1902884" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">parlor palm</a> I fell in love with outside the Korean grocer, and the only modestly-thriving <a href="https://abeautifulmess.com/how-to-care-for-a-rubber-tree/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rubber tree</a> in a neglected corner of the hardware store, and a little tangle of <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/pilea-glauca-care-guide-8404971" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pilea glauca</a> from a gardening club sale in a church, where the old man checking me out clucked “You’re just buying <em>one</em> plant?” and an old lady behind me in line said, “Well, he’s young,” a compliment I’ve been repeating to myself every day since. My cuttings grew roots in their jars of water, and things seemed to be looking up.</p><p>Over the weekend, I moved all the plants to new soil and pots, sizing up the ones that needed more space and giving them all a refresh. I put the water propagations into dirt to start their new lives as real plants. While I knew my sad yellow plants wouldn’t magically become green again, I hoped the infusion of fresh nutrients would help both me and my plants turn over a new leaf (sorry) back in the city.</p><p>But before all this, my new parlor palm’s leaf tips started browning, and it’s stressing me out. This brings me to the crux of this blog: whenever you Google <em>any</em> problem with a plant, the potential causes are, officially, Everything. Why is my parlor palm browning? Too much water, too little water, too much sun, not enough sun, the pot is too small, the pot is too big, it’s too humid in my apartment, it’s not humid enough. Pages and pages of plant advice from self-styled experts feels functionally useless. Is it that plants express all their struggles through the same symptoms? Are all these plant websites just SEO farms, using every possible plant word to rank high in Google? Am I just a dumbass who doesn’t understand plants and can’t take care of them well? If I had to, I’d say I’m a plant guy, but I don’t want to become A Plant Guy. I vacillate between over-attending to them, and deciding that since plants tend to do fine in nature, they can do fine without me and I need to stop worrying so much. (This last one is hard, because I <em>love</em> to worry.)</p><p>This morning, after Googling “why parlor palm tips brown” for the thousandth time and rereading the same useless advice, I moved the parlor palm from the bigger pot I’d put it in on Sunday into a smaller pot, after watching a video saying they struggle with too much space. Of course, now I’m worried I’ve moved it around too much and this will stress it out and make its problems <em>worse</em>. And of course it hasn’t magically and immediately let me know it’s happier, because plants move at their own slow pace and that is what is <em>supposed</em> to make them so peaceful and not represent yet another out-of-control variable in my ultimately uncontrollable life. I put it back on its <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/how-to-make-a-pebble-tray-7371481" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pebble tray</a>, which half of Reddit says is a real hack for humidity and the other half says is bullshit, but I like being the kind of plant owner who uses <em>a pebble tray</em>.&nbsp;</p><p>I wish I could give you everything, plants, in the exact right amounts to make all of you happy. But I am just one man, with just two windows. I will never be the cool people on YouTube with big rooms full of grow lights and plant stands and a primordial jungle of greenery. I will never keep detailed spreadsheets of your needs and care schedules, despite becoming a spreadsheet guy against my will in <a href="https://aftermath.site/starting-a-website-has-taught-me-too-much-about-myself" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">other aspects</a> of my life. I will do what I can for you and learn to make peace with your mysteries–or I will go buy another parlor palm, and then a really green <a href="https://www.gardeningknowhow.com/houseplants/snake-plant/snake-plant-care.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">snake plant</a> instead of my yellowing one that until Sunday had another mysterious plant growing alongside it in the pot because it came that way from the farmer’s market. Maybe I’ll try to solve my plant problems by getting <em>more</em> plants to have problems with, until I reach some kind of problem equilibrium. But if any readers know a plant website that’s <em>actually</em> useful, drop the link in the comments.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord open beta and early access weekends announced for July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/27/concord-open-beta-and-early-access-weekends-announced-for-july/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-open-beta-and-early-access-weekends-announced-for-july.913545/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/27/concord-open-beta-and-early-access-weekends-announced-for-july/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sony and developer Firewalk will be holding an open beta weekend for their upcoming hero shooter <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/concord">Concord</a>. Both <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/30/concord-gets-flashy-cinematic-trailer-gameplay-reveal-beta-test-confirmed-with-august-launch/">an open beta weekend</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/07/concord-price-beta-preorder-details-for-ps5-and-pc-confirmed/">an early access weekend for pre-orders</a> will be taking place in July, across both <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PS5</a> and PC, on the following dates:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Concord Beta Early Access</strong> – 12th-14th July</li>
<li><strong>Concord Open Beta</strong> – 18th-21st July</li>
</ul>
<p>The early access weekend will be available to all those that pre-order Concord, but each person that pre-orders any edition of the game will actually get five codes for the early access weekend, meaning to you can bring yourself and four friends to create a full fireteam of Freegunners.</p>


<p>During the beta, you’ll have four maps to play on and there will be four game modes introduced by the second weekend: Trophy Hunt (Team Deathmatch), Cargo Run (Search &amp; Destroy), Clash Point (like single capture point Search &amp; Destroy), Area Control (uh… Control)</p>
<p>The two pre-launch test weekends will also have full cross-play support, though this is an optional side to the game (as it should be in any competitive shooter).</p>

<p>The full launch for Concord is then set for 23rd August, both physically and digitally for £34.99 here in the UK and $39.99 / €39.99 / ¥4,480 in other regions</p>
<p><iframe title="Concord - Gameplay Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7jqQJhjf_3o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Firewalk and Sony have big ambitions for their shooter, looking to usurp the formula laid out by Overwatch almost a decade ago. It will drop you into the shoes of the crew of the North Star, taking on high-stakes jobs that will see you facing off against other Freegunner crews. With 16 class-based characters each with contrasting abilities and gear, the parallels to Overwatch are clear, but there is a key distinction to how the game plays as some gear and gadgets will be able to have effects that persist between rounds &nbsp;– traps, lane-blockers, shield barriers and more can shape an entire match between teams.</p>
<p>There’s also a greater emphasis on story being built directly into the game.&nbsp;Each week will open with a new cinematic vignette that will feed into the character building and overarching universe that Firewalk is creating, aiming to go beyond the character building of other examples of the genre.</p>



<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where To Find Elden Ring: Shadow Of The Erdtree's Bloodfiend's Arm]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-bloodfiends-arm-guide-1851563979</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-to-find-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtrees-bloodfiends-arm.913539/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-bloodfiends-arm-guide-1851563979<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Bloodfiend’s Arm is a Colossal Weapon found only in <em>Elden Ring</em>’s <em>Shadow of the Erdtree </em>expansion. This is one of the DLC’s best overall weapons—especially for slaying bosses—thanks to its shocking stagger damage and ability to quickly build up Bleed. With the right build, you can make quick work of just about anyone or anything with this massive weapon.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195502" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="307" data-playlist="195502,195624,196394" data-current="195502"><div><p>The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20979.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Here’s what you need to know about the Bloodfiend’s Arm and where to find it.</p><h2 id="h8393"><a id=""></a><strong>Bloodfiend’s Arm stats and features</strong></h2><p>The Bloodfiend’s Arm has a weight of 20.0 and requires the following stats to wield:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>STR - 28</li><li>DEX - 11</li><li>ARC - 16</li></ul><p>The weapon comes equipped with Ash of War: Endure. This Ash of War allows you to assume a stance that briefly increases your poise and reduces damage taken, making it a solid ability to use on bosses with powerful attacks.</p><p>The Bloodfiend’s Arm can be upgraded to +25 with standard Smithing Stones.</p><h2 id="h8394"><a id=""></a><strong>Bloodfiend’s Arm item description</strong></h2><p>The Bloodfiend’s Arm’s item description reads:</p><p>“Weapon used by the bloodfiends. An arm pulled from the corpse of one of their kin, and wielded as a makeshift weapon.</p><p>Having been sanctified by a blood ritual, this armament is capable of spraying blood stored within when executing a strong attack.”</p><h2 id="h8395"><a id=""></a><strong>Where to find the Bloodfiend’s Arm</strong></h2><p>You can find the Bloodfiend’s Arm by farming Bloodfiend enemies, which can be found in various spots within the DLC. The easiest place to farm them is called Prospect Town, which can be accessed during the opening hours of the expansion.</p><p>To reach Prospect Town, start from the Three-Path Cross Site of Grace in Gravesite Plain and head through the giant archway. As you emerge on the other side, stick to the left wall and follow a thin path up the side of the cliff until you see the Cliffroad Terminus Site of Grace. Rest there, then look ahead of you to see Prospect Town.</p><figure id="" data-id="f46bc5bcb1f18c1693bff7e0a96ab855" data-recommend-id="image://f46bc5bcb1f18c1693bff7e0a96ab855" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A map showing the location of the Bloodfiend’s Arm." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A map showing the location of the Bloodfiend’s Arm." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f46bc5bcb1f18c1693bff7e0a96ab855" data-recommend-id="image://f46bc5bcb1f18c1693bff7e0a96ab855" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A map showing the location of the Bloodfiend’s Arm." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>When you arrive in Prospect Town, climb the structures using Torrent until you reach the top area. Note that there are a significant number of Bloodfiends here to slay, so either kite them around, killing them one by one, or use AOE spells/abilities to drop as many as you can at one time.<br></p><p>One of the Bloodfiends in this pack is likely to drop the Bloodfiend’s Arm weapon, so kill them all. If you don’t get the drop, respawn back at the Site of Grace and try it again. You can always wear the Silver Scarab Talisman or use a Silver-Pickled Fowl Foot to increase your chances of the drop, too.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Probably Missed The Best Video Game Song Of The Year So Far]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-night-springs-times-and-galaxy-theme-songs-1851564121</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-probably-missed-the-best-video-game-song-of-the-year-so-far.913536/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-night-springs-times-and-galaxy-theme-songs-1851564121<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>2023’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-review-control-max-payne-1850994952&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-review-control-max-payne-1850994952"><em>Alan Wake II</em></a></span> is an impressive horror game that melds mediums and tells a metatextual story about creating art. It’s a wondrous accomplishment of game design. It also has one of the catchiest songs ever put into a video game, memorably accompanied by a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-ii-2-herald-of-darkness-music-video-musical-1851024833&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-ii-2-herald-of-darkness-music-video-musical-1851024833">spectacular interactive performance</a></span>. So I shouldn’t have been surprised to find out that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-dlc-night-springs-canon-1851525597&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-dlc-night-springs-canon-1851525597"><em>Night Springs</em></a></span>, the game’s DLC, also has a song I can’t stop listening to. But the DLC has a twist: this is a proper theme song, and now I think every video game needs one too.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195922" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="390" data-playlist="195922,195928,196055" data-current="195922"><div><p>Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21438.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><em>Night Springs</em> is a cheeky bit of DLC for an already meta-heavy game. It plays out as episodes of an in-game <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://www.kotaku.com.au/2014/03/modern-twilight-zone-plots-in-10-horryfing-tweets/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.kotaku.com.au/2014/03/modern-twilight-zone-plots-in-10-horryfing-tweets/"><em>Twilight Zone</em></a></span> spoof written by Alan Wake himself and hosted by the mysterious Mr. Door. This gives each of the three episodes a canon explanation while not requiring them to actually make sense. With no responsibilities to stay consistent with existing lore, Remedy really lets loose in ways you wouldn’t expect even after playing <em>Alan Wake 2</em>. And as the entire DLC is a TV show, it just makes sense for it to have a theme song. </p><p>Simply titled “Night Springs,” the theme is a synth-pop tune that will quickly worm its way into your head. The lyrics talk about many of the weird happenings that can occur in the show’s titular town, with examples including getting caught in a time loop and finding a solar system in a bowl of soup, among others. Each one sounds like it could be its own bite-sized episode, and they all fit right alongside the stories we do play through. </p><p>Upon finishing the first episode, “Number One Fan,” the theme song plays for the first time and It feels so good to hear the pop anthem play after gunning down enemies in a rose-tinted world as the psychotic (but incredibly loveable) Waitress. Now I listen to the theme song and I think about how fun the DLC is. It’s just a feedback loop of good times between the song and the game. </p><p>Not that I needed more proof that things are better with a theme song, but this year’s indie journalism satire sim<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/times-and-galaxy-review-journalist-sim-mass-effect-1851547336&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/times-and-galaxy-review-journalist-sim-mass-effect-1851547336"><em>Times &amp; Galaxy</em></a></span> also has one. Spoiler alert, it rules. Before you even build your unique robo reporter in the game, an animated intro plays set to a catchy tune. What works in this theme song is how it introduces you to the basic premise and cast of the game. You are going to report a bunch of stories across a number of beats (arts, politics, and more) and do it alongside the staff of the titular paper. Give it a listen and try not to be excited about the game. I, for one, have sung the lines “Space is a lonely void. We’ve got the whole thing covered. From the trash heaps of Aug to places undiscovered” more times than I can count (or would like to admit).</p><p>All I’m saying is that no game would be made worse by adding a theme song. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/keeping-an-open-mind-about-the-halo-4-soundtrack-453101141&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/keeping-an-open-mind-about-the-halo-4-soundtrack-453101141"><em>Halo</em></a></span>? Drop some lyrics on top of that choral soundtrack! <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/red-dead-redemption-2-the-kotaku-review-1829984369&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/red-dead-redemption-2-the-kotaku-review-1829984369"><em>Red Dead Redemption</em></a></span>? Give me some cowboy music!<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-fromsoftware-review-hidetaka-miyazaki-dark-s-1848694257&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-fromsoftware-review-hidetaka-miyazaki-dark-s-1848694257"><em>Elden Ring</em></a></span>? You’d be having a better time if you could sing a catchy tune while you died to the same boss again and again. So please, let’s get some more theme songs in video games.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord First Hands-On: Plenty of Balancing Left to Go, and Not Much Time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/concord-first-hands-on-plenty-of-balancing-left-to-go-and-not-much-time</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-first-hands-on-plenty-of-balancing-left-to-go-and-not-much-time.913533/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/concord-first-hands-on-plenty-of-balancing-left-to-go-and-not-much-time<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Concord was originally teased last year with a simple video that showcased a ship cruising through space. I think a hamburger was involved. Anyway, after seeing that short teaser, I honestly expected to see a story-driven FPS  – this is a first-party Sony game, after all – but maybe it’d be something like an MMO, a la Destiny. I was on board for a new experience regardless, but then I was somewhat surprised to learn that Concord is, in fact, a 5v5 shooter.</p><p>And now that I’ve played it, I’m very glad that Concord does plan on keeping up with its world lore and ongoing storyline, since some of my favorite FPS games like Overwatch and Apex Legends do this seasonally as well . Additionally, each season that releases will be free to all players, who only have to purchase the game and enjoy future updates to come.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Concord - June 2024 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>While I enjoyed my time in the limited hands-on preview overall, I have several concerns for the longevity of Concord and what it has to offer. Concord’s meat-and-potatoes formula is a pretty standard 5v5 set up, with two teams choosing their preferred character before diving into an objective-based team battle.</p><p>During the preview, I was able to play three of six modes that will be available at launch: Trophy Hunt, Cargo Run, and Clash Point. Trophy Hunt was the only one that featured respawns in the match and was basically Kill Confirmed team deathmatch.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>While I enjoyed my time in the limited hands-on preview overall, I have several concerns for the longevity of Concord and what it has to offer.</p></div><p>Cargo Run, meanwhile, was a single-life match where the objective was to run to the center, steal a Blue Buddy package and plant it at one of two sites. If planted, the enemy team could go and stand on the package to diffuse it and take it back. And finally, Clash Point was a round-based single-life game mode with the objective being to control the only capture zone in the entire map multiple times to get the victory.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The single-life modes were tough to warm up on while still getting to know the game, as failure obviously means you’re out of the action for a bit. And while Concord is a fairly straightforward FPS, I have a core criticism a mere two months from its August 23 launch: in the build I played, the movement felt extremely floaty and required a bit of time to get used to. This is exacerbated by the fact that each Freerunner character you can play has a unique set of movement and skills they bring to the team, so each time you swap to a new character, you’re then attempting to learn and configure your brain to how they work. So you can imagine that it gets a bit disorienting.</p><p>And while Concord will be released on PC day and date with PS5, I was only able to preview this on the PS5 with a controller, and so with that in mind, I’d say the movement is heavily reminiscent of Destiny and Halo. Again, it is incredibly floaty, which could be a fun element if it is done well. However, the way the preview build felt, the feather-light jumps and hang time really did not match the amount of fast-paced fights that could occur at any time in the matches.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>While Halo does utilize a similar floaty jump mechanic, the rest of the mechanics and gameplay in Halo justify that reasoning and do not make it feel like the odd element out. Grenades also feel light when lobbed through the air, the various abilities in Halo all have the same weight and cadence to them, and the match pacing reflects the balancing between the base game mechanics. Players in Halo, even in competitive ranked matches, do heal over time after avoiding taking damage for a while.</p><p>Similarly, Destiny is a game that’s more PvE related and thus does not need the incredibly snappy mechanics that Halo or Concord need in PvP fights. Even in the PvP fights in Destiny, the usual TTK is slower since the fights can be drawn out due to the different class abilities allowing for slower or faster play, depending on how players choose to engage (i.e. more directly or more reserved). Each class also has different movement capabilities and healing abilities that ensure match pacing stays consistent throughout.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>So the problem in Concord, at least in this preview version, is that it takes little pieces from games like Halo and Destiny and mixes them together in a formula that doesn’t quite come together for me as of yet. Concord actually utilizes the same type of dodge  animation from Destiny that pulls you out in third person. While I liked this element in Destiny, in Concord it doesn’t quite work because there’s a  brief-but-noticeable delay between your input of the dodge and the actual deployment. This can make or break your life since timing is everything in competitive play and a single hesitation, or simulated hesitation through the delayed input, can punish you greatly.</p><p>Sony says there will be twelve total maps at launch, so perhaps some of the game modes will feel better paced and optimized on the others when spread out. But the way things stand currently, most maps felt very oddly misshapen. Some lanes were too long or big and barely saw rotations while the second lane in another map would just feel entirely too small and cause prolonged team fights due to its claustrophobic size.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Concord touts its competitive nature and fast-paced fights. I love all of that but found that the competitiveness risks being unwelcoming to new players attempting to learn the game because most of the game modes are single-life-focused. </p><p>It’s important to note that even if you are an incredible player, Concord is not a game that allows for many 1v2 fights to be won. Unlike a game of Apex or Halo where you can potentially outsmart your opponents and win in 1v2 scenarios, Concord is so heavily a team game that you’re not able to succeed if you’re on your own. While this <em>is</em> the point of team FPS games, it’s pretty punishing for modes like Trophy Hunt where you’re encouraged to go off and get kills for the objective.</p><p>Another reason these lopsided matchups are impossible to win is the fact that each character in Concord has their own health pool and hitbox. This would be fine if these characters had your traditional classes, but Concord doesn’t utilize your typical class system. Usually, each class has their own health stats that you can expect each character in that label to have.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Concord Gameplay Trailer Screenshots - State of Play 2024</h3></div></output><p>Taking a look at Overwatch, for instance, most Tanks have a base health of anywhere from about 525 to 700 (with combinations of shields or armor in game for specific characters that have them like DVA and Reinhardt). In Concord, it was incredibly difficult to tell what exactly the health pool was for any of the classes since nothing was really quite established with their system.</p><p>For example, 1-Off is a cute robot who sucks up trash and is most definitely a tank character with his big physique and clunky movement and hard-hitting weaponry who has 300 health. However, Teo, who is essentially a DPS that plays like your traditional ground soldier-like character with no tank qualities, has 220 health as a Concord Ranger class. But Roka, another character who is essentially a DPS, is classified as a Haunt and has 170 health. </p><p>What these non-traditional classes mean is extremely confusing. In the preview, we weren’t given details on each class and what the terms mean, but it all seems a bit arbitrary when the health pools and damage numbers vary so much, causing an even further division of game balancing.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Concord Trailer Screens</h3></div></output><p>Overwatch also utilizes the system of ensuring there is a roster for the amount of characters allowed from each class. Concord currently does not utilize a mechanic like that and allows players to use whatever characters they want, since these class systems are not traditional. While this is fun in theory, in my brief experience playing a competitive game like Concord, it doesn’t pan out too well. </p><p>Another reason Concord is so heavily a team-based game is that each character has their own running speed and damage output. It could be argued that this is an extension of the lack of clear classes, but I did want to focus on this as its own balancing issue. The DPS on characters is pretty important since you’re allowed to have a team of whatever characters you want.</p><p>There were some definitely “overpowered” characters in the preview build that you really did need on your team if you wanted to win, especially in Trophy Hunt. Let’s look at the rocket launcher Freegunner, Roka.</p><p>She’s able to deal 43 damage with direct hits while firing rapidly and establishing her lock-on target almost instantly. After having done some watch backs, it seems there’s no real answer to what the distance of Roka’s splash damage is and how much it does consistently. So far I’ve seen it hit from a decent distance for 12 damage, then also hit for 27 damage closer to the target. Roka also has eight total rockets to use before she has to reload so these numbers add up.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The ever-ongoing battle between controller aim assist versus keyboard and mouse movement seems to just be aggravated here.</p></div><p>Comparing this to Overwatch’s Pharah, another rocket-launcher-wielding character, she only does 40 damage to an enemy when it is a <em>direct</em> hit, with her splash damage being about half that. She also only has six rockets before having to reload and does not have any abilities for lock on fire.</p><p>Obviously comparing these two games head-to-head isn’t fair to either, but it’s important to note the difference between balancing. It’s entirely possible that with time, Concord will be able to get a better grasp for how its balancing should be maintained. But the way it stands currently, I’m concerned for the more casual players’ experience and general approachability.</p><p>The option to play crossplay with PC and PS5 will be available at launch which is good news for players like me who have friends on both platforms, but it’s a bit of a double-edged sword. The preview build I played showcased heavy aim assist on controllers. It was most noticeable on Roka, the rocket launcher character, since her weapon locks-on. I would find myself having to really rip the thumbstick away to get her to turn away from the nearest enemy that I didn’t even want to target.</p><p>The other characters I played didn’t feature nearly as aggressive aim assist, but I could feel the magnetization there, which was a bit frustrating and concerning considering the option for crossplay would be enabled at launch. While yes, you can argue that on PC you can do more rapid movement adjustments on the fly, the ever-ongoing battle between controller aim assist versus keyboard and mouse movement seems to just be aggravated here.</p><p>Fortunately, there are still a couple of months to go until Concord’s launch – still a decent bit of time for the balancing and tweaking of every aspect of the game that always happens at this stage of the development process. Fingers crossed Concord is able to tighten up its floaty controls and address its character balancing before it drops on August 23 for PS5 and PC.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hitman's Latest Target Is MMA Star Conor McGregor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hitmans-latest-target-is-mma-star-conor-mcgregor</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hitmans-latest-target-is-mma-star-conor-mcgregor.913530/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/hitmans-latest-target-is-mma-star-conor-mcgregor<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Meet The Disruptor.</h2></div><section><p>The latest elusive target in <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/hitman-world-of-assassination">Hitman: World of Assassination</a> is MMA star Conor McGregor.</p><p>Developer IO Interactive has revealed McGregor will play a mysterious multi-millionaire MMA fighter known only as The Disruptor, who players must hunt down and kill as Agent 47. The character is practically identical to McGregor, tattoos and all.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>"Conor McGregor features in Hitman: World of Assassination as The Disruptor, a multi-millionaire MMA Fighter with worldwide fame who started a feud with the CEO of a prominent tech company, putting a target on his back in the process," the official synopsis reads.</p><p>Players can access the mission from today, June 27 to July 29, on all platforms Hitman: World of Assassination, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hitman-3-being-rebranded-as-world-of-assassination-putting-entire-trilogy-in-one-package">previously Hitman 3</a>, is available: PlayStation 4 and 5, Xbox One and Series, Nintendo Switch, and PC.</p><p>"The age of the Disruptor is here," McGregor said of his role. "I had a lot of fun creating the character and bringing him to life. I can’t wait for players to try to take him down. Agent 47 is in for the fight of his life."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Hitman: World of Assassination The Disruptor Trailer Images</h3></div></output><p>It's not the first time Hitman: World of Assassination has tasked players with hunting down a real-world person, as in July 2023 it released <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hitman-world-of-assassination-to-get-first-new-elusive-target-in-two-years">a mission about assassinating a character identical to DJ and actor Dimitri Vegas</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/hitman-iii">In our 9/10 review of the original game</a>, IGN said: "Rich, rewarding, and highly replayable, Hitman 3 is one of the barcoded butcher's best appearances."</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[College Football 25: EA Sports Reveals the Best Offensive Teams]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-best-offensive-teams</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/college-football-25-ea-sports-reveals-the-best-offensive-teams.913524/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-best-offensive-teams<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>With less than a month until <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/college-football-25">College Football 25</a> releases, EA Sports has revealed the best offensive teams available in the game.</p><p>As part of its week-long plan to reveal new information about College Football 25, EA Sports confirmed the top 25 best offensive teams you can play. EA Sports noted that it factored in several parameters when compiling this list, such as vetting thousands of players, "years worth of game film," and viewing a slew of statistics. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>College Football 25 Official Reveal Trailer Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>The top-ranking offensive team in College Football 25 is the University of Georgia (UGA), with an offense overall rank of 94. Led by head coach Kirby Smart and offensive coordinator Mike Bobo, UGA has become a dominant force in collegiate football, winning back-to-back national championships in 2021 and 2022. Last season, UGA had a 13-1 record, with its only loss coming from Alabama in the SEC Championship. </p><p>Oregon, Alabama, Texas, and Ohio State are some other top-ranking offenses in College Football 25. The full list of the top 25 offensive teams, as well as each team's overall offensive ranking in College Football 25 is available below.</p><p>College Football 25 <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-release-date">is out on July 19</a> or July 16 if you buy the Deluxe Edition or MVP Bundle. For more information, check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-ea-sports-details-the-immersion-created-by-college-sights-sounds-and-tradition">yesterday's Sights and Sounds gameplay deep dive</a>, the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-toughest-places-to-play">top 25 toughest places to play</a>, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-preview-more-than-just-a-madden-clone">our hands-on preview</a>, where I explain why College Football 25 is much more than a Madden NFL clone. </p><h2><u><strong>Top 25 Offensive Teams in College Football 25</strong></u></h2><ol data-cy="list"><li>Georgia - (94 OVR)</li><li>Oregon - (94 OVR)</li><li>Alabama - (91 OVR)</li><li>Texas - (91 OVR)</li><li>Ohio State - (89 OVR)</li><li>LSU - (89 OVR)</li><li>Miami - (89 OVR)</li><li>Colorado - (89 OVR)</li><li>Missouri - (89 OVR)</li><li>Clemson - (87 OVR)</li><li>Utah - (87 OVR)</li><li>Penn State - (87 OVR)</li><li>Ole Miss - (87 OVR)</li><li>Kansas - (87 OVR)</li><li>Arizona - (87 OVR)</li><li>NC State - (87 OVR)</li><li>Notre Dame - (85 OVR)</li><li>Texas A&amp;M - (85 OVR)</li><li>Memphis - (85 OVR)</li><li>SMU - (85 OVR)</li><li>UCF - (85 OVR)</li><li>Florida State - (83 OVR)</li><li>Oklahoma - (83 OVR)</li><li>Virginia Tech - (83 OVR)</li><li>USC - (83 OVR)</li></ol><p><em>Taylor is a Reporter at IGN. You can follow her on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/TayNixster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@TayNixster.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hidetaka Miyazaki Open to Elden Ring Movie if a "Very Strong Partner" Were to Step In]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hidetaka-miyazaki-open-to-elden-ring-movie-if-a-very-strong-partner-were-to-step-in</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hidetaka-miyazaki-open-to-elden-ring-movie-if-a-very-strong-partner-were-to-step-in.913521/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/hidetaka-miyazaki-open-to-elden-ring-movie-if-a-very-strong-partner-were-to-step-in<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">“I don’t see any reason to deny another interpretation...".</h2></div><section><p>FromSoftware president Hidetaka Miyazaki has revealed that he would be open to an adaptation of the studio’s hit 2022 RPG <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring">Elden Ring</a>, but only if a “very strong partner” were to come into play.</p><p>“I don’t see any reason to deny another interpretation or adaptation of Elden Ring, a movie for example,” explained Miyazaki in an interview with <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/article/2024/jun/26/pushing-buttons-meeting-hidetaka-miyazaki" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Guardian</a>. “But I don’t think myself, or FromSoftware, have the knowledge or ability to produce something in a different medium.”</p><p>Elden Ring was designed by FromSoftware to be a profoundly challenging experience, and it is likely that any attempt to translate the mystery-laden fantasy world into another format altogether would prove to be equally difficult to execute. After all, Elden Ring’s history and lore — much like that of most other Miyazaki-directed games — is fractured and obfuscated by intent, with hints as to its true nature often found only in the descriptions of obscure items, or through conversation with NPCs. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree DLC Review Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>This works in a video game, where players are at liberty to explore and seek out answers organically, but could prove difficult to parse in another artistic medium lacking a similar level of agency. That said, Elden Ring has an incredibly rich setting that Game of Thrones author <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-george-r-r-martin-miyazaki-writing">George R. R. Martin himself had a hand in creating</a>, so there’s plenty of lore for a determined partner to explore should they gain Miyazaki’s trust, and according to the FromSoftware president, there is interest in doing so.</p><p>“So that’s where a very strong partner would come into play,” continued Miyazaki. “We’d have to build a lot of trust and agreement on whatever it is we’re trying to achieve, but there’s interest, for sure.” The FromSoftware president didn’t specify exactly what this “interest” entailed, though his example of a potential movie adaptation wouldn't be far-fetched considering the current enthusiasm surrounding video game films and TV shows, many of which are set to light up our screens in the coming years. </p><p>For more on that, why not check out our list of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/upcoming-video-game-movies-and-tv-shows">every video game movie and TV show slated for release in 2024, and beyond</a>, and for more Elden Ring news read up on our list of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-hardest-bosses-ranked">the top 10 most challenging bosses from the Shadow of the Erdtree DLC</a>.</p><p><em>Anthony is a freelance contributor covering science and video gaming news for IGN. He has over eight years experience of covering breaking developments in multiple scientific fields and absolutely no time for your shenanigans. Follow him on Twitter @BeardConGamer</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trinity Fusion coming to Switch on August 1]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/trinity-fusion-coming-to-switch-on-august-1</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/trinity-fusion-coming-to-switch-on-august-1.913518/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/trinity-fusion-coming-to-switch-on-august-1<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Pre-orders now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Angry Mob Games [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/angry-mob-games">Angry Mob Games</a> will release a <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,566 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> version of roguelite <a title="Genres > Action [1,965 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [477 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Trinity Fusion [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/trinity-fusion">Trinity Fusion</a></em> on August 1 for $19.99, the developer announced. Pre-orders are available now via <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/trinity-fusion-switch/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Nintendo eShop</a>. <span id="more-895649"></span></p><p><em>Trinity Fusion</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1911360/Trinity_Fusion/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on April 13, 2023, followed by a full release across PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC on December 15, 2023.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Angry Mob Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Take control of your parallel selves on a mission to save the dying multiverse. Explore dark, science-fiction worlds and engage in fast-paced, smooth and precise combat.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>A <a title="Genres > Roguelite [179 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">Roguelite</a> Journey through the Multiverse</strong> – The various branches of the multiverse are always changing. Fight through a combination of procedurally-generated levels as well as hand-crafted challenges and arenas that will put your skills to the test. Levels with 3D graphics are seamlessly constructed out of hundreds of hand-made rooms.</li><li><strong>High-Intensity Combat</strong> – With weapons and attack systems that leverage our previous experience working on fighting games. You’ll slide, dash and dodge between enemy attacks and strike back with an arsenal of satisfying special weapons and abilities.</li><li><strong>Three Characters, Three Universes to Explore</strong> – Each of your parallel selves has their own world with multiple biomes to explore, as well as their own sets of unique abilities and weapons. Travel through a universe of desolate wastes and caverns roamed by mutant creatures, escape the endless forges and labs of a world ruled by machines, and survive the dangerous sky cities of a post-human society.</li><li><strong>Constant Progression</strong> – Unlock permanent upgrades in the Hub and discover new starting points for your run as you reclaim major locations in each universe. Finding yourself getting stuck in one area? Start your next run in a different one! No matter where you die, or which starting point you pick, you’re making progress somewhere.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Switch Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Trinity Fusion – Release Date Trailer – Nintendo Switch" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v2Wubfo9mKs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>