<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 03:43:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country has a very cinematic trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/13/mafia-the-old-country-has-a-very-cinematic-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-has-a-very-cinematic-trailer.1060248/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/13/mafia-the-old-country-has-a-very-cinematic-trailer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The Mafia <a href="https://x.com/mafiagame/status/1866165956134707406">social media</a> account kept things pretty tame this week just saying “See you at [The Game Awards]” and sure enough they were there.&nbsp; The new trailer (some of which leaked earlier today) gives us a release date of Summer 2025 which is much sooner than expected, previously Hangar 13 had said the game is “years” away.</p>
<p>Here is the trailer!</p>
<p><iframe title="Mafia: The Old Country - The Initiation Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lkdV6NxPOLc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Meet Enzo Favara, who sinks into the criminal underworld on Siciliy in the early 1900s. You’ll have to fight to survive in this dangerous era, and the game looks great from the few snippets of actual action with really fluid animations to go with the bleeding edge graphics.</p>
<p>“Across the first three entries in the&nbsp;Mafia&nbsp;franchise, we introduced players to the world of the Mafia through brutal stories set in different eras,” said Nick Baynes, President of Hangar 13. “In&nbsp;Mafia: The Old Country, we’re going back to the roots of what fans love about the franchise, crafting a deep, linear narrative with that classic mob movie feeling, visiting a stunning new setting, and delivering it all in a tight, focused package perfect for fans of immersive experiences.”</p>

<p>Mafia: The Old Country will be released on PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC via Steam.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Part II Remastered PC Is Out on April 3, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-pc-is-out-on-april-3-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-pc-is-out-on-april-3-2025.1060245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-pc-is-out-on-april-3-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At The Game Awards 2024, Naughty Dog and Sony Interactive Entertainment have announced that The Last of Us Part II Remastered is coming to PC on April 3, 2025. That's around a year after the arrival of Part I.</p>
<p>The Remastered version launched on PlayStation 5 earlier this year. Francesco De Meo wrote in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-the-definitive-package/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wccftech's review</a>:</p>
<p><em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered is, without a doubt, the best way to enjoy Naughty Dog's excellent survival horror game, thanks to the addition of the surprisingly fun No Return roguelike mode, the cut Lost Levels, developer commentary, and two display modes for a proper 4K resolution experience. The main campaign's bleak story remains as controversial as it was when the original game launched on PlayStation 4, but underneath it is one of the finest survival horror games ever made.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="The Last of Us Part II Remastered - Announcement Trailer | PC Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O6MdexNSy3o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>PlayStation 5 Pro owners can already <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-the-definitive-package/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">play</a> an enhanced version, but the PC version might just be the Definitive Edition of Naughty Dog's masterpiece - provided it does not suffer from the issues of Part I's PC port.</p>

			
			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
	</div>

		
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Classic '90s PC racing series Screamer is returning, from the makers of Hot Wheels Unleashed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/classic-90s-pc-racing-series-screamer-is-returning-from-the-makers-of-hot-wheels-unleashed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/classic-90s-pc-racing-series-screamer-is-returning-from-the-makers-of-hot-wheels-unleashed.1060242/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/classic-90s-pc-racing-series-screamer-is-returning-from-the-makers-of-hot-wheels-unleashed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/screamer-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Milestone Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Back in the mid '90s, I was hooked on an PC racing game called <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/screamer">Screamer</a>. It got a sequel a couple of years later, and then the series went dormant. Until now, when it's seemingly returning as a foreboding, anime-infused racer about defying death, once again called simply Screamer. Huh! Huh. You'll find a trailer below.
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Screamer - Teaser Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8ohDOlboyZg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Screamer - Teaser Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8ohDOlboyZg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8ohDOlboyZg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Screamer's animated announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8ohDOlboyZg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>I guess <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-more-kidding-around-i-just-want-another-screamer">Ed will be happy?</a>
</p>
<p>The trailer doesn't show anything in-game, and there's very little information about the game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/">on its official site</a>. I only knew it was connected to the '90s original by the logo for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milestone_(Italian_company)">Milestone Games</a> at the start of the trailer. They're the Italian game developer who created the first two games (the first under the name Graffiti), and are more recently known for (the better than expected) racing game <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hot-wheels-unleashed">Hot Wheels Unleashed</a> and its sequel.
</p><p>Did the first Screamer have any kind of plot or framing device? If it did, I've long forgotten it. I remember it having great, Ridge Racer-style car control, and I remember my brothers and I becoming extremely competitive about trying to beat each other's times. I also remember the rally-oriented sequel being less good.
</p>
<p>I don't hate that the new Screamer seemingly moves in a new direction. It's been a long time, and there was nothing about the original duology that feels essential today. You can these days grab <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/697580/Screamer/">Screamer 1</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/698620/Screamer_2/">Screamer 2</a> from Steam, although you're better off just watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Er9ecGTA7lw&amp;ab_channel=Squakenet">a few minutes of the original on YouTube</a>.
</p>
<hr>
<p><em>The Geoffening has begun! Catch all the latest Game Awards announcements on our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/the-game-awards-2024">Game Awards 2024</a> hub page. You can also get the news hot from our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2024-liveblog">liveblog</a>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The creator of Ico and Shadow Of The Colossus is making a giant robot-piloting game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-creator-of-ico-and-shadow-of-the-colossus-is-making-a-giant-robot-piloting-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-creator-of-ico-and-shadow-of-the-colossus-is-making-a-giant-robot-piloting-game.1060239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-creator-of-ico-and-shadow-of-the-colossus-is-making-a-giant-robot-piloting-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_sSDq2cF.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games / IGN</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Fumito Ueda is the august visionary behind ICO (small boy rescues small girl from evil castle), Shadow Of The Colossus (grieving boy murders several massive stone animals), <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/last-guardian">The Last Guardian</a> (small boy and huge, dopey dogcat escape from another evil castle). Now, he's getting into Gundams, though it looks like small boys are still a feature. Epic Games Publishing have just unveiled Ueda and genDESIGN's latest creation - Project: Robot. Find a trailer below.
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Project: Robot - Reveal Trailer (Studio Behind Ico &amp; Shadow of the Colossus) | The Game Awards 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g7duXPcEYb0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Project: Robot - Reveal Trailer (Studio Behind Ico &amp; Shadow of the Colossus) | The Game Awards 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g7duXPcEYb0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/g7duXPcEYb0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g7duXPcEYb0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
To recap that footage: it looks like the boy has set the giant robot to self-destruct, hence the garbled countdown, in order to defeat that tsunami of evil black goop. Then he flies away in the robot's head - a sequence that reminds me of the anime Gurren Lagann. Look, I'm struggling to phrase this elegantly and draw proper conclusions because I'm very tired. It's 3am here. You're not supposed to write about Fumito Ueda games at 3am - they tend to require a bit more thought, dare I say, a touch of reverie, rather than the frenzy of the Game Awards.
</p>
<p>
There's not much to say beyond the trailer, though you'll notice it has a bunch of text at the end in a tauntingly narrow, borderline unreadable font. It could be just the credits, but perhaps there's a synopsis hidden away in there. When I can see straight I'll have a go at deciphering it.
</p><p>
All weariness and snarking aside, I love Fumito Ueda's stuff and it's good to see that he and his colleagues are still churning out wacky originals. A less committed soul would have made Ico 2: Iconic by now. Project Robot seems closest in style to The Last Guardian, given that you are a small thing riding a larger thing. I am predictably concerned that the game will make me form an emotional bond with the giant robot, then destroy it in some heart-breakingly tragic way. Mind you, we did just see the robot get decapitated. So perhaps it's more of a tool than a friend.
</p>
<p>
Release date? None yet. More as we get it. Speculations welcome.

</p>
<hr>
<p><em>The Geoffening has begun! Catch all the latest Game Awards announcements on our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/the-game-awards-2024">Game Awards 2024</a> hub page. You can also get the news hot from our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2024-liveblog">liveblog</a>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game of Thrones: Kingsroad Mobile Game is Launching 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-mobile-game-is-launching-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-mobile-game-is-launching-2025.1060236/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-mobile-game-is-launching-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-74014">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>An open-world action RPG set in the illustrious Game of Thrones universe has been revealed at The Game Awards. Game of Thrones: Kingsroad debuted via a trailer littered with recognizable characters and the iconic score from the hit HBO series.</p>



<p>Winter is coming to mobile next year.</p>



<hr>



<p>Game of Thrones: Kingsroad will occur in the midst of events that take place during the show’s third season, following the Red Wedding and the near destruction of House Stark. You play a bastard of the northern House Tyre, who is summoned back home following the unimaginable betrayal. During the game, you will travel north past the Wall, and as far south as King’s Landing.</p>



<p>During your travels, you will meet another famous Northern bastard in Jon Snow, as well as other characters from the show including Cersei Lannister, Jaime Lannister, and Varys. According to the game’s website, the player will be able to choose between three class types: the longsword-wielding Knight, the brutal axe-wielding Sellsword, or the cunning Assassin.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="[Game of Thrones: Kingsroad] Official Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zeyBwI8D9YU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The game is being developed by Netmarble, a South Korean mobile game developer. On <a href="https://gameofthrones.netmarble.com/en">the game’s website</a>, it’s listed as “a blockbuster story-driven action-adventure RPG,” but only lists Android and iOS as its platforms.</p>



<p>Is Game of Thrones: Kingsroad a game you eventually hope comes to PC or consoles? Tell us in the comments and join the discussion on&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">our forum</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-mafia-the-old-country-trailer-released-release-window-confirmed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-mafia-the-old-country-trailer-released-release-window-confirmed/">New Mafia: The Old Country Trailer Released; Release Window Confirmed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>At The Game Awards 2024, fans got a brand new trailer for its upcoming prequel Mafia: The Old Country along with a confirmed release window.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cdpr-wont-let-the-witcher-4-cyberpunk-2077/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cdpr-wont-let-the-witcher-4-cyberpunk-2077/">CDPR Won’t Let Witcher 4 Be Another Cyberpunk 2077 At Launch</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>CDPR has explained how and why it won’t let The Witcher 4 become another Cyberpunk 2077 when it’s released.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-best-adaptation-the-game-awards/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-best-adaptation-the-game-awards/">Fallout Wins Best Adaptation at The Game Awards, Beating Riot’s Arcane</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fallout has won the award for the Best Adaptation at The Game Awards, despite many believing Arcane would win.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Mafia: The Old Country Trailer Released; Release Window Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-mafia-the-old-country-trailer-released-release-window-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-mafia-the-old-country-trailer-released-release-window-confirmed.1060233/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/new-mafia-the-old-country-trailer-released-release-window-confirmed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-72870">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Developer Hangar Studios and publisher 2K have released a new trailer for Mafia: The Old Country. The trailer, which debuted during The Game Awards 2024, gives players a new look at the game’s Sicily setting, its story, and confirms a summer 2025 release window.</p>



<p>The trailer is a longer version of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-the-old-country-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what leaked on Thursday</a> morning ahead of the event.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Mafia: The Old Country - The Initiation Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lkdV6NxPOLc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>“Uncover the origins of organized crime in Mafia: The Old Country, a gritty mob story set in the brutal underworld of 1900s Sicily,” the game’s description reads. “Fight to survive in this dangerous and unforgiving era, with action brought to life by the authentic realism and rich storytelling that the critically acclaimed Mafia series is known for.”</p>



<p>While Mafia: The Old Country <a href="https://mafia.2k.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">is scheduled</a> to release in the summer, an exact date hasn’t been confirmed. It’s expected not to be released around Borderlands 4 or Grand Theft Auto 6. It was also confirmed via press release that the game will feature a linear story as opposed to being open-world.</p>



<p>What do you think of the new trailer for Mafia: The Old Country? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official Insider Gaming Forums.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-combat/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">gameplay deep dive</a> for Assassin’s Creed Shadows. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cdpr-wont-let-the-witcher-4-cyberpunk-2077/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cdpr-wont-let-the-witcher-4-cyberpunk-2077/">CDPR Won’t Let Witcher 4 Be Another Cyberpunk 2077 At Launch</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>CDPR has explained how and why it won’t let The Witcher 4 become another Cyberpunk 2077 when it’s released.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-best-adaptation-the-game-awards/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-best-adaptation-the-game-awards/">Fallout Wins Best Adaptation at The Game Awards, Beating Riot’s Arcane</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fallout has won the award for the Best Adaptation at The Game Awards, despite many believing Arcane would win.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-why-ciri-main-character/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-why-ciri-main-character/">‘It Was Always About Her’: CDPR Reveals Why Ciri is the Lead in The Witcher 4</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In an interview, the leadership team at CDPR has explained why Ciri is – and always has been – the lead in The Witcher 4</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us: Part 2 Remastered coming to PC in April]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-part-2-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-coming-to-pc-in-april.1060227/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-part-2-pc/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-74017">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The Last of Us: Part 2 was present at The Game Awards. The game was confirmed for PC and given a release date of April 3, 2025.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Last of Us Part II Remastered - Announcement Trailer | PC Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O6MdexNSy3o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p id="tw-target-text">Interestingly, the PC version had already been leaked months ago by the trustworthy billbil-kun. The insider stated that the port was already ready but that PlayStation would hold the release to coincide with the arrival of the second season of the series.</p>



<p>By default, the PC version should have several features such as support for widescreen resolution, new graphics options and more. The version is being led by Nixxes and Iron Galaxy, a studio praised for its good quality ports.</p>



<p>Are you going to play the port? Tell us in the comments and join the discussion on&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">our forum</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-best-adaptation-the-game-awards/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-best-adaptation-the-game-awards/">Fallout Wins Best Adaptation at The Game Awards, Beating Riot’s Arcane</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fallout has won the award for the Best Adaptation at The Game Awards, despite many believing Arcane would win.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-why-ciri-main-character/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-why-ciri-main-character/">‘It Was Always About Her’: CDPR Reveals Why Ciri is the Lead in The Witcher 4</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In an interview, the leadership team at CDPR has explained why Ciri is – and always has been – the lead in The Witcher 4</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-the-beast-new-trailer/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-the-beast-new-trailer/">Dying Light: The Beast Received a New Trailer at The Games Awards 2024</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Dying Light: The Beast received a new gameplay trailer at The Game Awards 2024. No concrete date has been announced, just a window for the summer of 2025.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-release-date/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-release-date/">The First Berserker: Khazan arrives in March</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>During The Game Awards 2024, The First Berserker: Khazan got a new trailer that confirms this week’s leak.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout Wins Best Adaptation at The Game Awards, Beating Riot’s Arcane]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-best-adaptation-the-game-awards/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-wins-best-adaptation-at-the-game-awards-beating-riot%E2%80%99s-arcane.1060224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-best-adaptation-the-game-awards/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-74018">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>In a twist that nobody expected – because let’s be honest, Arcane is incredible – Fallout won Best Adaptation at The Game Awards.</p>



<p>Fallout debuted in April on Prime Video and quickly became one of the biggest launches ever on the platform. It proved to be a boon for the post-apocalyptic series, bringing millions of players into the fold across the whole franchise as viewers everywhere fell in love with the live-action adaptation.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-tough-competition">Tough Competition</h2>



<p>It has been a phenomenal couple of years for adaptations. Arcane has broken viewership records and turned heads thanks to a whopping $250 million budget, The Last of Us won Emmy Awards, and now Fallout has won the award for Best Adaptation at The Game Awards.</p>



<p>As a Fallout fan, I can speak to the accuracy and delivery of the Fallout TV series. It’s nothing short of phenomenal, and the world-building was spot-on. There are high expectations for the second season, which recently started filming at Amazon and Kilter Films.</p>



<p>Here’s a trailer for the Fallout TV show, just to give you an idea of the authenticity of it:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Fallout - Official Trailer | Prime Video" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V-mugKDQDlg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Did you watch the Fallout TV show? Let us know what you think on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">the Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-why-ciri-main-character/">why Ciri is the lead character in The Witcher 4</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-why-ciri-main-character/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-why-ciri-main-character/">‘It Was Always About Her’: CDPR Reveals Why Ciri is the Lead in The Witcher 4</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>At The Game Awards in Los Angeles, CDPR revealed The Witcher 4 with a lengthy CGI trailer, rewarding the fans who have waited almost a decade to see what’s next for the monster-slaying series. At the heart of the trailer sat Ciri, Geralt of Rivia’s ward and the protagonist of the upcoming title. In an […]</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-release-date/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-release-date/">The First Berserker: Khazan arrives in March</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Nexon’s promising soulslike got a new trailer and the release date</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Part II Remastered coming to PC on April 3, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-coming-to-pc-on-april-3-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-coming-to-pc-on-april-3-2025.1060221/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-coming-to-pc-on-april-3-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PlayStation 5.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,930 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Naughty Dog [306 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a> and Nixxes Software will release <a title="Games > The Last of Us Part II Remastered [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered">The Last of Us Part II Remastered</a> for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,954 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2531310/The_Last_of_Us_Part_II_Remastered/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [346 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store on April 3, 2025, the companies announced. <span id="more-934020"></span></p><p><em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> first launched for PlayStation 5 on January 19.</p><p>Here is an overview of the PC version, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Ellie and Abby’s Journey Now on PC</strong></p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the winner of over 300 Game of the Year awards now with an array of technical enhancements that make <em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> the definitive way to play Ellie and Abby’s critically acclaimed story.</p><p>Five years after their dangerous journey across the post-pandemic United States, Ellie and Joel have settled down in Jackson, Wyoming. Living amongst a thriving community of survivors has allowed them peace and stability, despite the constant threat of the infected and other, more desperate survivors. When a violent event disrupts that peace, Ellie embarks on a relentless journey to carry out justice and find closure.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Added Features</strong></p><p><em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> enhances the original game in ways not possible before, including:</p><ul><li>A host of graphical improvements bring the beautiful-yet-dangerous world to life.</li><li>Full PlayStation DualSense controller integration.</li></ul><p><strong>No Return: A <a title="Genres > Roguelike [283 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">Roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Survival [361 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> Mode</strong></p><p>Experience <em><a title="Games > The Last of Us Part I [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-last-of-us-part-i">The Last of Us Part I</a>I</em>‘s deep combat via an entirely new mode! Survive as long as you can in each run, as you choose your path through a series of randomized encounters. Play as a host of different unlockable characters, each with unique gameplay traits. The variety of challenges features different foes and memorable locations from throughout <em>Part II</em>, all culminating in tense boss battles.</p><p><strong>More Ways to Play</strong></p><ul><li>Delve deeper into this beloved <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,946 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> and learn how the original game was created.</li><li>Lost Levels lets you explore early-development versions of three levels not seen in the original.</li><li>Enjoy hours of developer commentary to hear insights into <em>Part II</em>‘s development as you experience the game.</li><li>Live up to your musical potential with Guitar Free Play, which includes unlockable instruments, or take on the Speedrun Mode² and post your best times.</li><li>Descriptive Audio³ and Speech to Vibrations have also been added to <em>Part II</em>‘s suite of accessibility features.</li><li><em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> also features unlockable character and weapon skins for players to use for both Ellie and Abby.</li></ul><p>¹ Account for PlayStation Network required.<br>² Game progression required to unlock.<br>³ Only available for audio supported languages.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PC Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The Last of Us Part II Remastered - Announcement Trailer | PC Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O6MdexNSy3o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sci-fi racer reimagining Screamer announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/sci-fi-racer-reimagining-screamer-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sci-fi-racer-reimagining-screamer-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.1060218/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/sci-fi-racer-reimagining-screamer-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in 2026.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Milestone S.r.l. [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/milestone-s-r-l">Milestone</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Screamer (2026)" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/screamer-2026">Screamer</a></em>, a reimagining of its 1995 racing game of the same name. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,528 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,476 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,954 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [346 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store in 2026. <span id="more-934019"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Milestone:</p><blockquote><p><em>Screamer</em>, the 1995 title that pushed the boundaries of <a title="Genres > Racing [214 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing games</a>, set a new benchmark in the genre, and brought the excitement of virtual races from <a title="Platforms > Arcade [375 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">arcades</a> into players’ homes.</p><p>Embracing the trailblazing spirit of the original, Milestone has reimagined its most iconic intellectual properties, combining over 30 years of expertise in racing games to craft a brand-new experience with standout fighting mechanics destined to leave a lasting impact on the genre, just as the original did in the ’90s.</p><p>This brand-new <em>Screamer</em> seamlessly blends high-octane <a title="Genres > Arcade [66 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> with revolutionary gameplay dynamics and a deep storyline enriched by interwoven character arcs. Drawing inspiration from anime and manga from the ’80s and ’90s, the game’s narrative and visual framework will be its beating heart and soul. The game features contributions from industry-leading partners, including animated cutscenes created in collaboration with Polygon Pictures—one of the oldest and most renowned Japanese animation studios—and the acclaimed American actor Troy Baker, one of gaming’s most recognizable voices.</p><p>Combining plot themes of human will, revenge, love, and greed with classic science-fiction imagery, <em>Screamer</em> immerses players in the clash between personal desires and external forces that seek to control them. This journey unfolds through the eyes of a diverse cast of characters involved in a street racing tournament organized by a mysterious figure.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/screamer-2026/december-12-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Screamer - Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8ohDOlboyZg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_934026"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Classic Racing Game Screamer Roars Back To Life As An Anime-Inspired Tale Of Revenge And Greed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/classic-racing-game-screamer-roars-back-to-life-as-an-anime-inspired-tale-of-revenge-and-greed/1100-6528404/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/classic-racing-game-screamer-roars-back-to-life-as-an-anime-inspired-tale-of-revenge-and-greed.1060215/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/classic-racing-game-screamer-roars-back-to-life-as-an-anime-inspired-tale-of-revenge-and-greed/1100-6528404/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528404">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>During <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-game-awards-2024-nominees-announced-see-them-all-now/2900-5956/" data-ref-id="2900-5956">The Game Awards</a>, developer Milestone showed off its new project, a resurrection of the classic arcade racer Screamer. While the trailer didn't show off any gameplay, it did tease a darker take on the series set in a neon-light city straight out of old-school anime. Milestone says that it's aiming to blend Screamer's classic arcade driving with a deep storyline featuring multiple character arcs, and the game is currently scheduled to be released in 2026 on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p>Screamer draws inspiration from anime and manga from the '80s and '90s. Milestone says that the game's narrative and visual framework will be enhanced by animated cutscenes created in collaboration with Polygon Pictures, the Japanese animation studio behind series such as Tron: Uprising, Transformers Prime, and Pacific Rim: The Black.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8ohDOlboyZg" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8ohDOlboyZg" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>According to Milestone, the Last of Us voice actor Troy Baker is also involved, as he lends his voice to a 'pivotal" character in the game. The storyline will feature themes of human will, revenge, love, and greed with classic sci-fi influences.</p><p>The first Screamer game was released back in 1995, and at the time, it was notable for its arcade-style gameplay and demanding system requirements. Three sequels followed in its wake--Screamer 2, Screamer Rally, and Screamer 4x4--with the series being developed by Milestone. If you didn't have a PlayStation and Ridge Racer or a Sega Saturn with Daytona USA, this was the next best game to play on PC at the time.</p><p>For more, check out our roundup of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2024-winners-revealed/2900-5956/" data-ref-id="2900-5956">all The Game Awards nominees and winners</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overcooked Studio Reveals Stage Fright, A Co-Op Game Inspired By Luigi's Mansion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/overcooked-studio-reveals-stage-fright-a-co-op-game-inspired-by-luigis-mansion/1100-6528450/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overcooked-studio-reveals-stage-fright-a-co-op-game-inspired-by-luigis-mansion.1060209/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/overcooked-studio-reveals-stage-fright-a-co-op-game-inspired-by-luigis-mansion/1100-6528450/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528450">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Ghost Town Games, the indie team behind the chaotically cute <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/overcooked/" data-ref-id="5000-453001">Overcooked</a> series, has revealed Stage Fright live on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2024-winners-revealed/2900-5956/" data-ref-id="2900-5956">The Game Awards 2024</a> stage, a new co-op game. Judging by the reveal trailer, the game seems to hint at a split-screen presentation in which paired players will each have their own problems to deal with in a story that separates them by time and space.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T_i0xhr4utk" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/T_i0xhr4utk" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The studio said the game combines elements of both the series that put it on the map--the frustrating yet endearing Overcooked--as well as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/luigis-mansion/" data-ref-id="5000-3596">Luigi's Mansion</a>, with a very light spooky vibe all built for two players playing locally or online. Stage Fright is being published by Hello Games, creator of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/no-mans-sky/" data-ref-id="5000-221687">No Man's Sky</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warframe's motorbiking, pal romancing, boyband battling 1999 expansion finally has a release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/warframes-motorbiking-pal-romancing-boyband-battling-1999-expansion-finally-has-a-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warframes-motorbiking-pal-romancing-boyband-battling-1999-expansion-finally-has-a-release-date.1060206/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/warframes-motorbiking-pal-romancing-boyband-battling-1999-expansion-finally-has-a-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>And it's coming very, very soon.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/warframe-1999-arthur-bike.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Digital Extremes</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It feels like forever since we first laid eyes on Warfarme's 1999 expansion (it was, in fact, a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/warframes-next-big-expansion-whispers-in-the-walls-gets-weird-with-necramechs-and-retro-earth-tech">little over a year ago during TennoCon 2023</a>), but the free-to-play sci-fi shooter's time-travelling, boyband battling 1999 story expansion finally has a release date: it launches for all platforms on 13th December - which is to say, later today.
</p>
<p>
1999, if you're unfamiliar, catapults players away from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/warframe">Warframe</a>'s usual far-flung sci-fi future to an eerily familiar Earth-like world of grungy subways stations and retro tech. And, yes, it really is set in 1999 (New Year's Eve to be exact) - but not the Earth we know, despite its familiar sights.
</p>
<p>
And honestly, pretty much everything about 1999 looks wild, from its new hub area - an abandoned 90s shopping mall full of artificial palm trees, arcade machines, and blaring infomercials - to its meaty new motorbike traversal across its urban open-world sprawl.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Warframe: 1999 Official Gameplay Trailer - Launching December 13 on All Platforms" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lr30oQoKeIo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Warframe: 1999 Official Gameplay Trailer - Launching December 13 on All Platforms</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lr30oQoKeIo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Lr30oQoKeIo?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Warframe: 1999 gameplay trailer. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lr30oQoKeIo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Then there's its new Syndicate, known as the Hex, consisting of six iconic Warframes in their original proto-forms - including grizzled squad leader Arthur Nightingale, batch designation: Excalibur. And if that's still not enough to convince you to get stuck in, how about the fact 1999 introduces a romance system so you can potential get a New Year's smooch if you play your cards right? Or that, yes, you get to kill a 90s boyband in space.
</p>
<p>
So yes, all this - and more! - will finally be available to Warframe players on Xbox, PlayStation, Switch, and PC starting today, 13th December.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There's a new Turok game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/theres-a-new-turok-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/theres-a-new-turok-game.1060200/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/theres-a-new-turok-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GepQ-EeW0AEfdLr.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Saber Interactive</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
There's a brand new <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/turok">Turok</a> video game from Saber Interactive.
</p>
<p>
It's called Turok: Origins, and yes, Eurogamer readers, you know what that means. 
</p>
<p>
Turok: Oranges will be launching on PC via Steam, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Turok: Origins World Premiere Trailer from The Game Awards 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tkoACmI_rLs?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Turok: Origins World Premiere Trailer from The Game Awards 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tkoACmI_rLs?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tkoACmI_rLs?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Turok: Oranges reveal trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tkoACmI_rLs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Tonight's trailer, debuted during The Game Awards 2024, promised a "new evolution" of the veteran dinosaur-hunting franchise, which has been absent for many years. The last Turok game arrived in 2006 as something of a reboot for the series, six years after the last entry. 
</p>
<p>Now, eight years later, Saber Interactive is having another crack. Notably, this time around Turok: Origins will be a third-person game. Intrigued? There's no release date yet, but we'll update you with more when we have it.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Onimusha: Way of the Sword revealed for 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/13/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-revealed-for-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-revealed-for-2026.1060185/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/13/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-revealed-for-2026/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Capcom is reviving another of their classic franchises with Onimusha: Way of the Sword set to come out in 2026!</p>
<p><iframe title="Onimusha Way of the Sword Reveal Trailer The Game Awards 2024" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9xQa_iW958E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The Onimusha series has lent on a blend of Japanese history blended with supernatural elements for its setting, built around third-person hack and slash combat for the gameplay.</p>
<p>Debuting on PS2 in 2001, the series flourished through the generation with a string of sequels, a tactics spin-off on GBA and a fighting game. The most recent main new entry was Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams in 2006, so Way of the Sword will mark two decades since that point. We did have a remaster of the original in 2018, though.</p>
<p>Games have come a long, long way since then – just see Capcom’s mastery of the remake and remaster in recent years – so it will be fascinating what parts of the original concept they retain, and what they update and overhaul.</p>



<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Berserker: Khazan New Trailer Confirms March Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-new-trailer-confirms-march-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-berserker-khazan-new-trailer-confirms-march-release-date.1060182/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-new-trailer-confirms-march-release-date/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The First Berserker: Khazan, the action role-playing set in the Dungeon and Fighter universe, will launch in late March on PC and consoles.</p>
<p>The latest cinematic trailer, shown during today's The Game Awards Show 2024, confirmed that the game will be released on March 27th, 2025, on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. In addition, a playable demo will be released in a little over a month, on January 16th, to allow players to get a taste of the experience before release.</p>
<p><iframe title="The First Berserker: Khazan | Release Date Trailer | Begin Your Vengeance on March 27, 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9QGALVsiwYY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The First Berserker: Khazan will be an action role-playing game that will be worth the time of those looking for a challenging experience with some similarities with the Souls series. In the past few months, I had the opportunity to try out the game, and I was thoroughly <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-closed-beta-hands-on-preview-setting-up-for-greatness/">impressed</a> by it, especially by its combat mechanics, so much so that it has become one of my most anticipated games launching in 2025.</p>
<p><em>The longer playtime of The First Berserker: Khazan Technical Closed Beta Test also allowed me to appreciate combat more. While it is undeniable that the stamina-based combat system is very reminiscent of the Souls series, the Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice and Nioh series influences are more prominent. For starters, the evade maneuver doesn't have a whole lot of invincibility frames, making it a little risky to use in close-quarter. The parry, called Brink Guard, on the other hand, is a much more effective defensive technique as it is generally easy to pull off and allows Khazan to stay on the offensive since there's a small cancel window at the end of each move that allows going into the guarding stance immediately, and it restores stamina while depleting the enemy's. An instant evade technique called Brink Evade, is also in, but it seems to interrupt the flow of combat when used to avoid attacks that could be parried.</em></p>
<figure></figure>
<p>The First Berserker: Khazan launches on March 27th on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S.</p>

			
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Onimusha: Way of the Sword Announced For PC and Consoles With a 2026 Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-announced-for-pc-and-consoles-with-a-2026-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-announced-for-pc-and-consoles-with-a-2026-release-date.1060179/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-announced-for-pc-and-consoles-with-a-2026-release-date/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, a new entry in the Onimusha series, Onimusha: Way of the Sword, was announced for PC and consoles.</p>
<p>The first new entry in the series in a very long time was revealed today with an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0auCmtj2K6g&amp;t=1s">intense trailer</a> shown during The Game Awards show which showed how the game will retain the unique atmosphere of the first few entries in the series but feature vastly different gameplay.</p>
<p><iframe title="Onimusha Way of the sword  Trailer 4K - THE GAME AWARDS 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0auCmtj2K6g?start=1&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As Onimusha: Warlords, a remaster of the first entry in the series, did not exactly set the world on fire, the announcement of Onimusha: Way of the Sword comes as an almost complete surprise. In case you haven't played the remaster, you can learn more about this remaster in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/onimusha-warlords-feudal-japan-evil/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>Onimusha: Warlords is a game from another era and the remaster, despite its many enhancements, sadly highlights how the experience hasn't aged too well. This doesn't mean that the game isn't good, as many of its ideas, such as combat, leveling system and puzzles, only required a few small tweaks to be truly excellent. The fact that it's a game from 2001 is clear when playing the game, but Onimusha: Warlords can still provide a sweet, albeit short, experience.</em></p>
<p>Onimusha: Way of the Sword launches on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S sometime in 2026.</p>

			
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Onimusha Way Of The Sword is the Capcom action-RPG's first new instalment in almost 20 years]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-is-the-capcom-action-rpgs-first-new-instalment-in-almost-20-years</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-is-the-capcom-action-rpgs-first-new-instalment-in-almost-20-years.1060176/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-is-the-capcom-action-rpgs-first-new-instalment-in-almost-20-years<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_UccQlcJ.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Capcom / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Well here's one I didn't see coming: a new Onimusha game. It's called Onimusha Way Of The Sword, and is the first new game in Capcom's samurai action-horror series since... well, that upcoming VR entry doesn't count, and nor does the Warlords remaster in 2018. So, 2012? Maybe 2006, if you rule out the Unity browser game? Cor.</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Onimusha Way of the Sword - Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/16KXGqX59Z8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Onimusha Way of the Sword - Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/16KXGqX59Z8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/16KXGqX59Z8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=16KXGqX59Z8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>On the off-chance that you've never played an Onimusha game, and possibly weren't alive back in 2006, it's basically <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/resident-evil">Resident Evil</a> but with a samurai and set in Japan. That was true of the first one, anyway. Later instalments took... interesting liberties. Onimusha 3 had Jean Reno in it for some reason. One thing they all share is more of a combat focus than the Resis. You don't need to find ammo for a katana, after all. But they certainly aren't hack-and-slash games.</p>
<p>The Way Of The Sword trailer doesn't reveal much, but it suggests a back-to-basics approach, as you might expect from a series that hasn't had a mainline instalment in almost two decades. It appears to be set in feudal times, and a bunch of demons are causing a ruckus in the woods. There are scenes of swordplay, including a few vicious finishers and some dramatic parrying. If it's cleaving close to formula, there should be RPG elements as well.</p>
<p>It's out in 2026. Any old Onimusha players in the haus? I think I fell off the series around about the time Jean Reno showed up.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>The Geoffening has begun! Catch all the latest Game Awards announcements on our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/the-game-awards-2024">Game Awards 2024</a> hub page. You can also get the news hot from our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2024-liveblog">liveblog</a>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘It Was Always About Her’: CDPR Reveals Why Ciri is the Lead in The Witcher 4]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-why-ciri-main-character/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98it-was-always-about-her%E2%80%99-cdpr-reveals-why-ciri-is-the-lead-in-the-witcher-4.1060158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-why-ciri-main-character/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>At The Game Awards in Los Angeles, CDPR revealed The Witcher 4 with a lengthy CGI trailer, rewarding the fans who have waited almost a decade to see what’s next for the monster-slaying series.</p>



<p>At the heart of the trailer sat Ciri, Geralt of Rivia’s ward and the protagonist of the upcoming title. In an interview, CD Projekt Red explained why Ciri is leading this single-player title, stressing that, ‘It was always about her.’</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-an-amazing-layered-character">‘An Amazing, Layered Character’</h2>



<p>In an interview <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-4-developer-cd-projekt-explains-why-it-went-with-ciri-over-continuing-with-geralt-as-protagonist?utm_source=threads,twitter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">with IGN</a>, The Witcher 4’s executive producer, Małgorzata Mitręga, explained why Ciri is heading up The Witcher 4, one of the most ambitious games that CDPR has ever made:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>It was always about her, starting from Saga when you read it in the books. She’s an amazing, layered character. And of course, as a protagonist we said goodbye to Geralt previously. So this is a continuation. I guess for all of us it’s like she was meant to be. That was always her.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The director of The Witcher 4, Sebastian Kalemba, expanded on that:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>She’s actually about to become the Witcher. </p>



<p>She’s about to actually form her own codex, but on her own terms. The way she actually deals with the monsters, the way she deals with quests, the adventures, it’s her own unique way. And also I think that she gives more room to be able to tell different stories here and there. </p>



<p>Of course, we want to give the opportunity for the player to explore more nuance because this is what we do. But she deserves that.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It was confirmed that she was always intended to be the protagonist of The Witcher 4. In Blood and Wine, The Witcher 3’s final expansion, Geralt of Rivia effectively retired, so for the true fans of the franchise, Ciri’s arrival as the next game’s main character makes complete sense.</p>



<p>The team at CDPR revealed that Ciri’s story was settled for The Witcher 4 almost ten years ago.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to The Witcher 4? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-virtua-fighter-game-revealed-at-game-awards/">a new Virtua Fighter is coming</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light: The Beast Received a New Trailer at The Games Awards 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-the-beast-new-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-the-beast-received-a-new-trailer-at-the-games-awards-2024.1060155/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-the-beast-new-trailer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-73758">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Dying Light: The Beast received a new gameplay trailer at The Game Awards 2024. No concrete date has been announced, just a window for the summer of 2025.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Dying Light: The Beast — MEET THE BARON - THE GAME AWARDS 2024 TRAILER" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8Tkwem4M1uw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The game serves as a spin-off from Techland’s popular zombie franchise. Check out the synopsis:</p>



<p>“<em>After 13 years of enduring experiments, you escape and hunt down your captors to seek retribution, only to discover there’s far more at stake. While the region is not as populated as it once was, there are still people and factions here, as well as plenty of horrors. Some will ask for your help, others will want to kill you. And that’s not to mention the mysterious creature that’s turned the woods into its personal hunting grounds.</em>“</p>



<p>The adventure stars Kyle Crane, an individual who saved several people when the virus spread across the world. However, after several years in captivity and undergoing various experiments, Kyle’s DNA has completely fused with zombie DNA, allowing him to transform into a beast. That’s where the game’s subtitle comes from.</p>



<p>The game is structured with an open world and we’ll have various types of landscapes such as forests, industrial complexes and small villages. It will be possible to play alone or in co-op for up to 4 people and, yes, the mechanics of day and night will be present.</p>



<p>Are you going to play Dying Light: The Beast? Tell us in the comments and take part in the discussion on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">our forum</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-release-date/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-release-date/">The First Berserker: Khazan arrives in March</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>During The Game Awards 2024, The First Berserker: Khazan got a new trailer that confirms this week’s leak.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-onimusha-capcom/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-onimusha-capcom/">Capcom Reveals New Onimusha Game at The Game Awards</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new game in the Onimusha franchise has been announced. The latest title in the saga, the remaster of Onimusha: Warlords, was released in October 2018.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-virtua-fighter-game-revealed-at-game-awards/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-virtua-fighter-game-revealed-at-game-awards/">New Virtua Fighter Game Revealed at The Game Awards 2024</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The first brand new Virtua Fighter title in over a decade was officially announced at The Game Awards.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-feybreak-trailer-revealed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-feybreak-trailer-revealed/">Palworld: Feybreak Trailer Unveiled at The Game Awards</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Palworld: Feybreak has been revealed at The Game Awards, and it’s set to drop on December 23 on all platforms.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeon & Fighter: ARAD debut trailer, details, and screenshots]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/dungeon-fighter-arad-debut-trailer-details-and-screenshots</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeon-fighter-arad-debut-trailer-details-and-screenshots.1060149/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/dungeon-fighter-arad-debut-trailer-details-and-screenshots<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Open-world action adventure RPG from Nexon.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Nexon [121 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nexon">Nexon</a> has released the first trailer, information, and screenshots for <em><a title="Games > Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dungeon-fighter-arad">Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD</a></em>, its <a title="Genres > Open-World [532 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> action <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,946 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> <a title="Genres > RPG [16,865 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> for console, <a title="Platforms > PC [21,954 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, and mobile. <span id="more-933974"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p><em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD</em> is a brand new title developed by <a title="Companies > Nexon Games [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nexon/nexon-games">Nexon Games</a> and published by Nexon Korea for PC, mobile, and console. This open world action-adventure RPG utilizes the <em><a title="Series > Dungeon &amp; Fighter [52 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/dungeon-fighter">Dungeon &amp; Fighter</a></em> intellectual property, which boasts over 850 million players worldwide, and expands upon the Dungeon &amp; Fighter universe with an appealing new narrative never before seen in the series. <em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD</em> features action packed combat, engaging characters and a stunning open world filled with monsters and puzzles for players to experience, all backed by the powerful Unreal Engine 5.</p><p><em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD</em> features a variety of content, including:</p><ul><li><strong><a title="Genres > Action [2,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> Packed Combat</strong> – <em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD</em> features distinct classes each with their own diverse combat techniques that are unique to Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD, while still drawing inspiration from the action-packed combat that DNF fans know and love.</li><li><strong>Engaging Characters</strong> – Players will interact with characters that have their own distinct stories, intricately and realistically portrayed with rich, robust personalities and visually captivating designs.</li><li><strong>Stunning Open World</strong> – <em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD</em> boasts an expansive open world filled with stunning visuals, high quality graphics and a vibrant atmosphere, all powered by the dynamic Unreal Engine 5.</li><li><strong>And So Much More!</strong> – With a wide variety of field monsters and puzzles featured throughout the massive world of <em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD</em>, players will have plenty to explore as they unravel a brand-new story in the <em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter</em>&nbsp;universe.</li></ul><p>In addition, <em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD</em> will make an appearance on large-scale advertisements placed around the Peacock Theater during The Game Awards ceremony. The advertisement features iconic logos from the history of the <em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter</em> Universe with new images and the trailer from the <em>Dungeon &amp; Fighter: ARAD</em>.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch the trailer below. View the screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/dungeon-fighter-arad/december-12-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="『Dungeon&amp;Fighter: ARAD』 The First Trailer | The Game Awards 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LH6AM7mTkd8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_933985"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Onimusha: Way of the Sword announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.1060146/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in 2026.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Capcom [2,548 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Onimusha: Way of the Sword" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/onimusha-way-of-the-sword">Onimusha: Way of the Sword</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,528 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,476 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,954 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (Steam). It will launch in 2026. <span id="more-933800"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://www.capcom-games.com/onimusha/ws/en-us/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">official website</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Fight through bloodbaths of intense swordplay <a title="Genres > Action [2,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>. Explore the historic Japanese capital of Edo-era Kyoto, twisted by malevolent clouds of <a title="Games > Malice" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/malice">Malice</a>. With every stage cloaked in mystery, danger and intrigue. Battle against monstrosities from the underworld known as Genma in a tale of dark fantasy. Follow the tale of a samurai who wields the Oni Gauntlet, a mystical artifact that grants its bearer the power to slay Genma. Through gritty, blood-soaked brawls, he searches for his reason to fight. What fate awaits at the end of his path?</p><p><strong>About the <em>Onimusha</em> Series</strong></p><p>Debuting in 2001, the first game in the <em>Onimusha</em> series tells the story of a young warrior during a time of widespread war in feudal Japan. Acquiring the power of the Oni, he becomes an <em>Onimusha</em> and battles against the evil Genma that are attempting to conquer of the world.<br><!-- AD: content -->
        </p>The game’s “Issen” critical counter action mechanic and satisfying swordplay action became defining pillars of the series.<p>With people and events inspired by real-life history cast into its eerie dark fantasy setting, the trials and fates of the characters painted a unique and engrossing tale that drew widespread acclaim.</p><p>Building on that success, the series has gone on to spawn numerous hit titles and even an original Netflix animation. To date the Onimusha series has sold over 8.7 million* units worldwide.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword/december-12-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Onimusha: Way of the Sword - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KOiJGLZDnFw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『鬼武者 Way of the Sword』 アナウンストレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/la0NtENnuf8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_933999"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Onimusha Way Of The Sword Coming In 2026, Reviving The Franchise After Nearly Two Decades]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-coming-in-2026-reviving-the-franchise-after-nearly-two-decades/1100-6528447/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-coming-in-2026-reviving-the-franchise-after-nearly-two-decades.1060140/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-coming-in-2026-reviving-the-franchise-after-nearly-two-decades/1100-6528447/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528447">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Revealed during <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2024-winners-revealed/2900-5956/" data-ref-id="2900-5956">The Game Awards,</a> Onimusha Way of the Sword is the first new entry in the series since 2006. Capcom revealed the game with a cinematic trailer and confirmed it's coming to Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC in 2026.</p><p>The trailer shows a bunch of red flames floating around in different feudal Japanese locations, before being absorbed by the protagonist. There are also a few moments of combat that appear to be in-game, showing off the third-person action against different supernatural monsters, like fungus-infected samurais and giant monsters. A few different big monsters are shown near the end of the trailer, including a large boar looking enemy walking around on two legs.</p><p>Onimusha is historically a hack-and-slash action series, using historical figures to retell parts of Japanese history, with a healthy dose of the supernatural injected, of course. Previous entries were set in the Sengoku period, but Capcom has revealed that Way of the Sword will be set in the early Edo period, taking place in Kyoto. The last mainline entry in the series was Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams in 2006, with only a mobile game and a remaster released since.</p><p>Check out our list of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-game-awards-2024-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6077/" data-ref-id="2900-6077">The Game Awards announcements</a> to see everything revealed during the award show.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overcooked developer unveils spooky "escape room style" co-op adventure Stage Fright]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/overcooked-developer-unveils-spooky-escape-room-style-co-op-adventure-stage-fright</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overcooked-developer-unveils-spooky-escape-room-style-co-op-adventure-stage-fright.1060137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/overcooked-developer-unveils-spooky-escape-room-style-co-op-adventure-stage-fright<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>No Man's Sky studio publishing.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/stage-fight-split-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ghost Town Games/Hello Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It's been six years since developer Ghost Town Games gave the world a sequel to its smash-hit culinary caper <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/overcooked">Overcooked</a>, so you might very well be wondering what it's been up in the time since. Well, all is now revealed, with Ghost Town having unveiled its brand-new co-op adventure Stage Fright - which is being published by <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/no-mans-sky">No Man's Sky</a> studio Hello Games.
</p>
<p>
Hello Games' announcement describes Stage Fright as a mix of "Overcooked style chaotic moments [and] escape room style cooperation" that's designed for two players. It's playable either as a classic couch co-op adventure or by teaming up online.
</p>
<p>
There's not much to share in the way of specific gameplay details, but we do known Stage Fright takes place in a "magical and spooky" setting - "think <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/luigis-mansion">Luigi's Mansion</a> meets Overcooked" - and that it promises a "really charming story" that's "touching, with a real heart".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Stage Fright Announcement Trailer (The Game Awards 2024)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T_i0xhr4utk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Stage Fright Announcement Trailer (The Game Awards 2024)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T_i0xhr4utk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/T_i0xhr4utk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Stage Fright teaser trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T_i0xhr4utk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"The codename of Stage Fright was Project Attic," Hello Games continues, "because [Ghost Town members] Phil, Oli, and Gemma have been in the attic at the top of their house working on this new game for the last five years, joined by a small team of talented contributors... They have so many stories of the joy Overcooked has brought to families and partners and friends (as well as near divorces). They really want to create more of those moments."
</p><p>
Hello Games says it'll be lending Ghost Town its behind the scenes experience and support as development continues. "But if we're honest," it adds, "it really appeals to us to have fun working with a bunch of creative people we just love spending time with." 
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/stage-fright-monster-chase-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Ghost Town Games/Hello Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
You can catch a few initial glimpses of Stage Fright in its <a href="https://youtu.be/T_i0xhr4utk">announcement trailer</a> above, but for more substantial information, you may have to wait a bit longer. Additional details are set to be shared by Ghost Town Games "over the next 12 months".
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Onimusha game in development from Capcom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/new-onimusha-game-in-development-from-capcom</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-onimusha-game-in-development-from-capcom.1060134/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/new-onimusha-game-in-development-from-capcom<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Capcom has revealed a new Onimusha game is in development.
</p>
<p>
Shown at tonight's The Game Awards, Onimusha: Way of the Sword is set to launch in 2026 - so there's quite a wait.
</p>
<p>
A short clip of gameplay was shown, which appears to eschew the Resident Evil-esque fixed perspectives of the first game for full 3D combat.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="『鬼武者 Way of the Sword』 アナウンストレーラー" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/la0NtENnuf8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>『鬼武者 Way of the Sword』 アナウンストレーラー</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/la0NtENnuf8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/la0NtENnuf8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Onimusha: Way of the Sword reveal trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=la0NtENnuf8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>
As for the story, it's unclear who the protagonist will be, though he does bear a resemblance to the first game's Samanosuke.
</p>
<p>
Still, there's a good glimpse at some bloody slicing and dicing, as he battles samurai zombies and collects those precious golden orbs. I just hope it can stand apart from the likes of Sekiro, Phantom Blade Zero, and the Nioh games.
</p>
<p>
The first Onimusha game was released on the PS2 in 2001, which was remastered in 2018 for Switch, PS4, and Xbox One (with a PC release a year later). 
</p>
<p>
That was the last release in the series, while the last new console game was Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams in 2006. It's been a long wait for fans, then.
</p>
<p>
Still, will Capcom appease fans with a return to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dino-crisis">Dino Crisis</a> next?
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s finally happening! We’re getting a new Virtua Fighter!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/13/its-finally-happening-were-getting-a-new-virtua-fighter/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it%E2%80%99s-finally-happening-we%E2%80%99re-getting-a-new-virtua-fighter.1060119/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/13/its-finally-happening-were-getting-a-new-virtua-fighter/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Is it me, or is The Game Awards really good this year? It’s made all the better because one of the key announcements was the upcoming arrival of a brand new entry in the Virtua Fighter series. Seriously, if you lived on the Sega side of the street, you never needed to bother with Tekken, because Virtua Fighter was – to my mind anyway – vastly superior. The fact that it’s going to go up against the fantastic Tekken 8 means that 3D-fighting fans are really eating well right now.</p>
<p><iframe title="NEW VIRTUA FIGHTER Project | World Premiere Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pmeGL2JP9N0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The teaser trailer was a particularly teasy trailer, as it only gave us a few details. First amongst them was that once again it’s the Ryu Ga Gotoku studio that’s working on this new entry in the Virtua Fighter series. You might know them as the team behind the huge Yakuza/Like A Dragon series, and given that Yakuza’s own combat was a hand-me-down from Shenmue, which in turn fed from Virtua Fighter, made them the perfect team to take the series’ reins.</p>
<p>Thus far, we’ve only seen Akira and Sarah Bryant going at it in a sandy cityscape, with Akira sporting a new undercover look – that’s a fedora and trenchcoat if you were wondering – before then shifting perspective to point us towards an upcoming VF Direct where we’ll learn (hopefully) all the most important details.</p>
<p>Fans of the series – myself included – have been waiting patiently ever since the original launch of Virtua Fighter 5. While it leapt through the past couple of generations, and is still very playable on modern consoles, there’s little to no online community right now, so I’m hoping that with the new title coming a few more people will hop in so I can practice poking them with Lion’s silly pointy fingers.</p>

<p>The VF Direct will take place on December 13th at 12am ET. Stay tuned for more as we have it</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RGG reveal Project Century – Like a Dragon goes back to 1915]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/13/rgg-reveal-project-century-like-a-dragon-goes-back-to-1915/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rgg-reveal-project-century-%E2%80%93-like-a-dragon-goes-back-to-1915.1060116/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/13/rgg-reveal-project-century-like-a-dragon-goes-back-to-1915/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The first of two big and bold game reveals, Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio has revealed Project Century, which seems to be a Like a Dragon game that takes us back to 1915 Japan.</p>
<p><iframe title="Project Century Reveal Trailer The Game Awards 2024" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JanPitSWd94?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Project Century is set in a particularly interesting point in time, both as newer technologies like record players filter into society, but also as more and more morsels of Western culture could filter through to Japan.</p>
<p>Of course, you know what was around back then? Gangs. Fisticuffs. Smoking. Looking cool.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turok: Origins Is an Upcoming Co-Op Game by Saber]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/turok-origins-is-an-upcoming-co-op-game-by-saber/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/turok-origins-is-an-upcoming-co-op-game-by-saber.1060113/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/turok-origins-is-an-upcoming-co-op-game-by-saber/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At The Game Awards 2024, Saber Interactive announced Turok: Origins, an upcoming co-op game based on the classic IP. In this title, players will become Turok warriors to face off against ferocious dinosaurs and a terrifying alien threat that seeks to destroy all humanity. However, they'll be powerful enough to take them on with devastating attacks powered by weapons and abilities. They may also harness fallen enemies' DNA to upgrade their arsenal.</p>
<p>In Turok: Origins, players will join the fight either alone or as a team against a variety of dinosaurs, creatures, and bosses that take to the ground, sky, swamps, and caves to push their skills to the limit. Engage in intense combat, where players must use everything at their disposal to ensure success, including melee attacks, special abilities, and fine-tuned weapons. Throughout the game, they'll unlock and upgrade advanced weaponry to dominate battles and neutralize foes. Plasma rifles, ray guns, snipers, bows, shotguns, and more are all at disposal.</p>
<p>As mentioned earlier, it will be possible to extract DNA from fallen enemies and the environment to unlock game-changing powers that evolve the Turoks' suit in real-time. Each DNA power not only enhances the character's look but also offers upgradable skills and abilities to give the players an edge in combat.</p>
<p>In the game's missions, players journey across deadly worlds on various planets. From ancient temples and wasteland canyons to dense jungles, each location is said to hold pieces of an unforgettable story packed with twists and turns.</p>
<p><iframe title="Turok: Origins - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x1ELi_UslrA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Turok: Origins doesn't have a release window, but you can add it to your <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1967610/Turok_Origins/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> wishlist right now.</p>

			
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>