<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 21:30:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hogwarts Legacy Expansion Reportedly Canceled]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hogwarts-legacy-harry-potter-dlc-definitive-edition-1851772868</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hogwarts-legacy-expansion-reportedly-canceled.1147224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/hogwarts-legacy-harry-potter-dlc-definitive-edition-1851772868<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="21700121ca93e9e8ff93267db216feda" data-recommend-id="image://21700121ca93e9e8ff93267db216feda" data-format="jpg" data-width="1340" data-height="753" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A wizard stares out at a castle. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A wizard stares out at a castle. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Avalanche Software</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="21700121ca93e9e8ff93267db216feda" data-recommend-id="image://21700121ca93e9e8ff93267db216feda" data-format="jpg" data-width="1340" data-height="753" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A wizard stares out at a castle. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>A new story expansion for <em>Hogwarts Legacy</em> was supposed to arrive later this year, but the content has been canceled according to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-03-27/warner-bros-cancels-planned-hogwarts-legacy-game-expansion?sref=P6Q0mxvj&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-03-27/warner-bros-cancels-planned-hogwarts-legacy-game-expansion?sref=P6Q0mxvj" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a new report by <em>Bloomberg</em></a></span>. The change in plans comes amidst continued fallout at Warner Bros. Games after recent sales flops and studio closures. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196358" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: December 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="359" data-playlist="196358,196013,196653" data-current="196358"><div><p>The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: December 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196358/196358_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196358/196358_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196358/196358_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196358/196358_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21905.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The new content would have <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hogwarts-legacy-review-harry-potter-rowling-transphobia-1850127849?_gl=1*1y7plr8*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MzEwMzg0Ny41MS4xLjE3NDMxMDgyNjEuMTYuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hogwarts-legacy-review-harry-potter-rowling-transphobia-1850127849?_gl=1*1y7plr8*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MzEwMzg0Ny41MS4xLjE3NDMxMDgyNjEuMTYuMC4w">apparently added more storylines to the open-world wizarding RPG</a></span>, including ones that had originally been cut during development. The expansion would have been bundled as part of a new definitive edition of <em>Hogwarts Legacy</em>; however, Warner Bros. leadership recently abandoned the idea after determining it wouldn’t be enough to justify the price tag to new and returning players. </p><p>The <em>Harry Potter</em> adventure has sold over 34 million copies and a director’s cut release seemed like it might be one of the few bright spots for Warner Bros. Games this year <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monolith-productions-wonder-woman-multiversus-cancel-wb-1851766400?_gl=1*16e4sbs*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MzEwNTU5Ni40MC4xLjE3NDMxMDY3MTMuNTcuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monolith-productions-wonder-woman-multiversus-cancel-wb-1851766400?_gl=1*16e4sbs*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MzEwNTU5Ni40MC4xLjE3NDMxMDY3MTMuNTcuMC4w">after it recently killed Monolith Productions</a></span>, which was working on a Wonder Woman game, alongside two other studios including the team behind <em>MultiVersus</em>. </p><p>Avalanche Software was working on the expansion with Rocksteady Studios, which ended support on 2024's failed <em>Suicide Squad </em>live-service venture. It’s now also currently early in development on a new Batman game, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-02-07/warner-bros-video-game-division-faces-thin-slate-wonder-woman-issues?sref=P6Q0mxvj&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-02-07/warner-bros-video-game-division-faces-thin-slate-wonder-woman-issues?sref=P6Q0mxvj" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bloomberg</em></a></span> previously reported. The Arkham series has been on ice for almost a decade outside of last year’s <em>Batman: Arkham Shadow</em> for Oculus VR. </p><p>Warner Bros. Games is currently in the midst of a leadership change and interim boss JB Perrette told staff that the publisher group needed to regain its “credibility and swagger at producing great games.” Part of that strategy will revolve around doubling down on franchises like <em>Harry Potter</em> and <em>Game of Thrones</em>. WB currently has a<em> Harry Potter </em>reboot TV show in production for HBO, and <em>Hogwarts Legacy 2</em> has already been announced as well.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warzone Season 3 Returns to Verdansk With New Movement Changes]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-season-3-returns-to-verdansk-with-new-movement-changes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warzone-season-3-returns-to-verdansk-with-new-movement-changes.1147221/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-season-3-returns-to-verdansk-with-new-movement-changes/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Call of Duty: Warzone Season 3 takes players back home with the return of Verdansk, adding new movement adjustments, original game modes, weapons and more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-warzone-season-3-verdansk-details">Warzone Season 3 Verdansk Details</h2>



<p>With the return of the popular battle royale map, the developers are adopting a back-to-basics approach. The map will now feature 150 players, and the original announcer is returning. Players will be able to shoot during freefall and should expect new infill and exfil cinematics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, with Verdansk, we see the return of the original supply box colours, floating loot, and the original armour satchel. Moreover, the original bus station inventory and the original buy station placement will be returned, too. Furthermore, the Original Armor Box, Deployable Cover, Heartbeat Sensor, Ammunition Box, Recon Drone, and Trophy System will also return.&nbsp;</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<h2 id="h-warzone-season-3-movement-adjustments">Warzone Season 3 Movement Adjustments</h2>



<p>Warzone Season 3 makes movement adjustments while keeping omnimovement as the foundation. Originally, the battle royale mode adopted the movement from the multilayer mode; however, the developers have realised that new adjustments are needed to make the gameplay more engaging.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With season 3, the player movement speed will be scaled back. These adjustments will help players experience Warzone more in line with its early days. Moreover, the devs are changing omni-sprint speed scaling and slide friction to address the strength of strafe engagements while preserving the feel of sprint-strafe reloading and general movement.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-warzone-season-3-killstreaks-contracts-and-events">Warzone Season 3 Killstreaks, Contracts and Events</h2>



<p>Keeping the theme of bringing the originals back, Warzone Season 3 will see the return of Original Cluster (Mortar) Strike, Precision Airstrike, and UAV. Moreover, Contracts such as Original Bounty, Most Wanted, and Scavenger Contracts will reappear too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Coming to events, players should expect the Original Fire Sale, Jail Break, Loadout Drop, and Restock events along with the Original Capture the Flag Gulag Variant.&nbsp;</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<h2 id="h-warzone-season-3-returning-maps-and-modes">Warzone Season 3 Returning Maps and Modes</h2>



<p>Along with Verdansk, players will see the return of another fan-favourite resurgence mode, Rebirth Island. Moreover, the following modes are returning for Verdansk: Battle Royale, Plunder Quads, and Call of Duty: Warzone Bootcamp. There are also some new modes to look out for:&nbsp; Battle Royale Ranked Play and Battle Royale Casual. More game modes will be released mid-season.</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<h2 id="h-warzone-season-3-weapons-and-attachments">Warzone Season 3 Weapons and Attachments</h2>



<p>Warzone Season 3 will feature a bunch of new and returning weapons. The Kilo 141 is being offered as a login reward. Check out all the upcoming weapons and attachments below.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-weapons">Weapons</h3>



<ul>
<li>Kilo 141 (Primary Weapon)</li>



<li>CR-56 AMAX (Primary Weapon)</li>



<li>HDR (Primary Weapon)</li>



<li>Kali Sticks (Melee Weapon)</li>



<li>Ladra (Primary Weapon)</li>



<li>Nail Gun (Special Weapon)</li>
</ul>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<h3 id="h-attachments">Attachments</h3>



<ul>
<li>Monolithic Suppressor</li>



<li>SWAT 5.56 Grau Conversion</li>



<li>C9 10mm Auto 30-Round Mags</li>



<li>Goblin Mk2 7.62 Mini-Rocket Conversion</li>
</ul>



<figure></figure>



<p>Interested players can check out the new events, battle pass and black cell details <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2025/03/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-warzone-zombies-season-three-critical-launch-announcement#Weapons" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>. Also, check out the latest content for Black Ops 6 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-3-introduces-new-multiplayer-maps-modes-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">multiplayer</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-zombies-unveils-shattered-veils-map-and-new-enemies-for-season-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Zombies</a> modes in Season 3. What are your thoughts on all the original content returning for Warzone Season 3? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-is-forming-a-new-subsidiary-with-tencent-valued-at-4-3-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft forming a new gaming subsidiary with Tencent</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unannounced Hogwarts Legacy Paid DLC Reportedly Canceled by WB]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/unannounced-hogwarts-legacy-paid-dlc-reportedly-canceled-by-wb</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/unannounced-hogwarts-legacy-paid-dlc-reportedly-canceled-by-wb.1147215/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/unannounced-hogwarts-legacy-paid-dlc-reportedly-canceled-by-wb<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">An unannounced paid DLC for Hogwarts Legacy has been canceled, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-03-27/warner-bros-cancels-planned-hogwarts-legacy-game-expansion" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">according to a Bloomberg report</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Per Bloomberg's sources, Warner Bros. was planning a paid story expansion to its Harry Potter adventure game, Hogwarts Legacy, that would have released this year alongside a "Definitive Edition" of the game. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">However, WB canceled the DLC this week, allegedly due to concerns that "the amount of content was not substantial enough to justify the price being considered," per Bloomberg. WB declined Bloomberg's request for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Warner Bros. has been actively restructuring its gaming division amidst ongoing financial struggles. Earlier this year, it <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warner-bros-cancels-wonder-woman-game-closes-three-studios">canceled its planned Wonder Woman game</a> and closed down the studio making it, Monolith Productions, alongside WB San Diego and MultiVersus studio Player First Games. WB also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rocksteady-reportedly-lays-off-staff-following-suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-flop">laid off employees at Rocksteady just last September</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite this cancelation, WB has stated repeatedly that Hogwarts Legacy and Harry Potter in general are among its most important assets, having said that a sequel to the game is "<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/harry-potter-video-game-sequel-hogwarts-legacy-2-one-of-the-biggest-priorities-at-warner-bros">one of the biggest priorities</a>" at the company as it focuses on fewer and bigger franchises. The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hogwarts-legacy-2-coordinating-big-picture-storytelling-with-harry-potter-tv-show-storylines">first game has sold over 30 million copies</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hunt: Showdown Needs To Be Easier, But Not Easy, Dev Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hunt-showdown-dev-needs-to-be-easier-but-not-easy-dev-says/1100-6530442/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hunt-showdown-needs-to-be-easier-but-not-easy-dev-says.1147212/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hunt-showdown-dev-needs-to-be-easier-but-not-easy-dev-says/1100-6530442/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530442">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/hunt-showdown/" data-ref-id="5000-283965">Hunt: Showdown</a> takes the title of the game I enjoy the most despite being bad at it. Like most people probably do, at a certain point, I'll drop a game from my life if the losing streaks are piling up too much and it's not feeling fun anymore. I don't win much in the horror-western extraction shooter, but I still play it a lot anyway because I find it alluring in other ways; the audio design is as immersive and instructive as any game I know; the artwork, especially its character design, is diverse and captivating. It's a no-holds-barred PvPvE game that I often play, even when I've come to expect failure.</p><p>As the game kicks off its latest event, <a href="https://www.huntshowdown.com/news/garden-of-the-witch-live-now" rel="nofollow ">Garden of the Witch</a>, during its ongoing seventh-anniversary celebration, I recently caught up with a few folks from the Hunt: Showdown team at Crytek. This difficulty ramp was top of mind for me, but we touched on some other subjects too, like that aforementioned audio design being integral to the Hunt experience, and whether we might see Hunt: Showdown in other media, like movies or TV, someday. (Hint: It seems likely.)</p><p>You can find our full chat below, including thoughts on how the team hopes to make Hunt's learning curve a bit more manageable without losing its signature ruthlessness.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>GameSpot: Hunt: Showdown recently celebrated its seventh anniversary. What have been some of the game's biggest milestones or moments through the years?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Dennis Schwarz, Design Director</strong>: Some of the biggest moments for the game have definitely been within the events that we’ve run. One of the first in 2021 was ‘As the Crow Flies.’ This was the first event where the community had to work to unlock Scrapbeak. This event was beloved by both the community and the development team, and we’ve built from there.</p><p dir="ltr">Another moment that stands out is when we broke our [concurrent users] record in 2023 with the release of Rotjaw during ‘Tide of Shadows.’ It was a great moment for us to see that there was so much excitement around a new boss/Wild Target and also to see this in the CCU record being broken was an amazing moment for the team!</p><p dir="ltr">Of course, more recently, we also broke this record once again with the release of Hunt: Showdown 1896. This was easily one of the most pivotal moments for us as we launched CRYENGINE 5.11, the new map Mammon’s Gulch, and a host of other changes. While that release didn’t go without some hiccups, the reception we got around Mammon’s Gulch was unmatched and something we are still very proud of.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Hunt's audiovisual experience is clearly a focal point for the team. When I play, it feels like everything is so intentionally placed and important to both the setting and surviving in it, and the audio is so instructive. Can you talk about the process of finding and expanding on Hunt's specific style over the years?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Schwarz</strong>: We defined audio as one of the main pillars for our gameplay early on and started prototyping how sound would help support our core concept of “hunting” through gunfire broadcasting across the entire map and animals being startled in the distance. Our testers quickly started building up these mental maps of what was going on in a match based on the sounds they heard and how this affected their planning on where to go or what to avoid.</p><p dir="ltr">While we have certain supernatural elements in the game, Hunt is generally a grounded game defined by its clunky weapons and limits of the technology of the era. Every move you make produces a sound that risks giving away your position. By embracing this, we managed to focus on a very unique soundscape where creaking wooden boards, shattered glass on the ground or some hanging chains with a bucket could easily spell doom, if you are not careful.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>A live-service game often changes based on player feedback. How has the Hunt community helped reshape the game over all these years?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Schwarz</strong>: Definitely--community feedback is a huge driver for us. One of the main ways we do this is via event surveys this can give us real data-driven insight as to what people like or didn’t like, what they want to see more of, etc. We also pay extremely close attention to our key player hubs online like Reddit, Steam, Discord, and so on.</p><p dir="ltr">With this update, we have implemented changes, especially to game balance. We heard from the community that some weapons/ammo types were unbalanced or changed the game in ways with which they were not satisfied, so we have stripped back some of the choices that led to those complaints. We have many more improvements coming to the game throughout the year, such as UI changes, which are at the forefront of the community’s mind.</p><p dir="ltr">Another good example was the crosshair, which we implemented with our 2.0 update. Since the beginning of Hunt, the crosshair was always lowered. Some players really liked this about the game, but others were vocal about it changing. We changed this in the update to give players the option of having a centered one or a lowered one.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Are there any aspects of the game the community has been vocal about changing, but Crytek finds them integral and non-negotiable to Hunt's identity? Surely the community for any game isn't </strong><em><strong>always</strong></em><strong> right, yeah?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Schwarz</strong>: There are some things which we have implemented from community feedback but put our own twist on it to make sure gameplay and the community's feedback were balanced.</p><p dir="ltr">For example, we had a lot of requests from the community to put a “Roaming Boss” in the game since Early Access, but this concept never quite worked with the Compound Arena style of boss fights in Hunt. The compromise we came up with was Wild Targets, which spawn outside certain compounds but don’t quite “roam,” and this was seen first with the release of Rotjaw.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Hunt has changed shape a lot, especially in the 1896 update last year. How satisfied are you with the game's onboarding of new players right now? I find the game extremely unforgiving, but I also love it for that. But maybe some are turned away by this. Do you feel the game is very hard, and if so, is that a "bug" or a feature? If you are still addressing that, how might players expect to see it change in the future?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Schwarz</strong>: Onboarding is a very important topic for us. We realize that while many players fall in love with the game exactly for how unforgiving it can be at times, there is a very hard and sometimes frustrating journey ahead for many before they reach that point or quit before.</p><p dir="ltr">Moving forward, we expect to have further improvements here to better ease new players into the game step-by-step. Hunt, in its core, is a hard game. We feel this is what makes it appealing for many and honestly, is expected of us by our community. That doesn’t mean we cannot make becoming a Veteran Hunter a far smoother and more enjoyable experience, however.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>There are a lot more extraction shooters today than there were in 2018 when Hunt began, and live-service games are always competing with other live-service games outside of their own genre, too. How does the team look at the challenge of staying successful well into the future in such a competitive space?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Schwarz</strong>: We are confident in our core gameplay loop and the overall gameplay experience Hunt offers through its unique setting and features. The aesthetic and world of Hunt is unlike anything else on the market--and when you begin to add in our unique approach to sound and music with elements like Port Sulphur Band, our dedicated in-game band, we offer a distinctive package.</p><p dir="ltr">There are a number of really interesting games on the horizon of course, but we are confident about our strengths and what sets us apart and continue to embrace that to move Hunt forward in the right direction.</p><p dir="ltr">Of course, sometimes that also means pausing for a moment, reflecting on the past updates and doing corrections where needed. We are not perfect, but we are lucky to have such a dedicated community that give us tons of excellent feedback on how they envision the game to be and help correct where we might oversteer. After all, this longstanding relationship with our players is what has helped keep us focused year after year.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>The Garden of the Witch event kicks off today and revamps the weekly challenge system. What went into the decision to change those and how will they alter how players approach the game?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Sam Tunnel, Game Designer</strong>: The rationale behind the decision to revamp the weekly challenge system was to make the games more varied. We got feedback that the same weapons and ammo types were being used every week to complete the challenges and in some weeks there would be half the teams in the match using the same items as they all had the same challenges. By changing this up by giving players different weekly challenges every week it now means that players will have more varied games and teams won’t be incentivized to use the same items.</p><p dir="ltr">In terms of how this will affect players’ approach to games, players can still work together to complete challenges, as many of them are open-ended and complimentary (i.e. Player X will have a challenge for “Deal damage with rifles” and Player Y has a challenge for “Deal damage with Frontier 73C”). It’ll require a little more coordination and ensure that players should encounter less instances of the same items in their games.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>This event also adds more to the story that's always underlying every action in Hunt. Live-service storytelling is an interesting, relatively new facet of games. How much weight does the team give to its overarching mythology? Could we see the Hunt storyline come to other media, such as a movie, TV series, or comic book?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Nicollette Kyle Stewart, Lead Narrative Designer</strong>: A live-service game gives us really unique storytelling opportunities, and it’s something we will continue to experiment with. Storytelling is the lifeblood of any fiction world, and a game’s depth, immersion, and believability all live and die by its worldbuilding. Everything we put in the game--whether Hunter, weapon, or location--unwinds another thread of the bigger story. You can read up on a lot of the archival Hunt lore on our website Mythos, and that’s just the tip of the iceberg.</p><p dir="ltr">As for exploring storytelling media outside of the game, we’ve already had great success utilizing our music in this way. Port Sulphur Band--who are both an in-game story element and a real-life band made up of Crytek developers--release a new single for every event, and every song tells another story from the Hunt universe.</p><p dir="ltr">We’re not ready to share details of other upcoming projects, but Hunt’s world and mythos has incredible storytelling potential, and you can be certain there will be more to come.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft’s $4 billion carveout sells Tencent a 25 percent stake in some of its biggest games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/637775/ubisoft-tencent-carveout-assassins-creed-far-cry-tom-clancy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft%E2%80%99s-4-billion-carveout-sells-tencent-a-25-percent-stake-in-some-of-its-biggest-games.1147188/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/637775/ubisoft-tencent-carveout-assassins-creed-far-cry-tom-clancy<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/emma-roth">Emma Roth</a> <span>is a news writer who covers the streaming wars, consumer tech, crypto, social media, and much more. Previously, she was a writer and editor at MUO.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Ubisoft is spinning off <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>, <em>Far Cry</em>, and <em>Tom Clancy’s Rainbow Six</em> into a subsidiary backed by Tencent, according to <a href="https://staticctf.ubisoft.com/8aefmxkxpxwl/1uPFqvuRRej3UoemTIgVLH/18f1d055777e1b39a3f79a951452b9e1/2025.03.27_-_Press_Release_vfinal.pdf">an announcement on Thursday</a>. The Chinese gaming giant will invest €1.16 billion (~$1.3 billion) for a 25 percent stake in the carveout, which will have a total value of about €4 billion (~$4.3 billion).</p><p>Ubisoft says the new entity will include the teams working on all three franchises, along with the publisher’s back catalog of games and new titles currently in development. It will work to improve the “quality of narrative solo experiences,” as well as “expand multiplayer offerings with increased frequency of content release.”</p><p>Last year, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-10-04/tencent-guillemot-family-are-said-to-consider-buyout-of-ubisoft"><em>Bloomberg</em> reported</a> that Tencent, which currently has a 10 percent stake in Ubisoft, was considering a buyout of the French game publisher. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24264469/ubisoft-tencent-buyout-rumors-statement">Ubisoft responded</a> by saying it “regularly reviews all its strategic options.” The deal is expected to close this year.</p><p>“With the creation of a dedicated subsidiary that will spearhead development for three of our largest franchises and the onboarding of Tencent as a minority investor, we are crystalizing the value of our assets, strengthening our balance sheet, and creating the best conditions for these franchises’ long-term growth and success,” Ubisoft co-founder and CEO Yves Guillemot, says in the press release.</p><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/631744/assassins-creed-shadows-review-ubisoft">Ubisoft released <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em></a> last week, which the <a href="https://x.com/assassinscreed">publisher says</a> has reached over 3 million players and had the second highest day one sales revenue in the franchise.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Soon Venom Will Be Twerking His Juicy Cheeks All Over Marvel Rivals]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-twerk-emote-ass-venom-april-fools-free-1851772825</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/soon-venom-will-be-twerking-his-juicy-cheeks-all-over-marvel-rivals.1147176/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-twerk-emote-ass-venom-april-fools-free-1851772825<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="17e92fa6857e7532c8d8c14dad865826" data-recommend-id="image://17e92fa6857e7532c8d8c14dad865826" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Venom twerking in Marvel Rivals. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="17e92fa6857e7532c8d8c14dad865826" data-recommend-id="image://17e92fa6857e7532c8d8c14dad865826" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Venom twerking in Marvel Rivals. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Free-to-play juggernaut <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975"><em>Marvel Rivals</em></a></span> is getting a twerking Venom emote just in time for April Fool’s Day. And yes, this is real.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196013" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: October 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="316" data-playlist="196013,196646,195410" data-current="196013"><div><p>The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: October 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196013/196013_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196013/196013_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196013/196013_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196013/196013_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21533.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Since it arrived on the scene last year, <em>Marvel Rivals</em> from NetEase has been a massive hit across console and PC, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-netease-game-director-layoffs-season-2-1851765290&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-netease-game-director-layoffs-season-2-1851765290">though all that success didn’t stop the publisher from laying people off in February</a></span>. And since release, <em>Rivals </em>has added more characters, costumes, and modes. Now, the Marvel-themed third-person hero shooter is getting something very different: An emote that will let deadly symbiote baddie Venom throw it back and bounce that ass. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.marvelrivals.com/gameupdate/20250325/41548_1222027.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.marvelrivals.com/gameupdate/20250325/41548_1222027.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On March 26, <em>Marvel Rivals</em> shared a preview</a></span> of a new small update coming to the game, along with a teaser for a free, limited-time April Fool’s Day gift for players.<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://r.res.easebar.com/pic/20250325/d2dd093c-f59a-4cfc-a4be-64c3c4c867a9.jpg&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://r.res.easebar.com/pic/20250325/d2dd093c-f59a-4cfc-a4be-64c3c4c867a9.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">  In the image shared online by NetEase</a></span> we can see what appears to be an image of Venom twerking. And while officially NetEase hasn’t confirmed this emote to be the gift, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/RivalsLeaks/status/1905189968739197059&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/RivalsLeaks/status/1905189968739197059" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dataminers and leakers have begun sharing footage</a></span> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/RivalsInfo/status/1905191131375153486?&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/RivalsInfo/status/1905191131375153486?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">of Venom throwing it back</a></span> after the latest <em>Rivals</em> update went live on Thursday. </p><p>Yes, this might look like a mod or a fan-created AI video or something like that, but that’s not the case. That is, in fact, Venom from the video game <em>Marvel Rivals</em>,<em>&nbsp;</em>twerking. Since the game launched people have created memes about and fixated on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.dexerto.com/gaming/marvel-rivals-venom-winter-skin-caked-up-3010038/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.dexerto.com/gaming/marvel-rivals-venom-winter-skin-caked-up-3010038/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Venom and how big and juicy his ass is in game</a></span>. So it only makes sense that NetEase would give the fans what they want and let Venom drop it and pop it. As for why Venom is orange in the video above, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/MarvelRivals/status/1905077649191628883&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/MarvelRivals/status/1905077649191628883" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">that’s a new bonus skin included in a paid mini-battle pass available now in the game.</a></span></p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.marvelrivals.com/gameupdate/20250325/41548_1222027.html#:~:text=Galacta%27s%20Cosmic%20Adventure,hidden%20twist%20surprise.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.marvelrivals.com/gameupdate/20250325/41548_1222027.html#:~:text=Galacta%27s%20Cosmic%20Adventure,hidden%20twist%20surprise." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">To unlock this special gift</a></span> you’ll need to finish enough challenges to unlock enough dice rolls to completely unlock the current Galatica’s Cosmic Adventure board. While that will take some time and some grinding, the board and the emote are free for all players. Everyone gets a chance to drop it and bounce around. </p><p>You’ll only be able to unlock and earn this <em>Marvel Rivals </em>twerking emote between April 1 and 4, so don’t wait around too long or you’ll miss out on this incredible emote. And that would be a real shame. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Black Ops 6 Introduces "John Black Ops" As Free Operator Skin]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-introduces-john-black-ops-as-free-operator-skin/1100-6530443/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-black-ops-6-introduces-john-black-ops-as-free-operator-skin.1147170/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-introduces-john-black-ops-as-free-operator-skin/1100-6530443/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530443">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-3-expected-start-date-og-style-rumors-and-leaks-so-far/1100-6529766/">Call of Duty Season 3</a> arrives in Black Ops 6 on April 2, bringing new multiplayer and Zombies content. There's also an upcoming Black Ops Tribute event that lets you unlock a new operator skin hilariously called John Black Ops. Here's how you can get this new free operator skin for Black Ops 6.</p><p dir="ltr">Treyarch is paying tribute to the Black Ops series with a new event that launches next month. The Black Ops Tribute event runs from April 17 to May 1, and it includes 17 rewards themed around the series.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4466846-bo6-season-03-announcement-047b.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4466846" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4466846-bo6-season-03-announcement-047b.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4466846"></a><figcaption>John Black Ops operator skin</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4466846-bo6-season-03-announcement-047b.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">One of these event rewards is an operator skin for someone who is mysteriously dressed in an all-gray jumpsuit with tactical goggles and a helmet, as seen in the image above. This operator is simply named John Black Ops, and Activision describes this new character as "Anonymous. Unassuming. Deadly."</p><p dir="ltr">The Black Ops Tribute event is one of Call of Duty's XP-based events, so you'll just need to play and grind XP in order to unlock John and all the other rewards. This XP can be earned by playing any modes across multiplayer, Zombies, and Warzone.</p><p dir="ltr">For more news, make sure to check out all of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-black-ops-6-season-3-adds-iconic-mp-map-new-zombies-plus-jay-and-silent-bob/2900-6380/#1">highlights for Season 3 of Black Ops 6</a>, which showcase the new Shattered Veil Zombies map, new multiplayer maps, and Jay and Silent Bob operator bundles. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-warzone-season-3-roadmap-highlights-verdansk-event-omnimovement-changes-and-bots/2900-6375/">Warzone's Season 3 content is showcased here</a>, including the classic features and vehicles returning with Verdansk. </p><p dir="ltr">Verdansk was rebuilt from the ground up with new technology, and Activision's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-warzone-heres-what-verdansk-looks-like-for-season-3/2900-6376/" data-ref-id="2900-6376">side-by-side comparison of Verdansk's map changes</a> can be viewed in the images below. The battle royale recently celebrated its 5-year anniversary, so we spent some time <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-warzone-a-look-back-on-the-battle-royales-evolution/1100-6530385/">reminiscing on Warzone's evolution and talking with some of the developers</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Hope For System Shock 3 Isn't Lost Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-hope-for-system-shock-3-isnt-lost-yet/1100-6530444/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-hope-for-system-shock-3-isnt-lost-yet.1147167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-hope-for-system-shock-3-isnt-lost-yet/1100-6530444/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530444">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>System Shock 3 has been in development hell since 2015, but Nightdive Studio is hoping to give fans some news about the game soon.</p><p>At GDC, Nightdive director of business development Larry Kuperman said that the situation surrounding System Shock 3 is complicated and that he didn't have any updates yet. "Not as yet, not as yet. I don’t know when it’s going to clarify, but it could potentially be within a year," he explained (via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/nightdive-offers-hopeful-update-on-system-shock-3s-future/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">VGC</a>). "It could be, or it could take longer. That said, what I can say is that we have visions of what we can do within what we control."</p><p>He also said that while System Shock 2's remaster is releasing soon, that doesn't mean that Nightdive won't do a remake. While it's unclear what the franchise's future holds after the release of the System Shock 2 remaster, he said that there were other actions the studio could take with both the first and second games. After all, a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/system-shock-tv-show-in-the-works/1100-6497025/" data-ref-id="1100-6497025">System Shock TV show</a> is currently in the works.</p><p>System Shock 3 was last in development over at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/system-shock-3s-future-remains-vague-as-otherside-/1100-6476246/" data-ref-id="1100-6476246">OtherSide</a>, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/system-shock-3-is-moving-forward-with-tencents-inv/1100-6477539/" data-ref-id="1100-6477539">Tencent took over</a> its development as well as the entire franchise in 2020. Nightdive still has the rights to the first two System Shock games.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/system-shock-2s-long-awaited-nightdive-studios-remaster-has-a-new-name/1100-6529509/" data-ref-id="1100-6529509">System Shock 2: 25th Anniversary Remaster</a> is set to launch for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S on June 26. It features newly enhanced character and weapon models, adjustable field of view, and widescreen support.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RoboCop: Rogue City Headlines PlayStation Plus Essentials Games For April]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/03/27/robocop-rogue-city-headlines-playstation-plus-essentials-games-for-april</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robocop-rogue-city-headlines-playstation-plus-essentials-games-for-april.1147161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/03/27/robocop-rogue-city-headlines-playstation-plus-essentials-games-for-april<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text" typeof="schema:Article"><p>PlayStation Plus Essentials subscribers can look forward to a fresh batch of&nbsp; "free" games hitting the service next month. Coincentedally, all three titles are based on popular TV/film franchises&nbsp;</p>

<p>Subscribers can add <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/robocop-rogue-city/serving-the-public-trust">RoboCop: Rogue City</a>, The Texas Chainsaw Massacre, and Digimon Story: Cyber Sleuth – Hacker’s Memory to their libraries beginning April 1. These titles will remain available until May 5.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CDxXIlX4hyw" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>RoboCop: Rogue City is a first-person shooter telling an original story between the events of <em>RoboCop 2 </em>and <em>RoboCop 3</em>. The Texas Chainsaw Massacre is an asymmetrical horror game that pits a team of survivors against a player-controlled Leatherface. Meanwhile, Hacker’s Memory is a follow-up to Digimon Story: Cyber Sleuth. This turn-based RPG stars a Digimon Tamer looking to clear his name for a crime he didn’t commit.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As a reminder, this is the last week to add the current Essentials offerings to your libraries if you haven’t already.&nbsp;<a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/dragon-age-the-veilguard/sticking-the-landing">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a>, Sonic Colors: Ultimate, and TMNT: The Cowabunga Collection remain available until March 31.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Magically Cozy Life-Sim Witchbrook Comes To Switch This Holiday]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/03/27/the-magically-cozy-life-sim-witchbrook-comes-to-switch-this-holiday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-magically-cozy-life-sim-witchbrook-comes-to-switch-this-holiday.1147155/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/03/27/the-magically-cozy-life-sim-witchbrook-comes-to-switch-this-holiday<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Since its announcement in 2017, we have been patiently waiting for Witchbrook, the next game from Chucklefish. You might recognize them as the developers known for Starbound and Wargroove, but they also published big indie hits like Stardew Valley, giving us plenty of reasons to be excited. Luckily, the latest Nintendo Direct not only gave us a fresh look at the magically collegiate adventure but also gave us a launch window: holiday 2025.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZWDGCwFZMbk" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Witchbrook is a cozy life-sim where players embody a student at the titular magical college. As you take classes and learn spells, you'll be able to bring them into other areas of life, like selling magical decorations at a stand in the town square. Players can also explore the town of Mossport to get jobs, make money, and meet up with their friends. It's all showcased through a cute, isometric, pixelated art style.</p>

<p>The trailer featured cozy mechanics galore. In addition to the aforementioned shop mechanic, you can use a telescope to read the stars, deliver mail to townsfolk, and rearrange your living quarters by using levitation spells to move furniture. The game also supports up to 4-player online co-op, which the new video showcases through footage of four people flying across the town on their brooms. At a different point, we see someone also driving a moped, which seems objectively inferior to a flying broom, but I'll leave the magic to the students of Witchbrook.</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:1,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;A moped? Really?&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="f48793ec-aa99-48bc-aabe-6c3d6eec4626" data-langcode="en"><a data-featherlight="image" href="">
</a>





<p>A moped? Really?</p>

</article><p>While the trailer was specifically for the Switch version, the game is also headed to Xbox and PC. You can take classes, learn spells, and socialize with your fellow students on the platform of your choice when Witchbrook launches this holiday season.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Legends Z-A Trailer Reveals Battle Zones And The Z-A Royale]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/03/27/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-reveals-battle-zones-and-the-z-a-royale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-a-trailer-reveals-battle-zones-and-the-z-a-royale.1147152/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/03/27/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-reveals-battle-zones-and-the-z-a-royale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>After the Pokémon Presents earlier this year, we got our first real look at Pokémon Legends Z-A, including gameplay, new characters, and the game's selection of starters. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/9OqoRxXUjGA">Today's Nintendo Direct</a> gave us just a bit more information, specifically explaining what the deal was with the mysterious teaser at the end of the previous trailers.</p>

<p>Pokémon Legends Z-A is the second of a new style of mainline Pokémon games, with a free third-person camera, an open world, and revamped combat. While Legends Arceus took place in an ancient Sinnoh region, Legends Z-A is a return to the Kalos region from Pokémon X&amp;Y, allowing players to see what happened after that game's campaign. Given that those titles are the only mainline Pokémon games without sequels or DLC, it's been a highly anticipated return.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tezs2FsIxgA" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>The game takes place entirely within Lumiose City, a huge Paris-like metropolis with multiple districts. Wild Pokémon will now appear in Wild Zones, closed-off areas within the city where the creatures are able to live peaceful lives undisturbed. While this feature appeared in the Pokémon Presents trailer, we only saw what the areas were like during the day. Today's Nintendo Direct revealed they're a bit different once the sun goes down.</p>

<p>At night, Battle Zones appear. While Wild Zones have an inviting green entrance, the Battle Zones are an aggressive red-orange and are full of trainers looking for challengers. Collectively, these encounters are known as the Z-A Royale, a competition where a trainer makes their way from Rank Z to Rank A. Rules here are similar to other games – eye contact with a trainer forces you into a battle – but the new action-based battle system allows for alternate approaches too, like the ability to ambush a trainer with an attack before they see you.</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="6e7b3bea-04e4-45bc-91f0-8f11d4375674" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p>Reach Rank A, and you'll "have a wish granted," though it's not entirely clear who grants the wish and how far their powers go. Examples in the trailer include a taxi driver hoping to abolish all public transit except taxis and a woman hoping the city will host a marathon, so don't go into it expecting to solve world hunger or anything.</p>

<p>The inclusion of Battle Zones raises many questions. When you lose, do you drop ranks? How often can we battle in the daylight, outside of Battle Zones? Who's hosting the Z-A Royale to begin with? We'll have answers once Pokémon Legends Z-A drops on Switch in late 2025.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Gameplay Trailer Reveals Samus’ New Psychic Powers]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/03/27/metroid-prime-4-beyond-gameplay-trailer-reveals-samus-new-psychic-powers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metroid-prime-4-beyond-gameplay-trailer-reveals-samus%E2%80%99-new-psychic-powers.1147146/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/03/27/metroid-prime-4-beyond-gameplay-trailer-reveals-samus-new-psychic-powers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond made its presence known during today’s Nintendo Direct with its first gameplay demonstration. Today’s trailer reveals a new world Samus unexpectedly finds herself in, the first extended look at combat, and a brand-new suite of powers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The trailer unfolded on planet Viewros, a planet of lush jungles including a colossal tree at its center, not unlike Pandora from the Avatar films. To learn more about her surroundings, we see Samus use her trusty scanner to glean information on fauna and flora, some of which, believe it or not, are hostile.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The first-person gunplay looks familiar but polished like never before. In addition to blasting new alien threats and killer plants with her cannon, Beyond sees Samus become augmented by an ancient force granting her new Psychic powers.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nmwAhBxakw4" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>These powers grant her telekinetic-like abilities, allowing her to manipulate mechanisms with her mind. We see her turning what looks to be a giant clock hand by simply waving her hand, for example. In combat, Samus can now psychically guide her arm cannon’s projectiles to her targets, essentially turning them into homing blasts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The trailer concludes with a tantalizing tease of a new red and black suit for Samus, but we’ll have to wait and see what abilities accompany her new armor. Unfortunately, Nintendo didn’t reveal a release date, but Metroid Prime 4: Beyond is slated to launch for Switch later this year.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything Announced At The Dreamhaven Showcase]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/03/26/everything-announced-at-the-dreamhaven-showcase</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-announced-at-the-dreamhaven-showcase.1147140/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/03/26/everything-announced-at-the-dreamhaven-showcase<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/2020/09/23/mike-morhaime-launches-dreamhaven-with-other-blizzard-veterans">Dreamhaven</a>, a publisher founded in 2020 by Blizzard co-founder and former CEO Mike Morhaime, held its first showcase yesterday detailing updates for a handful of titles from its studios. The publisher was formed alongside other Blizzard alumni to “create and publish original games for players around the world." To that end, it established two internal studios, Secret Door and Moonshot Games, which consist of industry veterans hailing from Blizzard and beyond. Today’s showcase sees Dreamhaven roll the carpet out for their upcoming slate of games in a big way, and if you missed the event live, here’s a quick round-up of notable announcements.</p>

<h2>Wildgate Announced by Moonshot Games</h2>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f2jvZzieaBo" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Freshly unveiled for the first time, Wildgate is the space-faring debut title by Moonshot Games. Described as a crew-based first-person shooter, players (called Prospectors) work together as a ship crew to explore a mysterious region of space to steal a powerful artifact called, well, the Artifact.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Each crew pilots a ship, which takes different shapes and sizes and can be customized with various guns and gadgets. Each crew member sports unique tools and skills, and success depends on how well players cooperate to keep the ship running effectively. That includes jobs like piloting the ship, salvaging loot and resources, and engaging in space combat with hostile aliens and rival treasure hunters. The crew that retrieves the Artifact must race to an exit gate to successfully escape with it. Alternatively, you can also opt to annihilate all rival ships to be the last crew standing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Wildgate launches for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC this year. You can sign up now for a community playtest taking place on April 10-14.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Sunderfolk Gets A Release Date&nbsp;</h2>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rre2LkxZjDQ" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>First announced last October, Sunderfolk aims to streamline the tabletop RPG experience. Up to four players assume the roles of heroes to protect a peaceful animal village from encroaching corruption using their phones or tablets as controllers. This ensures everyone can play, and the lack of physical materials (resources like the rulebook are accessed in the Sunderfolk mobile app) aims to get the party adventuring as quickly and painlessly as possible. Additionally, only the host needs to own the game; everyone else can join in for free.</p>

<p>Featuring six classes to choose from – Arcanist, Bard, Berserker, Pyromancer, Ranger, and Rogue – players can outfit themselves with weapons, armor, skills, and items to face enemies in turn-based tactical battles. Players execute commands using a customizable card deck, and battles encourage cooperation and strategy. Between fights, players will upgrade the village of Arden to add new vendors and cultivate relationships with its residents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Curious players can try Sunderfolk now via a free demo, though you’ll have to sign up with NVIDIA GeForce Now to access it. Sunderfolk launches on April 23 for $49.99 and will be available on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, Switch, and PC.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Lynked: Banner of the Spark Goes 1.0 This May</h2>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ozF5rFIR4Ck" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Lynked: Banner of the Spark launched into Steam Early Access last October, and developer FuzzyBot is preparing to bring it to prime time in a couple of months.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This action RPG can be played solo or in co-op and combines roguelite progression with cozy city-building. Players hack ‘n’ slash through waves of robotic enemies, harvest their parts, and then use those materials to expand a home base. When you’re not fighting, you can engage in more laid-back activities at the hub like fishing, harvesting crops, collecting animals, and crafting home decor.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 1.0 version will introduce five new chapters, bringing the main campaign up to a total of 40 missions. A new biome, The VoidSpyre, will be introduced along with five new bosses. New weapon mods and skins will also become available for crafting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lynked: Banner of the Spark arrives on May 22 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p>

<p>Additionally, Dreamhaven announced a publishing partnership for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/669330/Mechabellum/">Mechabellum</a>, a mech-themed tactics game that launched last September. A premium edition of the game launches today with over 18 exclusive skins, avatars, and emotes. This version runs for $29.99 versus the previous standard edition’s $14.99.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Soccer Legend Cristiano Ronaldo Is A Playable Fighter In Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/03/26/soccer-legend-cristiano-ronaldo-is-a-playable-fighter-in-fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/soccer-legend-cristiano-ronaldo-is-a-playable-fighter-in-fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves.1147137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/03/26/soccer-legend-cristiano-ronaldo-is-a-playable-fighter-in-fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Fighting games have long established a trend of including guest characters on their rosters. Whether you’re talking about Akuma appearing in Tekken 7, Yoda showing up in Soulcalibur IV, or the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles being added as DLC in Injustice 2, guest characters are nothing new for this genre. However, with the announcement of soccer legend Cristiano Ronaldo joining its main roster, the upcoming Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves makes a strong case for hosting one of the more unique and unpredictable guest inclusions.</p>

<p>Widely regarded as one of the greatest soccer players to ever step foot on the pitch, holding various individual records and titles, Ronaldo joins the main playable roster of Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves. Representing his native Portugal in international play, Ronaldo has spent large portions of his career playing for Manchester United, Real Madrid, and Juventus. He joined Al Nassr in Saudi Arabia in 2023, where he has played since.</p>

<p>In Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves, Ronaldo is voiced by Juan Felipe Sierra. In-game, Ronaldo uses techniques he developed during his career as a footballer to punish his opponents, with his fighting style listed as, “Football + Martial Arts.” You can see how this style plays out through the reveal trailer below.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fbeEWm4_qeg" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Ronaldo’s inclusion brings the current main roster size to 15, though that number could still grow en route to next month’s launch. Additionally, we know DLC is on the horizon, as SNK announced last year that two other guest characters, Ken and Chun-Li from the Street Fighter series, will join the roster after launch. Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves arrives on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, PlayStation 4, and PC on April 24. If you’d like to familiarize yourself with other playable Fatal Fury characters before then, Mai Shiranui and Terry Bogard joined the Street Fighter 6 roster by way of downloadable content over the course of 2024.</p>

<p><em>Editor’s note: Apologies to all the non-American readers for our use of the word “soccer.”&nbsp;</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 Dawn of the Hunt Q&A – ‘Throw Everything You Knew in the Bin’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunt-qa-throw-everything-you-knew-in-the-bin/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunt-q-a-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98throw-everything-you-knew-in-the-bin%E2%80%99.1147113/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunt-qa-throw-everything-you-knew-in-the-bin/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following the <a href="https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunt-is-out-next-week-adding-a-new-class-and-tons-of-content/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Path of Exile 2 Dawn of the Hunt</a> press presentation, Grinding Gear Games Game Director Jonathan Rogers sat down to answer several questions from the assembled press, both regarding the new expansion and the game as a whole. You can find the full transcript below.</p>
<p>As a reminder, Dawn of the Hunt will launch simultaneously on April 4th across all platforms.</p>
<p><iframe title="Path of Exile 2: Dawn of the Hunt Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-CnACIrCOkc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Path of Exile 2 has two radically different gameplay tempos: the slow, methodical campaign and the faster endgame, more similar to the first game. Do you aim to slow down the end game and provide players with more agency to use slow reactive skills like parry, blocks, and combo skills?</strong></p>
<p>The answer to that is that it's not that in the endgame things suddenly change or anything. It's just that there are various meta builds that I would say were overpowered and have led to a situation where, in order to fight in the endgame effectively, people have tended to center around a few broken things. Now, this patch also contains a full rebalance that will improve a lot of the more broken things that have been going on, which means that we don't have as many people feeling like they're forced into some of that stuff, which should balance things out. The other thing is that we're changing the on-ramp to endgame quite a bit, especially with things like being able to die in the endgame. You should be in a scenario where people don't feel the need to use that staff and those builds are not so much available. We do want to make it so that you can still get very powerful as you go through, but it should be more earned than it is currently, where there's just a few broken things. It will take a while for us to get all that stuff fully resolved. It might take a few iterations before every single broken thing is ironed, but it's a constant goal and we'll get there in the end.</p>
<p><strong>Will unique bosses created by wisps drop increased loot?</strong></p>
<p>Yep, absolutely. That's the whole point.</p>
<p><strong>Are we going to face monsters as strong as we've seen in the first Path of Exile if we juice the wisps too hard?</strong></p>
<p>We've obviously got a very different balance overall. One thing we want to try and avoid is having monsters that are just complete damage sponges. That being said, it is important that you have the ability to make mistakes, to go too far with this kind of stuff. If you add a lot of mechanics to maps, you can get to the point where content becomes very, very difficult, but obviously more rewarding as well.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any information about the development progress of the Druid class?</strong></p>
<p>I don't have anything to announce right now. The plan is to announce it and release it as soon as we can. Classes do take a long time. There's a lot of work involved in them. One thing we've definitely learned is that it's hard to promise a specific release timeline for a class.</p>
<p><strong>In the last season, there wasn't much of a balancing nerfing the class skills or items. Are you going to make balance changes during the season or continue the way you did in the last season?</strong></p>
<p>When we went into early access with Path of Exile 2, we did believe that we'd be able to do a bunch of nerfing and that kind of stuff during leagues, which we don't normally do. We quickly found out that it's really just like a live game. You can't just nerf stuff mid-league because it breaks people's builds and they get very angry. We pretty much stopped doing that very quickly. This update will do a huge amount of balance and then anything really egregious we'll fix as it comes up, but generally speaking, we try to leave the balance mostly alone during the league. We now effectively bottle up all of those balance changes and then we release them when we're doing a season. As I said, it's a full game rebalance this time. A lot of the things that players are currently complaining about, like Herald Device and this kind of stuff, will definitely get nerfed this season.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'Different Rogue exiles have different sets. There are lots of different ones that they can have. There's actually 12 Rogue exiles in this version. The idea is to try and make it so that, basically, the big full set of uniques that could drop from regular content can spawn on them. They all have specific AI for those uniques but they have lots of different options. There'll be Rogue exiles that contain most uniques that you would want to find. They're very interesting fights because they know how to use the items. They're pretty cool and&nbsp;feel very PvP-like. They're dodge rolling around and everything.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Do Rogue exiles have preset items, or will it be completely random?</strong></p>
<p>They do have random items, but I believe that different Rogue exiles have different sets. There are lots of different ones that they can have. There's actually 12 Rogue exiles in this version. The idea is to try and make it so that, basically, the big full set of uniques that could drop from regular content can spawn on them. They all have specific AI for those uniques but they have lots of different options. There'll be Rogue exiles that contain most uniques that you would want to find. They're very interesting fights because they know how to use the items. They're pretty cool and feel very PvP-like. They're dodge rolling around and everything.</p>
<p><strong>A lot of changes in the new content touch on player feedback. How do you balance that with Grinding Gear's vision for Path of Exile 2?</strong></p>
<p>We always listen to the players to determine what the problems are, but we still have our ideas with regard to how we're going to solve those problems. The players are really the ones bringing things to our attention. Normally, there'll always be some kind of third way. Like, we've got an idea of how it should be, and the players have an idea of how it should be. If we try to combine the concerns of both us and them, we'll come up with a third way. There are a few issues that aren't like that, but generally speaking, we're always going to be able to come up with some kind of thing that both the players can get excited about and we can feel happy about as well. Ideally, that's the best solution.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any plans to enable players to loot items from the ground in case they die immediately after killing a mob?</strong></p>
<p>That's kind of something that I would say is pretty disliked as far as solutions go, because we tend to avoid things that don't make any physical sense thematically. Obviously, if you're dead you can't pick items. I know that's one of those issues that players are unhappy about, but fundamentally, there is just a thing of if you die, you don't get to loot stuff.</p>
<p><strong>Will the least-played Ascendancies, as Acolyte, Chronomancer, Warbringer, and Witch Hunter, get changed in the update?</strong></p>
<p>I wouldn't say Chronomancer is not very well played, but for the others, the overall balance is changing very significantly. The reason why certain Ascendancies are played the most is usually because there's something broken going on with them. It isn't necessarily the case that the less played ones need buffing, although in lots of cases, we will do it. Effectively, all your previous assumptions just need to be thrown in the bin because there's enough changes as far as balance is concerned that you just can't expect things to work exactly the same.</p>
<p><strong>Can the Smith of Katava take multiple of the armor modifiers, and does it require committing one Ascendancy point for each of them?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, you can take as many as you like as long as you have Ascendancy points. It's a question of, do you want to be using the other elements of the class or do you want to go all in on those armor modifiers, which can be pretty powerful. There's just quite a lot of choice there in this class.</p>
<p><strong>What additional uses do you have planned for gold in the future?</strong></p>
<p>I'm not going to announce any right now, but it's just useful having that currency around.</p>
<p><strong>It looks like map portals are tied to the number of resurrects and get lower if it gets harder. If we have some maps with fewer portals to go back and forth, does it mean we won't be able to carry as many items, especially for maps with multiple breaches?</strong></p>
<p>That is the case. However, I guess the theory here is that you shouldn't generally need to take more than an inventory or two full of items. It is a concern, though, and we'll have to see how well it works. I would hope there's something that we can do to alleviate that. I'm just thinking right now that maybe after the map is completed, we could allow potentially more, but I'll have to think about that. It's actually something that I should probably um investigate a bit more.</p>
<p><strong>Will Temporalis get removed or overhauled? It broke the game in several ways.</strong></p>
<p>It's not getting removed and it's not getting overhauled either. It might get nerfed a little bit but I should mention that it's not like everyone should be getting a temporalis just on demand. It's supposed to be a very hard unique to get. Just due to the other balance issues, it meant that getting a Temporalis was much easier than it would have otherwise been. Consider what you actually have to do to get one: you have to be able to play through Sanctum without getting hit one time. It shouldn't be something that is easy to get. Sometimes, we balance things by rarity, like, they are supposed to be a broken thing, but if you get them, they are incredibly ridiculous.</p>
<p>This is one of those cases, but because there were builds that allowed things to be very broken, it just meant that there were too many of them in the economy. Something I just want to stress is that it should be possible to become incredibly powerful. It's just that it shouldn't be the case that you get that without a huge amount of effort. For example, it really was a problem that the pinnacle bosses got killed in like 14 seconds the first time that people fought them. It really should be a long, protracted battle the first time, but of course, once you've played it several times, you've had more time to grind other stuff, you get to the top of the end of what is economically possible.</p>
<p>At that point it's fine to be killing pinnacle bosses in 14 seconds. It's just that it shouldn't be like that the first time. It's a question of getting the power scaling right. When you release a new game, there's just tons of stuff that's unintended.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'I am definitely very keen to get it done this year. I would be very disappointed if we weren't able to. It's not 100% guaranteed. We might slip. I'm still very much hoping that we're not going to. Looking at the content of this particular expansion, there's a lot of stuff going on here and a lot of it is reactionary to the problems that we saw with the game, but in the background, we've still got artists and people all working on other acts. There is a lot of behind-the-scenes work going on in creating the rest of the content.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Are you planning to adjust the drop rates of currency items?</strong></p>
<p>There's always adjustments. Generally speaking, normal currency is mostly fine. We don't really have a particular issue with it. There are certain things, for example omens are not common enough and we made it so that every ritual has an omen in it now. But I wouldn't say overall that currency items needed a buff or anything like that. We're mostly happy with them.</p>
<p><strong>Any hints about the remaining story? Will they be released individually or maybe as a big story </strong><strong>league or expansion?</strong></p>
<p>We are planning on launching them later. We're not going to announce when that's going to be for the time being, but obviously, they all have to get done by the time we get into full release.</p>
<p><strong>You initially talked about wanting the Path of Exile 2 early access phase to last one year. Now we're a little further in, does it still feel like a realistic goal to reach the state you want for 1.0?</strong></p>
<p>I am definitely very keen to get it done this year. I would be very disappointed if we weren't able to.<br>
It's not 100% guaranteed. We might slip. I'm still very much hoping that we're not going to. Looking at the content of this particular expansion, there's a lot of stuff going on here and a lot of it is reactionary to the problems that we saw with the game, but in the background, we've still got artists and people all working on other acts. There is a lot of behind-the-scenes work going on in creating the rest of the content. We might have released more of that stuff if it hadn't been for the fact that we felt like we had to add a lot of in-game features. Can we get it done this year? I think it's possible.</p>
<p><strong>Are there any plans to change gold so it isn't a drop item but rather an auto-pickup on kill, like expedition artifacts received that QoL in Path of Exile?</strong></p>
<p>Definitely not. I think it's nice that you pick it up. It's got a relatively large pickup radius; you just run over it. I don't have any particular problems with this myself at this point.</p>
<p><strong>What changes to the trading system can players expect during the Path of Exile 2 early access?</strong></p>
<p>I don't have anything to announce about this, but I do have some things I want to try and improve here. Obviously, currency is much easier to trade. There are other things people want to do with trading. There are things that I would potentially change,&nbsp;and we definitely want to make sure we're testing those changes before the end of early access because it's one of those things that can affect the economy pretty significantly.</p>
<p><strong>Will the new update implement more cosmetics people have unlocked in POE1?</strong></p>
<p>The answer is yes. I don't have a list of them, but we're continuing to move through that list and add more things, so yes, more of them will be added.</p>
<p><strong>Will you please clarify if this update is a league on its own or if there will be several leagues before the next major content update?</strong></p>
<p>Every new update we do will contain a new economy. In this particular case, we decided not to put any of the content exclusive to the new economy, but in the future, we may decide to do that before early access is over. But generally speaking, there's probably going to be more content in these Path of Exile 2 updates than what you would have seen in Path of Exile 1 leagues in the past, just because we're finishing the game at the same time. That should result in a lot. In this particular case, our focus was really more on endgame and making sure there were lots of new encounters to find there. While we did add the wisps throughout the game and we've also added a strongbox&nbsp;and things like that, we didn't think it quite rose to the level of being able to make it exclusive to the league and to be able to call it a challenge league in the way that we would have done in the past.</p>
<p>The wisps were the closest thing to a new league mechanic here, but as I said, we decided not to make them exclusive this time. I am keen to do exclusive challenge league content for future expansions before the end of early access just because when we do that, we can also decide whether we want to remove them, change them, or mess around with them. That's our plan, but honestly, we'll see because, ultimately, everything comes down to the degree to which we want to feel like we're addressing the concerns that people have online.</p>
<p><strong>Currently, having plus level link levels to skills feels like a must since it gives such a large power boost for one mod. Is it intentional? Are there any changes coming to it?</strong></p>
<p>It is intentional and it's exactly the same as having increased physical damage on weapons. There are certain mods that are more powerful than others; that's part of the fun of finding them. It's one of those things, just like how you need run speed on boots. There are certain things that you want to be able to find. You need chase mods in order to make the bad mods feel better. It's just part of the design.</p>
<p><strong>Any plans to add a higher difficulty mode for existing acts?</strong></p>
<p>No, because even the fact that we have two difficulties right now is not the final stage. We'll be removing that difficulty the moment we have the rest of the campaign. The higher-difficulty content is the endgame content, which is already done. While it all looks unique, it technically remixes all the act content and reuses the bosses in different ways. It's not like you don't have high-level content to do; it's just that it's done in a way that feels different from the campaign.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'There is actually a chance of not being able to add all classes in time. I suspect we're probably not going to have all of them for full release, but we'll see. It depends on how things go and where things end. Obviously, I'd like to get them all in, but they do take a long time to make. The most important thing for the full release is that we have the full campaign and there's all the content that we need. It's not like we've got a shortage of classes. If we didn't have one or two of them for the full release, that wouldn't be the end of the world. We'll try to get them all in, but if we don't, then whatever.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Will all the remaining classes be added to early access before release, or could some&nbsp;be held back for the full launch of Path of Exile 2?</strong></p>
<p>There is actually a chance of that. I suspect we're probably not going to have all of them for full release, but we'll see. It depends on how things go and where things end. Obviously, I'd like to get them all in, but they do take a long time to make. The most important thing for the full release is that we have the full campaign, and there's all the content that we need. It's not like we've got a shortage of classes. If we didn't have one or two of them for the full release, that wouldn't be the end of the world. We'll try to get them all in, but if we don't, then whatever.</p>
<p><strong>The last time, you mentioned that Path of Exile 1 will continue receiving updates as long as it has players. Are the current player numbers sufficient to justify ongoing development?</strong></p>
<p>So it absolutely is. The issue with Path of Exile 1 development really just comes down to studio bandwidth from the perspective of designers who know how to make Path of Exile. We don't have a huge number of them. Obviously, we have a bunch of people who work on the game, but in terms of game director tier people who are able to lead a project like that, we don't have enough to the point where we can just be, okay, you just go off and you do your thing.</p>
<p>Mark and I have to keep an eye on it. For that reason, it's been a challenge to get the structure in place so that we can actually get both games rolling. Right now, I think we're getting to that point, but it certainly was a bit rough around the launch of Path of Exile 2's early access where POE 1 stuff got quite paged in order to make POE2 happen. We're going to continue to do that stuff.</p>
<p>With regard to your question, our company had both games in the top 20 player concurrency for Steam at one point a few weeks ago. I'd certainly say that both games have their place with<br>
regard to player popularity. It's definitely worth continuing to support Path of Exile 1.</p>
<p><strong>Are there any mana cost changes?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. I don't even know what they are because, as I said, everything's just been rebalanced. Some will go up; some will go down, and some will go sideways. For the specifics, you're going to have to wait for the patch notes to see.</p>
<p><strong>Will Path of Exile 2 and its predecessor alternate new seasons from now on, or will there be another Path of Exile 2 season after Dawn of the Hunt?</strong></p>
<p>There will be another Path of Exile 1 season between Dawn of the Hunt and the next Path of Exile 2 season for sure. As for how it works going forward, we're keen to alternate them, but it's going to come down to the realities of development and what happens. Certainly the eventual goal by the time everything is rolling and working smoothly, it will definitely be the case that they're going to alternate like that, but I can imagine scenarios during early access of POE 2 where POE 1 might end up with a delay here or there.</p>
<p><strong>Any plans for the endgame map to have an option to place bookmarks or better navigation changes?</strong></p>
<p>We actually do have plans for this. Unfortunately, they didn't make it for this update. We have UI designs. I have a feeling you might see them in 0.21. We definitely know that that's an issue, but our UI guys were quite busy. We'll get to it.</p>
<p><strong>With the Atlas tree expanding, are we going to have more points for the Atlas tree?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, you are. Actually, I don't remember the number now. Both the corrupted Nexus objective and the unique map objectives get you Atlas points. Both the tree and the points have expanded.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 Dawn of the Hunt Is Out Next Week, Adding a New Class and Tons of Content]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunt-is-out-next-week-adding-a-new-class-and-tons-of-content/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunt-is-out-next-week-adding-a-new-class-and-tons-of-content.1147110/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunt-is-out-next-week-adding-a-new-class-and-tons-of-content/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grinding Gear Games has unveiled Path of Exile 2 Dawn of the Hunt, a huge free expansion to its <a href="https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-early-access-hands-on-the-arpg-that-could-rule-them-all/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acclaimed action RPG title</a> currently in early access. The expansion launches next week on all platforms; don't forget to also check out the <a href="https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunt-qa-throw-everything-you-knew-in-the-bin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">press roundtable Q&amp;A with Game Director Jonathan Rogers</a>, who revealed even more details about the expansion and the game's future.</p>
<p>Dawn of the Hunt introduces the first new class since the early access of Path of Exile 2: the huntress. She is a spear-wielding warrior born into a society with strict traditions. She was exiled from her homeland after using her powers to defend her. She specializes in both melee and ranged combat, dashing into and out of battle. Spears have extended range and a short dash, but unlike other melee weapons, you can also throw them. In order to make a hybrid ranged/melee character work, the developers had to think about ways to make it fun to both enter and exit the melee range. The first skill players will get as a Huntress is Whirling Slash.</p>
<p>As well as striking in a circle the player, the skill creates a whirlwind that blinds enemies. Leaving the whirlwind will make it explode, and the more Whirling Slash is used, the bigger the explosion gets. Once out of melee, the Huntress can follow up with something ranged. She can whip the spear around to shoot twisters towards foes. These twisters bounce off walls and can hit enemies multiple times. Twisters can also be thrown inside a whirlwind to shoot out extra tornadoes that do way more damage. In her off-hand, the Huntress will hold a buckler which allows her to Parry.</p>
<p>While holding that down, the character will counterattack any incoming attack from nearby monsters, stunning them. Additionally, the monsters will take extra attack damage from your follow-up strike. Some of the specific class skills have been designed to be used after a Parry.</p>
<p>Disengage is a skill that does a quick jump back, damaging enemies in front of you. It can be used to interrupt other actions like dodge roll. If you use it against a parried enemy, it causes an explosion and gives you a frenzy charge. However, the Huntress cannot Parry too much, lest they get stunned and possibly killed.</p>
<p>The Huntress also has a variety of elemental spear throw attacks. Lightning Spear bounces lightning between your foes. Explosive Spears can be thrown into the ground and detonate after a while, incinerating anyone caught in the blast. All spear throws can also be empowered by frenzy charges. For example, Explosive Spears will cause an even larger explosion and leave fire on the ground. These empowered versions can activate even more combos. Using Whirling Slash off a ground fire will suck it into the whirlwind, adding fire to the explosion. Using Twisters inside a fire whirlwind will shoot out fire tornadoes as well, and you can do similar combos with ice and lightning, too.</p>
<p>A key aspect of hunting is exhausting your foes by causing blood loss. Rake dashes towards your target and unleashes a deadly slash opening up wounds on your enemies. You can follow up with Disengage and watch them bleed out as they run towards you. On the monsters health bar, you can see how much blood loss the enemy has experienced. The Huntress has skills to take advantage of this: for example, using Blood Hunt will thrust forward and cause a bloody explosion. the more blood loss, the bigger the explosion. Thunderous Leap will allow you to jump onto and explode any Spears either in the ground or in your enemies.</p>
<p>As well as hunting animals, the Huntress also has the ability to work with them. While fighting any beast, you have the ability to tame it and use it as a companion. You can only have one companion at a time, but it will keep the mods that were on it. Try to find a rare beast with good mods to take full advantage of your ability to tame. There's a huge amount of synergy between ranged and melee options. There are a total of 22 new skills available for the Huntress.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ritualist-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The first Ascension class you could choose is the Ritualist, which has embraced the darker side and harnessed the power of animal sacrifice and plague. The Corrupted Life Force skill causes all enemies around you to grow volatile blood boils on their skin. When those enemies are slain, the boils will burst, spreading corrupted blood to all enemies around them. The Ritualist also excels in taking advantage of magical trinkets. The Unfurled Finger skill allows you to equip an additional ring on a finger. Taking Mystic Attunement increases the bonuses of all the rings and Amulets you have equipped. You can even cut your own hand sacrificing some of your own blood to empower yourself.</p>
<p>The Amazon Ascension is for those looking to hunt more than just beasts. Trained as a guard to the most important Elders, the Amazon will use more traditional fighting techniques mastered to perfection. The Predatory Instinct skill will cause you to reveal weaknesses in the defenses of rare and unique enemies, allowing you to deal more damage. You can see those weak spots represented on their life bars. While using Elemental Infusion, any charges you consume will infuse your weapon with elemental power, causing any projectile attacks to explode on impact. The Critical Strike skill is as simple as it sounds: it takes your accuracy and gives it to you as Critical Strike chance.</p>
<p>Path of Exile 2 Dawn of the Hunt also brings three new Ascendancy classes for other classes:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Lich (Witch) -</strong> The Lich tears their own soul apart, becoming a master of undeath and chaos. The Lich is a master of Chaos and Curses who can use her own life to enhance her Energy.</li>
<li><strong>Smith of Kitava (Warrior) -</strong> The Smith of Kitava forges weapons of destruction in fire and suffering. Embrace sheer power and take Smithing skills to greater heights by resonating with the insatiable one - Kitava.</li>
<li><strong>Tactician (Mercenary) -</strong> The mercenary Tactician brings military-grade brutality to the battlefield. As a former trained Blackguard Elite, the Tactician is able to decimate the monsters of Wraeclast while earning a healthy income at the same time.</li>
</ul>
<p>The expansion also adds two new skills:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Raise Spectre -</strong> This skill lets you trap and summon the souls of almost any monster in the game. With hundreds of monster variants in Path of Exile 2, expect endless experimentation to find the perfect undead army.</li>
<li><strong>Summon Rhoa Mount -</strong> Call forth a Rhoa to fight by your side or mount it to move at full speed while attacking. But beware, taking too much damage can knock you off, leaving you vulnerable to a brutal fate.</li>
</ul>
<p>This expansion also brings a massive overhaul to character development by adding over 100 new Support Gems to enhance build diversity. Support gems add a variety of interesting effects to your existing skills, modifying them in game-changing ways. For example, Haemocrystals turn bleed effects into explosive Vaal crystals, and Caltrops allow your existing skills to litter the battlefield with slowing hazards.</p>
<p>A big focus of the expansion is to expand on the endgame. There are over a hundred new unique items, ensuring high-level characters have more thrilling bounty to chase. New crafting tools have also been introduced as rewards across many areas of the game:</p>
<ul>
<li>Over 20 new runes have been added allowing you to craft new mods onto your gear</li>
<li>Runes now scale with multiple tiers, allowing for stronger mods that remain viable in the endgame.</li>
<li>We're expanding crafting options further by introducing more specialized socketable mods, with the first wave arriving in an upcoming content update.</li>
</ul>
<p>There's more. The so-called Azmeri Spirit has made itself present in Wraeclast. When approached, these wisps will flee, and monsters coming into contact will be infused by it, making them more powerful. Wisps will also find and possess Rare or Unique monsters, granting them powerful new abilities, and powerful new rewards. There are twelve distinct types of wisp, each with their own mechanics and rewards.</p>
<p>Path of Exile 2 Dawn of the Hunt adds eight new Maps to the game, offering fresh challenges and rewards. In each case, players will have interesting new encounters to look forward to, such as&nbsp; being forced to fight mirrored Rare monsters in a shifting, warped reality in The Fractured Lake, or being thrust into the wild Ezomyte Forests of The Phaaryl Megaliths where rune-carved stones surge with energy. Survive the storm-fueled gauntlet of deadly boss waves, and you’ll earn full boss rewards and exclusive Runes.</p>
<p>The update introduces four new Unique Strongboxes, each with deadly mechanics and valuable rewards:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ogham's Legacy features a rune-carved stone and a slain creature that, when activated, revives as a powerful Rare. Each defeat triggers another resurrection with added modifiers making the fight progressively more difficult, but also more rewarding.</li>
<li>Ixchel’s Torment harnesses ancient Vaal thaumaturgy, unleashing Chaos-empowered guardians to protect a powerful artifact. Victors will be rewarded with a unique item featuring a specific Corrupted outcome.</li>
</ul>
<p>Essences also received major upgrades, with four new Corrupted Essences - Hysteria, Delirium, Horror, and Insanity - offering new combat mechanics and powerful new crafting outcomes, such as guaranteed double Enchantments when using a Vaal Orb on belts.</p>
<p>Corruption has continued to spread throughout Wraeclast and has formed into larger and larger zones. In the center of each one lies a Corrupted Nexus, the home of three new terrifying bosses, amalgamations of Corruption itself. Upon defeating these bosses, any remaining areas within the zone of Corruption will become cleansed. Cleansed Maps have additional new monsters, a new boss, and their own set of Modifiers and rewards.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/RogueExilesCinematic-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Path of Exile 2 Dawn of the Hunt also introduces Rogue Exiles - others like you who have been exiled and are openly hostile. They will challenge you in a fight to the death. These NPCs have the ability to Dodge Roll and avoid your abilities with smart pathfinding, smart targeting, and much more action-packed gameplay. Rogue Exiles use the same skills available to players, and even the same items. They aren't just dressed up in those items; they know how to take advantage of the Uniques they are using, which, of course, will be available for players once they have prevailed.</p>
<p>Lastly, there's a significant rebalance of the endgame. The number of towers has been drastically reduced, but they have been made much more powerful. Tablets now affect twice as many areas and running higher tier Maps in Towers increases this number further still. In addition, each Tower will be able to consume up to three Tablets at once. These changes greatly reduce the amount of busy work required in the endgame while improving the player's ability to use them. On top of that, Towers can now spawn with all mechanics, and have their own new Bosses.</p>
<p>Path of Exile 2 Dawn of the Hunt will launch on Friday, April 4.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2: Dawn of the Hunt's New Huntress and Ascendancy Classes Look Sick]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-hunts-new-huntress-and-ascendancy-classes-look-sick</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-the-hunts-new-huntress-and-ascendancy-classes-look-sick.1147107/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/path-of-exile-2-dawn-of-hunts-new-huntress-and-ascendancy-classes-look-sick<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/path-of-exile-2-update-011-full-patch-notes" rel="nofollow"><em>Path of Exile 2</em></a>, the long-awaited sequel to a cherished ARPG, is fully underway and players have had the chance to dive head first into its sumptuous content. It <em>is</em> in Early Access, however, so we can expect many updates with new inclusions. That said, Patch 0.2.0, dubbed <em>Dawn of the Hunt</em>, is sure to shake things up with tons of new content.</p>

<p>Along with the brand new Huntress class in <em>Path of Exile 2: Dawn of the Hunt</em>, there are also three new ascendancies (and two for the Huntress) that will drastically change up how you play. This is what I want to focus on, because outside of additional endgame changes, players are chomping at the bit for new characters to play.</p>

<p>Introducing the Huntress, a spear-wielding range and melee hybrid class that can tame wild beasts and channel elements and spirits to slay her foes. Her signature spear can be used to fight enemies up close, or you can throw it at enemies as a ranged attack.</p>



<p>One of the Huntress' signature abilities is the Whirling Slash, which sets a whirlwind on the ground that blinds enemies and causes damage. In a press-only preview of this class, we saw her use this ability multiple times to create a larger whirlwind. You can also enhance the whirlwind by using certain elemental attacks, creating fire or lightning-based tornadoes, as an example.</p>

<p>What stuck out to us, however, was the ability to tame beasts. The Huntress can choose a companion from enemy beasts, though we don't quite know the limitations. What we do know is that it allows players to tame rares -- even those with monster-only modifiers -- so you'll want to keep a look out for those with good synergy with your build.</p>

<p>"There is going to be some level of competition for getting the rares," said which have the best mods, because they come with all the powers they had while they were rare, so you're probably going to want to keep an eye out..." said <em>Path of Exile 2 </em>Game Director Johnathan Rogers during a press Q&amp;A TechRaptor attended.</p>



<p>Her two ascendancy classes -- which are essentially specializations to further improve your character -- include Ritualist and Amazon. The former is a "forbidden magic" archetype while the latter is more of your typical spear-wielding warrior focusing on furiously attacking your enemy.</p>

<p>The Witch, Mercenary, and Warrior also get one new ascendancy class each. The Witch can become a Lich, the Mercenary a Tactician, and the Warrior a Smith of Kitava. The Smith of Kitava is a very intriguing take on ascendancy classes -- other than being able to improve your weapons mid-battle, you can also drastically alter your armor.</p>

<p>The Smith of Kitava can allocate ascendancy points to disconnected nodes on their skill tree, which essentially adds modifiers to their armor. This would replace the stats on your armor with whatever node you choose, but it allows you to pick modifiers that are much more powerful or even unobtainable from normal loot drops.</p>

<p>"In terms of fulfilling an interesting part of your build, they're just pretty cool," said Rogers. "Now the other thing as well, if you want, because you can choose how many other of the ascendancy nodes or how much of the armor crafting nodes you want, you can put all of your mods -- like you can put all eight ascendancy points into that, and now you have, that's a pretty damn powerful armor you have at that point."</p>



<h2>What other Changes Are Coming to <em>Path of Exile 2: Dawn of the Hunt</em>?</h2>

<p>There are a <em>slew</em> of other changes including a skill gem that gives you a mount to ride on, but to go over each and every change would be a Sisyphean task, so be sure to check Grinding Gear Games' announcement <a href="http://pathofexile.com/dawn-of-the-hunt-patch-notes" rel="nofollow">here</a>. As a quick rundown, players can expect dozens of new skills, new maps, endgame changes, and even rogue exiles.</p>

<p>Rogue exiles are NPCs players can fight that and have the same abilities as other players, including dodge rolling. They are smarter in nature and drop the loot set they're wearing, meaning there's a high risk of engaging them, but the reward is worth it.</p>

<p>With <em>Path of Exile 2: Dawn of the Hunt</em>, players can dive back or continue playing with tons of new added content. This particular update launches on April 4th at 3pm EST, so you won't have to wait long to dive into these new additions.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Zombies Unveils Shattered Veils Map and New Enemies for Season 3]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-zombies-unveils-shattered-veils-map-and-new-enemies-for-season-3/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-zombies-unveils-shattered-veils-map-and-new-enemies-for-season-3.1147101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-zombies-unveils-shattered-veils-map-and-new-enemies-for-season-3/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Season 3 roadmap is live now. It provides new details about the Zombies mode, including the Shattered Veil map and new enemies.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-6-zombies-season-3-map-shattered-veil">Black Ops 6 Zombies Season 3 Map: Shattered Veil</h2>



<p>Shattered Veil is the new map for Black Ops 6 Zombies Season 3 on April 2. It is set in an old mansion called Colton Hall. Players have arrived to meet S.A.M. with the Sentinel Artifact in their possession. They must unlock the mysteries of this artefact with the help of S.A.M.’s synthetic mind; however, things will not be that easy for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Players must enter Colton Hall and confront the new tyrant from the next chapter of the Black Ops 6 Zombies narrative. The map features different areas to explore, including a main hall with a massive fossil exhibit, an outdoor area, and a basement to unearth all kinds of mysteries.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-6-season-3-brings-new-zombies-enemies">Black Ops 6 Season 3 Brings New Zombies Enemies</h2>



<p>Black Ops 6 Season 3 Roadmap has revealed brand new enemies for the Zombies mode. First up is the Elder Disciple, a strange floating apparition found in the mansion’s estate. These enemies can use dark magic to summon more undead to the battle and even force them to evolve. Low-ranking zombies can transform into a Doppelghast or some other sinister form with the help of the Elder Disciple.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Zombies Season 3 also sees the arrival of other entities from the Shattered Veil. Players should keep an eye out for the toxic zombie, as it can leave a damaging pool of acid around it. However, it is easy to spot, with its greenish hue and more skeletal exterior, and it makes shrieking sounds when close.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-6-zombies-season-3-new-weapons">Black Ops 6 Zombies Season 3 New Weapons</h2>



<p>The Black Ops 6 Season 3 Roadmap has introduced two new wonder weapons for the Zombies mode: the Ray Gun Mark II and the Wunderwaffle DG-2.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Ray Gun Mark II allows players to attack multiple Zombies simultaneously through a three-round burst of energy and doubles as a bludgeoning instrument. Players can also test three different variants of the Ray Gun Mark II. The W variant provides similar bullet patterns as a submachine gun, the P variant mimics a shotgun, and the R variant can be compared to a Marksman Rifle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The other new weapon is Wunderwaffle DG-2, the best way to electrify hordes of zombies quickly. Players can use this weapon to inflict chain-lighting bolts that can stun crowds and provide terminal damage over time.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Season 03 Zombies Trailer -  Shattered Veil | Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Zombies" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FjdEtiV_n0I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Check out Black Ops 6 Zombies’ new perks, augments, and additional map content <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2025/03/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-warzone-zombies-season-three-critical-launch-announcement#Double-Tap" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>. Also, check out all the latest additions to Black Ops 6’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-3-introduces-new-multiplayer-maps-modes-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">multiplayer mode</a> in Season 3. What are your thoughts on the new content for Zombies in Season 3? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-is-forming-a-new-subsidiary-with-tencent-valued-at-4-3-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft forming a new gaming subsidiary with Tencent</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hogwarts Legacy Definitive Edition Canceled By Warner Bros]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hogwarts-legacy-definitive-edition-canceled-by-warner-bros/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hogwarts-legacy-definitive-edition-canceled-by-warner-bros.1147095/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/hogwarts-legacy-definitive-edition-canceled-by-warner-bros/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Warner Bros. Games has canceled the planned Hogwarts Legacy Definitive Edition. </p>



<p>According to a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-03-27/warner-bros-cancels-planned-hogwarts-legacy-game-expansion?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc0MzEwMzc5MiwiZXhwIjoxNzQzNzA4NTkyLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTVFNSRDZUMEFGQjQwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.dGBdhB7lWw3cxZNYXHsmp5Xz3rOJ-TM3ph6fDrDzGpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">new report</a> from Bloomberg’s Jason Schreier, the definitive edition and DLC’s cancellation comes as part of “an ongoing restructure at the entertainment company’s video game unit.”</p>



<p>The project was officially canceled this week “due to concerns that the amount of content was not substantial enough to justify the price being considered.”</p>



<p>Insider Gaming<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-hogwarts-legacy-definitive-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"> exclusively first reported</a> on the development of the Hogwarts Legacy Definitive Edition and DLC back in October 2024. The new version of the game was scheduled to include 10-15 hours of additional content, including a new story quest, side quest, activities, and outfits.</p>



<h6 id="h-read-more-exclusive-yves-guillemot-s-internal-memo-on-ubisoft-and-tencent-s-new-subsidiary">READ MORE: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-tencent-internal-memo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EXCLUSIVE – Yves Guillemot’s Internal Memo on Ubisoft and Tencent’s New Subsidiary</a></h6>



<p>In addition to the definitive edition of the game, the DLC was expected to be available separately for those who already owned the base game.</p>



<p>With no extra content now planned for Hogwarts Legacy, the studio seems to be moving forward focusing on the eventual sequel to the popular game. Back in November, outgoing Warner Bros. Games president <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hogwarts-legacy-2-in-production-at-warner-bros-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">David Haddad said that Hogwarts Legacy 2</a> was a “very big priority” for the company and that production on the game was in progress.</p>



<p>The sequel is being developed by the same studio—Avalanche Software—that developed the first Hogwarts Legacy. The original game has sold nearly 35 million copies, and has remained a top-selling game each month since its February 2023 release.</p>



<p>What do you think about the Hogwarts Legacy Definitive Edition and DLC being canceled?? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1776/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-employees-worried-about-layoffs-after-tencent-deal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft employees being worried</a> about layoffs after a new subsidiary with Tencent was announced. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These Popular EA Games Are Now Playable In A New Place]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-popular-ea-games-are-now-playable-in-a-new-place/1100-6530438/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/these-popular-ea-games-are-now-playable-in-a-new-place.1147092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-popular-ea-games-are-now-playable-in-a-new-place/1100-6530438/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530438">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Amazon Luna+, the game-streaming platform run by the online retail giant, is adding a trio of high-profile games from Electronic Arts. Amazon has <a href="https://amazonluna.blog/amazon-luna-signs-multi-year-content-deal-with-electronic-arts-and-expands-to-sweden-portugal-152881cdd355" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">confirmed</a> that it's reached a multi-year deal with EA to bring "many" of its games to Luna+, and this begins with Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order, Star Wars Jedi: Survivor, and 2023's Dead Space. These three games join Luna today, while more are coming to Luna "soon."</p><p>EA executive David Tinson said it partnered with Amazon in part to help its games reach an even bigger audience. Amazon teased that some of the upcoming EA titles to join the Luna catalog will include EA Sports games, though no titles were named outright.</p><p>Luna+ is not part of Amazon Prime but is instead an additional $10/month subscription (after a free seven-day trial). The subscription service has more than 100 games in the catalog already, including Batman: Arkham Knight, Sonic Frontiers, Resident Evil 2, Control, Alien: Isolation, and Lego Star Wars: The Complete Saga. These games are playable over the cloud on a variety of devices, including Amazon's own TVs and tablets, as well as smartphones and PC.</p><p>Luna is one of many cloud-streaming services in gaming today, sitting alongside Microsoft's Xbox Cloud Gaming and Nvidia's GeForce Now. Some EA games are also streaming on Xbox Cloud Gaming, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-adds-cfb-25-today-but-only-for-ultimate-subscribers/1100-6530430/" data-ref-id="1100-6530430">including College Football 25. </a></p><p>The appeal of such services is that users do not need a beefy PC or high-end console because games are streamed. However, a good cloud-gaming experience requires a consistent and powerful connection.</p><p>Amazon created its own Luna controller, too, and it's on sale now for $45 (down from $70). Luna is also compatible with a controller you may already own, including Xbox, PlayStation, and Switch controllers.</p><p>Amazon also confirmed that Luna is now available in more places, including Sweden, Portugal, Belgium, and Luxembourg. This brings the total number of supported countries to 14 worldwide. The other supported countries for Luna are the US, Canada, the United Kingdom, Germany, France, Italy, Spain, Austria, Poland, and the Netherlands.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 director didn't expect early access launch to be studio's biggest success yet, and that caused complications]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/path-of-exile-2-director-didnt-expect-early-access-launch-to-be-studios-biggest-success-yet-and-that-caused-complications</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-director-didnt-expect-early-access-launch-to-be-studios-biggest-success-yet-and-that-caused-complications.1147083/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/path-of-exile-2-director-didnt-expect-early-access-launch-to-be-studios-biggest-success-yet-and-that-caused-complications<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Found the whole Elon Musk situation "weird".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/path-of-exile-2-huntress.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Grinding Gear Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Grinding Gear Games apparently didn't expect action role-playing game <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/path-of-exile-2">Path of Exile 2</a> to do as well as it did when it launched in early access late last year.</p>
<p>The New Zealand-based company suspected that the £25 entrance fee, there temporarily while the game is in open development in early access (it will eventually be a free to play game), would put people off. But it didn't. At its peak, Path of Exile 2 had between 800,000 and 900,000 concurrent players. It was, I'm told, the company's biggest ever release.</p>
<p>"It was absolutely 100 percent a success," company co-founder and game director Jonathan Rogers told me in an interview. "As we started to get closer to release and see pre-sales and stuff like that, suddenly it was like oh crap, this is looking like it might be one of our biggest releases ever, and then it did indeed turn out to be. And that is indeed our largest release by quite a lot that we've ever done."</p>
<p>But intense popularity can change things. What was once intended as a way for dedicated fans to help shape a project ended up feeling more like a full-scale release, which meant development priorities had to change. "And you saw that early on where we started doing a bunch of changes, like nerfing stuff that needed to be nerfed," Rogers said.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Path of Exile 2: Dawn of the Hunt Gameplay Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-CnACIrCOkc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Path of Exile 2: Dawn of the Hunt Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-CnACIrCOkc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-CnACIrCOkc?autoplay=1" title="Path of Exile 2: Dawn of the Hunt Gameplay Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Path of Exile 2: Dawn of the Hunt gameplay trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-CnACIrCOkc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We immediately ran into the situation we would normally expect in the full released game, which is a bunch of players are like, 'oh you're breaking my build', so we had to realise, okay, we have to treat this like it's a released game in this regard and be a bit more careful," he said. Less experimenting, more treating it like a live service operation.</p>
<p>"Whenever you've got players, it derails what your plans are," Rogers added, "and it has to. It's good that it does because it forces you immediately to be responding to what the game needs, which now becomes very obvious because you've got actual players playing it." Devs don't have the time to test some things as intensely as players, collectively, do. That's why we're seeing a big push to expand areas like the endgame now, for example.</p>
<blockquote>"I would be incredibly disappointed if we weren't cracking a million [concurrent players] for the full release."</blockquote>
<p>The other side of intense popularity is unexpected stories related to your game such as the headline-grabbing revelation that <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2025/01/20/elon-musk-finally-admits-to-path-of-exile-2-account-boosting-in-dms/">Elon Musk paid someone to boost his Path of Exile 2 </a>account - play his character for him - for some reason. Presumably bragging rights.</p>
<p>This appears to be against <a href="https://www.pathofexile.com/legal/terms-of-use-and-privacy-policy">the game's Terms of Service</a> - players can't make money by performing services in the game, as a booster would - but Musk doesn't seem to have been reprimanded. So I asked Rogers what the procedure was for dealing with suspected cases of boosting such as this. "I don't really want to comment about that whole drama, to be honest," he said.</p>
<p>To which I asked him what he thought more broadly of Path of Exile 2 being in the news in this way. "I don't know. It was kind of weird," he said. "But it is what it is."</p>
<p>Since release, the concurrent player numbers for Path of Exile 2 have significantly dropped off; a quick glance at <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed">Steam's Most Played chart</a> shows a high point of around 25,000 players today. But this doesn't worry Rogers.</p>
<p>"No, no, not at all. Not at all," he said. "Because the thing is, ultimately, the way we've always developed our game is that it's seasonal. The way people play our game is that they come, they play for a month, they enjoy what they do, they leave, then they come back after the season ends."</p>
<figure data-count="3" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Huntress_Gameplay.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Huntress_Skills_UI.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Huntress_Rhoa_Gameplay.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption>The new Huntress class. She can also summon a Rhoa mount and ride around on it - in combat too. But if she were to fall off it during the fight, the fall can prove fatal. You have to keep a careful eye on your stagger bar. | <span>Image credit: <cite>Grinding Gear Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>There's a pattern to it, Rogers has come to realise. Player numbers dip after your initial release, dipping at around update 0.2, which is what we're getting next week, and then from 0.3 onwards they start to rise again. "This is what happens with action-RPGs," he said. That's what happened with every market GGG launched <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/path-of-exile">Path of Exile 1</a> in.</p>
<p>He's confident, then, Path of Exile 2 can go even bigger than early access <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/path-of-exile-2s-full-release-has-a-65-chance-of-arriving-this-year-says-grinding-gear-games-so-what-could-go-wrong">when it launches in full, potentially this year</a> - and if not this year then shortly after, in early 2026. "100 percent it will be [bigger]," he said. "And the reason for that is because, for that one, you've got the fact that it's going free, and there are a lot of people, of course, who will try a game once it's free, and then they'll discover they enjoy it. I have no doubt it will be bigger.</p>
<p>"Look," he added, "I would be incredibly disappointed if we weren't cracking a million [concurrent players] for the full release, and honestly, I think we can do better than that."</p>
<p>Path of Exile 2 launched in early access in December last year, and I reviewed it, and loved it. It's an action-RPG that considerably ups the risk, making for a more frugal and perilous campaign than in genre-relative, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/diablo-iv">Diablo 4</a>. "Soulslike thrills combine with sky-high production values to make Path of Exile 2 a hugely impressive package, even in early access," I wrote in my <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/path-of-exile-2-early-access-review">Path of Exile 2 early access review</a>.</p>
<p>Update 0.2, which is dubbed Dawn of the Hunt and due next week (4th April), brings a significant amount of new content to the game, including a considerable rework of the endgame, a brand new Huntress class to play as, scores of new items, monsters, and encounters, new ascendency class options, and more. Grinding Gear Games showcased <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/pathofexile">Path of Exile 2 patch 0.2 in detail on Twitch</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>