<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 14:44:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legendary Publisher Acclaim to Return and "Resurrect" Classic IP]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/acclaim-returning-90s-2000s-publisher</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/legendary-publisher-acclaim-to-return-and-resurrect-classic-ip.1124760/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/acclaim-returning-90s-2000s-publisher<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Famed 90s and 2000s publisher Acclaim is to make a return to the games industry, and it seems the studio is looking to "resurrect and revitalize" some of its classic IPs.</p>

<p>Per <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/game-publisher-acclaim-returns-with-focus-on-indie-studios-and-classics" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Gematsu</a>, Acclaim's revival will be headed up by industry veteran Alex Josef, who wasn't among the original founders or executives of Acclaim but who has experience publishing thanks to his time with studios like&nbsp;<em>Turnip Boy&nbsp;</em>publisher Graffiti Games, among others.</p>

<p>Josef says bringing back Acclaim is an "honor", and that the new version of the studio has "already signed some incredible indie titles". In addition, Josef says he wants to "resurrect and revitalize [Acclaim's] beloved portfolio" of intellectual properties, although he doesn't say which ones those might be.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/acclaim-entertainment-returning-turok.jpg?itok=ZTGkLsh2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/acclaim-entertainment-returning-turok.jpg?itok=tclY_hf- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Acclaim's original portfolio of games includes the likes of&nbsp;<em>Turok</em>, plus many more.</figcaption></figure><p>Intriguingly, the new Acclaim's advisory board also counts wrestling legend Jeff Jarrett among its ranks. Jarrett's Global Force Entertainment is helping out with the new version of the studio, and Jarrett says resurrecting Acclaim is a chance to impart "passion and love to a new generation" via "great games".</p>

<p>Some of Acclaim's games, including the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/turok-3-shadow-of-oblivion-remaster-delayed" rel="nofollow"><em>Turok&nbsp;</em>series</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;dark action game&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nightdive-studios-remastering-shadow-man-restoring-cut-content" rel="nofollow"><em>Shadow Man</em></a>, have already returned to modern systems in one form or another, so it'll be interesting to see which of Acclaim's properties it's able to "resurrect".</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with Acclaim, it got its start back in the late 80s, going on to become a prolific and fairly successful publisher throughout the 90s and early 2000s.</p>

<p>For many, however, Acclaim is more well-known for its many controversial marketing ideas, including awarding money to parents who named their baby "Turok", trying to buy ad space on tombstones for&nbsp;<em>Shadow Man: 2econd Coming</em>, and offering to pay UK speeding fines when&nbsp;<em>Burnout 2&nbsp;</em>was released.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/shadow-man-remastered-acclaim.jpg?itok=PhW6X0e- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/shadow-man-remastered-acclaim.jpg?itok=5w28Xb9x 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Would you want a&nbsp;<em>Shadow Man</em>&nbsp;ad on your tombstone?</figcaption></figure><p>Acclaim closed down in 2004 following poor sales, filing for bankruptcy in August that year. The company subsequently sold publishing rights to many of its franchises to other studios.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen what the revived version of Acclaim will do, but it's not the only old-school publishing label to be revived recently.</p>

<p>Back in April last year, Atari announced it would <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atari-infogrames-publishing-revival" rel="nofollow">revive the classic Infogrames label</a>, with the studio going on to acquire the rights to the&nbsp;<em>Totally Reliable Delivery Service&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/surgeon-simulator-acquired-by-infogrames" rel="nofollow">Surgeon Simulator</a>&nbsp;</em>brands.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alienware has a $549 QD-OLED gaming monitor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/623428/dell-alienware-oled-monitor-aw2725d-price-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alienware-has-a-549-qd-oled-gaming-monitor.1124757/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/623428/dell-alienware-oled-monitor-aw2725d-price-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>2024 was the year <a href="https://youtu.be/yYjBf94WY2M?si=tn4aXejPyf_7jfQ9&amp;t=510">OLED cemented its victory</a> — and 2025 might let more gamers actually afford the glorious screens. Today, Alienware says it will try* to bring the price of a QD-OLED gaming panel down to $549 this summer with the AW2725D, a new 27-inch 2560 x 1440 QHD monitor that’ll offer OLED’s incredible blacks and deep colors.</p><p>Outwardly, the AW2725D looks and sounds almost identical to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335564/alienware-27-inch-4k-240hz-oled-price-date">$899 27-inch AW2725Q 4K 240Hz QD-OLED monitor</a> that Alienware is just now <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://www.dell.com/en-us/gaming/alienware" rel="sponsored">putting on sale today</a> — but $350 cheaper, if you can settle for 110 pixels per inch (ppi), rather than the class-leading 166ppi that Alienware’s 4K OLED screen will offer.</p><p>There could be other compromises, too, as Alienware didn’t have spec sheets available by press time… but it’s actually a slightly faster panel at 280Hz versus 240Hz, offers the same 99 percent DCI-P3 color coverage, Delta E&lt;2 color accuracy, and the same small rounded rectangle of an adjustable height stand (see below). Alienware display product manager James Cha tells us it also has the same graphite film heatsink and not-too-aggressive burn-in protection algorithm <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/12/24034953/ces-2024-verge-awards-best-tv-laptop-monitor-gaming-car">I’ve been enjoying</a> in the $1,199 32-inch version of the screen.</p><p>If that $549 panel wasn’t enough to tempt you away from the $899 version, what about a curved 34-inch ultrawide for $799? That’s what Dell is targeting* for the AW3425DW you see above, its latest version of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23011794/alienware-aw3423dw-review-qd-oled-curved-gaming-pc-monitor">the first 3440 x 1440 QD-OLED monitor it wowed us with</a> in 2022.</p><p>There, you’re getting a 240Hz panel (up from 165Hz), HDMI 2.1 fixed rate link instead of TMDS signaling (which should provide enough bandwidth to go above 4K60 HDR over HDMI), a USB-C port with 15W charging, and a new user interface for its onscreen display, all for $100 less* than before.</p><p>Alienware’s also still offering its same three-year burn-in warranty on its QD-OLED panels, where it’ll ship you a new monitor before you have to return the old one. When I asked whether Dell might further extend its warranty now that panel maker Samsung Display offers more protections, Cha says, “That’s something we could look into.”</p><p>Alienware has more new monitors where these came from, including a pair of budget 25-inch and 27-inch Fast IPS screens that start at $249* and $269,* respectively, each using the same new industrial design as the QD-OLED screens. (The 25-inch AW2525HM is a 1080p 320Hz panel coming in the summer; the 27-inch AW2725DM is a 1440p 180Hz screen arriving in two days.)</p><p>It’s unlikely that Dell has an exclusive on the Samsung panels inside these new monitors, so don’t be surprised if other 27-inch and 34-inch QD-OLED screens hit the market at new low prices, too. In fact, Samsung Electronics recently reduced the price of its 27-inch Odyssey G61SD (1440p 240Hz QD-OLED) to $549 in an extended sale <a rel="sponsored" href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Odyssey-FreeSyncTM-Warranty-LS27DG610SNXZA/dp/B0DHJD894W?th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">at Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-27-odyssey-qd-oled-g6-g61s-qhd-240hz-0-03ms-freesync-premium-pro-and-g-sync-compatible-gaming-monitor-with-hdr-silver-metal-with-slim-design/6604804.p?skuId=6604804">Best Buy</a>, and <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/computing/monitors/oled-monitor/27-odyssey-oled-g6-g61sd-qhd-240hz-0-03ms-freesync-premium-pro-gaming-monitor-with-sleek-metal-design-ls27dg610snxza/">its own store</a>, perhaps in anticipation of successors.</p><div><p><em>*We’ve used asterisks to indicate that Dell apparently can’t promise exact prices for these quite yet, with all of them subject to change — possibly due to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/620865/trump-tariffs-china-canada-mexico-march-4">President Donald Trump’s tariffs on China that are set to go into effect today</a>.</em></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia GeForce RTX 5070 review: definitely not a $549 RTX 4090]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/gpu-reviews/623441/nvidia-rtx-5070-review-test-benchmark</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5070-review-definitely-not-a-549-rtx-4090.1124754/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/gpu-reviews/623441/nvidia-rtx-5070-review-test-benchmark<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The RTX 50-series launch hasn’t gone smoothly so far. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/603863/nvidia-rtx-5090-out-of-stock-paper-launch">Severely limited stock</a>, high prices, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/618748/nvidia-admits-the-rtx-5080-is-affecte">manufacturing issues</a> have left PC gamers frustrated. Now, Nvidia is trying to get things heading in the right direction with the RTX 5070, a GPU that it promised would deliver $1,599 RTX 4090-like performance for $549.</p><p>It doesn’t, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/8/24338999/nvidia-rtx-5070-vs-rtx4090-performance-price">it was never going to</a>. It’s about 20 percent faster than the RTX 4070 and a bare 4 percent faster than last year’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24039832/nvidia-rtx-4070-super-review-gpu-graphics-card-benchmark-test">RTX 4070 Super</a>. It’s a solid card for 1440p gaming, just like the RTX 4070, but as with the rest of the 50-series cards, Nvidia’s performance claims rely on Frame Generation rather than meaningful improvements to rendering.</p><p>At $549, the RTX 5070 will also come up against <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/621339/amd-radeon-9070-xt-price-release-date-gpu">AMD’s new $549 Radeon RX 9070</a> and $599 Radeon RX 9070 XT when they launch on March 6th. If AMD manages to beat Nvidia’s RTX 5070 or come close to the $749 RTX 5070 Ti, that’s going to put a lot of much-needed pressure on Nvidia’s pricing.</p><p>You might want to wait a couple of days to purchase anything until we can talk about those AMD cards.</p><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->550</span></p><div><div><h4>The Good</h4><ul><li>Compact size</li><li>Great 1440p performance</li><li>Power draw isn’t significantly higher than RTX 40 series</li></ul></div><div><h4>The Bad</h4><ul><li>12GB of VRAM</li><li>Definitely not RTX 4090 levels of performance</li><li>Multi Frame Generation is less effective at 4K</li></ul></div></div></div><div><p id="1440p-and-4k-benchmarks"><h2><strong>1440p and 4K benchmarks</strong><br></h2></p></div><div><div><p id="test-machine"><h2>Test machine:</h2></p></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>CPU:</strong> AMD Ryzen 9 9800X3D</span></li><li><span><strong>CPU cooler:</strong> Corsair H150i Elite LCD</span></li><li><span><strong>Motherboard:</strong> Gigabyte Aorus Master</span></li><li><span><strong>RAM:</strong> 32GB G.Skill DDR5-6000</span></li><li><span><strong>Storage:</strong> Samsung 970 Evo Plus 2TB</span></li><li><span><strong>PSU: </strong>Corsair HX1000W</span></li><li><span><strong>Case: </strong>Streacom BC1 V2 open benchtable</span></li></ul></div></div><p>The RTX 5070 Founders Edition card I’ve been testing looks like a miniature RTX 5090 with a slightly darker paint job and no LEDs. It’s still a two-slot card, and it retains the two fans at the bottom that direct cooler air over the card and exhaust it out of the top, as well as the slightly angled 12V-2x6 power connector that makes it easier to fit into more cases. </p><p>I really like the size. It feels like the ideal companion for a small form factor PC, and I don’t think I’d be too worried about the heat this little GPU would generate or the power draw (more on that later).</p><p>I’ve been testing the RTX 5070 card with AMD’s Ryzen 9 9800X3D processor and Asus’ 32-inch 4K OLED PG32UCDP. I’ve put it up against the previous <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23678453/nvidia-rtx-4070-review-gpu-graphics-card-benchmark-test">RTX 4070</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24039832/nvidia-rtx-4070-super-review-gpu-graphics-card-benchmark-test">RTX 4070 Super</a> cards, as well as the more expensive <a href="https://www.theverge.com/gpu-reviews/615075/nvidia-rtx-5070-ti-review-test-benchmark">RTX 5070 Ti</a> and AMD’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23499697/amd-radeon-rx-7900-xt-xtx-review-benchmarks-price">RX 7900 XT</a>, which you can see in the benchmark charts below.</p><p>I’ve tested a variety of games at both 1440p and 4K, including more demanding titles like <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> and benchmarking favorites like <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> and <em>Shadow of the Tomb Raider</em>. All games have been tested at very high or Ultra settings, so you’ll get a good idea of the RTX 5070’s true capabilities, though you’ll probably want to drop the settings for better frame rates.</p><p>As with every other 50-series card, the 5070 isn’t much of an upgrade in raw performance over the last generation. Without DLSS or RT enabled, the RTX 5070 is 18 percent faster than an RTX 4070 at 1440p and 22 percent faster at 4K; compared to the 4070 Super, it’s only 3 percent faster at 1440p and 4 percent at 4K. You’ll see a solid boost if you’re coming from a 30-series card or older, though; it’s nearly 55 percent faster than the RTX 3070 Ti. </p><p>The RTX 5070 is still largely a 1440p card, which has been the sweet spot for Nvidia’s 70 lineup for a few generations. While it delivers playable frame rates for most games in my test suite at 4K resolution, you’ll need to enable DLSS in some titles if you want to be over 60fps consistently with all the settings maxed out. If you’re willing to drop some quality settings and enable DLSS, the RTX 5070 becomes a lot more capable.</p><p>If you’re looking for better 4K performance, stepping up to an RTX 5070 Ti gets you about 29 percent higher frame rates, but you’ll pay at least 35 percent more, assuming either card stays anywhere near MSRP.</p><p>My main concern about the RTX 5070 for 4K gaming is its 12GB of VRAM. I’ve already run into performance issues testing entry-level 4K gaming with the 8GB RTX 3070 Ti in certain games, and I don’t think 12GB of VRAM is going to fare well in the future, either. This is particularly relevant when AMD is about to ship its RX 9070 and RX 9070 XT with 16GB of VRAM. I wish Nvidia had done the same.</p><div><p id="dlss-4-and-multi-frame-gen"><h2><strong>DLSS 4 and Multi Frame Gen</strong></h2></p></div><p>It was obvious from the start that Nvidia’s claims that the RTX 5070 would match the RTX 4090 relied entirely on DLSS 4’s Multi Frame Generation. The 50-series cards have up to 4x frame generation with DLSS 4, so they can generate up to three additional frames per frame rendered traditionally. The RTX 4090 can use DLSS 4, including Nvidia’s updated transformer models, but only has 2x frame generation.</p><p>It’s only the fact that the 5070 can generate three times as many interstitial frames as the RTX 4090 that lets it appear anywhere near as fast. In <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> at 4K with Ultra settings, ray tracing enabled, and 4x Frame Generation, the RTX 5070 averaged 122fps. The older RTX 4090, with 2x Frame Generation, managed 128fps, and it’s rendering far more of them the old-fashioned way.</p><p>If you take Nvidia at face value and assume performance equals frame rate, the RTX 4090 is still 5 to 10 percent faster than the RTX 5070 when frame generation is cranked up all the way on both cards. In traditional rendering, the RTX 4090 is 75 percent faster on average. Without ray tracing or frame generation, the RTX 4090 got 76fps in <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>, and the RTX 4070 got 48fps. </p><p>As I’ve discussed in previous reviews, and as even Nvidia’s materials show, multi-frame generation makes gameplay <em>look </em>smoother, but the game will still feel sluggish if the base frame rate is low. You can really feel it on the RTX 5070, especially in 4K. With DLSS Super Resolution and x4 Multi Frame Generation, <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> hit 77fps at Ultra settings with full path tracing, but it still feels like the 24fps it is before Multi Frame Gen is applied.</p><p>Multi Frame Gen makes more sense at 1440p because the base frame rates are a lot higher. I wouldn’t buy the RTX 5070 because of Multi Frame Generation alone, but the DLSS 4 improvements and the new transformer model have certainly improved image quality for me in a variety of games, and you can even force DLSS 4 in unsupported games through Nvidia’s new app. But you don’t need an RTX 5070 for DLSS 4, so if you don’t care about Multi Frame Generation and you can somehow find an RTX 4070 Super at a reasonable price, it’s still a good choice.</p><p>Beyond gaming, the RTX 5070 can also deliver better performance in video editing or for AI workloads. In Procyon’s AI XL (FP16) test, the RTX 5070 is nearly 28 percent faster than the RTX 4070, or nearly 4 percent faster than the RTX 4070 Super. For video editing, I tested the RTX 5070 with PugetBench’s DaVinci Resolve test and found it’s 11 percent faster than the RTX 4070 and nearly 10 percent faster than the RTX 4070 Super.</p><div><p id="power-draw-and-heat"><h2><strong>Power draw and heat</strong></h2></p></div><p>Nvidia recommends a 650-watt power supply for the RTX 5070, which is exactly the same as both the RTX 4070 and RTX 4070 Super. The total graphics power has increased to 250 watts in total, up by 50 watts over the RTX 4070 and just 30 watts over the RTX 4070 Super.</p><p>At 4K resolution, the RTX 5070 averaged 210 watts across the nine games tested — 25 watts more than the RTX 4070 averaged (185 watts) and just four watts more than the RTX 4070 Super (206 watts). The RTX 5070 hit its max power draw of 250 watts during the <em>Metro Exodus Extreme</em> benchmark, and it hit a maximum temperature of 77 degrees Celsius in that same test on my open bench, compared to 67C on both the RTX 4070 and 4070 Super.</p><p>I’m once again impressed that Nvidia hasn’t massively increased the power requirements here, but it looks like the RTX 5070 will run hotter than previous cards. While the RTX 5090 is certainly power-hungry, both the RTX 5070 and RTX 5070 Ti are a lot more efficient, while delivering gains over the previous-generation cards.</p><div><p><figcaption><em>The RTX 5070 on top of an RTX 5080.</em></figcaption></p></div><p>I feel like a broken record saying that the RTX 5070 continues the trend of modest generational improvements with the RTX 50 series, but unfortunately, that’s the case here again. This is really an ideal 1440p card thanks to the high frame rates at that resolution, or an entry-level 4K card if you’re willing to drop settings down and enable DLSS.</p><p>But it’s hard to recommend the RTX 5070 until the question hanging over it has been answered: AMD’s RX 9070-series cards. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/621339/amd-radeon-9070-xt-price-release-date-gpu">AMD surprised everyone</a> with a $549 price tag for its RX 9070 and $599 for its RX 9070 XT last week. Both cards are challenging Nvidia’s pricing for its RTX 5070 and RTX 5070 Ti, and if they’re good enough, they might put pressure on Nvidia to adjust its pricing.</p><p>Until we know how all four cards compare, I would hold off on buying an RTX 5070 on day one. AMD might just surprise us with its performance as well as its pricing.</p><p><em>Photography by Tom Warren / The Verge</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get Ahead In Path Of Exile 2 By Farming Uniques]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/path-of-exile-2-farm-uniques-guide-grinding-gear-games-1851767532</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-ahead-in-path-of-exile-2-by-farming-uniques.1124745/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/path-of-exile-2-farm-uniques-guide-grinding-gear-games-1851767532<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="1cf63d2c523558b4a9f25356eb1e0ab7" data-recommend-id="image://1cf63d2c523558b4a9f25356eb1e0ab7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Red beams of magic sweep the battlefield in Path of Exile 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Red beams of magic sweep the battlefield in Path of Exile 2." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Grinding Gear Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1cf63d2c523558b4a9f25356eb1e0ab7" data-recommend-id="image://1cf63d2c523558b4a9f25356eb1e0ab7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Red beams of magic sweep the battlefield in Path of Exile 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Whether you followed an intricate online build guide, or decided to wing the entire experience and choose fabulous skills and passives, <em>Path of Exile 2</em> offers a metric ton of variety regarding how you grow in power. But one of the most essential aspects isn’t your class or abilities; it’s the gear you wield. If you’re rocking standard-tier gear, you’re in for a bad time. You need to up your game by farming uniques in <em>Path of Exile 2</em> to stand toe-to-toe with end-game bosses and other players.</p><h2 id="h6748"><a id=""></a><strong>Increase your odds of acquiring unique item drops in PoE 2</strong></h2><p>While you’re not guaranteed to receive a unique drop from any activity in the game, you can increase your odds through farming, utilizing key items, and gambling a bit with your gold. The latter is, of course, one of the more challenging and bland ways to gain power, but some people like that challenge.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e23fc5dd2cfa9fafb63a4e751a3a61ea" data-recommend-id="image://e23fc5dd2cfa9fafb63a4e751a3a61ea" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Fighting the Mighty Silverfist boss in Path of Exile 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Fighting the Mighty Silverfist boss in Path of Exile 2." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Grinding Gear Games / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e23fc5dd2cfa9fafb63a4e751a3a61ea" data-recommend-id="image://e23fc5dd2cfa9fafb63a4e751a3a61ea" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Fighting the Mighty Silverfist boss in Path of Exile 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The most common way for most players to obtain a rare, unique item in <em>Path of Exile 2</em> is by farming. You can either farm high-level enemies throughout key zones, or farm bosses across the campaign and the countless optional bosses scattered about each act. In total, there are around 100 bosses in the game, and they all have a chance to drop rare and unique items that bolster your power levels.</p><p>It’s usually best to visit a zone that’s two or three levels below your current one; that way, you stand a chance at farming rather than simply surviving an enemy’s onslaught. Furthermore, choose a boss you genuinely enjoy fighting, as you’ll wind up repeating the battle repeatedly by clearing the instance and starting a fresh one.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="455b19492ee22e6a22bab4a44015d4be" data-recommend-id="image://455b19492ee22e6a22bab4a44015d4be" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A unique random shield in Path of Exile 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A unique random shield in Path of Exile 2." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Grinding Gear Games / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="455b19492ee22e6a22bab4a44015d4be" data-recommend-id="image://455b19492ee22e6a22bab4a44015d4be" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A unique random shield in Path of Exile 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>An Orb of Chance is a rare gemstone-like item that offers a chance to evolve a normal item into a unique item, or outright destroy the item. It’s a gamble. You can obtain an Orb of Chance by:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Disenchanting magical equipment and items by speaking to Una (Act 1), Zarka (Act 2), or Servi (Act 3).</li><li>Slaying enemies throughout any zone in the game.</li><li>Visit a Currency Exchange NPC, which unlocks upon Cruel Difficulty after finishing Act 3 on Normal.</li></ul></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="dfb43a8b6b4431bf1560e7655187faf1" data-recommend-id="image://dfb43a8b6b4431bf1560e7655187faf1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A random item purchase from vendors in Path of Exile 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A random item purchase from vendors in Path of Exile 2." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Grinding Gear Games / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dfb43a8b6b4431bf1560e7655187faf1" data-recommend-id="image://dfb43a8b6b4431bf1560e7655187faf1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A random item purchase from vendors in Path of Exile 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Alternatively, you can speak to one of the many vendors spread across each Act of the game. Some of them sell random items that offer a slight chance to drop a unique variant, but it will cost you thousands of gold per item, and there’s no guarantee you’ll receive a unique item in exchange.</p><p>Depending on the vendor you speak with, they may sell two-handed weapons, crossbows, various armor pieces, or even jewelry—all randomized yet expensive.</p><hr><p>To successfully grind anything in<em> Path of Exile 2</em>, consider <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/path-exile-2-solo-play-best-class-witch-mercenary-1851755253&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/path-exile-2-solo-play-best-class-witch-mercenary-1851755253">choosing the best solo class </a></span>to help you level through Wraeclast! <em>PoE 2</em> is available now in Early Access on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Pass adds 33 Immortals, Mullet Madjack, One Lonely Outpost, and more in early March]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/game-pass-adds-33-immortals-mullet-madjack-one-lonely-outpost-and-more-in-early-march</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-pass-adds-33-immortals-mullet-madjack-one-lonely-outpost-and-more-in-early-march.1124739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/game-pass-adds-33-immortals-mullet-madjack-one-lonely-outpost-and-more-in-early-march<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>No More Heroes 3, Yakuza 5, Yakuza 6, and more leaving soon.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Microsoft has <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/03/04/xbox-game-pass-march-2025-wave-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> new titles coming to Game Pass in early March, including <em><a title="Games > 33 Immortals [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/33-immortals">33 Immortals</a></em> in Early Access, <em><a title="Games > Mullet MadJack [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mullet-madjack">Mullet MadJack</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > One Lonely Outpost" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/one-lonely-outpost">One Lonely Outpost</a></em>, and more.</p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p>■ <strong>Available Today</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Monster Train" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/monster-train">Monster Train</a></em></strong> (Cloud, Console, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,507 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>) Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard – Returning to the Game Pas library, <em>Monster Train</em> brings a new strategic layer to <a title="Genres > Roguelike [303 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> deckbuilding, with three vertical playing fields to defend. Hell has frozen over and only you can protect the final burning pyre from the forces of heaven and restore the inferno.</li></ul><p><strong>■ Coming Soon</strong></p><p><strong>March 5</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Galacticare [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/galacticare">Galacticare</a></em></strong> (<a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,817 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series X|S</a>) Now with Game Pass Standard – You are the Director of Galacticare, an interstellar healthcare company and quasi-voluntary savior of the galaxy (for cash). Build hospitals and recruit staff to satisfy the whims of various alien species and cure their bizarre illnesses. Save the (literal) galaxy in story mode, or head into sandbox to design the hospital of your dreams.</li></ul><p><strong>March 6</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em>One Lonely Outpost</em></strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass – Turn a barren alien planet into a flourishing home in this cozy, science-fiction farming sim! Terraform the land, grow organic or genetically modified crops, and raise adorable robo-livestock. Harness renewable energy, deploy drones to fish and forage, befriend and romance settlers, and uncover the planet’s secrets as your colony thrives.</li></ul><p><strong>March 11</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em>Enter the Gungeon</em></strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard – Returning to the Game Pass library, <em>Enter the Gungeon</em> is a gunfight dungeon crawler following a band of misfits seeking to shoot, loot, dodge, roll and table-flip their way to personal absolution by reaching the legendary Gungeon’s ultimate treasure: the gun that can kill the past.</li></ul><p><strong>March 13</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em>Mullet MadJack</em></strong> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass – <em>Mullet MadJack</em> is a high-octane-<a title="Genres > Action [2,531 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,019 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> that puts you directly inside a classic anime. Pick your favorite weapon and reach the last floor to beat your best time or try again. Haste makes waste… of your enemies!</li></ul><p><strong>March 18</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em>33 Immortals</em></strong> (Game Preview) (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass – Available on day one! <em>33 Immortals</em> is a <a title="Genres > Co-Op [236 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> action-roguelike for 33 players. Play as a damned soul, and rebel against God’s final judgment. Dive straight into epic, 33-player cooperative battles with instant “pick-up and raid” matchmaking. Cooperate with your allies to survive against hordes of monsters and massive, challenging bosses. Expand your arsenal and equip powerful new relics to permanently upgrade your soul.</li></ul><p><strong>■ In Case You Missed It</strong></p><p><strong>Available Now</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Balatro [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/balatro">Balatro</a></em></strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard – This award winning, poker-inspired roguelike deck builder is all about creating powerful synergies and winning big. Play illegal poker hands, discover game-changing jokers, and trigger adrenaline-pumping, outrageous combos. You’re going to need every edge you can get to reach the boss, beat the final ante, and secure victory.</li></ul><p><strong>■ Downloadable Content / Game Updates</strong></p><p><strong>Available Now</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Overwatch 2 [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/overwatch-2">Overwatch 2</a></em> – Season 15: Honor and Glory</strong> – Heroes, the battlefield is calling, and the fight is evolving. Season 15: Honor and Glory is here and pulling no punches with the debut of the Perks system, a fresh Competitive Year, and a treasure trove of rewards that make every victory count. Plus, Game Pass members can supercharge their progression with an additional 10% XP boost.</li></ul><p><strong>March 11</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024">Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024</a></em> – World Update XIX: Brazil</strong> – World Update XIX delivers the South American countries of Brazil, Guyana, Suriname, and French Guiana in fresh, vivid detail to the <a title="Games > Microsoft Flight Simulator (2020) [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/microsoft-flight-simulator-2020">Microsoft Flight Simulator</a> world. Discover new points of interest, Bush Trips, Landing Challenges, and more. Available for both <em>Microsoft Flight Simulator</em> and <em>Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024</em>.</li></ul><p><strong>March 13</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Forza Motorsport (2023) [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/forza-motorsport-2023">Forza Motorsport</a></em>: Velocity Month</strong> – Get ready to race! Velocity Month invites you to become a master of speed and cornering using some of the most advanced cars ever manufactured. Compete in new-to-Motorsport cars like the 2024 Lamborghini #63 Squadra Corse SC63, 2020 Oreca #38 07, and 2023 Porsche 911 GT3 RS. Plus, new driver suits, and more.</li></ul><p><strong>■ Game Pass Ultimate Perks</strong></p><p>Enjoy these Perks and more in the Game Pass section on your console, <a title="Platforms > Xbox [25,555 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> mobile app, or Xbox app on Windows PC to find new in-game content, consumables, and offers included with your Game Pass Ultimate membership. New Perks are added regularly.</p><p><strong>Available Now</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Companies > Electronic Arts [1,762 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts">EA</a> <a title="Genres > Sports [599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/sports">Sports</a> <a title="Games > F1 24 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/f1-24">F1 24</a></em>: Champions Icons Pack</strong> – Add some legends to the race with the Champions Icons Pack, available with your EA Play Membership.</li><li><strong>Time Waits #1 from <a title="Platforms > DS [55 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/ds">DS</a>TLRY: Free Digital Collectible Comic Book</strong> – Blue, an ex-soldier sent from the future to our present, tries to leave his violent past behind. But his ruthless overlords return, demanding he complete his mission. A new science-fiction <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> from DSTLRY.</li></ul><p><strong>■ Leaving March 15</strong></p><p>The following games will be leaving the library soon. Be sure to jump back in before they go and remember to use your 20% membership discount on your purchase to keep them in your library.</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Evil West [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/evil-west">Evil West</a></em> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Lies of P [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lies-of-p">Lies of P</a></em> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li><em><a title="Games > No More Heroes [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/no-more-heroes">No More Heroes</a> 3</em> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Solar Ash [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/solar-ash">Solar Ash</a></em> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li><em>SpongeBob SquarePants: Battle for Bikini Bottom – Rehydrated</em> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li><em><a title="Series > Yakuza (Like a Dragon) [53 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/yakuza">Yakuza</a> 5 Remastered</em> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li><em>Yakuza 6: The Song of Life</em> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cozy platformer ILA: A Frosty Glide to be published by First Break Labs for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/cozy-platformer-ila-a-frosty-glide-to-be-published-by-first-break-labs-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cozy-platformer-ila-a-frosty-glide-to-be-published-by-first-break-labs-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.1124733/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/cozy-platformer-ila-a-frosty-glide-to-be-published-by-first-break-labs-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > First Break Labs [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/first-break-labs">First Break Labs</a> will publish <a title="Companies > Magic Rain Studios" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/magic-rain-studios">Magic Rain Studios</a>-developed cozy <a title="Genres > Platformer [626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > ILA: A Frosty Glide" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ila-a-frosty-glide">ILA: A Frosty Glide</a></em>, the companies announced. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,975 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,817 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,773 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,822 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,733 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,507 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1560160/ILA_A_Frosty_Glide/" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2025. <span id="more-947932"></span></p><p>“We have had our eye on <em>ILA: A Frosty Glide</em> for a while and our team at First Break Labs was impressed by the overwhelming support and enthusiasm that <em>ILA: A Frosty Glide</em> received during its <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/magicrainstudios/ila-a-frosty-glide-cozy-witch-skatebroom-adventure-game" target="_blank">recent Kickstarter</a> and we knew we had to partner with them to bring this unique game to console and PC gamers,” said First Break Labs chief publishing officer Alfonso Cubias in a press release. “It’s clear that Magic Rain Studios is working on something special, and we’re happy to partner with them to support their mission of enriching lives and bringing joy to every player through <a title="Genres > Crafting [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting games</a>.”</p><p>Magic Rain Studios game director Italo D. added, “From the very beginning, we knew <em>ILA: A Frosty Glide</em> was a game that many people would enjoy, and we wanted it to reach as many players as possible. That meant finding the right partner, one who truly shared our vision for quality, creativity, and player joy. Fortunately, our Kickstarter campaign caught the attention of First Break Labs, and we immediately connected over our shared values, which was incredibly important to us. The First Break Labs team has an incredible track record of supporting unique and innovative games, and their expertise gives us full confidence that <em>ILA</em> will reach new heights. We’re excited to work together to make this the best experience possible for players around the world.”</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Ila is a curious and kind witch-in-training about to embark on the <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> of her life.</p><p>Coco, a small and affectionate black cat, was the last connection Ila had to her mother. From the moment Ila’s mother placed the tiny, dark-furred kitten into her arms, Ila understood that this fragile little ball of fur wasn’t just a pet—it was her responsibility, her companion, and her most loyal friend.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>But one fateful night, Coco vanished.</p><p>After Coco’s disappearance, Ila began experiencing dreams that revealed glimpses of an unknown island where Coco, fragile and seemingly lost in the cold, calls her toward an adventure she can’t ignore. With her trusty skatebroom, Ila sets out to explore this mysterious island and find her lost companion, Coco.</p><p>In <em>ILA: A Frosty Glide</em>, players arrive on a whimsical island with snowy mountains and cozy Scandinavian vibes. Immerse yourself in this charming small open world as ILA, a spirited young witch-in-training, who embarks on an intriguing adventure fueled by determination and her trusty skatebroom to find her lost kitty Coco. Transform your journey into an adventure of learning and overcoming, as you solve platform puzzles defying gravity and collect valuables to enhance ILA’s appearance and abilities. All of this while listening to its beautiful original soundtrack</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Glide Around</strong> – Who needs a broom when you have a skatebroom? Soar through snowy mountains and enchanted forests, feel the wind as you cross stunning landscapes. <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter and upgrade the magic of your to soar higher and farther.</li><li><strong>Discover Secret Places</strong> – Explore ILA’s small open world at your own pace and relax. Find hidden nooks, uncover treasures, and unlock secrets flying on your skatebroom. Each discovery rewards you with valuable items and deeper lore, enriching your magical journey.</li><li><strong>Witchy Customization</strong> – Collect special items and coins to personalize ILA’s outfit with stylish hats, capes, and skatebrooms to reflect your unique style. As you progress, access new skatebroom upgrades to improve ILA’s flying powers.</li><li><strong>Immersive Soundtrack</strong> – Feel the magic and enjoy the captivating original soundtrack composed by Joaquim Scandurra (Sku), which builds up and grows with you as you approach the summit.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Publisher Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="ILA: A Frosty Glide - Game Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zv7B78FEq_4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mullet MadJack coming to Xbox Series on March 13]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/mullet-madjack-coming-to-xbox-series-on-march-13</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mullet-madjack-coming-to-xbox-series-on-march-13.1124730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/mullet-madjack-coming-to-xbox-series-on-march-13<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Fast-paced first-person shooter currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Hammer95 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hammer95">Hammer95</a> Studios will release anime-inspired fast-paced <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,615 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> Mullet MadJack for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,817 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,822 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> on March 13, the developer announced. It will also be available via Game Pass.</p><p><em>Mullet MadJack</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2111190/MULLET_MAD_JACK/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/mullet_madjack" target="_blank">GOG</a> on May 15, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>We are in the 90s… 2090 to be precise. <em><a title="Games > Mullet MadJack [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mullet-madjack">Mullet Mad Jack</a></em>&nbsp;is a frantic first-person <a title="Genres > Action [2,531 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> set in a vintage anime world.</p><p>In this future, man and the internet have merged into a new being. This being needs dopamine every 10 seconds, or else it will die!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>This is the “Peace System” and it is ruled by the ultra wealthy A.I. robots.</p><p>Those who put their 10 seconds of life on the line to kill the robots are called Moderators!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>You are Mullet Mad Jack, and you must kill enemies to refill your 10 seconds of life.</li><li>Beat randomly-generated stages full of exciting new obstacles at each chapter!</li><li>Cleverly build your character every floor, in a <a title="Genres > Roguelite [220 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> experience.</li><li>Defeat the mysterious masterminds and experience the ultimate 90s old school anime campaign!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Platforms > Xbox [25,555 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="MULLET MADJACK - XBOX GAME PASS Release Date Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fcv3-uiIq9c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Civilization 7's Ongoing Issues, A New Patch Launches Today Without Planned Event]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amid-civilization-7s-ongoing-issues-a-new-patch-launches-today-without-planned-event/1100-6529842/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amid-civilization-7s-ongoing-issues-a-new-patch-launches-today-without-planned-event.1124727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amid-civilization-7s-ongoing-issues-a-new-patch-launches-today-without-planned-event/1100-6529842/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529842">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Firaxis is focused on quality-of-life improvements with Sid Meier's Civilization VII, resulting in a previously announced in-game event being pushed back to a future date. As such, it's not included alongside the new patch rolling out today, which brings UI improvements and the reintroduction of cross-play between PC and consoles to the strategy game.</p><p dir="ltr">Called Update 1.1.0, <a href="https://civilization.2k.com/civ-vii/news/civ-vii-update-check-in-feb-27/" rel="nofollow ">the Civilization website</a> notes that the planned Natural Wonder Battle event has been "postponed to a later update." Instead, Firaxis is using this patch to address player feedback. That includes "UI adjustments," major alterations to "the Modern Age's Cultural Legacy Path and Victory," and a "balance pass on several Mementos." The Bermuda Triangle will also be a new discoverable natural wonder.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-quality-of-life-fixes-are-inbound-starting-with-its-ui/1100-6529313/">Civilization VII quality-of-life fixes have been targeted</a> by Firaxis even before the strategy game's full launch (there was an early-access release). Last month, the developer released <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-civilization-7-patch-takes-aim-at-text-issues-and-war-hungry-ai-opponents/1100-6529386/">a patch that took aim at text issues and missing leader portraits</a>. Looking ahead, it's currently scheduled for Civilization VII to receive Update 1.1.1 on March 25, featuring further UI improvements as well as AI adjustments regarding scouting and settling.</p><p dir="ltr">For more, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-review/1900-6418332/">Civilization VII review</a>. We also have an extensive <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-guides-hub/1100-6529111/">guides hub for the strategy game</a>, which will be <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-vii-vr-lets-you-build-your-cities-on-a-virtual-reality-tabletop/1100-6529332/">getting a VR version for Meta Quest 3 and 3S platforms </a>this spring. Below are additional patch notes for Update 1.1.0:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">New Natural Wonder to discover: Bermuda Triangle (free to all players)</li><li dir="ltr">Additional UI adjustments, polish, and addressing of reported issues</li><li dir="ltr">Significant changes to the Modern Age's Cultural Legacy Path and Victory; AI leaders will also be better at completing a Cultural Victory (so expect fewer Explorer Unit stacks!)</li><li dir="ltr">Now able to convert Holy Cities in the Exploration Age. Note that when players create their own Missionary Units, they will always follow the player’s chosen Religion</li><li dir="ltr">Naval Units will be able to disperse Coastal Independent Powers</li><li dir="ltr">Balance pass on several Mementos</li><li dir="ltr">Refinements to the Army Unpacking action</li><li dir="ltr">Addressing reported issues with multiplayer and adding friends with a 2K Account</li><li dir="ltr">For console players: all prior updates from Update 1.0.1 Patches 1, 2, and 3 will be implemented, in addition to the items noted above</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529808&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/space-marine-2-dev-apologizes-to-players-says-the-game-wont-become-a-live-service-title\/1100-6529808\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529750&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-first-major-update-will-add-a-lot-in-april\/1100-6529750\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529831&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-patch-coming-tuesday-but-dont-expect-it-to-improve-performance\/1100-6529831\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529818&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sonic-movie-reacts-to-shrek-5s-divisive-character-redesigns\/1100-6529818\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529782&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-5s-new-enhanced-pc-edition-how-to-preload-and-transfer-story-progress-for-free\/1100-6529782\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529806&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/pokemon-go-march-2025-events-raids-spotlight-hours-community-days-and-more\/1100-6529806\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529803&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-season-8-delayed-but-will-feature-return-of-an-old-friend\/1100-6529803\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529810&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/it-finally-happened-we-got-john-cena-heel-turn-before-gta-6\/1100-6529810\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529744&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-ai-companions-sos-flare-guide\/1100-6529744\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529749&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-tempered-monsters-artian-weapons\/1100-6529749\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529662&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-essential-free-games-for-march-2025\/1100-6529662\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529695&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/8bitdos-new-ultimate-2-controller-sounds-very-impressive-and-its-available-now\/1100-6529695\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529829&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-thing-remastered-is-getting-a-collectible-deluxe-edition-for-a-budget-price\/1100-6529829\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529621&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-all-oasis-retreat-star-path-duties-and-how-to-complete-them\/1100-6529621\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529777&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/psvr-2-horizon-call-of-the-mountain-bundle-gets-permanent-200-price-drop\/1100-6529777\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529797&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-change-appearance-guide\/1100-6529797\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529766&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-3-expected-start-date-og-style-rumors-and-leaks-so-far\/1100-6529766\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's our first batch of Xbox Game Pass titles for March]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-our-first-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-titles-for-march</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-our-first-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-titles-for-march.1124724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-our-first-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-titles-for-march<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>33 Immortals! Monster Train! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/33-immortals-image-with-an-Xbox-logo-overlayed-ontop.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microsoft/Thunder Lotus/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Microsoft has announced its first wave of Game Pass titles for March.</p>
<p>Day one releases with this batch of games include co-op action-roguelike 33 Immortals. "Play as a damned soul, and rebel against God's final judgment. Dive straight into epic, 33-player co-op battles with instant 'pick-up and raid' matchmaking," reads the official blurb. "Cooperate with your allies to survive against hordes of monsters and massive, challenging bosses. Expand your arsenal and equip powerful new relics to permanently upgrade your soul."</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the critically acclaimed deck-building roguelike Monster Train is making its return to the service across Cloud, Console, and PC.</p>
<p>Here's everything coming to Game Pass in the coming weeks.</p>
<ul>
<li>Monster Train - Cloud, Console, and PC via Game Pass Standard, Ultimate and PC Game Pass -  4th March</li>
<li>Galacticare - Xbox Series X/S, now with Game Pass Standard - 5th March</li>
<li>One Lonely Outpost - Cloud, Console and PC via Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass - 6th March</li>
<li>Enter the Gungeon - Cloud, Console and PC via Game Pass Standard, Ultimate and PC Game Pass - 11th March</li>
<li>Mullet Madjack - Cloud, PC and Xbox Series X/S via Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass - 13th March</li>
<li>33 Immortals (Game Preview) - Cloud, PC and Xbox Series X/S via Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass - 18th March</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Does Anyone Really Want Long Games Anymore? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D9-4YFvps5k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In addition, and as is the case with every new batch of games, the following titles will be leaving Game Pass on 15th March:</p>
<ul>
<li>Evil West (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Lies of P (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>No More Heroes 3 (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Solar Ash (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>SpongeBob SquarePants: Battle for Bikini Bottom – Rehydrated (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Yakuza 5 Remastered (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Yakuza 6: The Song of Life (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
</ul>
<p>If you want to keep playing these games after they leave Game Pass, you'll need to purchase them. On the plus side, Game Pass subscribers get a 20 percent discount.</p>
<p>For everything else in Microsoft's subscription service, you can check out our handy <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-game-pass-games-list-this-month-price-6400">Xbox Game Pass guide</a> detailing the many titles available.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Repentance, Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds’ Second Update, Is Out Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/repentance-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-second-update-is-out-next-week/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/repentance-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds%E2%80%99-second-update-is-out-next-week.1124706/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/repentance-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-second-update-is-out-next-week/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, ArenaNet announced the release date for Repentance, the second free update for <a href="https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-finally-launched-bringing-in-housing-mechanism-new-raids-much-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds</a>. The content patch is scheduled to go live on public servers on Tuesday, March 11th, introducing a host of new rewards and challenging activities for players of the MMORPG, as well as a new map, the Mistburned Barrens.</p>
<p>Deep within the ruins of Bava Nisos lies the Mists Gate, which brought the otherworldly titans to Tyria. Players will delve into the secrets of the mysterious Mursaat, long a source of legend dating back to the original Guild Wars, and confront their arcane experiments that have left their lands riven with spectral torment and bloodstone magic.</p>
<p>Repentance will feature a variety of new rewards, including a new weapon and armor set, six new relics to enhance character builds, an update to the Wizards Vault, new mini-pets, and new homestead recipes to be earned through in-game achievements. A new Mursaat Shadowcraft mastery track will help players explore the far reaches of Repentance.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>In addition, the Titan Greer will be added to the Janthir Wilds Convergence gameplay mode, beginning an alternating boss rotation for players to test their mettle in the challenging 50-player activity. A more difficult challenge mode will be available in the Mount Balrior raid (first introduced in the November content update), with the most prestigious rewards available to players who complete it. Following the release of Repentance and the previous launch of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/arenanet-to-release-godspawn-update-for-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-on-november-19-featuring-new-50-player-titan-battle-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Godspawn update</a>, ArenaNet plans to release a third and final free content update for Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds before moving on to the next expansion.</p>
<p>As we covered <a href="https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-2-qa-arenanet-on-switch-to-yearly-expansions-secrets-of-the-obscure-learnings-and-2024-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in our exclusive late 2023 interview</a>, ArenaNet has switched to a yearly release plan for expansions. As such, fans can expect a new Guild Wars 2 expansion to land in the latter half of 2025.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Konami Finally Announces a New Suikoden Game, Sort Of]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/suikoden-star-leap-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/konami-finally-announces-a-new-suikoden-game-sort-of.1124703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/suikoden-star-leap-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Konami has finally announced a new entry in the&nbsp;<em>Suikoden&nbsp;</em>series after thirteen years, but&nbsp;<em>Suikoden Star Leap&nbsp;</em>might not be what you want it to be.</p>

<p>During a&nbsp;<em>Suikoden&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/suikoden-program-march-3rd-announced" rel="nofollow">news broadcast</a> held earlier today, Konami revealed that&nbsp;<em>Suikoden Star Leap&nbsp;</em>will be a free-to-play mobile RPG, although it will be set in the main&nbsp;<em>Suikoden&nbsp;</em>timeline, so it won't be an alternate-history spinoff or anything like that.</p>

<p>The game will take place a few years after&nbsp;the events of&nbsp;<em>Suikoden V</em>, which itself served as a prequel to the original game. That, of course, also means that we might well see some of both games' characters appearing in&nbsp;<em>Star Leap</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/suikoden-star-leap-mobile-rpg-viki.jpg?itok=bjiUk453 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/suikoden-star-leap-mobile-rpg-viki.jpg?itok=02oowrx5 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Familiar faces may well be making an appearance in&nbsp;<em>Suikoden Star Leap</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>In fact, one of the screenshots shown on the <a href="https://www.konami.com/games/suikoden/star_leap/us/en-us/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">official website</a> for&nbsp;<em>Suikoden Star Leap&nbsp;</em>appears to show Viki, a recurring character who serves as your method of fast travel in every mainline&nbsp;<em>Suikoden&nbsp;</em>game to date.</p>

<p>Of course, Viki is heavily implied to be able to travel through time as well as through space, so her presence here probably shouldn't come as a shock. It does, however, reinforce that this isn't just a spinoff, but a game that wants to take its place alongside the main series.</p>

<p>The trailer for the game also appears to show Gregminster, the capital city of the Toran Republic and one of the key locations in the original&nbsp;<em>Suikoden&nbsp;</em>(as well as the site of a brief but memorable stopover in the sequel).</p>

<p>You can check out the debut trailer for&nbsp;<em>Suikoden Star Leap&nbsp;</em>right here. Honestly, I know it's a mobile RPG, but the art style and overall presentation has me cautiously excited for it.</p>




<p>According to Konami,&nbsp;<em>Suikoden Star Leap&nbsp;</em>will be a free-to-play game with "in-game purchases", although the studio doesn't say what form those purchases will take. I hate to say it, but&nbsp;<em>Suikoden&nbsp;</em>is ripe for some kind of character gacha mechanic, so that's probably what it'll be.</p>

<p>In addition to&nbsp;<em>Star Leap</em>, Konami is also gearing up to release remasters of the first two&nbsp;<em>Suikoden&nbsp;</em>games, which are due to land later this week, having been <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/suikoden-i-ii-hd-remaster-delayed" rel="nofollow">delayed</a> beyond their <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/suikoden-and-suikoden-2-remaster-confirmed-for-2023" rel="nofollow">original release window</a> of 2023.</p>

<p>You'll be able to check out those remasters when they launch on March 6th across <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1932640/Suikoden_III_HD_Remaster_Gate_Rune_and_Dunan_Unification_Wars/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/JP0101-PPSA18305_00-SUIKODENREMASTER" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/suikoden-iii-hd-remaster-gate-rune-and-dunan-unification-wars-pre-order-bonus/9P9FM62WZXR2" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/suikoden-i-and-ii-hd-remaster-gate-rune-and-dunan-unification-wars-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>.&nbsp;<em>Suikoden Star Leap&nbsp;</em>is due to arrive at some point in the future on iOS and Android, although we don't know when yet.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VALORANT Patch 10.04 Notes – New Duelist Waylay, Balance Changes, Map Pool Rotation]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-patch-10-04-notes-new-duelist-waylay-balance-changes-map-pool-rotation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-patch-10-04-notes-%E2%80%93-new-duelist-waylay-balance-changes-map-pool-rotation.1124694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-patch-10-04-notes-new-duelist-waylay-balance-changes-map-pool-rotation/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>VALORANT Patch 10.04 is officially live, and since it goes hand-in-hand <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-ditches-episodes-for-yearly-season-model/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">with a new Act</a>, it means that it’s a big one. The latest patch adds a dynamic, potentially game-breaking new duelist agent, major balance changes to existing agents, and some key changes to map pool.</p>



<p>Let’s dive into the full list of updates now live as of VALORANT Patch 10.04.</p>



<h2 id="h-welcome-to-the-waylay-era">Welcome to the Waylay Era</h2>



<p>Waylay is the newest addition to the duelist class, and this new light-bending duelist from Thailand has “broken” written all over her. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-pros-say-the-next-duelist-will-be-an-even-more-annoying-jett/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The pros weren’t lying when they said she could replace Jett</a>, or be just as annoying. Her kit is designed to disrupt, hinder, and surprise enemy players.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Waylay Official Gameplay Reveal // VALORANT" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/njK6KgRNr2k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Here are each of the abilities for Waylay, the newest VALORANT duelist:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Refract</strong>: Create a light beacon on the floor. Reactivate to return to the beacon, traveling as an invulnerable mote of pure light. This is like a stationary Yoru Gatecrash, but it affords the opportunity to gather info before returning to the starting point.</li>



<li><strong>Light Speed</strong>: It’s a Jett double dash. Waylay’s Light Speed can be used to jump over walls or push deep into a site during an execute. There are going to be so many highlight plays from this one.</li>



<li><strong>Saturate</strong>: Throw a cluster of light that explodes when it hits the ground, applying the Hinder effect to nearby players. Hinder slows enemy fire rate, recoil recovery, equip time, reload speed, movement speed, and jump speed.</li>



<li><strong>Convergent Paths</strong>: Waylay’s ultimate ability. Project a beam of light forward, which after a delay, applies Waylay with a speed boost and applies Hinder to enemies caught in the beam.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-valorant-10-04-balance-changes">VALORANT 10.04 Balance Changes</h2>



<p>Clove, Tejo, Iso, and Deadlock are the primary recipients of this patch’s balance changes. In this section, we dive into the major changes made to each of those four agents.</p>



<h3 id="h-clove">Clove</h3>



<p>Meddle, Clove’s Decay-applying throwable, now explodes 0.75 seconds after hitting the ground, instead of just a 1.3 second delay. The cooldown on their Ruse smokes has increased from 30 seconds to 40. Pick Me Up’s health buff duration has increased from eight seconds to 10, but the move speed durations drops from eight seconds to just three.</p>



<h3 id="h-deadlock">Deadlock</h3>



<p>GravNet is now Deadlock’s signature ability, costing no money at the start of the round and receiving a 40 second rechargeable cooldown. GravNet’s size has slightly decreased from 16m to 13m. Barrier Mesh now costs 400 credits.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-iso">Iso</h3>



<p>Iso now only gets one charge of his Undercut, but it now applies Suppression along with Vulnerability. The tagging on Double Tap has been changed, so he is now slowed more when his shield breaks. Iso will always have Double Tap applied now when he wins a duel in his Kill Contract ultimate.</p>



<h3 id="h-tejo">Tejo</h3>



<p>Tejo’s Guided Salvo missiles deal 65 points of damage and deal half damage to non-player objects. This changes has been made so that Tejo’s Guided Salvo does not successfully destroy Killjoy’s Lockdown.</p>



<h2 id="h-valorant-10-04-map-changes">VALORANT 10.04 Map Changes</h2>



<p>With the start of the new act, the VALORANT map pool is getting a change. <strong>Ascent and Icebox are back in</strong> the Competitive and Deathmatch queues, while <strong>Abyss and Bind are being taken out</strong>. Ascent is returning with a big change: the infamous B Main wall that players spam through with the Odin has been reinforced. Riot noted that all the spamming at this spot was “creating unhealthy gameplay and frustrating experiences.”</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Which change to VALORANT in Patch 10.04 is of the most interest to you? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/call-of-duty-2025-in-development-for-last-gen-consoles.1711/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Insider Gaming Forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cache-is-returning-to-counter-strike-but-only-once-valve-approves-it-for-cs2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cache is finally returning to Counter-Strike</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 5 Enhanced Is Live Now on PC, But What’s New?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-enhanced-pc-out-now-whats-new/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-5-enhanced-is-live-now-on-pc-but-what%E2%80%99s-new.1124688/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-enhanced-pc-out-now-whats-new/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Grand Theft Auto 5 has been upgraded on PC with the Enhanced update, and players are excited. This overhaul of sorts brings technical upgrades, content changes, and some UI improvements to the decade-old open-world game. If you’re downloading the GTA 5 Enhanced update, which is live now, you might be wondering what’s changed.</p>



<p>Read on to learn what’s new in the GTA 5 Enhanced update.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-what-s-different-in-gta-5-enhanced">What’s Different in GTA 5 Enhanced?</h2>



<p>On February 20, <a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/akk98a4o755825/free-upgrade-for-grand-theft-auto-v-on-pc-coming-march-4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Rockstar Games revealed</a> the impending release of a free upgrade for GTA 5 on PC, which included features once available exclusively on PS5 and Xbox Series consoles. The overhaul was promised to be considerable, and it’s finally here – but what has changed?</p>



<p>Once players have migrated their story and GTA Online progress to the ‘new version’, they’ll be able to soak up the advantages of GTA 5 Enhanced, which includes:</p>



<ul>
<li>Upgraded ray-tracing features (ambient occlusion, global illumination, ray-traced shadows and reflections)</li>



<li>Support for DLSS 3 and FSR3</li>



<li>Faster loading times</li>



<li>Enhanced support for higher resolutions and frame rates</li>



<li>DualSense controller support with haptic feedback</li>



<li>Enhanced audio with improved fidelity across the board</li>



<li>Upgraded particle effects</li>
</ul>



<p>On social media, users have started sharing images revealing comparisons between the old version of GTA 5 and GTA 5 Enhanced on PC:</p>



<div><article><p><span>The new RTGI is SOILD! 

Left – Disabled
Right – Enabled</span></p></article></div>



<h2 id="h-but-wait-there-s-more">But Wait, There’s More!</h2>



<p>Rockstar has also added new vehicles to GTA Online, introduced wildlife to the multiplayer platform, and added new menus and a fresh landing page to GTA 5 Enhanced.</p>



<p>PC players can now lean on the GTA+ subscription service to get boosts and special benefits, and a new GTA Online ‘Career Progress’ feature has been implemented. New players will also get a $4 million boost when they start playing after the update, just to help them out in their life of crime in GTA Online.</p>



<p>Rockstar stressed that GTA 5 Enhanced includes kernel-level anti-cheat protections and voice chat moderation to keep GTA Online safe and secure for everyone involved. </p>



<h3 id="h-what-are-the-new-vehicles-in-gta-online">What are the new vehicles in GTA Online?</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>Rockstar has added:</p>



<ul>
<li>Coil Cyclone II (Super)</li>



<li>Imponte Arbiter GT (Muscle)</li>



<li>Karin S95 (Sports)</li>



<li>Pegassi Weaponised Ignus (Super)</li>



<li>Pfister Astron Custom (SUV)</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-what-does-gta-come-with">What does GTA+ come with?</h3>



<p>If you subscribe to GTA+ on PC, you’ll get:</p>



<ul>
<li>$500,000 GTA Cash every month</li>



<li>Shark Card bonuses</li>



<li>Exclusive apparel, vehicles, and paints</li>



<li>Access to The Vinewood Club Garage and The Vinewood Club App</li>



<li>Access to The Gun Van</li>



<li>Access to a classic Rockstar Games library</li>
</ul>



<p>Have you tried out the new GTA 5 Enhanced update on PC? Let us know what you think in the comments.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/runescape-developer-new-ceo-jon-bellamy/">Jagex has a new CEO</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Acclaim Is Coming Back As Game Publisher Focused On Reviving Classic Franchises]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/acclaim-is-coming-back-as-game-publisher-focused-on-reviving-classic-franchises/1100-6529576/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/acclaim-is-coming-back-as-game-publisher-focused-on-reviving-classic-franchises.1124685/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/acclaim-is-coming-back-as-game-publisher-focused-on-reviving-classic-franchises/1100-6529576/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529576">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Acclaim, an iconic game publisher from the 1990s behind series like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/nba-jam/" data-ref-id="5000-2852">NBA Jam</a>, has been revived as an indie-game publisher.</p><p>Acclaim was founded in 1987 and made a name for itself in many ways. It was known for licensed games, ranging from NBA Jam to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/justice-league-task-force/" data-ref-id="5000-16280">Justice League Task Force</a>, being the console publisher for arcade classics like Mortal Kombat, and its wild marketing stunts promoting games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/turok-evolution/" data-ref-id="5000-4168">Turok: Evolution</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/shadow-man-2econd-coming/" data-ref-id="5000-3729">Shadow Man: 2econd Coming</a>. After several high-profile flops like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/bmx-xxx/" data-ref-id="5000-4220">BMX XXX</a>, Acclaim filed for bankruptcy in 2004 and had been defunct--until now.</p><p>Companies like Striker Entertainment, Ridge Partners, Global Force Entertainment, VaynerFund, and JET Management have all come together to revive Acclaim as a game publisher that will "support indie developers and reignite classic franchises." It plans to provide funding, marketing, and PR support for any independent developers it works with. This new version of Acclaim is following in Atari's footsteps; Atari has also revitalized itself in recent years and reimagined classic titles like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/atari-revisits-an-arcade-classic-with-breakout-beyond/1100-6529212/" data-ref-id="1100-6529212">Breakout</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/atari-and-polybius-creator-are-reimagining-the-rare-arcade-game-i-robot/1100-6529425/" data-ref-id="1100-6529425">I, Robot.</a></p><p>It's unclear what specific franchises this new version of Acclaim has ownership over, as this initial announcement is more focused on confirming members of its new leadership team, like CEO Alex Jose. That also includes Jeff Jarrett, a Hall of Fame wrestler who worked with the old version of Acclaim on its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/wwf-attitude/" data-ref-id="5000-2348">WWF titles</a>. "Resurrecting Acclaim is an opportunity to impart the same degree of passion and love to a new generation, and I'm excited to be involved," Jarrett said of the revival in a press release.</p><p>No new games were announced alongside this revival of Acclaim, although Josef teased that the company has "already signed some incredible titles, which we'll be revealing soon."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears Of War Collection Set For PS5 This Year, E-Day Releasing In 2026 - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gears-of-war-collection-set-for-ps5-this-year-e-day-releasing-in-2026-report/1100-6529840/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-collection-set-for-ps5-this-year-e-day-releasing-in-2026-report.1124679/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gears-of-war-collection-set-for-ps5-this-year-e-day-releasing-in-2026-report/1100-6529840/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529840">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A Gears of War collection is reportedly going to be announced this summer with a PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S release. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gears-of-war-e-day-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6526145/" data-ref-id="1100-6526145">Gears of War: E-Day</a> also reportedly is targeting a 2026 release window.</p><p>According to leaker ExTas1s, Microsoft is reportedly going to reveal a Gears of War collection during the upcoming Xbox Games Showcase in June. While the exact games in the rumored collection are unknown, it's likely going to at least include the first three, although the spin-off Gears of War: Judgment could be part of the package too. The leaker doesn't have any information about a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Nintendo Switch 2 port</a>.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T7FO40pCi8Y" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/T7FO40pCi8Y" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Gears of War: E-Day was reportedly <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-next-gears-of-war-brings-back-the-developer-of-judgment/1100-6529045/" data-ref-id="1100-6529045">aiming for a 2025 release</a>, but it's now apparently slipped into next year. Microsoft is reportedly having the Gears of War collection fill in the release calendar this year as E-Day isn't ready for launch yet. However, the leaker said that there's a slim chance that it could still make it out the door in 2025.</p><p>This leaker <a href="https://x.com/eXtas1stv/status/1861854891389432228" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">correctly reported</a> that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/forza-horizon-5-on-ps5-releases-in-april/1100-6529770/" data-ref-id="1100-6529770">Forza Horizon 5 was being ported to PS5</a>. However, the leaker also reported that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-tony-hawks-pro-skater-game-to-launch-this-summer-report/1100-6529575/" data-ref-id="1100-6529575">Tony Hawk Pro Skater 3 + 4</a> would be announced at the Xbox Games Showcase and shadow-dropped in June, although Activision is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tony-hawk-34-remaster-is-seemingly-all-but-confirmed/1100-6529701/" data-ref-id="1100-6529701">apparently fully revealing it today</a>.</p><p>A Gears of War collection has been <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gears-of-war-getting-mcc-style-collection-report/1100-6503487/" data-ref-id="1100-6503487">rumored for a several years now</a>, but nothing concrete came about these rumors.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Famed 90s publisher Acclaim to be revived, focused on indie developers and classic franchises]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/famed-90s-publisher-acclaim-to-be-revived-focused-on-indie-developers-and-classic-franchises</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/famed-90s-publisher-acclaim-to-be-revived-focused-on-indie-developers-and-classic-franchises.1124676/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/famed-90s-publisher-acclaim-to-be-revived-focused-on-indie-developers-and-classic-franchises<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Acclaim, the publisher behind hundreds of classic games from the 80s and 90s, is set to be revived.</p>
<p>The company closed back in 2004 as it filed for bankruptcy, but will now return to support indie developers and "reignite classic franchises" from its portfolio of IP.</p>
<p>Acclaim was known in the 90s for game adaptations of familiar franchises, from WWF (now WWE) and The Simpsons, to movie tie-ins like Alien 3, Judge Dredd and Batman Forever, to comic book games like Spider-Man and Wolverine.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NXBJ-a0iUaw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NXBJ-a0iUaw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NXBJ-a0iUaw?autoplay=1" title="Newscast: Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NXBJ-a0iUaw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>It also published the likes of the controversial Mortal Kombat games and Theme Park. Then, in the late 90s, it was prolific for publishing N64 games like <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/turok">Turok</a>, Extreme-G, Shadow Man, and the South Park FPS.</p>
<p>As well as resurrecting its old franchises, the company will be offering funding, marketing, and PR support to indie studios.</p>
<p>The newly-revived publisher has an advisory board of industry leaders, including "licensing icons, professional athletes, living music legends and season veterans who have defined the intersection of video games and pop culture". That includes two-time Hall of Fame wrestler Jeff Jarrett.</p>
<p>"For more than three decades, I've had the privilege to have been a part of both the wrestling and gaming universes, and I'm thrilled to now be a partner in the revival of Acclaim, an iconic publisher known for releasing some of the most legendary games of the '80s and '90s," said Jarrett.</p>
<p>"From my early involvement with the publisher's hit 16-bit WWF titles to my experience helping shape the TNA Wrestling series, which spawned the first video game wrestler to become a full-time roster member in the Squared Circle, I've seen firsthand the type of impact great games can have on players and fans. Resurrecting Acclaim is an opportunity to impart the same degree of passion and love to a new generation, and I'm excited to be involved."</p>
<p>Acclaim was originally founded in 1987, publishing a number of NES and Game Boy games. However, sales of its games declined in the early '00s which led to a number of studio closures across the UK. Eventually the company closed in August 2004, closing all of its facilities and terminating all employees at its Austin and New York studios.</p>
<p>Still, a number of game franchises first published by Acclaim have made a return in recent years.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/two-n64-racing-games-join-nintendo-switch-online-today">High-speed racer Extreme-G and puzzle game Iggy's Reckin' Balls</a> were added to Nintendo Switch Online's N64 catalogue last year, which were followed by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-online-mature-app-receives-two-additional-n64-games">Turok 2: Seeds of Evil and Shadow Man in the Mature app</a>.</p>
<p>What's more, as previously reported, a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/new-shadowman-game-in-the-works-21-years-after-the-last">new Shadow Man game is in development</a> from Blowfish Studios along with comic publisher Valiant Entertainment, while <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/theres-a-new-turok-game">Saber Interactive is working on a new Turok game</a> it revealed at last year's The Game Awards.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Breaks 8m Sales in Just Three Days]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-sales-8m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-breaks-8m-sales-in-just-three-days.1124649/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-sales-8m<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Capcom has revealed the first sales figures for&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, and it probably won't surprise you to learn that the game has dwarfed the two most recent entries in the series in terms of launch weekend figures.</p>

<p>Per a Capcom <a href="https://www.capcom.co.jp/ir/english/news/html/e250304.html" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">press release</a>,&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>managed to reach eight million sales within the first three days of its launch. That, as Capcom points out, is the quickest a&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>game has reached that figure.</p>

<p>For comparison's sake,&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter World&nbsp;</em>hit <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/monster-hunter-world-shipped-5-million-units-in-a-weekend" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">five million</a> sales within the same period, while&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Rise</em>, which was initially exclusive to the Nintendo Switch, reached four million.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-sales-8m-hunting-horn.jpg?itok=1dV9mxLT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-sales-8m-hunting-horn.jpg?itok=cX-gdTxy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>It's fair to call&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>a runaway success.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course, this isn't just the fastest a&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>game has reached that eight million milestone; it's also the fastest any Capcom game has managed to do so. It's fair to say Capcom has a bona fide success on its hands with&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>.</p>

<p>If you've been following&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>' launch, its impressive sales performance probably won't surprise you. The game debuted to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-steam-player-record" rel="nofollow">well over a million players on Steam at launch</a>, breaking records for both the&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>franchise and Capcom as a whole.</p>

<p>The signs were there even before launch;&nbsp;<em>Wilds</em>' first open beta, which was held across PC and consoles back in November, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-steam-records" rel="nofollow">attracted more Steam players</a> than any game in the series had managed up to that point.</p>

<p>Indeed,&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>was expected to do so well before launch that&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>developer Pocketpair <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palworld-pocketpair-monster-hunter-wilds-day-off" rel="nofollow">gave the majority of its staff the day off</a> on Friday, recognizing that many employees would just call in sick to play the game anyway.</p>




<p>The game's success hasn't come without a cost. Although critical reviews are broadly positive, players have provided much more mixed feedback for&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, especially <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/#app_reviews_hash" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">on PC</a>, with many pointing to lackluster performance and poor multiplayer implementation.</p>

<p>If you'd like to check out&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>for yourself, you can play it right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/monster-hunter-wilds/9NMT6XFN0LVD" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. For what it's worth, our own Tyler liked the game a lot, and you can check out his review here.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Probably Won't See A Console Launch As Good As The Nintendo Switch Ever Again]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-launch-zelda-botw-anniversary-1851767489</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we-probably-wont-see-a-console-launch-as-good-as-the-nintendo-switch-ever-again.1124646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-launch-zelda-botw-anniversary-1851767489<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>We’re just a month out from the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-direct-switch-2-release-date-april-2025-1851740848&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-direct-switch-2-release-date-april-2025-1851740848">big Nintendo Direct</a></span> giving us the full rundown on the Switch 2. Fans have been patiently waiting for the new hardware for years, excited to see what the future holds for the successor to one of the best video game consoles ever made. I’m excited too, but I also know that no matter what Nintendo has planed, the Switch 2 doesn’t have a prayer of recapturing the magic of the original Switch launch. Perhaps no future console does. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195670" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="184" data-playlist="195670,196181,196230" data-current="195670"><div><p>This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21167.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>This week marks the eighth anniversary of the handheld console hybrid’s release and somehow the device is still going. It’s been a hell of a ride  full of great games, but some of the biggest are still to come later this year with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-nintendo-direct-switch-retro-studios-1848510132&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-nintendo-direct-switch-retro-studios-1848510132"><em>Metroid Prime 4</em></a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-switch-mega-evolution-1851766684?_gl=1*7kcsfg*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTAzNzExNy42MS4xLjE3NDEwMzgzOTUuMTcuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-switch-mega-evolution-1851766684?_gl=1*7kcsfg*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTAzNzExNy42MS4xLjE3NDEwMzgzOTUuMTcuMC4w"><em>Pok</em></a></span><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-switch-mega-evolution-1851766684&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-switch-mega-evolution-1851766684">é</a></span><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-switch-mega-evolution-1851766684?_gl=1*7kcsfg*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTAzNzExNy42MS4xLjE3NDEwMzgzOTUuMTcuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-switch-mega-evolution-1851766684?_gl=1*7kcsfg*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTAzNzExNy42MS4xLjE3NDEwMzgzOTUuMTcuMC4w"><em>mon Legends: Z-A</em></a></span>. No other console has gone on this strong and this consistently for this long, and none of it might have been possible without the constellation of factors that serendipitously collided to make the Switch launch one for the history books.</p><p>First there was the drama surrounding Nintendo, the storied gaming company whose name had once been synonymous with “video game console,” but whose Wii U had bombed so spectacularly that many thought it should exit the hardware business entirely. At only 13.56 million units sold, the white box with the clunky tablet controller performed even worse than the GameCube. Nintendo’s handheld at the time, the 3DS, was similarly its worst performing portable ever, though by a much smaller margin. </p><p>Nintendo had long ago abandoned the gaming graphics arms race, but by the mid-2010s it seemed like it had abandoned common sense as well, taking overly ambitious swings at superfluous hardware gimmicks instead of making decent hardware in service of great games. The fact that the Switch did exactly that, bringing Nintendo franchises into HD for the first time ever, felt like a remarkable coup considering the basement-level expectations coming out of the Wii U era. </p><p>But it also made a great first impression based on a novel insight: portable gaming doesn’t have to be secondary. The conventional wisdom at the time was that no one wanted to play big, deep games on the go. They had <em>Candy Crush</em> for that. The rise of smartphone gaming was thought to be one of the main factors in dooming the PlayStation Vita. It turns out that Sony just didn’t make the right games. Being able to take console-like experiences from home on the go, or just to the bedroom, made the sleek but otherwise humble-looking Switch feel revolutionary.</p><figure id="" data-id="91faaf8fdf1ebe4539e31a4b030e917d" data-recommend-id="image://91faaf8fdf1ebe4539e31a4b030e917d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Someone plays BotW in bed. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Someone plays BotW in bed. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="91faaf8fdf1ebe4539e31a4b030e917d" data-recommend-id="image://91faaf8fdf1ebe4539e31a4b030e917d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Someone plays BotW in bed. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>And there was no better showpiece for that than<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-the-kotaku-rev-1792885174&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-the-kotaku-rev-1792885174"><em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</em></a></span>. Most systems launch with a few visually dazzling but mechanically shallow games. They gesture at what the new tech is capable of but belie the developers’ inexperience in being able to completely capitalize on it. Few console launches get full-fledged sequels in one of the biggest franchises around, let alone a GOTY that redefines a genre. <em>Breath of the Wild</em> was all of those things, and eight years later its reverberations throughout the medium are still being felt.</p><p>The real magic of the Switch launch was feeling both of these things smashed together: a mechanically deep, richly emergent, gorgeous open-world adventure on a small tablet that could (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/what-is-your-favorite-gaming-handheld-of-all-time-1844962828&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/what-is-your-favorite-gaming-handheld-of-all-time-1844962828">almost</a></span>) fit into your pocket (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/what-gear-are-you-using-with-your-new-nintendo-switch-1793234536&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/what-gear-are-you-using-with-your-new-nintendo-switch-1793234536">or sock</a></span>).<em> Breath of the Wild</em> was a return to form for a series that had previously grown stiff and predictable, on a device that showed leaving the graphical arms race behind wasn’t a retreat from making great games, but the opposite. Hundreds of amazing games came to the Switch in the years that followed, but have any of them ever topped that feeling of first leaving the Great Plateau in <em>Breath of the Wild</em>? The fact that it’s even still debatable is remarkable. </p><p>There’s one final, less impressive reason why the Switch 2 will have a hard time living up to the  original Switch’s launch window hype: there’s no graveyard of Wii U games to cannibalize this time around. <em>Mario Kart 8</em> was ported to Switch within its first two months, eventually becoming its most popular game ever. Plenty of other first-party Wii U orphans have been rescued this way, filling out the Switch’s release calendar as needed while Nintendo consolidated its console and portable game development teams into a single, streamlined machine. </p><p>Maybe the Switch 2 will launch with a brand-new 3D <em>Mario </em>whose sprawling levels and inventive designs rival those of <em>Super Mario Odyssey</em>. Maybe <em>Mario Kart 9</em> will revolutionize the racing series the way <em>Breath of the Wild </em>did for<em> Zelda</em>. Maybe somehow, someway, a new mainline <em>Zelda</em> will also hit the Switch 2 in its first year even though <em>Tears of the Kingdom </em>will only be three years old. In any case, though, it’s still only possible to experience the feeling of playing those types of games on a handheld for the first time once, and that already happened eight years ago. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Has Become The Fastest Selling Game in Capcom’s History]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-has-become-the-fastest-selling-game-in-capcoms-history/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-has-become-the-fastest-selling-game-in-capcom%E2%80%99s-history.1124640/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-has-become-the-fastest-selling-game-in-capcoms-history/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds sold 8 million units in the first 3 days of release, becoming the fastest-selling game in Capcom’s history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Monster Hunter Wilds was released on February 28, 2025, and the game has been breaking records since the first day. The game brought in over 1.3 million players on Steam alone <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-players/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">within the first 12 hours</a> and is still managing to bring in more than 1 million players within the past 24 hours (at the time of writing). Their latest record, with 8 million sales in 3 days, has made Monster Hunter Wilds the fastest-selling game in the series and Capcom’s history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the announcement <a href="https://www.capcom.co.jp/ir/english/news/html/e250304.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">post</a>, the developers discussed what it took to sell over 8 million copies in such a short span of time. With the new instalment in the series, the developers wanted to take Monster Hunter to a broader audience. So, they conducted several global initiatives, such as appearing at global game showcases, hosting online beta tests, and hosting individual showcases to spread the word.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Apart from the initiatives, the developers have also worked on several core aspects of the game that have helped Monster Hunter Wilds reach this significant sales milestone. Through the Forbidden Lands, players experience a new, dynamically changing open world where they can be in the harshest environment at one moment and then suddenly find themselves in a “rich natural environment teeming with life”. The game is also the first in the series to feature cross-play co-op, which helps more players across platforms enjoy the game together.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Monster Hunter Wilds - Proof of a Hero Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gjV35rfGgV0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, here’s how to farm <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-farm-gold-crowns-in-monster-hunter-wilds/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gold Crowns</a> in Monster Hunter Wilds. Also, check out the details on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-plans-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first title update</a>. What are your thoughts on Monster Hunter Wilds selling 8 million units in 3 days?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tony-hawk-3-4-details-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4 releasing on July 11</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RuneScape’s Developer Has a New CEO in Jon Bellamy]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/runescape-developer-new-ceo-jon-bellamy/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/runescape%E2%80%99s-developer-has-a-new-ceo-in-jon-bellamy.1124637/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/runescape-developer-new-ceo-jon-bellamy/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Jagex has announced a change-up at the highest level, with CEO Phil Mansell stepping down and being replaced by Jon Bellamy. Phil has been in the role of Chief Executive Officer at Jagex since 2017 but has been with the company for more than a decade. Jon Bellamy noted that he is excited to communicate his ‘broader vision’ for RuneScape soon.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-handing-over-the-baton">Handing Over The Baton</h2>



<p>In a press release, Phil Mansell expressed his sentiments at stepping back from the role of CEO at Jagex:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>After an incredible 14 years leading RuneScape and 8 years as Jagex’s CEO, I’m stepping back and handing over the baton to Jon Bellamy. </p>



<p>Working alongside such a talented and passionate team, we’ve significantly grown the Company and player community, cementing Jagex as an innovator in community-driven games and genuine leader in this industry. </p>



<p>As the Company embarks on its next chapter, I am delighted to be handing over to a leader who I know cares about our games and business as much as I do – and I look forward to supporting him as he builds upon the strong foundations we’ve created.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Bellamy echoed those sentiments:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>It’s a great honour to assume the leadership of Jagex and to help steward a game franchise that means so much to so many millions, myself included. I am also excited to get to work with the outstanding team, whom I know well from my time on the Board, to ensure our games continue to be the best in the world. </p>



<p>I plan to spend some time now with the team, reviewing our ambitions for Jagex, and plan to communicate my broader vision to the RuneScape community in the near-term.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Mansell was most recently in the press following an awful proposal made by Jagex to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/jagex-ceo-addresses-recent-runescape-scandal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">overhaul the paid membership model</a>. It rankled with the community and was taken with an awful reception, and Mansell branded the proposal ‘clumsy and inconsiderate’.</p>



<p>He said that they had failed to think the proposal through from the perspective of a player, and the plans were ultimately scrapped.</p>



<p>Last year, Jagex was in talks regarding <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/jagex-billion-dollar-buyout/">a potential billion dollar buyout</a>, but that conversation eventually faded out of the press.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hideki-kamiya-scalebound-develop-xbox/">Hideki Kamiya wants to make Scalebound again</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reignbreaker Dev Will Shut Down After Releasing The Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/reignbreaker-dev-will-shut-down-after-releasing-the-game/1100-6529839/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reignbreaker-dev-will-shut-down-after-releasing-the-game.1124634/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/reignbreaker-dev-will-shut-down-after-releasing-the-game/1100-6529839/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529839">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It's become all too common in the video game industry for small developers to shut down if their game isn't deemed a success after its debut. Unfortunately for Studio Fizbin, the decision to close its doors can't even wait another two weeks for the release of its final game, Reignbreaker.</p><p>Via <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/studio-fizbin-shutting-down-after-reignbreaker-s-mid-march-release" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Game Developer</a>, Studio Fizbin founder Alexander “Pepe” Pieper shared the news on <a href="https://www.studio-fizbin.com/fizbins-last-magic-trick" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the company's official site</a>. According to Pieper, the end of Studio Fizbin is happening in part because the dev team doesn't have a new project to work on after Reignbreaker is finished. Studio Fizbin's parent company, Thunderful, is also drastically cutting back on its internal development. Consequently, Studio Fizbin will be closing its doors after an 11-year run that included titles like The Inner World, The Inner World: The Last Wind Monk, Say No! More, Minute of Islands, and Lost at Sea.</p><p>However, Studio Fizbin will remain open long enough to ensure that its new roguelike action game, Reignbreaker, is "going to be the best game we've ever released." Following the game's debut on March 18, Studio Fizbin will provide post-launch support for Reignbreaker while helping its employees find new job opportunities in the industry.</p><p>"We want to thank every single one of our fans for your purchases, your fan art, your comments, your reviews, your passion, and your seemingly endless support," wrote Pieper. "And finally, we'd like to give the biggest thanks to our team--those who are here until the end, and the many others who have found a different path on the way. Fizbin and its games are defined by its team members, and you all made this the most inspiring place to perform the world's most difficult magic trick: making games."</p><p>Last year, there were large layoffs across the video game industry, and 2025 is already off to a rough start with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/three-studios-have-already-shut-down-in-2025-including-godfall-developer/1100-6528785/" data-ref-id="1100-6528785">the closure of Godfall developer Counterplay Games</a>, as well as Warner Bros. Games' decision to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-wonder-woman-game-canceled-multiple-studios-closed-report/1100-6529706/" data-ref-id="1100-6529706">shut down Monolith and two other studios</a> while <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-wonder-woman-legend-was-working-on-canceled-game-offers-heartfelt-tribute/1100-6529718/" data-ref-id="1100-6529718">canceling Monolith's Wonder Woman game</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision "AI slop" Guitar Hero advert is market research for a fake game that doesn't exist and maybe never will]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-ai-slop-guitar-hero-advert-is-market-research-for-a-fake-game-that-doesnt-exist-and-maybe-never-will</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-ai-slop-guitar-hero-advert-is-market-research-for-a-fake-game-that-doesnt-exist-and-maybe-never-will.1124631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-ai-slop-guitar-hero-advert-is-market-research-for-a-fake-game-that-doesnt-exist-and-maybe-never-will<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Call of Duty and Crash Bandicoot titles also touted.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_4fb725a530ea35d130a9db5eabf81b215869378b.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Activision</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Activision's social media post advertising a new entry in the Guitar Hero series is market research for a game that doesn't exist, and is not meant to be an actual announcement, Eurogamer understands.
</p>
<p>
The fake advert - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-accused-of-ai-slop-yet-again-this-time-for-new-guitar-hero">which has been dubbed "AI slop" for its use of poorly-generated imagery</a> - is one of several tests currently being run across the publisher's social media profiles. 
</p>
<p>
These adverts also include new smartphone games in other Activision franchises such as Call of Duty and Crash Bandicoot that also don't exist (yet) either. 
</p>
<p>
Clicking on some of the adverts will take you through to a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GuitarHero/comments/1j0jbh3/instagram_ad_for_a_new_guitar_hero_mobile_game/">mocked up mobile store page</a> organised by marketing service Geeklab, and then onto a survey that reveals "this isn't a real game, but could be some day!"
</p>
<p>
Market research questions then include queries asking users what made them click on the advert and what gameplay features they expected the game to include, based on the fake advert.
</p>
<p>
Activision posts on Instagram and Facebook have similarly advertised "Call of Duty: Zombie Defender", "Call of Duty: Sniper" and "Crash Bandicoot: Brawl".
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Activision plans to develop two new Call of Duty titles for mobile platform:</p><p>🔸 Call of Duty: Zombie Defender<br>🔸 Call of Duty: Sniper</p><p>AI-generated advertisements are being used to gauge player interests. If there is enough interest, the project will go into development. These… <a href="https://t.co/PWA1KjLd4h">pic.twitter.com/PWA1KjLd4h</a></p></div>— Leakers On Duty (@LeakersOnDuty) <a href="https://twitter.com/LeakersOnDuty/status/1896536223478403382?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 3, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Artwork for the latter game, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Activision/videos/569180362817791/">hosted on Facebook</a>, again shows obvious use of AI image generation. One squirrel-like character appears to be missing half a face.
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-03-04-125736.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Activision</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Will any of these Guitar Hero, Crash Bandicoot or Call of Duty smartphone games ever see the light of day? That remains to be seen. If and when they do, however, here's hoping Activision hires some actual humans to work on their artwork.
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-admits-call-of-duty-includes-generative-ai">Activision recently added a warning label to the Steam page for Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> confirming the game "uses generative AI tools to help develop some in-game assets", after players spotted various in-game examples - including a zombie Santa Claus with six fingers.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto V Enhanced is Now Available on PC; First Comparisons Highlight Visual Improvements Introduced By Ray-traced Global Illumination]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-v-enhanced-ray-tracing-improvements-comparison/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-v-enhanced-is-now-available-on-pc-first-comparisons-highlight-visual-improvements-introduced-by-ray-traced-global-illumination.1124619/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-v-enhanced-ray-tracing-improvements-comparison/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto V Enhanced is now available on PC, introducing plenty of new features that are sure to breathe new life into the latest main entry in the series.</p>
<p>The new version of the game includes, as announced a few days back, new features such as new ray tracing settings like ray-traced global illumination and ambient occlusion, that push the game's visuals beyond those offered in the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S versions of the game, NVIDIA DLSS 3, AMD FSR 1 and 3 support, faster loading times with DirectStorage support and more. Now that the upgrade is out, we have also learned that all settings can go as high as Ultra and that the game features a Scene BVH Quality, thanks to a new screenshot provided by <a href="https://www.resetera.com/members/gabdeg.8633/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">gabdeg</a> on the ResetERA forums. Unfortunately, HDR support is nowhere to be found, which is a shame.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GTA-V-Enhanced-RT-settings.png"></a></figure>

<p>It's too early to say if the new ray tracing features included in the Grand Theft Auto V Enhanced PC release improve the game's visuals universally, but from the <a href="https://imgsli.com/MzU1MTE5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">quick comparison</a> put together by gabdeg, it's clear they do have a significant impact. Another <a href="https://imgsli.com/MzU1MTIx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">comparison</a> put together by another ResetERA forums member, <a href="https://www.resetera.com/members/vic20.61250/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vic20</a>, highlights how much ray-traced global illumination makes a difference. Performance also seems to be solid, according to the first few reports, so it definitely looks like Rockstar Games has done a great job improving their highly successful game.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto V Enhanced is now available for all PC users as a free upgrade, while the Legacy version will continue to be available to allow those with PC configurations that do not match those for the upgraded version of the game to continue playing normally. More information on the Enhanced release can be found <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-v-pc-ray-traced-global-illumination-ambient-occlusion-dlss-fsr/">here.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4 Will Release July 11, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tony-hawk-3-4-details-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tony-hawk%E2%80%99s-pro-skater-3-4-will-release-july-11-2025.1124616/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/tony-hawk-3-4-details-leaked/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>New leaks for Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4 have revealed that the game will release on July 11, 2025.</p>



<p>That’s according to reputable dataminer and leaker <a href="https://x.com/billbil_kun" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">billbil-kun</a>, who took to X (formerly Twitter) to reveal details. </p>



<p>In his tweets, he revealed that the games will be released on July 11, 2025, but will come with a few different editions, including a collector’s edition that will allow you to play the games three days early.</p>



<p>The collector’s edition for Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4 will set you back $129.99 and will be available for the Xbox Series X\s, PlayStation 5, and Nintendo Switch. According to the dataminer, it comes with three days early access and other items included in the deluxe edition.</p>



<p>At such a hefty price tag for the collectors edition though, it’s currently unclear on if the edition will come with some sort of physical component. </p>



<p>The standard price for the game will be $49.99, with the deluxe costing $69.99 and comes with Doom Slayer &amp; Revenant Skaters + Unmaykr Hoverboard + In-Game Music.</p>



<p>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4 is set to officially be revealed later today.</p>



<p>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4 is set to launch on the Xbox Series S|X, PlayStation 5, PC, and come to Game Pass.</p>



<p>Are you excited for Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/call-of-duty-2025-in-development-for-last-gen-consoles.1711/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Insider Gaming Forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-verdansk-collection-stores/">a ‘Verdansk Collection’ is coming on March 10</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Becomes Capcom's Fastest-Selling Game In Just 3 Days]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-becomes-capcoms-fastest-selling-game-in-just-3-days/1100-6529838/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-becomes-capcoms-fastest-selling-game-in-just-3-days.1124613/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-becomes-capcoms-fastest-selling-game-in-just-3-days/1100-6529838/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529838">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Capcom has announced that Monster Hunter Wilds has sold 8 million copies in three days, a new record for the company. This is the fastest-selling game in Capcom's history, surpassing the previous record-holder Monster Hunter World by a sizable margin. When it first launched several years ago, Monster Hunter World reached five million sales in three days <a href="https://www.capcom.co.jp/ir/english/news/html/e240312.html" rel="nofollow ">and has so far reached 25 million lifetime sales</a>. Monster Hunter Wilds still has some way to go to reach and possibly surpass that number, but with extensive post-launch plans in place, it has a fighting chance to do so.</p><p><a href="https://www.capcom.co.jp/ir/english/news/html/e250304.html" rel="nofollow ">According to Capcom</a>, several open betas, a big marketing push, and the broad appeal of Monster Hunter Wilds have helped it reach this milestone, and the company remains "firmly committed to satisfying the expectations" of players. On Steam, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-hits-top-5-all-time-on-steam-for-concurrent-players/1100-6529828/">Monster Hunter Wilds has set a record on that PC platform</a> by reaching the top five for concurrent players, with 1.3 million people on March 1, 2025. The other top four ahead of Monster Hunter Wilds are PUBG, Black Myth: Wukong, Palworld, and Counter-Strike 2.</p><p>Overall, the Monster Hunter franchise is the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/capcoms-best-selling-game-franchises-of-all-time-and-whats-next-for-each/2900-6294/">second-best-selling Capcom franchise of all time</a>, with Resident Evil still holding the top spot. Even with Wilds adding 8 million more sales--and counting--to the franchise, Resident Evil holds a significant lead with 176 million sales in total for the franchise. It's not too surprising, given that the franchise launched several years before Monster Hunter and it has more games in its library.</p><p>"There are a few missteps along the way--of both an artistic and technical variety--but Wilds is another excellent entry in Capcom's beloved series," Richard Wakeling wrote in GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/monster-hunter-wilds-review-new-frontier/1900-6418338/">Monster Hunter Wilds review</a>. If you've just gotten started on the game, you can also check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-guides-hub/1100-6529740/">Monster Hunter Wilds guides hub</a> for several helpful features and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/psa-monsters-can-rudely-crash-your-bbq-in-monster-hunter-wilds/1100-6529833/">PSAs on party-crashing beasts</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jam City sells Canadian studio Ludia after receiving 'unsolicited offer']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/jam-city-sells-canadian-studio-ludia-after-receiving-unsolicited-offer-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jam-city-sells-canadian-studio-ludia-after-receiving-unsolicited-offer.1124610/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/jam-city-sells-canadian-studio-ludia-after-receiving-unsolicited-offer-<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Jam City has agreed to sell its Montreal studio Ludia to a group of Canadian investors.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://venturebeat.com/business/jam-city-sells-ludia-game-studio-to-canadian-institutional-investors/">As reported by Venturebeat</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the company explained it wasn't actively pursuing a sale but received an unsolicited offer that was too good to refuse.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Jam City co-founder and CEO, Joshua Yguado, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7302386821764657155/">confirmed the news on Linkedin</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and said Ludia will "thrive" as an independent company under the leadership of CEO Jimmy Gendron.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He said the sale represents a great opportunity for both Ludia and Jam City.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The news comes three years after Jam City purchased Ludia after raising $350 million in equity and debt financing.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">At the time, Jam City said the deal would help realize its mission of developing and publishing top-grossing titles based on licensed IP.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ludia is known for working on mobile games such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Jurassic World: The Game</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dragons: Titan Uprising</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>DC Heroes &amp; Villains</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Around 130 employees are expected to remain with Ludia following the sale. A small number of workers will stay with Jam City.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The sale means Jam City now has 10 studios around the world. The company, which has generated over $4 billion in aggregate lifetime bookings, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/jam-city-lays-off-nearly-85-employees-as-industry-fails-to-hit-upward-trend-">laid off around 85 employees in August 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> after some of its titles underperformed.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>