<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 19:33:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deep Cuts]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/deep-cuts/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deep-cuts.1174158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://remapradio.com/articles/deep-cuts/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p><em>Few things underscore the differences between Rob and Patrick more than their approach to playing new video games, which is to say that Patrick is often spending his time with The Next Thing, while Rob continues to mine the past.</em></p><p><em>That split is part of what makes Remap what it is, though!</em></p><p><em>Plus, who doesn't want an excuse to talk about BioForge? Who isn't excited to potentially have Rob and Cado playing Myth II: Soulblighter co-op on stream? It's our Remember Some Games era and it's great.</em></p><hr><p><strong>Rob: </strong>So we talked about this on the podcast, but I’ve spent a decent chunk of this week playing <em>Myth: The Fallen Lords </em>and <em>Myth 2: Soulblighter</em>. They just had some amazing updates drop from the Project Magma team, who have basically been working to keep the <em>Myth </em>series playable for the last fifteen years. The new update is called the <em>Twice Born Edition </em>and it’s as close to a remaster as the game is likely to get.</p><p><em>Myth </em>is one of my all-time favorite games. There are countless games that channel or outright copy from Tolkien, but <em>Myth </em>is one of the few that I think fully understands how the Lord of the Rings experience should be translated into a game. Mission briefings are given via bleak, well-written journal entries that evoke the idea that the game itself is a found text, like the history the Fellowship finds in the depths of Moria. Unit descriptions are pieces of larger, unseen texts (a technique that would resurface with <em>Destiny’s </em>Grimoire), and that narrative device suggests a world of cultures, languages, and histories both known and lost to time.</p><p>The narrative points to epic battles happening off-screen but the game is not aiming to be a fantasy <em>Total War</em>. Rather it plays out like a miniatures game, one where each warrior must be painstakingly positioned and maneuvered to get the most out of them in battle. You’re usually with a special forces team or a beleaguered rearguard or a clever diversionary raiding party, in situations where you still feel like you’re part of a military fantasy epic, but the scale is a little more personal, and little more ground-level.</p><p>Which means you have ample opportunities to witness the chaos caused by the game’s physics model. Stray arrows knock out friendly troops, grenades take miraculous or cursed bounces or turn out to be duds. Flying bits of debris (usually bone and meat, being honest) will smack into other units and cause damage, or perhaps knock a spear off-course. It’s a game that feels gleefully at odds with a lot of notions of game balance: the same encounter in <em>Myth </em>might go horrifically wrong despite your best efforts or you might make a horrible mistake that somehow breaks in your favor and hands you a wholly unearned victory. But because this is all depicted on screen and driven by some simple physics and overpowered explosives, <em>Myth </em>usually feels funny and surprising rather than a game where you can get screwed by a bad dice roll.</p><p>This game also served as my introduction to Bungie, and I was kind of surprised when the next I heard of them was when they were in the early stages of promoting <em>Halo </em>before it was picked up by Microsoft. I didn’t know about their history as a shoot developer for Macs, and so I was kind of disappointed when the studio that made this fantasy tactics masterpiece became Halo Incorporated. At the time I thought <em>Halo </em>was the outlier, now I understand that if anything, the two <em>Myth </em>games are a wildly successful experiment from a shooter studio.</p><p>Playing it this week got me wondering, are there studios you’ve been a fan of that have a game or a series that fascinates you <em>because </em>it doesn’t seem to fit what they are known for?</p><figure><figcaption><span>Back when they made real box art, folks.</span></figcaption></figure><p><strong>Patrick:</strong> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/giantbomb/comments/53we99/backflips_n_bioforge/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>“Did that say mecha raptor?”</u></a></p><p>Yeah, this one is easy. It’s Origin Systems making <em>BioForge</em>. I first fell for Origin Systems because of the <em>Wing Commander</em> series. More specifically, <em>Wing Commander III: Heart of the Tiger</em>. The more CDs a game shipped with, the better, imo. Remember <a href="https://www.indieretronews.com/2020/03/wing-commander-iii-heart-of-tiger-1994.html?ref=remapradio.com"><u>that killer box art</u></a>? Absolutely irresistible. But this was an era where it wasn’t easy to look up the history of a studio, unless you came across it in, say, a <em>PC Gamer</em>.</p><p>In my mind, Origin made <em>Wing Commander</em> games, or at the very least, flight simulator games. It was 1994 and I was nine years old. I didn’t know what <em>Ultima</em> was. I didn’t know about <em>System Shock</em>, either.</p>
		<div>
	<h2><svg role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" height="1em" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><!--! Font Awesome Free 6.4.2 by @fontawesome - https://fontawesome.com License - https://fontawesome.com/license (Commercial License) Copyright 2023 Fonticons, Inc. --><path d="M144 144v48H304V144c0-44.2-35.8-80-80-80s-80 35.8-80 80zM80 192V144C80 64.5 144.5 0 224 0s144 64.5 144 144v48h16c35.3 0 64 28.7 64 64V448c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64H64c-35.3 0-64-28.7-64-64V256c0-35.3 28.7-64 64-64H80z"></path></svg>  Library, Zeal or Foundation tier</h2>
	<p>Subscribe at  Library, Zeal or Foundation tier(s) or above to access "Deep Cuts". You'll also get access to the full back catalog of that tier's content.</p>
	<p><a href="https://remapradio.com/signup/">Sign up now</a>
	<small>Already have an account? <a href="https://remapradio.com/#/portal/signin/">Sign in</a></small>
</p></div>
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Expedition 33 Passes Huge Sales Milestone, And That's Not Even The Full Story Of Its Success]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/expedition-33-passes-huge-sales-milestone-and-thats-not-even-the-full-story-of-its-success/1100-6531140/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/expedition-33-passes-huge-sales-milestone-and-thats-not-even-the-full-story-of-its-success.1174155/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/expedition-33-passes-huge-sales-milestone-and-thats-not-even-the-full-story-of-its-success/1100-6531140/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531140">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 developer Sandfall Interactive has announced that the game has already sold 500,000 copies, just after launch. In a social media post, the studio said the game reached this sales milestone "sooner than we'd ever imagined."</p><p>Expedition 33 is also on Game Pass, and presumably the 500,000 figure does not include people playing via the subscription service. Expedition 33 is the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/topselling/US" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">No. 2 best-selling game on Steam right now</a>, only behind Oblivion Remastered, and it's reached <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">more than 70,000 concurrent players.</a> The game is also on PS5.</p><p>Some industry observers theorized that Expedition 33 might have had its lunch eaten by Oblivion Remastered, as it surprise-launched just two days before Expedition 33. Both are Game Pass titles, but clearly, there is enough room for multiple success stories this week. Both Bethesda and Sandfall <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/oblivion-remastered-dev-congratulates-expedition-33-studio-on-game-pass-launch/1100-6531082/" data-ref-id="1100-6531082">shared congratulatory messages with each other</a> regarding their respective game launches this week.</p><p>Expedition 33 was developed by a core team of around 30 people at Sandfall. "I truly believe that five or six years ago it would have been impossible for a team of our size to make this," creative director Guillaume Broche told <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/clair-obscur-expedition-33-creative-director-speaks-about-the-dark-fantasy-rpgs-stunning-unreal-engine-5-graphics-its-a-key-foundation-for-the-studio-to-really-look-for-the-latest-technology/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC Gamer</a> of the studio's use of Epic's Unreal Engine 5.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482902-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.39pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4482902" data-ratio="0.5587958607714" data-width="1063" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482902-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.39pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4482902"></a><figcaption>Expedition 33 is off to a fast start</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482902-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.39pm.png"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482905-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.20pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482906-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.25pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482907-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.30pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482908-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.35pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482909-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.40pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482910-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.45pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482911-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.29pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482912-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.34pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482913-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.39pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482914-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.44pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4482905,1300-4482906,1300-4482907,1300-4482908,1300-4482909,1300-4482910,1300-4482911,1300-4482912,1300-4482913,1300-4482914" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482905-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.20pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482906-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.25pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482907-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.30pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482908-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.35pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482909-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.40pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482910-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.45pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482911-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.29pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482912-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.34pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482913-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.39pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4482914-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.44pm.png"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482905-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.20pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482906-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.25pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482907-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.30pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482908-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.35pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482909-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.40pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482910-screenshot2025-04-25at12.47.45pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482911-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.29pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482912-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.34pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482913-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.39pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4482914-screenshot2025-04-25at12.48.44pm.png"></figure><p>GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review-light-and-shadow/1900-6418358/" data-ref-id="1900-6418358">Expedition 33 review</a> scored the game a 9/10, with reviewer Richard Wakeling writing, "There are minor pitfalls in relation to its narrow exploration and some quality-of-life issues, but these missteps aren't enough to significantly detract from a game with all the makings of an RPG classic."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Boss Talks AI, Single-Player Games, Managing Risk, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-boss-talks-ai-single-player-games-managing-risk-and-more/1100-6531142/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-boss-talks-ai-single-player-games-managing-risk-and-more.1174149/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-boss-talks-ai-single-player-games-managing-risk-and-more/1100-6531142/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531142">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Larian Studios created one of the most beloved and acclaimed RPGs in recent times with 2024's Baldur's Gate 3, and everyone wants to know what's coming next from the studio.</p><p>It's too soon for that, however, as Larian isn't ready to pull back the curtain on its next project, codenamed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-now-giving-full-attention-to-next-game-codenamed-excalibur/1100-6528758/" data-ref-id="1100-6528758">Excalibur</a>. While we wait, though, Vincke is sharing his thoughts on a wide variety of industry topics.</p><p>Speaking to GameSpot's Tamoor Hussain, Vincke discussed at a high level what's next for Larian and dug into hot-button issues like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-embraces-machine-learning-for-tasks-that-nobody-wants-to-do/1100-6531123/" data-ref-id="1100-6531123">his stance on AI/machine learning</a>. Vincke also talked about managing risk as Larian grows in size, weighed in with his take on if single-player games are dead or not, and discussed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-director-says-making-dlc-for-its-games-is-boring-for-larian/1100-6531125/" data-ref-id="1100-6531125">why Larian didn't release DLC for Baldur's Gate 3</a>.</p><p>These are just a few of the topics that Vincke discussed in our hour-long chat with the industry veteran--be sure to watch the full video to learn more.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gy9P2HPF9ss" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Gy9P2HPF9ss" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>We don't know what Larian is making next, but it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-isnt-making-baldurs-gate-4-next-thats-not-what-we-were-made-for/1100-6522049/" data-ref-id="1100-6522049">won't be Baldur's Gate 4.</a> Beyond Larian's immediate next game, Vincke is thinking even further out and has grand plans to create a "very big RPG" that will <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-is-working-toward-an-rpg-that-dwarfs-it/1100-6522051/" data-ref-id="1100-6522051">"dwarf"</a> any of Larian's previous releases. "It's an inspirational goal. That's it. I cannot say more, because it needs to stay in that dream-reality," he said.</p><p>While Larian will not make Baldur's Gate 4, Hasbro has said it is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hasbro-hopes-next-baldurs-gate-game-is-here-before-2050/1100-6522712/" data-ref-id="1100-6522712">keen to expand the Baldur's Gate series with other teams. </a>"We're going to take our time and find the right partner, the right approach, and the right product," Hasbro said to fans looking for another entry.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta reportedly lays off over 100 employees across AR/VR hardware and games division]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/meta-reportedly-lays-off-over-100-employees-across-arvr-hardware-and-games-division</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/meta-reportedly-lays-off-over-100-employees-across-ar-vr-hardware-and-games-division.1174113/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/meta-reportedly-lays-off-over-100-employees-across-arvr-hardware-and-games-division<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Company says cuts will help teams "work more efficiently".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/meta-quest-3-promo-shot-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Meta</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Facebook owner Meta has reportedly cut over 100 jobs at Reality Labs, the division responsible for its virtual reality and augmented reality software and hardware, including Quest.
</p>
<p>
The news was initially <a href="https://www.theverge.com/meta/655835/meta-layoffs-reality-labs-vr-supernatural">reported by The Verge</a>, whose sources said the cuts had impacted teams within Meta's Oculus Studios - which is focused on developing games for the company's Quest headsets - as well as "some" employees from Reality Labs' hardware arm. Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-24/meta-lays-off-more-than-100-staff-across-reality-labs-unit?embedded-checkout=true">later reported "more than 100" workers were impacted</a>.
</p>
<p>
In a statement provided to The Verge, Meta spokesperson Tracy Clayton confirmed cuts had been made within Oculus Studios, saying "some" teams were "undergoing shifts in structure and roles that have impacted team size." Clayton added the changes were intended to "help Studios work more efficiently on future mixed reality experiences for our growing audience, while still delivering great content for people today." The Verge says Meta declined to comment on layoffs outside of Oculus Studios.
</p>
<p>
Impacted staff include the team behind Meta Quest fitness application Supernatural, which Meta acquired for $400m USD - alongside its developer Within - in 2023, following an anti-trust battle with the FTC. The Supernatural team <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/getsupernatural/permalink/9571469649572696/">confirmed it had been affected by Meta's latest layoffs</a> in a statement shared on Facebook, writing it was "deeply saddened" by the loss of "some of our incredibly talented team members".
</p>
<p>
Despite the layoffs, Meta says it remains "committed to investing in mixed reality experiences, including fitness and games, and our drive to deliver the best experiences possible for the Quest and Supernatural communities remains unchanged."
</p>
<p>
Meta has dramatically reduced staff numbers of the last few years, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/facebook-owner-meta-announces-further-10000-job-losses">cutting more than 20,000 jobs in 2022 and 2023</a>. Lone Echo developer Ready at Dawn - which Meta acquired in 2020 - was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lone-echo-developer-ready-at-dawn-reportedly-heavily-impacted-by-latest-meta-layoffs">heavily impacted</a> by those cuts and was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lone-echo-and-the-order-1886-developer-ready-at-dawn-reportedly-shut-down-by-meta">closed down at the end of last year</a>.
</p>
<p>
Today's Reality Labs layoffs follow Meta's admission last April that the AR/VR <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/facebook-owner-meta-loses-a-billion-per-month-on-its-arvr-division-but-believes-it-will-be-worth-it">division had lost over $1bn every month</a> for most of the last two years, with the company saying it expected losses to increase as it deepened its investment.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reburn Has Delayed La Quimera With No New Release Date In Sight After Poor Reviews]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/reburn-has-delayed-la-quimera-with-no-new-release-date-in-sight-after-sending-out-review-codes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reburn-has-delayed-la-quimera-with-no-new-release-date-in-sight-after-poor-reviews.1174095/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/reburn-has-delayed-la-quimera-with-no-new-release-date-in-sight-after-sending-out-review-codes/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>La Quimera is a new first-person, linear, story-focused shooter from <a href="https://wccftech.com/la-quimera-developer-qa-powered-by-unreal-engine-4-main-story-to-last-5-hours/">Reburn</a>, the studio formerly known as 4A Games Ukraine, which previously worked on the Metro series with the rest of 4A Games based in Malta.</p>
<p>It was initially set to release today, April 25, 2025. The release date was set at the <a href="https://wccftech.com/sci-fi-co-op-shooter-la-quimera-arrives-on-pc-later-this-month/">beginning of April</a>, and review codes were sent out to Wccftech and other members of the press ahead of today's launch. Shortly after reviews went live, Reburn announced within its Discord server (spotted by <a href="https://www.dsogaming.com/news/la-quimera-has-been-quietly-delayed-no-new-release-date/">DSOGaming</a>) that La Quimera was delayed, with no new release date set.</p>
<p>In a statement, chief executive officer Dmytro Lymar apologized for the last-minute delay and attributed the issues Reburn had to unexpected problems it faced with this being its first project as an independent studio and "<em>the circumstances we're faced with here in the Ukraine</em>."</p>
<p>"<em>We'd like to apologise for the unexpected delay in getting La Quimera out to you, our fans and supporters. Our team here at Reburn has been working hard on the game, and it being our first title as an independent game developer has led to some unforeseen challenges. We are trying our best to address the matters as quickly as possible, while also navigating the circumstances we're faced with here in the Ukraine. We thank you for your patience, your continued support, and your understanding.</em>"</p>
<p>In our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/la-quimera-short-but-not-sweet/">review of La Quimera</a>, we noted plenty of bugs, which, on their own, made it abundantly clear that it needed more time in development. But the bugs weren't the only issues the game had. Core issues with the story and characters, with gameplay that only features a few cool moments, are all problems that take more than a few rounds of bug fixes to fix.</p>
<p>"<em>La Quimera is an incomplete game, a mixture of stitched together parts that don't come together to make a full image,</em>" our reviewer wrote.</p>
<p>"<em>The amount of bugs are clear indicators that this game needed more time in development, but so is the underwhelming story and gameplay that aren't given enough time to go anywhere. If La Quimera was communicated as an Early Access release, then I'd be more hopeful for what's to come, but if this is meant to be the full game, it's not one that's worth your time.</em>"</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infinity Nikki is coming soon to Steam and will add co-op mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/656486/infinity-nikki-co-op-steam-bubble-season</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/infinity-nikki-is-coming-soon-to-steam-and-will-add-co-op-mode.1174092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/656486/infinity-nikki-co-op-steam-bubble-season<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news">News</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>Bubble Season offers new co-op mode activities, a new platform to play on, and a new way to show off your style.</p></div></div><div><p>Bubble Season offers new co-op mode activities, a new platform to play on, and a new way to show off your style.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-04-25T17:56:11+00:00">Apr 25, 2025, 5:56 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/14/24320757/infinity-nikki-review-gacha-dress-up-game">Infinity Nikki</a></em>’s next update will add some major new features. Bubble Season starts April 29th and will include a new area, new activities, and, of course, new (and returning) outfits. But the biggest addition is one that fans have been asking for since launch: co-op. Check out the trailer above.</p><p>In the new season you’ll be able to have dress-up adventures with a friend in two player co-op mode. You can travel the world of<em> Infinity Nikki </em>together, solving special co-op mode puzzle games and participating in escort missions. Players will also prove they’re the most stylish one in the group chat with a fashion runway and new interactions that players can use in all the photos they’re going to take. </p><p>Like every new <em>Infinity Nikki</em> season, there will be special outfits to collect – though none of them inspire in me the kind of fanaticism that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/619372/infinity-nikki-eerie-season-event-march-2025">the cowgirl outfit</a> from two seasons ago did. (Which I did get without spending any money. Hooray!) For the first time though, <em>IN</em> is also bringing back outfits from previous seasons for players who missed out on them and for newbies to build up their wardrobe quickly. </p><div><p>Speaking of wardrobe,<em> Infinity Nikk</em>i is catching up to the MMO girlies by implementing a new dye system. In Bubble Season, players will be able to use dyes to change the color of their outfits the same way one can in <em>World of Warcraft</em> and <em>Final Fantasy XIV</em>. No word on exactly how dyes will work or if they will be yet more things to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/605811/infinity-nikki-gacha-mechanics">spend your precious currency on</a>. But I am interested in the potential of getting new colors for my clothes without the hassle of the current system, which involves the expensive and time consuming process of collecting duplicate outfits.</p><p>Bubble Season starts April 29th and if you’re one of the folks waiting for the game to come to PC, the Steam version of<em> Infinity Nikki </em>launches that day too.</p></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Installer</h2><p><span>A weekly newsletter by David Pierce designed to tell you everything you need to download, watch, read, listen to, and explore that fits in The Verge’s universe.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Green Minecraft Movie Milk Gets Its Color From Chemicals The Government Wants To 'Eliminate']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-creeper-milk-blue-dye-fda-safe-children-1851777905</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/green-minecraft-movie-milk-gets-its-color-from-chemicals-the-government-wants-to-eliminate.1174083/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-creeper-milk-blue-dye-fda-safe-children-1851777905<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="1761fb660f4c9f5e06a36770c88eb0cd" data-recommend-id="image://1761fb660f4c9f5e06a36770c88eb0cd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jack Black holds Creeper Milk. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Jack Black holds Creeper Milk. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Warner Bros. / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1761fb660f4c9f5e06a36770c88eb0cd" data-recommend-id="image://1761fb660f4c9f5e06a36770c88eb0cd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jack Black holds Creeper Milk. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Minecraft</em> has milk in it but it’s not green. Instead, the “Creeper milk” going viral on Tiktok arises purely from the marketing geniuses behind chocolate milk maker TruMoo.<strong>&nbsp;</strong>Drafting off of the <em>Minecraft Movie</em>’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-half-a-billion-550-million-box-office-1851776110&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-half-a-billion-550-million-box-office-1851776110">box office success</a></span>, the dairy company released jugs of <em>Minecraft</em>-licensed “Vanilla Green Lowfat Milk”  that looks like melted Shamrock Shakes. There’s only one problem: they get their Creeper green from petroleum-based dyes the federal government is trying to get rid of.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197544" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="4 Essential Tips to Survive Clair Obscur: Expedition 33’s Brutal First Hours" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="197544,197541,197533" data-current="197544"><div><p>4 Essential Tips to Survive Clair Obscur: Expedition 33’s Brutal First Hours</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197544/197544_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197544/197544_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197544/197544_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23069.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>As spotted <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/green-minecraft-milk-includes-a-food-dye-that-us-government-is-trying-to-get-rid-of/1100-6531081/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/green-minecraft-milk-includes-a-food-dye-that-us-government-is-trying-to-get-rid-of/1100-6531081/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by <em>GameSpot</em></a></span>, the contraband food dye is “Blue No. 1" and can be found in the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-review-bad-jack-black-kids-movie-steve-1851775345&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-review-bad-jack-black-kids-movie-steve-1851775345"><em>Minecraft Movie</em></a></span> milk’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://trumoo.com/products/minecraft-vanilla-green-lowfat-milk-half-gallon/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://trumoo.com/products/minecraft-vanilla-green-lowfat-milk-half-gallon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">list of ingredients</a></span>. It’s one of a number of synthetic coloring agents that the Trump Administration is looking to ban over concerns about potential links to behavioral changes in children and even cancer. Foods with certain chemical colorings like Red No. 3 <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2025/01/18/nx-s1-5262621/red-dye-3-food-children&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2025/01/18/nx-s1-5262621/red-dye-3-food-children" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">already require warning labels in places like Europe</a></span>. </p><p>“The FDA is fast-tracking the review of calcium phosphate, Galdieria extract blue, gardenia blue, butterfly pea flower extract, and other natural alternatives to synthetic food dyes,” the Federal Food and Drug Administration <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/hhs-fda-phase-out-petroleum-based-synthetic-dyes-nations-food-supply&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/hhs-fda-phase-out-petroleum-based-synthetic-dyes-nations-food-supply" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announced</a></span> earlier this week. “The agency is also taking steps to issue guidance and provide regulatory flexibilities to industries.” The plan is to get rid of the synthetic dyes from all foods sold in the U.S. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/health/2025/04/23/food-dyes-banned-phased-out-rfk-fda-hhs/83230760007/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/health/2025/04/23/food-dyes-banned-phased-out-rfk-fda-hhs/83230760007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by 2026</a></span>. </p><p>As it stands, Creeper milk has been <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.instagram.com/reel/DIJshP-Ri6w/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DIJshP-Ri6w/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">popping up</a></span> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/JimmyHere/status/1912735294610092093&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/JimmyHere/status/1912735294610092093" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">all over</a></span> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/bayarea/comments/1k0b8n8/on_a_desperate_search_for_the_fabled_green/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/bayarea/comments/1k0b8n8/on_a_desperate_search_for_the_fabled_green/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">social media</a></span> as people encounter the chilled emerald draughts in the dairy sections of their local supermarkets. “Found this creeper milk at Walmart yesterday,” one fan wrote on the <em>Minecraft</em> subreddit <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Minecraft/comments/1jov0l4/found_this_creeper_milk_at_walmart_yesterday/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Minecraft/comments/1jov0l4/found_this_creeper_milk_at_walmart_yesterday/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">earlier this month</a></span>. “I know you could milk squids before, but milking creepers is beyond me,” another responded. Others have pointed out that TruMoo was also the company behind last year’s blue<em> Star Wars</em> milk, a play on the substance fueling a grizzled Luke Skywalker’s stoic existence in the most recent trilogy. <br></p><p><em>Star Wars</em> and <em>Minecraft Movie</em> milk might not be long for this world if health secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr. and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/08/us/rfk-jr-brain-health-memory-loss.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/08/us/rfk-jr-brain-health-memory-loss.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">his dead brainworm</a></span> have their way. And the timing couldn’t be worse for lovers of depraved promotional drink crossovers. The next <em>Mario Bros. </em>and <em>Shrek </em>movies are both due out in 2026. Pour one out for the red Mushroom and green Ogre milks that might have been. </p><p>It might be safer to start staying away from milk altogether  in the near future anyway. With <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-fda-suspends-food-safety-quality-checks-after-staff-cuts-2025-04-17/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-fda-suspends-food-safety-quality-checks-after-staff-cuts-2025-04-17/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">unprecedented cuts to FDA staffing</a></span>, routine safety checks for dairy, meat, and other food prone to bacterial outbreaks are apparently slowing down. Today’s Creeper milk might end up being safer than 2026's store-brand 2 percent after all.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Blue Prince's success due to 'social play?']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/is-blue-prince-s-success-due-to-social-play-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-blue-princes-success-due-to-social-play.1174077/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/is-blue-prince-s-success-due-to-social-play-<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I may be slightly obsessed with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blue Prince</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, developer Dogubomb's recently released adventure/puzzle/mystery game that sees players drafting rooms in a massive, surreal manor, teasing out clues with each action and each day. It offers a potent blend of escape room-style puzzles (with math, logic, spatial reasoning, and other flavors), strategic room-drafting action straight out of the tabletop sensation </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/10547/betrayal-at-house-on-the-hill">Betrayal at House on the Hill</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and a personal favorite game paradigm: the player and player character attain knowledge and ply it at close to a 1:1 ratio. It's ostensibly a single player game, but I think it has even longer legs as an unofficial "co-op" experience.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Outer Wilds</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Return of the Obra Dinn</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, or </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/809950/Asemblance_Oversight/">Asemblance: Oversight</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, more emphasis is placed on the knowledge you gain by playing and exploring (access to secrets, methods, and rules about the way the world works) more so than an in-fiction leveling system (like XP in an RPG) or similar. While there are more standard elements (a general roguelike run-based structure, some permanent upgrades to your kit and abilities, rng), what feels most important is what you, the player are absorbing, experimenting with, and putting to the test in your actions.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">What's even more important? When two people—or even more—absorb that information.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-art-of-game-balance-evolution" target="_self" data-discover="true">The art of game balance: evolution</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Putting together a good run sometimes feels like science: you start formulating theories as you observe, and test them out as best you can. Even when those theories are disproven (or you were looking at the wrong variables), you learned something that day, and you take that lesson with you. Seeing those theories proven and disproven may explain why the game is doing so well.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Co-op play in Blue Prince">Co-op play in Blue Prince</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I'm enjoying the game a great deal on my own, but here's a second (and perhaps just as powerful) factor at work here: like a great escape room, it's even more fun with another person. The way my partner and I are tearing through, you wouldn't know it was a single player game: we'll pass the controller back and forth (sometimes for puzzles one of us is naturally better at, sometimes because it's simply dinner time), the non-player grasping my graphing notebook (yes, graphing paper, we are that serious), taking down notes, drawing charts, and offering suggestions and solutions as we draft and puzzle through. The first notes were kind of a mess, but we have that aspect down to a science now, about 30 hours into the mystery.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It doesn't hurt that we happen to have complementary puzzle preferences—she's easily ten times better and faster at the parlor rooms, while I've been playing 3D games longer and have spatial reasoning tasks more front of mind—so we very rarely get stuck and generally have a good flow going. We're certainly not the only ones playing this way, of the approximately </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://steamdb.info/app/1569580/charts/#max">12k players</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on Steam right now (plus players on the Xbox consoles and PS5). A cursory glance at Twitch reveals plenty of streamers playing with their communities (some without explicit "backseating," albeit with various degrees of clue acceptance from chat.)</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/must-have-tools-and-libraries-for-indie-game-developers-in-2024" target="_self" data-discover="true">Must-have tools and libraries for indie game developers in 2024</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We've had several "holy crap!" moments in our time with the game so far—when a wanton observation about room decorations was "confirmed" in a more definitive clue (and led us to break out the graph paper). Once we figured out the sequence required to take full advantage of the garage, we just about leapt off the couch in excitement. And lets not forget this little nugget: I've been so obsessed with solving one series of puzzles (in the gallery room, IYKYK) that last night, from a bus, I started texting my partner possible solutions (and full justifications for them) to try while I was out of the house.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Dogubomb may not have explicitly designed the game for this kind of social play, but it suits </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blue Prince</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s style like a perfect little key to a mysterious lock.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-overdesign-trap-of-game-design" target="_self" data-discover="true">The overdesign trap of game design</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Designers wanting to play with this magic, take heed: some element of this comes with the territory whenever you construct so many different types of puzzles. Without giving too much away here, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blue Prince </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">offers many flavors of puzzle and strategy that it naturally lends itself to the escape room logic of "many brains make light work:" just like my partner and I, certain types of players are attracted to (or repelled by) certain kinds of problem solving. It's wildly satisfying (for us and players like us) to collaborate and play this as a team sport and essentially share in the glory.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">You can support this as a developer by offering that variety, at a high standard of quality. Serve up a tasty buffet of puzzle types, and players like us will team up and happily scour every imaginable inch of the game.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Editor-in-Chief, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Danielle is the editor-in-chief of Game Developer, with previous editorial posts at Fanbyte, VICE, and Polygon. She’s also a lecturer in game design at the Berklee College of Music, and a hobbyist game developer in her spare time.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bag More Treasure When You Learn How To Lockpick In Oblivion Remastered]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-lockpicking-minigame-win-skills-1851777900</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bag-more-treasure-when-you-learn-how-to-lockpick-in-oblivion-remastered.1174053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-lockpicking-minigame-win-skills-1851777900<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Lockpicking is one of the very first skills you’ll need to learn and master early on in <em>Oblivion Remastered</em>. You’ll first encounter locked chests in the underground caverns beneath the prison, and then in nearly every dungeon thereafter. It’s a core component of the game. It’s also one of the most cumbersome to some players. But mastering the mini-game and leveling up essential skills will quickly turn your fortunes around. Eventually you’ll be putting the Gray Fox himself to shame.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195670" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="184" data-playlist="195670,196470,196848" data-current="195670"><div><p>This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21167.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h134106"><a id=""></a>Skills that affect lockpicking</h2><figure id="" data-id="653b719c7126f42340e5b3a015901a9d" data-recommend-id="image://653b719c7126f42340e5b3a015901a9d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Security skill in Oblivion Remastered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Security skill in Oblivion Remastered." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Brandon Morgan / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="653b719c7126f42340e5b3a015901a9d" data-recommend-id="image://653b719c7126f42340e5b3a015901a9d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Security skill in Oblivion Remastered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>If you think you’ll spend a lot of time lockpicking as a stealthy character, like one of the many members of the Thieves’ Guild, then <strong>you’ll want to increase your Security</strong>.</p><p>Like all other skills in the game, there are five levels to Security:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Novice (0)</strong>: Up to four tumblers will fall when you fail and break a lockpick.</li><li><strong>Apprentice (25)</strong>: Up to three tumblers will fall when you fail and break a lockpick.</li><li><strong>Journeyman (50)</strong>: Up to two tumblers will fall when you fail and break a lockpick.</li><li><strong>Expert (75)</strong>: Only one tumbler will fall when you fail and break a lockpick.</li><li><strong>Master (100)</strong>: No tumblers will fall when you fail and break a lockpick.</li></ul><p>You can level the skill by attempting lockpicks and speaking with the occasional thief or beggar to train your abilities higher in exchange for gold.</p><h2 id="h134107"><a id=""></a>How to lockpick successfully</h2><figure id="" data-id="21645820e555d8b5d125ad5525bbc2e9" data-recommend-id="image://21645820e555d8b5d125ad5525bbc2e9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="he lockpicking minigame HUD in Oblivion Remastered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="he lockpicking minigame HUD in Oblivion Remastered." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Brandon Morgan / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="21645820e555d8b5d125ad5525bbc2e9" data-recommend-id="image://21645820e555d8b5d125ad5525bbc2e9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="he lockpicking minigame HUD in Oblivion Remastered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Before you attempt to break into a treasure chest filled with junk that you’ll likely toss aside to satisfy your weight limit, you must have lockpicks in your inventory. You can find them all over, in any sack, box, or open chest in the game. You can also buy them at merchants, too, if you’d rather spend a little gold on the local economy.</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-starting-tips-guild-arena-potions-1851777734&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-starting-tips-guild-arena-potions-1851777734">Five Tips Kick Off The Ultimate <em>Oblivion Remastered</em> Adventure</a></span></p><p>With a lockpick at the ready, attempt to open the chest in question to begin the lockpicking minigame. It’s the usual tumbler and lockpick setup, as is common in most video game lock picking minigames, at first glance.</p><p>Your goal is to push each tumbler up with the pick until it reaches the very top of the lock mechanism. Once the tumbler connects with the top, click your interact button to set the tumbler in place. If you’re successful, it will lock open and turn grey, allowing you to move on to the next tumbler in the sequence. Repeat the process.</p><p>Depending on how hard the lock is, the number of tumblers necessary to unlock the box ranges from one to five. You must work through each one in turn, unlocking and opening them in sequence, and if you fail, you’ll reset the lock.</p><hr><p><em>Oblivion Remastered</em> is available now on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, Windows PCs, and Game Pass.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Clears 500,000 Copies Sold]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-clears-500000-copies-sold</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-clears-500-000-copies-sold.1174044/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-clears-500000-copies-sold<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">An auspicious start for the Expedition.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, the debut RPG from Sandfall Interactive, is already off to a strong start. The studio announced today that Expedition 33 has hit a sales milestone of 500,000 copies sold.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"A milestone for us, reached sooner than we'd ever imagined," the team said in a post on <a href="https://x.com/expedition33/status/1915777375834452273" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a>. "Thank you all."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 went live yesterday, April 24, across PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S. It's also a day-one Game Pass game, and despite launching a few days after the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-finally-revealed-in-first-look-gameplay-and-its-out-today">shadow-drop of The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a>, the RPG still seems to be making waves. When Oblivion dropped, Clair Obscur's publisher Kepler Interactive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-publisher-acknowledges-the-barbenheimer-energy-of-releasing-the-same-week-as-oblivion-remastered">even jokingly compared it to "Barbenheimer."</a> The comparison, as it turns out, has been fairly accurate.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Developed by the newly formed studio Sandfall Interactive, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is a turn-based RPG that takes heavy inspiration from the genre classics, from Final Fantasy to Persona. It follows a crew of Expeditioners in a fractured, post-apocalytpic world where every year, a giant being called The Paintress etches a new number and erases anyone older than it. The members of the Expedition, the next up on the block, have one goal in mind: travel to the ends of the continent and destroy the Paintress, ensuring she can never paint death again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The reception of Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 has been widely positive, sitting at <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/clair-obscur-expedition-33/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">92 on MetaCritic</a> and <a href="https://opencritic.com/game/18026/clair-obscur-expedition-33" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">91 on OpenCritic</a>, putting it alongside Split Fiction and Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 as some of the year's most lauded games thus far.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review">IGN's 9/10 review of Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, our reviewer described it as a "modern RPG classic," wearing its inspirations on its sleeve and painting itself into the pantheon of great RPGs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're starting the adventure this weekend, or maybe already have, be sure to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/Tips_-_Things_Clair_Obscur_Doesn't_Tell_You">check out our tips for the important things to know before going into Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TSA Warns That You Shouldn't Try to Fly With a Call of Duty Zombies Monkey Bomb Figurine]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tsa-warns-that-you-shouldnt-try-to-fly-with-a-call-of-duty-zombies-monkey-bomb-figurine</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tsa-warns-that-you-shouldnt-try-to-fly-with-a-call-of-duty-zombies-monkey-bomb-figurine.1174038/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/tsa-warns-that-you-shouldnt-try-to-fly-with-a-call-of-duty-zombies-monkey-bomb-figurine<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking to pick up some video game-inspired replicas or figurines while traveling, you might want to think twice about bringing anything that looks like a Call of Duty weapon in your baggage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That's the takeaway, at least, from a recent post by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) discussing prohibited items. As spotted by <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/call-of-duty/call-of-duty-fan-runs-into-tsa-by-trying-to-take-monkey-bomb-on-plane-3185682/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dexerto</a>, the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo?fbid=1202998258156542&amp;set=a.407732524349790&amp;locale=en_GB" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TSA account on Facebook</a> highlighted a replica figurine of the Monkey Bomb from Call of Duty's Zombies mode that officers at Boston Logan International Airport found in a checked bag.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/493273042-1202998264823208-4830061258408916107-n-1745593633126.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Transportation Security Administration - TSA / Facebook.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Monkey Bomb, or Cymbal Monkey, has appeared in numerous Call of Duty games, from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-world-at-war">World at War</a> through to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Black Ops 6</a>. This particular figurine is meant to be a controller, with its hands outstretched to cradle your favorite game controller. But it's also a replica of a weapon that, well, looks like it has dynamite and cables strapped to it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"This monkey may rack up points in a game, but in real life, leave the gear for your loadout screen, not your baggage," the post read. "Replica weapons and explosives, no matter how cool or collectible, aren't allowed in either carry-on or checked baggage."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The TSA website does also go into detail about <a href="https://www.tsa.gov/travel/security-screening/whatcanibring/items/toy-guns-and-weapons" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">prohibited toy weapons</a>, including "squirt guns, Nerf guns, toy swords, or other items that resemble realistic firearms or weapons." Maybe that's some decent advertising, at least, for the quality of the Monkey Bomb replica statue.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's good to be aware of if you're heading to a convention or place where you might pick up some merch. Whether a monkey figurine or a set of <a href="https://x.com/TSA/status/1744728996741537919" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Naruto-themed throwing knives</a>, the TSA warns that it prohbiits any item in checked or carry-on baggage if they believe it poses a security threat, even if it's a replica.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: Transportation Security Administration - TSA / Facebook.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gameloft CEO Reflects On 25th Anniversary And How There Is "No Miracle Recipe For A Blockbuster"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gameloft-ceo-reflects-on-25th-anniversary-and-how-there-is-no-miracle-recipe-for-a-blockbuster/1100-6531131/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gameloft-ceo-reflects-on-25th-anniversary-and-how-there-is-no-miracle-recipe-for-a-blockbuster.1174035/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gameloft-ceo-reflects-on-25th-anniversary-and-how-there-is-no-miracle-recipe-for-a-blockbuster/1100-6531131/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531131">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">In an industry overflowing with news regarding layoffs, closures, and reduction, any example of a company withstanding the tests of time is worthy of celebration. Gameloft is one such company, and right now it's in celebration mode as it commemorates its 25th anniversary.</p><p dir="ltr">What started as a small mobile gaming outfit has grown into a firm that employs over 2,900 people across 10 studios. With a mix of popular original IP and licensed games in its portfolio, Gameloft is poised to stick around for the foreseeable future.</p><p dir="ltr">GameSpot sat down with Gameloft CEO Alexandre de Rochefort to reflect on the past 25 years of Gameloft's history. He speaks about the main reasons Gameloft has been able to persist, four essential turning points in the history of the company, and the challenges of overcoming the perceived stigmas of the mobile gaming scene.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4482831-asphalt-9.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4482831" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4482831-asphalt-9.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4482831"></a><figcaption>Asphalt 9: Legends</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4482831-asphalt-9.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">"Agility" is key</h2><p dir="ltr">If there's a single word de Rochefort would use to describe Gameloft's persistence in the gaming industry--and he would know, as he's been with the company for its entire existence--it's "agility." In his view, the company has always shown the ability to adapt when needed, especially at the dawning of the mobile gaming boom.</p><p dir="ltr">"Every six months, it seems, we've been faced with critical changes, either within Gameloft or within the industry," de Rochefort says. "The number one reason I'm still here in the company is that I'm still having fun, because every six months there's something radically new happening." Laying out the timeline of Gameloft's history, de Rochefort points to four key moments that, according to him, played a major role in the direction Gameloft would take.</p><p dir="ltr">The first date the Gameloft CEO mentions is January 2003, when the Java programming language was added to Nokia and Siemens mobile phones. This, as de Rochefort explains, was the spark needed to turn the mobile gaming industry into what it is today.</p><p dir="ltr">"2000 through 2002 were extremely harsh years, both for Gameloft and for the few competitors that we had at the time, because nothing was happening in our space," de Rochefort explains. "We were right in our vision, but we were too early; thank God the Java technology was introduced.</p><p dir="ltr">The second core date in Gameloft's history is also a universal change: July 2008, which marked the introduction of the Apple App Store for the iPhone. This was a "game-changer," as de Rochefort describes, not only for Gameloft but for the entire industry, as it "kickstarted the growth of the industry" via smartphone and tablet gaming.</p><p dir="ltr">Next on de Rochefort's list of key moments is more nebulous than the previous two, but its effects are no less important: de Rochefort credits the rise of free-to-play gaming from 2010-2012 as essential to Gameloft's future, as it marked a second boom in the mobile gaming sphere--as well as gaming as whole. "For me, [free-to-play] goes well beyond mobile; it's a defining moment for the video game industry," he said.</p><p dir="ltr">The final milestone on the list of important dates, unlike the previous two, is specific to Gameloft: In January 2019, the company decided to branch out from phones and tablets to home consoles and PC, and doing so allowed them to grow the business not just in revenue, but in partnerships with other companies.</p><p dir="ltr">"At the time, Apple and Google were our biggest partners--and for a time, our only partners," de Rochefort said. "Now, when I look at the charts, we have seven, eight, nine different partners, and Apple and Google are now somewhere in the middle." Who, then, has taken their place at the top of Gameloft's partnership ranks? According to de Rochefort, it's Nintendo.</p><p dir="ltr">De Rochefort says that while moving away from mobile exclusivity has some drawbacks, it ultimately allows the company to be more agile in the long run. "By transitioning these teams to PC and console, we do release less games than we used to per year," he explains, "but the ambition that we have on those games is way more significant. Now, the majority of our games are meant to be cross platform between PC, console, and mobile."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4482835-ddv.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4482835" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4482835-ddv.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4482835"></a><figcaption>Disney Dreamlight Valley</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4482835-ddv.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">Defeating the stereotypes</h2><p dir="ltr">For some, the term "mobile game" comes with a set of stereotypes rooted in the predatory "gacha"-style tactics designed to separate a player from their money. de Rochefort is very aware of this, and he prides himself on Gameloft's games creating a barrier between those methods and the studio's games.</p><p dir="ltr">Having lived through the entire history of mobile gaming, de Rochefort feels the company is uniquely qualified to avoid such pitfalls. "We've been in the mobile space forever, and this was not how mobile gaming used to be," he says.</p><p dir="ltr">"With our Java games from 2003-2008, and then from 2008-2012, we were selling super high-quality mobile games for a premium price of $5 to $10," de Rochefort says. At the time, things were fair, straightforward, and easy to understand--and then free-to-play arrived."</p><p dir="ltr">There's a clear divide, in de Rochefort's opinion, when it comes to the overall reaction to free-to-play games. Some players, particularly younger players or those living in countries where mobile gaming is the most ubiquitous, are used to the free-to-play model and can identify when a game is particularly aggressive. Other players, those who grew up with console and PC gaming before mobile phones became a viable platform, are the ones who look down on the practice as predatory.</p><p dir="ltr">For his part, de Rochefort recognizes that "some games have been super aggressive and hurt the industry badly," but he has worked to ensure that Gameloft treats their players as fairly as possible. "I think free-to-play is fine, but it's important for the companies in this industry to make sure that we stay within the boundaries of what is fair to the user, and we really try to do that," he says. "I really don't think we're one of the greedy companies."</p><p dir="ltr">de Rochefort cites Disney Dreamlight Valley as an example: DDV is a premium game with an upfront cost, and it does include extra items and cosmetics purchased with in-game currency. However, as de Rochefort describes, "you can finish and can play every part of the main game without ever having to spend any extra money, and we try to avoid the traps of being too aggressive with things like paywalls and the like."</p><p dir="ltr">He also mentions in-game advertising as an example; free-to-play games feature many in-game ads, but "less than 10 percent of [Gameloft's] revenue" comes from advertising. "We've always wanted to make sure we make real gaming experiences," de Rochefort says. "That's why we didn't go hypercasual; it's simply not in our DNA."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4482836-oregon-trail.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4482836" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4482836-oregon-trail.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4482836"></a><figcaption>The Oregon Trail (2019)</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4482836-oregon-trail.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">Positioning for the future</h2><p dir="ltr">Just before the interview, Gameloft announced a 25th-anniversary celebration which would give players across its portfolio free in-game currency. 21 different games are included in the promotion, and maintaining 21 different games is no small feat. de Rochefort, however, says the company is well-equipped to handle them thanks to its 2900 employees across 10 studios.</p><p dir="ltr">The company was not immune to the recent wave of layoffs, however, with Gameloft Toronto seeing 49 employees laid off in 2024. de Rochefort is hopeful the worst is in the past, both for Gameloft and the industry at large, as long as companies are realistic in their goals.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think the industry is arriving at a more mature state after three difficult years for the video game industry," de Rochefort says. "We are optimistic, because we simply accept the fact that the industry is not going to grow double digits like it had in the 10 years prior to 2021. I don't see the growth engine that could allow the industry to grow like that coming in the next four or five years."</p><p dir="ltr">For Gameloft's part, staying afloat means a healthy mix of original IP and licensed games, and there are a lot of plans in the pipeline. Internal IP like Asphalt, Gangstar, and Dungeon Hunter are balanced with the aforementioned Disney Dreamlight Valley, an upcoming Dungeon and Dragons game in partnership with Hasbro and Wizards of the Coast, and a few other "unannounced titles" on the way.</p><p dir="ltr">The "agility" that's so important to de Rochefort's vision can also be seen in how many platform Gameloft games can be found on: along with PC, consoles, and traditional mobile marketplaces like the App Store, the company has focused on newer subscription services like Apple Arcade and Netflix Games to show off their games.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think we're the biggest supplier of games to Apple Arcade; we've launched eight games with them already, and we have more to come," de Rochefort says. "Same thing with Netflix, we've released four games there, and hopefully we'll have more games coming in the future."</p><p dir="ltr">As far as what future Gameloft titles may look like, however, the company knows there's no specific blueprint to follow. "There's no miracle recipe for a blockbuster, as you know, because if there were, we would all be doing the same games," de Rochefort says.</p><p dir="ltr">He does, however, make one prediction: The days of Gameloft developing games exclusively for mobile devices are likely over. "We will try and maximize our odds by being super clear on what kind of games we want to do, and we want to do cross-platform," de Rochefort explains. "We will probably not do mobile-only games anymore; if anything, we'll do a PC and console game, and we'll make the effort of porting the game to mobile."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBC: Firebreak Developers Clarify How Rewards And Cosmetic Microtransactions Work]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fbc-firebreak-developers-clarify-how-rewards-and-cosmetic-microtransactions-work/1100-6531136/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fbc-firebreak-developers-clarify-how-rewards-and-cosmetic-microtransactions-work.1174029/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fbc-firebreak-developers-clarify-how-rewards-and-cosmetic-microtransactions-work/1100-6531136/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531136">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>After announcing that its multiplayer co-op shooter <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/control-spin-off-fbc-firebreak-releases-in-june-free-post-launch-support-confirmed/1100-6531076/" data-ref-id="1100-6531076">FBC: Firebreak will launch this summer</a>, Remedy Entertainment detailed the game's reward system, which includes both free and paid goodies.</p><p>In an official post on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2272540/view/536600287259918382" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam</a>, the developers distinguished the difference between "Requisitions," which are sets with items earned through gameplay, and "Classified Requisitions," which are cosmetic-only microtransactions.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="579076136" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465799,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;FBC%3A%20Firebreak%20%E2%80%93%20Gameplay%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:127,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/fbc-firebreak-gameplay-trailer\/2300-6465799\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465799\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465799\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465799\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465799&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465799,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531136&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;fbc-firebreak&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,first-person,shooter&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;remedy-entertainment&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;control&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;control&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465799},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465799\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4463016-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/cJFKvUD2.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1742566260,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="cJFKvUD2" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> FBC: Firebreak – Gameplay Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Requisitions are sets of items that include weapons, equipment, and cosmetics. Players can obtain items in Requisitions using "Lost Assets," the in-game currency earned by completing Jobs. "Play the game, unlock stuff. Simple," the developer post succinctly reads.</p><p>Unlike other modern online games, which feature timed battle passes and stores with rotating items, FBC: Firebreak will offer its Requisitions permanently. Players will be able to choose which items to unlock in any order they please, and they can make progress in earning items from multiple Requisitions at once.</p><p>Meanwhile, Classified Requisitions are "premium" cosmetic item sets that cost real money and include armor sets, sprays, and weapon skins. Remedy did not clarify in the post how much these item sets will cost, but the studio promises that they will have "no impact on gameplay."</p><p>The Deluxe Edition of FBC: Firebreak, which goes for an extra $10 (the base game is modestly priced at $40), comes with the "Firestarter" Classified Requisition, which contains 36 unlockable cosmetic items.</p><p>This Requisitions structure resembles the Helldivers 2 Warbonds system, letting players earn rewards at their own pace and not be vulnerable to potential FOMO. As GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/remedys-fbc-firebreak-is-more-left-4-dead-than-live-service-and-thats-the-beauty-of-it/1100-6530228/" data-ref-id="1100-6530228">FBC: Firebreak preview</a> points out, the game "doesn't punish you for not playing on its schedule."</p><p>When FBC: Firebreak launches on June 17, it'll be on PC, Xbox Series X|S, and PlayStation 5 with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fbc-firebreak-will-feature-cross-play-multiplayer/1100-6530895/" data-ref-id="1100-6530895">full cross-play support</a>. Subscribers of Game Pass Ultimate and PS Plus (Extra and Premium) can hop on the game on day one.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WD’s 2TB SSD for Xbox is $50 off and the M4 MacBook Air is just $899]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/656169/wd-black-c50-xbox-storage-card-m4-macbook-air-deal-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wd%E2%80%99s-2tb-ssd-for-xbox-is-50-off-and-the-m4-macbook-air-is-just-899.1174005/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/tech/656169/wd-black-c50-xbox-storage-card-m4-macbook-air-deal-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Maybe, like me, you bought the Xbox Series S with 512GB of storage and realized, after installing <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6,</em> that you don’t have much (or any) space left for any other games. And maybe, like me, you had to hunt for another drive so you could install other games to play.</p><p>If you’re still in that boat, you might want to consider Western Digital’s 2TB WD_Black NVMe solid state drive. It’s currently on sale at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0DK74LG91/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon for an all-time low of $179.99</a> ($50 off), or about 22 percent off the standard price, and will provide you with plenty of additional storage to work with. To put the price in perspective, it’s only $30 more than the 1TB version, which isn’t on sale. WD is also one of two manufacturers I’m aware of that make these easy plug-in cards — the other is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/5/23712516/xbox-expansion-cards-seagate-price-cut-deal-sale">Seagate</a>.</p><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->180</span></p><div><p>Western Digital’s storage expansion cards for Xbox Series X / S consoles are speedy, plug-and-play cards that match the performance of the consoles’ onboard SSDs. They offer a slightly lower-cost alternative to Seagate’s expansion cards, which were the only game in town for years.</p></div></div><p>There’s no fiddling around with screws or anything to get it to work, either. Just pop it into the back of your Xbox Series S / X, and bam, you’re good to go. Plug and play at its finest, baby.</p><p>But let’s pivot to another good deal real quick.</p><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZD9S5GC/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1883962-REG%2Fapple_mw123ll_a_13_macbook_air_m4.html%2FkZa17940ZSRrfIj%26gclid%3DCj0KCQjw5azABhD1ARIsAA0WFUGYcUxik6ZHlmds-QlwCWAQgyNHflK_dp8WpOc1Xjs6EEW8YhjAkFcaArdXEALw_wcB" rel="sponsored">B&amp;H Photo</a> are also selling Apple’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/627186/apple-macbook-air-m4-13-15-inch-2025-laptop-review">brand-new M4 MacBook Air</a>, which just launched in March, starting at $899 (its best price to date). That’s $100 off Apple’s starting price of $999, which itself is already $100 cheaper than the entry-level price of the M3 model last year.</p><p>And, with the M4, you get 256GB of starting storage instead of 128GB, which is probably fine for most folks who don’t need a lot of local storage. Like me, for example. I’m using an M2 MacBook Air for work, and I only have 82GB used.</p><p>The latest M4 model also has a better 12-megapixel Center Stage camera that will follow your face around while you’re on camera (better said: it’ll keep you in frame) and 16GB of RAM. The design is unchanged from last year, which means you’re still getting just a MagSafe charger and two USB-C ports. But the update to M4 allows you to add two external monitors while also leaving the display open, for a total of three running screens. Good for multitasking.</p><p>It’s a MacBook Air. It’s the best MacBook for most people. You really can’t go wrong here.</p><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p><span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we’ve tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wait, Just How Long Is Oblivion Remastered?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-how-long-to-beat-hltb-expansions-1851777882</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wait-just-how-long-is-oblivion-remastered.1173996/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-how-long-to-beat-hltb-expansions-1851777882<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>The Elder Scrolls</em> ranks among the most beloved role-playing franchises of all time, so it makes sense that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remaster-elder-scrolls-eso-glitch-meme-1851777557&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remaster-elder-scrolls-eso-glitch-meme-1851777557">the internet has been absolutely in love</a></span> with the re-release of one of its most popular entries, <em>Oblivion</em>. After years of speculation,<em> Oblivion Remastered</em> has finally landed, bringing with it vastly improved visuals and a host of quality-of-life improvements. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196572" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: A Rebirth, A Remake, And A Remaster" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="94" data-playlist="196572,196626,196646" data-current="196572"><div><p>The Week In Games: A Rebirth, A Remake, And A Remaster</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196572/196572_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196572/196572_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196572/196572_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196572/196572_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22127.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remaster-elder-scrolls-eso-glitch-meme-1851777557&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remaster-elder-scrolls-eso-glitch-meme-1851777557">The Internet Reacts To <em>The Elder Scrolls: Oblivion Remaster</em> Taking Over Like It’s 2006 Again?</a></span></p><p>Whether it’s your first time playing this classic RPG, or if you’re diving back in after a long time away, you might be a little intimidated by a game as large as <em>Oblivion</em>. How much time will you need to set aside to jump into this massive open-world RPG? Let’s get into it. </p><h2 id="h1229"><a id=""></a>How long is <em>Oblivion Remastered</em>?</h2><p><strong><em>Oblivion Remastered</em>’s main quest can be completed in about 20-25 hours</strong>, while <strong>engaging in a majority of its side-quests can push that number well past 70-80 hours</strong>. And if you’re a true completionist who wants to see and do literally everything in<em> Oblivion Remastered</em>, <strong>you can probably manage to get around 150-200 hours of total gameplay from this trip to Cyrodil</strong>.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-starting-tips-guild-arena-potions-1851777734?rev=1745598807249&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-starting-tips-guild-arena-potions-1851777734?rev=1745598807249">Five Tips To Kick Off The Ultimate <em>Oblivion Remastered</em> Adventure</a></span></p><p>Of course, this is ignoring the fact that<em> Oblivion Remastered</em> also comes with the “Knights of the Nine” and “Shivering Isles” expansion packs, which include their own substantial campaigns to work through. <strong>Completing both expansions in full can add over 40 more hours</strong> of questing, exploring, and monster slaying to your time with the game.</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-horse-armor-free-stables-how-to-get-1851777703&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-horse-armor-free-stables-how-to-get-1851777703"><em>Oblivion Remastered</em> is a massive role-playing experience</a></span> with so much to see and do that it’s hard to say just how long it will take you, specifically, to see it through to the end. Do you want to focus solely on its main quests? Do you want to tackle some of its side-quests? Do you want to explore every nook and cranny of its dense open world? It’s all up to you and your playstyle.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-horse-armor-free-stables-how-to-get-1851777703&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-horse-armor-free-stables-how-to-get-1851777703">Yo, You Can Score A Horse For Free Early On In <em>Oblivion Remastered</em></a></span></p><p>Clearly, there’s no shortage of content in <em>Oblivion Remastered</em>, so if you’re looking for a vast open-world adventure at a reasonable price, you can pick up a copy of it right now on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, or Windows PC for $49.99.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amanda the Adventurer 3 announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/amanda-the-adventurer-3-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amanda-the-adventurer-3-announced-for-pc.1173993/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/amanda-the-adventurer-3-announced-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > DreadXP [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dreadxp">DreadXP</a> and developer <a title="Companies > MANGLEDmaw Games [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mangledmaw-games">MANGLEDmaw Games</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Amanda the Adventurer 3" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/amanda-the-adventurer-3">Amanda the Adventurer 3</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,995 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3657210/Amanda_the_Adventurer_3/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch in 2025. <span id="more-961218"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via DreadXP:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Amanda the Adventurer 3</em> serves as the conclusion to the past two years of puzzles, mysteries, theories, and scares from the viral series, and the masterminds behind the title have cooked up a teaser to give a small glimpse of what’s to come in the finale of Riley’s bizarre <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,235 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>.</p><p>Set immediately after the events of the previous game, <em>Amanda the Adventurer 3</em> once again follows Riley Park as they work to uncover the secrets surrounding the strangely interactive children’s show—<em><a title="Games > Amanda the Adventurer [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/amanda-the-adventurer">Amanda the Adventurer</a></em>. Having survived their Aunt Kate’s attic after being left a stack of VHS tapes of the 90s-style cartoon, Riley followed the mysteries to Kensdale Public Library, where new secrets and dangers awaited them. Now, after barely escaping the library with their life, thanks to the help of an enigmatic masked woman, Riley must explore the abandoned Hameln Entertainment facility to finally discover the truth.</p><p>As the culmination of Riley’s adventures, <em>Amanda the Adventurer 3</em> takes the best elements from its predecessors to offer a thrilling experience to fans of the series and newcomers alike as they take on the thought-provoking puzzles hiding secrets within the Hameln facility.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <div id="carousel_961221"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Challenging, escape room-style puzzles using clues hidden within the tapes.</li><li>Interact with Amanda and friends in an all-new series of 90s-style CGI adventures!</li><li>New Area: You’re not at the Kensdale Public Library anymore! Explore an abandoned Hameln facility with decades of secrets to uncover.</li><li>Bring closure to the story of Amanda, Riley, Aunt Kate, and everyone affected by the sinister production of <em>Amanda the Adventurer</em> and Hameln Entertainment’s mysterious motivations.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement teaser trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/amanda-the-adventurer-3/april-25-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Amanda the Adventurer 3 - Announce Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VTzkEwCrelc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Director Says Making DLC For Its Games Is "Boring" For Larian]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-director-says-making-dlc-for-its-games-is-boring-for-larian/1100-6531125/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-director-says-making-dlc-for-its-games-is-boring-for-larian.1173990/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-director-says-making-dlc-for-its-games-is-boring-for-larian/1100-6531125/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531125">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Baldur's Gate 3 was a tour de force when it launched in 2023, garnering multiple accolades--including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-is-gamespots-game-of-the-year-2023/1100-6519739/" data-ref-id="1100-6519739">GameSpot's Game Of The Year</a>--and launching developer Larian Studios into a household name. Because of that success, many assumed a DLC expansion would be coming for the megahit RPG, but that doesn't seem to be the case--and in Larian CEO Swen Vincke's opinion, that's because the studio finds making DLC "boring."</p><p dir="ltr">In an interview with GameSpot, Vincke mentioned that Larian is "not in the DLC business," pointing to Baldur's Gate 3's massive patches and updates as the way Larian prefers to update its games. When asked to expand further, Vincke called making DLC "boring" and said there's "no passion" in doing that at the studio.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="485120905" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465890,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Baldur%E2%80%99s%20Gate%203%3A%20The%20Final%20Patch%20-%20An%20Animated%20Short&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:276,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/baldurs-gate-3-the-final-patch-an-animated-short\/2300-6465890\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465890\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465890\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465890\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465890&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465890,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531125&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;baldurs-gate-3&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,stadia,macintosh,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;larian-studios,spike-chunsoft&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;baldurs-gate&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;dungeons-dragons&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465890},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465890\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4476905-55.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/PimKzh3M.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1744729380,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="PimKzh3M" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465890" data-src="/videos/baldurs-gate-3-the-final-patch-an-animated-short/2300-6465890/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Baldur’s Gate 3: The Final Patch - An Animated Short</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">"You want a happy player and happy business, but you also need to have a happy developer," Vincke said. "What we're doing now makes developers way more happy. We had a huge hit, and people said 'DLC this' and 'DLC that,' and we said we'd make DLC, but then when we had a moment to think, we asked ourselves, 'what are we doing?'"</p><p dir="ltr">The most recent patch for Baldur's Gate 3, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3s-final-patch-introduces-cross-play-photo-mode-and-12-new-subclasses/1100-6530875/">Patch 8</a>, brought 12 new subclasses, a photo mode, and cross-platform play for multiplayer campaigns. The official<a href="https://baldursgate3.game/news/the-final-patch-new-subclasses-photo-mode-and-cross-play_138" rel="nofollow "> Larian blog post</a> explaining the patch also mentioned that it will be the final patch for BG3, as the team is moving on to its next project.</p><p dir="ltr">Baldur's Gate 3 is out now on Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC. The full interview with Larian CEO Swen Vincke can be found here.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Dev Embraces Machine Learning For "Tasks That Nobody Wants To Do"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-embraces-machine-learning-for-tasks-that-nobody-wants-to-do/1100-6531123/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-dev-embraces-machine-learning-for-tasks-that-nobody-wants-to-do.1173987/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-embraces-machine-learning-for-tasks-that-nobody-wants-to-do/1100-6531123/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531123">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Machine-learning and artificial intelligence systems are some of the most-talked-about technologies in gaming--and across a variety of other industries. Some fear advancements to such systems might lead to negative consequences, while others predict a rosier future. Still others, like Larian Studios boss Swen Vincke, are trying to thoughtfully implement new technologies to help empower developers, not replace them. We caught up with Vincke recently, who discussed a range of subjects, including machine learning and AI. Watch the full interview below.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gy9P2HPF9ss" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Gy9P2HPF9ss" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Tasks "Nobody Wants To Do"</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">Vincke said Larian currently uses machine learning systems to help automate game-development tasks that "nobody wants to do."</p><p dir="ltr">"It's the obvious things, like a motion capture cleaning or voice editing or, something very specific. Retargeting. So that is basically if you play with different species, you want to be able to reuse an animation on a different species that are in different size, and then they're doing certain interactions with others," Vincke explained.</p><p dir="ltr">For these purposes, machine learning "works really well," Vincke said. Larian is also embracing the technology for what's called "white boxing," which is the term for how a studio like Larian iterates on ideas rapidly. "White boxing is essentially the stage before you actually do the real implementation," he said, noting that using machine learning can help speed up the process.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1675492517" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6461988,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Baldur%27s%20Gate%203%20Launch%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:105,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/baldurs-gate-3-launch-trailer\/2300-6461988\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6461988\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6461988\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6461988\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6461988&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6461988,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531123&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;baldurs-gate-3&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,stadia,macintosh,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;larian-studios,spike-chunsoft&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;baldurs-gate&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;dungeons-dragons&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6461988},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6461988\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1352\/13527689\/4173556-baldur%27sgate3_launchtrailer.mp4.00_00_34_33.still002.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/Nvmw1coN.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1691076300,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="Nvmw1coN" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6461988" data-src="/videos/baldurs-gate-3-launch-trailer/2300-6461988/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Baldur's Gate 3 Launch Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">Under traditional development circumstances, this might take "some time" before a developer can create something that's actually playable, but white boxing with machine learning helps "accelerate that."</p><p dir="ltr">But for Vincke's money, the most exciting implementation of machine learning is when it can be used for new gameplay elements. However, it's still early days, and Larian is "not there yet," or even close. But it's an area that Vincke is excited about because it could help the studio implement new RPG ideas faster.</p><p dir="ltr">"For an RPG developer, what you really want is something that helps with reactivity to agency," he said. "So, permutations that you did not foresee, reactions to things that the player has done, in the world, they will certainly augment the gameplay experience."</p><p dir="ltr">Vincke mentioned how in a game like FIFA (now called EA Sports FC), the under-the-hood procedural generation happens in real time, and that's what he's referring to in regards to how machine learning can impact gameplay.</p><h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Red Flags</strong></h2><p>For all of this hope and optimism about using new technologies like machine learning to help speed up and improve game development, Vincke said he understands there are "red flags" to consider. Some people have legitimate fears of machine learning and AI systems stealing their work or taking their jobs. However, Vincke said Larian is hiring more people, not fewer, thanks to new technologies. This is what others,<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-ceo-on-how-ai-will-impact-video-games-and-the-people-who-make-them/1100-6513969/" data-ref-id="1100-6513969"> like EA CEO Andrew Wilson and Take-Two boss Strauss Zelnick</a>, have predicted.</p><p dir="ltr">"It's always going to be the people that are going to make a difference," Vincke said. "And so for us, it's super clear that we're investing heavily into the team and the human touch that's being added to that."</p><p dir="ltr">With more automation, human workers are freed up to create more, which in turn leads to the possibility of making "more complex things," Vincke said.</p><p dir="ltr">"When complexity goes up, things start getting really interesting. So it's fair to say that the games that are being made today are arguably more complex than they were in the past," he said. "The faster you can iterate, the faster you will get to a certain result. And then and the tightening of those pipelines should allow you, in theory, to make your games in a more efficient manner."</p><h2 dir="ltr"><strong>More Time To Be Creative</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">Automation with machine learning AI is a "huge thing," Vincke said. People may not be aware of how much time an animator may spend on "stuff they don't want to work on." As such, thanks to automation, "It adds a lot to the time that they have to work on the creative stuff," Vincke said.</p><p dir="ltr">Vincke said it's "the wrong attitude" to assume that automation will replace various people and departments. Because automation should, in theory, allow people to do "more of what really matters and less of the stuff that they don't want to do."</p><p dir="ltr">"That's not necessarily cost reduction," he added. "But it's going to be an increase of ability, which is a good thing."</p><h2 dir="ltr"><strong>What's Next For Larian</strong></h2><p>Following the huge success of Baludr's Gate 3 in 2024, everyone is wondering what Larian is going to make next. We know it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-isnt-making-baldurs-gate-4-next-thats-not-what-we-were-made-for/1100-6522049/" data-ref-id="1100-6522049">won't be Baldur's Gate 4</a>, but instead a project codenamed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-now-giving-full-attention-to-next-game-codenamed-excalibur/1100-6528758/" data-ref-id="1100-6528758">Excalibur.</a></p><p>Beyond Larian's next game, Vincke is thinking even further out and has grand plans to create a "very big RPG" that will <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-is-working-toward-an-rpg-that-dwarfs-it/1100-6522051/" data-ref-id="1100-6522051">"dwarf"</a> any of Larian's previous releases. "It's an inspirational goal. That's it. I cannot say more, because it needs to stay in that dream-reality," he said.</p><p>While Larian will not make Baldur's Gate 4, Hasbro has said it is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hasbro-hopes-next-baldurs-gate-game-is-here-before-2050/1100-6522712/" data-ref-id="1100-6522712">keen to expand the Baldur's Gate series with other teams. </a>"We're going to take our time and find the right partner, the right approach, and the right product," Hasbro previously said about the future of Baldur's Gate.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>