<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:47:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Black Flag Resynced Has Been Rated By PEGI]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-has-been-rated-by-pegi</link>
            <guid>1377352</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Is a Switch 2 release on the cards?</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="ce9a64d835534"><a title="Black Flag" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ce9a64d835534/black-flag.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Ubisoft</em></figcaption></figure><p>In what is no doubt the worst kept secret of 2025, another hint regarding the remake of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/assassins_creed_iv_black_flag">Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag</a> has surfaced via the official <a href="https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=Assassin%27s+Creed+Black+Flag+Resynced">PEGI website</a>.</p>
<p>As detailed by our pals over at <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/12/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-leaks-in-age-rating-listing">Push Square</a>, <strong>Assassin's Creed Black Flag Resynced</strong> has been rated by PEGI, with an official listing indicating that the game will including violence, bad language, and ... *gulp*... in-game purchases.</p>
<p>No platforms have been specified in the listing, so it's unknown at this time whether Switch 2 is on the cards, but after the recent launch of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a>, we reckon there's a high chance that Black Flag could follow.</p><div><figure data-videoid="_mUe1VPypgs" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_mUe1VPypgs?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt_mUe1VPypgs" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_mUe1VPypgs?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_mUe1VPypgs?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3937e6lospju&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<figure data-uuid="0d60799fe5e89"><a title="Resynced" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/0d60799fe5e89/resynced.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: <a href="https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=Assassin%27s+Creed+Black+Flag+Resynced">PEGI</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>We're just a couple of days out from The Game Awards this week, so it seems highly likely that Ubisoft is planning to officially reveal the game during the upcoming event.</p>
<p>It's not the only thing that leaked from Geoff Keighley's awards bonanza, since <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/leon-kennedy-is-confirmed-for-resident-evil-requiem-via-psn-store-image">Sony accidentally revealed</a> the existence of an unannounced character in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a> before the game's planned appearance later this week.</p>
<p>Black Flag originally launches in 2013 and saw releases on both the Wii U and the Switch. It's frequently cited as one of the most popular entries in the series alongside <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/assassins_creed_the_ezio_collection">Assassin's Creed II</a>, largely thanks to its excellent navel combat and more lighthearted narrative.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194739,194517 @ 1765297804 -->
<p><em>Would you like to see the Black Flag remake on the Switch 2? Let us know your thoughts with a comment down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=Assassin%27s+Creed+Black+Flag+Resynced" rel="noopener" href="https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=Assassin%27s+Creed+Black+Flag+Resynced">pegi.info</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/12/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-leaks-in-age-rating-listing" rel="noopener" href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/12/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-leaks-in-age-rating-listing">pushsquare.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/e032de8b23e92e82732ec268264d14d3 @ 1765295927 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-has-been-rated-by-pegi]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Krafton Claims Unknown Worlds Co-Founders Testimony Proves Founders “Do Not Want, Nor Deserve, Their Jobs Back”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/krafton-claims-unknown-worlds-founders-do-not-want-nor-deserve-their-jobs-back-subnautica/</link>
            <guid>1377349</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The legal battle between Unknown Worlds co-founders Charlie Cleveland, Ted Gill, and Max McGuire and Krafton over the development of Subnautica 2 has been one of the biggest surprise stories of the year for 2025. It's had several twists and turns, the most recent of which being <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-strikes-back-unknown-worlds-founders-sharing-files-racist-views-korea/">accusations of racist comments made by Cleveland towards Korea</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-ceo-allegedly-asked-chatgpt-how-to-avoid-paying-subnautica-devs-bonus/">Krafton's chief executive officer asking ChatGPT if there was a way to avoid paying</a> Unknown Worlds <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-delayed-subnautica-2-2026-reportedly-to-avoid-250-million-bonus-pay/">the $250 million bonus</a> that is at the heart of this battle.</p>



<p>If you've not been following along, there is a bullet-point list at the bottom of this article taking you through all of our coverage of the story so far. Today's latest update comes after recent testimony given by Unknown Worlds co-founders Cleveland, Gill, and McGuire during a trial from November 17-19, 2025, in the Delaware Court of Chancery. </p>



<p>These testimonies given by the co-founders and the evidence displayed at the trial, in Krafton's view, prove a couple of key things. Firstly, the evidence and testimony make it "<em>unequivocally clear there was no preconceived plan by Krafton to remove Unknown Worlds' leadership to avoid the earnout obligation</em>," as has been previously alleged by the co-founders. </p>



<p>Secondly, Krafton states that the testimony and evidence prove that the co-founders "<em>lied and tried to hide their abandonment [of Subnautica 2 and their duties] because they wanted KRAFTON to pay them hundreds of millions of dollars for nothing</em>."</p>



<p>According to Krafton's timeline of events, Cleveland and McGuire were hiding the fact that both of them were checked out from their work at Unknown Worlds on Subnautica 2 until Krafton found out on May 20, 2025, and prior to that date, Gill and other members of Unknown Worlds were being forced into awkward positions where they had to avoid telling Krafton the truth about Unknown Worlds' leadership situation in order to protect the earnout.</p>



<p>Krafton shared excerpts with Wccftech from the evidence and testimony presented, including statements attributed to Cleveland like "<em>I stopped working four months ago and have entered semi-retirement</em>," which Cleveland made on January 8, 2024, in a private message. Cleveland previously admitted that he no longer wanted to work at Unknown Worlds and that he was burned out, though during this trial process he has come back to say he is 'fired up now' and wants to return to work.</p>



<p>A statement shared that was attributed to McGuire emailing the core Unknown Worlds team regarding his title as technical director on January 10, 2024, reads, "<em>I've continued to do bits and pieces of the job as needed, but I stopped using that title years ago when I felt it no longer reflected my primary contribution to the company</em>."</p>



<p>Another statement attributed to McGuire in his personal log on April 29, 2024, reads, "<em>At home, I met with Charlie and Ted to let them know I'm quitting</em>," followed by a statement from Cleveland on the same day where Cleveland expresses sadness at McGuire leaving, and saying that he is "<em>pretty sure [he'll] be doing the same thing</em>."</p>



<p>A statement attributed to Subnautica 2 lead designer Anthony Gallegos seems to describe the frustrations felt by the rest of the Unknown Worlds team, with Gallegos claiming he "<em>can't even get Max [McGuire] to look at some code for [Subnautica 2] water to help us, but he'll make money off a sale from four years ago and get paid to do nothing</em>."</p>



<p>All of that feels pretty damning against Cleveland, McGuire, and Gill, and their testimonies don't make their situation look any better. Per testimony from Cleveland, an email sent to Unknown Worlds staff titled "<em>Updates to Our Leadership Team's Roles and Responsibilities</em>" on August 5, 2024, excluded employees from Krafton. Cleveland did not confirm that Gill intentionally excluded Krafton staff, only that no one from Krafton was listed in the email.</p>



<p>Cleveland also admitted in his testimony that he did not directly tell Krafton CEO, Changham Kim, about his disengagement from work at Unknown Worlds. When Krafton's representation put to Cleveland, "<em>You stood to gain potentially tens of millions of dollars more in earnout, and you couldn't send him [Changham Kim] an email because your arms were hurting? Is that your testimony?"</em> Cleveland responded, "<em>That's not a great reason, I admit</em>."</p>



<p>Cleveland also admitted that Changham Kim "<em>seemed alarmed</em>" when he told Kim that he was "<em>no longer involved in Subnautica at all</em>," and could not provide Kim with an update on the state of the game's development.</p>



<p>A further statement from Gill, taken from an audio transcription of a June 10, 2025, call, reads, "<em>If you [Krafton] want to delay the game, just pay it. Just pay the earnout...agree to pay it now, we can sign something tomorrow...it'll be paid, and we'll give you flexibility on paying it. You can pay it over two years, instead of all at once. But just pay it</em>."</p>



<p>With all of the evidence presented last month at the Delaware Court of Chancery and testimonies from the co-founders, Krafton holds firm in its claim that the co-founders<em> "were always concerned first and foremost about the earnout</em>."</p>



<p>We'll continue to update you on this story as it progresses, though this latest batch of evidence seems to be a huge blow to the co-founders' chances of winning the case.</p>



<hr>



<p>If you need a recap on this whole saga, here's a timeline with everything save for today's news to catch you up:</p>



<ul>
<li>On July 2, it was reported that the founders of Unknown Worlds, Ted Gill, Max McGuire, and Charlie Cleveland, <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-developer-unknown-worlds-changes-leadership-krafton/">were fired</a> and replaced by former Striking Distance Studios head Steve Papoutsis. No concrete explanation for their dismissal was offered at the time, with Krafton instead emphasizing its commitment to delivering a game that players deserved.</li>



<li>On July 3, a <a href="https://unknownworlds.com/en/news/subnautica-community-letter">statement from the Unknown Worlds website</a> did its best to calm concerns from fans about the fact that the three original core creatives behind Subnautica were suddenly not at the studio.</li>



<li>The next day, on July 4, the situation began to grow even more confusing, as <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/subnautica/comments/1lryw9o/what_is_a_wave_but_a_thousand_drops/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">Cleveland claims</a> Subnautica 2 was "<em>ready for early access release</em>" and that his and his fellow co-founders' dismissals were "<em>quite a shock</em>."</li>



<li>Five days later, on July 9, a <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-delayed-subnautica-2-2026-reportedly-to-avoid-250-million-bonus-pay/">report from Bloomberg</a> adds a shocking allegation to the mix: that Krafton was delaying Subnautica 2 to avoid paying Unknown Worlds a $250 million bonus the studio would have been owed if they hit particular sales goals, which they would have done with Subnautica 2's launch. The delay was <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-delay-confirmed-krafton-claims-delay-decision-was-not-influenced-by-any-contractual-or-financial-considerations/">confirmed</a> hours after the report went live, and Krafton held that the delay was due to Subnautica 2 not being ready, citing feedback from internal playtesting.</li>



<li>On July 10, Krafton <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-blames-founders-subnautica-2-delay/">went on the offensive</a>, blaming co-founders Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire, claiming they had "<em>abandoned</em>" their roles to pursue personal interests. Krafton also clarified that 90% of the aforementioned $250 million bonus would go directly to the co-founders, with the rest to be split among the employees. Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire held that they always intended to distribute the bonus to other employees.</li>



<li>Also on July 10, Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire <a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/889109175/Fortis-Advisors-v-Krafton-via-Aftermath">filed a lawsuit</a> against Krafton.</li>



<li>On July 11, an<a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-leaked-document-shows-krafton-delay/"> internal document from a milestone review of Subnautica 2's progress leaked</a> on Reddit, seemingly showing further support to Krafton's claims that the game wasn't ready, citing a lack of content on top of previously mentioned internal playtest feedback.</li>



<li>Over the following weekend on July 13, Krafton <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-confirms-subnautica-2-leaked-documents-are-real/">confirmed the documents to be real</a>.</li>



<li>A few days later, on July 17, when the co-founders' suit against Krafton became publicly available, we discovered allegations that Krafton had <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-allegedly-sabotaged-subnautica-2-to-delay-avoid-paying-250-million-bonus/">been sabotaging</a> Subnautica 2 to ensure it would be delayed. There was even a claim that the CEO of Krafton met with the co-founders and admitted that having to pay out the $250 million bonus "<em>could be disastrous financially and hugely embarrassing for Krafton</em>." It also attacks every other claim Krafton had made up to this point, and that the feedback received on Subnautica 2 playtesting "<em>unequivocally proved</em>" the game was ready for an early access launch.</li>



<li>Jumping ahead to August 12, Krafton<a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-fires-back-unknown-worlds-founders-lawsuit-subnautica-2/"> shoots back</a> at Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire's lawsuit, again arguing that the co-founders were absentee leaders who abandoned their roles, and continued to hold that the game wasn't ready for an early access launch.</li>



<li>Eight days later, Unknown Worlds <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-legal-battle-unknown-worlds-files-lawsuit-against-co-founders-krafton/">files its own separate lawsuit</a> against its co-founders, telling Wccftech in an email that this suit "<em>is a direct response to their misconduct, including the theft of confidential information and attempts to pursue personal financial gain to the detriment of the company's interest</em>s<em>."</em></li>



<li>On September 19, a report revealed that the court denied two of Krafton's motions, and Krafton <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-unknown-worlds-founders-lawsuit-krafton-u-turn/">seemingly U-turned on one of its key arguments</a> regarding why the co-founders were fired in the first place.</li>



<li>On September 24, new motions from Krafton alleged that <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-accuses-unknown-worlds-founders-of-stealing-subnautica-blueprint/">the founders stole what Krafton called "<em>effectively, a blueprint</em>"</a> for Subnautica in an attempt to further its argument that the co-founders intended to release Subnautica 2 on their own.</li>



<li>On November 18, the co-founders and their legal team allege that Krafton's plan to avoid paying the $250 million earnout <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-ceo-allegedly-asked-chatgpt-how-to-avoid-paying-subnautica-devs-bonus/">was codenamed "<em>Project X</em>" internally within Krafton, and Krafton's chief executive officer, Changham Kim, asked ChatGPT</a> how to avoid paying Unknown Worlds the $250 million bonus.</li>



<li>On November 20, Krafton claimed that co-founder <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-strikes-back-unknown-worlds-founders-sharing-files-racist-views-korea/">Charlie Cleveland made racist comments regarding Korea in his preparation notes for the litigation</a> between Cleveland, his fellow co-founders, and Krafton, and that Cleveland said, "<em>history will remember that Krafton was bad</em>."</li>
</ul>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/krafton-claims-unknown-worlds-founders-do-not-want-nor-deserve-their-jobs-back-subnautica/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lie to futuristic billionaires so you can steal their stuff in Pentiment and Pratchett-inspired Better Than Us]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lie-to-futuristic-billionaires-so-you-can-steal-their-stuff-in-pentiment-and-pratchett-inspired-better-than-us</link>
            <guid>1377346</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Vampire Therapist's devs will examine the consequences of "extreme wealth inequality" when the latest work arrives in 2026</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/better-than-us-lie-to-billionaires-coming-2026-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/better-than-us-lie-to-billionaires-coming-2026-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/better-than-us-lie-to-billionaires-coming-2026-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/better-than-us-lie-to-billionaires-coming-2026-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/better-than-us-lie-to-billionaires-coming-2026-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/better-than-us-lie-to-billionaires-coming-2026-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/better-than-us-lie-to-billionaires-coming-2026-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/better-than-us-lie-to-billionaires-coming-2026-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/better-than-us-lie-to-billionaires-coming-2026-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Little Bat Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>My husband died in a horrible toilet accident. Also, I'm distantly related to Ronald Reagan and spend summers in an underwater chateau. These aren't just very true facts about the author of this article, they're things you can tell the reprehensible billionaires of the future in Better Than Us. It's the latest work of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/vampire-therapist">Vampire Therapist</a> developers Little Bat Games, and it's set to arrive in 2026.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Better Than Us Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LVUF2QlTa04?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Better Than Us Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LVUF2QlTa04?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/LVUF2QlTa04?autoplay=1" title="Better Than Us Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LVUF2QlTa04" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>As you can see in the trailer above, Better Than Us casts you as a master thief whose goal is to infiltrate the swanky parties of the year 2200's richest bastards and manipulate them into looking the other way as you swipe some of their stuff. There's some stealthing, but as you might expect of a game that lists The Count of Monte Cristo, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/pentiment">Pentiment</a>, and the works of Terry Pratchett as prominently among its inspirations as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/thief-the-dark-project">Thief: The Dark Project</a>, your words will be your most formidable weapon.</p>
<p>Lying is key, but you've got to do it properly. "Tell different stories to different people," the game's blurb reads. "Remember who you told what. Build a web of deception so intricate that even the powerful can't see through it. But slip up once—contradict yourself, forget a detail—and everything unravels."</p><p>For all its setting in futuristic floating cities built to save their wealthy inhabitants from the climate change-ravaged Earth below, Little Bat Games make clear that this isn't a cartoonish flight of fancy. Better Than Us' Steam description reveals that it's been "developed in consultation with historians from Oxford, UC Davis, and the University of Florida". The game "deals heavily with issues of extreme wealth inequality and faith. It explores philosophical underpinnings of class oppression, effects of climate change on underprivileged populations, and refugees. It also addresses sexual and gender issues, artificial intelligence, and faith in historical contexts".</p>
<p>"Looking to the past is a helpful way of examining modern issues," Little Bat creative director and voice actor Cyrus Nemati says of the studio's approach. "Not only is the historical record inspiring, but dead people are less able to sue small game studios." He and fellow <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hades-2">Hades 2</a> alum Sarah Grayson - the pair voiced Ares and Selene respectively - lead Better Than Us' cast.</p>
<p>As someone who loves a good bit of stealth and weaving wordly webs in the likes of Pentiment, if Little Bat can strike that balance in entertaining fashion while offering plenty of freedom in the way you go about prying the possessions from a set of faithfully-rendered fat cats, I can see myself having a ball with this one.</p>
<p>For now, Better Than Us has a 2026 release window and you can wishlist it on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3954390/Better_Than_Us/">Steam</a>, if you're so inclined. You can also check out former RPSer Alice B's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/vampire-therapist-is-like-playing-language-puzzles-against-different-types-of-theatre-kid">verdict on</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-mel-brooks-and-twilight-inspired-a-vampire-visual-novel-mixing-funny-with-therapy">interview about</a> Little Bat's previous work, Vampire Therapist.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lie-to-futuristic-billionaires-so-you-can-steal-their-stuff-in-pentiment-and-pratchett-inspired-better-than-us]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zero36 Studio and CCG Lab announce Star Wars digital collectible card game for PC, iOS, and Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/zero36-studio-and-ccg-lab-announce-star-wars-digital-collectible-card-game-for-pc-ios-and-android</link>
            <guid>1377328</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>From Zero36 Studio and CCG Lab.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > ByteDance" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bytedance">ByteDance</a> subsidiary <a title="Companies > Zero36 Studio" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bytedance/zero36-studio">Zero36 Studio</a> and <a title="Companies > CCG Lab" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ccg-lab">CCG Lab</a> have <a href="https://ccglab.com/press/" target="_blank">announced</a> a collaboration with <a title="Companies > Lucasfilm Games [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/lucasfilm-games">Lucasfilm Games</a> to develop a new <em>Star Wars</em> digital collectible card game for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,000 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, iOS, and Android. <span id="more-1012813"></span></p><p>“The opportunity to develop a game for the <em>Star Wars</em> galaxy is a profound honor for our studio,” said Zero36 Studio head Hades Lu in a press release. “Our team is dedicated to creating an immersive journey worthy of the Star Wars legacy, one we truly believe will capture the hearts of fans across the galaxy.”</p><p>CCG Lab CEO Cory Jones added, “As a trailblazing game development studio, CCG Lab brings a deep well of creativity and passion to this project. Our mission is to craft an experience that captures the thrill, <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,761 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>, and heart of <em>Star Wars</em>—a game that feels instantly familiar yet constantly surprising. Together with Zero36 Studio and Lucasfilm Games, we’re creating something truly exciting for players and fans alike—an experience that celebrates the joy of play in the galaxy far, far away.”</p><p>Lucasfilm Games vice president and general manager Douglas Reilly said, “The <em>Star Wars</em> galaxy, with its wide roster of iconic characters, is a perfect fit for a collectible card game. We’re confident that the unique expertise of Zero36 Studio and CCG Lab makes them the right teams to deliver a <em>Star Wars</em> card game that brings the saga to life in a new way for the genre.”</p><p>Further information was not announced.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/zero36-studio-and-ccg-lab-announce-star-wars-digital-collectible-card-game-for-pc-ios-and-android]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fairy Tail: Dungeons coming to Switch on January 7, 2026 alongside major update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/fairy-tail-dungeons-coming-to-switch-on-january-7-2026-alongside-major-update</link>
            <guid>1377325</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Enjoy a refreshed, upgraded gameplay experience.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Kodansha [34 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kodansha">Kodansha</a> and developer <a title="Companies > ginolabo [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ginolabo">ginolabo</a> will release a Switch version of <a title="Genres > Roguelike [402 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Deckbuilder [126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/deckbuilder">deckbuilder</a> <em><a title="Games > Fairy Tail: Dungeons [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fairy-tail-dungeons">Fairy Tail: Dungeons</a></em> on January 7, 2025 alongside a major update for the <a title="Platforms > PC [25,000 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> version, the companies announced. <span id="more-1012762"></span></p><p><em>Fairy Tail: Dungeons</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2305500/FAIRY_TAIL_DUNGEONS/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on August 26, 2024.</p><p>“We wanted our first major content update to be massive,” said game creator gino in a press release. “Fans of the series will enjoy a refreshed, upgraded gameplay experience. The <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,073 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> is perfect for quick dungeon-diving sessions, and we look forward to welcoming a new console community into the <a title="Genres > Action [3,265 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>!”</p><p>Here is an overview of the Switch version and major update, via Kodansha:</p><blockquote><p>Whether a first-time player on Nintendo Switch or returning for new challenges on PC, form a tenacious trio, build a deck of magic cards, and navigate an underground maze filled with treasures and secrets. Battle brutes blocking the path forward in strategic, turn-based combat. Play cards in a specific order to activate Magic Chains for a massive damage boost, and upgrade cards and skillsets after each run.</p><p><em>Fairy Tail: Dungeons</em>‘ first major content update since PC launch invites five new heroes to monster-filled dungeon dives, all unlockable through gameplay: Gajeel, Juvia, Mirajane, Laxus, and Gildarts. Countless new battle strategies await with the addition of over 200 amulets, over 170 magic cards, over 100 skills, 50 Labyrinth quests, 30 monsters, and 20 items.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Return to the depths with the newly added Special Labyrinth Exploration. Test skills with higher difficulty levels in the Labyrinth and Abyssal Conquest modes, or focus on the story in the new casual mode. Fuse duplicate cards together with the new card upgrade system, and enjoy quality-of-life updates like user interface improvements, additional control schemes, and much more.</p></blockquote><p>And here is the bullet point summary of the update:</p><blockquote><p><strong>New Content and New Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>New Content: “Enter Special Labyrinth”</strong> – After clearing the main story, it will be added to the guild menu.</li><li><strong>New Feature: “Expedition Records”</strong> – <a title="Genres > Strategy [298 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">Strategy</a> guides for each labyrinth and each character are available.</li><li><strong>New Difficulty Level</strong> – Added to “Labyrinth” and “Grand Clash”. Solved by fulfilling specific conditions</li><li><strong>Card Upgrade</strong> – When you obtain the same card again, you can choose to upgrade it.</li><li><strong>Miscellaneous</strong> – Added TIPS display and Casual Mode.</li></ul><p><strong>Expanding Content Volume and Enhancing Comfort</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Playable Characters</strong> – Expanded from five to 10 units.</li><li><strong>New Features</strong> – Over 50 Labyrinth <a title="Platforms > Quest [163 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a>s / Over 170 Magic Cards / Over 100 Skills /Over 200 Amulets / Over 30 Monsters / Over 20 Items / New Event Added.</li><li><strong>Tomes of Remembrance</strong> – Expand the save slots from four to six..</li><li><strong>Miscellaneous</strong> – Minor feature enhancements and fixes for existing bugs.</li></ul></blockquote><p>View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/fairy-tail-dungeons/december-9-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_1012773"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/fairy-tail-dungeons-coming-to-switch-on-january-7-2026-alongside-major-update]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Official Nintendo Switch 2 Wheel Set For Mario Kart Gets First Discount At Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/official-nintendo-switch-2-wheel-set-for-mario-kart-gets-first-discount-at-amazon/1100-6536789/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1377322</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536789">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If you're one of the many holiday shoppers who took advantage of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-mario-kart-console-bundle-is-discounted-for-cyber-monday/1100-6536599/" data-ref-id="1100-6536599">last week's Nintendo Switch 2 Mario Kart World bundle promotion</a>, you should check out this week's deal on the racing wheel attachment set. Nintendo's official Joy-Con 2 Wheel Set is on sale for $21.49 (was $25) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Test-17-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B09Z1FRRJP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Official+Nintendo+Switch+2+Wheel+Set+For+Mario+Kart+Gets+First+Discount+At+Amazon&amp;fnauthor=stevenpetite&amp;fndate=2025-12-09+08%3A12%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-12-09+08%3A12%3A50&amp;fnarticle_id=6536789&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fnintendo-switch-2-joy-con-2-wheel-set-of-2%2F-%2FA-94704604&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fofficial-nintendo-switch-2-wheel-set-for-mario-kart-gets-first-discount-at-amazon%2F1100-6536789%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Target</a>. Deals on first-party Nintendo accessories are uncommon, so even though you're only saving $3.50, it's still a noteworthy deal. Designed for playing Mario Kart World with motion controls, the two-pack of steering wheels launched alongside the Switch 2 console in June.</p><div title="[Nintendo Switch 2] Joy-Con 2 Wheel Set - First-party" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="5212" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="[Nintendo Switch 2] Joy-Con 2 Wheel Set - First-party" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Test-17-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B09Z1FRRJP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Test-17-Nintendo-Switch\/dp\/B09Z1FRRJP?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Test-17-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B09Z1FRRJP?tag=gamespot-promos-20">Nintendo Switch 2 Wheel Set for Joy-Con 2</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Test-17-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B09Z1FRRJP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Test-17-Nintendo-Switch\/dp\/B09Z1FRRJP?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Test-17-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B09Z1FRRJP?tag=gamespot-promos-20">$21.49 (was $25)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>The official Nintendo Switch 2 Wheel Set comes with one light blue and one red attachment that match the color scheme of the Joy-Con 2 controllers. The textured grips are nicer than a lot of third-party wheels and Nintendo's attachments from the Nintendo Wii era.</p><p>Just like the Switch 2 console itself, the first-party steering wheels have magnetic connectors for the controllers. Large shoulder buttons (SL and SR) are built into the back of each wheel.</p></div>                      </div><p>Considering the popularity of the Mario Kart World bundle deal, which ended on Sunday, it wouldn't be surprising if Amazon and Target sold out of this deal. Last week, Amazon sold out of all three of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0G31KXK29,B0G31KPFZS,B0G31FX7N4&amp;tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hori's new Mario Kart World-themed Joy-Con 2 wheel attachments</a>. Themed around Mario, Peach, and Yoshi, the officially licensed $15 wheels launched December 5. Amazon lists all three as "temporarily out of stock."</p><p>For a larger Switch 2 racing wheel, check out the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0FH6QN5JS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">recently released Joy-Con 2 accessory by Numskull</a>. Officially licensed by Nintendo, Numskull's attachment is table-mounted and has slots for both controllers. It launched for $30, but Amazon has since raised the price to $33.83.</p><hr><p>It's worth noting you can use a real racing wheel controller for Mario Kart World. The best option is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Mario-Racing-Wheel-Deluxe/dp/B01C6XAO7M?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hori's officially licensed Mario Kart Pro Deluxe Wheel</a>. Compatible with Switch and Switch 2, the Mario-themed steering wheel and pedal set is available for $100 (was $110) at Amazon.</p><p>Several <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-carrying-case-cyber-monday-deals/1100-6536578/" data-ref-id="1100-6536578">officially licensed Nintendo Switch 2 carrying cases</a> are still on sale after Cyber Week. The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/RDS-Licensed-Nintendo-Systems-Traveler-microSD/dp/B0F3YXTMPF?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">RDS Industries Game Traveler Deluxe System Case</a> is on sale for $25 (was $30), and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0F69R7LLR,B0FR9V7QWR&amp;tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PowerA Slim Case</a> is down to $15 (was $20). The Game Traveler Deluxe is designed for the console as well as the Dock Set, whereas PowerA's hardshell case is only for the console.</p><hr><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/official-nintendo-switch-2-wheel-set-for-mario-kart-gets-first-discount-at-amazon/1100-6536789/">Official Nintendo Switch 2 Wheel Set For Mario Kart Gets First Discount At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/asus-rog-xbox-ally-gets-110-discount-at-amazon/1100-6536577/">Asus ROG Xbox Ally Gets $110 Discount At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rosalinas-storybook-super-mario-galaxy-dark-horse-nintendo-book-amazon-preorder/1100-6534724/">Super Mario Galaxy Storybook Hardcover Edition Restocked With 15% Discount At Amazon</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (3)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/psvr-2-horizon-call-of-the-mountain-bundle-is-still-on-sale-for-all-time-best-price/1100-6529777/">PSVR 2 Horizon Call Of The Mountain Bundle Is Still On Sale For All-Time Best Price</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-lord-of-the-rings-the-hobbit-illustrated-box-set-restocked-with-nearly-50-discount-at-amazon/1100-6536300/">New Lord Of The Rings &amp; The Hobbit Illustrated Box Set Is Back In Stock With $72 Discount</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/walmart-exclusive-dualsense-icon-blue-controller-is-back-in-stock-for-64/1100-6535294/">Walmart-Exclusive DualSense Icon Blue Controller Is Back In Stock For $64</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/official-nintendo-switch-2-wheel-set-for-mario-kart-gets-first-discount-at-amazon/1100-6536789/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MS Flight Sim's Stranger Things Collab Has Landed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ms-flight-sims-stranger-things-collab-has-landed/1100-6536792/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1377319</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536792">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>While Stranger Things is wrapping up after an almost decade run on Netflix, that hasn't stopped the Upside Down from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024s-new-crossover-is-one-youll-never-expect/1100-6536708/" data-ref-id="1100-6536708">seeping into places most wouldn't expect</a>. Microsoft Flight Simulator 24's collab with Stranger Things has arrived today on Steam, cloud, Xbox, and, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-initially-rejected-idea-to-bring-flight-simulator-to-ps5-dev-says/1100-6536767/" data-ref-id="1100-6536767">despite initial pushback, PS5</a>. The crossover is more than skins; it even features Murray Bauman (Brett Gelman) from the original cast as you help the citizens of Hawkins escape the encroaching darkness.</p><p>"Enter the world of Netflix’s Stranger Things to help Hawkins, a town under lockdown, heavy patrols, and supernatural threats," it reads on the official <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/12/09/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-introduces-netflixs-stranger-things-expansion/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation Blog</a>. "And, if you’re ready to visit Hawkins, Indiana, even after the credits roll on the crew’s last strange adventure, you will be able to explore a highly detailed map and recreation of the town with more than 40 iconic locations made famous by the show."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15976769/4619728-54964471784_6ea64028d8_h.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4619728" data-ratio="0.55875" data-width="1600" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15976769/4619728-54964471784_6ea64028d8_h.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4619728"></a><figcaption>Image Credit: Sony</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15976769/4619728-54964471784_6ea64028d8_h.jpg"></figure><p>Players will take to the skies in a Bell UH-1H, also known as the "Huey" helicopter, a model primarily used for troop and cargo transport, medical evacuations, and aerial assault during the Vietnam War. In their civilian use, they're usually involved in humanitarian aid efforts, research operations, and search-and-rescue duties. While the expansion is free, players need to make sure their simulator is updated to the latest version of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, visit the in-sim Marketplace, then select the Stranger Things Expansion. </p><p>This isn't Stranger Things' only collab this year, as more characters were introduced in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-stranger-things-kids-are-coming-to-fortnite-with-a-few-major-exceptions/1100-6536438/" data-ref-id="1100-6536438">Fortnite last month</a>. Since its debut, Stranger Things has collaborated with Mattel and even <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/dungeons-and-dragons-stranger-things-starter-set-w/2900-2915/" data-ref-id="2900-2915">Dungeons &amp; Dragons</a>.</p><p>Stranger Things' fifth and final season debuted on November 26 with the first volume of episodes. The second batch arrives on December 25, followed by the <a href="https://www.netflix.com/tudum/articles/stranger-things-finale-episode-length" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">two-hour finale on December 31</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ms-flight-sims-stranger-things-collab-has-landed/1100-6536792/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's Hard Not To Call Everything AI When Everything Keeps Being AI]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/ai-goonswarm-fortnite-postal/</link>
            <guid>1377307</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      <p>Last week saw a spate of accusations of AI use in video games, ones where developer denials took strange turns when even the studios or individuals accused couldn’t say for sure they hadn’t used AI. The case of both <em>Fortnite</em>’s new sprays and a swiftly announced-then-cancelled <em>Postal</em> game are the latest signs of how the specter of AI is ruining all of our lives.</p><p>Last week, publisher Running With Scissors announced a new game in the <em>Postal</em> series, called <em>Postal: Bullet Paradise</em>. Viewers swiftly began lobbing <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/developer-of-new-postal-game-shuts-down-studio-after-game-was-announced-then-canceled-over-gen-ai-allegations?ref=aftermath.site"><u>accusations of AI</u></a> at the game’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Af1TA0Am1U&amp;ref=aftermath.site" rel="noreferrer">announcement trailer</a>, which has since been pulled down, accusations that developer Goonswarm Games denied. People highlighted concern over the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/postal/comments/1pdenph/rws_using_ai_is_incredibly_disappointing/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>sprites’ mouths</u></a> in the trailer and an apparently suspicious <a href="https://x.com/LunetaleVT/status/1996457896339710174?ref=aftermath.site"><u>speedpaint</u></a> Running With Scissors released, but none of it featured the telltale too-many-fingers or other undeniable signs.&nbsp;</p><p>On December 5, Goonswarm announced that the whole thing had gotten so out of hand that they were closing the studio, writing on <a href="https://x.com/goonswarmgames/status/1996984553257279918?s=20&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>Twitter</u></a>, “Our studio was mistakenly accused of using AI-generated art in our games, and every attempt to clarify our work only escalated the situation… It’s tough to pour so much energy into a game and end up caught in the middle of an AI war by accident. We’ve decided to shut down the studio and end all future activities.”</p><figure><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’ve shut down the studio <a href="https://t.co/tbW2f2VQxL?ref=aftermath.site">pic.twitter.com/tbW2f2VQxL</a></p>— Goonswarm Games (@goonswarmgames) <a href="https://twitter.com/goonswarmgames/status/1996984553257279918?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref=aftermath.site">December 5, 2025</a></blockquote>
</figure><p>I am a person who has zero interest in a <em>Postal</em> game, much less in 2025, but I found watching it all unfold concerning. If Goonswarm had used AI, it seemed unlikely to me that they would deny it so strenuously–what would be the point of lying like this, much less sticking to the lie so intently that you’d close the studio? I wondered if this wasn’t some new version of AI brainrot, where the bullshit technology has been forced down our throats so much that we can’t help but see it everywhere, just as its most strenuous boosters hope.</p><p>But then, on December 6, Goonswarm <a href="https://x.com/goonswarmgames/status/1997357931436663056?s=20&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>returned to Twitter</u></a> with an update. It turns out that after “conducting an internal review, we agree with your criticism. The promo art does appear to include or be influenced by AI-generated material.” Goonswarm wrote that “We collaborated with external artists for years and never saw any sign of this” and that the files they received from these external artists “always looked legitimate within our internal pipeline, which is why our initial reaction was to protect our team and defend our innocence. We understand now that your concerns were valid. And we take responsibility for not catching this earlier.” The studio wrote that this possible AI use only extended to the game’s promo art, and that it will “replace all disputed promo art across our projects with pieces created entirely by human artists.” The studio concluded by writing, “We never intended to mislead anyone, and our earlier statements reflected what we honestly believed at the moment.”</p><figure><blockquote><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/UR5g4rxJxz?ref=aftermath.site">pic.twitter.com/UR5g4rxJxz</a></p>— Goonswarm Games (@goonswarmgames) <a href="https://twitter.com/goonswarmgames/status/1997357931436663056?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref=aftermath.site">December 6, 2025</a></blockquote>
</figure><p>Running With Scissors followed up on <a href="https://x.com/RWSstudios/status/1998068355593630181?ref=aftermath.site"><u>December 10</u></a> to say that while it had “needed to cut ties with Goonswarm Games on Friday and state the reason for doing so, our broken trust, we still wanted to give Goonswarm the time and space to be transparent about what had occurred… We wish them all the best as we both move forward our separate ways.”</p><p>The idea that an outside artist used AI and didn’t disclose it to the studio is more plausible than Goonswarm riding a lie into the ground, and highlights the insidious nature of AI’s forced ubiquity–how can you <em>ever</em> trust it isn’t being used? The situation bears some similarities to another AI dustup earlier last week, involving <a href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-season-7-gen-ai-tim-sweeney-latata-2000649103?ref=aftermath.site"><u>accusations of AI use in some new <em>Fortnite</em> sprays</u></a>. Fans were already on edge about AI in Epic games over <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/831747/tim-sweeney-epic-ceo-steam-game-stores-made-with-ai?ref=aftermath.site"><u>comments</u></a> Tim Sweeney made that “AI will be involved in nearly all future [games] production,” and the sprays in question definitely have the signs, including the telltale too many toes. Other accusations centered on some in-game music.&nbsp;</p><p>The freelance artist of one of the sprays responded to the accusations on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/andthankyou/p/DRstwipDuxw/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Instagram</u></a>, but rather than clearing things up, they made the situation even <em>more</em> confusing. They wrote that “I think the culprit is a clock in the background. I grabbed some clocks off image search, collaged them, and halftoned them. The numbers are bad, entirely possible I grabbed an AI clock and wasn’t paying attention.” Epic has yet to comment on the situation.</p>
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<blockquote data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DRstwipDuxw" data-instgrm-version="14"></blockquote>

<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<p>Putting aside the idea that a whole cadre of professionals might not notice an AI <em>clock</em>, a ubiquitous and straightforward object that is designed to be easy to gauge the accuracy of, this response highlights a deeper problem with AI. Even if an individual isn’t actively using it, it’s increasingly easy for it to slip in under our noses if we’re not constantly on alert. As AI becomes more convincing, and as it’s <a href="https://aftermath.site/ai-video-game-development-art-vibe-coding-midjourney/"><u>forced into more and more places</u></a>, even if we aren’t trying to engage with AI, we can’t be sure we haven’t.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>It’s no wonder that widespread paranoia over all this has taken hold. If even the people making things can’t be sure they aren’t using AI (or at least claim they aren’t sure), how can their audience be confident? And while vigilance is healthy and warranted, what does it mean–especially these days–when we feel like we can’t trust <em>anything</em> we see? False accusations of AI use can harm a person’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/05/17/style/ai-chatgpt-turnitin-students-cheating.html?ref=aftermath.site"><u>academic</u></a> or <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/chrisstokelwalker/art-subreddit-illustrator-ai-art-controversy?ref=aftermath.site"><u>artistic</u></a> career, and it’s also just bad for all of our souls and brains to be constantly on high alert. It makes us prone to distrust and dismissiveness, leaving us less open to other people’s creative works and making it harder for them to share it, especially if they’re still developing their skills. AI is already eroding trust, and our heightened suspicion can make us hostile not just to the work, but to each other. It’s not good for creators or their audiences to live like this, and it’s certainly not a good environment for anyone to try to make things in.</p><p><em>But</em>! “Let’s all show each other some grace, huh?” is not a lesson I can impart to you in the situations above, both of which prove that suspicion <em>was</em> warranted and that the accusations might have been correct. If anything, they suggest that even <em>more</em> suspicion is called for, when the people denying AI use themselves might not even know if they can truthfully deny it. So <em>now</em> how are you supposed to live, pinned between the slow spiritual death of thinking everyone around you is full of shit and the world-eating encroachment of the full-of-shit machine?&nbsp;</p><p>Honestly, I don’t know. As we wait for the AI bubble to gloriously burst and all of this to go the way of NFTs and the <a href="https://aftermath.site/mark-zuckerberg-meta-ai-metaverse/"><u>metaverse</u></a>, I think the best we can do is remember who our common enemy is: the AI companies and the people who stand to get rich off the tech, who <em>need</em> us to believe all of this is inevitable. We can double down on our commitment to proving them wrong, refuting their bullshit claims and making our displeasure known when AI products get forced into our tools without our consent. No one wants to take the extra time to make sure some reference art or a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/aug/21/ai-author-articles-wired-business-insider?ref=aftermath.site"><u>freelance pitch</u></a> isn’t AI (ask me how I know!), but maybe we can motivate ourselves by seeing it as one more way to tell the Sam Altmans of the world to get fucked. It wouldn’t prevent the situations above, and it doesn’t help us navigate a world increasingly full of AI slop, but it can at least be a small act of resistance against their shit.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/ai-goonswarm-fortnite-postal/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Legends: Z-A Confirms Return Of Hoenn Starter Mega Stones]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/pokemon-legends-z-a-confirms-return-of-hoenn-starter-mega-stones</link>
            <guid>1377295</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>

<p>Trainers around the world will be returning to Lumiose City tomorrow as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a>'s <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pokemon_legends_z-a_mega_dimension">Mega Dimension</a> DLC drops on 10th December. But there's plenty more to look forward to than just new Megas — some major returning Mega Evolutions have also been confirmed, including a headlining trio.</p>
<p>Earlier today, alongside the announcement of a new <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/pokemon-legends-z-a-mystery-gift-code-list">Mystery Gift 'mon</a>, The Pokémon Company revealed that Sceptile, Blaziken, and Swampert will be getting their Mega Stones very soon.</p>
<p>However, similar to the Kalos trio's stones, the Sceptilite, Blazikenite, and Swampertite Stones will only be available via the Z-A Battle Club's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/pokemon-legends-z-a-ranked-battles-all-seasons-and-rewards">Ranked Battles</a>. Which means you need a Nintendo Switch Online subscription to get them.</p>
<figure data-uuid="464a0329e0ab6"><a title="Pokémon Legends: Z-A" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/464a0329e0ab6/pokemon-legends-z-a.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>These three stones will be available ink ranked season 5 (Sceptilite), season 6 (Swampertite), and season 7 (Blazikenite) and you don't need the DLC to get the stones. You will, however, apparently encounter these Pokémon <em>in</em> Mega Dimension.</p>
<p>The date for the new seasons hasn't been confirmed yet, but we'll let you know when, as we're sure you'll want this excellent trio of Megas on your team.</p>
<p>If you're looking for something a little more immediate, then you'll notice that most of the trailer up top focuses on Alpha Charizard, which you can get via a new Mystery Gift code. It'll make a very spicy Mega Charizard X or Y, we reckon.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Are you excited for the Mega Dimension DLC tomorrow? Will you be getting these three Mega Stones? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:192564,191762 @ 1765296004 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/pokemon-legends-z-a-confirms-return-of-hoenn-starter-mega-stones]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inquisitors Do More Than Fight: Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy Detective System Showcased In New Screenshots]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/inquisitors-do-more-than-fight-warhammer-40000-dark-heresy-detective-system-showcased-in-new-screenshots/</link>
            <guid>1377292</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Following the release of <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/review/warhammer-40000-rogue-trader-charting-a-new-course/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Warhammer 40,000: Rogue Trader</strong></a>, Owlcat Games will soon return to the universe created by Games Workshop with <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-dark-heresy-is-owlcats-next-inquisition-themed-crpg/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy</strong></a>, a game that is set to surpass its predecessor in many different ways while improving the player experience with some choice tweaks. Today, the development team has provided a new look at some of the game's standout features ahead of the launch of the Alpha version later this month.</p>



<p>Today's new screenshots, which can be found below, provide a new look at the party members, the detailed environments, combat sequences, and the first look at the mind map powering the detective gameplay, which I found to be among the most interesting additions to the experience when I had the chance of seeing the game in action during this year's Gamescom.</p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-1-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy expands the foundation set by its predecessor with new gameplay systems</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-2-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-3-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-4-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-5-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-6-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-7-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-8-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-9-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-10-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-11-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Warhammer-40000-Dark-Heresy-Alpha-12-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>As mentioned above, the new batch of Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy precedes the launch of the game's Alpha version, which will debut on December 16 on Steam. This early version of the game allows players to test out some of the game's features, including the tactical turn-based combat system and the investigative features that suit the Inquisitor protagonist well, while helping Owlcat with the game's development.</p>



<p>Although it may not look that much different from its predecessor at a glance, Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy packs a lot of improvements and new features that will set the two games apart. Combat, in particular, has been significantly enhanced, with an overhaul of the cover system and a new targeting system that opens up numerous tactical options. You can learn more about them by checking out my <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-dark-heresy-gamescom-preview-inquisitors-are-always-right/"><strong>Warhammer 40,000: Dark Heresy hands-on preview.</strong></a></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/inquisitors-do-more-than-fight-warhammer-40000-dark-heresy-detective-system-showcased-in-new-screenshots/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced rated by PEGI, as the siren song of remake sea shanties grows deafening]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-rated-by-pegi-as-the-siren-song-of-remake-sea-shanties-grows-deafening</link>
            <guid>1377289</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Weigh-hay and up she rises?</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Ubisoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Look lively, me hearties. There, cast your eyes starboard. Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced PEGI rating ahoy. The fair winds have seemed to be blowing our sails towards Ubisoft's long-rumoured remake or remaster of the fourth mainline Assassin's Creed, the one that's all piratey, for years at this point. At last, it seems, we may be on track to slide our hull into its port.</p>
<p>Our compasses have endured much flitting between different directions, buffetted by the rogue gusts of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-voice-actor-claims-ubisoft-threatened-to-sue-him-over-remake-tease">voice actors saying a thing</a> and many <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-assassins-creed-4-black-flag-remake-will-release-in-march-2026-according-to-the-latest-whispers">reports also saying things</a>. The seasick landlubbers among us may indeed finally <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/">breathe their sigh of relief very soon</a> after all, it would seem.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>That said, if you're hoping this <a href="https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=Assassin%27s+Creed+Black+Flag+Resynced">freshly unearthed listing</a> on the Pan European Game Information ratings board's website is awash with details about Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced, you're going to be disappointed. Spotted by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/">YouTuber Corkben</a>, the listing's naught but a name, an indication that you'll have to be 18 to play this Ubisoft-developed game, and a selection of reasons that rating's been applied.
</p>
<p>Violence, bad language, and the most piratey of all infractions: in-game purchases. Some combination of the same trio adorns <a href="https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=assassin%27s+creed&amp;op=Search&amp;age%5B%5D=&amp;descriptor%5B%5D=&amp;publisher=&amp;platform%5B%5D=&amp;release_year%5B%5D=&amp;page=1&amp;form_build_id=form-bz8nbznbz_F9jMJ_MJXFYGrsaKZAZWOHaA9gS6afh1Y&amp;form_id=pegi_search_form">the listings</a> of all the other Assassin's Creed entries, though those have some additional blurb about platforms and release dates that the Black Flag Resynced rating is currently missing. The timing might suggest a a formal announcement at this Thursday's Geoff Awards, something that'd seem to mesh with recent reporting alleging a release early next year.</p><div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>This year's seen plenty of Black Flag remake chatter, regardless of Ubisoft continuing to remain tight lipped on the subject, as they have since such a project was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-might-be-remaking-their-swashbuckling-pirateventure-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag">first reported to be in the works</a>. Back in September, French publication Jeux Vidéo Magazine <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-will-release-early-2026-and-swaps-modern-day-sections-for-more-piracy-claims-report">claimed</a> that Ubisoft Singapore, Ubisoft Bordeaux and Ubisoft Belgrade are involved in putting together the remake. The magazine also asserted that this Black Flag revamp will ditch with the original's modern-day Abstergo office-wandering segments for some cut content featuring Mary Read. The likes of inventory and combat mechanics have reportedly been tweaked to more closely mirror recent entries Shadows and Valhalla.</p>
<p>So, hoist the main sail! We're headed for remake-laden land at last. Or just an island covered in fools' gold.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-rated-by-pegi-as-the-siren-song-of-remake-sea-shanties-grows-deafening]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Is Being Released…Again]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-is-being-released-again/</link>
            <guid>1377280</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s 2025, and The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim is about to be released for what feels like the millionth time. Skyrim is available on just about every platform in the world at this point, even the Amazon Echo to an extent, but now you can add another format to the list.</p>



<p>Yes, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bethesda-skyrim-against-call-of-duty-2011/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</a> is an exceptional RPG. Yes, Bethesda, everyone knows how proud you are of the game and its legacy. It’s at a point now where Skyrim has been ported to every device in the world, making it beyond being a meme at this point. One key platform is missing, and Skyrim is about to be released on it.</p>











<figure><figcaption>It’s been a while since the last release. Credit to Bethesda</figcaption></figure>



<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 is welcoming a The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim port. The news was confirmed by Bethesda Game Studios on their official X page.</p>







<p>Here’s what the company said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“Bring your adventure everywhere with you during the holidays with the release of The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim on Switch 2, available today!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The Switch 2 release is completely free for owners of the Anniversary Edition on Switch 1, it includes the Dawnguard, Dragonborn, and Hearthfire expansions, and comes with Nintendo-exclusive content—namely Zelda-inspired gear and armor.</p>



<p>Check out the complete message and a full look at the trailer and all content included below.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Bring your adventure everywhere with you during the holidays with the release of The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim on Switch 2, available today! <a href="https://t.co/Jr2tF30o0Y">pic.twitter.com/Jr2tF30o0Y</a></p>— Bethesda Game Studios (@BethesdaStudios) <a href="https://twitter.com/BethesdaStudios/status/1998409350067458172?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 9, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>Are you a reader who’s somehow never owned a copy of The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim? Or is this about to become your seventh purchase of the iconic RPG? Discuss it and more through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-appears/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced Appearing On The PEGI Ratings Site</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/saros-getting-new-look-at-the-game-awards-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Saros Getting ‘New Look’ at The Game Awards 2025</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-is-being-released-again/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive: CD Projekt-Backed Cyberpunk TCG Revealed, Featuring Characters From 2077 and Edgerunners — Here's Everything You Need to Know]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-tcg-revealed</link>
            <guid>1377277</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The brainchild of Mike Pondsmith back in 1988 as a TTRPG, Cyberpunk as a property has exploded in the past decade, thanks in no small part to CD Projekt Red and 2020's release of their first-person RPG, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a>. Now, five years and expansions, patches, and board games later, the world of Cyberpunk is trying its robotic hands in a brand new – and highly competitive – market with a fully fledged, and collectible, <strong>Cyberpunk: Trading Card Game</strong>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has had the opportunity to speak with the teams at WeirdCo and CD Projekt Red, who are working on the newly announced TCG, to get a better understanding of the designers at WeirdCo, how this partnership came to be, and even some goodies about the game itself. We've also got an <strong>exclusive first look</strong> at key card art from the Cyberpunk TCG <strong>(flip through the gallery below)</strong>, featuring Cyberpunk 2077's Saburo and Yorinobu Arasaka, and their handy bodyguard, Goro Takemura. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">WeirdCo, a new face in the world of TCGs, has been working in close partnership with CDPR themselves to devise this new card game, aiming to capture the tone and aesthetic of 2077 and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/cyberpunk-edgerunners">Edgerunners' Netflix anime</a>, to deliver a game that doesn't just feel like another TCG just with a coat of Cyberpunk yellow overtop. One way the team is doing this is by working with high-profile artists, both internal to CDPR and the wider community, to deliver gorgeous card art featuring faces that will be familiar to anyone worth their wait in Chrome. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking with Elliot Cook (WeirdCo President) and Luohan Wei (WeirdCo CEO), both co-founders of the business, I wanted to know how this new studio came about. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Elliot began, "WeirdCo was formed when Luohan and I met each other through our mutual mentor, Bill Mooney: a true legend in the digital gaming space. We immediately hit it off over our passion for building games that truly connect with their communities. Later, we formed WeirdCo to create games together — ones that authentically bring together and inspire people." </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>"Players can look forward to collecting an array of unique variants of characters including V, Johnny, Panam, Judy, Adam Smasher, and more."</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">"CD Projekt Red has a similar goal, and when we saw this in each other we knew it would be a great partnership. What has been paramount, and the question we ask ourselves daily, is “how do we make a game that represents and celebrates every part of Cyberpunk — everywhere it has been and everywhere it is going?" That is the north star of our development."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With Cyberpunk being one of the biggest media properties right now, I was curious how a brand new group could tackle such a monster IP, but despite it being a new team, the group working on the Cyberpunk TCG has worked on other large IP card games you probably have heard of. "We at WeirdCo have direct experience working on some great card games" Elliot explains. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Marvel Snap, Duel Masters, and Universus, to name a few. At our core we are disruptors, just like CD Projekt Red, and we both strive to inspire our players. We saw this in each other from the beginning, and I think CD Projekt Red saw our love for the Cyberpunk 2077 universe too. This is an IP that deserves to be explored in different and exciting ways, and we’re committed to doing this authentically with Cyberpunk TCG, side by side with the community."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">On the topic of CD Projekt Red, they have been a constant ally during the game’s design and development. Elliot provides further details, "We have worked with CD Projekt Red very closely since the beginning of development. They have been the ideal partner; you may even see the same amazing artists who worked on Cyberpunk 2077, Cyberpunk: Edgerunners, and more as featured artists in Cyberpunk TCG! Every part of the TCG has the impeccable RED touch, ensuring this is a completely authentic Cyberpunk experience."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Cyberpunk TCG won’t be CDPR’s first collaboration in the tabletop space, with other titles like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-gangs-of-night-city-board-game-review"><u>Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City</u></a> and <a href="https://review/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Cyberpunk Edgerunners: Combat Zone Board Game</u></a>, but I was curious what unique joys or challenges came from working on a TCG, so I asked Patrick Mills, CDPR’s Franchise Content Strategy Lead.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Every collaboration is unique, and we’re lucky to work with many partners who are passionate and extremely dedicated to their crafts. While making a physical TCG is something completely new for us, we see the genuine excitement, enthusiasm, and talent in WeirdCo that act as the foundation of any successful collaboration." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Their passion for the franchise has been evident at every stage, and they’re doing an incredible job developing an engaging TCG that ensures an authentic Cyberpunk experience. On the flip side, many of us at CD Projekt Red are huge TCG enthusiasts too — so we’re thrilled to be entering this space with WeirdCo"</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One thing that is clear is that both teams at WeirdCo and CDPR are taking care to ensure that this is faithful to the Cyberpunk property that its creator, Mike Pondsmith, imagined back in 1988. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>"For the initial release, our primary goal is to represent the core identity of Cyberpunk 2077"</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">"We want Cyberpunk TCG to be authentic to the spirit and dynamic nature of the Cyberpunk 2077 universe, and wanted to create a TCG that is accessible to Cyberpunk fans who have never touched a card game.” Luohan says, “At the same time, as TCG players ourselves, we wanted our game to have the depth necessary to entertain for a long, long time. And I think we have struck that balance well."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Elliot continues, "The best part of this job is spending hundreds of hours with the Cyberpunk universe — whether that’s replaying Cyberpunk 2077, watching Edgerunners for the fifth time, or reading all the Dark Horse comics. Every one of us at WeirdCo loves the Cyberpunk universe, and we built the TCG bit by bit on this foundation. At each step we analyzed every little detail, constantly asking ourselves: "How do we make this more authentic to Cyberpunk?" </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Many fan favorite characters will be making an appearance as well in this TCG and picking who would be included in this first set was a big decision. "For the initial release, our primary goal is to represent the core identity of Cyberpunk 2077 by featuring many of its most iconic and beloved characters,” explains Patrick. “We’ve collaborated closely with WeirdCo to ensure that the artwork and flavor of every card faithfully captures the essence of who they represent, providing a snapshot of their personalities and what they stand for, as well as including memorable moments players will instantly recognize. Given the complexity of our characters, we wanted to capture their many facets across multiple cards. So, players can look forward to collecting an array of unique variants of characters including V, Johnny, Panam, Judy, Adam Smasher, and more."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the WeirdCo side, Elliot shares, "We worked very hard to figure out which Legends make the most sense for players, and which ones make the most sense for the overall theme of Set 1. While some of them, like V and Johnny, are obvious hits, we have a few surprises up our sleeves too."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Being a game composed of a ton of cards, artwork is pretty important in a TCG and WeirdCo is special care to make sure that what players can expect is nothing short of beautiful. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We’ve been working for a long time with a team of over 20 talented artists for Set 1, and are excited to explore new ways of bringing the world of Cyberpunk to life through our card art. Working with artists like <a href="https://www.instagram.com/itoscaresme/?hl=en" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ito</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/vincenzo_riccardi_vinartwork/?hl=en" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vincenzo Riccardi</a>, and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/jsraphael_/?hl=en" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Joshua Raphael</a>, who each bring their own unique flair to the project, makes each card more exciting than the last," Elliot continues, "We’re not sharing gameplay details yet, so there’s not too much I can say. But Cyberpunk is known for its beautiful yet tragic atmosphere — this is a major focus of ours when it comes to the card art."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Details on how Cyberpunk TCG will work remain shrouded behind CDPR's and WeirdCo's firewalls, so we have a bit yet before we have an in-depth picture of how it plays. Cyberpunk's TCG will be launching its crowdfunding campaign in 2026, which is right around the corner. WeirdCo and CDPR will be revealing more of the game soon, along with a deep dive into how the game plays, more artwork, and card reveals, with some more special reveals found only here on IGN.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The TCG space is pretty crowded with new contenders entering the ring, it seems like every quarter or so, but few have the name recognition behind them like WeirdCo has with Cyberpunk. The fact that this project has so much support from CD Projekt Red behind it puts it in a different league from others, even before it's out. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The excitement from the designers is electric, with Luohan leaving players with this, “I can’t wait for players to see how we’ve adapted the themes of Cyberpunk, like taking on gigs or building a crew, to a trading card game format. I think it is both true to Cyberpunk itself while being innovative to the TCG market as a whole; it’s a perfect combination in this way.” As far as I know, no other TCG lets you play with Keanu Reeves, so that is already a big plus in its favor. Wake up, Samurai, there's a whole new way to burn the city coming.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If this sounds up your alley, follow the game and get yourself a special and exclusive Lucy "Nova Rare" card free by signing up over on the game's <a href="https://www.launchoracle.com/weird-co/cyberpunk-trading-card-game/MF7J3" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Launch Oracle page</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Scott White is a freelance contributor to IGN, assisting with tabletop games and guide coverage. Follow him on </em><a href="https://x.com/ProfessorRPG" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>X/Twitter</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/professorrpg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a><em>.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>This article features contributions from Robert Anderson, Senior Commerce Editor for IGN.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-tcg-revealed]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cozy hand-painted adventure game Seina: A Tale of Spirits announced for PS5, Xbox Series, Switch 2, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/cozy-hand-painted-adventure-game-seina-a-tale-of-spirits-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-2-and-pc</link>
            <guid>1377274</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > POFUPOFU STUDIOS" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pofupofu-studios">POFUPOFU STUDIOS</a> has announced cozy hand-painted <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,761 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Seina: A Tale of Spirits" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/seina-a-tale-of-spirits">Seina: A Tale of Spirits</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,998 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,409 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [764 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,000 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4119150/Seina_a_Tale_Of_Spirits/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch in 2026. <span id="more-1012459"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via POFUPOFU STUDIOS:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Seina: A Tale of Spirits</em> is a cozy, hand-painted adventure inspired by Japanese nature, folklore, and traditional values. Players explore a watercolor world filled with peaceful forests, ancient shrines, and friendly spirits, discovering a gentle narrative through non-verbal storytelling, expressions, and atmospheric details. Designed for relaxation and reflection, the game invites players to wander at their own pace, uncovering small secrets and quiet moments of beauty.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>Players follow Mika, a young girl searching for her missing cat who accidentally wanders into a serene spirit realm. This world reflects memories held by nature itself, shrines forgotten by time, paths shaped by ancient folklore and gentle spirits who guide or observe her journey.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>As Mika explores deeper, she uncovers small stories hidden in the world: places where past and present quietly overlap, revealing themes of companionship, kindness, and respect for nature. Instead of confronting danger, Mika connects with the environment and its spirits, learning how everything in this world is intertwined. The narrative unfolds softly through discovery, offering an emotional journey built on subtle details and moments of tranquility.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_1012467"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Gameplay</strong></p><p><em>Seina: A Tale of Spirits</em> focuses on peaceful exploration and intimate discoveries. Players wander through hand-painted locations, interact with friendly animal spirits, and solve light, accessible puzzles. Storytelling happens through gestures, environmental clues, and visual expression rather than dialogue or traditional cutscenes.</p><p>Each area encourages players to slow down, observe, and explore at their own rhythm. The world reacts gently to Mika’s presence—spirits respond with curiosity, shrines reveal fragments of memory, and small secrets emerge for those who take the time to look.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Hand-Painted Watercolor World</strong> – Explore environments created in soft watercolor tones, inspired by Japanese nature and folklore.</li><li><strong>Cozy, Stress-Free Exploration</strong> – No combat, timers, or pressure. Just peaceful wandering and simple discoveries.</li><li><strong>Friendly Animal Spirits</strong> – Meet glowing, charming spirits with unique personalities that enrich the journey.</li><li><strong>Light, Accessible Puzzles</strong> – Designed for all ages, adding gentle interaction without disrupting the game’s calm atmosphere.</li><li><strong>Non-Verbal Storytelling</strong> – The narrative unfolds through expressions, gestures, and atmospheric details rather than dialogue or text-heavy scenes.</li><li><strong>Heartfelt Inspiration</strong> – A personal journey crafted by a solo woman developer, shaped by real experiences traveling through Japan.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/seina-a-tale-of-spirits/december-9-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Seina: A Tale of Spirits - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xh9RBsev-eo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/cozy-hand-painted-adventure-game-seina-a-tale-of-spirits-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-2-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Go Fest 2026 Announced For Three Major Cities, Including Chicago]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-fest-2026-announced-for-three-major-cities-including-chicago/1100-6536790/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1377271</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536790">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Niantic Inc. has chosen three cities spanning three continents for Pokemon Go Fest 2026: Tokyo, Chicago, and Copenhagen in Denmark. The event--which will celebrate the popular game's 10th anniversary next year--will kick off in late May in Japan and end in the middle of June in Copenhagen.</p><p dir="ltr">Details are sparse outside <a href="https://pokemongo.com/news/save-the-date-go-fest-2026" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the host cities for Pokemon Go Fest 2026</a> so far. However, there will be global events as well, for players who can't attend at the main locations. For <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-is-adding-more-gigantamax-starters-during-global-go-fest-events/1100-6531756/">Pokemon Go Fest 2025</a>, global events introduced Gigantamax starters to the game, for example.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Pokemon Go Fest Locations and Dates</h2><h3 dir="ltr">Tokyo at Bay Area</h3><ul><li dir="ltr">Friday, May 29 to Monday, June 1, 2026</li><li dir="ltr">Ticketed Citywide Gameplay will begin Monday, May 25, 2026</li></ul><h3 dir="ltr">Chicago at Grant Park</h3><ul><li dir="ltr">Friday, June 5 to Sunday, June 7, 2026</li><li dir="ltr">Ticketed Citywide Gameplay will begin Thursday, June 4, 2026</li></ul><h3 dir="ltr">Copenhagen at Fælledparken</h3><ul><li dir="ltr">Friday, June 12 to Sunday, June 14, 2026</li><li dir="ltr">Ticketed Citywide Gameplay will begin Thursday, June 11, 2026</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Currently, there are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-events-raid-bosses-spotlight-hours-community-day/1100-6533384/">a ton of Pokemon Go December events</a> happening, such as five-star raids and Spotlight Hours. The Well-Armed event is set to go live this Thursday, December 11, and will bring the fighting-type octopus Clobbopus to the game for the first time.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-gos-leveling-system-overhaul-now-live-with-new-rewards-and-items/1100-6535468/">Pokemon Go saw its leveling system overhauled</a> in October. The level cap for the game was also substantially raised, from 50 to 80.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        
  
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536762&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-title-narrowed-down-to-two-candidates\/1100-6536762\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536755&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kojima-says-his-upcoming-game-od-may-not-work-out\/1100-6536755\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536754&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/shout-factory-4k-blu-rays-on-sale-amazon\/1100-6536754\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536751&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/netflix-considered-buying-ea-report\/1100-6536751\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528648&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-lord-of-the-rings-deals-barad-dur-rivendell-building-sets\/1100-6528648\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536723&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-truly-special-new-total-war-game-will-be-revealed-at-the-game-awards\/1100-6536723\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534941&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2026-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6534941\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536635&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/after-120-hours-in-arc-raiders-i-finally-killed-another-player\/1100-6536635\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536671&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-preorder-guide\/1100-6536671\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536753&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/an-ai-vtuber-is-trying-to-complete-hardcore-minecraft-and-all-hell-is-breaking-loose\/1100-6536753\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536750&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-game-awards-mysterious-monolith-is-not-for-lords-of-the-fallen-2\/1100-6536750\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536577&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/asus-rog-xbox-ally-gets-110-discount-at-amazon\/1100-6536577\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536770&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tomb-raider-news-confirmed-for-the-game-awards-following-remake-leak\/1100-6536770\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535971&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-echoes-of-victory-ridge-quest-guide\/1100-6535971\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/all-arc-raiders-quests-full-mission-list\/1100-6535922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536735&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-6-dev-announces-60-candle-that-smells-like-vice-city\/1100-6536735\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536108&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-armored-transports-quest-guide\/1100-6536108\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536018&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-celestes-journals-quest-guide\/1100-6536018\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535962&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-the-majors-footlocker-quest-guide\/1100-6535962\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-fest-2026-announced-for-three-major-cities-including-chicago/1100-6536790/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rumored Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag Remake Has A Really Silly Title, According To Rating]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rumored-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-has-a-really-silly-title-according-to-rating/1100-6536787/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1377265</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536787">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Evidence of a remake or remaster of the fan-favorite Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag is solidifying, with a listing from European content-rating board PEGI emerging.</p><p>According to the <a href="https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=Assassin%27s+Creed+Black+Flag+Resynced" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PEGI listing</a>, the re-release of the Ubisoft classic is titled Assassin's Creed Black Flag Resynced, and it unsurprisingly has an 18 adults-only rating for violence, language, and in-game purchases. Ratings are generally a sign that a title's release is imminent.</p><p>"Resynced" is an amusing subtitle for a re-release, most likely referring to the in-universe Animus virtual reality machine that lets the player character experience historical events through an avatar, "syncing" them with memories of someone else from that time period. If you really want to make a stretch, "Resynced" could be a nautical pun.</p><p>The existence of this Black Flag revisit has been an open secret in the industry for years, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-remake-is-reportedly-coming/1100-6515623/" data-ref-id="1100-6515623">leaks dating back to 2023</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-voice-actor-hints-at-a-potential-black-flag-remake/1100-6532817/" data-ref-id="1100-6532817">voice actors hinting</a> about the project. Per reports as recent as this November, the Black Flag remake <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-may-reportedly-launch-sooner-than-you-think/1100-6536439/" data-ref-id="1100-6536439">may launch on the week of March 23, 2026</a>.</p><p>Still unclear is if Black Flag Resynced is a straight remaster, similar to the treatment the Ezio trilogy and Assassin's Creed III received (with the latter simply titled "Assassin's Creed III Remastered"). "Resynced" could imply new or changed content for Black Flag--it's already been reported that this re-release <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-remake-wont-have-modern-day-sections-report/1100-6534827/" data-ref-id="1100-6534827">won't feature any modern-day sections</a>, which would be a major change from the original game.</p><p>Should Black Flag Resynced surface in early 2026, it will be a nice drop for Assassin's Creed fans, who recently learned that the latest title in the franchise, Assassin's Creed Shadows, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-wont-get-second-dlc-expansion/1100-6536570/" data-ref-id="1100-6536570">won't get a second major DLC</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rumored-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-has-a-really-silly-title-according-to-rating/1100-6536787/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk Trading Card Game Brings 2077 And Edgerunners To Tables With A Kickstarter Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/09/cyberpunk-trading-card-game-brings-2077-and-edgerunners-to-tables-with-a-kickstarter</link>
            <guid>1377262</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>CD Projekt Red and card game maker WeirdCo have revealed Cyberpunk TCG, a physical-only trading card game featuring characters, locations, gear, and more from the world of <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/07/cyberpunk-edgerunners-2-is-a-standalone-sequel-series-coming-to-netflix"><em>Cyberpunk Edgerunners</em></a>. A <a href="https://www.launchoracle.com/weird-co/cyberpunk-trading-card-game/MF7J3">Kickstarter</a> for the TCG will go live next year, and if you sign up now, you will eventually receive a free Lucyna Kushinada (from <em>Edgerunners</em>) card one day.&nbsp;</p><p>"In Cyberpunk Trading Card Game, you'll put together the ultimate edgerunner crew with characters from across the franchise, pitting them against your opponents as you fight to become a Night City legend," the Cyberpunk TCG reveal trailer description reads. "Featuring stunning, custom artwork, Cyberpunk TCG is designed for trading card players, avid collectors, and fans of the Cyberpunk franchise alike."&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Check out the Cyberpunk TCG reveal trailer for yourself below:&nbsp;</strong></p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ChsJ7XMrz14"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ChsJ7XMrz14" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>As you can see, if you sign up for the TCG <a href="https://www.launchoracle.com/weird-co/cyberpunk-trading-card-game/MF7J3">here</a>, you'll receive a free exclusive Lucy card when the game presumably launches one day. As for when that might happen, it could be a while because the Kickstarter for Cyberpunk TCG doesn't go live until next year, and then the game has to be made after it (hopefully) reaches Kickstarter's goals.&nbsp;</p>



<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="67e24c74-7d79-4889-a0c4-7045e64a6b04" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="image:responsive_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;responsive_image_style&quot;:&quot;content_body&quot;,&quot;image_loading&quot;:{&quot;attribute&quot;:&quot;lazy&quot;},&quot;image_link&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
          <picture>
                  <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/body_default/public/2025/12/09/46aa3088/cyberpunk_tcg_15.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 851px)" type="image/webp" width="800" height="448">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/12/09/46aa3088/cyberpunk_tcg_15.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 315px) and (max-width: 450px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="252">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/12/09/46aa3088/cyberpunk_tcg_15.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (max-width: 314px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="252">
                  

  </picture>


  
  
  
</article>

<p><strong>In the meantime, scroll through the gallery below for an early look at all the cards we spotted in the Cyberpunk TCG reveal trailer</strong>:&nbsp;</p><p>While waiting for Cyberpunk TCG's Kickstarter to go live next year, read <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/cyberpunk-2077/cyberpunk-2077-review-a-wild-time-in-night-city"><em>Game Informer's </em>Cyberpunk 2077 review</a>, and then read <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty/so-long-night-city">our review of Cyberpunk 2077: Phantom Liberty</a>.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Are you interested in this TCG? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/09/cyberpunk-trading-card-game-brings-2077-and-edgerunners-to-tables-with-a-kickstarter]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feature: "It's A Bit Of A Joke At This Point" - Skyrim Dev On Returning For A Switch 2 Re-Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/its-a-bit-of-a-joke-at-this-point-skyrim-dev-on-returning-for-a-switch-2-re-release</link>
            <guid>1377238</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="ec1d4fb898d23"><a title="Skyrim - Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ec1d4fb898d23/skyrim-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Bethesda</em></figcaption></figure><p>Somehow, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/surprise-skyrim-anniversary-edition-lands-on-switch-2-today">Skyrim returned</a>.</p>
<p>Yes, the rumours are true, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-anniversary-edition">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Anniversary Edition</a> is back (again), as a free Switch 2 upgrade. Making the most of the hardware's updated specs, the new release bundles in a whole host of fancy features, like enhanced performance and resolution, better load times, and Mouse Mode, <em>and</em> it gives us yet another chance to replay the iconic 2011 RPG in all of its <em>fus ro dah</em>-ing glory.</p>
<p>Keen to learn more about this new release, we were recently lucky enough to sit down with Bethesda Creative Director <strong>Matt Carofano</strong> (who was Lead Artist on the original game) to talk all things Skyrim. We chatted about Matt's favourite Skyrim moments, the game's mind-blowing Switch 1 reveal, the re-release process, and, of course, the team's plans for the future.</p>
<p>We began, however, right back at the start of his Skyrim journey. So, don your fanciest armour set, grab a tankard of Velvet LeChance, and prepare for a walk down memory lane.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Nintendo Life (Jim Norman): Let's start back at the beginning. What's your earliest memory of working on Skyrim?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Matt Carofano (Creative Director):</strong> I remember Todd Howard and I were talking about where we should set this, and we both naturally coalesced around the realm of Skyrim — 'Let's go to that province, it'll be great!'</p>
<p>A lot of that was a reaction to the previous games we had done. The theme of <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox/elder_scrolls_iii_morrowind">Morrowind</a> was 'stranger in a strange land,' so very weird, alien, and unusual, with high-fantasy elements. For <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-360/elder_scrolls_iv_oblivion">Oblivion</a>, we wanted to do more of a traditional European fantasy game. So there was a tonal shift between those games. When we got to Skyrim, we wanted to take a little bit of the strangeness, deeper culture, and more interesting things, but not too alien as we did in Morrowind. The home of the Nords, Skyrim, fit that really well, so we were excited about that province and wanted to work there.</p>
<p>Some of the earliest things I did were making the map and planning out what the world was. So I was looking for references around the world — the <em>real</em> world — of dramatic places that we could put together into a game. For us, the world is the main character and the foundation of the game. It's also inspirational for the team. So if you have this backdrop of frozen lands, a beautiful tundra, this forest in the south, the canyon off to the west, it's inspirational for the designers to write stories. Otherwise, you come at a game, and it's sort of a blank canvas; it's a bit like, 'Oh, what do we do? Who are the people who survive here?' It informs the characters and the quests. So for us, making the world is the first step in pretty much every game we do.</p>
<figure data-uuid="4bedc6ba68f76"><a title="Skyrim - Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4bedc6ba68f76/skyrim-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Bethesda</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>At what point did you know that you were onto a winner?</strong></p>
<p>It's hard to explain, because I was a fan of the Elder Scrolls before I started working here, and when I was working on Morrowind, I was like, 'This is the greatest thing ever!' I'm obsessive about the games we make, so are the people here. It's always on your mind; you're always thinking, 'What can I add to the game? How can I make it better?' I don't know if that's healthy or not, but that's just the way it works!</p>
<p>We knew Skyrim was something special throughout the development cycle, but really that last period where it all started coming together, and we were playing it and play testing, and you see all the systems layer together, and it's working as a game, I knew we had something good. The team felt it.</p>
<p>Did we know it was going to become what Skyrim became? No, absolutely not. I think it's still a shock to everyone here that Skyrim has been such a popular game, that we have such amazing fans who have played it for over a decade. That's pretty incredible. So none of us take that for granted, and we're really honoured and privileged to have this franchise that people love so much.</p>
<p><strong>You can see Skyrim in a lot of different games and properties that have come out since. What is it about this game that makes it so appealing?</strong></p>
<p>Our motto is, "let you be who you want and play how you want." You can make incredibly varied characters in this game — how they look, their race, all that, but also how they play, the skills you want to get into. So we're very freeing and open-ended.</p>
<p>Additionally, you take that kind of character, and you put them in the world and say, 'We're not going to railroad you to the main story. In fact, we encourage you to ignore it and do whatever you want.' So we write stories that we're really excited about. We think they're good, and we want people to play them, but the true story of the game is what the player does. It might be, 'I made my character and just wandered off in this direction, got into trouble, and it was really fun.' That was different from a lot of other games in the industry.</p>
<p>So there's something exciting about the freedom we allow to go anywhere, play how you want, and tell your own story in this world we made. It's really the ultimate kind of sandbox role-playing game.</p>
<figure data-uuid="5ffb9ecf629f7"><a title="Skyrim - Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/5ffb9ecf629f7/skyrim-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Bethesda</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>I have a very distinct memory of accidentally using a spell in a town and turning the entire place against me. Do you have one of those defining Skyrim memories from your first time playing through it?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, but I'll add on to yours. We made NPCs overreact to what you did. Everyone attacks the chicken in Riverwood, which is the very first town you come to, and then you're wanted. Like there's no getting around it. We talk about that moment a lot, because it's fun and funny, but it just presented itself because we made it a crime to attack the chicken, and the chicken is in the same faction as the town, so the people of the town will defend the chicken. It was initially unintentional and became a bit funny, but it might be a bit punitive. So we discussed how much we wanted to let you get away with playing around in the world without getting into too much trouble, and how quickly we can reset things.</p>
<p>For me, it's the surprise of going somewhere, and the systems of the game overlapping and something unexpected happening. Whether it's a giant is hurting something, then monsters attack, and then a dragon shows up, and you're like, 'This is not what we planned for,' but it turns out to be really fun.</p>
<p><strong>What's the re-release process like for you? How do you approach returning to a game again after working on it for over a decade now?</strong></p>
<p>It's really easy. We're huge fans of Nintendo, love working with them and getting our games to their consoles. And because there's a new console, it's 'Hey, let's bring back one of our most beloved games to the Switch 2 and see how we can improve it and make it the best experience for that console'. Some old fans will keep playing and want to play that version, and then there's a whole new generation who might be getting a Switch 2 for the first time, and that's the first time they've ever played Skyrim. So that's really it.</p>
<p>It's a bit of a joke at this point how often we release Skyrim, but it's a great game. We want everyone to be able to play it in the best way possible.</p>
<p><strong>What was the process like of developing it for the Switch 2? How does it match up against consoles you developed for in the past?</strong></p>
<p>We had previously done the version for the Switch, so this was going back to that and making improvements on it. So it was really an easy development process and actually pretty quick in terms of our timelines. Making the game takes years and years and years, but bringing it to this new console was a much, much faster process.</p>
<p>A lot of it was really just focusing on taking advantage of the new hardware. We can use DLSS now and get better resolution, better performance, and the game loads faster. Switch 2 has the Joy-Con 2 controllers that let you use mouse controls, so we added that. A lot of it is really just, 'How do we take advantage of the Switch 2? What can it do? And [how can we] give players the best version of Skyrim for that console?'</p>
<figure data-uuid="81bcc234f9b41"><a title="Skyrim - Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/81bcc234f9b41/skyrim-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Bethesda</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>What feature are you most pleased to see implemented this time?</strong></p>
<p>There are a couple of things. Overall, it's just general performance. The game performs better, runs smoother, and loads faster. So it's just a better play experience on the Switch 2.</p>
<p>Several years after we released Skyrim, we did a remastering process. We spent over a year on that project — I worked on that quite a bit — and we improved the lighting, graphics features, and things like that. That came to the Switch version, but there are some subtleties we can turn up and make better [on Switch 2], particularly the volumetric lighting is nicer on Switch 2. That's something I was personally very excited about, having tweaked all the numbers for the different weathers, fog, and clouds for months and months and months. Getting the best version of that on the Switch 2 is really important to me.</p>
<p><strong>Seeing Skyrim on Switch 1 was such a monumental part of that console's early life. What was it like working with Nintendo on that version?</strong></p>
<p>It was exciting to put one of our modern games on a Nintendo console, and the Switch was super exciting to everybody when it came out. I'm a big Nintendo fan. I have the Switch, I have the Switch 2. I played a lot at home with my family. But seeing it on a portable device was just really cool. And the thought of being able to sit on your couch or go anywhere with this and play a full, deep game like Skyrim that lasts for hundreds of hours was really awesome.</p>
<p>Then it was the fun stuff of getting the sword swing to work with the Joy-Con, or one of our artists here, Christiane Meister, made Zelda assets that we put on that version. As a fan of Zelda, having a Nintendo as a kid, and playing the original Zelda, and then, in a roundabout way, getting some Zelda in a game that I made was really cool.</p>
<p><strong>Were there any other Nintendo franchises that ever crossed your mind as a Skyrim crossover?</strong></p>
<p>It was always Zelda. A fun fact: the [former] voice of Mario [Charles Martinet] is Paarthurnax in Skyrim. So that was pretty cool too. But no, because Zelda is one of the first open-world RPGs, it was pretty awesome to have that connection there.</p>
<p><strong>Skyrim has defined over a decade of your working life now. What other games have really stood out to you in that time and inspired your work?</strong></p>
<p>The one that immediately jumps to my mind is <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/red_dead_redemption_2">Red Dead Redemption 2</a>. It took me a little while to get, but once it hooks you, I felt like I was an outlaw at the end of the Wild West, and the experience of living in that world. It's truly a masterpiece of a game.</p>
<p>I love the subtle moments in gaming where you're just riding your horse, appreciating the view, and then some birds fly by. It's things that we love putting into our games to make you feel like you are truly living another life in another world. A lot of games are focused on action and combat. But when you can take a moment and breathe and really experience something else, I think that's some of the best that gaming has to offer. Red Dead Redemption 2 is an amazing, amazing game.</p>
<figure data-uuid="c8daae20ee960"><a title="Skyrim - Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/c8daae20ee960/skyrim-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Bethesda</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>With Skyrim now making the jump, are there any other Bethesda games that we will see come to Switch 2 in the future?</strong></p>
<p>Well, we did just announce that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fallout-4-anniversary-edition">Fallout 4: Anniversary Edition</a> is coming to Switch 2, so that's really exciting. That's coming next year. Past that, nothing else to say! Whether we can do another game or not, I don't know. But it's cool to see. We've come back to Skyrim, and now a Fallout game is going to make that jump, too. We're really excited about that.</p>
<p><strong>As a gamer, what do you make of the Switch 2 so far?</strong></p>
<p>I have a different perspective on Skyrim because I've probably played it more than almost anyone on Earth. I tested and played it for years while we were making it, and then I come back to it every so often when we're making our current games — that can be a Fallout, that can be <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-series-x/starfield">Starfield</a>. I revisit our games and see what was special about them, what are the things we want to bring forward? Are there things we want to change or do differently? A lot of us do that here, but I take the time to go back and play our old games and see how that can inform or inspire what we're doing currently.</p>
<p>So getting a chance to play Skyrim again on the Switch 2 was like, 'What was fun about this? How did some of the game systems work here?' It's always a thought on our minds, as we're replaying old stuff.</p>
<p><strong>Are you ever able to just enjoy Skyrim, or is there always a little bit of dev brain going on?</strong></p>
<p>There's always a little bit of dev brain going on, and it even affects gaming in general. I'm currently replaying the <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/silent_hill_2">Silent Hill 2</a> remaster, but in every game I've ever played, I start the game, I stop, I look at the textures, and I spend time thinking about the technology they're using. I try to turn that off and just enjoy it, but that happens in every game. There are moments, though, even playing Skyrim, where I just get lost in a dungeon, and I'm once again a stealth archer sneaking around killing everybody. It's great.</p>
<p><strong>So, stealth archer is your preferred play style?</strong></p>
<p>It is, and I will stake a claim to being an OG stealth archer because I always play that way. I enjoy the magic system, too, but yes, I played that way internally with the game before it became a meme, but that's okay. I tend to enjoy stealth games in general, so it's fun.</p>
<figure data-uuid="a0d7ce84bce65"><a title="Skyrim - Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a0d7ce84bce65/skyrim-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Bethesda</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>What other assets from the game's early days do you still think hold up today?</strong></p>
<p>At the very beginning of this project, I started building Riverwood. That was our testing ground for the game systems and how the game worked and felt. Every time we started a new game internally, while we were making it, you started in Riverwood, and that was the test. So I built the farm houses there, the stone walls, and the wooden walkways. I was just setting up that location. I did a lot of world art on Skyrim, as well as the art direction. So that's what comes to mind when I think of Skyrim. We had an internal testing loop of starting at Riverwood, then going up to the first dungeon of Bleak Falls Barrow. That was our early, early loop of the game, and later it branched out to a bunch of things. We had a full team working on stuff.</p>
<p>At that point, I jumped over and worked on the College of Winterhold with our designer, Brian Chapin, who was the lead designer of the Mages Guild. So I made that tower in the interior. That was fun to work on for a while, but at that point, there's a huge team going, and I'm more managing the work than building the assets.</p>
<p><strong>It must be interesting to still see your fingerprints on those locations, after all this time.</strong></p>
<p>A little bit for sure. But also, at that point, it was more working with concept artists, art directing, having input on everybody's work, and just guiding people. That's really what it's about. My job is mostly helping everyone's ideas come to fruition in the game and making sure they all gel and work together in a good way.</p>
<p><strong>Was there any inciting inspiration that spawned those towns for you?</strong></p>
<p>It's a mix of things. As I said before, I'd start with a map, design the world, and we would lay out where the towns would go. A lot of that I was doing myself early on. Then I'd work with design on what would work for those locations.</p>
<p>If I jump back to Oblivion, we had a map made, and I drew maps and layouts of all the towns to get ready for the team to work on. Some of that just comes from liking worldbuilding and trying to think of what these things could be. It's almost like being a dungeon master from when you played <strong>D&amp;D</strong> as a kid, but in a professional setting.</p>
<p>With Skyrim, we have awesome concept artists who start painting and drawing, and then the team starts to build it. It becomes a much more collaborative effort. It starts with a few small seeds of things, some ideas, and then we're working with a big team to make it all happen.</p>
<figure data-uuid="a64318c6d508a"><a title="Skyrim - Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a64318c6d508a/skyrim-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Bethesda</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>And are those ideas still spawning? What else would you like to do in this world in the future?</strong></p>
<p>Ha ha, trick question! There's a lot. All I can say is, yeah, we're working on new things, very, very excited about it, but unfortunately, can't talk about any of that just yet.</p>
<p>But I will say this, I described how we make games as an obsession which never turns off. It seeps into everything. You're out in the world, and you see something cool, it's like, 'Hey, this view, these trees look really amazing. Let's make a mental note, we should recreate that.' It's a weird obsession with getting into the details of life and then how you can bring that to a game and make something interesting.</p>
<p>I did a lot of photogrammetry scanning of rocks and dirt for Starfield — I mean, hundreds of pieces of rock and dirt. I did some travelling and went to Hawaii, and scanned volcanic rock and stuff. But I think it comes from a fundamental excitement of how everything can be interesting if you really pay attention to it and think about how that works, and then recreating that in a virtual world. I think it brings something to it. Everyone here becomes little dungeon masters over our worlds. You research how smithing works or how people fish in real life, so you're making these observations, condensing them, and recreating them into a fantastical setting.</p>
<p>It really just comes from a fascination with life and trying to make something that other people are going to enjoy from that.</p>
<p><strong>That is a very wholesome and somewhat poetic way of dodging the initial question! [laughs]</strong></p>
<p>Oh yes, and we may be doing that again on a future project. There's your answer, right? [laughs]</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Our thanks to Matt for taking the time to talk to us, and to Samuel at Heaven Media for setting the discussion up.</em></p>
<p><em>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Anniversary Edition is now available on Switch 2 for <strong>£52.99</strong> (or your regional equivalent). Those with the Anniversary Edition already installed on Switch 1 can upgrade to the S2 version for free, or you can upgrade from the base game to the Anniversary Edition for <strong>£17.99</strong>.</em></p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:151222,171410 @ 1765296934 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/its-a-bit-of-a-joke-at-this-point-skyrim-dev-on-returning-for-a-switch-2-re-release]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed IV: Black Flag Remake Seemingly Leaked by PEGI Rating for Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-ubisoft/</link>
            <guid>1377235</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>As far as worst-kept video game industry secrets for 2025 go, the top two would arguably be <a href="https://wccftech.com/hes-really-here-leon-finally-confirmed-for-resident-evil-requiem-with-a-playstation-store-leak/">Leon Kennedy being in Resident Evil Requiem</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-targeting-march-2026-launch/">Ubisoft's upcoming remake of Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag</a>. After the former had a major leak, which practically confirmed what has long been suspected, the latter has matched it with a leak of its own, as a PEGI rating for Assassin's Creed Black Flag Resynced was spotted online.</p>



<p>Initially spotted by <a href="https://x.com/CorkbenYT/status/1998396558027440489">X (formerly Twitter) user and YouTuber CorkbenYT</a>, the <a href="https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=Assassin%27s+Creed+Black+Flag+Resynced">PEGI 18 rating on the official PEGI website is listed as from Ubisoft EMEA</a>. It appears that the "<em>Resynced</em>" subtitle is Ubisoft's play on 'remake' or 'remastered,' and could likely be the new official title for the upcoming remakes that <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-remakes-inbound-ubisoft-boss-confirms/">Ubisoft chief executive officer Yves Guillemot confirmed the company would be doing back in June 2024</a>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>To be clear, while Guillemot confirmed that players can expect to see remakes of older Assassin's Creed titles from Ubisoft, no individual remake has yet been confirmed, though we've had several rumours that the remakes would start with Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag. </p>



<p>Just last month, a new rumour pointed to the <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-targeting-march-2026-launch/">Black Flag remake arriving sometime in March 2026</a>, which would put it just ahead of Ubisoft's new fiscal year, and it would also mean that unless Ubisoft is looking to shadow-drop this remake, it would be announcing it fairly soon.</p>



<p>That announcement could come <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-where-to-watch-all-nominations-what-to-expect/">during The Game Awards later this week</a>, or, since <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-will-not-host-its-annual-ubisoft-forward-event-this-year/">Ubisoft opted to skip 2025 with its Ubisoft Forward event</a>, we could see that event return in the beginning of 2026 with an event in January or February to announce the remake's arrival in March.</p>



<p>At this point, <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-major-changes-rumor/">after this year's rumours</a>, rumours <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-is-reportedly-closer-than-we-thought/">from previous years</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-edward-kenway-actor-threatened-with-lawsuit-by-ubisoft/">comments from Edward Kenway's voice actor</a>, the remake is all but confirmed to be coming. All that's left is for Ubisoft to show it off, and hopefully it does so soon.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-pegi-rating-ubisoft/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bethesda Still Beating Skyrim Like A Dead Horse With Switch 2 Version]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bethesda-skyrim-port-switch-2-upgrade-free-release-date-trailer-dlc-2000651683</link>
            <guid>1377232</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The never-ending mission to port <a href="https://kotaku.com/its-2021-and-bethesda-has-announced-another-skyrim-port-1847521204"><em>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</em> to every possible platform continues</a>. This time, Bethesda has announced that the popular open-world RPG is getting a Switch 2 release. And you don’t have to wait long, as this new port of <em>Skyrim</em> is available now, and is free for previous owners of the game’s Anniversary Edition on Switch.</p> <p>On December 9, Bethesda released a trailer for the Nintendo Switch 2 edition of its <a href="https://kotaku.com/a-rogue-bee-kept-breaking-skyrims-iconic-cart-intro-1847504734">classic 2011 RPG, <em>Skyrim</em></a>. And yup, that sure looks like <em>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</em>, a game that feels like it has always been a part of my life and which is visually aging worse than I expected.</p>

  <p>The Switch 2 version of <em>Skyrim: Anniversary Edition</em> will cost you $60. If you already own the original Switch version of <em>Skyrim Anniversary Edition</em>, you can download the Switch 2 version for free. If instead you own the older, non-<em>Anniversary Edition</em> version of <em>Skyrim</em> on Switch (yes, there are multiple versions of the game on most platforms now), you’ll need to pay $20 to upgrade.</p>

 <p>So what do you get in this new version of <em>Skyrim</em> on Switch 2?<a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/fGtFCgI7J9FL3l6oi9j3B/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-anniversary-edition-out-now-on-nintendo-switch-2"> Well, Bethesda claims</a> that its popular RPG loads faster and has better performance on Nintendo’s new console when compared to how it ran on the OG Switch. It also boasts enhanced resolution and DLSS anti-aliasing. And yes, it supports Switch 2 mouse controls, motion controls, and Amiibo, and features the old <em>Legend of Zelda</em> exclusive cosmetic DLC seen in the old Switch port.</p> <p>Did the world need yet another way to play <em>Skyrim</em> in 2025? Probably not. But I bet this is going to sell really well, and I can’t wait to write about Skyr<em>i</em>m being ported to the PlayStation 6 in a few years. Meanwhile, we’ll still get to play <em>The </em><em>Elder Scrolls 6…</em>eventually.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bethesda-skyrim-port-switch-2-upgrade-free-release-date-trailer-dlc-2000651683]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anker Is Clearly Taking No Margin on Its Nano Power Bank as It Returns at Its Lowest Price for the Holidays]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/anker-is-clearly-taking-no-margin-on-its-nano-power-bank-as-it-returns-at-its-lowest-price-for-the-holidays-2000649289</link>
            <guid>1377229</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Black Friday and Cyber Monday are officially behind us. It was a week-long celebration of discounts and offers across every category you could possibly think of. Missed grabbing something? Don’t worry. There are new deals for holidays.</p>
<p>Apple users still looking to treat themselves to a reliable power solution without the typical cable mess should consider grabbing the ultra-slim. 5,000mAh Anker Nano power bank. I<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6310/">t usually retails for $55, but thanks to Amazon holiday deal, you can snap it up for just $41 right now, but only if you act fast.</a> The discount applies to all color options, so you can pick the one that complements your phone. Got an iPhone 16 in the stunning Desert Titanium? Go for the golden or the classic black version. Have an all-black model? Add some pop of color to it with the white or green power bank! Be sure to nab the deal quick, as these leftover discounts expire soon. We’re not expecting these to last more than a few more hours.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6310/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Attaches to Your Phone, Plus Supports Wired Charging</h2>
<p>It’s (mainly) a wireless power bank, featuring an ultra-slim design. At just 0.3 inches thin, it supports Qi2 certification and snaps at the back of your phone to deliver power on the go. Its 15W output is enough to juice your device up without waiting too long. You can expect an iPhone 16 Pro to go from 0 to 25% in just over 40 minutes. We won’t exactly label it as “ultra-fast”, but considering how it becomes a part of your phone and doesn’t make you feel like you’re carrying an extra accessory when out and about, it’s not too bad. The bulky versions offering better speeds are heavier and a bit inconvenient to carry around, so if ease of use and portability are what you’re after, it’s worth it.</p>
<p>Charging may stop automatically when your phone hits 80%, to preserve the battery and prevent overheating. Once your device cools down, the power bank gets back to work. To get you the best of both worlds, it also supports USB-C fast charging, which can get an iPhone 17 from 0 to 25% in 35 minutes. Recharging the power bank itself won’t take forever either. It’s capable of hitting 100% in just under two hours.</p>



<p>Reliability comes from graphene cooling, dual NTC chips, and smart heat control that Anker has packed it with. It says under 104°F, which is 14 degrees cooler than the industry standard for safer charging. Compatibility-wise, it plays nicely with iPhone Series 12 through 17. It won’t work with an iPhone 16e or iPhone SE Series, though. Best of all, you can even top your AirPods using the charger; great for non-stop jamming on the road. The box comes with the power bank itself, USB-C to USB-C charging cable, welcome guide, and a 24-month warranty for some extra peace of mind.</p>
<p>All in all, if you’ve been looking for a reliable, fuss-free charging solution that’s super easy to carry around, this Anker Nano power bank offers all that and more. It becomes a part of your phone to provide it the power it needs, plus supports wired charging for when you want to prioritize speeds. This deal brings its price down to just $41, but it expires soon. It was a part of the Amazon’s holiday deals, the discount won’t be around for long either. Act fast before that happens!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6310/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/anker-is-clearly-taking-no-margin-on-its-nano-power-bank-as-it-returns-at-its-lowest-price-for-the-holidays-2000649289]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saros Getting ‘New Look’ at The Game Awards 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/saros-getting-new-look-at-the-game-awards-2025/</link>
            <guid>1377223</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>PlayStation has just confirmed that players will receive a new look at Saros at The Game Awards 2025 on December 11. </p>



<p>Saros is the next sci-fi shooter from the hands of Housemarque, the team responsible for bringing us games like Returnal, Nex Machina, Matterfall, and more. They provided players with a look at the title’s gameplay during <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/saros-gameplay-release-trailer-state-of-play-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">September’s State of Play event</a> and have now confirmed a new look at the title for TGA. </p>







<h2 id="h-saros-pre-order-announcement-expected-at-the-game-awards">Saros Pre-Order Announcement Expected at The Game Awards</h2>



<p>PlayStation confirmed Saros’s presence at The Game Awards 2025 through a new post on their <a href="https://x.com/PlayStation/status/1998407291754729536" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> account (formerly Twitter). The post says that players will receive a “new look” for the title, but doesn’t explain what that means. We could receive a new gameplay trailer or a trailer focusing on the narrative bit as well. Some players are also speculating that pre-orders will open that day, as the game was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/saros-has-been-rated-in-taiwan-pre-orders-expected-imminently/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rated in Taiwan</a> recently. </p>



<p>Saros is an entirely new IP from Housemarqye which focuses on a “haunting story of a lost off-world colony on Carcosa under an ominous eclipse.” The key difference between Saros and Returnal gameplay is the presence of permanent resources and progression, which makes every death valuable. Which means that even though the world will change after each death, players can come back stronger with the ability to choose and permanently upgrade their loadout from an evolving set of weapons and suit parts.</p>







<p>In other news, a new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-the-game-awards-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tomb Raider title</a> will be revealed at The Game Awards, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-the-game-awards-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight</a> will appear at the event as well. What are your thoughts on Saros getting a ‘new look’ at The Game Awards? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-resynced-appears/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Resynced appearing on the PEGI ratings site</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/saros-getting-new-look-at-the-game-awards-2025/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Fortnite Ninjago Update Brings Human Versions Of Ninjago Characters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-fortnite-ninjago-update-brings-human-versions-of-ninjago-characters/1100-6536783/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1377220</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536783">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Lego Fortnite Odyssey is getting a Ninjago-themed makeover on Thursday, and for the very first time Epic Games will offer Fortnite versions of Lego characters--with Kai, Cole, Zane, and Jay from the Ninjago TV series all getting human-style Fortnite skins.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UYzJvHNmC6A" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UYzJvHNmC6A" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Kai will actually be the subject of the next Lego Pass--buying the pass for 1,400 V-Bucks, or unlocking it via Fortnite Crew, will instantly unlock both the Lego and Fortnite varieties for Kai. Progressing through the pass from there with XP in any Fortnite experience will grant you a number of Ninjago-themed builds that you can use wherever you like in Lego Fortnite Odyssey, or on your home lot in Lego Fortnite Brick Life.</p><p>The rest of the Ninjago gang will be available in the item shop on Thursday, and you'll be able to buy them individually or in a big bundle that includes all three and their accompanying accessories. Where are Lloyd and Nya, the other two members of the ninja squad from the show? We don't know, but don't count out the possibility they'll be added later--especially since the trailer description teases another major Ninjago update in 2026.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619700-legopasskaioutfit.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4619700" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619700-legopasskaioutfit.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4619700"></a><figcaption>Kai from Ninjago is becoming fully human for the first time in Fortnite.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619700-legopasskaioutfit.jpg"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619702-dragonenemy.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619703-icesanctumscreenshot.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619704-lightningtemplescreenshot.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619705-earthtemplescreenshot.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619706-legopasskaioutfit.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619707-premiumrewards-builds.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619708-legofortniteninjago.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4619702,1300-4619703,1300-4619704,1300-4619705,1300-4619706,1300-4619707,1300-4619708" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1757/17577455/4619702-dragonenemy.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1757/17577455/4619703-icesanctumscreenshot.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1757/17577455/4619704-lightningtemplescreenshot.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1757/17577455/4619705-earthtemplescreenshot.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1757/17577455/4619706-legopasskaioutfit.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1757/17577455/4619707-premiumrewards-builds.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1757/17577455/4619708-legofortniteninjago.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619702-dragonenemy.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619703-icesanctumscreenshot.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619704-lightningtemplescreenshot.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619705-earthtemplescreenshot.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619706-legopasskaioutfit.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619707-premiumrewards-builds.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4619708-legofortniteninjago.jpg"></figure><p>On the gameplay side of this week's update, Lego Fortnite Odyssey is getting a new Ninjago island this week with new weapons, like Nunchuks and Shurikens, as well as new elemental abilities that you'll need to master by questing to Elemental Sanctums around the island. Be warned that when you first load into Lego Fortnite Odyssey after the update you'll start on the Ninjago island, you may want to make sure all your stuff is in safe zones before then.</p><p>With Chapter 7 launching last week alongside a new music pass, Fortnite is just about done making news this year. The December 11 update will include the last new major additions to Epic's metaverse in 2025, with Lego Ninjago, Fortnite OG Season 7, Playboi Carti's new activation, and this year's Winterfest celebration, which should come with free skins.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-fortnite-ninjago-update-brings-human-versions-of-ninjago-characters/1100-6536783/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two hires Perfect Dark studio leads for new team]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/take-two-hires-perfect-dark-studio-leads-for-new-studio</link>
            <guid>1377217</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">December 9, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>3 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Take-Two, the parent company of Rockstar Games, Zynga, and 2K, has hired two key developers who were working on the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Perfect Dark</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> reboot to start a new studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Via LinkedIn, Brian Horton, former creative director at The Initiative, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/brianhortonart_happy-to-announce-i-joined-2k-as-vp-head-activity-7403908881246318592-Unhq">announced</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> his new role as VP, head of creative at 2K at a new studio with Darrell Gallagher.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Gallagher, former studio head at The Initiative, has joined 2K as SVP, studio head, where he'll &nbsp;be "building a new studio and leading an ambitious opportunity unlike anything I've taken on before."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I've spent my career believing in what's possible when great people come together with a bold vision. I can't wait to get started with the exceptional team at 2K!" he </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/darrell-gallagher-278914_im-excited-to-share-that-i-will-be-joining-activity-7403902973464014848-HuIT">wrote on LinkedIn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The news comes three months after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-02/-perfect-dark-developer-lays-off-staff-after-funding-deal-falls-through">Bloomberg</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> broke the news that Embracer had come close to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-crystal-dynamics-layoffs-came-after-developers-scrambled-to-save-perfect-dark">striking a deal</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in which Take-Two would purchase the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Perfect Dark</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> reboot from Xbox, which owned the rights. According to the report, Take-Two would then fund and publish the game.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to anonymous sources speaking to Bloomberg, the talks collapsed at least in part because the companies involved were unable to come to terms over long-term ownership of the Perfect Dark franchise.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Xbox closed The Initiative back in July">Xbox closed The Initiative back in July</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Initiative, a Santa Monica-based studio tasked with reviving the Perfect Dark series in 2018, was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-xbox-closes-the-initiative-and-cancels-its-perfect-dark-reboot">shuttered</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in July. The closure took place in the midst of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-xbox-begins-latest-round-of-mass-layoffs-with-cuts-at-king-and-zenimax">mass layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> at Xbox and across Microsoft, during which </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-xbox-begins-latest-round-of-mass-layoffs-with-cuts-at-king-and-zenimax">9,000 people</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> were affected.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/paramount-bid-for-warner-bros-backed-by-ea-acquisition-group-members" target="_self" data-discover="true">Paramount bid for Warner Bros. backed by EA acquisition group investors</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to an email sent to employees by Matt Booty, head of Xbox Game Studios, The Initiative was shut down to "adjust priorities and focus resources to set up our teams for greater success within a changing industry landscape."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Development on the reboot was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/perfect-dark-reboot-initiative-dev-clashes">reportedly turbulent</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as a result of clashes between developers and lack of clear vision from studio leadership. As of 2025, the game would have been in development for 7 years (IGN reported that the game was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xboxs-perfect-dark-reboot-is-still-years-away">effectively rebooted</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in 2022, and was years away from release).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In addition, Crystal Dynamics, developer of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Marvel's Avengers</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tomb Raider,</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> which was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/microsoft-taps-crystal-dynamics-to-co-develop-i-perfect-dark-i-reboot">appointed to co-develop</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Perfect Dark</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in 2021, has also been caught up in layoffs.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Embracer-owned studio made </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-owned-crystal-dynamics-confirms-another-round-of-layoffs">three rounds of job cuts</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> this year, the latest taking place this past November, which affected "fewer than 30 people" across various departments.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Crystal deeply thanks all of those impacted for their incredible talent, hard work, and dedication, which helped shape the studio in so many ways. We are committed to offering our fullest resources and support to you during this transition," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/crystal-dynamics_today-weve-made-the-difficult-but-necessary-activity-7394805539140169729-lwXF/">read a statement</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> at the time.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/kingdom-of-gaming-event-to-debut-in-saudi-arabia-with-state-backing" target="_self" data-discover="true">Kingdom of Gaming event to debut in Saudi Arabia with state backing</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"To our players—as the realities of the industry continue to evolve, we've made these painful choices as a way to optimize the continued development of our flagship Tomb Raider game, as well as shaping the rest of the studio to make new games for the future."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/take-two-hires-perfect-dark-studio-leads-for-new-studio]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Switch 2 Version Out Now]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/09/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-switch-2-version-out-now</link>
            <guid>1377211</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>One of Bethesda's most critically acclaimed games, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</a>, is the latest game to receive an upgraded version for Nintendo's new, more powerful console. The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim arrived on Switch in 2017, complete with some exclusive items inspired by the Legend of Zelda franchise. Today, Bethesda surprise-launched the Switch 2 version of Skyrim Anniversary Edition.</p><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/2021/11/05/skyrim-anniversary-edition-price-revealed-alongside-upgrade-path-option-for-special">The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Anniversary Edition</a> gathers the base game and its three official expansions. Today's new Switch 2 edition adds better resolution, faster load times, more optimized performance, and Joy-Con 2 mouse support. Those new features join the existing Switch-exclusive features, including motion controls, Amiibo support, and items from <a href="https://gameinformer.com/games/the_legend_of_zelda_breath_of_the_wild/b/switch/archive/2017/03/02/game-informer-the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-switch-review.aspx">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a>, including the Master Sword, Hylian Shield, and Champion's Tunic. The Anniversary Edition also includes access to user-generated Creations Club content.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fIntv_QfQjU"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fIntv_QfQjU" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Anniversary Edition for Switch 2 costs $60. If you own The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Anniversary Edition on Switch, the upgrade to the Switch 2 version is free. If you only own the base edition of Skyrim on Switch, you can purchase a $20 upgrade to the Anniversary Edition to also receive the Switch 2 upgrade.</p><p>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim originally launched on November 11, 2011. To this day, it's one of the most critically acclaimed video games of all time, with a Metacritic average score of 96, including a <a href="https://gameinformer.com/games/the_elder_scrolls_v_skyrim/b/pc/archive/2011/11/20/an-rpg-worth-shouting-about.aspx">9.5 from <em>Game Informer</em></a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/09/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-switch-2-version-out-now]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video game workers across Europe fight back against exploitation, AI and layoffs in "historic milestone" for union efforts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/video-game-workers-europe-fight-back-against-exploitation-ai-layoffs-historic-milestone-union-efforts</link>
            <guid>1377208</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"We can do something, and we will."</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Paris_Summit_2025_Cropped-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Paris_Summit_2025_Cropped-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Paris_Summit_2025_Cropped-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Paris_Summit_2025_Cropped-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Paris_Summit_2025_Cropped-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Paris_Summit_2025_Cropped-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Paris_Summit_2025_Cropped-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Paris_Summit_2025_Cropped-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Paris_Summit_2025_Cropped-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>IWGB</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Video game workers from multiple unions across Europe have released a joint statement pledging a "united front" against industry exploitation.</p>
<p>Last month, delegates from six game worker unions met in Paris for a summit hosted by French union Syndicat des Travailleureuses du Jeu Vidéo (STJV) to discuss the challenges facing the games industry, and are now demanding better working conditions without threat of layoffs, free from AI, and free from "authoritarian mismanagement".</p>
<p>"Our jobs are under threat, we are denied a voice in our workplaces, and policies such as 'return to office' and tools like generative AI are being forced upon us, even though they degrade our working conditions," the <a href="https://www.gameworkers.co.uk/blog/">joint statement reads</a>.</p>
<p>"Multinational companies already operate globally. Game workers already collaborate transnationally. It follows, then, that unions must also organise across borders."</p>
<p>The statement comes from unions in the UK (IWGB Game Workers), France (STJV), Ireland (Game Workers Unite Ireland), Germany (ver.di Game Devs Roundtable), Italy (FIOM-CGIL Milan Work Council) and Spain (Coordinadora Sindical del Videojuego). It follows joint meetings and a solidarity protest outside the Paris office of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/rockstar-games">Rockstar Games</a>' parent company <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/take-two-interactive">Take-Two Interactive</a>, after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-developer-rockstar-accused-of-union-busting-after-it-fires-dozens-of-developers">31 members were dismissed from the Grand Theft Auto maker</a>.</p><p>"From these meetings, one thing became absolutely clear: that together, workers can transform their jobs, their careers, and their lives for the better," the statement continues. "We can do something, and we will. We vow to increase cooperation between our unions in both the short and long term, and to stay united in front of all that's going on in our industry and the world."</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>IWGB Union</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For the past few years, mass layoffs have rocked the video game industry worldwide. <a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/vg-layoffs/Archive/2025">According to one tally</a>, 10.5k employees lost their jobs in 2023, a further 14.6k lost their jobs in 2024, and so far this year an estimated 5.3k have lost their jobs. That's on top of stories such as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mindseye-boss-alleges-saboteurs-within-the-company-were-behind-its-poor-reception-according-to-new-report">reported mismanagement at MindsEye studio Build A Rocket Boy</a>, as well as widespread use of AI technology - EA CEO Andrew Wilson, for instance, stated <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ai-is-the-very-core-of-our-business-says-ea-ceo">AI is "the very core of our business"</a>.</p>
<p>"This is a historic milestone for the video game industry," said IWGB Game Workers delegate Scott Alsworth. "For the first time, we are seeing game workers organising across borders, coordinating campaigns, and standing together in solidarity. For years, there has been a collective sense of isolation, a climate of fear - many have felt powerless and divided in the face of seemingly unstoppable conglomerates. But now, we're marshalling politics in the workplace and learning over again, in adversity, the struggles of the past. That there is indeed strength in unity."</p>
<p>The IWGB Game Workers union has been instrumental in supporting the Rockstar employees who were controversially dismissed back in October. The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/unacceptable-and-unlawful-gta-6-developer-rockstar-hit-with-legal-claim-from-uk-trade-union-following-alleged-unfair-dismissal-of-staff">union has launched a legal claim against alleged unfair dismissal</a>, which then <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rockstars-controversial-dismissal-of-31-employees-is-such-a-big-deal-its-made-its-way-to-uk-parliament">made its way to UK Parliament</a>.</p>
<p>Later, a report claimed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-rockstar-games-staff-were-fired-for-sharing-internal-company-messages-on-an-employee-and-union-only-discord-server-new-report-suggests">Rockstar employees were dismissed for sharing internal company messages on an employee and union-only Discord server</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  




  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/video-game-workers-europe-fight-back-against-exploitation-ai-layoffs-historic-milestone-union-efforts]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>