<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 14:41:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune: Awakening Shows Off Its Extensive Base Building]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dune-awakening-shows-off-its-extensive-base-building-feature/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakening-shows-off-its-extensive-base-building.1177518/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dune-awakening-shows-off-its-extensive-base-building-feature/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Funcom has shared a new Dune: Awakening trailer entirely focused on the game's extensive base-building feature, which improves upon the systems seen in Conan Exiles. Here's the transcribed overview provided by the narrating voice:</p>
<p><em>On Arrakis, exposure to the raw, unbridled elements is death. But walls alone will not save you from the maelstrom. You need power and the engineering of CHOAM to raise a protective shield against the storm. Without such protection, even the strongest walls will erode and fail in time, as will anything left in the open. Your exposed vehicle is beyond repair, but a lesson is learned.</em></p>
<p><em>You need better protection against the dangers of Arrakis. It's time to upgrade your base. Base construction and expansion can be done alone or together with others. With Celo projections, building as a group is easy. To further customize your base, you must align yourself with one of the warring Great Houses. Displaying your allegiance through their unique architecture, the Atreides welcome your aid. Swear your fealty to the Atreides and rise to greatness on Arrakis.</em></p>
<p><em>Your base serves as a reflection of both your influence and your allegiance to a faction. The safety provided by your base allows you to craft powerful new tools, technologies, and vehicles. Here we are crafting a ground car. Once each part of your vehicle is assembled, you can install modules to enhance its specialization further and customize its appearance.&nbsp; By aligning with the Atreides, you have earned the option to craft their faction-specific ground car. </em></p>
<p><em>On the horizon, another sandstorm approaches, but this time you are prepared. Your base is equipped with powerful shields for protection and a custom-built garage that will keep all your vehicles safe from the raging storm. The shields are vital, but they come with a cost. With a construction of this size, the Emperor demands taxes to keep your base running.</em></p>
<p><em>You will construct grand bases. And in Dune: Awakening, you will have the option to share them with others if you choose. All your creations can be recorded as blueprints. These can be shared with allies or even bought and sold on the Exchange. Anyone holding a blueprint can instantly</em><br>
<em>place a projection of the entire building and construct an exact copy for themselves. Dune: Awakening's building system allows for limitless creativity.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Dune: Awakening Building Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hO9RUC2HBcQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The trailer also shows off some truly impressive bases. In the press beta test, there wasn't anywhere near enough time to build something so grand, but I still got a glimpse at the very solid building system. After <a href="https://wccftech.com/dune-awakening-beta-impressions-desert-survival/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">playing several hours of the game</a>, my doubts certainly lie elsewhere.</p>
<p>If you wish to learn more about Dune: Awakening's crafting, building, and other features, Funcom held a more than two-hour-long developer live stream yesterday. The YouTube recording can be found <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_k0389iSNIw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>Dune: Awakening launches on June 10 for PC after <a href="https://wccftech.com/dune-awakening-has-been-delayed-to-june-5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a slight delay</a>. A large-scale beta test will take place between May 9 and May 12, during which many players will be able to test it out before the release.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Following ‘Mixed’ Steam Reception to Game of Thrones: Kingsroad Early Access, It Has a Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/following-mixed-steam-reception-to-game-of-thrones-kingsroad-early-access-it-has-a-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/following-%E2%80%98mixed%E2%80%99-steam-reception-to-game-of-thrones-kingsroad-early-access-it-has-a-release-date.1177512/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/following-mixed-steam-reception-to-game-of-thrones-kingsroad-early-access-it-has-a-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/game-of-thrones-kingsroad">Game of Thrones: Kingsroad</a> is set to leave early access and launch on May 21, Netmarble and Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment have announced.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The action-adventure role-playing game based on George R. R. Martin’s much-loved fantasy universe is set for release on all mobile platforms as well as on PC via Steam, the Epic Games Store, and Windows.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Game of Thrones: Kingsroad launched in early access form in March, and has a ‘mixed’ user review rating on Steam. Most of the negative reviews revolve around its monetization, which some have called “greedy.” “It’s like a mobile game on steroids and kinda not in a good way,” reads the current ‘most helpful’ review on Valve’s platform.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In a release date FAQ <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3183280/view/536600287259918993" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted to Steam</a>, Netmarble addressed the expected gap between the progression of early access and new players. It said that Game of Thrones: Kingsroad is “fundamentally designed with a focus on single-player gameplay,” and that it had worked to “minimize any feelings of imbalance or unfairness that might arise from differences in progression.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Testing was conducted to improve the game, the development team continued, "to improve the game and make it more enjoyable and accessible for everyone."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We encourage all players to focus on the inherent fun of progressing through the later stages and reaching the endgame content, rather than comparing progress with other characters,” Netmarble suggested.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Netmarble went on to apologize for its prior communication and patches, which it admitted were “somewhat lacking.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Moving forward, we are committed to more frequent and transparent communication through regular AMA sessions and Developer Notes,” it added. “We kindly ask for your continued anticipation and support as we approach the official launch.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As you’d expect from a game like this, there’s a premium Founder’s Pack that offers Early Access and other exclusive in-game content. Mobile players can pre-register through the App Store and Google Play store on iOS and Android devices ahead of the grand launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sea of Stars free DLC ‘Throes of the Watchmaker’ launches May 20]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/sea-of-stars-free-dlc-throes-of-the-watchmaker-launches-may-20</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sea-of-stars-free-dlc-%E2%80%98throes-of-the-watchmaker%E2%80%99-launches-may-20.1177509/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/sea-of-stars-free-dlc-throes-of-the-watchmaker-launches-may-20<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Over eight hours of new content.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Sea of Stars [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sea-of-stars">Sea of Stars</a></em> free downloadable content “Throes of the Watchmaker” will launch on May 20 for all platforms, developer <a title="Companies > Sabotage Studio [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sabotage-studio">Sabotage Studio</a> announced. It will adds over eight hours of new areas, music, dungeons, mini-games, enemies, bosses, and puzzles, including new playable classes for Valere and Zale, and new playable character Arty. <span id="more-962096"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the content, via Sabotage Studio:</p><blockquote><p>“Throes of the Watchmaker” returns to one of the most intriguing characters encountered in <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ main <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,246 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>—the genius inventor known as the Watchmaker, architect of the Clockwork Castle and creator of Wheels, a tabletop pastime enjoyed throughout Sea of Stars’ world. The downloadable content explores a fascinating invention by the Watchmaker, the miniature clockwork world of Horloge, a land threatened by a cursed carnival. Zale and Valere must adapt to Horloge’s peculiar rules to fully realize their mastery of Sun and Moon powers, the abilities they’ve refined since the beginning of <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ central journey to stop the Fleshmancer with Eclipse Magic.</p><p>This post-game bonus adventure downloadable content is designed around a self-contained progression loop featuring completely new classes, skills and combos to master for Zale, who trades his signature sword to become a skillful juggler, and Valere, who sets aside her trusty staff to dazzle as an acrobat. Throughout “Throes of the Watchmaker,” the duo fights alongside a new playable party member in Artificer, a mechanized, laser-wielding sharpshot.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_962097"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p>“Throes of the Watchmaker” features never-before-seen areas, puzzles and enemies throughout a compelling storyline wholly unique from <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ core adventure. “Throes of the Watchmaker”‘s cinematic budget is equivalent to that of the main game, allowing Sabotage to richly realize key narrative moments and deliver a dense, delightful new tale spanning eight hours of new content. Crafted as a quest to enjoy after completing <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ critical path, “Throes of the Watchmaker” is the perfect reason to begin a New Game+ playthrough or dive into the world of <em>Sea of Stars</em> for the first time ahead of this all-new journey arrives on May 20.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>A stirring new score from <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ Lead Composer, Eric W. Brown, accents the journey, with additional original songs composed in collaboration with Yasunori Mitsuda (<em><a title="Games > Chrono Trigger [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/chrono-trigger">Chrono Trigger</a></em>) who returns as a guest composer.</p><p>“Throes of the Watchmaker” follows “Dawn of Equinox,” a separate free update which added local <a title="Genres > Co-Op [257 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play, combat refinements, and more to <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ celebrated campaign.</p></blockquote><p><em>Sea of Stars</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,955 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,939 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,038 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1244090/Sea_of_Stars/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/sea-of-stars/april-30-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>DLC “Throes of the Watchmaker” Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Sea of Stars: Throes of the Watchmaker DLC | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tgFi2jXwzVI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Doesn't Need Another Trailer, Argues Former Rockstar Dev]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-doesnt-need-another-trailer-argues-former-rockstar-dev/1100-6531225/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-doesnt-need-another-trailer-argues-former-rockstar-dev.1177506/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-doesnt-need-another-trailer-argues-former-rockstar-dev/1100-6531225/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531225">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Every single day seems to bring new speculation about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/">Grand Theft Auto VI</a>--whether it's rumors about a release date, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-costing-100-could-reward-players-too-analysts-argue/1100-6529948/">$100 price tag</a>, or an impending second trailer. But former Rockstar developer Obbe Vermeij believes GTA VI doesn't need another teaser video.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://x.com/ObbeVermeij/status/1917025732074655981" rel="nofollow ">On X</a>, Vermeij explained that nothing else is required from Rockstar to promote GTA VI. "If it was my call, I wouldn't release any additional trailers," said the developer, who worked on GTA IV, San Andreas, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-vice-city-graphics-qanda/1100-2881042/">Vice City</a>. "There is more than enough hype around VI, and the element of surprise is going to make the release only bigger as an event."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/ObbeVermeij/status/1917025732074655981" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Also:<br>If it was my call I wouldn’t release any additional trailers.<br>There is more than enough hype around VI and the element of surprise is going to make the release only bigger as an event.</p>  — Obbe Vermeij (@ObbeVermeij) <a href="https://twitter.com/ObbeVermeij/status/1917025732074655981?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 29, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">A person on <a href="https://x.com/JoeDannyMan/status/1917032176706851123" rel="nofollow ">the social media app</a> responded that all Rockstar needs to do now is announce a release date. <a href="https://x.com/ObbeVermeij/status/1917032861003354335" rel="nofollow ">Vermeij agreed</a>, noting "it would be a boss move." Take-Two <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-release-date-remaining-a-mystery-could-be-on-purpose/1100-6530484/">seems to be keeping GTA VI's release date a mystery on purpose</a> and so far hasn't delivered any additional promo materials outside <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/grand-theft-auto-6-trailer-breakdown-easter-eggs-references-and-teases/2900-4973/">the first trailer</a>. There hasn't even been a new screenshot for the open-world game.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-trailer-2025-release/1100-6518649/">GTA VI's first trailer debuted</a> in December 2023, confirming the game will take place in Vice City and the surrounding state of Leonida. Earlier this month, the video <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-trailer-hits-massive-milestones/1100-6531085/">hit some massive milestones</a>: over 250 million views and more than 1 million comments. It's now been over 16 months without a second teaser video: <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-wait-for-gta-6s-second-trailer-just-broke-a-sad-record/1100-6528595/">a wait that hasn't gone unnoticed</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Take-Two is still <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-still-on-track-for-release-in-fall-2025/1100-6529307/">planning for GTA VI to release this fall</a>, though there is always the possibility Rockstar needs more time developing the highly anticipated game. Gearbox Software boss Randy Pitchford has just come out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-boss-insists-gta-6-is-not-reason-the-games-release-date-changed/1100-6531221/">to say Borderlands 4's release date wasn't moved up because of GTA VI</a>. The looter-shooter is now arriving September 12 (11 days earlier), with people <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-release-date-might-be-coming-into-focus/1100-6529480/">theorizing then that GTA VI could launch in October</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['It was really wearing people down:' The funding challenges that followed 'runaway success' Another Crab's Treasure]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-was-really-wearing-people-down-the-funding-challenges-that-followed-runaway-success-another-crab-s-treasure</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-was-really-wearing-people-down-the-funding-challenges-that-followed-runaway-success-another-crabs-treasure.1177497/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-was-really-wearing-people-down-the-funding-challenges-that-followed-runaway-success-another-crab-s-treasure<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Indie studio Aggro Crab has lamented the funding maelstrom that pushed the team to scale down its ambitions despite the "runaway success" of its latest release, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Another Crab's Treasure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">During a chat at GDC 2025, studio director Caelan Pollock explained </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Another Crab's Treasure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> sold "many multiples of what our bare minimum [sales forecast] would have been" after shifting between 600,000 to 700,000 units on a budget of $1.2 million, but noted that "huge success" (which included an Xbox Game Pass deal) hasn't made negotiating with investors any easier.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Another Crab's Treasure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was financed off the back of a single investment from Kowloon and was self-published. Pollock described that approach as more "typical," but feels the financing opportunities available to developers have become increasingly muddled over the past year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pollock said Aggro Crab didn't think securing funding for its next project would be "that much of a problem" given it had delivered the goods last time out, and explained the studio was "all guns blazing" when it came to pitching investors.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Aggro Crab had been seeking between $3 million to $4 million in funding this time around, which Pollock explained would have allowed the studio to really "swing for the fences" and pay its modest team (of around 12 full-time employees) a better wage. The response from prospective investors was lukewarm to say the least.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bloober-ceo-creating-a-safe-sustainable-workplace-takes-priority-in-studio-leadership" target="_self" data-discover="true">Bloober CEO: creating a 'safe,' sustainable workplace takes priority in studio leadership</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Time and time again, the studio was told it was asking for too much cash, leaving them at a creative and existential crossroads. "One of the biggest challenges of being a studio that works off project investment—which is many indie studios—is that the window is always shifting in terms of what people are willing to fund," explained Pollock.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I think it comes as a shock to some people to hear that there are budgets that are too low for some investors, as well as budgets that are too high. So, going into funding </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Another Crab's Treasure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> we increased our budget for that reason. We said lets put more into marketing, lets do real localization, QA—the sort of stuff that a very scrappy indie wouldn't necessarily do."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pollock described navigating around those perpetually shifting goalposts as "frustrating," but accepted it's simply the reality of doing business. Right now, he believes the overall funding pot available to developers is getting smaller, but suggests there are also fewer investors willing to bet big on "ambitious, higher-budget triple-I" projects.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Instead, they want to ostensibly minimize risk by investing in multiple, smaller projects instead of taking a punt on a larger-scale prospect—even when it's being pitched by a developer that just hit a home run.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/behind-the-headlines-at-valve-s-rocky-start" target="_self" data-discover="true">Behind the headlines at Valve's rocky start</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Aggro Crab believes smaller projects can also bring &quot;peace of mind&quot;">Aggro Crab believes smaller projects can also bring "peace of mind"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Where does that leave successful teams like Aggro Crab? "What we're doing right now is looking to change strategy and work on smaller games for a while" said Pollock, noting the team believes projects that require around one-year in the development furnace are more viable in the current climate.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a pivot that could also allow the studio to self-fund its work using earnings from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Another Crab's Treasure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. That said, Pollock remains confident Aggro Crab could secure funding for those smaller titles, but feels it's important to give his employees "peace of mind" by budgeting in such a way that projects won't "fall off a cliff" if the company fails to secure external investment.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pollock explained having to downscale their ambitions in the wake of a critical and commercial success like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Another Crab's Treasure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has been a "morale hit," despite some of the upsides.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"For me personally, as a creative, to have really put our all into something super ambitious and for it to have paid off so spectacularly is exhilarating. So a big part of me is like 'damn, I want to just run it back' and create these really ambitious projects with sweeping stories," he explained. "Financially for morale, there are really good things about having a multi-year project because you know where your money is coming from for years—but we were also working on prototyping our third project at the same time as seeking funding and hitting these dead ends. We felt caged by that too."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-microsoft-ea-and-others-unite-to-make-accessibility-messaging-a-priority" target="_self" data-discover="true">Nintendo, Microsoft, EA and others unite to make accessibility messaging a priority</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Conversely, Pollock said it's also liberating to know that if a smaller project doesn't work out, it's not going to bankrupt the team. The issue with a longer three-year production cycle, he acknowledged, is that whatever you bring to market had "better sell." Even if, as Pollock conceded, it does "hurt a little" to perhaps place your magnum opus on hold, there's a sense that might be the safest way forward in an game industry that feels actively hostile to developers.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Creating this monumental piece of work comes second to forming a good team that helps people make a living doing cool work they enjoy," said Pollock. "So I do think we were forced to make the choice to [downsize our next project], but I also think it was the right choice."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our spirits have been raised dramatically since making that decision. During the time we were spending working on this new larger project and jumping around from different funding talks, it was really wearing people down. Now, the new era of Aggro Crab is looking bright."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Angry Birds maker and Sega delay Sonic Rumble release once again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/angry-birds-maker-and-sega-delay-sonic-rumble-release-once-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/angry-birds-maker-and-sega-delay-sonic-rumble-release-once-again.1177494/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/angry-birds-maker-and-sega-delay-sonic-rumble-release-once-again<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sega has delayed the global launch of Sonic Rumble, the mobile and PC party game from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/angry-birds">Angry Birds</a> maker Rovio.</p>
<p>The Sonic Rumble team said "upcoming changes" such as its Rumble Ranking, Crews and Skills features will " fundamentally reshape" the game, and as such it will be postponing the release.</p>
<p>"We want to create a game that evolves and stays fun for months and years to come. To build the kind of high-quality, long-lasting Sonic game our players deserve, we need more time," <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/segas-mobile-party-game-sonic-rumble-lands-release-date">Sega wrote on Steam</a>.</p>
<p>"We know this news may be disappointing, and it wasn't a decision we made lightly. We at Sega share that disappointment, especially because we're making this call so close to the launch timing we had originally hoped for. However, we believe taking this extra time is the right choice for the future of Sonic Rumble."</p>
<p>At the time of writing, Sega has not announced a new launch date for Sonic Rumble, and its sales page simply reads the game is coming "soon".</p>
<p>In the meantime, the team will host a Q&amp;A over on its Discord channel on 2nd May at 2pm UK time. Here, it'll "answer your questions about the new features, the delay, the next steps, and more".</p>
<p>Sonic Rumble will be Rovio's first brand new game since the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-buys-angry-birds-maker-rovio-for-625m">studio was acquired by Sega in 2023</a> for £625m. It's a free-to-play battle royale game where up to 32 players collect rings (I mean, this is a Sonic title, after all) in competitive rounds like those seen in fellow party game <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fall-guys">Fall Guys</a>.</p>
<p>The title was initially set to make its debut sometime during the winter, but this was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sonic-rumble-segas-mobile-party-game-from-angry-birds-studio-delayed-into-spring">delayed until an unspecified spring release window</a>. Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/segas-mobile-party-game-sonic-rumble-lands-release-date">Sega and Rovio set a release date of 8th May</a>, which is - obviously - no longer happening.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stardew Valley creator promises no more updates until Haunted Chocolatier releases]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-creator-promises-no-more-updates-until-haunted-chocolatier-releases</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stardew-valley-creator-promises-no-more-updates-until-haunted-chocolatier-releases.1177491/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-creator-promises-no-more-updates-until-haunted-chocolatier-releases<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Knew you were truffle when you walked in.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>ConcernedApe/Cadbury/Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Solo developer Eric 'ConcernedApe' Barone says he's "committed to not working on Stardew Valley" until he's "done with Haunted Chocolatier"... but, other updates will probably still come after.</p>
<p>Pixelated farming sim Stardew Valley first debuted almost a decade ago, and has since gone from strength to strength. Last year, Barone released Stardew Valley's bumper 1.6 update, which essentially boosted the game to an almost 2.0 status, introducing a vast number of features to the base game such as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valleys-16-update-is-finally-here-with-some-impressively-lengthy-patch-notes">new NPC dialogues, home renovations and turtle pets</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Stardew Valley Multiplayer - THE ONE WHERE JOHNNY EATS AN EGG!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pLHH6x87k6U?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Stardew Valley Multiplayer - THE ONE WHERE JOHNNY EATS AN EGG!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pLHH6x87k6U?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pLHH6x87k6U?autoplay=1" title="Let's Play Stardew Valley Multiplayer - THE ONE WHERE JOHNNY EATS AN EGG!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Let's Play Stardew Valley Multiplayer - THE ONE WHERE JOHNNY EATS AN EGG! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pLHH6x87k6U" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition to Stardew Valley, Barone is also working on his next game, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-creator-reveals-haunted-chocolatier">Haunted Chocolatier, which he announced in 2021</a>. In May of last year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-creator-wont-rush-haunted-chocolatier-better-to-have-a-good-delayed-game-than-a-bad-game-on-time">Barone said he's "not too concerned with the pressure" of releasing Haunted Chocolatier</a>, stating "it's better to have a delayed game that's actually good than a bad game that's on time".</p>
<p>But, while he may not be concerned about the pressure, he of course still does want to get Haunted Chocolatier out there at some point. So, now that the dust is settling on Stardew Valley's 1.6 update, he is shifting his focus over to his next release.</p>
<p>"I do love Stardew Valley and I care about the fans and I want the fans to have a great experience," Barone told <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/life-sim/after-getting-stardew-valley-to-a-good-place-with-update-1-6-eric-barone-is-now-fully-focused-on-his-next-game-im-committed-to-not-working-on-stardew-valley-until-im-done-with-haunted-chocolatier/">PC Gamer</a> during GDC. "So I'm always concerned with Stardew Valley and making sure that it's doing well, and that pulls me away from devoting all my time to Haunted Chocolatier.</p>
<p>"I think at some point I'm going to have to completely cut off everything else. Honestly, I've thought about, maybe I should just go into a cabin in the woods and completely get off the internet, and just say, 'Okay guys, I'll see you in two years. You won't hear from me at all and I'm going to finish this game'."</p>
<p>The developer added he is currently "committed to not working on Stardew Valley until I'm done with Haunted Chocolatier", stating that his farming sim is now in "a good place" for players old and new.</p>
<p>"I think if anyone picks up Stardew Valley for the first time in 2025, I'm very proud of it, and I think they'll have fun with it if they like this kind of game," Barone said. He also noted that he doesn't think he will ever be able to "completely cut off" Stardew Valley, except for maybe when he "[passes] away". Then, we can say the "book is closed". This <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-creator-says-he-doesnt-want-to-definitively-close-the-book-on-its-development-even-12-years-on">echoes comments Barone has made before</a>.</p>
<p>Continuing, Barone said he has been working on Haunted Chocolatier for "a few years", and now "it's like, I look at some of the stuff I did at the beginning and I'm like, 'Oh man, here we go again. I'm gonna have to redo all of this'".</p>
<p>This doesn't mean Barone thinks what he has done is bad, by any means. It's just that, "part of the problem of being, like especially a solo dev, is it takes so long to make a game". Barone said he is "literally a different person in four years", and so his opinions and feelings change.</p>
<p>"My aesthetic sensibilities have evolved," he said. Later, he joked about adding a dentist to Haunted Chocolatier's village, as well as healthy superfood chocs to savour. You can check out the full interview below.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Eric Barone talks Stardew Valley &amp; Haunted Chocolatier | ConcernedApe Interview" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/olf3wAuCfeU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Eric Barone talks Stardew Valley &amp; Haunted Chocolatier | ConcernedApe Interview</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/olf3wAuCfeU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/olf3wAuCfeU?autoplay=1" title="Eric Barone talks Stardew Valley &amp; Haunted Chocolatier | ConcernedApe Interview">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eric Barone talks Stardew Valley &amp; Haunted Chocolatier | ConcernedApe Interview. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=olf3wAuCfeU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In January of this year, Barone revealed that, as of December last year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-continues-its-wholesome-farming-dominance-with-latest-sales-milestone">Stardew Valley had sold in excess of 41m copies across platforms</a>. Of those 41m, over half are on PC, with 26m copies sold. Meanwhile, the Nintendo Switch accounts for 7.9m Stardew Valley sales.</p>
<p>If you still fancy more Stardew Valley news, a new concert <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-symphony-of-seasons-concert-tour-announced-coming-to-the-uk-in-2026">known as Symphony of Seasons</a> was announced in November. The concert tour will be coming to the UK in 2026.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China Hero Project Game Lost Soul Aside Delayed to August]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lost-soul-aside-delayed-august</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/china-hero-project-game-lost-soul-aside-delayed-to-august.1177467/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lost-soul-aside-delayed-august<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Ultizero Games and publisher PlayStation have announced that China Hero Project game&nbsp;<em>Lost Soul Aside&nbsp;</em>has been delayed until summer.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/Lost_Soul_Aside/status/1917433911195353572" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X, Ultizero says that in order to deliver "a high-quality game experience", the game, which was originally due to be released on May 30th, will now be launching on PC and PS5 on August 29th. That, incidentally, means the game has moved from the&nbsp;release date of&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-nighreign-release-date" rel="nofollow">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>&nbsp;</em>to just one day before&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metal-gear-solid-delta-release-date-leak-playstation" rel="nofollow"><em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em></a>.</p>

<p>Ultizero goes on to say that in order to meet the "standards" it's set for itself when it comes to&nbsp;<em>Lost Soul Aside</em>, it needs "some additional time to polish the game".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/lost-soul-aside-delayed-boss.jpg?itok=bI-Hy5cG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/lost-soul-aside-delayed-boss.jpg?itok=hoe2jY-o 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Lost Soul Aside&nbsp;</em>is going to take a little more time to launch.</figcaption></figure><p>The game, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/impressive-one-man-project-lost-soul-aside-will-be-timed-exclusive-for-ps4" rel="nofollow">at least began life</a> as a one-man development project, was originally intended for PS4. It's been in development for some time, but in December last year, it was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lost-soul-aside-release-window-2025" rel="nofollow">finally given a 2025 release window</a>, before a release date of May 30th was subsequently revealed (although it won't be making that date now, it seems).</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Lost Soul Aside</em>, it's an action RPG in which you'll embark on a journey to save your younger sister, and humanity as a whole, from "mysterious dimensional invaders from beyond the starlit skies".</p>

<p>As part of that quest, you can expect a "gauntlet of formidable enemies and colossal bosses" to take on, as well as lots of exciting combat abilities to upgrade and skills to try out.</p>

<p>Of course, the PC version of the game will also boast a host of graphical options, including 4K resolution, ray tracing, and HDR, but if you want to use your DualSense controller on the Steam version, you'll be able to do that as well.</p>




<p><em>Lost Soul Aside&nbsp;</em>will launch on August 29th for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3378960/Lost_Soul_Aside/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/lost-soul-aside/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 launching early has "literally 0%" to do with GTA 6's release date, Marathon or anything save "confidence", says Gearbox boss]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-launching-early-has-literally-0-to-do-with-gta-6s-release-date-marathon-or-anything-save-confidence-says-gearbox-boss</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-launching-early-has-literally-0-to-do-with-gta-6s-release-date-marathon-or-anything-save-confidence-says-gearbox-boss.1177464/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-launching-early-has-literally-0-to-do-with-gta-6s-release-date-marathon-or-anything-save-confidence-says-gearbox-boss<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Pitchford in pitchfork mode</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Gearbox</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Gearbox and Take-Two recently <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-gets-an-earlier-release-date-as-accidentally-revealed-by-randy-pitchford">brought forward the release</a> of giggling gunslinger <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> from 23rd September to 12th September. This came a week or two after Bungie and Sony <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marathon-is-real-looks-ridiculously-stylish-has-a-release-date-and-is-getting-a-closed-alpha-this-month">also decided</a> to release their <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marathon">Marathon</a> reboot on 23rd September. 
</p>
<p>
If you thought all that was evidence of publishers playing 4D chess around the currently unannounced release date of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-everything-we-know">GTA 6</a>, with Bungie and Sony making the fair assumption that Take-Two won't release GTA 6 and Borderlands 4 on the same day... then you were mistaken. You should be ashamed to speculate in this fashion! Pshaw! Harrumph! Damn your eyes, sir, and damn the stalking horse you rode in on.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
So says Gearbox chieftain Randy Pitchford, who has climbed the parapets of social media to insist that the new Borderlands is only shipping early because it's super, duper good, and not because Gearbox are trying to avoid either an elevator fight with Marathon <em>or</em> the undivulged impact site of the incoming GTA 6 meteor, which will surely obliterate the sales of any game foolish enough to ship in close proximity. 
</p>
<p>

"Borderlands 4 shipping early is 100% the result of confidence in the game and development trajectory backed by actual tasks and bug find/fix rates," <a href="https://x.com/DuvalMagic/status/1917393753456664966">wrote</a> Pitchford. "Our decision is literally 0% about any other product's actual or theoretical launch date." 
</p>
<p>
As is the lot of many chieftains standing on parapets, Pitchford is getting a lot of heat for these assertions that Borderlands 4 is simply too darn brilliant to consign to the wastelands of late September. The Xitter replies are damning: three Dr Evil fingerquote gifs and counting, also a Pinocchio, an Anchorman, and several side-eyeing dogs. Now to see if Marathon, too, undergoes a sudden excess of confidence and brings its release date forward a few weeks. The Great Game continues.
</p>
<p>According to what we know for sure, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-release-date-wont-slip-to-2026-take-two-assure-theyre-highly-confident-about-fall-2025">GTA 6 will release in fall 2025</a>. "There is slippage in the industry and we're not immune from that," Take Two CEO Strauss Zelnick commented in November. "However, we narrowed the timing because we are highly confident in that timing."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rise of Industry 2 launches June 3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/rise-of-industry-2-launches-june-3</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rise-of-industry-2-launches-june-3.1177458/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/rise-of-industry-2-launches-june-3<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Business tycoon game sequel dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Business tycoon game sequel <em><a title="Games > Rise of Industry 2 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rise-of-industry-2">Rise of Industry 2</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,038 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2532490/Rise_of_Industry_2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/rise-of-industry-2-456a5c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on June 3, publisher <a title="Companies > Kasedo Games [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kasedo-games">Kasedo Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > SomaSim [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/somasim">SomaSim</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2532490/view/506201612758286361" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-962253"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Kasedo Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>80s U.S.A…. a time and place of rapid innovation, globalization and unprecedented profits. To dominate this competitive industrial landscape, you’ll need to build a cutting-edge manufacturing powerhouse and cultivate a rolodex full of jet-setting business contacts. Welcome to the land of opportunity!</p><p>In pursuit of unprecedented profits, you’ll need to seize every opportunity to innovate and grow each business you’re tasked with managing. Ever dream of running a hub of automotive production? A world-class winery with sweeping vineyard vistas? A sprawling mining operation extracting and refining valuable minerals? Or an aviation enterprise that assembles airplanes that will soar through the skies of an increasingly interconnected world?</p><p>You’ll need to optimize your production chains, import and export goods within the global market, keep up to date with the latest and greatest technologies, maintain strong relations with the local government and expand your business network to stay on top. Make all the right decisions along the way and you just might be able fulfill your American dream.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Rise to the Challenge</strong> – Conquer 15 unique and exciting scenarios in campaign mode, each with a different challenge. Alternatively, define your own path to success in sandbox mode.</li><li><strong>Optimize your Production</strong> – Set up manufacturing businesses featuring factories, power plants, industrial furnaces and farms! Establish utility networks to power your industries, making use of the natural resources around you. Provide the media industry with televisions, cameras, vinyl records, cassettes, computers, and video game consoles. Get distilleries and breweries up and running to create drinks such as vodka, whiskey and beer. Churn out candy, toys, dyes, batteries and so much more!</li><li><strong>Import and Export Resources</strong> – Capitalize on the emerging global market by signing contracts with executives around the world. Import goods and resources to accelerate your production chains and export your products to make the big bucks!</li><li><strong>Research Technologies</strong> – Build labs and set research strategies to help you acquire new technologies that will broaden your horizons and improve your production chains.</li><li><strong>Make Global Connections</strong> – Your social connections are vital – to stay on top you’ll need to know the right people and stay on their good side. Network with CEOs of other companies to trade in materials and finished products, and get introductions to their powerful friends in the industry.</li><li><strong><a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge Your Business</strong> – Satisfy your board of directors by keeping your profit margins high and completing goals to ensure further investment. Don’t worry, you’re not alone out there – hire integral executives to expand your business and increase efficiency.</li><li><strong>Maintain Civic Relations</strong> – Invest in the local town to keep your workers happy and ensure a strong relationship with the local government.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Comes After coming to PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, and Xbox One on May 9]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/what-comes-after-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-may-9</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-comes-after-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-may-9.1177455/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/what-comes-after-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-may-9<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Side-scrolling adventure game currently available for Switch and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Dolores Entertainment [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dolores-entertainment">Dolores Entertainment</a> will release <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [979 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,246 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > What Comes After" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/what-comes-after">What Comes After</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,955 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,939 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and Switch on May 9, the publisher announced. <span id="more-962268"></span></p><p>Developed by <a title="Companies > Pikselnesia [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pikselnesia">Pikselnesia</a> and <a title="Companies > Rolling Glory Jam" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/rolling-glory-jam">Rolling Glory Jam</a>, <em>What Comes After</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1421760/What_Comes_After/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on November 5, 2020, followed by Switch on April 1, 2021.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via the developers:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>From the creator of <em><a title="Games > Coffee Talk [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/coffee-talk">Coffee Talk</a></em>, in collaboration with Rolling Glory Jam the creator of <em>Rage in Peace</em>.</p><p><em>What Comes After</em> is a short experience, a heartwarming story, and a love letter to all of you who think you’re a burden for other people.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Help Vivi finds herself through the journey that takes her to where people go after they died, to what comes after. Ride the train filled with the souls of the people, animals, and plants that are on their way to leave this world, and talk to them to learn about love, regrets, life, and death that haunt us every day until our time has come. All presented in a light-hearted way with a sprinkle of comedy and philosophy.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>A short heartwarming story that will stay in your heart and memory.</li><li>A personal journey of learning how to love yourself.</li><li>A tale filled with love and comedy.</li><li>Colorful art to accompany your journey in the train not bound for the living.</li><li>An easy to pick-up gameplay.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Stadium Mode Is Excellent But Makes An Awful First Impression]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/overwatch-2-stadium-mode-is-excellent-but-makes-an-awful-first-impression/1100-6531214/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-stadium-mode-is-excellent-but-makes-an-awful-first-impression.1177452/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/overwatch-2-stadium-mode-is-excellent-but-makes-an-awful-first-impression/1100-6531214/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531214">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The first match I played of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-how-overwatch-2s-stadium-mode-heroes-powers-and-bounties-work/1100-6530857/">Stadium</a> in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/overwatch-2/">Overwatch 2</a> was a miserable experience. I was stuck in a third-person view that felt terrible and had to scramble to understand the different items you can get and how they impact your abilities. The enemy Soldier 76, however, was able to make his Helix Rocket one-shot me as Juno by the third round; he then proceeded to spend the rest of the match doing just that, while my allies spammed me in chat for not healing more.</p><p dir="ltr">By the end of the match, I was ready to dismiss Stadium as another unremarkable side mode for the hero shooter--one I planned to never touch again. Yet I continued to queue, as I wanted to better understand the mode. As I played more matches, I found that the new item builds and faster rounds are quite enjoyable, even if this mode needs far more polish.</p><h2 dir="ltr">What doesn't work in Stadium</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4485006-owthird-person.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4485006" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4485006-owthird-person.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4485006"></a><figcaption>Stadium defaults to a third-person perspective, but you can--and should--swap it back to first-person.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4485006-owthird-person.jpg"></figure><p>Stadium has a few issues out of the gate that make the onboarding experience feel bad. The first is that the mode is currently only available in competitive mode. On top of that, it doesn't offer placement matches, instead having everyone start at the same rank and work upwards. As such, initial matchmaking is wildly inconsistent, which is especially concerning in a mode that can snowball. Since you earn currency by playing well, which lets you buy better items, the team that's winning can quickly start to dominate.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition to the mismatched skill levels, it being competitive means the matches are longer and can't be backfilled if someone quits, and people have been quitting. In the three dozen or so matches I have played, someone has quit in about half of them. In a normal Overwatch competitive match, when someone quits and fails to return in two minutes, everyone on their team can quit without penalty and the match will conclude. If someone leaves prior to the match starting, or before a certain time, it cancels the match.</p><p dir="ltr">All of that is true, on paper at least, in Stadium, but the mode is quite buggy, leading to situations where the game fails to recognize when a game should be called off. For example, I had a match where our tank player picked Junker Queen, but never left the spawn area. The game waited too long to boot them, resulting in the match not being canceled, despite us never having a tank. The timer is also buggy too, as it resets at the end of round, and won't restart until after the Armory buy phase, which lasts over a minute. More often than not, if you don't want to get punished for leaving, you just have to play it out, as there is no surrender-vote option.</p><p dir="ltr">There is a mercy rule, where a team leading 3-0 with a currency lead of 15K or more will automatically win without having to play a fourth round. This also doesn't always work, as I've had matches where the requirements for a mercy rule were met, the in-between rounds loading screen stated that the requirements were met, and yet, a fourth round was played.</p><p dir="ltr">The final issue for onboarding is the third-person perspective. According to <a href="https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24191421/enter-the-stadium-lessons-learned-from-the-playtests/" rel="nofollow ">Blizzard</a>, it defaults to third-person to make it easier to see everything happening in Stadium. Yet Stadium does not feel like it requires being able to see more than regular Overwatch 2, and the third-person shooting feels stiff and strange. Fortunately, you can go into the settings and swap it back; I did and had a much better time. You can also establish Stadium-specific settings, allowing you to pick and choose which characters use which perspectives, and tweak your settings to better fit its third-person perspective. However, without a casual mode, all this adjusting will have to be done during competitive matches or in the training grounds.</p><h2 dir="ltr">What works in Stadium</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4485007-ow2stadiummap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4485007" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4485007-ow2stadiummap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4485007"></a><figcaption>Stadium features smaller versions of existing maps, and a few new maps like the Gladius Control map.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4485007-ow2stadiummap.jpg"></figure><p>So after all that, what makes Stadium worth pushing through to experience? For starters, it provides enough new and exciting experiences to be worth playing. The new building system is great, easy to understand once you spend some time with it, and there are tons of options. I appreciate that each hero has powers specific to them that can fit your playstyle.</p><p dir="ltr">For example, I enjoy building Ashe to deal high primary-attack damage. This means getting the powers that boost primary-fire damage, like Incendiary Rounds, which provides an extra 30 fire damage if you hit two scoped shots consecutively. After that, I can purchase items that further boost my primary-attack power to really increase the damage my shots do. However, you can also build Ashe to focus on dynamite explosion damage, or to buff B.O.B., Ashe's robot bodyguard and ultimate ability, so that you can use him more often and he does more damage.</p><p dir="ltr">This build system pairs well with heroes being locked from the start of the match. Unlike other modes, you cannot switch heroes during the game. This means that if you get stuck in a bad matchup, like Zarya against D.Va, instead of counter-swapping to a different hero, you must instead focus on building D.Va in a way to make it a more even fight. Swapping heroes mid-match is a huge part of the strategy of the game--even if Blizzard has seemingly <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-injects-more-moba-energy-into-overwatch-2-with-new-perks-system/1100-6529410/">taken steps</a> to try and discourage it--but Stadium completely removing this is a breath of fresh air.</p><p dir="ltr">Lastly, the shortened versions of each game mode make some of the more tedious ones actually feel fairer and more fun. In Stadium, each round is essentially an abridged version of another mode. Instead of Clash being best of five, it's best of three, while Push maps are about half the size, and Control is narrowed down to just a single round. The overall match is longer, but you get more variety, and modes that can feel like a stalemate--like Push and Clash--feel better suited to these shorter experiences.</p><p dir="ltr">Overwatch 2 Stadium needs a ton of polish and bug fixes before it can be a truly great experience, but the core aspects of the mode are there. The hero-building offers a ton of flexibility and options, the shorter rounds feel better, and having locked-in heroes removes one of the more frustrating aspects of the game. Fewer bugs and a casual playlist for Stadium could make the experience of learning the new mode less miserable, which would encourage more of the playerbase to try it out without having people constantly quitting from matches. The mode also should just default to first-person, with an option to swap to third-person, to make that first match feel less jarring. Stadium feels like it could be a staple of the hero shooter moving forward, if it gets the love and care it needs.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Pro Patch Drops For Returnal, Offers Big Resolution Boost]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-patch-drops-for-returnal-offers-big-resolution-boost/1100-6531222/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-pro-patch-drops-for-returnal-offers-big-resolution-boost.1177449/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-patch-drops-for-returnal-offers-big-resolution-boost/1100-6531222/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531222">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>For the fourth anniversary of its sci-fi action game Returnal, developer Housemarque has updated it for the PS5 Pro console. Full patch notes haven't been released yet, but Housemarque did confirm that the game features "up to 2.5x the pixels on PS5 Pro," which will result in a higher-resolution picture.</p><p>First released on PS5 in 2021, Returnal is a roguelite sci-fi take on Groundhog Day mixed with themes of loss and regret.<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/returnal-review-roundup-what-are-the-critics-saying/1100-6490772/" data-ref-id="1100-6490772"> Critically acclaimed</a>, Returnal revolves around the astronaut Selene and her attempts to escape a hostile alien planet while also dealing with the ghosts of her past, and following the release of the game, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-acquires-returnal-dev-housemarque/1100-6493351/" data-ref-id="1100-6493351">Housemarque was acquired by Sony</a>.</p><p>Returnal's spooky universe was the foundation for a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Returnal-Fallen-Asteria-Gregory-Louden/dp/1506742378?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="nofollow ">graphic-novel adaptation based on its premise</a>, created by Housemarque's narrative and design teams. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/150673958X?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="nofollow ">There's also a hardcover deluxe art book available</a>, in case you'd like to see how its nightmarish worlds and monsters were created.</p><p>Housemarque is also busy on a new single-player action game that looks thematically similar to Returnal. Revealed during <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/playstation-state-of-play-february-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6256/">February 2025's PlayStation State of Play</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/saros-is-returnal-developer-housemarques-new-game-starring-rahul-kohli/1100-6529469/" data-ref-id="1100-6529469">Saros is a single-player action game</a> that follows an explorer named Arjun Devraj, played by Rahul Kohli.</p><p>Scheduled to launch in 2026 for PS5--and there'll be an enhanced version for PS5 Pro as well--Saros will allow players to become stronger with every death, as it features permanent resources and progression systems.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOOM: The Dark Ages GeForce RTX 50 Series Bundle Available Now]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/doom-the-dark-ages-geforce-rtx-50-series-bundle-available-now/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-geforce-rtx-50-series-bundle-available-now.1177431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/doom-the-dark-ages-geforce-rtx-50-series-bundle-available-now/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, NVIDIA announced the <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/campaigns/doom-the-dark-ages-rtx-bundle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOOM: The Dark Ages GeForce RTX 50 Series bundle</a>. As with previous such bundles, the promotion stipulates that purchasing a GeForce RTX 5090, 5080, 5070 Ti, or 5070 desktop or GPU, or a laptop with a GeForce RTX 5090, 5080, 5070 Ti, or 5070 Laptop GPU provides a complimentary digital code for the game's Premium Edition.</p>
<p>Priced at $99.99, here's the full content of DOOM: The Dark Ages Premium Edition:</p>
<ul>
<li>Base Game</li>
<li>Up to 2-Day Early Access</li>
<li>Campaign DLC</li>
<li>Digital Artbook and Soundtrack</li>
<li>Divinity Skin Pack</li>
</ul>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/DOOM-TDA_PremiumEdition-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>DOOM: The Dark Ages will launch on May 15 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X. The game will support full-fledged path tracing and NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation to maximize visuals and performance. Check out our DOOM: The Dark Ages hands-on preview <a href="https://wccftech.com/doom-the-dark-ages-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>Today, NVIDIA also provided an update on the latest games that will adopt its DLSS upscaling technology. As <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-tech-test-hands-on-promising-extractions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> in my hands-on, DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation is already implemented in the ARC Raiders Tech Test that begins today for the public. Of course, GeForce RTX 40 users can enable Frame Generation, and GeForce RTX 20/30 users can activate Super Resolution.</p>
<p>The recently released <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-back-in-cyrodiil-19-years-later/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a> supports NVIDIA DLSS Frame Generation, Super Resolution, and DLAA, while also taking advantage of the ray tracing cores available in the RTX architecture if the user enables hardware-accelerated Lumen ray traced global illumination.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/DLSS-251-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>The roguelite first-person shooter game Deadzone: Rogue <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3228590/Deadzone_Rogue/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched</a> in early access this week with NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation, Frame Generation, Super Resolution, and DLAA. Just like Oblivion Remastered, it also takes advantage of the RT Cores when enabling Lumen-based hardware-accelerated ray tracing.</p>
<p>The Wuxia open world action/adventure roleplaying game Where Winds Meet was also updated to support NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation on top of Frame Generation and Super Resolution. According to NVIDIA, performance can be accelerated by 3.9X at 4K resolution and max settings. The GeForce RTX 5090 can run the game at over 500 frames per second. As a reminder, a new Closed Beta Test <a href="https://wccftech.com/where-winds-meet-new-cbt-set-for-may-16-19-on-pc-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">is coming in a couple of weeks</a>.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Lastly, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/mistfall-hunter-a-fantasy-pvpve-action-rpg-announces-new-steam-beta-test-for-late-april/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Beta 2 Test of the third-person PvPvE extraction RPG Mistfall Hunter</a> already supports NVIDIA DLSS Frame Generation and Super Resolution.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Nintendo Switch 2 New Footage Shows How the System Can Surpass PS4-Level Graphics]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-nintendo-switch2-surpass-ps4-graphics/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-nintendo-switch-2-new-footage-shows-how-the-system-can-surpass-ps4-level-graphics.1177428/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-nintendo-switch2-surpass-ps4-graphics/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Cyberpunk 2077 on Nintendo Switch 2 is setting out to be one of the most impressive ports launching together with the system, as the game's latest footage highlights how a more recent build of this version of the open-world RPG by CD Projekt Red has already been improved over the one used to capture the reveal trailer.</p>
<p>In a new analysis shared on YouTube, SuperMetalDave64 goes over the new footage released as part of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-FeYJHMW9xY">Nintendo's Creator's Voice series</a>, taking a good look at the game's visuals and performance. The most noticeable improvement is regarding textures, as the sequence where V is talking with Johnny Silverhand inside a restaurant, for example, features more detailed textures than in the same sequence shown in the reveal trailer. Additionally, the graphics settings seen in the new footage, a mix of mid and high PC settings, which is incredibly impressive, given the Nintendo Switch 2 hardware, and the stable performance in Dogtown, the demanding central location of the Phantom Liberty expansion which wasn't released on previous generation systems, highlight how the new Nintendo console is definitely capable of surpassing PlayStation 4 graphics and performance level.</p>
<p><iframe title="Switch 2 Cyberpunk 2077 Graphics Upgrade Confirmed in New Gameplay Trailer In-Depth Analysis" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xLYOReVmzXc?start=1&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Seeing Cyberpunk 2077 run on Nintendo Switch 2 in the way it currently does is extremely impressive, so it will be really interesting to see how the game will look at launch. Helping CD Projekt Red achieve this level of visual quality at solid performance is likely the use of <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-nintendo-switch-2-nvidia-dlss/">NVIDIA DLSS</a>, which the game will employ in all of its display modes, both docked and handheld.</p>
<p>Cyberpunk 2077 launches on Nintendo Switch 2 complete with the Phantom Liberty expansion on June 5th, the same day the system launches worldwide, with some exceptions like China, <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-wont-launch-in-central-america-or-the-caribbean-this-year/">Central America, and the Caribbean.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 and PC Single-Player Action Game Lost Soul Aside Delayed 3 Months to Add Polish]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-and-pc-single-player-action-game-lost-soul-aside-delayed-3-months-to-add-polish</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-and-pc-single-player-action-game-lost-soul-aside-delayed-3-months-to-add-polish.1177416/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-and-pc-single-player-action-game-lost-soul-aside-delayed-3-months-to-add-polish<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Fall 2025 looking pretty busy indeed.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/lost-soul-aside">Lost Soul Aside</a> is delayed three months, from May 30 to August 29, 2025, its developer has announced.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After roughly a decade in development, the PC and PlayStation 5 single-player action game was finally scheduled for llaunch next month, but a statement from developer Ultizero Games revealed the delay to late September to add polish.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We are truly grateful for the positive response we've received from players all over the world since we announced Lost Soul Aside," Ultizero Games said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We remain committed to delivering a high-quality game experience. To match the standards Ultizero Games have set for ourselves, we are going to take some additional time to polish the game. Lost Soul Aside will now release on August 29, 2025. We want to express our heartfelt thanks to our fans waiting for the launch."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Originally the passion project of solo developer Yang Bing, Lost Soul Aside has grown to become a major Sony-published title under the company's China Hero Project, with Bing now the founder and CEO of Shanghai-based studio Ultizero Games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-and-pc-single-player-action-game-lost-soul-aside-the-big-interview">IGN recently had the opportunity to sit down with Yang Bing to discuss the long road to launch</a>. So many years of development went into Lost Soul Aside, escalating from a solo creator's vision to a trailer reveal at Sony's State of Play broadcast. Through it all the hype has built up, with some calling Lost Soul Aside an exciting mix of Final Fantasy characters and Devil May Cry combat — even from the moment Yang Bing's initial reveal video went viral in 2016.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The main character Kesar wields a shape-shifting weapon you can swap between, which changes your playstyle, and you have a dragon-like companion named Arena who can summon abilities to support Kesar.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Like its inspirations, Lost Soul Aside emphasizes aerial dodging, precision timing, combos, and countering along with large-scale boss fights. The game blends its sci-fi premise with a variety of contemporary aesthetics that fit into a campaign that takes you across multiple dimensions. Although it's tough to glean where the story is going based on its trailers, Bing describes Kesar's journey as one of "redemption and discovery."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japanese Actor’s Dramatic Pokemon Save Data Loss Goes Viral, Triggering Traumatic Memories and Sympathy From Fellow Gamers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/japanese-actors-dramatic-pokemon-save-data-loss-goes-viral-triggering-traumatic-memories-and-sympathy-from-fellow-gamers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/japanese-actor%E2%80%99s-dramatic-pokemon-save-data-loss-goes-viral-triggering-traumatic-memories-and-sympathy-from-fellow-gamers.1177413/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/japanese-actors-dramatic-pokemon-save-data-loss-goes-viral-triggering-traumatic-memories-and-sympathy-from-fellow-gamers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Even if save data disappears, the memories remain!"</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Regardless of age, every gamer remembers when they suffered their first save game data loss, be it a corrupted console/PC harddrive, or a PS1 memory card suddenly showing blue blocks of damaged data. Japanese gamers were reminded of these painful feelings on April 30, when actor Shinya Okada’s dramatic reaction to losing all his original Pokemon Red save data from 1996 was captured in a YouTube video. The actor’s stunned facial expressions and fans’ outpourings of sympathy even led the incident to be featured on <a href="https://www.crank-in.net/news/165828/1" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Japanese entertainment news outlets</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A familiar face in Japanese TV dramas, 77-year-old actor Shinya Owada is also a huge Pokemon fan, regularly playing through various games from the series on his YouTube Channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@shinyaohwada" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>“Shinya Owada’s Hideout.”</u></a> Often accompanied by his trusty Squirtle plushie (that he <a href="https://x.com/oowadashinya/status/1887780979852673211" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>recently took on an adorable trip to the aquarium</u></a>), Owada’s warm-hearted enthusiasm for the games, plus his dramatic narration of the dialogue has earned the veteran gamer over 56.4K subscribers.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/30/japan-1746009732056.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Japanese actor Shinya Owada lost his Pokemon Red save data. Image credit Shinya Owada / YouTube.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In his latest “Let’s Play” <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NJH3njE-ezY" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>video</u></a> posted on April 29, Owada’s cheerful enthusiasm to continue his Pokemon Red adventure gradually morphs into disbelief as the game asks him if he wants to start from the beginning. Owada’s startled reactions of “wait? what?” as he realizes that all the hours he has put into capturing and training Pokemon have vanished are palpable.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Owada also <a href="https://x.com/oowadashinya/status/1917172028580434361" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>took to X </u></a>to share his feelings on the matter in a post that quickly amassed 4.4 million views and over 200 comments: “My Pokemon Red Game Boy cartridge save data has vanished. In my remaining lifetime, I will find another adventure to embark on.” Although he had previously streamed Pokemon Red, he announced that he plans to stop playing the game for now.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="ja" dir="ltr">【ご報告】<br>ゲームボーイソフト<br>ポケットモンスター 赤🟥の<br>冒険のセーブデータが<br>消えてしまいました^_^<br>人生の限られた時間の中で<br>また新しい旅を探します<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%83%9D%E3%82%B1%E3%83%A2%E3%83%B3?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#ポケモン</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%82%B2%E3%83%BC%E3%83%A0?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#ゲーム</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%81%AC%E3%81%84%E6%B4%BB?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#ぬい活</a> <a href="https://t.co/uofsbpsYDR" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/uofsbpsYDR</a></p>— 大和田 伸也 (@oowadashinya) <a href="https://twitter.com/oowadashinya/status/1917172028580434361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 29, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Owada’s unfortunate data loss experience attracted many sympathetic comments, with people reminiscing about the sadness they felt when they lost valuable saves when they were children, often on cartridge-based systems like the Game Boy and N64, or PS1 and PS2 memory cards. As many commenters suggested, it seems likely that the battery in Okada’s Game Boy cartridge of Pokemon Red finally died, thus deleting his precious save data. Without the benefits of cloud-based storage back-ups, it was quite easy to lose all the data on your cartridge or memory card if the contacts wore out, you took it out of the console too quickly, or even looked at the console in the wrong way (this writer swears that this is how she lost her 90 hours of Final Fantasy IX gameplay back in 2001...).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Losing save data is also losing life,” stated one commenter on Owada’s YouTube video, drawing stark attention to the hours of effort and grinding that vanish into oblivion when you lose a save (something that all Simmers, Citybuilders, and RPG fans can attest to). Others were more philosophical: “even if save data disappears, the memories remain!” Comments also showed fans’ fondness for Owada, with one user adding: "If this happened to any other video game streamer, I would laugh at how ridiculous it is, but with Mr. Owada, it's a different story."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If all this has strangely inspired you to go back to Game Boy-era Pokemon games, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-red-blue-yellow-version/walkthrough"><u>IGN’s comprehensive walkthroughs</u></a> for Pokemon Red, Blue and Yellow.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit Shinya Owada / YouTube.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Verity Townsend is a Japan-based freelance writer who previously served as editor, contributor and translator for the game news site Automaton West. She has also written about Japanese culture and movies for various publications.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals For Today: Pokémon TCG ETBs Are Back In Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-30-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deals-for-today-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-etbs-are-back-in-stock.1177410/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-30-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/score-60-off-a-sams-club-membership-today-only-and-secure-sold-out-pokemon-tcg-sets-at-a-discount">Pokémon TCG</a> fans are getting a strong lineup today, with multiple <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-surging-sparks-booster-bundle-shining-fates-amazon-restock-latest">Elite Trainer Boxes</a> on sale. That includes an early discount on the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-journey-together-preview">Journey Together</a> set, which is rare this soon after release. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Regardless of being in it for the promos or looking to crack packs, this is a great time to grab sealed product, not ot mention singles dropping in value across the board. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's also a deal on Iono’s Bellibolt Premium Collection, and the Iron Leaves ETB from the Temporal Forces expansion is holding steady at a fair price.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">TL;DR: Deals For Today</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Outside the world of cards, <a href="https://zdcs.link/a5YZbd?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">AirPods Pro 2</a> are available for $169, a significant drop from their usual $249 price tag. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you just picked up a Switch 2, there’s also a <a href="https://zdcs.link/QORvDY?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">quick-install screen protector available</a> for under $10. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Humble has a 17-title <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qbxd1G?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">XCOM bundle starting at just $10</a>, and the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QPpqym?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">IGN Store</a> is offering a limited <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-review">Oblivion</a> collectible ingot for pre-order, perfect for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-online">Elder Scrolls</a> fans and collectors.</p><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violetjourne"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Journe">Journey Together Elite Trainer Box</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219777"><div id="219777" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Journey Together Elite Trainer Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/98LMB8?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Journey Together Elite Trainer Box</a> is seeing a notable early discount at $64.95, down from its usual $97.99 price. With 9 booster packs, a full-art promo card featuring N’s Zorua, and 65 matching card sleeves, this is a solid pickup for collectors or competitive players looking to expand their deck.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’re also getting Energy cards, a player’s guide, dice, and other accessories packed in a themed storage box. With singles from this set trending down in price, picking up sealed product offers better value if you're after specific chase cards.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Journey Together Rare Cards</h2></p><p id="pokmon-tcg-ionos-bellibolt-ex-pr"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title=" Pokémon TCG: Iono’s Bellibolt ex Pr">Iono’s Bellibolt ex Premium Collection</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219778"><div id="219778" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3> Pokémon TCG: Iono’s Bellibolt ex Premium Collection</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/zJ2mdk?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">This Premium Collection</a> features Iono’s Bellibolt ex as a full-art foil promo, plus a foil Iono’s Tadbulb card and six booster packs. At $53.23, it’s a modest discount off the typical $55.88 price (for Amazon).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’ll also get standees, a photo sticker, and a backdrop display themed around Iono and Bellibolt. With several playable cards in this set seeing markdowns on the singles market, this box is a good option for collectors or those hoping to pull value.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Journey Together IRs</h2></p><p id="the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remast"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="The Elder Scrolls IV Oblivion Remast">Oblivion Gates</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219779"><div id="219779" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Elder Scrolls IV Oblivion Remastered - The Oblivion Gates by Ingot</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This <a href="https://zdcs.link/QPpqym?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">limited edition Oblivion Gates statue</a> from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered">Elder Scrolls IV</a> is available now for pre-order at $39.99. It’s officially licensed, limited to 5,000 units, and includes a display stand in a collectible box.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The detailed design captures the fiery gates seen in-game and measures 110 x 76mm. Scheduled to ship in October 2025, this is a good pick for fans of the series looking to add a unique item to their collection.</p></div><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-and-violet-tem"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet and Violet: Tem">Temporal Forces: Elite Trainer Box</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219782"><div id="219782" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet and Violet: Temporal Forces: Elite Trainer Box: Iron Leaves</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/9wXDeD?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Temporal Forces Elite Trainer Box</a> featuring Iron Leaves is holding at $55.42. It includes booster packs, Energy cards, themed sleeves, and tools for competitive play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This expansion brings back ACE SPEC cards and features both Ancient and Future Pokémon ex, including Walking Wake ex and Raging Bolt ex. With singles from this set also seeing price drops, sealed boxes may offer better pull value for players chasing newer cards.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Temporal Forces Chase Cards</h2></p><p id="xcom-complete-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="XCOM complete Bundle">XCOM Complete Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219784"><div id="219784" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>XCOM complete Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Humble is offering a full <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qbxd1G?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">XCOM franchise bundle starting at just $10</a>. That unlocks 17 titles, including XCOM 2, Enemy Unknown, Chimera Squad, and multiple DLCs with a combined value of $269.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is a rare chance to pick up nearly the entire series in one package, and part of your purchase supports the Michael J. Fox Foundation for Parkinson’s Research. Whether you're new to the franchise or filling gaps in your library, it's worth a look.</p></div><p id="auto-alignment-screen-protector-for"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Auto-Alignment Screen Protector for ">Screen Protector for Nintendo Switch 2</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219785"><div id="219785" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Auto-Alignment Screen Protector for Nintendo Switch 2</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This <a href="https://zdcs.link/QORvDY?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">2-pack screen protector for the Switch 2</a> uses amFilm’s latest auto-alignment system for quick, bubble-free installation in under 30 seconds. It’s currently down to $9.99, a 23% savings off its usual $12.99 list price.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’re getting tempered glass rated at 9H hardness, plus anti-fingerprint coating and responsive touch sensitivity. A smart add-on for anyone who's preordered Switch 2 and wants protection without hassle.</p></div><p id="apple-airpods-pro-2"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title=" Apple AirPods Pro 2 "> Apple AirPods Pro 2 </h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219786"><div id="219786" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3> Apple AirPods Pro 2 </h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/airpods-pro-2nd-generation">Apple’s AirPods Pro 2</a> with the updated USB-C case are <a href="https://zdcs.link/a5YZbd?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">available for $169</a>, which is $80 off the standard price of $249. That’s one of the lowest prices we’ve seen this month.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These wireless earbuds offer active noise cancellation, adaptive audio modes, personalized spatial audio, and a secure fit with multiple tip sizes. They’re also IP54-rated for water and dust resistance, making them a reliable option for both everyday listening and workouts.</p></div><p id="id-software-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="id Software Bundle">id &amp; Friends Humble Game Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219655"><div id="219655" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>id &amp; Friends Humble Game Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I think calling this a bundle is almost underselling it. You are getting <a href="https://zdcs.link/a0nyre?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">DOOM, Wolfenstein, DOOM Eternal, and a coupon toward DOOM: The Dark Ages</a>, just to name a few. It is a lot of chaos and a lot of catharsis for not a lot of money. Steam ratings are strong across the board if you care about that kind of thing, but honestly, DOOM 1993 still sells itself.</p></div><p id="surging-sparks-booster-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Surging Sparks Booster Box">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet - Surging Sparks Booster Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219656"><div id="219656" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet - Surging Sparks Booster Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Six booster packs in one bundle sounds good on paper, but in my opinion, the smarter move right now is to look at singles. Prices for this set are dropping fast, and if you are chasing specific cards, buying them outright is probably cheaper and less soul crushing than another box full of commons. </p></div><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violettwilig"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Twilig">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Twilight Masquerade Elite Trainer Box</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219744"><div id="219744" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Twilight Masquerade Elite Trainer Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Greninja ex SIR, that is all. In all seriousness, this is a brilliant set that's often overlooked. Whilst the price is a little over MSRP, it's worth getting just for the booster packs included. Plus the promo, sleeves and dice look great in this particular ETB. Following the trend, Twilight Masquerade single cards are also crashing in price, so make sure to check if you can just buy the cards you're after for less.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Twilight Masquerade Single Cards</h2></p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Surging Sparks Single Cards</h2></p><p id="shining-fates-collection"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Shining Fates Collection">Pokémon TCG: Shining Fates Collection Pikachu V Box</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219657"><div id="219657" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Shining Fates Collection Pikachu V Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">kachu gets a lot of oversized cardboard love in this box with a promo card, a giant version, and four Shining Fates booster packs. It is a decent pickup if you like opening packs, but single card prices are slipping hard right now. I think it makes more sense to hunt down the exact cards you want unless you are feeling reckless.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Shining Fates Single Cards</h2></p><p id="dark-brotherhood-medalion"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Dark Brotherhood Medalion">The Elder Scrolls IV Oblivion Remastered Dark Brotherhood Medallion</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219658"><div id="219658" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Elder Scrolls IV Oblivion Remastered Dark Brotherhood Medallion</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">In my opinion, this is one of those collectibles that you either want immediately or not at all. It is an officially licensed Dark Brotherhood medallion, limited to 5000 pieces, finished in black and gold, and somehow still cheaper than most novelty keychains. Ships later this year, assuming you survive the wait</p></div><p id="paldean-fates-booster-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Paldean Fates Booster Bundle">Pokémon TCG Paldean Fates Booster Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219659"><div id="219659" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG Paldean Fates Booster Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Paldean Fates brings back shiny Pokémon in a big way, and this bundle gives you six booster packs to chase them. I want to be excited about it, but again, single card prices for Paldean Fates are not holding up well. If you just want a shiny Charizard ex SIR without the suspense, the singles market is sitting there quietly judging your pack opening addiction.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Paldean Fates Single Cards</h2></p><p id="azure-legends-tin"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Azure Legends Tin">Pokemon TCG: Azure Legends Tin - 5 Packs</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219660"><div id="219660" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokemon TCG: Azure Legends Tin - 5 Packs</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes 2 x Surging Sparks Booster Packs</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I like a good tin, especially one with five booster packs packed inside, but getting a random Kyogre, Xerneas, or Dialga promo card feels a little like gambling with slightly better odds. It is a solid pickup for the price if you do not mind leaving your promo fate to the RNG gods. If you are only after one specific chase card though outside of the included two Surging Sparks boosters, it might save your blood pressure to just buy it separately.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Surging Sparks Single Cards</h2></p><p id="lexar-sale"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Lexar Sale">Lexar Sale</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219661"><div id="219661" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lexar Sale</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Up to 54% off Micro SDXCs, Portable SSDs, M.2 SSDs, Sata III SSDs and RAM </p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Lexar is finally giving some breathing room on pricing with this Amazon sale, and the Armor 700 is a standout. You are getting 4TB of rugged storage with serious transfer speeds for about 100 dollars off the typical price. It is water resistant, dust resistant, and a lot more durable than whatever junk is sitting at the bottom of your backpack right now.</p></div><p id="pokmon-game-sale"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon Game Sale">Pokémon Game Sale</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219557"><div id="219557" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon Legends: Arceus</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Click through for the full Woot gaming sale</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Woot is offering a solid spread of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/franchise/pokemon">Pokémon</a> games today, and I want at least three of them. Brilliant Diamond, Legends: Arceus, Let’s Go, Eevee!, and a few others are sitting between $39.99 and $44.99, which feels right for anyone catching up before Switch 2 changes the landscape again. In my opinion, it is a smart time to grab them while prices are behaving themselves. Everything here is fully playable now and will likely get performance bumps once Nintendo's next system arrives.</p></div><p id="msi-sale"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="MSI Sale">MSI Desktops &amp; Components Sale</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219558"><div id="219558" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>MSI Desktops &amp; Components Sale</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Click through for the full Woot gaming sale</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">MSI’s factory-reconditioned gaming desktops are quietly one of the best parts of today's sale. Machines like the AEGIS R 13NUE-448US are going for $1,129.99, and RTX 4060 GPUs are under $300. I want to be responsible, but this pricing makes it harder than it should be. If you have been thinking about rebuilding your setup, this is exactly the kind of deal you hope not to miss.</p></div><p id="samsung-512gb-microsdxc"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Samsung 512GB MicroSDXC">Samsung Pro Plus 512GB MicroSDXC + Reader</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219560"><div id="219560" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Samsung Pro Plus 512GB MicroSDXC + Reader</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon has the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/publisher/samsung">Samsung</a> PRO Plus 512GB microSD card with a USB reader for $29.99. I think it is a good fit if you are adding games to your Switch, Steam Deck, ROG Ally, or anything else still using microSD storage. It is fast enough for quick transfers, big enough for most libraries, and cheap enough that you do not have to think too hard about it. Just know it is not built for Switch 2, in case you're planning ahead.</p></div><p id="8bitdo-xbox-edition-keyboard"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="8BitDo Xbox Edition Keyboard">8BitDo Retro 87 Mechanical Keyboard (Xbox Edition)</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219562"><div id="219562" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>8BitDo Retro 87 Mechanical Keyboard (Xbox Edition)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/8bitdo-retro-mechanical-keyboard-review">8BitDo Retro 87 Mechanical Keyboard</a> is down to $99.99 at Amazon. I think it is one of the best-looking keyboards out right now if you want something that works and does not scream “boring office equipment.” It has Kailh Jellyfish X switches, a top-mount design, fast response, and Xbox-inspired styling that actually looks good on a gaming desk. I probably do not need another keyboard. I am thinking about it anyway.</p></div><p id="8bitdo-mouse-xbox-edition"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="8BitDo Mouse Xbox Edition"> 8BitDo Retro R8 Mouse (Xbox Edition)</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219563"><div id="219563" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3> 8BitDo Retro R8 Mouse (Xbox Edition)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon also has the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/8bitdo-retro-mechanical-keyboard-review">8BitDo Retro R8 Wireless Mouse</a> on sale for $58.68. It feels like the natural companion to the Retro 87 Keyboard, but it also stands fine on its own. It packs a PAW 3395 sensor, programmable buttons, a 4K polling rate, and a charging dock that doubles as a signal booster. I want one for a low-key gaming setup that does not look like it is held together with RGB lighting and prayer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 30, 2025 10:41 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cattle Country launches May 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/cattle-country-launches-may-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cattle-country-launches-may-27.1177407/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/cattle-country-launches-may-27<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Cowboy life <a title="Genres > Simulation [727 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Cattle Country [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/cattle-country">Cattle Country</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,038 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2818150/Cattle_Country/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 27, publisher <a title="Companies > Playtonic Friends [35 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playtonic-games/playtonic-friends">Playtonic Friends</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Castle Pixel [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/castle-pixel">Castle Pixel</a> announced. A demo is now available for Xbox Series, Switch, and PC, with a PlayStation 5 demo coming soon. <span id="more-962275"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2818150/Cattle_Country/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Cattle Country</em> straddles the saddle of cozy wholesome gaming and <a title="Genres > Action [2,703 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,246 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>. Serving up hours of the slice-of-life you’d expect on the frontier—including mining, fishing, <a title="Genres > Crafting [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a>, and farming—along with deep-rooted Wild West <a title="Platforms > Quest [138 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a>s delivering stories of romance, cattle drives, bandits, and robberies.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Ranchin’ and Handcraftin’</strong> – Making your home on the range is a modern departure. From sunup to sundown, you’ll be rollin’ up your sleeves and gettin’ your hands dirty working the land and raising your cattle. Building and crafting as you go to make your own little slice of heaven under the blues skies of <em>Cattle Country</em>.</li><li><strong>Swappin’ Stories and Settlin’ in With Your Neighbors</strong> – Get to know the townsfolk, hear their stories, help them out. The people here are a hardy bunch- you’ve got be to survive here. But they have hearts as warm as a hearth in the wintertime if you make the effort to stoke the flames.</li><li><strong>Beware of Bandits</strong> – Not everyone in <em>Cattle Country</em> is the warm and <a title="Companies > fuzz" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fuzz">fuzz</a>y type, so watch out for nefarious plots and shady characters. Protect your homestead and your community.</li><li><strong>Rodeos to Romance</strong> – Making friends is a must in the Wilderness, relying on each other through the thick and the thin. But maybe you’ve got a yearnin’ for more? With 18 romanceable characters, take a chance and grab love by the reigns.</li><li><strong>Buried <a title="Companies > Treasure [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/treasure">Treasure</a></strong> – Did yer hear? There’s treasure in the mines, for those who are brave enough to look for it. From precious metals and minerals to bandit stashes. Grab your pickaxe and venture out into the thrill of prospecting.</li><li><strong>Trackin’ Game in the Wild</strong> – From bunnies to bovine, there’s many a critter waiting in the woodlands for a keen adventurer. Hunting to eat or venturing out just to see all of nature’s wonders, it’s your call.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>This is just a taste of the adventures on offer, so throw down roots and work the land. Become part of a story that’s as old as these hills and a part of this small community of settlers. Welcome to <em>Cattle Country</em>!</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Cattle Country launches May 27th!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T_yWgRPXWPI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aliens-inspired Metroidvania Moadra adds PS5, Xbox Series, and Switch versions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/aliens-inspired-metroidvania-moadra-adds-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch-versions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/aliens-inspired-metroidvania-moadra-adds-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch-versions.1177401/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/aliens-inspired-metroidvania-moadra-adds-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch-versions<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Alien</em>-inspired science-fiction <a title="Genres > Metroidvania [205 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/metroidvania">Metroidvania game</a> <em><a title="Games > Moadra" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/moadra">Moadra</a></em> will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> alongside its previously planned PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1713730/Moadra/" target="_blank">Steam</a>) version when it launches later in 2025, developer <a title="Companies > Gloomsoft" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gloomsoft">Gloomsoft</a> announced. <span id="more-962063"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Gloomsoft:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Set out on a deadly mission to explore the mysterious planet of Protea VI and uncover what happened to a once-thriving civilization as Lieutenant Moadra Meras, a member of the Neera elites. Through coarse sand and freezing ice, delve into lush underground caverns brimming with secrets. Activate your scanner bot and use X-ray vision to examine creatures, reveal hidden paths, and discover secret areas that have been previously lost to time. The fate of an entire species hangs in the balance. Can you survive the <a title="Genres > Horror [602 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a>s that await, or will you become just another lost soul to fall victim to Protea VI?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Explore an Otherworldly Wasteland</strong> – Whether you are trying to endure the desolate surface, ascend the deadly, freezing summits, or scout the research facility infested with malicious alien species, Protea VI has many lost secrets to uncover after your ancestor’s extinction 20,000 years ago. Dangers await around every corner.</li><li><strong>Tools of <a title="Genres > Survival [411 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a></strong> – Use Moadra’s agility to your advantage to roll, dodge, leap, wall jump, and sprint at never-before-seen speeds to evade deadly organisms and hazardous elements. Use your swift reflexes, an arsenal of weapons, and special abilities to survive everything from low-level threats to gargantuan monsters that force you to use every tool at your disposal.</li><li><strong>Use the Environment to Evolve</strong> – Activate your scanner bot and use X-ray vision to examine creatures and your surroundings more closely. Reveal hidden paths and secret areas invisible to the naked eye, and map out the places you explored.</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Action [2,703 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a>-Packed Mutations</strong> – Blow up unfriendly creatures and organisms to absorb their Protoplasm, lumps of energy-packed biomass. Consume it inside organic chambers to apply metamorphosis, and evolve your abilities and weapons to new levels.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Consoles Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Moadra | Console Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qe5HQg0pSpU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ToHeart remake six-minute trailer, latest character profiles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/toheart-remake-six-minute-trailer-latest-character-profiles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/toheart-remake-six-minute-trailer-latest-character-profiles.1177395/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/toheart-remake-six-minute-trailer-latest-character-profiles<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Meet Lemmy, Kotone, Hikari, and George.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Aquaplus [208 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hike/aquaplus">Aquaplus</a> has released a six-minute official trailer for its upcoming 3D remake of love <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,246 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > ToHeart (2025) [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/toheart-2025">ToHeart</a></em>. <span id="more-962231"></span></p><p>The company also published the first episode of the 1999 anime series <em>ToHeart</em> anime and a bonus video to YouTube for a limit time as a preview of the Premium Edition, which includes a Blu-ray disc of all 13 episodes of the series, remastered in high-definition.</p><p>The <a href="https://aquaplus.jp/toheart/en.html" target="_blank">official website</a> was also updated with the following character profiles:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Lemmy Miyauchi</strong> (newly voiced by Ai Fukuda, originally voiced by Rumi Kasahara)</p><p>A girl in the protagonist’s year who was born in California to an international couple. Her cheerful, easygoing personality and flashy style come off as stereotypically American, but in her heart there is a demure Japanese woman—and however foolish her straightforwardness may seem, it never fails to lighten the mood.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_001.jpg"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_003.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_004.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_005.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Kotone Himekawa</strong> (newly voiced by Yuka Nukui, originally voiced by Kyoko Hikami)</p><p>One year the protagonist Hiroyuki’s junior, she tends to be avoided by most of the school due to the apparently supernatural phenomenon that she set off as soon as she enrolled. She rarely speaks and does not seek social interaction, but as Hiroyuki tries to befriend her, she finds herself slowly opening her heart…</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_006.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_007.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_008.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_009.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_010.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Hikari Kamigashi</strong> (newly voiced by Yuko Gibu, originally voiced by Ayako Kawasumi)</p><p><a title="Games > Aka [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/aka">Aka</a>ri Kamigishi’s mother is a gentle woman with a love for children who works as a tutor for both <a title="Genres > Cooking [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/cooking">cooking</a> and traditional Japanese dress. Her voice sounds so much like Akari’s that even the protagonist sometimes gets them confused.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_011.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_012.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>George Miyauchi</strong> (newly voiced by Hiroki Maeda, originally voiced by Takeshi Kuwabara)</p><p>Lemmy Miyauchi’s father is a man who treasures his family. Blessed with Hollywood good looks and a powerful but friendly personality, he works as the CEO of a trading company.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_013.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ToHeart_2025_04-30-25_014.jpg"></a></figure></blockquote><p><em>ToHeart</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,038 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3380520/ToHeart/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on June 26 worldwide, as well as for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on the same day in Japan.</p><p>Watch the trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/toheart-2025/april-30-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Official Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『ToHeart』オフィシャルトレーラーPV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NsMPgCixaNc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span><em>ToHeart</em> <a title="Platforms > Anime [322 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/anime">Anime</a></span></h2><p><strong>Episode 1: “A New Morning”</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="【予約受付中】新生「ToHeart」発売記念 プレミアムエディションに収録されるTVアニメ第1話『新しい朝』期間限定公開" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xgN2-4LZ-z0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Bonus Video: “Private Room”</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="【予約受付中】新生「ToHeart」発売記念 プレミアムエディションに収録される映像特典『Private Room』期間限定公開" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lubL38vZG6w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_962233"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Boss Insists GTA 6 Is Not Reason The Game's Release Date Changed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-boss-insists-gta-6-is-not-reason-the-games-release-date-changed/1100-6531221/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-boss-insists-gta-6-is-not-reason-the-games-release-date-changed.1177392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-boss-insists-gta-6-is-not-reason-the-games-release-date-changed/1100-6531221/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531221">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Gearbox Software boss Randy Pitchford has insisted that the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-release-date-moved-up/1100-6531192/" data-ref-id="1100-6531192">recent release date change</a> for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6529507/" data-ref-id="1100-6529507">Borderlands 4</a> has nothing to do with "any other product's actual or theoretical launch date."</p><p>Pitchford issued this statement on social media after many people said they thought Gearbox shifted Borderlands 4 date forward 11 days to September 12 to give Borderlands 4 more room to breathe before <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">GTA 6</a> comes out. GTA 6, of course, has no release date, but some are speculating it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-release-date-might-be-coming-into-focus/1100-6529480/" data-ref-id="1100-6529480">could launch in October. </a></p><p>So why was Borderlands 4's release date brought forward? Pitchford said it was "100% the result of confidence in the game and development trajectory backed by actual tasks and bug find/fix rates."</p><p>Pitchford said the decision was "literally 0%" about another game's confirmed or speculated release date.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/DuvalMagic/status/1917393753456664966" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Borderlands 4 shipping early is 100% the result of confidence in the game and development trajectory backed by actual tasks and bug find/fix rates. Our decision is literally 0% about any other product’s actual or theoretical launch date.</p>  — Randy Pitchford (@DuvalMagic) <a href="https://twitter.com/DuvalMagic/status/1917393753456664966?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 30, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Borderlands fans don't have to wait much longer to learn more about the game, though, as a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-focused-state-of-play-takes-place-today-how-to-watch-and-what-to-expect/1100-6531223/" data-ref-id="1100-6531223">PlayStation State of Play</a> dedicated to Borderlands 4 is taking place today, April 30. The event begins at 2 PM PT / 5 PM ET and will be streamed live.</p><p>Gearbox and Rockstar Games share a parent company in Take-Two, and the company has discussed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-and-borderlands-4-wont-be-released-close-to-each-other-take-two-boss-says/1100-6527624/" data-ref-id="1100-6527624">giving each of its titles room to shine</a>. Take-Two's 2K division also has Mafia: The Old Country on the way, and it's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mafia-the-old-country-release-date-seemingly-leaked-for-august/1100-6530796/" data-ref-id="1100-6530796">reportedly set for release in August</a>.</p><p>Some are theorizing that Take-Two could have a banner year in 2025, with Mafia: The Old Country coming in August, Borderlands 4 and NBA 2K26 in September, and GTA 6 potentially in October.</p><p>GTA 6 alone is expected to sell <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-5-could-make-3-billion-in-first-year-alone/1100-6528605/" data-ref-id="1100-6528605">40 million copies in its first year</a>, and <a href="https://ir.take2games.com/static-files/3ae54582-44bf-4163-9024-4da314c31541" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Borderlands is 2K's most successful franchise ever based on unit sales</a>. Never before have there been new entries in the Borderlands and GTA main franchises released in the same year.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Returnal PS5 Pro patch is out now, promising 2.5x the pixels]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/returnal-ps5-pro-patch-is-out-now-promising-2-5x-the-pixels/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/returnal-ps5-pro-patch-is-out-now-promising-2-5x-the-pixels.1177371/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/returnal-ps5-pro-patch-is-out-now-promising-2-5x-the-pixels/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Housemarque has released an update for the early PlayStation 5 hit, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/games/returnal">Returnal</a>, adding support for the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps5-pro">PS5 Pro</a> that brings a higher resolution experience to players of the game.</p>
<p>Once you’ve downloaded the update, the PS5 Pro is capable of running the game with up to 2.5x the pixels of the game on base PS5.</p>


<p>Looking back at early analysis of the title, Digital Foundry pegged the game’s original PS5 release to having a native 1080p pixel count that was then upscaled through temporal reconstruction to 1440p, and a further checkerboarding pass to 2160p. Housemarque hasn’t put a firm figure on the new resolution targets, but with 1920×1080 delivering just over 2 million pixels, rendering 2.5x the pixels would put this around 5 million pixels, or an uncommonly heard of 1700p. Of course, this is “up to” and we’re dealing with dynamic resolutions throughout.</p>
<p>While it’s perhaps a little disappointing that Housemarque haven’t enhanced the game with a 120Hz performance mode – 120fps is generally out of reach for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/01/19/returnal-pc-15-february-release-date-minimum-recommended-specs/">the PC version of the game</a>, even – a straight up resolution bump still has plenty value for increasing image clarity and reducing the effects that temporal and checkboarding upscaling have on image quality.</p>
<p>Looking back on Returnal,<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/04/29/returnal-review-ps5/"> our glowing 9/10 review</a> of the PS5 launch window game said, “It feels immensely satisfying to be sat here in 2021, eons after playing Super Stardust HD on PS3, and see just how far Housemarque has come. Offering a visual bullet hell spectacle, a showcase for the DualSense controller and a rewarding sci-fi narrative woven around the roguelike loop, we can say with unflinching confidence that Returnal is the PS5’s best game to date.”</p>

<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/12/saros-is-the-next-time-looper-shooter-from-returnal-devs-housemarque/">Housemarque announced Saros</a>, their next project during February’s State of Play, which following in the footsteps of Returnal’s roguelike shooter form, starring Rahul Kohli as our player character Arjun Devraj.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://xcancel.com/Housemarque/status/1917443799619342788">Housemarque</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Multiplayer Maps Discovered in the Game’s Files]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-multiplayer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-multiplayer-maps-discovered-in-the-game%E2%80%99s-files.1177368/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-multiplayer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows may get expanded in the future with a multiplayer mode, judging from some recent discoveries.</p>
<p>As reported on X by game modder Sliderv2, the game's current version features, inside its Bootstrap file, a mention of a few developer test maps for multiplayer and PVP. This not only gives more credibility to some earlier rumors that suggested the new entry in the series would feature multiplayer in some form, but also suggests that it could still be coming at some point in the future, especially considering the game has yet to receive any major new feature as some of its predecessors did after launch.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Rumors of a planned multiplayer mode for Assassin's Creed Shadows may be true. The Boostrap file mentions a few developer test maps for Multiplayer and PVP. <a href="https://t.co/GJYqn99pNT">pic.twitter.com/GJYqn99pNT</a></p>
<p>— Sliderv2 (@Totocko97) <a href="https://twitter.com/Totocko97/status/1917365143895433361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Regarding content, however, Assassin's Creed Shadows is not lacking, as the game is full of side activities to complete as Naoe and Yasuke further their war against the Shinbakufu. While the game is not on par with the best open-world RPG available on the market, it is a solid and enjoyable game, and one of the best entries in the series, as I highlighted in my<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/assassins-creed-shadows-a-gorgeous-dive-into-feudal-chaos/"> review.</a></p>
<p><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows is one of the finest entries in the series, successfully bringing back stealth-oriented gameplay while retaining the RPG mechanics and refined combat mechanics seen in previous entries in the series, seamlessly integrating them with the dual protagonist setup and a well-paced story that doesn't overstay its welcome. While the game still features way more content and gameplay systems than necessary, its rendition of Feudal Japan is among the best ever seen in a video game, and it is well worth experiencing for the vast majority of players.</em></p>
<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S worldwide.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devil May Cry-inspired Lost Soul Aside delayed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/devil-may-cry-inspired-lost-soul-aside-delayed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/devil-may-cry-inspired-lost-soul-aside-delayed.1177359/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/devil-may-cry-inspired-lost-soul-aside-delayed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Ultizero Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>It's been nearly a decade since the first reveal of the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lost-soul-aside-launches-in-2025-nine-years-after-devil-may-cry-and-final-fantasy-15-inspired-action-games-reveal">Devil May Cry and Final Fantasy 15-inspired RPG action game Lost Soul Aside</a>. Now the wait is <em>almost </em>over - though things are now going to take a little longer than expected.</p>
<p>Lost Soul Aside is still set to debut later this year but - in order to allow for some extra polish and whatnot - it will not arrive quite as soon as initially planned, its developer has said. "To match the standards Ultizero Games have set for ourselves, we are going to take some additional time to polish the game," <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3378960/view/507326880609731162?l=latam">Lost Souls Aside game director and studio head Yang Bing explained on Steam</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Lost Soul Aside – Gameplay Trailer | PS5 &amp; PC Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nJM3z2pTLaQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Lost Soul Aside – Gameplay Trailer | PS5 &amp; PC Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nJM3z2pTLaQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nJM3z2pTLaQ?autoplay=1" title="Lost Soul Aside – Gameplay Trailer | PS5 &amp; PC Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Lost Soul Aside – Gameplay Trailer | PS5 &amp; PC Games. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nJM3z2pTLaQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As such, Lost Soul Aside will now release on 29th August. It was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/after-nearly-a-decade-of-development-playstation-published-action-game-gets-a-release-date">initially slated for 30th May</a>, which was the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/here-are-the-pc-requirements-for-elden-ring-nightreign">same day as Elden Ring's co-op spinoff Nightreign</a>. Bing said the team was "truly grateful" for all those who have responded positively since the game's announcement, and everyone involved wants to make sure Lost Soul Aside releases with a "high-quality game experience" for fans.</p>
<p>The upcoming game is being published by PlayStation, and will be launching across PC and - of course - PS5.</p>
<p>"Embark on an epic odyssey to save your younger sister – and the whole of humanity – from mysterious dimensional invaders from beyond the starlit skies in Lost Soul Aside," reads the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3378960/Lost_Soul_Aside/">official game description over on Steam</a>.</p>
<p>"Run the gauntlet of formidable enemies and colossal bosses in this breathtakingly stylish single player action-adventure RPG; chaining weapon and spectacular attack combos in high-octane, dynamic combat. Adapt your fighting style, solve puzzles, and evolve incredible abilities on a truly heroic quest."</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Ultizero Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>RPG's are having a bit of a moment right now. Earlier this month, reactive turn-based RPG <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> released, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/clair-obscur-expedition-33-hits-500k-sales-in-one-day">going on to sell one million copies in just three days</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, dark fantasy action RPG <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/chinese-dark-fantasy-wuchang-fallen-feathers-release-date-announced">Wuchang: Fallen Feathers secured itself a release date yesterday</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>