<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 14:39:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Riven remake release date is June 25th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/03/riven-remake-release-date-is-june-25th/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/riven-remake-release-date-is-june-25th.888063/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/03/riven-remake-release-date-is-june-25th/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Cyan Worlds has announced the release date of the Riven remake, set for June 25th, with the game being available on PC, Mac, Meta Quest 2, and Meta Quest 3. This complete overhaul of the classic 1997 game brings back many of the original creators to re-envision Riven for modern audiences. The original itself was the sequel to Myst and had built upon the foundations of that influential puzzle game too.</p>
<p><iframe title="Riven Launch Trailer PC 16x9 4k FINAL" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LN1TQm942_U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The remake of Riven will have new content, such as additional puzzles and an expanded storyline beyond the original game. It will also feature an enlarged world encompassing environments like jungles and caverns across the game’s five islands, offering both familiar secrets for veteran players and fresh content for all players to enjoy. The flatscreen and VR versions of Riven are being developed concurrently to ensure a consistent experience across all platforms. The release date for PC and VR has been announced, but the console release date remains unconfirmed at this time.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Soulmask Sales Hit 100k in Less Than 48 Hours]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/soulmask-sales-100k</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/soulmask-sales-hit-100k-in-less-than-48-hours.888060/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/soulmask-sales-100k<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Indie survival craft-'em-up&nbsp;<em>Soulmask&nbsp;</em>has managed to smash through a major sales barrier in less than 48 hours on sale.</p>

<p>Speaking <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2646460/view/4150709171067099848" rel="noopener" target="_blank">on Steam over the weekend</a>, developer CampFire Studio and publisher Qooland Games announced that&nbsp;<em>Soulmask&nbsp;</em>sales reached a total of 100,000 in just 31 hours.</p>

<p>The two studios go on to say that the game reached the number two spot on Steam's global bestseller list in just four hours, and that after eight hours,&nbsp;<em>Soulmask&nbsp;</em>was in "the top 1 position for paid games worldwide".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/soulmask-sales-100k-art.jpg?itok=fPGU6jU1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/soulmask-sales-100k-art.jpg?itok=l8QgO3g1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Soulmask&nbsp;</em>has already hit a pretty impressive sales milestone, and it's not showing signs of stopping.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Soulmask</em>'s devs also say they've reached the number one spot in paid game sales across the US, the UK, Canada, Germany, France, Japan, and Brazil, which is pretty darn impressive.</p>

<p>CampFire and Qooland also point to&nbsp;<em>Soulmask</em>'s 80% Very Positive review rating on Steam, with the two studios saying they're "immensely grateful" for the support and pledging to "do our utmost to improve the quality of&nbsp;<em>Soulmask</em>" in the coming weeks and months.</p>

<p>The game's meteoric rise has been impressive indeed.&nbsp;<em>Soulmask&nbsp;</em>was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/soulmask-steam-survival-crafter">released on Friday</a>&nbsp;and quickly found itself climbing the Steam player charts, attracting a peak of almost 17,000 players within a few short hours.</p>

<p>At time of writing, the game's 24-hour player total, <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2646460/charts/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">according to SteamDB</a>, stood at 38,746, which is also its all-time peak player count. Suffice it to say this one's not going away any time soon.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/soulmask-sales-100k-fire.jpg?itok=EzWT4EgF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/soulmask-sales-100k-fire.jpg?itok=W3OWPEoU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Have you played&nbsp;<em>Soulmask&nbsp;</em>yet?</figcaption></figure><p>For the uninitiated,&nbsp;<em>Soulmask&nbsp;</em>is an indie survival-crafter in the vein of games like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/enshrouded-roadmap-2024">Enshrouded</a>&nbsp;</em>or&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/valheim-ashlands-update-ptr-launch"><em>Valheim</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Promising over 500 hours of content in its current state (yes, really),&nbsp;<em>Soulmask&nbsp;</em>tasks you with building a tribe, exploring the world around you, and scavenging for supplies and resources to help you survive.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The game offers a "vast world" to explore, with plenty of different biomes to discover and creatures to fight. It's in Early Access right now, where the devs say it will remain "for one year at least".</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Soulmask&nbsp;</em>on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2646460/Soulmask/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a>. Stay tuned for more on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for five years, and in those five years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't expect big reveals at Summer Games Fest, says Geoff Keighley]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-expect-big-reveals-at-summer-games-fest-says-geoff-keighley</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dont-expect-big-reveals-at-summer-games-fest-says-geoff-keighley.888057/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-expect-big-reveals-at-summer-games-fest-says-geoff-keighley<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>He's "expectation setting"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/geoff-keighly-summer-games-fest-2024-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Twitch / Summer Game Fest</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Since <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/e3-is-officially-dead-say-esa">the death of E3</a>, June has descended into a chaotic clusterfunk of trailers, broadcasts, announcements, and a generalised frenzy of publicity-seeking barking noises. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/summer-game-fest">Summer Game Fest</a> has emerged as a hub for a lot of developers seeking eyes. The 2-hour show hosted by marketing man Geoff Keighley will be broadcasting on Friday, blasting you in the ocular nerves with, probably, a lot of games. However, most of these games will not be brand new, exciting reveals, said Keighley himself in a fresh Twitch Q &amp; A. "There will be, definitely, new announcements," he said, "but the show is largely focused on, I think, existing games that have new updates for fans." He's mentioning this ahead of time, he said, to set expectations.
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.twitch.tv/?video=v2162199165&amp;parent=www.rockpapershotgun.com&amp;autoplay=false" frameborder="0" loading="lazy">
</iframe> </p>
</figure>
<p>
During the session, Keighley confirmed that a lot of games wouldn't be on show. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> will not by shown, for example. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/kingdom-hearts-4">Kingdom Hearts 4</a> is also off the table, as is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-wolf-among-us-2">The Wolf Among Us 2</a>. Neither should we expect anything about upcoming BioShock-like shooter <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/judas">Judas</a>, nor anything on future <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/five-nights-at-freddys">Five Nights At Freddy's</a> games. Keighley contrasted the Summer Game Fest with his other big show, The Game Awards, which is normally the place for reveals, he says.
</p>
<p>
"[The] Game Awards has a lot of usually big surprises - we're thankful for those - and big, new reveals. This [Summer Game Fest] is largely focused on announced stuff...
</p>
<p>
"There definitely are things that are being announced but this is not a show that has a lot of like 'coming in 2026' or '2027', or teasers for games that are years and years out... That's generally what I would say in terms of expectation setting."
</p>
<p>
It makes sense that the largest reveals will not automatically flock to Keighley's flag, given the splintered state of the summer games bonanza in recent years. Even before E3 itself was entirely dissolved, many publishers have been hosting their own events in which bigger announcements are traditionally made. 
</p>
<p>
Keighley did highlight some games that would make an appearance, however, including dino-punching hunt 'em up <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a>, medieval <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-2">Kingdom Come 2: Deliverance</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/metaphor-refantazio">Metaphor: Refantazio</a>, the upcoming fantasy JRPG from the creators of Persona. So that's something! It's worth noting that Geoff's Jambalaya is followed by indie-focused showcases such as Day of the Devs and the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/devolvers-e3-showcase-was-again-a-highlight-in-an-underwhelming-year">historically excellent</a> Devolver Digital Direct. 
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Riven Preview - Everything Old is New Again]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/riven-preview-everything-old-is-new-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/riven-preview-everything-old-is-new-again.888054/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/riven-preview-everything-old-is-new-again<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It’s been a solid 27 years since the release of <em>Riven</em>, the adventure follow-up to the much-acclaimed <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/myst-remake-xbox-and-pc-release-confirmed"><em>Myst</em></a>. Like <em>Myst</em>, <em>Riven</em> is about to see a remake of its own, bringing the original up to scratch using the current generation graphics technology of Unreal Engine 5.</p>

<p>It’s not an easy task – the original <em>Riven</em> has a lot of history behind it, and as such, expectations need to be set properly in place. <em>Riven</em> is important to its developer, Cyan, who had used the resources Myst provided to really tell a story. To them, they wanted <em>Riven</em> to feel like Lord of the Rings to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/review/realmyst-masterpiece-edition-pc-review"><em>Myst</em></a>’s Hobbit.</p>

<p>After watching the technology change over the years, and their ability as a company, Cyan felt the time was right to do a revisit to <em>Riven</em> justice.</p>

<p>The goal was simply this: let’s make a 3D version of the original <em>Riven</em> without messing with anything. But then, the team started questioning things and realizing they could change things to make them more coherent. Thus, the changes made had to make sense. It was a meticulous process, but not one done from a corporate standpoint. This was done for the fans.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riven-screenshot-01.jpg?itok=Ggy8q8Nt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riven-screenshot-01.jpg?itok=grqJmJJp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>With Unreal Engine 5 at their fingertips, Cyan was afforded a lot of freedom. Whilst the game is 3D, there is an optional 2D and VR mode, with mobile VR also supported throughout.</p>

<p>We had a chance to attend a preview presentation showing off a little bit of the game, as well as take our own turn exploring for ourselves with a special demo build ahead of <em>Riven</em>’s just-announced release date of June 25.</p>

<p>The demo begins with a cutscene, and you, the player character of sorts, are given a mysterious book. This book seems to be important for some reason or another, so it’s best to pay attention. Paying attention is a key aspect of <em>Riven</em> after all.</p>

<p>It’s important to note that things aren’t exactly the same as the original <em>Riven</em>, so for those old fans, rest assured that things have been added for good reason. Expect little details from the start, such as items on the desk in the opening scene. These details are meant for continuity and story reasons prevalent throughout <em>Riven</em>.</p>

<p>This was done so that old players can hopefully get a clue that this isn’t just the same game – it’s a chance to look at it with fresh eyes.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riven-screenshot-02.jpg?itok=B4o91D3_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riven-screenshot-02.jpg?itok=FAvoSiWm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As the demo continues, you’re thrown in jail immediately, and a man speaks to you in an unknown language. He takes the book you were given and seems excited about it, but his joy is short-lived as he falls and drops the book. Another person appears and sets you free, but not without taking the book with them.</p>

<p>At the jump, with free roaming now available, it’s important for original players to avoid assuming this is the same <em>Riven</em>. Details from the original may have changed and little things like this are part of the enhanced narrative.</p>

<p>Specifically, a lot of effort went into delineating the different areas while still maintaining the visual feeling of the original <em>Riven</em>. So, while there are those changes, the main essence is the same.</p>

<p>For example, you can look through portals and see a bit more than what you could before, and areas with a window to the outside are visible from the exterior.</p>

<p>Exploring around the cliff face in the demo, we eventually come upon a golden room, and outside of it, there is a button you can press to sort of spin it around to open up other places. The room itself has a reason for being there, and the main challenge is figuring out how to use the room to advance through the game.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riven-screenshot-03.jpg?itok=qBYUjRIc 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riven-screenshot-03.jpg?itok=9SrbJeYj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>There’s a lot more attention to detail throughout this remake, as is the essence of <em>Riven</em>. You can find little daggers, for example, that might suggest some rebels are trying to draw your attention to something. Maybe they’ll help you get around a locked door – it’s important to examine everything you can.</p>

<p>On the presentation side of things, there are a lot of sounds and performances that carried over from the original <em>Riven</em>, including some of the original voice actors. The level crafted in Unreal Engine 5 is beautiful, and the modeling of the rockery and textures are detailed throughout.</p>

<p>It’s these details that allow you to be more observant, which can certainly help when things don’t go the way you expect them to. Be sure to pay attention to what you interact with as the ability to look around in real time is encouraged. It's also noteworthy to express just how relaxing moving around the world of <em>Riven</em> feels to be. You can spend a lot of time just taking in the details, or taking out your journal and reading some of the entries found within. It seems like there will be a lot more to uncover on the narrative side of things in the full release.</p>

<p>While we’re not able to check out the VR capabilities for <em>Riven</em>, the team at Cyan has told us that there will be comfort settings available including a snap camera, teleporting to different areas, smaller windows in some enclosed areas, and even environment settings.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/riven-screenshot-04.jpg?itok=2TRJZESM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/riven-screenshot-04.jpg?itok=8vYoJpg0 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The default settings should be comfortable, and there are further accessibility settings overall for things like colorblindness, and a lot of other considerations the team tried to address.</p>

<p><em>Riven</em> will be available for PC, Mac, and Meta Quest 2 and 3. Additional platforms will be forthcoming, but Cyan wasn’t able to say what those are quite yet. The playable demo featured in this preview will be available during the Steam Next Fest this month.</p>

<hr><p><em>TechRaptor was invited to preview <strong>Riven</strong> at a digital event by the publisher.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Erren is a staff writer for TechRaptor whose writing experience stems from years of helming Nova Crystallis – a website dedicated to everything Square Enix… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/erren-van-duine">More about Erren</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Slug Tactics launches this fall for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/metal-slug-tactics-launches-this-fall-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-slug-tactics-launches-this-fall-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.888051/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/metal-slug-tactics-launches-this-fall-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PC demo available from June 10 to 17.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Strategy RPG [320 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/strategy-rpg">Strategy RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Metal Slug Tactics [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/metal-slug-tactics">Metal Slug Tactics</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,139 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,743 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,188 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,395 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1590760/Metal_Slug_Tactics/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> this fall, publisher <a title="Companies > Dotemu [89 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/focus-entertainment/dotemu">Dotemu</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Leikir Studio [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/leikir-studio">Leikir Studio</a> announced. The <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [45,155 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,109 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> versions are newly announced. A demo will be available for a limited time for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1590760/Metal_Slug_Tactics/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> from June 10 to 17 during Steam Next Fest. <span id="more-886856"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1590760/Metal_Slug_Tactics/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Metal Slug Tactics</em> brings the explosive charm and nostalgic fun of the cult <em><a title="Platforms > Meta [102 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a>l Slug</em> series to the tactical scene! Get ready for an intense ride through the best of both worlds: classic <a title="Genres > Arcade [52 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> <a title="Genres > Action [1,868 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> and <a title="Genres > Roguelite [171 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> tactical thrills. Jump into the combat zone and revive your <em>Metal Slug</em> nostalgia in a whole new way!</p><p><strong>Tactical <a title="Genres > RPG [16,297 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> With <a title="Genres > Roguelike [216 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">Roguelike</a> Elements</strong></p><p><em>Metal Slug Tactics</em> offers a fresh perspective on the iconic battles of the <em>Metal Slug</em> series. Lead your squad to victory through strategic guile and superior firepower in a perfect blend of classic action and tactical depth. Unleash powerful special attacks and shape the outcome of each encounter!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Accumulate experience after each battle to unlock new weapons or bonus perks to upgrade your team’s firepower and tactical skills.</p><p>Assemble your team and rewrite the rules in this modern tribute to a cult classic!</p><p><strong>Get Your Gear, Soldiers! Mission Start!</strong></p><p>Choose between iconic brothers-in-arms from across the <em>Metal Slug</em> series and create the perfect team to stop Morden’s devious plans.</p><p>Determine the best weapon loadouts and mods to maximize combo efficiency on the battlefield.</p><p>Launch simultaneous attacks with the “SYNC” mechanic to deal massive damage to the enemy! And if your team is in trouble, you can always call in some reinforcements and watch the big guns at work: heavy artillery, airstrikes, the glorious <em>Metal Slug</em> itself—you name it, you get it!</p><p><strong>Fight Your Way to Victory</strong></p><p>Embark on an exalting campaign through beautiful, hand-crafted maps to end the war and defeat the infamous Rebel Army once and for all! You’re going to face many challenges, so brace yourself for countless deaths, but don’t give up and push through.</p><p>Whether you’re a skilled veteran or a new recruit, play and replay your favorite missions, learn precious strategic insight from each <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,505 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> and hone your skills with each hard-fought victory.</p><p>Gain experience, level up your operatives, adapt to your enemies, and remember: every defeat is a lesson, yet triumph awaits those who refuse to surrender!</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>Donald Morden is back! After years of hiding in a country opposed to the World Government, the devious General patiently staged a coup. Now, he is finally ready to take revenge upon the World with the army he has secretly gathered throughout the years.</p><p>The Peregrine Falcon Squad will have to do everything in their power to make it through the enemy lines and take down General Morden before the war escalates into catastrophe!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Discover the first tactical RPG in the <em>Metal Slug</em> franchise.</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a huge replayability with its die-and-retry roguelite progression.</li><li>Enjoy amazing pixel art graphics, a heartfelt tribute to the series.</li><li>Battle Morden’s Army in 110 hand-crafted maps and 20 different mission types.</li><li>Bring the perfect setup for every mission with 36 different weapons and 176 weapon mods.</li><li>Choose between nine iconic characters from the series and create the perfect team.</li><li>Experiment with 36 loadouts and combos to outsmart your enemies.</li><li>Challenge iconic bosses from the <em>Metal Slug</em> universe.</li><li>Headbang all the way with an amazing soundtrack by Tee Lopes.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Window Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Metal Slug Tactics - New trailer | Coming Fall 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kjQ5hyo-Jkk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Riven remake launches June 25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/riven-remake-launches-june-25</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/riven-remake-launches-june-25.888048/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/riven-remake-launches-june-25<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Available for PC and Quest.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Riven [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/riven">Riven</a></em>, the remake of <em>Riven: The Sequel to Myst</em>, will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1712350/Riven/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/riven/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a>, Mac via Mac App Store, and virtual reality via <a title="Platforms > Quest [102 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest 2 and Quest 3</a> on June 25, developer Cyan announced. Users who pre-order the game on Quest will receive 11 percent off the $34.99 price. PC and Mac users will receive 10 percent off at launch, but only for a limited time. <span id="more-886677"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Cyan:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Embark on a thrilling <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,505 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> that delves deeper into the enigmatic universe that Cyan’s first game <em>Myst</em> only hinted at. <em>Riven</em> seamlessly weaves its puzzles into a sprawling and decaying world, immersing players in a conflict between the world’s villainous ruler and those rebelling against him.</p><p>In this from-the-ground-up and expanded remake of the 1997 best-seller, players will be able to explore this lush, mysterious age with complete freedom of movement and a world brought to life through updated visuals, gameplay, and freedom of movement. While <em>Riven</em> has been a video game touchstone for decades, this modern update allowed <a title="Companies > Cyan [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cyan">Cyan Worlds</a> to add depth and scope to both the story and world..</p><p>The key team of creatives that made 1997’s <em>Riven</em> such a landmark game contributed to bring the game to a modern audience. Puzzles have been refreshed, new characters will be introduced, and new challenges are waiting to be discovered. Whether you’re a fan of the original or new to <em>Riven</em>, the expanded storylines and breathtaking visuals will take players on an exhilarating journey like no other.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Riven</em> is a modern remake of 1997’s monster hit <em>Riven: The Sequel to Myst</em> and is a love letter to classic narrative-driven puzzle games of the ’90s. When exploring <em>Riven</em>‘s decaying age, the player will feel like an archeologist, slowly unraveling the mysteries revealed by carefully exploring <em>Riven</em>‘s five enigmatic islands. Players will lose themselves in the world as they uncover clues, decipher foreign languages, and immerse themselves in the game’s intricate lore.</p><p>Key Features:</p><ul><li><strong>Intricate Storytelling and Mind-Bending Puzzles</strong> – Challenge your intellect with <em>Riven</em>‘s cunning puzzles woven throughout its narrative.</li><li><strong>Immersive Environments and Stunning Graphics</strong> – Explore surreal islands, each meticulously crafted with unparalleled attention to detail, from dense, lush jungles to awe-inspiring caverns.</li><li><strong>An Expanded World To Explore</strong> – Encounter an immersive and visually stunning world that will captivate newcomers and reveal new mysteries for long-time fans.</li><li><strong>Fully Re-imagined Gaming <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong> – Experience <em>Riven</em> like never before, with free movement through a real-time 3D environment. Whether you’re a seasoned adventurer returning to <em>Riven</em> or a newcomer eager to explore <em>Riven</em>‘s mysteries for the first time, this immersive and visually stunning world will captivate you.</li><li><strong>A Truly Immersive Experience Developed in Parallel for Flatscreen and <a title="Genres > Virtual Reality [142 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/virtual-reality">Virtual Reality</a></strong> – Cyan Worlds is simultaneously developing the flatscreen and virtual reality versions of the game to ensure a high-quality experience regardless of players’ platform of choice.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>PC</strong></p><p><iframe title="Riven Launch Trailer PC 16x9 4k FINAL" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LN1TQm942_U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Quest</strong></p><p><iframe title="Riven | Official Meta Quest Launch Trailer | Available June 25th | 4k" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ap6fnRLXk20?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asus ROG Ally X Full Specs Revealed, Up For Preorder Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/asus-rog-ally-x-full-specs-revealed-up-for-preorder-now/1100-6523874/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/asus-rog-ally-x-full-specs-revealed-up-for-preorder-now.888045/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/asus-rog-ally-x-full-specs-revealed-up-for-preorder-now/1100-6523874/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523874">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Preorders are now live for the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1844055374637939299%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fasus-rog-ally-x-full-specs-revealed-up-for-preorder-now%2F1100-6523874%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus ROG Ally X</a> which launches in July as a major revision to the Windows PC gaming handheld introduced by Asus last year. This new version from Asus looks set to address some of the problems from the original device, as it has made several tweaks to its design.</p><p>While the Steam Deck is still seen as the go-to gaming machine in the market, the ROG Ally emerged as a strong alternative thanks to its flexibility and powerful mobile technology packed inside of an attractive frame.</p><p>The ROG Ally X will be released on July 22 and is priced at $800.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311986-rog-ally-x-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4311986" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311986-rog-ally-x-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4311986"></a><figcaption>ROG Ally X</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311986-rog-ally-x-2.jpg"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311987-rog-ally-x-1.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311988-rog-ally-x-3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311989-rog-ally-x-4.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311990-rog-ally-x-5.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311991-rog-ally-x-6.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311992-rog-ally-x-7.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4311987,1300-4311988,1300-4311989,1300-4311990,1300-4311991,1300-4311992" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4311987-rog-ally-x-1.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4311988-rog-ally-x-3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4311989-rog-ally-x-4.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4311990-rog-ally-x-5.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4311991-rog-ally-x-6.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4311992-rog-ally-x-7.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311987-rog-ally-x-1.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311988-rog-ally-x-3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311989-rog-ally-x-4.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311990-rog-ally-x-5.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311991-rog-ally-x-6.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4311992-rog-ally-x-7.jpg"></figure><p>For the ROG Ally X, Asus has addressed the criticism from users related to the 2023 model. It has upgraded battery life, RAM, storage, and a more ergonomically friendly chassis design, as well as improved cooling and connectivity.</p><p>Internally, you'll find a 1TB M.2 SSD, 24GB of LPDDR5X-7500 RAM, and a monstrous 80Wh battery alongside improved joysticks--rated for 5 million rotation cycles-- and a more precise D-pad. The PC gaming handheld will still be using a Z1 Extreme chipset and the same seven-inch 120Hz VRR screen, but these parts of the original model's design were lauded for offering a powerful gaming experience.</p><p>These changes have made it slightly heavier as it now weighs 678g, but alongside a custom cooling system, lighter circuit boards, and other improvements, the ROG Ally X is aiming to be a longer-lasting and more comfortable device to play your games on. Thanks to its design, the internal storage space can be upgraded easily, and the SD card reader has also been replaced. Hopefully, this will fix the issue of the ROG Ally randomly ejecting Micro SD cards.</p><p>Last year's ROG Ally was a great device when it first launched, even with several issues like the aforementioned poor battery life and its bad habit of weaponizing Micro SD cards. The Z1 Extreme version proved to be more than capable of running demanding games once you'd made a few graphical concessions, and in our own testing, we had titles like Marvel's Spider-Man, Cyberpunk 2077, Street Fighter 6, and Forza Motorsport running very smoothly on it.</p><p>The other big plus was the adoption of a Windows operating system, which gives you more room to download your favorite games from a variety of digital marketplaces, like Steam, Ubisoft Connect, the Epic Games Store, and the Xbox store. If you have a Game Pass subscription, it's quite nice to have a massive library of games right out of the box. Admittedly, Windows on a small screen isn't the best to use, but in terms of performance, it runs pretty smoothly on the ROG Ally.</p><h2>Asus ROG Ally X specs</h2><table dir="ltr"><tbody><tr><td><strong>Operating System</strong></td><td>Windows 11 Home</td></tr><tr><td><strong>CPU</strong></td><td>AMD Ryzen Z1 Extreme Processor: Zen 4 architecture, 8-core/16-thread (up to 5.1 GHz boost)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>GPU</strong></td><td>AMD Radeon Graphics (AMD RDNA 3, 12 CUs, up to 2.7 GHz, up to 8.6 Teraflops)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>APU Power Draw</strong></td><td>9 to 30 Watts</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Display</strong></td><td>7-inch IPS panel (Glossy finish, 500 nits peak brightness, 7ms response time, touch screen)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Resolution</strong></td><td>1920x1080 @ 120 Hz refresh rate (AMD FreeSync Premium)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Memory</strong></td><td>24 GB LPDDR5X</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Storage</strong></td><td>1TB PCIe 4.0 NVMe M.2 SSD (2280)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Ports</strong></td><td>1x 3.5mm Combo Audio Jack<br>1x Thunderbolt 4 support DisplayPort / power delivery<br>1x USB 3.2 Gen 2 Type-C support DisplayPort / power delivery<br>1x UHS-II microSD card reader (supports SD, SDXC and SDHC)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Battery</strong></td><td>80WHrs, 4S1P, 4-cell Li-ion</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Power Supply</strong></td><td>65W AC Adapter, Output: 20V DC, 3.25A, 65W Input: 100~240V AC 50/60Hz universal</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Weight</strong></td><td>678 g / 1.49 lbs</td></tr></tbody></table>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Someone Got The Original Fallout Running On Nintendo 3DS]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/someone-got-the-original-fallout-running-on-nintendo-3ds/1100-6523882/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/someone-got-the-original-fallout-running-on-nintendo-3ds.888042/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/someone-got-the-original-fallout-running-on-nintendo-3ds/1100-6523882/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523882">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">The renewed interest in the Fallout franchise has led to one person playing the first game in the post-apocalyptic RPG series on a platform discontinued years ago: Nintendo 3DS. That's right, it's now possible--thanks to a mod--to visit the wasteland in its original form on the handheld system.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.thegamer.com/fallout-first-game-3ds-mod/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Gamer</a> spotted that someone is playing through Fallout in a way that didn't seem possible. The RPG is technically only available on PC, without any sort of port on Switch, PlayStation, or Xbox. However, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/classicfallout/comments/1d22ukh/finally_gonna_play_through_and_finish_fallout_1/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=post_embed&amp;utm_content=whitespace&amp;embed_host_url=https://www.thegamer.com/fallout-first-game-3ds-mod/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a Reddit user</a> transferred their "original, legally purchased copy" over to 3DS and says it's "running great." The only issue they've experienced is the fact you have to "cycle between left and right click with [the] L button."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1609576297" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6463893,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;It%27s%20Time%20To%20Remake%20Fallout%201%20%26%202&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:788,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/its-time-to-remake-fallout-1-2\/2300-6463893\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463893\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463893\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463893\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6463893&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6463893,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6523882&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;fallout&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,macintosh,linux,3ds&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;interplay,bethesda-softworks,mac-play&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;fallout&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;fallout&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6463893},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6463893\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4287888-falloutremakes_v1_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/6QFRwaEV.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1713315600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="6QFRwaEV" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> It's Time To Remake Fallout 1 &amp; 2</p>
      </div>
<p>It's worth noting that <a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/55888/~/intellectual-property-%26-piracy-faq#s2q6" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Nintendo disputes the legality of playing a ROM of a game on another system</a> simply because you own a physical copy already.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-games-see-a-massive-player-boost-after-shows-release/1100-6522673/" data-ref-id="1100-6522673">Fallout games have seen massive player boosts</a> since the Prime Video TV series premiered in April. However, the main beneficiaries from the franchise have been those easily available on current consoles, such as Fallout 76, Fallout 4, and Fallout: New Vegas. Things don't stop there, though. The latest Fortnite season has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallouts-t-60-power-armor-confirmed-for-fortnite/1100-6523630/" data-ref-id="1100-6523630">Fallout crossover content, including the T-60 power armor</a>, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/leaked-call-of-duty-crossover-with-fallout-reveals-vault-dweller-skins/1100-6523789/" data-ref-id="1100-6523789">a leak points to a Call of Duty collaboration with Fallout</a> in the near-future as well.</p><p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-3ds-has-been-officially-discontinued/1100-6482298/" data-ref-id="1100-6482298">Nintendo 3DS was officially retired in 2020</a> when the company stopped production on the handheld. The system, which launched in 2011, ended up selling over 75 million units over its lifetime.</p><p dir="ltr">Looking ahead, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-fallout-games-are-being-planned-todd-howard-says/1100-6523813/" data-ref-id="1100-6523813">new Fallout games are being planned</a> at Bethesda, but no timeline has been given for when the next entry could arrive. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fallout-season-2-release-date-trailers-news/2900-5269/#1" data-ref-id="2900-5269">A second season of the Fallout show</a> is also in the works.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge Of Spirits Guides Players To Xbox In August]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/06/03/kena-bridge-of-spirits-guides-players-to-xbox-in-august</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kena-bridge-of-spirits-guides-players-to-xbox-in-august.888039/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/06/03/kena-bridge-of-spirits-guides-players-to-xbox-in-august<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Kena: Bridge of Spirits is making the leap to Xbox in August. The 2021 action-adventure game has been available only on PlayStation and PC, and its move to Microsoft’s platform comes with some new in-game goodies.</p>

<p>As the debut title by Ember Lab, this story-driven action game stars Kena, a young spirit guide who must unravel the mystery of a destroyed village by helping lost souls move on to the afterlife. She’s assisted by the Rot, tiny, adorable spirits Kena can command to aid in puzzle-solving and combat. The game’s design draws inspiration from series such as The Legend of Zelda, while combat has shades of From Software’s Dark Souls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kena hits Xbox Series X/S and Xbox One on August 15 for $39.99 and will include exclusive pirate-themed Rot hats, a Golden Rot skin, and a unique staff for Kena. A new physical premium edition will also be available and will consist of these items, a digital soundtrack, and an exclusive sticker sheet. The Xbox version also includes the <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2022/08/22/kena-bridge-of-spirits-anniversary-update-out-next-month-alongside-steam-debut">Anniversary DLC update</a>, which includes the Spirit Guide Trials, additional Kena outfits, and New Game+</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rrqpJuUfYKI" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>We awarded Kena: Bridge of Spirits a 9 out of 10, with former editor-in-chief Andrew Reiner writing in <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/kena-bridge-of-spirits/kena-bridge-of-spirits-review-one-of-the-best-adventures-of-the-year">his review,</a>&nbsp;"Bridge of Spirits stumbles a little in spots, yet confidently sprints into the heart of the adventure, rewarding the player with secrets galore and visuals that are almost always worth admiring. If you love Zelda-like games or are just looking for an experience that will make you smile every step of the way, you can’t go wrong with Kena: Bridge of Spirits." The game was also a sales success, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2021/10/25/kena-bridge-of-spirits-has-already-recouped-its-development-costs">recouping its development costs</a> a month after its initial release in September 2021.&nbsp;</p>

<p>You can learn more about Kena: Bridge of Spirits by checking out our behind-the-scenes features in our <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/kena">cover story hub</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 to get official mod support this September]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/baldurs-gate-3-to-get-official-mod-support-this-september/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=baldurs-gate-3-to-get-official-mod-support-this-september</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-to-get-official-mod-support-this-september.888036/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/baldurs-gate-3-to-get-official-mod-support-this-september/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=baldurs-gate-3-to-get-official-mod-support-this-september<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="430" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Developer Larian Studios <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4179982568653520452" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed in a Community Update</a> on Steam today that the already massive cRPG <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em> will soon be getting even bigger with official mod support as part of Patch 7. The Patch will be split into two phases with the first beginning today in the form of a closed alpha for established mod authors in the community. In September Patch 7 will release publically adding the highly requested feature.</p> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"></figure> <h2 id="h-a-universe-of-possibilities-for-baldur-s-gate-3-via-mods" data-injectable="false">A universe of possibilities for <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em> via mods</h2> <p data-characters="304" data-current-count="604" data-injectable="true">Even though you can technically download and install mods in <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em> today, the process is a bit monotonous, especially for those not familiar with modding. Official mod support will streamline the process while also improving compatibility across the various platforms you can play <em>BG3</em> on.</p>
 <p data-characters="228" data-current-count="228" data-injectable="false">Support will be implemented via Mod.Io, a popular modding solution that allows developers to integrate modding into their title in a more managed format, allowing the mods to be downloaded and utilized on a variety of platforms.</p> <p data-characters="110" data-current-count="338" data-injectable="false">At first, modding will launch on PC via Steam with support coming to Mac, PlayStation, and Xbox shortly after.</p> <p data-characters="170" data-current-count="508" data-injectable="true">The Patch 7 update will also implement the <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em> Toolkit which will enhance the modding process for modders and players alike with the following features:</p>
 <ul data-found-items="8" data-current-count="320" data-injectable="false"> <li>Access the editor to create your own mods.</li> <li>Upload mods directly to mod.io servers.</li> <li>Load levels read-only to look at all the local entities, as well as the setup, and test your mods in-game while creating them.</li> <li>Get access to our internal editors for supported asset types such as textures and visual models, allowing you to override them directly in your mod through the developer interface.</li> <li>Publish your mod via the editor where it will be moderated and made visible in the in-game browser, or pack your mod locally to upload to a third-party site.</li> <li>Mod UIs through file editing. We will provide documentation that will explain how our internals are set up to solve mod loading/compatibility issues.</li> <li>Within Baldur’s Gate 3 itself, you’ll be able to: <ul> <li>Download and manage your mods directly.</li> <li>Manage multiplayer and save game files through a verification UI.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p data-characters="210" data-current-count="530" data-injectable="false">The Patch 7 update for <em>Baldur’s Gate 3 which will include official mod support but also implement new evil endings, bug fixes, and a trove of quality-of-life</em> improvements is set to release this September.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where to get Crude Ring in Wuthering Waves]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/where-to-get-crude-ring-in-wuthering-waves/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=where-to-get-crude-ring-in-wuthering-waves</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-to-get-crude-ring-in-wuthering-waves.888033/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/where-to-get-crude-ring-in-wuthering-waves/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=where-to-get-crude-ring-in-wuthering-waves<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="205" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Crude Ring in Wuthering Waves is a vital resource. You will need it to level up characters, so prepare to get a lot of it, especially if you have multiple characters in your party who need it for upgrades.</p> <p data-characters="149" data-current-count="149" data-injectable="false">Crude Ring is used as an ascension material for Calcharo, Yangyang, Yanwu, and Danjin. At the moment, you do not need it for any weapons in the game.</p> <h2 id="h-where-to-get-crude-ring" data-injectable="false">Where to get Crude Ring</h2> <p data-characters="330" data-current-count="479" data-injectable="true">Crude Ring can be obtained in several ways. Some cost resources, while others are free. I always suggest farming these the free way, where possible, and saving resources for harder-to-get things. It just makes sense to hold on to resources as much as you can, especially when the item you want really isn’t very hard to get.</p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">Farming from enemies</h2> <p data-characters="195" data-current-count="195" data-injectable="false">You can farm Exile enemies anywhere on the map, and they have a chance to drop the Crude Ring on death. There are numerous types of Exiles in the game, and they are pretty standard human enemies.</p> <ul data-found-items="3" data-current-count="315" data-injectable="false"> <li>Exile Leader – normally armed with dual blades and capable of channeling Electro energy.</li> <li>Exile Technician – a caster who can create shields for themselves and others and cast blades of damaging enemies.</li> <li>Standard Exiles – will be armed with either a melee weapon or a gun. They are not a very serious threat.</li> </ul> <p data-characters="114" data-current-count="429" data-injectable="true"><strong>You can find Exiles all over the map, but they are quite common on the Central Plains, and the Desorock Highlands.</strong></p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">Purchase from the weapon shop</h2> <p data-characters="372" data-current-count="372" data-injectable="false">Crude Rings can also be purchased from the weapon shop in Jinzhou. The weapon store is found in the northeast of the city, near the Synthesis console. It will cost 1500 Shell Credits to buy Crude Ring, and there will be a limit to how many you can purchase each day. Getting your resources this way can get expensive quickly, so it is not really the best way to do things.</p> <h2 data-injectable="false">Purchase from the in-game store</h2> <p data-characters="376" data-current-count="748" data-injectable="true">Hands down, the worst way to get anything is to buy it from the in-game store. You really do not need to do this. You can spend 15 Oscillate Corals to get 5 Crude Rings, but it is absolutely not worth it. The inventory for this store also rotates, so they may not be available when you need them. If you are tempted to go this route, I implore you to just go farm some Exiles.</p>
 <p data-characters="286" data-current-count="286" data-injectable="false">An important note on Crude Ring is that you can use it at the Syntehsiser to make the higher ranked Rings at a rate of 3 to 1. So, you can use 3 Crude Ring to make a Basic ring, and so on. Keep that in mind as you get later into the game and need higher rarities of Ring for ascensions.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Mod Tools Arrive With Patch 7 in September]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/baldurs-gate-3-mod-tools-september</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-mod-tools-arrive-with-patch-7-in-september.888006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/baldurs-gate-3-mod-tools-september<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Larian has announced that official&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>mod tools will arrive in September, as will everything else that's coming as part of the hotly-anticipated Patch 7.</p>

<p>We first learned that official mod support for&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>would arrive as part of Patch 7 <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/baldurs-gate-3-mod-support-patch-7">back in April</a>, but we now know roughly when we can expect it, although no final release date has been revealed yet.</p>

<p>The closed alpha for mod support kicks off today, according to a&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4179982568653520452" rel="noopener" target="_blank">community update on Steam</a>, and another test will open up registrations in July, allowing Larian to work through player feedback for the rest of the summer.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/baldurs-gate-3-mod-tools-aylin.jpg?itok=e2YYe5xO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/baldurs-gate-3-mod-tools-aylin.jpg?itok=WTTD3wh- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>mod tools are just around the corner.</figcaption></figure><p>In the aforementioned community update, Larian also sets out what mod tools and modding support will mean for&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3</em>.</p>

<p>Of course, it's possible to mod&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>right now, but implementing an official mod pipeline should make things much smoother and allow for better compatibility between each mod, as well as between mods and the game itself.</p>

<p>You'll still be able to mod&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>outside of Larian's official system if you want to, of course. Modding will use the <a href="https://mod.io/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">mod.io</a> platform and will be PC-only at first, but Mac support, as well as modding support for PS5 and Xbox Series X|S players, is on the cards too.</p>

<p>With that said, PlayStation and Xbox players won't have access to the&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>mod toolkit, so if you want to make your own mod for the game, you'll need to have a PC to do it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/baldurs-gate-3-mod-tools-party.jpg?itok=1GruCJg0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/baldurs-gate-3-mod-tools-party.jpg?itok=9nLRutF- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You'll soon be able to mod&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>with Larian's official blessing.</figcaption></figure><p>The toolkit will let you create, edit, and upload mods, as well as loading in-game levels on a read-only basis, accessing internal editors, and more. It's set to be a fully-featured mod toolkit that should help you realize whatever crazy dreams you've got for&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>mods.</p>

<p><em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>is out right now for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1086940/Baldurs_Gate_3/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/baldurs-gate-3/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/baldurs-gate-3/9nd58lqtg09t" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. Modding support is scheduled to arrive this September. Be sure to check out our&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/baldurs-gate-3-review">review</a> if you've somehow not played the game yet and want to know if it's worth your time!</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for five years, and in those five years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Venom: The Last Dance trailer picks up after all those wacky multiverse post-credits teases]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24170373/venom-3-trailer-last-dance</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/venom-the-last-dance-trailer-picks-up-after-all-those-wacky-multiverse-post-credits-teases.888003/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24170373/venom-3-trailer-last-dance<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="ebiZue"><em>Venom 3</em>, cheekily subtitled the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23042540/el-muerto-bad-bunny-venom-3-ghostbusters-5-sony-cinemacon"><em>The Last Dance</em></a>, looks like a splashy payoff to one of the superhero movie era’s weirder franchises. Tom Hardy is back as Eddie Brock and on the run from some gun-toting scientists who believe the Venom symbiote must be eradicated for the sake of Earth. Crossing my fingers this is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ETPVU0acnrE"><em>The Fugitive</em></a> / <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=khVFiUShfR8"><em>Midnight Run</em></a> with a Venom horse.</p>
<p id="gkd7Z0"><em>Venom: The Last Dance</em> appears to pick up where we left Eddie and Venom in <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/22701590/venom-2-review-let-there-be-carnage"><em>Venom: Let There Be Carnage</em></a>: lying low in the tropics after killing serial killer Cletus and leaving detective Mulligan (Stephen Graham) <a href="https://www.polygon.com/comics/22691862/venom-2-blue-eyes-detective-toxin-marvel-symbiote">infected with his own symbiote</a>. But if you are a total dork about this stuff, you might be wondering: Hey, didn’t Eddie and Venom cross over into the Marvel Cinematic Universe in <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22701094/venom-2-let-there-be-carnage-after-credits-scene">a post-credits tease at the end of <em>Let There Be Carnage</em></a>? Yes, they did! At least that’s what appeared to happen, a theoretical connection to Doctor Strange’s multiversal spell in <em>Spider-Man: No Way Home</em>. </p>
<p id="BzG3HE">But in the end, only Andrew Garfield’s and Tobey Maguire’s previous Spider-Mans showed up in the crossover movie — no Venom. In fact, Marvel went so far as to undo the whole tease. <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22836376/spider-man-no-way-home-post-credits-scenes-venom-doctor-strange">A post-credits scene in <em>No Way Home</em></a> saw Eddie grumbling at a bar over his multiverse displacement, only to be immediately transported back to his walled-off Sony-Marvel timeline in a flash. Nothing mattered! Wild.</p>
<p id="AilrKq">So here we are, <em>The Last Dance</em>, with Eddie and Venom back where they started: on the run, biting heads, and amped for more black-goo hijinks. There are some <a href="https://comicbookmovie.com/venom/venom-let-there-be-carnage/venom-the-last-dance-rumored-plot-leak-claims-to-reveal-the-movies-villains-and-plans-forpeter-parker-a211156">out-there rumors on dubious corners of the internet</a> that Eddie might somehow might be on the hunt for a 10-year-old Peter Parker, but the trailer pretty much dispels the post-credits-inspired hope. We do get a tease of Mulligan’s transformation into Toxin, and while Chiwetel Ejiofor shows up as a big bad, he’s not playing Karl Mordo from <em>Doctor Strange</em> — just some dude in army fatigues who likely bonds with a symbiote for a final fight. <em>Ted Las</em>so<em>’s </em>Juno Temple is also in the cast, and is also rumored to do some symbioting. </p>
<p id="0HBa7S"><em>Venom: The Last Dance</em>, which does not take place in the MCU timeline, is out on Oct. 25.</p>

  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Will Be Officially Moddable This Fall]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-mod-support-larian-1851515329</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-will-be-officially-moddable-this-fall.888000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-mod-support-larian-1851515329<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>“Hey everyone,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4179982568653520452&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4179982568653520452" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">says <em>Baldur’s Gate 3 </em>developer Larian in a breezy update on Steam</a></span>, “We come bringing news of Patch 7!” But it’s more than a pile of bug-fixes: the headline here is the forthcoming official release of what they call “an officially sanctioned toolkit” that’ll allow fully supported modding of the 2023 role-playing mega-hit.</p><div data-video-id="195376" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: What’s Releasing Beyond Baldur’s Gate 3" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="99" data-playlist="195376,195281,195618" data-current="195376"><div><p>The Week In Games: What’s Releasing Beyond Baldur’s Gate 3</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195376/195376_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195376/195376_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195376/195376_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195376/195376_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20843.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>Because we live in a wild future where there simply are no rules, you may not have to wait until September to get your hands on this update to the game. Larian has a habit of releasing its games unfinished into the hands of its community, and it’ll be doing the same for Patch 7. At first this will be a “closed beta,” where a hand-picked group of the finest vintage of mod creators will be given access, with the intention that these amateur experts will help them iron out major issues and test the tech to see how it works with unofficial mods they’ve already built.</p><p>That all starts today, June 3, with more modders being let behind the secret door as the month goes on. But come July, the crack in the door widens slightly, and 1,000 members of the hoi polloi who register will be allowed through. Over the next couple of months, Larian and this motley crew of unpaid laborers will get things shipshape and hopefully released for the masses in September.</p><p>It’s a studio that certainly seems to understand why a community wants to be able to mod. The recent update states,</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>Whether you are turning fireballs pink, boosting the attack damage of a hand-wielded sausage, or bestowing all citizens of Faerûn with a personal handgun, modding lets you alter a game to change how it looks or behaves.</p></blockquote><p>More usefully, the mod tools will allow people to create new classes and subclasses, weapons and armor, spells and skins, and thus craft entire new approaches to the game. It’s a long-running tradition of <em>D&amp;D</em> games, especially those made by BioWare—and most especially <em>Neverwinter Nights</em>—to let the community then create their own stories within (and without) the Forgotten Realms, so it’s great to see it being supported this time too.</p><p>Larian is at pains to say that this doesn’t close down options for the unofficial modding scene that’s already established around <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>, which they fully intend to endorse. This will also provide a way for mods that won’t get approval from the license owners to still be possible to create and share. The game will still recognize them and run them, but obviously they won’t be supported.</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p> We understand and appreciate the hard work and dedication of the modding community, and have no plans to limit modding to our official pipeline. We are committed to supporting the modding community as comprehensively as we can, and can’t wait to see what ideas you bring to life!</p></blockquote><p>Larian certainly are saying all the right words here. Mods and modding will be launched first for PC via software called Mod.io, with Mac and consoles to follow at an unspecified time. However, mod <em>creation</em> will require a PC. </p><p>The update includes no new information regarding the forthcoming new endings we know are coming to the game, with Larian referring players back to April’s last <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4172097464031362567&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4172097464031362567" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Community Update</a></span>.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naughty Dog 'Will Not Be The Last of Us Studio Forever' as it Works on 'Multiple' Single Player Projects, Neil Druckmann Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/naughty-dog-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-as-it-works-on-multiple-single-player-projects-neil-druckmann-says</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/naughty-dog-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-as-it-works-on-multiple-single-player-projects-neil-druckmann-says.887997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/naughty-dog-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-as-it-works-on-multiple-single-player-projects-neil-druckmann-says<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"We will not be The Last of Us studio forever."</h2></div><section><p>The Last of Us and Uncharted developer Naughty Dog has "multiple single player projects" in the works, studio head Neil Druckmann has said.</p><p>Speaking to the <a href="https://www.latimes.com/l-a-influential/story/2024-06-02/neil-druckmann-the-last-of-us-video-game" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Los Angeles Times</a>, Druckmann didn't mention what projects the PlayStation studio was working on or if any had entered full development, but did suggest it was looking to break away from being predominantly associated with The Last of Us.</p><p>"I promise you, we will not be The Last of Us studio forever," Druckmann said, speaking of Naughty Dog's beloved post-apocalyptic franchise that debuted in 2013 and received its "Part 2" sequel in 2020. The studio is otherwise best known for creating the Uncharted franchise, though this was put to bed with 2016's <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/uncharted-4-a-thiefs-end-review">Uncharted 4: A Thief's End</a> and smaller follow-up <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/uncharted-the-lost-legacy-review">The Lost Legacy</a> a year later.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I promise you, we will not be The Last of Us studio forever.</p></div><p>Naughty Dog hasn't released a game since The Last of Us: Part 2 beyond remasters, remakes, and collections, and while the studio confirmed it had decided on its next major title in March 2023, nothing is known about it externally.</p><p>Druckmann's comments suggest it may not be a new The Last of Us game, however, if he's certain Naughty Dog won't be predominantly known for the franchise in the future. It's also entirely possible The Last of Us is just one of these "multiple single player projects" in the works at Naughty Dog. Only time will tell.</p><p>Druckmann didn't say these projects were all in development either, but simply being worked on, meaning several, if not all, could still be in early conceptual phases and far from being worked on proper, never mind released. Projects this early in development are also regularly cancelled or drastically changed.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Every IGN Naughty Dog Game Review</h3></div></output><p>Regardless, Druckmann did say Naughty Dog's incoming games would follow the same principles as the studio's previous. "We create experiences that are steeped in story and character, especially relationships," he said. "The stories have some sort of philosophical core that everything is going to revolve around and feed into."</p><p>These comments will hopefully not be retracted like another media appearance from Druckmann was, as in a bizarre turn of events, Naughty Dog owner <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-pulls-controversial-interview-with-naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-after-finding-several-significant-errors-and-inaccuracies">Sony published and then deleted an interview with him</a> after several misquotes.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/neil-druckmann-says-naughty-dogs-next-game-could-redefine-mainstream-perceptions-of-gaming-update">Myriad comments from Druckmann were published incorrectly</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/neil-druckmann-did-not-quite-say-naughty-dogs-next-game-could-redefine-mainstream-perceptions-of-gaming">forcing him to release clarifying statements online</a>. "We apologize to Neil for misrepresenting his words and for any negative impact this interview might have caused," Sony said.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Closer the Distance launches in 2024 for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/closer-the-distance-launches-in-2024-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/closer-the-distance-launches-in-2024-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.887994/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/closer-the-distance-launches-in-2024-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A "deeply moving" slice-of-life simulation game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Slice-of-life <a title="Genres > Simulation [482 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Closer the Distance [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/closer-the-distance">Closer the Distance</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,139 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1991300/Closer_the_Distance/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2024, publisher <a title="Companies > Skybound Games [67 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/skybound-games">Skybound Games</a> and developer Ostomic Studio announced. <span id="more-886838"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1991300/Closer_the_Distance/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><em>Closer the Distance</em> is a deeply moving, slice-of-life sim that tells a story about the connections between family and friends in the face of tragedy. Following a fatal car accident, players take on the role of Angela, a young girl from the town of Yesterby, who finds herself watching over her loved ones as they navigate the grieving process. Using her ethereal ability to influence the townspeople she once knew, Angela’s choices will ultimately determine the fate of Yesterby.</p><p><em>Closer the Distance</em> combines several key gameplay features for an immersive playthrough. The game’s compelling narrative is emotionally charged and highlights themes of empathy, community, friendship, grief, and closure. Choices-matter gameplay allows players to make decisions that affect the outcome of the story, making each playthrough unique. <em>Closer the Distance</em> offers something for everyone, and its emotional depth and engaging gameplay will leave players wanting more.</p><p><a title="Games > Content Warning [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/content-warning">Content Warning</a>: <em>Closer the Distance</em> deals with themes of death, illness, and grief.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Story Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Closer the Distance - Story Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NJbaxcVOis0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Geoff Keighley Says 'People Are Setting Themselves Up For Failure' When Asked About Kingdom Hearts IV At SGF]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/03/geoff-keighley-says-people-are-setting-themselves-up-for-failure-when-asked-about</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geoff-keighley-says-people-are-setting-themselves-up-for-failure-when-asked-about-kingdom-hearts-iv-at-sgf.887991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/03/geoff-keighley-says-people-are-setting-themselves-up-for-failure-when-asked-about<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>This year's <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/05/08/the-2024-summer-gaming-showcase-schedule">Summer Game Fest showcase is happening this week,</a> on Friday, June 7, at 2 p.m. PT/5 p.m. ET, and <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/05/16/summer-game-fest-to-have-more-than-55-studios-and-publishers-including-playstation">with more than 55 studios and publishers set to be featured</a> at the event (including Play Days this weekend) this year, fans have been speculating on what they might see. That includes Kingdom Hearts fans, who have been hoping to see something related to Kingdom Hearts IV at SGF this year, given it's been more than two years since its <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2022/04/10/kingdom-hearts-4-revealed-in-20th-anniversary-trailer">reveal</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, SGF host and creator Geoff Keighley thinks Kingdom Hearts fans should lower their expectations for the show.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"People keep asking about Kingdom Hearts, I don't know why," Keighley says during a recent stream where he answered questions about SGF. "I think it's because we did [Final Fantasy VII Rebirth] last year or something like that. But yeah, people are setting themselves up for failure but you guys can keep hoping."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Here's a clip of it, too:&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, Keighley could be playing coy, especially with the "but you guys can keep hoping" part at the end, but it's more likely that he's trying to nicely let Kingdom Hearts fans know that if they expect to see Kingdom Hearts IV during SGF, they might be disappointed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the meantime, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2022/04/10/kingdom-hearts-4-revealed-in-20th-anniversary-trailer">watch the Kingdom Hearts IV reveal trailer</a>, and then read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2022/06/14/nomura-reveals-more-on-kingdom-hearts-iv-and-the-series-future-with"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>exclusive interview with Tetsuya Nomura</a> about Kingdom Hearts IV, the series' future with Final Fantasy, and more.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><em>Do you think we'll hear about Kingdom Hearts IV this upcoming weekend? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge of Spirits Xbox Release Announced for August]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kena-bridge-of-spirits-xbox-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kena-bridge-of-spirits-xbox-release-announced-for-august.887982/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kena-bridge-of-spirits-xbox-release<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ember Lab has announced that a&nbsp;<em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits&nbsp;</em>Xbox release is happening later this year, with the acclaimed action-adventure game set to debut on Microsoft's consoles in August.</p>

<p>Per a press release,&nbsp;<em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits</em>, which debuted on PlayStation in 2021 before <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kena-bridge-of-spirits-steam-release-and-anniversary-update-announced">hitting PC the following year</a>, will arrive on Xbox Series X|S and Xbox One on August 15th.</p>

<p>The Xbox version of the game will, according to Ember Lab, feature Xbox-exclusive goodies, including "Xbox Exclusive pirate-themed Rot hats" and a unique staff for Kena.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kena-bridge-of-spirits-xbox-release-ghosts.jpg?itok=1ppS_RyY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kena-bridge-of-spirits-xbox-release-ghosts.jpg?itok=i6y2Br9W 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits&nbsp;</em>is heading to Xbox soon.</figcaption></figure><p>You'll also be able to pick up a physical Premium Edition of&nbsp;<em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits&nbsp;</em>on Xbox, and it'll come with extra stuff like a soundtrack and a sticker sheet, plus the aforementioned Xbox-exclusive bonuses for the game.</p>

<p>Ember Lab COO Josh Grier says the studio is "thrilled" that&nbsp;<em>Kena&nbsp;</em>is heading to Xbox, and that the new platforms represent the chance to "share Kena's journey with more players". It's hard to argue with that.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits</em>, it's an action-adventure game that draws on influences like&nbsp;<em>The Legend of Zelda</em>; in fact, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbMQfaG6lo8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">viral&nbsp;<em>Zelda</em>-themed short film&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbMQfaG6lo8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Terrible Fate</a>&nbsp;</em>was also created by Ember Lab.</p>

<p><em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits&nbsp;</em>has you playing as the titular Kena, a Spirit Guide in search of a sacred mountain shrine. As she searches for the shrine, she must also help the ghosts of a village trapped in the past to move on.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kena-bridge-of-spirits-xbox-kneeling.jpg?itok=iCvhA7OY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kena-bridge-of-spirits-xbox-kneeling.jpg?itok=s2jzUACq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Zelda&nbsp;</em>is perhaps&nbsp;<em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits</em>' biggest influence.</figcaption></figure><p>Gameplay-wise,&nbsp;<em>Kena&nbsp;</em>is all about exploration, combat, and puzzle-solving, all of which you'll achieve with the help of the Rot, tiny adorable creatures that you can dress up in a variety of hats (yes, really).</p>

<p><em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits&nbsp;</em>comes to Xbox on August 15th. It's also already available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1954200/Kena_Bridge_of_Spirits/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/kena-bridge-of-spirits/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>. Be sure to check out our <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/kena-bridge-of-spirits-guide-for-beginners">beginners' guide for the game</a> if you're just getting started!</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for five years, and in those five years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge of Spirits coming to Xbox this summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/kena-bridge-of-spirits-coming-to-xbox-this-summer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kena-bridge-of-spirits-coming-to-xbox-this-summer.887979/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/kena-bridge-of-spirits-coming-to-xbox-this-summer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Xbox owners will soon be able to get their hands on Kena: Bridge of Spirits.</p>
<p>The game is set to arrive on both Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S on 15th August, priced £34.99 on the Microsoft Store. It will come with exclusive pirate-themed hats for the Rots - the game's timid and elusive spirits - as well as a unique Kena Staff and a Golden Rot Skin (you can check out how the hats look in the video below).</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Kena Coming to Xbox -  August 15" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rrqpJuUfYKI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Kena Coming to Xbox -  August 15</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rrqpJuUfYKI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rrqpJuUfYKI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Kena: Bridge of Spirits is coming to Xbox.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rrqpJuUfYKI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Those on Xbox Series X will also be able to purchase a Premium physical edition of Kena: Bridge of Spirits, which will include a digital soundtrack and a retail exclusive sticker sheet.</p>
<p>Both versions of the game will also come with Kena: Bridge of Spirits' Anniversary DLC update, which <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/kena-bridge-of-spirits-free-anniversary-update-adds-new-game-plus">arrived on PlayStation and PC back in 2022</a>. This update added New Game Plus as a major addition, as well as other additions such as equipable Charmstones that provided adjustments to stats and abilities.</p>
<p>"We're thrilled to bring the story of Kena to a new audience on Xbox platforms," said Josh Grier, COO of the game's developer Ember Lab. "As our debut game, Kena means a great deal to everyone at the studio and the team is excited to share Kena's journey with more players  - we really hope everyone enjoys meeting Kena and her Rot friends!"</p>
<p>Kena: Bridge of Spirits will be available to pre-order both digitally and physically for Xbox "soon", the team said.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_4d7ba9f26600f9beaa31427c84749b668f07c440.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Ember Lab</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>We described the game as "a gorgeous yet unoriginal adventure" in our original <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/kena-bridge-of-spirits-review-gorgeous-looking-yet-wholly-unoriginal">Kena: Bridge of Spirits review</a>.</p>
<p>"If you've played a decent number of games before," Eurogamer contributor Malindy Hetfeld wrote back in 2021, "it's likely you'll tire of the repetition of well-worn ideas here... This is a game that offers beautiful facsimiles of Zelda, Uncharted, The Pathless, and Pikmin that glide by through its 10 to 15 hour running time. But playing Kena gets very boring, very fast."</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Summer Game Fest 2024 Will Be Quieter When it Comes to Shocking Announcements, Says Keighley]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/summer-game-fest-2024-will-be-quieter-when-it-comes-to-shocking-announcements-says-keighley/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/summer-game-fest-2024-will-be-quieter-when-it-comes-to-shocking-announcements-says-keighley.887976/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/summer-game-fest-2024-will-be-quieter-when-it-comes-to-shocking-announcements-says-keighley/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>We've finally arrived at the <a href="https://wccftech.com/summer-game-fest-june-date-tickets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Summer Game Fest 2024</a> week, and host Geoff Keighley has provided some advance info for fans <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2162199165" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in a Twitch Q&amp;A</a>. To begin with, Keighley tried to temper expectations, saying there won't be many shocking announcements this year:</p>
<p><em>One of the things you'll see with the Summer Game Fest show this week is that we've really tried to program some unexpected things with smaller teams and independent studios alongside the sort of big blockbuster games and franchises that you will see in the show as well, but I think what's cool about our industry right now is that it's a great time where small games can really get significant success as we've seen. I think it's going to be a little bit quieter this Summer when it comes to crazy new announcements and shocking surprises and things like that. That's one of the things I always see online: the crazy speculation. Just like last week with the State of Play, people went in with crazy expectations. I see all this stuff, even around Summer Game Fest, and I think it's going to be a good, solid show, but we're not going to have a new GTA 6 trailer for you. I know sometimes when I see the feedback online people have lots of crazy that they get excited about. Hopefully, we will deliver on some of those things, but I'm sure many things we won't. Hopefully what happens is that people tune in and find something that surprises them.</em></p>
<p>Keighley also talked specifically about games that will or won't be at Summer Game Fest 2024. In the first category, gamers can expect to see a new Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 trailer, a new Metaphor: Refantazio trailer, a new Monster Hunter Wilds trailer, and a new Batman: Arkham Shadow trailer. On the other hand, don't get your hopes up to see Kingdom Hearts 4, Metal Gear Solid: Delta, The Wolf Among Us 2, and Hollow Knight: Silksong.</p>
<p>Keighley's Summer Game Fest 2024 will go live on Friday, June 7, at 2 PM Pacific Time across most platforms and social channels. It is expected to last around two hours.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge of Spirits Launches on Xbox Series X|S on August 15th]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-xbox-august-15th/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kena-bridge-of-spirits-launches-on-xbox-series-x-s-on-august-15th.887973/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-xbox-august-15th/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ember Lab's <a href="https://emberlab.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kena: Bridge of Spirits</a> will finally launch on Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S and Xbox One in a few months, almost three years since its release on PlayStation consoles and PC.</p>
<p>The Xbox Series X|S version of the action-adventure game will launch on August 15th worldwide, complete with some exclusive content such as the pirate-themed Rot hats, a unique Kena Staff, and a Golden Rot Skin.</p>
<p>In partnership with Maximum Entertainment, a physical Xbox Series X Premium Edition of Kena: Bridge of Spirits will also be released. It will include the Official Digital Soundtrack, a Retail-Exclusive Sticker Sheet, and the exclusive Xbox-themed content available in the digital edition of the game.</p>
<p><iframe title="Kena Coming to Xbox -  August 15" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rrqpJuUfYKI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Following its release back in September 2021, Kena: Bridge of Spirits was updated the following year with additional content, such as a New Game Plus mode, new trials that further push the limits of some gameplay mechanics, and more. You can learn more about the Anniversary Update in my<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/kena-bridge-of-spirits-anniversary-update-review-trials-of-the-mountain-shrine/"> review</a>.</p>
<p><em>Featuring new content that expands the game in some interesting ways and new trials that push the limit of the game's mechanics, the Kena: Bridge of Spirits Anniversary Update has a lot to offer to returning and new players alike. The new additions aren't particularly game-changing, so those who did not like the original release won't change their opinion with the new content. Those who loved the base game, however, will find a lot to like in the Anniversary Update.</em></p>
<p>Kena: Bridge of Spirits is now out on PC, PlayStation 5, and PlayStation 4. It will launch on Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S and Xbox One on August 15th.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Trek: Discovery tore itself apart for the good of Star Trek’s future]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24168842/star-trek-discovery-finale-interview-showrunner-end</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-trek-discovery-tore-itself-apart-for-the-good-of-star-trek%E2%80%99s-future.887970/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24168842/star-trek-discovery-finale-interview-showrunner-end<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  
    <a href="https://www.polygon.com/">
      
  <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 355.3 128"><title>poly-lt-wire-logo</title><path fill="#fff" d="M92.4,54.8c10.2,0,13.9,1.6,16.9,4a18.79,18.79,0,0,1,6.5,14.5c0,5.6-2.3,11.4-5.8,14.4-3.8,3.2-7.5,4.8-16,4.8H88.5v17.2h-14V54.8Zm-4,25.4h5.1a13.87,13.87,0,0,0,5.4-.8c1.9-.8,3.3-2.5,3.3-5.8s-1.6-4.8-3.5-5.6a15.31,15.31,0,0,0-5.8-.8H88.3v13Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M116.2,89c0-10,7.2-21.8,22.2-21.8S160.6,79,160.6,89.1,153.4,111,138.4,111,116.2,99.2,116.2,89Zm12.3.1a9.91,9.91,0,1,0,9.9-10.5C133,78.6,128.5,83,128.5,89.1Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M164.5,54.8h12.3v54.9H164.5Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M195.1,107.6,179.9,68.5H193l8.4,23.9,7.9-23.9h13l-20.6,54.9h-13Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M266.5,104.7c0,6.2-.4,10.1-2.4,13.6-3.2,5.2-10.7,9.7-20.8,9.7-14.3,0-19.7-8.6-20.5-14.5H237a7.08,7.08,0,0,0,3.9,3.6,10.57,10.57,0,0,0,3.3.5c4.7,0,10-2.9,10-10v-2.4c-1.4,2.4-5,5.9-11.4,5.9-11.2,0-20.8-8.5-20.8-21.7,0-14.1,10.1-22.2,20.8-22.2,4.6,0,9.1,1.6,11.5,5.2V68.5h12.3v36.2ZM234.2,89c0,6.5,4.7,10.5,9.9,10.5a9.8,9.8,0,0,0,7.2-2.8,11.18,11.18,0,0,0,2.9-7.1,11.56,11.56,0,0,0-2.6-7.7,9.2,9.2,0,0,0-7.4-3.2,10,10,0,0,0-10,10q0,.15,0,.3Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M270.3,89c0-10,7.2-21.8,22.2-21.8S314.7,79,314.7,89.1,307.5,111,292.5,111,270.3,99.2,270.3,89Zm12.3.1a9.91,9.91,0,1,0,9.9-10.5C287.2,78.6,282.6,83,282.6,89.1Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M317.2,68.5h11.5v4.4c1.4-2,4-5.8,11.3-5.8,13.9,0,15.3,11.3,15.3,16.8v25.7H343V87.1c0-4.5-1-8.5-6.5-8.5-6.1,0-7,4.4-7,8.6v22.4H317.2Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M73.9,37.3a1.09,1.09,0,0,0,.1-.5v-.1c0-.2-.1-.3-.3-.5h0L37.8.3a1.4,1.4,0,0,0-.9-.3h-.1c-.2,0-.3.1-.5.3h0L.4,36.1a.1.1,0,0,1-.1.1.1.1,0,0,1-.1.1l-.1.1a.6.6,0,0,0-.1.4H0V72.9a.55.55,0,0,0,.3.5h0l35.9,35.9a1.14,1.14,0,0,0,.8.3.6.6,0,0,0,.4-.1,1.2,1.2,0,0,0,.7-1V73.1L73.7,37.5C73.8,37.5,73.8,37.4,73.9,37.3ZM36,38V70.2L3.7,38ZM2.2,39.5,34.4,71.7H2.2ZM38.1,38H70.3L38.1,70.2Zm0-2.2V3.6L70.3,35.8Zm-2.1,0H3.7L35.9,3.6V35.8Zm0,70.3L3.8,73.9H36Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path></svg>


      
    </a>
  
  
    <p>
      <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717423223_5278_10059" data-cdata="{&quot;image_id&quot;:73385202,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cZWrQYqLSrrrhP8itK30iX-wjbc=/0x0:7281x4856/320x128/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/23S6MxX6uVXcNYdV36QXkI-jJJc=/0x0:7281x4856/570x228/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 570w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CbYw5VWCmOMyTB47VcxwFx8fB2g=/0x0:7281x4856/820x328/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 820w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zBssDe40sHWXPf56GFjX7sln9aM=/0x0:7281x4856/1070x428/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 1070w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E9dpnciFlUt7m3PoNRotbmjH2LA=/0x0:7281x4856/1320x528/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dSDN9w1b8mtVLxcAAv_Zt_G8B0E=/0x0:7281x4856/1570x628/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 1570w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ChkB6Qtj-WOU4ltfDcthh2GtTCs=/0x0:7281x4856/1820x728/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 1820w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HHbWklVDQuGjaUQWbDg-XQmse90=/0x0:7281x4856/2070x828/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 2070w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H0TmpZNhW__8RZHfKW2gIizlnks=/0x0:7281x4856/2320x928/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 2320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SuBG5wWaoGMRLd_ezM2DefULg5U=/0x0:7281x4856/2570x1028/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 2570w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pKA5dwTAGxpMS-hfRnGzezYblrg=/0x0:7281x4856/2820x1128/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 2820w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/McLUCezRk0mlDW3FYCFtkCjT9bg=/0x0:7281x4856/3070x1228/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 3070w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LIh40lsW_4_ZCw724WHJbdApdDY=/0x0:7281x4856/3320x1328/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 3320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E9DYRbUyHOulu27wKKLTpE5zGmI=/0x0:7281x4856/3570x1428/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 3570w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BvkrFaE25fbG4taekYr_o0rcCmU=/0x0:7281x4856/3820x1528/filters:focal(3194x1504:4358x2668):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73385202/DISCO_510_MAG_1031_00033_1_RT1.0.jpeg 3820w" sizes="100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Michael Gibson/Paramount Plus</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


    </p>
  
  <div>
    


    
    

    <p>And it helped set the tone for where Star Trek is now</p>

    <div>
  <p><span>
    
      By
      
      
        
          <span>
            
            <time data-ui="timestamp" datetime="2024-06-03T13:00:00">
  Jun  3, 2024,  9:00am EDT
</time>
          </span>
        
      
      
      
    
    
      <span>
        

      </span>
    
  </span>
  <span>
    <a data-entry-admin="23932883" data-cid="tools/entry_admin_button-1717423223_9733_10060" data-cdata="{&quot;id&quot;:23932883}"></a>

  </span>
</p></div>

  </div>
</div><div>
  <main id="content" tabindex="-1">
    
    


      
    

      



    






<div>
  <p id="WLkOr4">If you were to jump directly from the first episode of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24107999/star-trek-discovery-season-5-preview"><em>Star Trek: Discovery</em></a> to its finale — which just debuted on Paramount Plus — the whiplash would throw you clear out of your seat like your ship had suffered an inertial damper malfunction. Since its first two chapters premiered on CBS All Access in 2017, the series has moved to a different ship and a different century, and has acquired an almost entirely different set of characters. Moreover, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24119983/star-trek-progenitors-discovery-picard-chase"><em>Discovery</em></a> has received a radical tonal refit, evolving in fits and starts from a dark and violent war story to a much sunnier action-adventure serial. </p>
<p id="2Cu42h">Though it never won the mainstream attention or critical acclaim of its spinoff, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23755316/star-trek-strange-new-worlds-lanthanites-pelia-species-carol-kane"><em>Strange New Worlds</em></a><em>,</em> nor the gushing fan adulation of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23620555/worf-star-trek-picard-season-3-michael-dorn-interview"><em>Picard</em>’s <em>Next Gen</em> reunion</a>, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23345284/star-trek-tv-show-best-start"><em>Discovery</em> spearheaded Star Trek’s return to television</a>, the franchise’s maiden voyage into the frontier of premium streaming content. Like any bold pathfinder, <em>Discovery</em> encountered obstacles, suffered losses, and made some major course corrections. But, if you ask the cast and crew, the adventure has been more than worth the tumultuous journey.</p>
<h2 id="XtieQm"><strong>Tacking into the wind</strong></h2>
<p id="Ugaio7">“We were on wobbly legs for a long time,” admits star Sonequa Martin-Green, whose character, Michael Burnham, has had the rug pulled out from under her a number of times over the course of the series. In the first season and backstory alone, Burnham lost her parents, saw her mentor murdered, was tried for mutiny, discovered that her first love is a Klingon sleeper agent, and was betrayed by not one but two Mirror Universe doppelgängers of trusted Starfleet captains.</p>
<p id="R71ZFb">Move over, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23547617/deep-space-nine-star-trek-ds9-watch-analysis"><em>Deep Space Nine</em></a> — this was instantly the grimmest canonical depiction of the Star Trek universe on screen. Season 1 of <em>Discovery</em> was rated TV-MA and featured more blood and gore than the franchise had ever seen, not to mention an instance of graphic Klingon nudity. (Actor Mary Wiseman recalls seeing her co-star Mary Chieffo walking the set wearing prosthetic alien breasts and thinking, <em>What the hell?</em>) The corpse of Michelle Yeoh’s character is cannibalized by Klingons off screen, and her successor, portrayed by Jason Isaacs, turns out to be a manipulative psycho from the Mirror Universe who tries to mold Burnham into his plaything.</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717419655_3747_85954" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25472698,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/67bN08Km7rwNecJ0K4FECm4mUHs=/0x0:3000x2000/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1A8GkjRJNDh48Lt2JLgu1cMfAV8=/0x0:3000x2000/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J_6KvL2-G6K_5sGQs_X9JI6BIzM=/0x0:3000x2000/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RhmTSgOUeWlLPUsaJABpGa7rRyI=/0x0:3000x2000/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/301883_WCog3VZPIJWVYDxpiRVA=/0x0:3000x2000/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ts_Cs9oF9nitvE42pJVzO28sOO8=/0x0:3000x2000/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Zmrj0abhEQ0XD0DzPftPnFKPCmo=/0x0:3000x2000/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qYL4qLAKPWADOxVPtRuzptfKJF8=/0x0:3000x2000/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QcW2tNcx_fAKRCOIdHkNX4LkaEY=/0x0:3000x2000/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472698/111659_2373b.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Jan Thijs/CBS</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="yTFYTX">The bleak, adult-oriented tone was not the only sticking point with Star Trek purists, as <em>Discovery</em> would take place a decade before the original 1960s <em>Star Trek</em> but have a design aesthetic much closer to that of the 2009 movie reboot, leading to some irreconcilable clashes with continuity. The show’s serialized, season-long arcs were a far cry from the familiar “planet of the week” stories of most previous incarnations of the franchise. Then there was Burnham’s backstory as the never-before-mentioned human foster sister to <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23824684/star-trek-spock-strange-new-worlds-actors">Trek’s iconic Vulcan Spock</a>, a creative decision that has “clueless studio note” written all over it. Even ahead of its debut, <em>Discovery</em> faced vocal opposition from the fan base for straying so far from their notion of what Star Trek was supposed to be. (Not to mention the revolting but quite vocal faction of fans who were incensed that Star Trek had “gone woke,” as if it hadn’t been that way the whole time.) Many of <em>Discovery</em>’s detractors flocked toward <em>The Orville</em>, a Fox series starring and created by Seth MacFarlane that was essentially ’90s-style Star Trek with the occasional dick joke thrown in. <em>The Orville </em>offered fans alienated by <em>Discovery</em>’s vastly different approach to Star Trek a more familiar (but far less ambitious) alternative. </p>
<p id="OeE52Z">The grim Klingon War story was the brainchild of co-creator Bryan Fuller, who had been a member of the <em>Star Trek: Deep Space Nine</em> and <em>Voyager </em>writers rooms before creating cult series like <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22967661/pushing-daisies-bryan-fuller-genre-aids"><em>Pushing Daisies</em></a> and <em>Hannibal</em>. Fuller would end up <a href="https://ew.com/tv/2017/07/28/bryan-fuller-star-trek-discovery/">departing Team Discovery</a> before production even began, asked to resign after a string of creative differences with the studio. New showrunners Aaron Harberts and Gretchen J. Berg carried out a version of Fuller’s plans without him, and then oversaw the show’s first major pivot. <em>Discovery</em>’s second season was immediately brighter, more colorful, and cozier with established Star Trek lore. (This is the arc that would introduce <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23057405/star-trek-strange-new-worlds-creator-anson-mount-pike-masculinity">the versions of Pike</a>, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2019/2/28/18245209/spock-star-trek-discovery-season-2-changes">Spock</a>, and Number One who now lead <em>Strange New Worlds</em>.) But things weren’t so sunny behind the scenes — <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/star-trek-discovery-showrunners-alex-kurtzman-take-1120416/">Harberts and Berg were fired</a> midway through the season after writers accused the duo of creating an abusive work environment.</p>
<p id="6unkV0">As different as <em>Discovery</em> would eventually stray from the HBO-style drama of its first season, co-creator Alex Kurtzman feels that the mission of the series has never changed. </p>
<p id="0IRyNW">“One of the things that we set up in season 1 is that we knew that Burnham would start as a mutineer and end up a captain,” says Kurtzman. “What was exciting about that is that we knew it would take time.”</p>
<h2 id="cnmvOm"><strong>Captain on deck</strong></h2>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717419655_3231_85955" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25472707,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4HJkNVIzHor1rWkIW5y9e5AgfSw=/0x0:3000x2000/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t7oekGGFIb3awzTjztjYMHFQIeE=/0x0:3000x2000/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tm-rtRYHKD5de3dTu0WkIVGTPWs=/0x0:3000x2000/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jKf_ZRTMG8zO44lQP2n7eiGKypc=/0x0:3000x2000/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GFPWT67XvfL2FLjjwXZgpV3Cxjk=/0x0:3000x2000/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/chd03Coujw6rWaLxx7gb4_w_ljU=/0x0:3000x2000/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O2TM3Xlpi3hBXyVN3e5Sdh3gELg=/0x0:3000x2000/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FH2epmiPgIPpzl1JnBjxdwy3tr8=/0x0:3000x2000/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3yJjme_tj1jx2ZZfBnneALIW2yI=/0x0:3000x2000/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472707/112617_0006b.JPG 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Jan Thijs/CBS</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="IrZcz7">It was after Harberts and Berg’s departure that Kurtzman, who had remained involved but been primarily occupied with the development of the growing television Star Trek franchise as a whole, took the helm of <em>Discovery</em> himself. Before long, he would promote writer and co-executive producer Michelle Paradise to the role of co-showrunner, which she would retain for the remainder of the series. Just as the late, great Michael Piller did during the third season of <em>The Next Generation</em>, Paradise brought a sense of stability and confidence to <em>Discovery</em>, which reverberated onto set.</p>
<p id="Z0YCgd">“I commend Michelle Paradise and the rest of the writers because this show <em>evolved</em>,” says Martin-Green. “Our initial showrunners, Aaron Harberts and Gretchen Berg, they made their impact and that’ll never be erased, but landing where we did with Michelle co-showrunning with Alex Kurtzman, jumping farther than any Trek had gone before, I feel that’s when our feet were solid on the ground and when we really established our identity.”</p>
<p id="Cb976A">Season 2 fell into a steady rhythm that felt more in tune with Kurtzman’s “movie every week” philosophy, never far in tone from the reboot film trilogy on which Kurtzman served as a writer and producer. The steady presence of Michelle Yeoh’s deliciously amoral Emperor Georgiou was a major boon, essentially becoming Star Trek’s answer to <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23069583/buffy-spuffy-elysian-fields-fanfiction"><em>Buffy</em>’s Spike</a> or <em>Dragon Ball Z</em>’s Vegeta. However, <em>Discovery</em> was also undeniably borrowing clout from legacy characters Pike and Spock, and the constant friction with established canon wasn’t sitting well with Kurtzman or the audience.</p>
<p id="lBBM7E">The season ended with a surprising twist that resolved the continuity problems but also changed the entire nature of the show. The titular starship and its crew would be propelled 930 years into the future, past the furthest fixed point in Star Trek’s continuity. No longer forced to tiptoe around the sacred canon, <em>Discovery</em> was free to sprint in a bold new direction. Once again and in a more tangible way, it was a whole new show.</p>
<p id="7Z4xNc">“If the folks who came in had sort of taken us off the rails that would have been a very different experience,” says Anthony Rapp, who portrays the prickly Commander Paul Stamets. “But Michelle Paradise came through as such a shining light and a beautiful presence in our lives. She took the show into this territory of being able to have the heart in its center in a way that felt very grounded and meaningful, and really helped us to make that transition.”</p>
<h2 id="9VIO37"><strong>An open sky</strong></h2>
<div>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717419655_4885_85956" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:21961916,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OgdefuxHuwxDXM04dvPAo-bghPY=/0x0:3000x2004/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F5Zuq70Oz06DSamZ1hK3Qf8GLdc=/0x0:3000x2004/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GGP8nFnZ0zGUKztt70UXLq0hIwA=/0x0:3000x2004/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nuzz7NOzdpuY1lDsa6I_QA415Ow=/0x0:3000x2004/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FGSquYvZOqiak5LB6J_IkTVuYl0=/0x0:3000x2004/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DCz57LaAA5lh6bO8Qjem4pVFzkg=/0x0:3000x2004/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j6BLPKlkJOHnOsrmXlTyCTUhWC8=/0x0:3000x2004/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tu8LYWyhlgtNpOzN8xqx00btl94=/0x0:3000x2004/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wLhv73BO1h_8f_6PHIoGqtxY7jY=/0x0:3000x2004/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21961916/115791_0846b__1_.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Michael Gibson/CBS</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717419655_3608_85957" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25472780,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lpRBZIVaTXSKSFUw935fvjI69lU=/0x0:3000x2024/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2024):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UmKOq6N-ZESz4umF1v2f-JZrFns=/0x0:3000x2024/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2024):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PmKl4PXmGiZRPjKyuHlHEsh5u3Q=/0x0:3000x2024/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2024):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kgFndvnxWXBpZEINKfVbYuq6M1c=/0x0:3000x2024/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2024):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n62CstnhYMTLldttj0N6yaY3Us8=/0x0:3000x2024/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2024):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9zIk0ZdFEF3rIPOMKE5I4NTzs1k=/0x0:3000x2024/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2024):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PZhmy6G9eO1ZVCsTV-gv_kzX5Ws=/0x0:3000x2024/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2024):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/poA2Mvld4cgdI2fMrEF7HMTwhZ8=/0x0:3000x2024/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2024):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PnruEPt7RAsKQDgUkI9S-4S4hSM=/0x0:3000x2024/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2024):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472780/DISCO_403_MG_0433_RT.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Michael Gibson/Paramount Plus</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717419655_1984_85958" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25472782,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K8xIw-sdkCDZIycCtMZ55x18Y8w=/0x0:3000x2004/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7v9wKA_GWTA3OhWrTa8HXSieEtI=/0x0:3000x2004/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V-EZi9o0LHSuG0RBFE53lzeRGmo=/0x0:3000x2004/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8C0411hkGJzX_hCKq8odQo_FNZ8=/0x0:3000x2004/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JZf6600gfIiQxB03NHbGLOj5EKM=/0x0:3000x2004/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o_fX2osZCliB7gJom05al-0mTrA=/0x0:3000x2004/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hqarKWfRRhHwJ0QX4TZn2qZuARU=/0x0:3000x2004/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MR-nQWamov6dk5sdpkmHBXs4jyA=/0x0:3000x2004/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lAbhs0mFLWPHNaGjeeGErz35R_I=/0x0:3000x2004/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2004):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472782/ST_D1_EP304_0052_RT.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Michael Gibson/CBS</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
</div>
<p id="Qt68Bb">Season 3 of <em>Discovery</em> offered Kurtzman, Paradise, producing director Olatunde Osunsanmi, and the rest of the creative team <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24107999/star-trek-discovery-season-5-preview">a rare opportunity to completely rewrite Star Trek’s galactic map</a>. Not since the launch of <em>The Next Generation</em> in 1987 had a writers room been able to venture onto such “fresh snow,” as Paradise puts it. In the 32nd century, beyond the furthest point explored in the established Trek canon, the righteous United Federation of Planets has all but collapsed in the aftermath of “the Burn,” a mysterious space calamity. Some longtime friends are now adversaries, and even Earth has become an isolationist state. The USS Discovery, displaced in time, becomes the means by which to reconnect the shattered galaxy. It’s not hard to read this as a mission statement for Star Trek as a whole — a relic from another time, back to offer hope to a bleak present.</p>
<p id="vCsiV0">Season 3’s 13-episode arc restored a bit of Star Trek’s space Western roots, with warp drive a rare and costly luxury in the ravaged 32nd century and half the galaxy dominated by a vast criminal empire known as the Emerald Chain. Michael Burnham spent much of the season out of uniform, having found a new purpose as a more roguish freelance courier alongside the sweet and savvy Cleveland Booker (David Ajala). This is arguably the most interesting version of the show, as Michael questions whether or not Starfleet — the institution whose trust she has worked so hard to restore — is still her home.</p>
<p id="QrdSe7">By the end of the season (and right on schedule with Fuller and Kurtzman’s original plans), Michael Burnham finally accepts her destiny and becomes captain of Discovery. More subtly, this altered the premise of the show for a third time, as the central question of “Will Michael ever become captain?” had been answered in the affirmative. But, since she’d already been the central character and a figure of improbable cosmic import, the change was mostly cosmetic. And symbolic — Martin-Green considers her presence “being Black, and a woman, and a captain sitting in that chair” to be her greatest contribution to Star Trek. After three seasons of struggle and uncertainty, Burnham could now be as aspirational a character as <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22957090/jean-luc-picard-romance-tng">Picard</a>, Sisko, or <a href="https://www.polygon.com/features/22870436/star-trek-prodigy-cameos-spock-uhura-kobayashi-episode">Janeway</a>.</p>
<p id="FGIWj8">The tone on which the show settled at the end of season 3 would be the one that finally stuck. Where the series had initially been bloody and brooding, it was now squarely an adventure show featuring a cast of characters with a boundless and demonstrative love for each other. The crew would face mortal danger each episode and a galactic-level threat each season, bolstered by very expensive-looking visual effects and a rousing score. At the same time, many conflicts both large and small would eventually be resolved by characters talking through their feelings and finding common ground. This was exhausting as often as it was compelling, but it was consistent. For its final two seasons, viewers could finally know what to expect from <em>Star Trek: Discovery</em>.</p>
<h2 id="EGuRvE"><strong>Discovering itself</strong></h2>
<p id="V1bjxn"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/22924014/star-trek-discovery-character-emotions">This “feelings over phasers” approach</a> was not for everyone, but it was never intended to be. Even from the outset, before Paramount began pumping out more Star Trek series to target different facets of the fan base, <em>Discovery</em> was never meant to be a definitive Star Trek experience that checked every box.</p>
<p id="SPj4Dq">“You’ll never be able to be everything to everybody,” says Michelle Paradise. “The goal was always to make the best version of <em>Discovery</em>. It’s a different kind of Star Trek. It’s serialized, it’s fewer episodes, it’s a movie every week. That’s a thing that will appeal to many people, and for some people it won’t be their cup of tea.”</p>
<div>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717419655_7782_85959" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25472728,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bsEFLnqfirYjWaBscFz80RAOeJA=/0x0:2880x1921/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2880x1921):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XnjCzFcMblWZTlcdxhrgo69R914=/0x0:2880x1921/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2880x1921):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UhiOxSRGZ7zMIQB2tpKF7_6t5DI=/0x0:2880x1921/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2880x1921):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mJEk_STcLR1eqejo3QekfnGyuhs=/0x0:2880x1921/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2880x1921):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EjU_7dIYS_gebG2UqQfrlnUz2Cc=/0x0:2880x1921/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2880x1921):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZrSZWnI2txDgr-su_lFjI7lKn1A=/0x0:2880x1921/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2880x1921):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LUobHo4EQC9kDn67y_fnpONAEk4=/0x0:2880x1921/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2880x1921):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GtfHyBV9ic_l0v8mck8eUq9PPS4=/0x0:2880x1921/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2880x1921):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xlo2hBIQwBgjp7nEIxUnORpG-mw=/0x0:2880x1921/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2880x1921):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472728/116981_D_123_RT.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Michael Gibson/CBS</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717419655_5808_85960" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25472730,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fB6XXEP14pDf3WnZGBJ5eOHWc7s=/0x0:7598x5068/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:7598x5068):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c-7QFaJ-r91GEmtMVq2XgWHG7xE=/0x0:7598x5068/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:7598x5068):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6f0NmTxISXSV8-jmmg61eOTb_To=/0x0:7598x5068/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:7598x5068):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yi_QSF0OR9qiyCoTx4NejenZh3s=/0x0:7598x5068/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:7598x5068):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fBtqM0L0alDWbLlTs4WNtA4yLUQ=/0x0:7598x5068/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:7598x5068):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q6E39bsL6nq9FdMclJ7Z-hZRFJU=/0x0:7598x5068/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:7598x5068):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2Z3Z3Xk2LZAjIvMSJWe9rxHd624=/0x0:7598x5068/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:7598x5068):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2Qc1EsMZXjx4zhTbk24NFLqBuFY=/0x0:7598x5068/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:7598x5068):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AcLgAWNeYGC-qAFaA2Au4PXlHGA=/0x0:7598x5068/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:7598x5068):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25472730/DISCO_510_MAG_0426_03405_1_RT.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Michael Gibson/Paramount Plus</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
</div>
<p id="CZZ4WU"><em>Discovery</em> has bounced up and down my personal ranking of Star Trek series a number of times during its run, more than any of its past or present siblings. I have begun each season of the show with great excitement, and that excitement is frequently exhausted by season’s end. Most Trek series have good years and bad years. To me, <em>Discovery</em> suffers from being simultaneously brilliant, innovative, lazy, cringe, inspiring, and eye-rolling at all times, only in different measures. It features the franchise’s strongest lead actor since Patrick Stewart, and a supporting cast that has never been leveraged to my satisfaction. In my career, I have written more words about <em>Star Trek: Discovery</em> than any other television series, and I still haven’t made up my mind about it. For as many cheerleaders and haters as the show must have, I imagine there are many more viewers who feel the way I do — it’s a show that I wanted to love, but never fully fell in love with.</p>
<p id="V0r8GI">As <em>Discovery</em> disappears in the aft viewport, some will bid it a fond farewell, some will be blowing it raspberries, and some will turn away with total disinterest. But regardless of how well <em>Discovery</em> itself is remembered in the coming years, it has already made a substantial impact on the franchise. It paved the way for every Trek series that followed, including <em>three</em> direct spinoffs. Its second season was the incubator for <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23799328/star-trek-kirk-spock-snw-strange-new-worlds"><em>Strange New Worlds</em></a>, now the most acclaimed Trek series in a generation. Michelle Yeoh had such fun in her recurring role on <em>Discovery</em> that, even <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23636975/oscars-2023-michelle-yeoh-best-actress-speech">after winning an Academy Award</a>, she was still <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23637514/star-trek-michelle-yeoh-section-31-show-release">keen to return for the upcoming <em>Section 31</em> TV movie</a>. <em>Discovery</em>’s 32nd-century setting will continue to be explored in the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23663131/star-trek-starfleet-academy-show-paramount-plus-release">new <em>Starfleet Academy</em> series</a>, leaving the door open for some of its characters to return.</p>
<p id="F1TwWO">Even the new shows that have no direct relationship to <em>Discovery</em> have benefitted from the precedent it set by being different from what came before. <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23735961/star-trek-strange-new-worlds-season-2-trailer-lower-decks"><em>Lower Decks</em></a> is an animated sitcom, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22753008/star-trek-prodigy-review-kate-mulgrew-janeway"><em>Prodigy</em> is a kid-targeted cartoon</a>, <em>Picard</em> is… <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23691934/picard-season-3-finale-review">a bunch of different things that don’t work together</a>, but they are all different shows. <a href="https://www.polygon.com/star-trek">Star Trek</a> was one thing, and beginning with <em>Discovery</em>, it became many things. And for Star Trek, an institution that preaches the value of infinite diversity in infinite combinations, that’s a legacy to be proud of. </p>
<p id="4CSt25"><small><em>Star Trek: Discovery</em></small><small> is now streaming in full on Paramount Plus. </small></p>
  
</div>











  </main>
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 Patch 7 Will Add Modding in September 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-will-add-modding-in-september-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-patch-7-will-add-modding-in-september-2024.887964/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-will-add-modding-in-september-2024/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/baldursgate3/status/1797586744088621138" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new post</a> on Twitter/X, the Baldur’s Gate 3 team announced that the anticipated Patch 7 update will arrive sometime in September 2024, adding official modding tools.</p>



<p>The post adds that a closed alpha begins today, and that a closed beta is coming in July. The Beta will be capped at about 1,000 players. Larian previously <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-will-introduce-first-official-modding-tools/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced in April</a> that Patch 7 will introduce the first official modding tools. </p>



<p>During a community update, the devs explained that players will get to “change up visuals, animations, sounds, stats, and more.”</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Coming to you this September, Patch 7 will introduce an official modding toolkit so you can bring your wildest ideas to life!</p><p>💬Closed Alpha Begins Today<br>🗓️Closed Beta – July<br>🛠️Modding FAQ</p><p>Read more in Community Update #27 – Official Modding Support: <a href="https://t.co/lwdOkUUUOa">https://t.co/lwdOkUUUOa</a> <a href="https://t.co/EOwNFqh3gt">pic.twitter.com/EOwNFqh3gt</a></p></div>— Baldur's Gate 3 (@baldursgate3) <a href="https://twitter.com/baldursgate3/status/1797586744088621138?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>In community update 27 <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4179982568653520452" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">via Steam</a>, the devs elaborated on further details. The devs reiterated plans for fixes, Crossplay, and an in-game Photo Mode. However, they also teased some “anniversary extravagance.” </p>



<p>For Patch 7, the devs confirmed that PC players will be the first to use and install mods. Then, they will be available for “Mac players, as well as PlayStation and Xbox consoles” later on. Today’s post does not confirm exact release dates.</p>



<p>However, fans playing Baldur’s Gate 3 on console will only get to browse existing mods, rather than modding their own.  The devs confirmed that “the official modding tools themselves will not be available to those playing on console.”</p>



<p>Today’s post also mentions that the toolkit will include “a subset of our internal development tools.” This will allow players to edit mods, upload to mod.io servers, get access to supported asset types, and more.</p>



<p>Baldur’s Gate 3 developer Larian Studios also recently announced it is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-developer-larian-studios-opening-new-studio-in-warsaw/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">opening a seventh studio</a> located in Warsaw. The announcement comes as Larian looks ahead to two ambitious new RPGs.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/naughty-dog-the-last-of-us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Neil Druckmann suggesting</a> Naughty Dog won’t be a The Last Of Us studio forever, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leximan launches August 13]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/leximan-launches-august-13</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/leximan-launches-august-13.887961/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/leximan-launches-august-13<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Wordy adventure game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Wordy <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,505 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Leximan [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/leximan">Leximan</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2017200/Leximan/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on August 13 for $14.99, publisher <a title="Companies > Marvelous [1,300 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/marvelous">Marvelous</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Knights of Borria [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/knights-of-borria">Knights of Borria</a> announced. <span id="more-886833"></span></p><p>A “Digital Deluximan Edition” will also be available for $19.99, which includes the base game, the official sountrack featuring over 100 minutes of music, and the “Basement Breakout” mini tabletop <a title="Genres > RPG [16,297 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> campaign PDF.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2017200/Leximan/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In a stroke of good fortune, you’ve enrolled in the world’s most exclusive magic school: Academy Elementinia. But on the downside, this is a world in which magic is a bit embarrassing.</p><p>Still, you’ve got something special. You alone have the ability to use Leximancy, a hitherto unimaginable power driven by something as fascinating as it is enchanting: language.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Leximancy is an endlessly fun branch of magic, but it is also a risk of buttock-clenching magnitude. Years ago you caused THINGS to happen, and ever since then you’ve been banished to the school basement with the other failures- I mean learners.</p><p>Your life as a humble basement-wizard is interrupted as Academy Elementinia is attacked by someone with a baffling agenda and a huge set of fireballs.</p><p>Don your trusty hat, ready your lexicon, become the outcast that saves the school. Or if you don’t vibe with heroics, at least cause some more THINGS to happen. After all, you’re out of the basement now. Let’s see what you can do.</p><p><strong>How to Be Leximan</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Be Wordy</strong> – Cast Leximancy spells in a unique word-based encounter system, snatching word fragments from thin air to spell out clever incantations.</li><li><strong>Be You</strong> – Unravel a surprisingly wholesome story about embracing and empowering the real you. I say “surprisingly wholesome”, because there’s also a bit where you kick a trout.</li><li><strong>Go Rogue</strong> – Use your utter hooligan of a brain to figure out words, puzzles, and a variety of minigames. Summon. Soothe. Enlarge. Enrage. Explode. Have a little sleep. Succeed strangely, or sit back and enjoy your failures. There are hundreds of different ways to play this game, and the best way is your way.</li><li><strong>Go Explore</strong> – It’s an absolute situation out there. The magical wilds are delirious with magic, the people of the cities hate wizards like you, and there are prisons. Wizard superprisons.</li><li><strong>Make Friends?</strong> – Bother a chaotic cast of characters, from potion witches and sweaty musclemancers, to a bombastic policewoman and a pyromancer who’s just fed up to be honest.</li><li><strong>Get Hats</strong> – Give hats to the hat goblins, please and thank you.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Leximan | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mZfWzBugnQg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge of Spirits coming to Xbox Series, Xbox One on August 15]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/kena-bridge-of-spirits-coming-to-xbox-series-xbox-one-on-august-15</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kena-bridge-of-spirits-coming-to-xbox-series-xbox-one-on-august-15.887958/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/kena-bridge-of-spirits-coming-to-xbox-series-xbox-one-on-august-15<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Ember Lab [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ember-lab">Ember Lab</a> will release <em><a title="Games > Kena: Bridge of Spirits [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kena-bridge-of-spirits">Kena: Bridge of Spirits</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,188 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> both physically and digitally on August 15 for $39.99 / €39.99 / £34.99, the developer announced. <span id="more-877435"></span></p><p><em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits</em>first launched for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and PC via <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/p/kena-bridge-of-spirits" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on September 21, 2021, followed by <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1954200/Kena_Bridge_of_Spirits/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on September 27, 2022. </p><p>The <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,109 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> versions will feature exclusive pirate-themed Rot hats, as well as a unique staff for Kena and a Golden Rot skin.</p><p>The physical edition, distributed by <a title="Companies > Maximum Entertainment [309 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/maximum-entertainment">Maximum Entertainment</a>, will feature the base game, a digital soundtrack, and a retail-exclusive sticker sheet.</p><p>“We’re thrilled to bring the story of Kena to a new audience on Xbox platforms,” said Ember Lab chief operating officer Josh Grier in a press release. “As our debut game, <em>Kena</em> means a great deal to everyone at the studio and the team is excited to share Kena’s journey with more players—we really hope everyone enjoys meeting Kena and her Rot friends!”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Ember Lab:</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits</em> is a story-driven <a title="Genres > Action [1,868 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,505 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> set in a charming world rich with exploration and fast-paced combat. Players find and grow a team of tiny spirit companions called the Rot, enhancing their abilities and creating new ways to manipulate the environment.</p><p>Kena, a young Spirit Guide, travels to an abandoned village in search of the sacred mountain shrine. She struggles to uncover the secrets of this forgotten community hidden in an overgrown forest where wandering spirits are trapped.</p><p><strong>Find the Rot</strong></p><p>Timid and illusive spirits scattered throughout the forest. They maintain balance by decomposing dead and rotting elements.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Build Your Team</strong> – Find and collect Rot to gain powerful abilities, make discoveries, and transform the environment.</li><li><strong>Explore</strong> – A forgotten village and a strange curse. Draw on the power of the Spirit Realm to restore this once-majestic world.</li><li><strong>Fast-Paced Combat</strong> – Spirits have become corrupt, trapped and unable to move on, challenging Kena at every turn.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Xbox Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Kena Coming to Xbox -  August 15" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rrqpJuUfYKI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["We Will Not Be The Last Of Us Studio Forever," Neil Druckmann Says About Naughty Dog]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/we-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-neil-druckmann-says-about-naughty-dog/1100-6523878/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-neil-druckmann-says-about-naughty-dog.887955/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/we-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-neil-druckmann-says-about-naughty-dog/1100-6523878/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523878">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Naughty Dog executive Neil Druckmann has teased the developer's future projects, saying the company will likely create something outside the Last of Us universe at some point in the future. Speaking to <a href="https://www.latimes.com/l-a-influential/story/2024-06-02/neil-druckmann-the-last-of-us-video-game" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Los Angeles Times</a>, Druckmann re-confirmed that Naughty Dog has multiple single-player projects in the works, and, while The Last of Us: Part III may be among them, there will be other games outside that universe.</p><p>"I promise you, we will not be The Last of Us studio forever," he said.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="2030090208" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6463201,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;The%20Last%20of%20Us%20Part%20II%20Remastered%20-%20Features%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:196,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-features-trailer\/2300-6463201\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463201\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463201\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463201\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6463201&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6463201,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6523878&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;the-last-of-us,the-last-of-us-part-ii&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-3,playstation-4,playstation-5,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;scee,scea,sce-australia,scei&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;the-last-of-us&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;the-last-of-us&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6463201},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6463201\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4246237-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/J247NnlO.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1705421760,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="J247NnlO" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> The Last of Us Part II Remastered - Features Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>After Naughty Dog canceled The Last of Us Online in 2023, the developer <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/naughty-dog-has-two-single-player-games-in-development-described-as-ambitious-and-brand-new/1100-6519980/" data-ref-id="1100-6519980">confirmed it had multiple single-player games in development.</a> These games remain unannounced, but Druckmann has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-last-of-us-3-sounds-more-likely-than-ever/1100-6520812/" data-ref-id="1100-6520812">strongly suggested one will be The Last of Us: Part III.</a></p><p>"I've been thinking--is there a concept there [for The Last of Us 3]? For, now years, I haven't been able to find that concept. But recently that's changed," he said in comments published in 2024. "I don't have a story. But I do have that concept that is, to me, as exciting as 1, as exciting as 2. As its own thing, and yet has this throughline for all three. So it does feel like there's probably one more chapter to this story."</p><p>Beyond another entry in The Last of Us series, could Naughty Dog return to the Uncharted series? Don't get your hopes up for that, as Naughty Dog has said it is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/naughty-dog-is-done-with-uncharted-and-might-not-make-last-of-us-3-neil-druckmann-says/1100-6510879/" data-ref-id="1100-6510879">"done" with the franchise </a>(though a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/uncharted-5-could-happen-with-another-developer-di/1100-6438426/" data-ref-id="1100-6438426">different team could, of course, make Uncharted 5</a>).</p><p>Druckmann is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-last-of-us-director-confirms-hes-writing-and-directing-a-new-game/1100-6516818/" data-ref-id="1100-6516818">writing and directing a new game</a>, but he can't say what it is just yet. "I know the fans really want The Last of Us: Part III, I hear about it all the time," Druckmann said in 2023. "All I can say is that we're already into our next project, the decision has already been made. I can't say what it is."</p><p>Some also believe that Naughty Dog might turn its attention to a totally new genre, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fans-think-the-last-of-us-part-1-is-teasing-naughty-dogs-next-ip/1100-6507123/" data-ref-id="1100-6507123">fantasy</a>, for its next game, which could be a new IP.</p><p>Druckmann recently made headlines for calling out the editing of an interview he did with his own company. While Sony removed the interview from its website, <a href="https://x.com/Neil_Druckmann/status/1794187395279253837" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Druckmann uploaded his raw, unedited answers</a>, in which he said he is currently working on a "dream" project. He said, "It's maybe the most excited I've been for a project yet."</p><p>Sony's recent <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/state-of-play-may-2024-all-the-biggest-ps5-announcements-and-games/2900-5435/" data-ref-id="2900-5435">State of Play briefing</a> had no details on any future Naughty Dog games. Many are expecting Sony to conduct its next PlayStation Showcase later this year, and if that happens, it could be a venue for Naughty Dog to announce a new project, but this is just speculation.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skybound CEO David Alpert to keynote Gamescom Latam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/skybound-ceo-david-alpert-to-keynote-gamescom-latam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skybound-ceo-david-alpert-to-keynote-gamescom-latam.887952/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/skybound-ceo-david-alpert-to-keynote-gamescom-latam<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Exec will discuss the potential for expanding IP across all forms of entertainment with games investor Jon Goldman</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>The organisers of Gamescom Latam have announced David Alpert, CEO of Skybound Entertainment, as its inaugural keynote speaker.</p>
<p>Alpert — who is also known as the executive producer behind The Walking Dead and Invincible — will take part in a fireside chat with video games investor Jon Goldman on June 28, midway through the first ever Gamescom Latam.</p>
<p>During their session, entitled 'Expansion of IP and games', the pair will discuss the state of the games industry, as well as the opportunities for video games IP in other forms of entertainment (and vice versa).</p>
<p>"Being the keynote speaker at Gamescom Latam is an honor," said Alpert. "This inaugural event is a testament to the global reach of gaming culture, which never fails to bring together diverse communities to foster the future of games.</p>
<p>"We've reached a critical time in the industry where expanding our intellectual properties across movies, TV, games, and immersive realities is about more than just entertainment; it's about creating interconnected universes that immerse audiences in storytelling like never before."</p>
<p>Gamescom Latam CEO Gustavo Steinberg added:  "David and Jon's involvement marks a pivotal moment for Gamescom Latam as we explore the intersection of storytelling and gaming.</p>
<p>"The expansion of intellectual properties across platforms is not merely a trend but a fundamental shift in how we engage with content. David's profound knowledge of this phenomenon will undoubtedly enrich our audience's understanding and inspire new avenues of creative exploration."</p>
<p>Announced earlier this year, Gamescom Latam is a brand new event that encompasses and builds on the foundations of the BIG Festival in Brazil.</p>
<p>It will run from June 26 to 30 in São Paulo, Brazil, and is the product of a partnership between Gamecom organiser Koelnmesse, German trade body Game, BIG Festival, and pop culture and events firm Omelete Company.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/gamescom-latam-launching-in-2024-merging-with-big-festival">we spoke to the organisers</a> to find out more about their ambitions for the event.</p>
<section><p>GamesIndustry.biz is a media partner for Gamescom Latam and will be attending with the support of the organisers.</p></section>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Arctic Eggs are a dish best served cold]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/why-arctic-eggs-are-a-dish-best-served-cold</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-arctic-eggs-are-a-dish-best-served-cold.887949/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/why-arctic-eggs-are-a-dish-best-served-cold<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">takes the player to a gray, frozen Antarctic settlement, having them fry up eggs, bacon, and other odd eats for the people eking out a living in such a frigid place.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer caught up with Keven Brown of The Water Museum, creators of this chilly cooking experience, to talk about the strange origins of creating a game about frying eggs in a depressing sci-fi future, the deep thoughts that went into making the frying mechanic work just right, and how the limitations of a game jam would lead to creating just the perfect bleak world for thw players to cook in.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer: </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> is a “sci-fi cooking game” about a poultry peddler feeding lonely folks in the Arctic. What inspired the creation of this game? Why explore egg frying in a chilly future?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Keven Brown</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">: So frying eggs in the future was definitely not what I initially set out to do. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> began as a much larger and more complex project. The initial idea was that you are actually a fast-food worker working night shifts, hoping to save up enough money for a plane ticket to Antarctica. It was meant to feature tons of cooking activities and ingredients, but after months and months of work, nothing really felt fun in a meaningful way except for just flipping eggs around in a pan. At the time, I really didn't believe I could make a full game with just that one mechanic, so I moved on.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Later, as I was knee-deep in another project, I played </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tales From Off-Peak City</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, a game where all you do is make pizzas, talk to people, and explore the world. It is deceptively simple and I loved it. I figured once I was done with this bigger project I would try to make something like this with the frying pan mechanic I made prior. As luck would have it, shortly afterward, Youtuber Dunkey announced he was hosting a two-week-long game jam, and I figured this would be a quick way to get this idea out of my system.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The futuristic part of the game wasn't well thought out at first. While working on another project called </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ettare</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, I met CDbunker2. He is not only a skilled 3D artist but also an incredibly fast worker. Because of this, I knew if I wanted to make something really interesting I needed his help on the project. I doubted I would be able to convince him to abandon </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ettare</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for a few weeks to help out on a random cooking game. So, in order to maybe create a bit more intrigue around the idea, I decided to just tack on some sort of sci-fi twist to the whole thing. Thankfully, this was just enough to spark his interest and get him excited about the entire prospect. And just as I hoped, bringing him on board transformed the game into something special and unique. It became as much about storytelling as it was about cooking.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Can you tell us the thoughts that went into the game's complex frying system and tying that action to mouse movements?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">So, the frying itself is extremely simple. You move your mouse, and it tilts the pan, and you need to keep the pan moving to generate heat. I had to fight really hard with myself to keep it that way throughout development because I think that's where the success of the game comes from. The lack of options allows anyone, in less than a few seconds, to be completely ready for any challenge I throw at you, allowing the actual levels to be pretty open in how you decide to navigate them.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Also, this lack of complexity in the frying pan forces you to pay much more attention to the food itself. The shape and positioning are incredibly important, and throughout the game, you learn what each food is capable of and how best to maneuver it. Because of this, though, that means that the challenge of the game is completely dependent on you, because there are no tricks/upgrades/stats to make the game easier. It's all about your understanding of the frying pan and what you have to do to best maneuver what's inside it.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What challenges went into making this control scheme feel comfortable and getting the motion of flipping eggs and other foods to feel somewhat intuitive?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">So, the biggest challenge, as I mentioned before, was sticking to the incredibly simple control scheme because moving the mouse to tilt the pan was, thankfully, a very intuitive process right from the start, and I was worried I would mess that up if I kept adding to it.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the jam version of the game, you will notice some features that were present that got removed in the final version that's releasing soon. A big one was the ability to use WASD to move the pan around a little bit. My thinking was that if you flipped something poorly, you would get the chance to try to catch the falling food by adjusting your pan’s position. Granted, this did work for the most part; however (and you can see even see this in Dunkey’s stream of the game), players would mistakenly think that WASD was more important than mouse movement, leading to some extreme frustration early on, where they would just be mashing WASD hoping that the egg would hit the edge of the pan just right and with enough momentum to flip it over.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This, and one or two other pan abilities, just kind of muddied the waters, in my opinion. It was like I was telling players that there is a way to circumnavigate learning the ins and outs of the pan/physics when, in reality, there is not, and any time spent trying something different is time wasted in my eyes.</span></p><p>Images via The Water Museum.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What thoughts went into creating the different (sometimes odd) cooking requests the characters will ask the player? How did you design these around challenging the player with your cooking systems?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When coming up with new ingredients for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, it always began with the question of, “How can I add a new challenge that gets in the way of egg flipping?” and then thinking of a food item or object that would justify that challenge.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One of the most basic challenges in most other cooking games is “don’t burn the food” and that was the first challenge I tried for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as well. That is pretty easy to add—the part that really matters, though, is how this is communicated to the player. The video game-y thing to do would be to make some sort of UI element that indicates a food's health. I attempted this, but I hated everything I tried. It felt like it was no longer the frying pan and I taking on this world; it was me, the frying pan, and this out-of-place little UI hovering above the food babying me. That is when the cigarette ingredient was born. It provided a unique and UI-free method to indicate the remaining time via how much of the cigarette is left. And since I made this so early on in development (I think it was the first thing I made after the eggs), it really set the tone for the rest of the game. I decided any additional ingredient I make should make sense visually with the challenge at hand without any UI.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">“I want an ingredient that you have to be more careful with.” Okay… Maybe a beer that you don't want tipping over and spilling everywhere? “I want an ingredient that you have to fight to keep in the pan.” Maybe a cockroach that scurries to the edge and tries to jump out? “I want an ingredient that you have to toss OUT of the pan.” Maybe a bullet that explodes if it gets too hot?</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There were so many non-food related ideas I had that were built on top of the egg-flipping foundation, and since the cigarette itself&nbsp;is introduced so early on in the game I think players are very willing to accept it as a valid request in this world.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What thoughts went into the design of this grim Antarctic settlement? What feelings did you want the environments to evoke as the player wandered through here and fed people?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">So, to get myself in a sci-fi headspace, I watched a ton of Cowboy Bebop (fantastic anime if you have never watched it) during the game jam, and I remember feeling a bit stuck on what the city should feel like near the beginning. Frustrated, I just decided to watch the show with my full attention instead of just having it off to the side. The Jupiter Jazz episodes just happened to be playing at the time. The city in those specific episodes is very cold and sparse, but because of how isolating it is, it feels as lifeless as a desert. The people there are all pretty indifferent towards their situation and each other. They aren't really sad; it just seems like the only glint of happiness they feel is when they are just hanging out together in the bar, listening to some guy play his saxophone. After watching these episodes, I remember thinking how perfectly that aligned with what I wanted to do.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The somewhat depressing brutalist aesthetic of the outer city was definitely born just out of necessity for the game jam. I didn't really think too much of it at the time. It is relatively easy to achieve a convincing brutalist city look with a couple of cement textures and some windowed rectangles. The city in the Jupiter Jazz episodes did have a ton of detail to them—ads hung up everywhere, pipes wrapping around other pipes—but with less than a week to finish everything, that type of busy look would have taken too long.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">However, what’s interesting is what happened after the jam. I tried going back and sprucing things up, making things more “interesting,” but anything I tried just felt dishonest to the world. You are in Antarctica, the people are cold, hungry, and smoking cigarettes constantly. Something is clearly wrong here and making the environments more suited for people didn't feel right. The people barely belong here.&nbsp;I think the harshness of the environment is what really motivates players as well. Ultimately, you, as the player in the world, are inconsequential. You aren't trying to be a hero or kill the bad guy. You are just feeding people. I think that almost feels more important than saving the day when in contrast with the environment. Like you are just trying to be a tiny little moment of warmth for individuals in this cold, uninviting city.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Likewise, what ideas went into the designs of the characters players would be cooking for?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The initial idea for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> involved people at a rooftop party in a future Antarctic city. They needed cold-weather clothes but still looked like they'd come to have a good time. Above all else, I wanted them to be a little bit strange and off-putting on first impression to justify the weird stuff they ingest throughout the game.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">CDbunker2 handled most of the character modeling in the game, and he writes this about their design/look: “The characters owe a heavy debt to fashion designers like Walter Van Beirendonck as well as comic books like Transmetropolitan and the hyper-detailed background characters in the works of Geoff Darrow. The nose tubes, cyborg parts, and random details are all attempts to suggest a typical cyberpunk future where people take part in extreme fads with drugs and body modification.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As the game developed its own feel, I tried to make the characters suggest a disaffected, disassociated sort of mood. They're contemplative, maybe bored, and always waiting to be fed, entertained, or to smoke another cigarette. Also, most importantly, as a designer, they had to look interesting. The players should want to come up to them. Even the menacing soldiers.”</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What drew you to explore storytelling through food and cooking for people? How did you weave frying eggs into the stories that people tell you as you cook for them in </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Storytelling is one of the main things I wanted to explore with the game. Cooking in video games has been represented in many different ways already, whether it is used to demonstrate the technical intricacies of the culinary arts, explore a certain culture, or even just as a low-stakes break from a game’s main focus. But, in my opinion, the social aspect of cooking/eating has been kind of put on the back burner in most cooking games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Cooking or eating makes for an incredibly welcoming setting when trying to tell a story because functionally when eating or cooking in a group setting, you are meant to just sit for a long period of time and mingle. As an inexperienced writer, I find it hard to tell a complex story naturally because I never want to come across as preachy, especially when it comes to lore. In real life, when was the last time you got a huge exposition dump about the history of our world from someone you just met? Or even someone you have known for awhile? I rarely do. In games, whenever this happens, I find myself skipping the dialogue. I feel like it's easy to see that it's not a real world I am learning about, it's just a writer going “Look at me! I am writing something interesting! Look!”</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rarely in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> does someone say anything outwardly important to you because these are strangers who don't really know you. This created an atmosphere that I think a lot of people found refreshing in the game. This is a setting where people are eating, so mingling with them feels natural—there is a story, but you genuinely don't have to engage with it if you don't want to because these characters have far more to say about mundane things they deal with every day.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The game is like being at a cookout, I think. The food is definitely the main selling point but it's really all just an excuse to get a big group together and socialize.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What interested you about exploring human connection and condition in a bleak future through cooking for people? What is it about cooking and eating that can help weave unique shared connections between people all over the world, and how did you want to use those feelings in </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I think many cooking games do a fantastic job at exploring human connection through cooking. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Venba</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Nainai’s Recipe</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> come to mind. Both are incredibly beautiful games about culture, heritage, and reconnecting with something or someone through the act of making food. Cooking is a uniquely human ritual where we are expected to slow down and mingle, so it is unsurprising that so many cooking games are able to tell incredibly personal and emotional stories.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is also about connecting with others, but I think what sets it apart is the emphasis is taken off of the food itself. Most of the food in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is kinda gross and unappetizing. The ingredients used are also repeated throughout at varying quantities, so it's hard to really make a connection with it. Because of this, though, the emphasis is on what the character says before you feed them (and sometimes after). This stranger who you would have probably walked right by (if you weren't specifically looking for another mouth to feed) has a life and you get a glimpse at what they care/worry about.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arctic Eggs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the food might not be appealing, but it's the vehicle that brings players into these unique exchanges with people you would have never connected with otherwise. Each interaction adds a layer to the story, making the mundane act of feeding someone a profound experience of connection and understanding.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neil Druckmann Says Naughty Dog 'Will Not Be The Last Of Us Studio Forever,' Multiple Single-Player Projects In Development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/03/neil-druckmann-says-naughty-dog-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-multiple</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neil-druckmann-says-naughty-dog-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-multiple-single-player-projects-in-development.887946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/03/neil-druckmann-says-naughty-dog-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-multiple<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Naughty Dog won't be The Last of Us studio forever, according to studio president Neil Druckmann. He told the <a href="https://www.latimes.com/l-a-influential/story/2024-06-02/neil-druckmann-the-last-of-us-video-game"><em>LA Times</em></a>&nbsp;this in a new interview, which is where he also said the studio has multiple single-player projects in development, as reported by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/we-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-says/"><em>VideoGamesChronicle</em></a>.</p>

<p>"I promise you, we will not be The Last of Us studio forever," Druckmann said, revealing the team is working on "multiple single-player projects." He continued, adding, "We create experiences that are steeped in story and characters, especially relationships. The stories have some sort of philosophical core that everything is going to revolve around and feed into."</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CpqyeBP-_14" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Elsewhere in the interview, Druckmann told the&nbsp;<em>LA Times</em>&nbsp;he came up with the idea about a man and a girl crossing a post-apocalyptic landscape – the premise of The Last of Us – in college. He planned to get that story out of his head one day as a graphic novel. Even after getting hired at Naughty Dog, he didn't bring up this story to the studio, he said. Instead, he was given the task of recreating <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/games/jak_and_daxter_collection/b/ps3/archive/2012/02/07/jak-and-daxter-collection-updates-a-classic-ps2-trilogy.aspx">Jak and Daxter</a> into "something more reality-based," the publication writes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, he and those on the task were struggling. They went to Naughty Dog's then-president Evan Wells, who retired last year, and asked, "Do we need to do Jak and Daxter?" Wells said no, and Druckmann told the&nbsp;<em>LA Times</em>, "Immediately the lightbulb went off" as the time for what would become The Last of Us had arrived. And the rest is history.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HKFJhbjlJaw" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>This interview follows Druckmann's recent interview with PlayStation, which resulted in a public rebuttal of the interview by Druckmann, with him claiming he was heavily misquoted, and <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/05/29/update-sony-pulls-down-heavily-misquoted-neil-druckmann-interview-and-apologizes-for">PlayStation eventually pulling the interview down completely</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Word of multiple single-player projects in development at Naughty Dog follows news from last December where <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2023/12/14/naughty-dog-ceases-development-of-the-last-of-us-online">Naughty Dog canceled its Last of Us live-service multiplayer project after years of development</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For more, read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/games/the_last_of_us/b/ps3/archive/2013/06/05/the-last-of-us-review-naughty-dogs-grim-masterpiece.aspx"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>review of The Last of Us</a> and then read <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/the-last-of-us-part-ii/the-last-of-us-part-ii-review-a-perfect-circle">our review of The Last of Us Part II</a>. After that, read <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/opinion/2022/08/31/i-thought-the-last-of-us-was-better-than-this#:~:text=Part%20I%20is%20undeniably%20gorgeous,more%20stunning%20than%20ever%20before.">our impressions of Naughty Dog's remake of The Last of Us</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>[Source: <a href="https://www.latimes.com/l-a-influential/story/2024-06-02/neil-druckmann-the-last-of-us-video-game">LA Times</a> via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/we-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-says/">VideoGamesChronicle</a>]</em></p>

<hr>
<p><em>What do you hope Naughty Dog's next game is? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Corsairs: Battle of the Caribbean launches in 2024 for PC; 2025 for PS5, Xbox Series, and Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/corsairs-battle-of-the-caribbean-launches-in-2024-for-pc-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/corsairs-battle-of-the-caribbean-launches-in-2024-for-pc-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch.887922/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/corsairs-battle-of-the-caribbean-launches-in-2024-for-pc-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PlayStation 4 and Xbox One versions seemingly no longer planned.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Pirate <a title="Genres > Strategy [173 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">strategy game</a> <em><a title="Games > Corsairs: Battle of the Caribbean [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/corsairs-battle-of-the-caribbean">Corsairs: Battle of the Caribbean</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [338 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store in 2024, followed by <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,139 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,395 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> in 2025, publisher <a title="Companies > Microids [185 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/microids">Microids</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Fishing Cactus [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fishing-cactus">Fishing Cactus</a> announced. <span id="more-886763"></span></p><p>The <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2023/06/corsairs-battle-of-the-caribbean-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc">previously announced</a> <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,743 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,188 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> versions were not mentioned in today’s announcement, suggesting they may no longer be planned.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Microids:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Take on the role of a privateer, serving your chosen nation to earn fame and wealth. Navigate treacherous seas, build a powerful fleet, and wage epic battles against enemy vessels.</p><p>Your journey will take you to the exotic islands of the Antilles, where you can discover treasures and fight for your nation’s supremacy in the Caribbean. Choose to represent one of the great maritime powers: French, Danish, Spanish, British, or Dutch.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Live a Pirate’s Life!</strong></p><p>Combining both tactical combat and <a title="Genres > Management [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a>-oriented gameplay, lead smartly your fleet and defend your trading positions. Discover new types of soldiers, and an expanded campaign mode for a more immersive experience.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Engage in intense naval battles with a fleet of 12 different ships, and make use of 3 types of unique ammunition.</li><li>Master the enhanced trading mechanics, manage your fleet and cities wisely, and defend your trading positions to establish your dominance.</li><li>Upgrade your ships and strengthen your crew by earning resources from quests, defeating enemies, and exploring new territories.</li><li>Three types of soldiers: Tank, Gunner and Agile are now the mainstay of your crew’s fighting force.</li><li>Dive into the expanded Campaign Mode with five engaging storylines.</li><li>The game also introduces a revamped “Boarding” mode, featuring different soldier classes and a Captain who can take part in battles.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a teaser trailer below.</p><h2><span>Reveal Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Corsairs – Battle of the Caribbean – Reveal Teaser ESRB" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G_WzdPSxnFA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MW3 players are sick of old guns getting nerfed into the ground every season]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/mw3-players-are-sick-of-old-guns-getting-nerfed-into-the-ground-every-season/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=mw3-players-are-sick-of-old-guns-getting-nerfed-into-the-ground-every-season</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mw3-players-are-sick-of-old-guns-getting-nerfed-into-the-ground-every-season.887919/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/mw3-players-are-sick-of-old-guns-getting-nerfed-into-the-ground-every-season/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=mw3-players-are-sick-of-old-guns-getting-nerfed-into-the-ground-every-season<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="244" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">It started off as a meme, grew into a theory, and now is widely accepted by the community: When new guns are added into <em>Modern Warfare 3</em>, Sledgehammer makes them way too powerful and nerf older guns into the ground, and players are sick of it. </p> <p data-characters="357" data-current-count="357" data-injectable="false">Every season, Sledgehammer will introduce at least one new weapon to the game, giving completionists a weapon to rank up. This is a good idea in theory, but what you find is that any new gun added is immediately the best in the game, and dominates the meta for weeks, while older guns that have been in the game before have their effectiveness turned down. </p> <p data-characters="152" data-current-count="509" data-injectable="true">This causes great frustration among fans, and FlowKom took specific offense to this on Reddit, complaining about how the launch of the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/best-kar98k-loadout-in-mw3-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kar98k</a> has gone. </p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>It’s been a controversial return for the Kar98k. Image via Activision</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="251" data-current-count="551" data-injectable="true">“New gun=good, Old gun=bad,” wrote the <em>CoD </em>fan. “That’s their entire philosophy for balance. There’s no reason for the SP-R and SA-B to be utterly useless while the Kar98k is the new best sniper in the entire game.”</p>
 <p data-characters="244" data-current-count="244" data-injectable="false">FlowKom made their point by showing the effective damage range for the Kar98k and the SP-R208. While the Kar98k is powerful up to 50.8m, the SPR208 only has a damage range of 13m, which is almost four times less powerful than the new inclusion.</p> <p data-characters="507" data-current-count="751" data-injectable="true">Unsurprisingly, the comments were largely in agreement with the post, with one fan writing: “I get they want to make the new guns better than the old ones, but they didn’t have to make the old ones that bad,” while another questioned the process entirely: “I personally don’t see the point in making your new gun [overpowered] when we know it’ll get nerfed into the ground later. Is the appeal that you get a couple of weeks of enjoyment where you feel like a god?”</p>
 <p data-characters="326" data-current-count="326" data-injectable="false">It’s having a clear effect though. As shown by <a href="https://wzstats.gg/mw3/meta" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WZStats.gg</a>, the Kar98k is currently the most-picked weapon in the game at 5.37%. The SP-R208’s pickrate? 0.02%. Clearly, something isn’t quite right with Sledgehammer’s balancing principles, and I, along with other <em>MW3</em> fans, would love to see it changed. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fabledom Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/03/fabledom-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fabledom-review.887910/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/03/fabledom-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/03/fabledom-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Fabledom Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Dominic L">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-06-03">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-06-02">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Witches cast curses on you, fawns walk the streets, and you’ve found a missing glass slipper. You might think you know the rest of this particular story, but the question that Fabledom poses for you is whether to return that glass slipper to its owner or pawn it to swell your kingdom’s coffers. Fabledom is a city builder with a severe case of the bedtime stories, merging a traditional dose of laying down pathways, houses and woodcutters with princesses, dragons and evil witches. It’s an approachable and fun take on a genre that often takes itself a bit too seriously, and it’s all the better for it.</p>
<p><iframe title="FABLEDOM - 1.0 Launch &amp; Console Preorder Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NtCwO_YUbKQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>When I say that Fabledom is a traditional city-builder, that’s perhaps selling it short. Sure, the first thing you have to do is start chopping down trees and building houses, but there’s a series of well though-out wrinkles to the formula to make you sit up and take notice. Building a house, or several other structures, requires you to build corresponding attachments, whether that’s a garden, which you can lay out with a selection of different furniture, or a storage unit’s palettes of useful material. It immediately means that your little hamlet looks more unique, and more lively, and that your Fablings have a much more interesting home to tootle about in.</p>


<p>There’s a surprising level of additional depth to the building shenanigans too, bringing in more advanced features like ensuring that homes have access to water and sanitation and that your kingdom has a decent stock of coal in preparation for the winter. You also have to consider the attractiveness of an area if you’re going to build homes there. Pop down a bakery and everyone in the vicinity will be happier. If it’s a sawmill instead, be prepared for some unhappy faces, and far less chance you’ll attract new citizens to join you.</p>


<p>Those new citizens are the lifeblood of your domain, as they provide daily taxes with which you expand your reach, and as the workers in your key locations. It’s often a juggling act, as you reach the limits of your undeniably cute workforce, but need to continue expanding or stocking up for the winter. This is where Fabledom takes things a little too slowly, and I often found myself punching the game speed to the highest rate while I waited for a woodcutter to decide to chop enough trees down, or a mason to pump out enough stone bricks. I’m all for relaxed, but the developer might need to make a few tweaks here to the output levels of some structures.</p>
<p>Once you’ve laid the foundations of your kingdom, there’s a real push to beautify and titivate your land with flowers, gardens and additional furniture. You’ll finish up with a city that’s far more attractive than in any other city builder. The cute visuals are more in the vein of The Settlers, or its recent spiritual successor Pioneers of Pagonia, and when you add in the fairytale aspects as well I can see this being a huge success with younger gamers, particularly when it arrives on console later in the year. That said, there’s a lot to balance here so they might need some adult assistance along the way.</p>

<p>So, where do the fables come in? Once you’ve reached a certain point in proceedings, you unlock a Hero. This mighty knight can be equipped with all manner of equipment that you find along the way, and while he’s your greatest warrior he’s also something of a busybody, heading out to explore your kingdom and sticking his nose into all manner of fairytale nonsense. You’re generally presented with a choice of how to proceed, so a talking tree you encounter might offer a boon to the growth of your trees, or you can chop him down for a big payday. There’s a fun and slightly tongue-in-cheek tone to everything in Fabledom, and I really enjoyed its mildly subversive take on some classic fairytale stories.</p>
<p>There are, of course, battles to be won as well. As a city builder you must raise an army to protect your lands, and perhaps to conquer others. However, you can simply try to stay safe within the walls of your kingdom, building immense structures and siting weaponry on top of them to keep the invaders out. It’s hugely appealing, and just as with the rest of the experience, there’s a steady stream of upgrades to keep everything moving forward.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Fabledom offers one of the most well-rounded takes on the city-builder genre, mixing addictive kingdom-building with a fun and unique dose of fairytale shenanigans.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>City building with real depth</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Attractive visuals</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Genuinely amusing and engaging</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Occasionally a little too slow for its own good</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Patch 7 adds official modding toolkit this autumn]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-adds-official-modding-toolkit-this-autumn</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-adds-official-modding-toolkit-this-autumn.887907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-adds-official-modding-toolkit-this-autumn<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Closed alpha test begins today.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bg3_baldursgate3_nightsong_dameaylin.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer / Larian</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Baldur's Gate 3 will finally add official mod support in September, after a summer of ongoing testing - which begins today.
</p>
<p>
Patch 7, which will include the game's modding toolkit, begins testing now via a closed alpha which will run for around a month. In July, a further 1000 players will be added, as part of a closed beta. 
</p>
<p>
The idea is that the alpha test will develop mod tools and bring over existing mods, while the beta test will then provide feedback on these. That should then take everyone through to September, when Patch 7 rolls out for everyone. 
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Baldur's Gate 3 for Dummies,<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X9MOORXyRtI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
"With the intention of working through your feedback throughout the summer, it will give us time to polish off Patch 7 ready for release in September," Larian wrote today in a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4179982568653520452">blog post</a> on Steam. 
</p>
<p>
"In the meantime, we still have plenty coming your way, including some anniversary extravagance as we look back on the months since release. We're also still pressing on with the development of an in-game photo mode, crossplay, and more fixes that will arrive later down the line!"
</p>
<p>
The blog post goes into detail on why the modding support is important - to avoid issues with game stability and compatibility - and detail how it will work, using Mod.io to enable support for all platforms. 
</p>
<p>
"Releasing first on PC, we expect to roll out the support to the wider community and various platforms shortly after - including for Mac players, as well as PlayStation and Xbox consoles," Larian continued.
</p>
<p>
There's detail too on which mods may fall foul of the Dungeons &amp; Dragons license.
</p>
<p>
"Our goal with mod.io and our partners is to strike a balance that allows for extensive modding while keeping the guidelines in mind," Larian wrote. "While some NSFW mods and certain script-heavy modifications may not be supported through the official pipeline, modding outside of our pipeline will still be an option."
</p>
<p>
Larian Studios boss Swen Vincke recently discussed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/larian-studios-ceo-says-we-did-have-to-do-a-bit-of-crunch-making-baldurs-gate-3">the need to "do a bit of crunch" making Baldur's Gate 3</a>, but only "very, very, very rarely".
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 once had a portable hole, but Swen Vincke says it would have been a "crime against humanity"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-once-had-a-portable-hole-but-swen-vincke-says-it-would-have-been-a-crime-against-humanity</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-once-had-a-portable-hole-but-swen-vincke-says-it-would-have-been-a-crime-against-humanity.887904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-once-had-a-portable-hole-but-swen-vincke-says-it-would-have-been-a-crime-against-humanity<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>"We had to remove it, but it was fantastic."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bg3-success-3.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Larian Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>I'm sure you could fill a bottomless pit with the things Larian decided not to add to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-class-list">Baldur's Gate 3</a>. One of those things was, in fact, a bottomless pit. Not just a bottomless pit, but a conveniently portable, Looney Tunes-esque hole into which you could seemingly chuck everything from items and equipment to characters. Speaking to me during the same interview in which they discussed <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-baldurs-gate-3-might-have-brought-back-candlekeep-the-library-fortress-where-baldurs-gate-began">long-abandoned plans for bringing back Baldur’s Gate 1’s Candlekeep</a>, Larian CEO Swen Vincke and Baldur’s Gate 3 lead writer Adam Smith (RPS in peace) touched on the subject with tantalising brevity. Argh, if only I hadn’t had to run off and catch a taxi, I’d still be there now, discussing the many applications of a portable hole. Bypassing carrying capacity limits would just be the start of it.</p>
<p>The hole came up during a discussion of whether Larian have considered testing any smaller, more focussed videogame concepts, perhaps to let younger developers try their wits on something less sprawling than a Baldur’s Gate. “Oh, you mean within Larian in terms of incubation? But there's always stuff happening that you never see,” Vincke began. “I think people still underestimate how much work these big <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPGs</a> are already, and how many components there are in there - you never see a lot of small things that are being done, but there's a lot of innovation happening, other things that never see the daylight.”</p>
<p>“You see small groups, and juniors in those small groups, you know, they'll bring the things that they care about,” Adam added. “You can see, I think, in Baldur’s Gate 3 that there a lot of scripters who are immersive sim fans, and who are bringing ideas from elsewhere. The world is sandboxy, and within that they are playing with their favourite genres. I get to play with horror, you know, one of my favourite genres, in the storytelling. An RPG of that scale, you’re kind of making lots of things all at the same time. So there's definitely the space to do that.”</p>
<p>There’d have been even more space if one particular cosmic impossibility hadn’t been left on the cutting room floor. “There's one mechanic in particular that I'm thinking of that they brought in,” said Vincke, apparently in reference to the aforesaid scripters. “It was fantastic. It was just we couldn't make it work in all cases, so we had to remove it, but it was fantastic. And it was a portable hole, which is like a mechanic, so you could basically throw down a hole, you can throw people in it, and then you could do start doing all kinds of abusive mechanics in the game.” My audio is a bit smudgy here – Vincke may have said “abusive” or “abuse of mechanics”, both of which would make sense in context.</p>
<p>Larian’s QA staff ultimately “vetoed” the idea, which strikes me as a display of utmost sanity and powerful self-respect from testers who do not wish to spend the rest of their mortal lives hotfixing a pocket-sized infinity. “When you see all the things that [our QA director] had to go through just to be able to test this game - really, adding anything else to that would have been a crime against humanity,” Vincke noted.</p>
<p>Still, we players do not have to worry about patching out bugs and exploits, and are free to mourn the hole-based playthroughs that might have been. Seriously, I can think of <em>any</em> number of uses for a portable bottomless pit and barely any of them are sexual. The obvious one is trying to dump the entirety of Baldur's Gate 3 inside it – mindflayers, tieflings, cheese, Medallions of +5 Whatever, rehaired cats, cities, the Underdark, etcetera.</p>
<p>I can imagine an endgame version of the Sword Coast that consists of Tav balancing on the last remaining barrel, hole in hand, surrounded by coruscating silver strands of pure absence. Tav catches your gaze and winks. Then they stuff <em>themselves</em> into the hole, from ankle to head, reaching out as they vanish to grab the barrel and yank it into the hole as though corking a bottle. Years later, while playing Larian's next game (<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/larian-dont-know-what-their-next-game-is-yet-but-it-wont-be-baldurs-gate-4-or-baldurs-gate-3-dlc">not Baldur's Gate 4</a>), you notice a strange little dark spot. You right-click the spot and the entirety of Baldur's Gate 3 appears in your inventory. Hopefully, we'll have bigger SSDs by then.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Disclosure: Former RPS deputy editor Adam Smith (RPS in peace) now works at Larian and is the lead writer for Baldur's Gate 3. Former contributor Emily Gera also works on it.</em></p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abubakar Salim addresses "fever pitch" of racism received after launch of Tales of Kenzera: Zau]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/abubakar-salim-addresses-fever-pitch-of-racism-received-after-launch-of-tales-of-kenzera-zau</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/abubakar-salim-addresses-fever-pitch-of-racism-received-after-launch-of-tales-of-kenzera-zau.887895/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/abubakar-salim-addresses-fever-pitch-of-racism-received-after-launch-of-tales-of-kenzera-zau<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"There's room for all of us."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/tales-of-kenzera-ps.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Surgent Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Abubakar Salim, creator of the recent Tales of Kenzera: Zau, has addressed the "fever pitch" of "constant targeted harassment" the studio has received since the release of the game.
</p>
<p>
The game is inspired by Salim's own story of grief and set in an Afrofuturist world based on Bantu Tales and African folklore.
</p>
<p>
However, in a video posted to X, Salim responded to the abuse received and announced a price drop for the game on Switch.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Tales of Kenzera: ZAU Official Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mYYYJ5w0O_I?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Tales of Kenzera: ZAU Official Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mYYYJ5w0O_I?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mYYYJ5w0O_I?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Tales of Kenzera: Zau Official Launch Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mYYYJ5w0O_I" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"We are being faced with constant targeted harassment from people who see diversity as a threat, from people who look across the vast landscape of modern media and decide that anything that doesn't speak to them or centres around them is unnecessary and inauthentic," he said.
</p>
<p>
"There's always a reason diverse stories can't exist. It's either we're doing it the wrong way or it's just there to tick boxes. And it's just beginning to feel like there is no right way, these exclusionary rules just continue to stack up and the goalposts continue to shift until me, my studio, people who look like us just sit down, be quiet and just accept the fact that you're outsiders. But I won't do that."
</p>
<p>
He continued: "If there are people who aren't like you in a game, I want you to know that game is still for you. If the characters are a different race, or a different gender, or a different ideology, or a different perspective, that doesn't mean the game isn't for you. It can still be for you. It's an opportunity to live in rich new worlds, to explore different perspectives, to explore different cultures... you just need to be open to it."
</p>
<p>
In response, Salim has worked with Nintendo to drop the price of Tales of Kenzera: Zau in the US until the end of June, which he intends to do across all platforms.
</p>
<p>
"I really believe games are for everyone, that's why I insisted on setting Zau's cost at the price of a pizza," said Salim.
</p>
<p>
"I genuinely believe in the power that games have to bring us closer together," he surmised. "Diverse games are not about taking something away from you, they're about adding something in. Because there's room for all of us."
</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>
Sadly, since the release of the video, Salim and the development team have received further abuse accusing them of faking the harassment as a marketing ploy.
</p>
<p>
Salim has addressed this in a further thread.
</p>
<p>
"Since the first moments of creating this game, the focus was on my father's legacy and what I wanted it to leave behind to represent that," he said. "Since announcing, we steered away from race as a subject matter as much as possible, because the game isn't about that. It's about the human journey of grief. 
</p>
<p>
"This didn't stop the harassment that came our way. And I knew that as soon as I chose to address the subject of race, the legacy of this game would be diluted. But something had to be said. Suffering in silence wasn't an option. It needed to be addressed. Because by not speaking to it, countless others out there who would also suffer in silence and not see the power they have to tell stories through their unique perspectives, whether they choose to make the race of the character a key focus or not."
</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">I’ve been reading&nbsp; a lot of comments and opinions on the video I posted Friday and I want to thank those who have shown their support. I’m aware that the world doesn’t revolve around social media, but there is something to be said about seeing that love and support come from so…</p>— Abubakar Salim (@Abzybabzy) <a href="https://twitter.com/Abzybabzy/status/1797351024685944996?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 2, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>
Salim has been refreshingly open about the development of the game in the run up to its launch and ever since. 
</p>
<p>
"There are all sorts of obstacles you have to go through [to make a game], but I feel like that knowledge needs to be shared," <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/abubakar-salim-on-metroidvanias-as-a-vehicle-for-grief-and-storytelling">he previously told Eurogamer about his transparency</a>. "I think it's important to be quite open and talk about this and I think we're getting there, we're slowly moving towards that kind of position."

</p>
<p>
Salim's comments follow a new wave of anti-diverse sentiment that's seeped into the gaming community, particularly after the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/spider-man-alan-wake-ridiculous-fishing-devs-speak-up-in-support-of-consultancy-studio-sweet-baby-inc">work of diversity consultancy Sweet Baby Inc.</a>, which has been wrongly accused by some of pushing a "woke agenda" in the games industry. 

</p>
<p>
"I've not played a game like Tales of Kenzera before because this type of setting isn't seen enough in gaming, whether due to under-representation in the industry or perceived lack of interest from players," I wrote in our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tales-of-kenzera-review">Eurogamer Tales of Kenzera: Zau review</a>. "But these stories deserve to be told and Salim deserves praise for creating a game with a world that feels so fresh and unique."


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Remake Part 3 to Feature More Combat Freedom and a Potentially Different Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-combat-freedom-different-experience/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-to-feature-more-combat-freedom-and-a-potentially-different-experience.887892/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-combat-freedom-different-experience/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The third and final entry in the Final Fantasy VII Remake series may end up being a very different game than its predecessors, judging from some recent statements from the development team.</p>
<p>Speaking in a new episode of <a href="https://youtu.be/j4fE8ATUr3s">Inside Square Enix</a> focusing on Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, battle director Teruki Endo revealed how he is thinking about how to give players even more freedom, suggesting a further push towards an action-based combat system, a push that was already evident in the INTERmission expansion and Rebirth with the inclusion of Precision Guard and improved aerial combat.</p>
<p>It's not only combat that will likely feel different in the third part of the Final Fantasy VII Remake over its predecessors. Director Naoki Hamaguchi commented on the conclusion of the series, saying that they want to give the fans a different kind of gameplay experience than what they had in the previous two games, suggesting that even the open-world formula introduced in Rebirth is going to be shaken up to offer this different type of experience.</p>
<p><iframe title="シナリオ×ワールド×バトル 『ファイナルファンタジーVII リバース』 こだわりの掛け算と限界への挑戦【#スクエニの創りかた】#FF7リバース #FF7R" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j4fE8ATUr3s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>No matter what, it will be a few years before we can experience the conclusion of the Final Fantasy VII Remake series, as it will take at least three more years to come out. Given Rebirth's ending, it will be very interesting to see which direction the story will take in the third and final part of the series and how everything will be wrapped up in a game that promises to be epic.</p>
<p>The second entry in the Final Fantasy VII Remake series, Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, is now available on PlayStation 5. You can learn more about it by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/">review.</a></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next Xbox Will Use AI Accelerator to Handle AI Tasks, Jez Corden Claims to Have Heard]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/next-xbox-will-use-ai-accelerator-to-handle-ai-tasks-jez-corden-claims-to-have-heard/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-xbox-will-use-ai-accelerator-to-handle-ai-tasks-jez-corden-claims-to-have-heard.887889/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/next-xbox-will-use-ai-accelerator-to-handle-ai-tasks-jez-corden-claims-to-have-heard/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Microsoft's next Xbox console is said to feature an AI accelerator to handle AI tasks.</p>
<p>At least, that's what WindowsCentral's Jez Corden <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/microsoft/the-enormity-of-microsofts-windows-phone-shut-down-mistake-is-becoming-increasingly-clear-in-the-ai-era" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> to have heard from reliable sources in a freshly-published feature article about Windows Phone. According to Corden, this neural processing unit&nbsp;(NPU) inside Microsoft's next hardware will be able to perform some AI tasks, including Auto SR - <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsofts-automatic-super-resolution-upscaling-limited-to-copilot-pcs-select-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft's own resolution upscaling tech</a>. "Reliable sources tell us that the next Xbox will sport an NPU for handling some AI tasks, such as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/microsoft-demos-baldurs-gate-3-borderlands-running-at-30-fps-on-the-new-snapdragon-x-elite-windows-on-arm-platform-with-auto-super-resolution-support-in-tow" data-analytics-id="inline-link" data-before-rewrite-localise="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/microsoft-demos-baldurs-gate-3-borderlands-running-at-30-fps-on-the-new-snapdragon-x-elite-windows-on-arm-platform-with-auto-super-resolution-support-in-tow" data-component-tracked="1" data-hl-processed="none" data-custom-tracking-id="2826340130651112283" data-hawk-tracked="hawklinks" data-google-interstitial="false" data-label="automatic Super Resolution">automatic Super Resolution</a>, for example, without detracting from the CPU or GPU", Corden writes. "The next Xbox will also have some form of Copilot, offering guidance in-game without having to use websites like ours (<em>RIP Windows Central</em>). Still, the amount of people likely to use these tools on Xbox is minuscule compared to the default setting on iOS or Android."</p>
<p>Although Corden initially said the AI accelerator (NPU) would come from Qualcomm, he later clarified that the manufacturer isn't known at this point.&nbsp; "<em>Currently, the manufacturer is unknown at my end, but it's most likely AMD", </em>he later added.</p>
<p>Further details haven't been shared by Corden, but it's interesting information nonetheless. As covered last week, <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-next-reference-design/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft's next Xbox console is said to be very different from the current console and will be a "reference design" for manufacturers</a> to make their own game devices.</p>
<p>Back in April of this year, we reported that Microsoft is seemingly working on an Xbox AI chatbot that helps automate certain tasks. According to The Verge, this bot can, for instance,&nbsp; help automate game refunds. Whether this AI Chatbot is related to the copilot that Corden mentioned, is not entirely clear. "“We are testing an Xbox Support Virtual Agent, an internal prototype of an animated character that can query Xbox Support topics with voice or text,” Xbox general manager of gaming AI, Haiyan Zhang, told the Verge last month. “The prototype makes it easier and quicker for players to get help with support topics using natural language, taking information from existing Xbox Support pages.”</p>
<p>We'll update you as soon as we learn about Microsoft's next Xbox.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asus ROG Ally X is Official, Pre-Orders are Now Live]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rog-ally-x-launch-specifications/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/asus-rog-ally-x-is-official-pre-orders-are-now-live.887886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/rog-ally-x-launch-specifications/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>The Asus ROG Ally X has officially been revealed, and pre-orders are now live! Here’s more information about the handheld console, including specifications, pricing, and availability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The handheld gaming community has been growing steadily in recent times, with manufacturers releasing new devices and refreshes more frequently. The latest refresh comes for arguably the most used handheld console in the industry right now: the Asus ROG Ally. The Asus ROG Ally X is the successor to the handheld console, and it brings a few exciting upgrades. However, it isn’t a complete overhaul that many might be expecting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ROG Ally X vs ROG Ally</p>



<p>There are some notable enhancements for the ROG Ally X, including a lot more RAM, coming in at 24GB LPDDR5 – 7500 MT/s, compared to last gen’s 16GB LPDDR5 – 6400 MT/s. This upgrade will help with performance through the increased RAM and faster speeds. The next big change is its storage, which has doubled from last-gen’s 512GB to 1TB M.2 2280 NVMe PCIe Gen 4 SSD this time around. This means you can fit even more games on your device when traveling (how convenient!)</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<p>Moreover, the one change that fans will be the most excited about is the battery, as Asus has listened to the community and doubled the capacity from 40Wh to 80Wh, which is exciting, to say the least. Lastly, there are minor tweaks to the body, such as enhancements for the handles, the chassis, and the joysticks. Also, the ROG XG Mobile port has been discarded for USB 4 ports on the new device. However, the APU is the same one from the last gen, which is AMD Ryzen 1 Extreme. Check out the full specifications of the ROG Ally X below.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>ROG Ally X Specifications&nbsp;</strong></p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td>Specifications</td><td>ROG Ally X</td></tr><tr><td>CPU</td><td>AMD Ryzen Z1 Extreme Processor (“Zen4” architecture with 4nm process, 8-core /16-threads, 24MB total cache, up to 5.10 GHz boost)</td></tr><tr><td>GPU</td><td>AMD Radeon Graphics (AMD RDNA 3, 12 CUs, up to 2.7 GHz, up to 8.6 Teraflops)<br>TDP: 9-30W</td></tr><tr><td>Display</td><td>7-inch FHD (1920 x 1080) 16:9, IPS-level, glossy display, sRGB:100%, Adobe:75.35%, Gorilla Glass Victus, Touch Screen (10-point multi-touch), Refresh Rate:120Hz, Response Time:7ms, Brightness:500nits, FreeSync Premium</td></tr><tr><td>Memory</td><td>12GBx2 LPDDR5 on board, Support dual channel memory</td></tr><tr><td>Storage</td><td>1TB PCIe 4.0 NVMe M.2 SSD (2280)</td></tr><tr><td>Ports</td><td>1x 3.5mm Combo Audio Jack<br>1x Type C USB 4 support DisplayPort™ / power delivery<br>1x USB 3.2 Gen 2 Type-C support DisplayPort™ / power delivery<br>1x UHS-II microSD card reader (supports SD, SDXC and SDHC)</td></tr><tr><td>Control and Input</td><td>A B X Y buttons, D-pad, L &amp; R Hall Effect analog triggers, L &amp; R bumpers, View button, Menu button, Command Center button, Armoury Crate button, 2 x assignable grip buttons, Thumbsticks: 2 x full-size analog sticks, Haptics: HD haptics, Gyro:6-Axis IMU. </td></tr><tr><td>Audio</td><td>A B X Y buttons, D-pad, L &amp; R Hall Effect analog triggers, L &amp; R bumpers, View button, Menu button, Command Center button, Armoury Crate button, 2 x assignable grip buttons, Thumbsticks: 2 x full-size analogue sticks, Haptics: HD haptics, Gyro:6-Axis IMU. </td></tr><tr><td>Network and Communication</td><td>Wi-Fi 6E(802.11ax) (Triple band) 2×2 + Bluetooth 5.2 (*Bluetooth version may change with OS version different.)</td></tr><tr><td>Battery</td><td>80WHrs, 4S1P, 4-cell Li-ion</td></tr><tr><td>Power Supply</td><td>TYPE-C, 65W AC Adapter, Output: 20V DC, 3.25A, 65W, Input: 100~240V AC 50/60Hz universal</td></tr><tr><td>Weight and Dimensions (W x D x H)</td><td>678 g (1.49 lbs)<br>28.0 x 11.1 x 2.47 ~ 3.69 cm (11.02″ x 4.37″ x 0.97″ ~ 1.45″)</td></tr><tr><td>Security </td><td>Built-in Fingerprint Sensor<br>Microsoft Pluton security processor</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Pricing and Availability </p>



<p>The ROG Ally X has been priced at $799, a $100 increase over the launch price of the previous model. An understandable spike thanks to the substantial upgrades that have arrived for the mid-gen refresh. In terms of availability, interested readers can pre-order the Asus ROG Ally X either from the <a href="https://shop.asus.com/us/rog/90nv00f1-m002f0-rog-ally-x-2024.html">Asus website</a> or <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/asus-rog-ally-x-7-120hz-fhd-1080p-gaming-handheld-amd-ryzen-z1-extreme-processor-1tb-black/6583218.p?intl=nosplash&amp;loc=asus_rogally_6583218_ROG_PDP&amp;ref=186&amp;skuId=6583218" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">BestBuy.com</a>.</p>



<p>Will you pre-order the ROG Ally X? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gamers-libraries-when-they-die/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what happens to your games when you die</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>