<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 03:17:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: New 007 First Light Trailer Introduces Lenny Kravitz As Bawma]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/video-new-007-first-light-trailer-introduces-lenny-kravitz-as-bawma</link>
            <guid>1381006</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Out next year for Switch 2</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>IO Interactive is gearing up to release <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/007-first-light">007 First Light</a> next year on the Switch 2 and multiple other platforms.</p>
<p>Ahead of the big release, at The Game Awards a new trailer has been shared introducing the singer and musician Lenny Kravitz.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>He rose from nothing, broke free, and built his own Kingdom of Aleph.<br>
Introducing Bawma, the largest black-market dealer in the Western Hemisphere who’s as charismatic as he is unpredictable. Brought to life by the one and only Lenny Kravitz.</p>
<p>007 First Light comes to PlayStation®5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch 2, and PC on March 27th, 2026.</p></blockquote><blockquote>
<p>Pre-order now and get a free Deluxe Edition Upgrade.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194787,188416 @ 1765508584 -->
<p>Will you be checking this game out on the Switch 2? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/video-new-007-first-light-trailer-introduces-lenny-kravitz-as-bawma]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saros has a new story trailer for Housemarque’s Returnal successor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/12/saros-has-a-new-story-trailer-for-housemarques-returnal-successor/</link>
            <guid>1381003</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Rahul Kohli introduced a new story trailer for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/saros">Saros</a>, Housemarque’s roguelite shooter successor coming out on 30th April 2026 for PS5.</p>
<p><iframe title="Saros - Pre-Order Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xmsc_GokLPI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>There’s an intriguing element here with, as Arjun Devraj (portrayed by Rahul Kohli), is not alone here. He’s led a team of Soltari Enforcers to this planet, but for some reason they’re now trapped here in a time loop with a dying sun. This is a…. stressful situation and they’re not handling it all too well in the trailer.</p>
<p>From what we’ve seen in previous trailer and reveals, the gameplay structure will be pretty familiar. It’s a roguelike third person shooter, very much in the vein of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/returnal">Returnal</a>, with a permanent progression system wrapped around individual runs that reshape the world and give you new upgrade possibilities to find on the next attempt.</p>
<p>The action looks a bit faster than Returnal, though this may be my imagination, with more sprinting and dashing. Arjun comes with a Soltari Shield that can absorb and reflect projectives, using them to feel the Power Weapon, an Eclipse-driven weapon.</p>

<p>Looking back on Returnal,<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/04/29/returnal-review-ps5/"> our glowing 9/10 review</a> of the PS5 launch window game said, “It feels immensely satisfying to be sat here in 2021, eons after playing Super Stardust HD on PS3, and see just how far Housemarque has come. Offering a visual bullet hell spectacle, a showcase for the DualSense controller and a rewarding sci-fi narrative woven around the roguelike loop, we can say with unflinching confidence that Returnal is the PS5’s best game to date.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/12/saros-has-a-new-story-trailer-for-housemarques-returnal-successor/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lenny Kravitz revealed as Bawma in 007: First Light]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/12/lenny-kravitz-revealed-as-bawma-in-007-first-light/</link>
            <guid>1381000</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>James Bond will be facing a piratical villain in 007: First Light as rock legend Lenny Kravitz steps in the world of video games in his first role. He will play as Bawma, “the largest black-market dealer in the Western Hemisphere who’s as charismatic as he is unpredictable.”</p>
<p><iframe title="007 First Light – Lenny Kravitz Announcement" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hT1kFDUmu_4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>007: First Light is coming out on 27th March 2026&nbsp;across <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PS5</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X|S</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> and PC. The game is an Xbox Play Anywhere title, meaning you can buy it once and play across both Xbox and PC through the Microsoft Store.</p>
<p>The game is IOI’s first outside the Hitman series for quite a while, and as a licensed IP of this scale, it’s a pretty big deal for the studio. The story sees James Bond as a relative newcomer to MI6, working as part of a team as they race to catch and foil the plans of 009, who’s gone just a little bit rogue.</p>
<p>Last time out we saw a mission to intercept 009 at a chess tournament, showcasing the game’s evolved stealth action gameplay, before leading into a high speed car chase and then deadly combat as Bond chases his target to a fleeing cargo plane. Would you believe that the plane doesn’t have a smooth take off and landing?</p>

<p>We had an early preview of the gameplay reveal back at Gamescom and had the opportunity to speak with Franchise Art Director Rasmus Poulsen. Here’s a little tidbit, as we discuss Bond’s visits to Q Lab and whether they’re more Desmond Llewelyn or Ben Wishaw. “We have quite a bit of humour everywhere, but it’s important to mention that it is, first and foremost, a reasonably dry British wit, because otherwise it doesn’t feel quite like it belongs. And, you know, you’ll get to a Q lab and you’ll get to understand how that relationship was formed in that surprising way, I would say, so look forward to that!”</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/03/007-first-light-preview-how-io-are-crafting-a-new-kind-of-bond-game/">Head here for our wider 007: First Light preview</a>, with insights on how they settled on James Bond’s look, brought cars, vehicles and high speed chases in alongside action set pieces and, of course, the more open stealth action style inherited from the Hitman franchise.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hT1kFDUmu_4">YouTube</a></em></p>



<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/12/lenny-kravitz-revealed-as-bawma-in-007-first-light/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis reimagines Lara’s original adventure]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/12/tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis-reimagines-laras-original-adventure/</link>
            <guid>1380997</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Crystal Dynamics and Flying Wild Hog have announced Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis a reimagining and remake of Lara’s original adventure. With <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/11/tomb-raider-catalyst-legacy-of-atlantis/">an original game expected in 2027</a>, Legacy of Atlantis will arrive in 2026.</p>
<p><iframe title="Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n6JxVxSHjqE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The original Tomb Raider has been revisited a good few times over the years. Originally released in 1996, Tomb Raider: Anniversary was released in 2007, a PS3 era remake that came early on in Crystal Dynamics’ tenure as the franchise developer.</p>
<p>Now we’re entering into a new era for Tomb Raider, with Amazon acting as publisher after Crystal Dynamics was sold off by Square Enix a few years ago. A remake tends to be an easy go-to for publishers to greenlight and developers to refind a series’ core and often make a jump to a new game engine – usually Unreal Engine, let’s be honest. It will be interesting to see how faithful and how reimagined this game ends up being.</p>
<p>Want some blurb to pad the word count? Yeah, let’s have that.</p>

<p><em>As Lara Croft, harness your wits and athleticism to explore exotic locations lost to time—from the jungles of Peru to the ancient ruins of Greece, the deserts of Egypt, and a mysterious Mediterranean island shrouded in myth. Traverse treacherous landscapes, solve deadly contraptions, and face lethal predators as you hunt for the scattered pieces of the Scion, an artifact of immeasurable power.</em></p>
<p><em>Whether you’re a veteran raider or new to Lara’s world, Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis delivers jaw-dropping visuals powered by Unreal Engine 5, modern game design, and new surprises, while honoring the spirit and atmosphere of Lara Croft’s debut adventure.</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/12/tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis-reimagines-laras-original-adventure/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New 007 First Light Trailer Showcases Grammy Winner Lenny Kravitz As the Pirate Villain Bawma]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/007-first-light-trailer-showcases-lenny-kravitz-as-latest-bond-villain/</link>
            <guid>1380985</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/io-interactive-spoils-007-first-light-villain-ahead-of-the-game-awards-2025/">After it leaked earlier today</a> from the official 007 First Light account, IO Interactive has now officially announced that Lenny Kravitz is stepping into the role of Bawma, and appears to be the main antagonist that James Bond will face in the plot of 007 First Light.</p>



<p>While fans of Kravitz will know that this is not his first time stepping into a role as an actor, it does appear to be his first time acting in a video game. This makes 007 First Light a new frontier for Kravitz in a couple of ways, since this is also seemingly his first time in the role of a villain.</p>



<p>And not just any villain, but a Bond villain to boot, with his own pet alligators he can use to threaten his enemies, as he appears to do so in the trailer shown at <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-where-to-watch-all-nominations-what-to-expect/">The Game Awards 2025</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="007 First Light – Lenny Kravitz Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/igTh9ud5Liw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The new trailer takes us to a remote location called Aleph, a black market city in Africa built by Lenny Kravitz's pirate character, Bawma. It's unclear if this is where the story of IO Interactive's Bond ends, but it is definitely a stop along the way.</p>



<p>007 First Light is due to arrive on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S <a href="https://wccftech.com/007-first-light-release-date-march-2026-james-bond/">this coming March 27, 2026</a>. For all of our coverage of <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-where-to-watch-all-nominations-what-to-expect/">The Game Awards 2025, check out our hub page here</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/007-first-light-trailer-showcases-lenny-kravitz-as-latest-bond-villain/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lords of the Fallen II Gets First Look at Gameplay in New Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-ii-gets-first-look-at-gameplay-in-new-trailer/</link>
            <guid>1380982</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>2026 is going to be packed with Soulslikes, which is not surprising considering the genre's continued popularity. Joining the likes of <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-is-the-culmination-of-every-team-ninja-action-rpg-hands-on-preview/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Nioh 3</strong></a> and <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/code-vein-ii-set-january-30-2026-debut/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Code Vein</strong></a><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/code-vein-ii-set-january-30-2026-debut/"> II</a></strong> will be Lords of the Fallen II, the third entry in the series which is set out to expand some of the best features of its predecessor, including the dual-world setup that sets it apart from other similar games.</p>



<p>Following its <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-ii-debut-trailer-gamescom-2025/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Gamescom 2025 debut</strong></a> earlier this year, a new look at CI Games' upcoming Soulslike arrived today with a new trailer shown during today's <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-where-to-watch-all-nominations-what-to-expect/"><strong>The Game Awards</strong></a>. <span data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Judging from the new footage,</span> the intensity of the game will be amped up, improving on some of its predecessor's core features, such as the aforementioned dual-world setup, considerably.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Lords of the Fallen II - Gameplay Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7ncv_eS96lw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The new look at Lords of the Fallen II isn't the only news related to the franchise today. The original Lords of the Fallen received its final update, update 2.5, which builds on the improvements introduced in update 2.0 "<em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">by further refining the flow of battle across both Legacy mode (the base experience), and all-new Veteran mode,</em>" both of which sport <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1501750/view/649211284269564005?l=english">more brutal boss battle</a></strong><strong><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1501750/view/649211284269564005?l=english">s</a></strong><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(26, 87, 132, 0.2)" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1501750/view/649211284269564005?l=english"> and more</a></strong>. This extended support for the game is commendable, demonstrating CI Games' commitment to delivering an experience that all Soulslike fans can appreciate.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Lords of the Fallen - VERSION 2.5 (Deadlier Boss Battles, All-New Veteran Mode) | PC, PS5, Xbox X|S" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BUTsB_cuDYA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>If you're planning to get Lords of the Fallen II on PC, you can also check out its <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-ii-pc-requirements/">official system requirements</a></strong> to prepare ahead of yet another year filled with Soulslikes.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-ii-gets-first-look-at-gameplay-in-new-trailer/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight Arrives on PC and Consoles in May 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-release-date-the-game-awards-2025/</link>
            <guid>1380976</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight from developer TT Games got a brand new gameplay trailer and the reveal of its release date at <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-where-to-watch-all-nominations-what-to-expect/">The Game Awards 2025</a>, as it is set to arrive on PC, PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and Nintendo Switch 2 on May 29, 2026.</p>



<p>Initially announced during <a href="https://wccftech.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-tt-games-gamescom-onl-2025/">Gamescom's 2025 ONL Show</a>, Legacy of the Dark Knight was described as the "<em>definitive</em>" Batman story and experience, as it spans across Batman eras with the whimsical tone you'd expect from a LEGO game. </p>



<p>Tonight's gameplay and release date trailer is chock-full of that whimsical tone, and all the humour and gameplay variety that made every LEGO game from TT Games worth checking out for years. This latest entry, however, seems to add new layers of complexity to the gameplay and combat system. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="LEGO® Batman™: Legacy of the Dark Knight - Official Heroes &amp; Villains Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xciD-Vz6T_Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>"<em>With the combat system, our goal has been to offer an experience that is different from previous LEGO and LEGO Batman games, while keeping the trademark LEGO movement and humor fans have come to love and expect</em>," writes TT Games community manager Gehan Amaranayke in a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/12/11/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-out-may-29-2026-on-ps5/">PlayStation Blog post.</a> "<em>As groups of enemies grow larger and better-equipped, even Batman needs help. That’s where the other members of the DC Bat-Family come in</em>."</p>



<p>Amaranayke also points to another old classic aspect of LEGO games updated for Legacy of the Dark Knight. In most LEGO games, you can collect and swap between characters included in whatever franchise the LEGO game you're playing is based on. In Legacy of the Dark Knight, you can play as other Batman characters, though their differing abilities seem to go a little deeper than they do in previous games.</p>



<p><em>"Detective Jim Gordon, Robin, Nightwing, Batgirl, and Catwoman will join Batman throughout the campaign. Each partner has unique gadgets and abilities showcasing their special skills and distinctive personality in combat. You saw Jim Gordon’s foam sprayer in action when we first announced the game at Gamescom in Germany. In this new trailer, you’ll see Robin using his circus training acrobatics, Batgirl with her hackarang to bypass security systems and take remote control of machinery, and Nightwing joins the party in with his battle staff. You’ll also notice Catwoman calling on her feline friends to distract and attack enemies and using her whip and cartwheel kicks to take out the baddies.</em>"</p>



<p>All together, Legacy of the Dark Knight is looking like it has the potential to be the best LEGO game yet, which is a high bar considering more than a few of TT Games' titles are some of the best family oriented 3D action platforming experiences out there, even to this day.</p>



<p>For all of our coverage of <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-where-to-watch-all-nominations-what-to-expect/">The Game Awards 2025, check out our hub page here</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-release-date-the-game-awards-2025/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frictional reveal Soma follow-up Ontos, a lunar nightmare with talking rat walls and Stellan Skarsgård]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frictional-reveal-soma-follow-up-ontos-a-lunar-nightmare-with-talking-rat-walls-and-stellan-skarsgard</link>
            <guid>1380973</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Trading the deep blue for the Sea of Tranquility</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ontos_elyrjiQ.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ontos_elyrjiQ.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ontos_elyrjiQ.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ontos_elyrjiQ.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ontos_elyrjiQ.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ontos_elyrjiQ.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ontos_elyrjiQ.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ontos_elyrjiQ.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ontos_elyrjiQ.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Kepler Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            
<p>
Amnesia developers Frictional have finally done the decent thing and confirmed their <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/soma-devs-frictional-release-video-of-something-new-aka-their-nice-hotel-game-in-which-nothing-awful-will-happen">much-teased</a> follow-up to Soma, the much-beloved/dreaded underwater sci-fi horror game from 2015. Revealed just now at the Geoffrey Awards, the new game is called Ontos, which appears to be the Greek word for "Being". It's set in some kind of creepy lunar mad science resort called Samsara, and it honestly reminds me more of Bioshock at a glance than Soma, even though it's set in outer space. That's partly because it has a noticeably chattier NPC cast. 
</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ONTOS – Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ll4ZPxUzPhc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ONTOS – Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ll4ZPxUzPhc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ll4ZPxUzPhc?autoplay=1" title="ONTOS – Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ll4ZPxUzPhc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
There are a lot of talking heads in that trailer, for a project from the Amnesia devs. Admittedly, some of the talking heads are only half a head. There's also a talking... wall of rats? One of the less ratty, fully jaw-equipped NPCs is voiced by Stellan Skarsgård. It sounds like he wants you to experiment on yourself.
</p>
<p>
Plot? Well, you are Aditi Amani, and you've been invited to the Moon to investigate something your estranged dad did. "What begins as a search for answers quickly spirals into something far stranger," the blurb expounds. "As you delve deeper, guided by fragments of your father's past, you must confront disturbing revelations about the nature of reality- and your place in it.
</p><p>
"Your beliefs will be questioned, and you will be pushed far out of your comfort zone," it continues. "Choose your path and face the consequences." Don't wanna, Frictional! I know your methods. At least one of those paths is bound to be the domain of something I can't kill that makes my vision glitch out.
</p>
<p>
It's out for PC in 2026. There is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2924520/ONTOS/">a Steam page</a>, from which we learn that Ontos "presents a gauntlet of chilling experiments and disturbing encounters that push the boundaries of both science and morality". It sounds like the game is a series of tests, each an existential dilemma "that will make you question the nature of the soul, suffering, and the very fabric of reality itself". 
</p>
<p>
"These trials are not just puzzles--they are provocations," the developers continue. I like you Frictional but I think you need to wind your neck in a little. Less grandly, the page characterises the game as "an immersive narrative with a tactile, systems-driven gameplay experience" in which you'll "scavenge materials, manipulate intricate machinery, and engage with analog systems requiring careful calibration and hands-on interaction".
</p>
<p>
I'm most attracted to the setting, which is "a vast, interconnected labyrinth built atop the ruins of a failed mining colony and an opulent hotel lost to time". It's divided between a bunch of warring philosophical factions, and features theatre stages, caves, casinos and laboratories. Again, definitely getting some Bioshock energy from this. In a promising way.

</p>
</div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frictional-reveal-soma-follow-up-ontos-a-lunar-nightmare-with-talking-rat-walls-and-stellan-skarsgard]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s Our First Look At Tomb Raider’s New Lara Croft]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/heres-our-first-look-at-tomb-raiders-new-lara-croft-2000652781</link>
            <guid>1380961</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Tomb Raider</em> is back in a big way. At the 2025 Game Awards, Amazon Game Studios revealed trailers for not one, but two new, upcoming <em>Tomb Raider</em> games starring Lara Croft.</p> <p>The first game shown off during the awards show was <em>Tomb Raider: Catalyst</em>, a new adventure starring a redesigned Lara Croft that seems to have connections to the past <a href="https://kotaku.com/games/tomb-raider-definitive-survivor-trilogy"><em>Survivor Trilogy</em> version</a>.</p> <p>Here’s the trailer for <em>Catalyst</em>, which arrives sometime in 2027:</p>  <p>After revealing the new <em>Tomb Raider</em> sequel, we also got a trailer for <a href="https://kotaku.com/new-tomb-raider-game-details-leak-and-it-looks-like-a-reboot-2000652612">the previously leaked <em>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</em></a>, a full-on, big-budget remake of the original Tomb Raider game that appears to have connections to the <em>Survivor Trilogy</em> and <em>Catalyst.&nbsp;</em></p>

 <p>Here’s the trailer for <em>Legacy of Atlantis</em>:</p>  <p>We don’t know much about Catalyst, but the remake,<em> Legacy of Atlantis,</em> is being developed in Unreal Engine 5. Here’s how Amazon describes it:</p> <blockquote><p><em>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</em> is a stunning reimagining of the 1996 genre-defining game. As Lara Croft, harness your wits and athleticism to explore exotic locations lost to time—from the jungles of Peru to the ancient ruins of Greece, the deserts of Egypt, and a mysterious Mediterranean island shrouded in myth. Traverse treacherous landscapes, solve deadly contraptions, and face lethal predators as you hunt for the scattered pieces of the Scion, an artifact of immeasurable power.</p></blockquote> <p>In both trailers, it seems like we are getting a more classic Lara, complete with dual pistols, confidence, and that cool move where she lifts herself up slowly while climbing on a ledge. Oh, and dinosaurs are back in <em>Legacy of Atlantis.</em> And now they have feathers. Truly, a modern spin on the classic game.</p> <p><em>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</em> is out in 2026. <em>Catalyst</em> is out in 2027.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/heres-our-first-look-at-tomb-raiders-new-lara-croft-2000652781]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4: Lord of Hatred Expansion Coming April 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-lord-of-hatred-coming-april-2026/</link>
            <guid>1380955</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>During The Game Awards, Blizzard unveiled Diablo 4’s upcoming Lord of Hatred expansion, scheduled to drop on April 28, 2026. The trailer, which was in typical cinematic fashion for a Blizzard reveal, showcased Mephisto, otherwise known as the Lord of Hatred, and it offered a little glimpse at the new Paladin class, a ‘holy knight’ kind of character.</p>



<p>Check out the new Lord of Hatred trailer below.</p>







<h2 id="h-diablo-4-players-are-getting-two-new-classes">Diablo 4 Players Are Getting Two New Classes</h2>



<p>The next major expansion for Diablo 4 is dubbed Lord of Hatred, and it’s centered around Mephisto, one of the universe’s most terrifying and capable entities.</p>



<p>Blizzard revealed that the Paladin class is coming to Diablo 4 <strong>now</strong>, but it’s available exclusively to those who pre-order the new Lords of Hatred expansion. In the trailer content, a second new class was teased, but we don’t yet know what that will look like.</p>



<p>In the subsequent information divulged from Lord of Hatred, it was confirmed that massive gameplay updates are incoming, including an overhaul to endgame systems, a level cap increase, and the return of the Horadric Cube.</p>



<p>Here’s the new trailer for Lord of Hatred:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Diablo 4: Lord of Hatred | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JHd495UuMRs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>It was later reported that the new expansion, Lord of Hatred, will introduce <strong>fishing</strong> as a side activity. It’s not clear why you’d want to consume the fish found across the Diablo universe, but perhaps they serve another purpose.</p>







<p>Do you think you’ll be investing in Lord of Hatred? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tomb-raider-remake-legacy-of-atlantis-reveal-the-game-awards-2025/">new Tomb Raider game has been revealed at The Game Awards</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-lord-of-hatred-coming-april-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadpool Is Coming To Marvel Rivals In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/deadpool-is-coming-to-marvel-rivals-in-2026/</link>
            <guid>1380952</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-164002">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Marvel Rivals already has a roster that can rival any hero game in existence. So, it makes sense to throw in the foul-mouthed and hilarious Deadpool for good measure in 2026.</p>



<p>Deadpool might be one of the most popular Marvel heroes ever. Let’s be clear, this was BEFORE Ryan Reynolds elevated the character to new, bloody heights. At The Game Awards 2025, Deadpool made his mark and will make his mark in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-confirmed-to-feature-at-the-game-awards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel Rivals</a>.</p>







<h2 id="h-marvel-rivals-adding-deadpool-in-2026">Marvel Rivals Adding Deadpool In 2026</h2>



<p>Marvel Rivals Season 6: Night at the Museum starts on January 16, and Deadpool will be a headline attraction.</p>







<p>The wonderful Wade Wilson arrives in the legendary Deadpool get-up, and it’s going to be fascinating how much NetEase can keep a lid on the silly, sarcastic, and sharp (in more ways than one) assassin.</p>



<p>Check out the complete Deadpool reveal trailer below, first shown during <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Game Awards 2025</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Marvel Rivals | Deadpool Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9clsvx_PGCQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Head to the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server</a> to express how happy you are that the red assassin is zooming into Marvel RIvals next year.  Who should have the impossible job of following Wade into Marvel RIvals next? Share your wishlist.</p>



<hr>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tomb-raider-remake-legacy-of-atlantis-reveal-the-game-awards-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tomb-raider-remake-legacy-of-atlantis-reveal-the-game-awards-2025/">
                                New Tomb Raider Remake Revealed at The Game Awards                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A full-fledged remake of the 1996 classic, Tomb: Raider: Legacy of Atlantis, has been revealed at The Game Awards 2025.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-tomb-raider-catalyst-reveal-the-game-awards-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-tomb-raider-catalyst-reveal-the-game-awards-2025/">
                                Tomb Raider: Catalyst Officially Announced at The Game Awards                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Crystal Dynamics and Amazon have revealed Tomb Raider: Catalyst, a new entry in the franchise, at The Game Awards 2025.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-release-date-announced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-release-date-announced/">
                                LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight Release Date Announced                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight’s release date was revealed at The Game Awards 2025. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/control-resonant-confirmed-the-game-awards-remedy/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/control-resonant-confirmed-the-game-awards-remedy/">
                                Control: Resonant Officially Confirmed at The Game Awards                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The next entry in the Control series, Control Resonant, has been revealed at The Game Awards and releasing in 2026.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/deadpool-is-coming-to-marvel-rivals-in-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom Finally Confirms Leon S. Kennedy Is In Resident Evil Requiem | The Game Awards 2025 - IGN]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-finally-confirms-leon-s-kennedy-is-in-resident-evil-requiem-the-game-awards-2025-ign</link>
            <guid>1380949</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">After months of speculation and a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/confirmed-leon-s-kennedy-is-in-resident-evil-requiem-playstation-store-leak-reveals">revealing leak earlier this week</a>, Capcom has finally, officially confirmed what we all knew: Leon S. Kennedy is in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a>, and he's here to kick butt.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tonight, at The Game Awards 2025, a fresh trailer for Resident Evil Requiem saw Leon fully revealed, swinging into action as the now-grizzled veteran zombie fighter we all know and love. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We learned what many of us had expected, that Leon will feature as one of two playable characters, alongside the previously announced Grace Ashcroft. While Grace's campaign focuses on survival horror, Leon's separate antics will focus on action. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/12/resident-evil-requiem-world-premiere-trailer-from-the-game-awards-2025-00-02-46-1765504545021.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this week, the reveal of new Resident Evil: Requiem cover art featuring Leon finally put to bed one of this year's biggest gaming mysteries — something developer Capcom has itself refused to address — just days ahead of Requiem's appearance tonight. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rumors have persisted for months over Leon's involvement in Resident Evil: Requiem, with Capcom <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-big-resident-evil-requiem-interview-why-the-games-monster-got-supersized-why-its-probably-not-lisa-trevor-and-a-tease-for-areas-beyond-raccoon-city-just-dont-talk-about-leon">specifically declining to answer IGN's questions over the character</a> back at Gamescom in August. The game's developers have even suggested that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-says-leon-s-kennedy-is-a-bad-match-for-horror-as-fan-speculation-swirls-around-whether-hes-still-secretly-playable-in-resident-evil-requiem">Leon would be a poor fit as a protagonist for the game's quieter sections</a> as he is now too grizzled to be scared. But through all of this, Capcom left itself with just enough wiggle room for Leon to still be lurking somewhere — presumably during Requiem's more action-packed sequences.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite Leon's involvement now being confirmed, Requiem may still have secrets left in store. There was no mention tonight of a potential third playable character — something raised earlier this week by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-gamestop-listing-leaves-fans-bewildered-by-mentioning-a-shock-second-character-and-its-not-leon">a GameStop listing that referenced Rosemary Winters</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced">everything announced at The Game Awards 2025</a> for more, as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-winners-the-full-list">the winners list in full</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-finally-confirms-leon-s-kennedy-is-in-resident-evil-requiem-the-game-awards-2025-ign]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witness and Braid Creator Jonathan Blow Announces New 250-Hour Puzzle Game, Order of the Sinking Star | The Game Awards 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witness-and-braid-creator-jonathan-blow-announces-new-250-hour-puzzle-game-order-of-the-sinking-star-the-game-awards-2025</link>
            <guid>1380943</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Its 1,000-plus puzzles have been 10 years in the making.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Puzzle games have changed a lot since The Witness hit in 2016, which showed us new ways of interpreting game environments and <em>connecting the dots</em>. And even in 2025 we had the likes of Blue Prince shake up our understanding with the twist of a roguelike deckbuilding puzzler. In the years since, the lead designer of Braid and The Witness, Jonathan Blow, had been working on a new project with a bigger team than his previous games — it’s called Order of the Sinking Star, which was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-winners-the-full-list">revealed at The Game Awards 2025</a>. It’s an ambitious project on paper — Blow said to have 1,000 individual puzzles and can take up to 250 hours to complete at a normal pace (and upwards 500 hours for completionists), but it’s the way it layers its gameplay mechanics as you get deeper into the game that’s the more impressive part.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I recently saw an off-hands demo of Order of the Sinking Star, which is a grid-based isometric adventure with a branching overworld that encompasses a large majority of its individual puzzles. Blow showcased a number of these puzzles in real time; it started out with simple block-pushing mazes that worked as a brief tutorial for how different characters interact with obstacles — such as the thief who can only pull objects and the wizard who must swap places with objects in line-of-sight. However, later levels began to stack more variables that add complexity to the objective of simply going from point A to point B. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Order of the Sinking Star - Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Mirrors that teleport you (or objects) across gaps equal to your distance from the mirror itself, or hostile creatures that will kill you if you move to an adjacent block on the grid, or beams that can phase you through walls; these are a few of the things I saw in action. Each puzzle teaches you how these mechanics work by introducing them in a basic challenge without explaining them outright and gets increasingly difficult as you progress — fairly standard stuff. Like Braid, you also have a rewind tool to move back as many steps as you want, which makes it easier to experiment with a puzzle’s variables instead of constantly having to restart a puzzle from the beginning. But it’s when these mechanics are used in multiple combinations that test your understanding of them and build on that knowledge when you have to consider your moves several steps ahead. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">When mixing in the specific ways in which each character interacts with objects on the grid, you’ll have many more layers to consider as puzzles expand in size and complexity. I saw one room in the overworld that asked you to jump through gates on the grid to switch characters and tee up the obstacles for each of them — since the wizard <em>must </em>swap spots with blocks across from him, he’ll get stuck behind a block locked behind a gate so you have to find a way to pull a new block from across the grid to make sure the wizard get in the right position to when he has to teleport. Another twist I saw was having a character replicate themselves by phasing through multiple mirrors at once, making you control clones simultaneous, which leads to interesting solutions for certain puzzles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Zooming out to a bird’s eye view of the overworld showed just how expansive Order of the Sinking Star will be — and in a way that felt overwhelming. You start exploring the puzzles available in any of the cardinal directions, letting you go as far as you want in one direction and leaving open the option to go in a different one in case you get stuck. The overworld itself has puzzles that unlock new sections of the map as a way of progression, creating additional layers to the puzzle-solving  And perhaps you’ll have a eureka moment in the process that will shine a light on previous puzzles to make more of these pieces make sense. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The thing I’m hesitant about is its overwhelming nature being intimidating that it becomes daunting to engage with. And retaining the knowledge that you’ve built up for subsequent puzzles may just get lost over time if you take an extended break from playing. From what I’ve seen, even tracking what you did and didn’t complete in the overworld might get tough even though the map does have glints to highlight key locations to visit and explore.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I asked Blow about how he and the team have thought about guiding the player and balancing a general hands-off approach. He said they’re considering implementing a hint system or a limited-use mechanic to nudge players in the right direction, but it’s tricky since he doesn’t want it to become a crutch. He went on to mention that the environmental design of puzzle rooms can be instructive as well and intends to contain visual cues for what’s important to look at as you find solutions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There also seems to be an underlying story with each series of puzzles where different sections of the overworld put you in control of characters from various timelines in the game’s lore. And the ways these timelines intersect and showcase cooperation between various civilizations might have something to say about what happened to their world and perhaps have a broader message about human cooperation. So far, it feels similar to The Witness where very little is told to you and the mystery slowly unravels, but this time you have distinct characters with voice lines who will interact with each other in small ways as they cross paths throughout the game’s puzzles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Order of the Sinking Star is also meant to showcase the proprietary game engine and programming language that Blow has been working on in tandem, and intends for it to be available as an open-source tool shortly after the game’s release. As far as release date, all we know for now is that Order of the Sinking Star is set to launch sometime in 2026 on PC and other platforms at a later date.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced">everything announced at The Game Awards 2025</a> for more, as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-winners-the-full-list">the winners list in full</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael is the tech reviews editor at IGN, but regularly contributes to games coverage with reviews, features, and news. </em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witness-and-braid-creator-jonathan-blow-announces-new-250-hour-puzzle-game-order-of-the-sinking-star-the-game-awards-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4:Loop Revealed as PlayStation's New Sci-Fi Co-Op Shooter from Bad Robot and Left 4 Dead Designer | The Game Awards 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/4loop-revealed-as-playstations-new-sci-fi-co-op-shooter-from-bad-robot-and-left-4-dead-designer-the-game-awards-2025</link>
            <guid>1380940</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">J.J. Abrams and Left 4 Dead creator Mike Booth took to The Game Awards 2025 to announce that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-announces-partnership-with-jj-abrams-bad-robot-games-to-publish-4-player-co-op-shooter-from-valves-former-left-4-dead-designer">their mysterious new co-op video game</a> is a sci-fi third-person shooter called 4:Loop.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A video for Bad Robot Games' PlayStation 5 and PC project was unveiled during today’s show, revealing a twisted new version of Earth filled with deadly creatures (and a lot of purple lights). The first 4:Loop trailer teases gameplay that requires players to form a world-saving team that will live and die by how it learns from its failures.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">For all of tonight’s biggest highlights, you can check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced"><u>everything announced</u></a> at The Game Awards 2025. You can also keep up with our running list of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-winners-the-full-list"><u>all of the winners</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Developing…</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/4loop-revealed-as-playstations-new-sci-fi-co-op-shooter-from-bad-robot-and-left-4-dead-designer-the-game-awards-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic Announced From Former KOTOR and Mass Effect Director Casey Hudson | The Game Awards 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-announced-from-former-kotor-and-mass-effect-director-casey-hudson-the-game-awards-2025</link>
            <guid>1380934</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Game Awards 2025 kicked off with a huge announcement: Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic is led by Casey Hudson, former director of the much-loved Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic and the Mass Effect trilogy. The development studio is Edmonton, Alberta-based Arcanaut Studios.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's described as a narrative-driven, single-player RPG and spiritual successor to Knights of the Old Republic. Lucasfilm insisted Fate of the Old Republic is not a direct sequel or continuation of KOTOR, and will introduce new characters for an all-new story. It's said to be in the early stages of development. The teaser trailer is below.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's the official blurb:</p><blockquote>Players step into the role of a Force user in a galaxy on the edge of rebirth. Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic will blend innovative storytelling, memorable characters, and heart-pounding combat for an unforgettable experience where every decision deepens the player’s journey toward light or darkness.</blockquote><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“Working on Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic was one of the defining experiences of my career,” Hudson said. “With Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic, we’re telling a completely new and different story with everything we’ve learned since - crafting an adventure about choice, destiny, and the timeless struggle between light and dark. It’s a dream come true to once again collaborate with Lucasfilm Games.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We look for partners who have the drive and the leadership to build something groundbreaking, and that’s what we see in Casey,” said Jay Ong, President of Disney Games Group. “Under Casey’s direction, Arcanaut Studios is assembling a team with a deep passion for storytelling and building immersive worlds. Their vision for Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic is exactly the kind of ambitious, high-quality experience we want to deliver for our players.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The Old Republic era is a rich and beloved part of the Star Wars™ galaxy, and we are thrilled to be exploring a fresh story that we’ve never seen before in Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic,” added Douglas Reilly, VP and GM of Lucasfilm Games. “Arcanaut Studios shares our enthusiasm for the galaxy far, far away, and their plan for this new narrative is inspiring. We believe fans will be delighted by the journey that awaits them, and we can't wait to share more."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Star Wars Fate of the Old Republic Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic is in early development for PC and consoles. Be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced">everything announced at The Game Awards 2025</a> for more, as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-winners-the-full-list">the winners list in full</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-announced-from-former-kotor-and-mass-effect-director-casey-hudson-the-game-awards-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neon Giant announces cyber-noire first-person shooter NO LAW for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/neon-giant-announces-cyber-noire-first-person-shooter-no-law-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>1380931</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>From the studio behind The Ascent.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > KRAFTON [75 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/krafton">KRAFTON</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Neon Giant [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neon-giant">Neon Giant</a> have announced first-person, story rich, cyber-noire <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,355 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > NO LAW" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/no-law">NO LAW</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,032 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,438 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,060 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2161710/NO_LAW/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/no-law-9877c5" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/no-law/9pl82pd1pqxh" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>). A release date was not announced. <span id="more-1010787"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via KRAFTON:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>NO LAW</em> is a first-person, story rich, cyber-noire shooter set in a decadent port city built on neon sleaze instead of regulations. Explore its rich history and meet the veiled hearts of the city as you take back what was wrongfully taken from you.</p></blockquote><!-- zp_shiv error: no images in gallery! --><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Rich Story</strong> – In <em>NO LAW</em> you get to take on the role of Grey Harker, a seasoned veteran of both the battlefield and the city of Port Desire. After receiving near-fatal injuries on his last deployment, Harker decides to finally turn his back on the military life and instead set his sights on a life of peace, once and for all. However, while he no longer goes looking for trouble, one fateful day, trouble finds its way to his front door.</li><li><strong>Impactful Gameplay</strong> – Even in a city of no laws, <a title="Genres > Action [3,278 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s still have consequences. Throughout your journey as Harker, you will come across plenty of colorful characters – friends and foes alike. Whether you decide to help a friend in need or flatline some mouth-breathing alley rat, your choices will leave a mark. Play through multiple times to uncover alternate paths and new outcomes.</li><li><strong>Explore Port Desire</strong> – Nestled against a cliff overlooking the sea is Port Desire, an industrial cybergrunge city lush with greenery and overflowing with personalities. A hub for import and export, where people from all walks of life flock to experience their wildest dreams. In this port nothing is off-limits and the city is your playground for tactical <a title="Genres > Stealth [106 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a> or hard-hitting <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,843 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">FPS</a> action. Leave your morals at the bordergate and explore this vertical wonder from the rooftops that scrape the smog to the alleys that choke on it. But be careful where you step. In a city of no laws, many take it into their own hands.</li><li><strong>Play Your Way</strong> – <a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter the tools, learn the systems, and turn every mission into your own story. Will you utilize Grey’s tactical background and stick to the shadows, or will you let him give in to his unbridled rage and go in guns blazing? Whether you prefer the tactical route or revel in the destruction left in your wake, make sure you take the time to explore the variety of military upgrades available to you. Outsmart enemies with sci-fi devices, vertical movement, or full-frontal chaos.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/no-law/december-11-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="NO LAW | The Official Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uD6kFXZlX00?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/neon-giant-announces-cyber-noire-first-person-shooter-no-law-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin – The Game Awards 2025 trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/the-seven-deadly-sins-origin-the-game-awards-2025-trailer</link>
            <guid>1380928</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out on January 28, 2026.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Netmarble [50 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netmarble">Netmarble</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Netmarble F&amp;C [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netmarble/netmarble-fc">Netmarble F&amp;C</a> have released a new trailer for <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [486 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> <a title="Genres > Open-World [791 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,889 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-seven-deadly-sins-origin">The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin</a></em> as part of The Game Awards 2025. <span id="more-1012656"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the trailer, via Netmarble:</p><blockquote><p>The trailer captivated global audiences with high-resolution graphics powered by Unreal Engine 5 and immersive cinematic storytelling. Highlighting the game’s multiverse narrative, it featured characters like Meliodas and Tristan flying over Britannia on pets, showcasing the game’s expansive open-world experience.</p><p>It also revealed real-time cooperative raid battles, where players team up to defeat powerful bosses, underscoring the game’s core feature as a multiplayer-driven open-world RPG. The gameplay focused not only on exploration but also on teamwork and shared challenges. In addition, a key moment hinted at Escanor’s possible return through the multiverse, further building anticipation for fans.</p></blockquote><p><em>The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,032 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [25,060 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3679080/The_Seven_Deadly_Sins_Origin/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, iOS, and Android on January 28, 2026.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="[7DS Origin] 2025 The Game Awards Trailer | The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uRhdSmU0kyw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『七つの大罪：Origin』2025 The Game Awards 映像" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8H4s183NYSo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe title="[일곱 개의 대죄: Origin] 2025 The Game Awards 출품 영상" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cZBRf_CjTew?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/the-seven-deadly-sins-origin-the-game-awards-2025-trailer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomb Raider remake Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/tomb-raider-remake-tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>1380922</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A remake of the 1996-released Tomb Raider.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Amazon Games [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/amazon-games">Amazon Games</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Crystal Dynamics [154 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cde-entertainment/crystal-dynamics">Crystal Dynamics</a> and <a title="Companies > Flying Wild Hog [39 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/plaion/flying-wild-hog">Flying Wild Hog</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis">Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</a></em>, a remake of the 1996-released <em>Tomb Raider</em>, for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,032 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,438 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,060 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3558670/Tomb_Raider_Legacy_of_Atlantis/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch in 2026. <span id="more-1013526"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Amazon Games:</p><blockquote><p>Experience the pinnacle of adventure with Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis, a stunning reimagining of the 1996 genre-defining game.</p><p>As Lara Croft, harness your wits and athleticism to explore exotic locations lost to time—from the jungles of Peru to the ancient ruins of Greece, the deserts of Egypt, and a mysterious Mediterranean island shrouded in myth. Traverse treacherous landscapes, solve deadly contraptions, and face lethal predators as you hunt for the scattered pieces of the Scion, an artifact of immeasurable power.</p><p>Whether you’re a veteran raider or new to Lara’s world, Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis delivers jaw-dropping visuals powered by Unreal Engine 5, modern game design, and new surprises, while honoring the spirit and atmosphere of Lara Croft’s debut adventure.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis/december-11-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n6JxVxSHjqE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><!-- zp_shiv error: no images in gallery! --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/tomb-raider-remake-tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomb Raider: Catalyst announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/tomb-raider-catalyst-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>1380919</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in 2027.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Amazon Games [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/amazon-games">Amazon Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Crystal Dynamics [154 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cde-entertainment/crystal-dynamics">Crystal Dynamics</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Tomb Raider: Catalyst [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tomb-raider-catalyst">Tomb Raider: Catalyst</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,032 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,438 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,060 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (Steam). It will launch in 2027. <span id="more-1012645"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Amazon Games:</p><blockquote><p>Set in the wake of a mythical cataclysm that has unleashed ancient secrets and awakened mysterious guardian forces, <em>Tomb Raider: Catalyst</em> follows Lara Croft on a new adventure across Northern India.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/tomb-raider-catalyst/december-11-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Tomb Raider: Catalyst Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N2yLZQFPSLo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><!-- zp_shiv error: no images in gallery! --></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/tomb-raider-catalyst-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jonathan Blow has spent the past decade designing 1,400 puzzles for you]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/12/jonathan-blow-has-spent-the-past-decade-designing-1400-puzzles-for-you/</link>
            <guid>1380913</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<p>For many independent developers, of course, spending nine years on a single game idea is an unthinkable luxury. Financial constraints mean many game ideas have to be shipped “as soon as you get to the point where it’s fun and shippable,” Blow said, leading to games that “kind of converge to a certain level of complexity and then stop there.”</p>
<p>But thanks to the sales success of <em>The Witness</em>—which reportedly <a href="http://the-witness.net/news/2016/02/fun-sales-fakts/">grossed over $5 million in just its first week</a>—Blow said he and his team have had the freedom to spend years “generat[ing] this giant space that’s much more complex than where you go with a typical puzzle game… When we create that much possibility, we feel like we have to explore it. Otherwise we’re not doing our duty as designers and correctly pursuing this agenda of design research.”</p>
<figure>
    <div>
            <p>
              The sales success of&nbsp;<em>The Witness</em> helped enable the&nbsp;extended development time for <em>Order of the Sinking Star.</em>
                          </p>
          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      The sales success of&nbsp;<em>The Witness</em> helped enable the&nbsp;extended development time for <em>Order of the Sinking Star.</em>

          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Blow also said the size of this project helped get him past his general distaste for playtesting, which he said he was “not that big on” for his previous games. “Even <em>The Witness</em> didn’t have that much play testing, because I always felt like that was a way to make games a little more generic or something, you know? Like playtesters have complaints and then you file down the complaints and then you get a generic game.”</p>
<p>After being immersed in <em>Order of the Sinking Star</em> development for so long, though, Blow said he realized it was important to get a fresh perspective from playtesters who had no experience with the idea. “We have to playtest it because it doesn’t fit in my brain all at once, you know?” he said.</p>
<figure><p><iframe allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gI886DV0FJA?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent"></iframe></p></figure>
<p>Some might say a nine-plus-year development cycle might be a sign of perfectionist tinkering past the point of diminishing returns. But Blow said that while he “might have been a perfectionist” in his younger days, the difficult process of game development has beaten the tendency out of him. “But I have the remnants of perfectionism,” he said. “I have… wanting to do something really good.”</p>
<p>And eventually, even an idea you’ve been tinkering with for roughly a decade needs to see the light of day. “Even for us, this was very expensive,” Blow admitted. “Man, I’ll be happy to get it out and have a new game making some money, because we need to make that happen at this point.”</p>


          
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/12/jonathan-blow-has-spent-the-past-decade-designing-1400-puzzles-for-you/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard Announces Next Diablo 4 Expansion, Two New Classes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-announces-next-diablo-4-expansion-two-new-classes/1100-6536900/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1380907</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536900">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The end of Diablo 4's Age of Hatred saga is nigh. Blizzard has officially announced the game's second expansion, Lord of Hatred, is coming April 28, 2026. The expansion marks the end of Diablo 4's ongoing story, culminating in an epic battle against the MMO-ARPG's biggest antagonist: Mephisto.</p><p>Revealed as part of 2025's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-game-awards-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-7341/" data-ref-id="2900-7341">The Game Awards</a>, Lord of Hatred sees players team up with an unlikely ally in an attempt to put an end to the Lord of Hatred's uprising. The expansion takes players to the fabled isles of Skovos, a region that was meant to appear in Diablo 3 before ultimately being cut, and serves as the former home of both Lilith and Inarius. In addition to finally taking us to these long-anticipated islands, Lord of Hatred also brings with it two new classes. While Blizzard has yet to reveal what one of these classes might be, they studio confirmed the fan-favorite Paladin is finally making their return.</p><p>"The Paladin rises as the realm darkens, wielding hammer, shield, and Holy Light to smite Mephisto’s demon army with righteous fury," Blizzard wrote in its press release. "Through melee combat and divine abilities, the Paladin empowers players to strike with both unwavering faith and overwhelming force."</p><p>Other changes to Diablo 4 coming with the next expansion include: reworked skill trees for all eight classes, a new loot filter, enhanced crafting systems, the return of the Horadric Cube, and an overhauled endgame "built around player choice, mastery, escalating challenge, and ever-more rewarding loot."</p><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621493-paladin_zealot.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621494-paladin_judicator.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621495-paladin_disciple.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621496-paladin_juggernaut.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621497-dia_x2_basiliskmount_paladin_005.png" data-ref-id="1300-4621493,1300-4621494,1300-4621495,1300-4621496,1300-4621497" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4621493-paladin_zealot.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4621494-paladin_judicator.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4621495-paladin_disciple.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4621496-paladin_juggernaut.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1639/16394322/4621497-dia_x2_basiliskmount_paladin_005.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621493-paladin_zealot.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621494-paladin_judicator.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621495-paladin_disciple.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621496-paladin_juggernaut.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4621497-dia_x2_basiliskmount_paladin_005.png"></figure>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-announces-next-diablo-4-expansion-two-new-classes/1100-6536900/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomb Raider: Catalyst Revealed Alongside Original Tomb Raider Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tomb-raider-catalyst-revealed-alongside-original-tomb-raider-remake/1100-6536853/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1380901</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536853">

            
            
    


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Tomb Raider franchise is one of the most prolific and longest-running in all of gaming, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-game-awards-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-7341/" data-ref-id="2900-7341">we got a tease</a> of what's next for Lara Croft during <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2025-winners-nominees/2900-7258/#1" data-ref-id="2900-7258">The Game Awards</a> on December 11. Surprisingly, there isn't just one game in production, but two. The new entry in the franchise is Tomb Raider: Catalyst, coming in 2027, while a total remake of the first title in the series arrives next year with Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis.</p><p>Lara Croft's "Survivor" trilogy wrapped up in 2018 with Shadow of the Tomb Raider, but fans have seen enough iterations of the hero to know this wasn't the end for Tomb Raider. Alongside a new game, the franchise is also coming to Prime Video with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tomb-raider-tv-series-finds-another-actor-joining-sophie-turners-lara-croft/1100-6536605/">Sophie Turner starring as Croft</a>. Previously, the character has been played in live-action by Angelina Jolie and Alicia Vikander.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N2yLZQFPSLo" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/N2yLZQFPSLo" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Tomb Raider: Catalyst sees Lara heading to Northern India, where a mythical cataclysm has taken place. This draws the attention of all sorts of treasure hunters, and Lara must figure out who's friend and foe. Developer Crystal Dynamics is behind the all-new entry in the franchise, which is planned for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis reimagines the original 1996 Tomb Raider. Crystal Dynamics is teaming up with Flying Wild Hog for the remake, which will utilize Unreal Engine 5 just like Tomb Raider: Catalyst. Similarly, Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis is set to come to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p dir="ltr">Both games will see actress Alix Wilton Regan portray Lara. She's previously provided performances for Cyberpunk 2077 and Mass Effect 3.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n6JxVxSHjqE" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/n6JxVxSHjqE" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tomb-raider-catalyst-revealed-alongside-original-tomb-raider-remake/1100-6536853/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Street Fighter Movie Cast Revives Mortal Kombat Rivalry For No Real Reason]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/street-fighter-movie-cast-revives-mortal-kombat-rivalry-for-no-real-reason/1100-6536913/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1380895</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536913">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Like any awards show, there's bound to be a moment or two that leaves you perplexed about what's going on. The Game Awards had one such moment just like this, and it came during the reveal trailer for the upcoming Street Fighter film, which was quite chaotic and loud.</p><p>Moments after Geoff Keighley introduced the Street Fighter trailer, the film's main cast took to the stage. Andrew Koji (Ryu), Andrew Schulz (Dan Hibiki), Callina Liang (Chun-Li), Cody Rhodes (Guile), David Dastmalchian (M. Bison), Jason Momoa (Blanka), Mel Jarnson (Cammy), Noah Centineo (Ken Masters), Olivier Richters (Zangief), Orville Peck (Vega), Rayna Vallandingham (Juli), Roman Reigns (Akuma), and Vidyut Jammwal (Dhalsim) all took the stage to yap about ... nothing much, really.</p><p>That's not entirely true, sort of. Liang confirmed that the cast wrapped up filming Street Fighter "a few weeks ago." Momoa--with a slight sway and a slight slur--cheekily argued with Koji over the pronunciation of "Ryu." Koji said the cast was there to present the Best Ongoing Game Award (which Hello Games' <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/no-mans-sky/" data-ref-id="5000-221687">No Man's Sky</a> won). Schulz really sought applause by asking the audience to "make some noise" if they ever played the game in their life. Schulz, for some reason, then reignited the longstanding rivalry between Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter by inviting "the whole cast of Mortal Kombat 2" onto the stage (which didn't happen).</p><p>After that, there was a brief moment of cheers and screams as the Street Fighter cast talked over each other. Wait, weren't they supposed to present the award for Best Ongoing Game? They remembered at the last minute when Koji refocused the uncoordinated cast. Centineo made a confused remark about "the mic not coming out of the floor" before announcing the award's winner. Hello Games took the stage, accepted the award, gave a speech, and walked off--everyone included.</p><p>After about five minutes of chaos and rambunctiousness, the moment ended, and the show continued as normal. It was odd, but nothing too out of the ordinary. If you remember a few years ago, the "Bill Clinton kid"--Matan Even--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/random-kid-arrested-after-appearing-on-stage-at-the-game-awards/1100-6509914/" data-ref-id="1100-6509914">snuck onto the stage before LAPD detained him</a>. While this ain't that, this is certainly just as confusing and just as weird as that moment back in December 2022.</p><p>We have a<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-game-awards-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-7341/#1" data-ref-id="2900-7341"> collection of the biggest announcements</a> from the livestream. There's a lot to dig through, so be sure to bookmark the post to keep up with the reveals and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2025-winners-nominees/2900-7258/" data-ref-id="2900-7258">awards</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/street-fighter-movie-cast-revives-mortal-kombat-rivalry-for-no-real-reason/1100-6536913/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadpool Is Coming To Marvel Rivals]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/the-game-awards-2025/2025/12/11/deadpool-is-coming-to-marvel-rivals</link>
            <guid>1380889</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text" typeof="schema:Article"><p>The Marvel shooter is getting the Merc with a Mouth, and I bet he knows he is in the popular video game. The trailer proves that he at least knows he was in three movies.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Aj53c2Uxrtc"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Aj53c2Uxrtc" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>The Game Awards trailer announcing his arrival does not show gameplay or explain how he will work in the game, but it does showcase some fun and impressive 2D animation. It also teases another new character, Elsa Bloodstone.</p>



<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="dc2a1756-da84-4862-a6b1-753f3e730241" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="image:responsive_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;responsive_image_style&quot;:&quot;content_body&quot;,&quot;image_loading&quot;:{&quot;attribute&quot;:&quot;lazy&quot;},&quot;image_link&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
          <picture>
                  <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/body_default/public/2025/12/11/612e683c/rivals02.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 851px)" type="image/webp" width="800" height="450">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/12/11/612e683c/rivals02.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 315px) and (max-width: 450px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/12/11/612e683c/rivals02.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (max-width: 314px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
                  

  </picture>


  
  
  
</article>

<p>Deadpool will be part of season 6, Night at Museum, which begins January 16.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/the-game-awards-2025/2025/12/11/deadpool-is-coming-to-marvel-rivals]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>