<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:46:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft I and II get a new remaster that’s available now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295730/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest-1-2-3-reforged-upgrades-windows-mac-blizzard-battle-net</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-i-and-ii-get-a-new-remaster-that%E2%80%99s-available-now.1035132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295730/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest-1-2-3-reforged-upgrades-windows-mac-blizzard-battle-net<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Blizzard just released <em>Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest </em>for PC and Macs<em>, </em>which collects remasters of realtime strategy classics <em>Warcraft I and II, </em>as well as a 2.0 update for <em>Warcraft III: Reforged. </em>The company announced the collection, which is <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest">$39.99 on Battle.net</a>, during today’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0rEfOTxr59o">Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct livestream</a>.</p><p>The first two games have been updated much the same way that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/26/15064910/blizzard-remastering-starcraft-4k-resolution-gaming"><em>Starcraft</em> was in 2017</a>, replacing the original game sprites and maps with more detailed, high-res artwork. Both games also have “updated quality of life features for modern day gaming,” according to the Battle.net store page for the collection. </p><div tabindex="0" aria-label="Zoom" role="button"><p>1<!-- -->/<!-- -->5</p><div><figcaption>Warcraft II: Remastered.</figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Blizzard</cite></p></div></div><p><em>Warcraft III: Reforged </em>2.0<em> </em>looks like the company’s attempt to make up for the <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/warcraft-iii-reforged/">widely-panned</a> 2020 remaster, <em>Warcraft III: Reforged,</em> a game that was so hated that the company started offering a <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/blizzard-is-offering-refunds-upon-request-for-warcraft-3-reforged/">no-questions-asked automated refund policy</a><em>. </em>Blizzard says it has updated environments and “fully customizable visuals,” as well as an option to play with the game’s original graphics at a higher resolution. </p><div><p>If you don’t want all three, you can get them individually. Blizzard charges $9.99 for <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-1-remastered?p=1849794"><em>Warcraft I: Remastered</em></a><em>, </em>$14.99 for <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-2-remastered?p=1849795"><em>Warcraft II: Remastered</em></a>, and $29.99 for <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-3-reforged?p=44414"><em>Warcraft III: Reforged</em></a><em>.</em></p></div><p>In addition to the remasters, Blizzard also announced a January 2025 Hearthstone / StarCraft crossover called “Heroes of StarCraft”<em> </em>centered around <em>StarCraft. </em>(It’s no new <em>StarCraft </em>game, but at least Blizzard mentioned the series, I suppose). Blizzard is also updating <em>World Of Warcraft</em>, adding things like a new dungeon to the modern version, and a version of Mists of Pandaria for <em>WoW</em> Classic that resembles the expansion as it was in 2012. And <em>Warcraft Rumble</em> will launch in beta on PC on December 10th.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Of Warcraft Is Finally Getting Player Homes After 20 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/wow-world-of-warcraft-player-housing-homes-blizzard-mmo-1851697796</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-warcraft-is-finally-getting-player-homes-after-20-years.1035123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/wow-world-of-warcraft-player-housing-homes-blizzard-mmo-1851697796<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Blizzard has announced that two decades after its release, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/wow-war-within-review-expansion-is-it-good-1851643832&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/wow-war-within-review-expansion-is-it-good-1851643832"><em>World of Warcraft</em></a></span> is finally going to let players build a home and live in it. The feature has long been requested by <em>WoW</em> players and now it’s finally coming in the game’s next expansion.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195326" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="326" data-playlist="195326,195150,194907" data-current="195326"><div><p>Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20784.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Player housing is a big part of many other popular MMORPGs, like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/my-elder-scrolls-online-apartment-is-very-sad-and-crapp-1846793042?_gl=1*1qyn08u*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUyMTM4Ni4xMTEuMS4xNzMxNTIzNzE4LjQ4LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/my-elder-scrolls-online-apartment-is-very-sad-and-crapp-1846793042?_gl=1*1qyn08u*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUyMTM4Ni4xMTEuMS4xNzMxNTIzNzE4LjQ4LjAuMA.."><em>The Elder Scrolls Online</em></a></span><em>, Final Fantasy 14,</em> and <em>New World</em>. But it’s never been a feature in <em>World of Warcraft</em>, even though files left in the game indicate that Blizzard had worked on a version of it early in <em>WoW’s </em>development. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://wowpedia.fandom.com/wiki/Player_housing#:~:text=In%20the%20BlizzCon%202009%20minigame%20Failoc%2Dalypse%2C%20one%20of%20the%20joke%20messages%20displayed%20upon%20level%2Dup%20says%2C%20%22Player%20housing%20unlocked%22.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://wowpedia.fandom.com/wiki/Player_housing#:~:text=In%20the%20BlizzCon%202009%20minigame%20Failoc%2Dalypse%2C%20one%20of%20the%20joke%20messages%20displayed%20upon%20level%2Dup%20says%2C%20%22Player%20housing%20unlocked%22." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The company has even joked about player housing in the past</a></span>, too. But now, finally, after 20 years, Blizzard is actually doing it, though it likely won’t be in the game for at least another year or more. </p><p>On November 13, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/warcraft-2-3-rts-classic-remastered-blizzard-pc-1851697730?rev=1731523171634&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/warcraft-2-3-rts-classic-remastered-blizzard-pc-1851697730?rev=1731523171634">during Blizzard’s 3o years of <em>Warcraft </em>event</a></span>, the studio revealed a lot of plans and updates for various <em>Warcraft </em>games. The presentation’s segment about the future of <em>WoW </em>was capped off with a very tiny tease about player housing. Here’s that teaser: </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.pcgamer.com/games/world-of-warcraft/player-housing-is-coming-to-world-of-warcraft-after-20-years-though-youll-have-to-wait-until-the-next-expansion-its-a-tremendously-large-undertaking/?utm_campaign=socialflow&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_medium=social&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/world-of-warcraft/player-housing-is-coming-to-world-of-warcraft-after-20-years-though-youll-have-to-wait-until-the-next-expansion-its-a-tremendously-large-undertaking/?utm_campaign=socialflow&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_medium=social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>PC Gamer </em>spoke to <em>WoW </em>director Ion Hazzikostas</a></span> about the teaser and confirmed that, yes, Blizzard is bringing player homes to the MMORPG. However, as seen in the teaser, this feature won’t be added until the next expansion, <em>Midnight</em>. So why tease it now? </p><p>“We want to give players a little sneak preview of some of what the team is cooking,” Hazzikostas explained to <em>PC Gamer</em>. “This also gives us a chance, I think, to have more open conversations about it that aren’t possible when it’s a top-secret feature.”</p><p>According to Hazzikostas, Blizzard wants to hear “what people are excited about, what they expect, and what they’d like to see from housing” in <em>World of Warcraft</em>. The plan is for that input to help “guide the team’s development efforts” on player housing.</p><p>“[Player housing] an idea that’s been kicked around for a long time—but we knew that to do it, we needed to be able to do it right. It’s a tremendously large undertaking,” said Hazzikostas, who also explained that another reason housing is happening now is that Blizzard has developed new tech behind the scenes in <em>WoW</em> to make this feature possible.</p><p>So now people can stop bugging Blizzard about player housing in <em>World of Warcraft</em> and start bugging them about how much they don’t like the way player housing works in <em>WoW </em>once it’s available in game. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After 20 Years, World of Warcraft is Getting Player Housing]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/after-20-years-world-of-warcraft-is-getting-player-housing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-20-years-world-of-warcraft-is-getting-player-housing.1035114/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/after-20-years-world-of-warcraft-is-getting-player-housing/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>I’ve lost myself to the MMORPG genre since 2004, and no, it wasn’t at the launch of World of Warcraft. I started with EverQuest 2. But I quickly jumped ship after a few years, joining the fun in Blizzard’s monolithic MMO sometime around the launch of Cataclysm. However, the experience always missed one immersive feature that most other games in the genre offered. Well, it’s happening. World of Warcraft will receive player housing after two decades!</p>



<p>In a teaser on <a href="https://x.com/Warcraft/status/1856769095112200343" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X (formerly Twitter)</a>, Blizzard unveiled player housing for World of Warcraft, which is coming in the next major expansion, Midnight. From the short teaser trailer, it appears we can decorate the walls and floors with various trinkets and furniture, and there’s a quick scene of a warrior consuming a mug of some type of drink before sitting down at the fire, with the whole trailer culminating in a look at two floor mats with Horde and Alliance logos, respectively.</p>



<p>Speaking with <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/world-of-warcraft/player-housing-is-coming-to-world-of-warcraft-after-20-years-though-youll-have-to-wait-until-the-next-expansion-its-a-tremendously-large-undertaking/?utm_campaign=socialflow&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_medium=social" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PC Gamer</a>, Blizzard’s Ion Hazzikostas said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We want to give players a little sneak preview of some of what the team is cooking. This also gives us a chance, I think, to have more open conversations about it that aren’t possible when it’s a top secret feature.</p>



<p>[Player housing] an idea that’s been kicked around for a long time—but we knew that to do it, we needed to be able to do it right. It’s a tremendously large undertaking.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Furthermore, Hazzikostas said the team wants to hear from the community regarding what they want to see and what they expect from player housing. If you have suggestions, don’t be afraid to make them known. Blizzard is generally quite active on social media, and they have forums where you can submit suggestions for the player homes feature coming in the upcoming expansion!</p>



<p>After all these years, are you still enjoying World of Warcraft? Let us know over at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>It was only earlier this past summer that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/world-of-warcraft-developers-have-formed-a-union/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">World of Warcraft developers formed a union</a>, so hopefully we see better working conditions and content coming from the studio!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Zombie Survival Game is on Sale Through the End of November]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/this-zombie-survival-game-is-on-sale-through-the-end-of-november/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-zombie-survival-game-is-on-sale-through-the-end-of-november.1035111/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/this-zombie-survival-game-is-on-sale-through-the-end-of-november/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Depending on how long you’ve had an account on Steam, you probably have hundreds of titles waiting in your backlog. You scored them cheap, right? I couldn’t help myself, either. I have so many games in my library, many of which I’ve never played, but whenever a new zombie survival game is on sale, I can’t help myself. I grab it. And now, you can score Dread Dawn, by developer Kioop, on sale until November 26!</p>



<h2 id="h-dread-dawn-is-on-sale-through-november-26">Dread Dawn is On Sale Through November 26</h2>



<p>Dread Dawn is available for 20% off for this extended sale, bringing the total price down from $19.99 to $15.99. While $20 for an open-ended zombie survival game is already an excellent deal, the reduced price through the end of November should help anyone on the fence.</p>



<p>On launch, Dread Dawn received a mixed reception from fans. The studio launched the game as a full release, but it was evident that it required more time to cook. An Early Access launch may have mitigated many negative reviews, but it’s still an exciting zombie survival sandbox!</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-dread-dawn">What is Dread Dawn?</h2>



<p>Dread Dawn is a top-down, open-world zombie survival game with sandbox and RPG elements. You play a student trapped on the campus alongside your classmates and other survivors as the evacuation goes wrong and you’re left behind. With zombies approaching on all sides, you must find ways to survive, growing food, wielding firearms and melee weapons, and constructing barricades and turrets to help you defend against the encroaching hordes. It’s part tower defense and part Project Zomboid, but with a little more jank and no controller support currently.</p>



<h2 id="h-other-zombie-survival-games-worth-your-time">Other Zombie Survival Games Worth Your Time</h2>



<p>Of course, the zombie survival genre is positively massive, thanks to years of content flowing through the game development pipeline. If Dread Dawn doesn’t catch your fancy, then check out:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Project Zomboid</strong></li>



<li><strong>Dying Light 2</strong></li>



<li><strong>7 Days to Die</strong></li>



<li><strong>Left 4 Dead 2</strong></li>



<li><strong>Zompiercer</strong></li>



<li><strong>No More Room in Hell 2</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>What’s your favorite zombie survival game of all time? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forums</a>, and maybe you’ll find a few like-minded players to join your next survival run!</p>



<hr>



<p>It’s been a huge year for zombie games, and we have a list of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/10-best-zombie-games-to-play-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ten best zombie games to play in 2024</a> that I don’t think you should skip!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Valve made Half-Life 2 and set a new standard for future games]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/how-valve-made-half-life-2-and-set-a-new-standard-for-future-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-valve-made-half-life-2-and-set-a-new-standard-for-future-games.1035108/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/how-valve-made-half-life-2-and-set-a-new-standard-for-future-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
            <article data-id="2061641">
  
  <header>
  <div>
    <div>
      

      

      <p>
        From physics to greyboxing, <em>Half-Life 2</em> broke a lot of new ground.
      </p>

      
    </div>

    <div>
    
    <p>
      This article is part of our 20th anniversary of <em>Half-Life 2</em> series.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Aurich Lawson

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
  </div>
</header>


  

  
      
    
    <div>
                      
                      
          
<p><em>It's </em>Half-Life 2<em> week at Ars Technica! This Saturday, November 16, is the 20th anniversary of the release of </em>Half-Life 2<em>—a game of historical importance for the artistic medium and technology of computer games. Each day up through the 16th, we'll be running a new article looking back at the game and its impact.</em></p>
<p>There has been some debate about which product was the first modern “triple-A” video game, but ask most people and one answer is sure to at least be a contender: Valve’s <em>Half-Life 2</em>.</p>
<p>For Western PC games, <em>Half-Life 2</em> set a standard that held strong in developers’ ambitions and in players’ expectations for well over a decade. Despite that, there’s only so much new ground it truly broke in terms of how games are made and designed—it’s just that most games didn’t have the same commitment to scope, scale, and polish all at the same time.</p>
<p>To kick off a week of articles looking back at the influential classic, we’re going to go over the way it was made, and just as importantly, the thought that went into its design—both of which were highly influential.</p>
<h2>A story of cabals and Electronics Boutique</h2>
<p>Development, design, and production practices in the games industry have always varied widely by studio. But because of the success of <em>Half-Life 2</em>, some of the approaches that Valve took were copied elsewhere in the industry after they were shared in blog posts and conference talks at events like the Game Developer’s Conference (GDC).</p>
<h2>The cabals of Valve</h2>
<p>Valve is famous for influencing many things in gaming, but it was most influential in its relatively flat and democratic team structure, and that played out even during <em>Half-Life 2</em>’s development back in the early 2000s. While many studios are broken up into clear departments big and small for different disciplines (such as art, level design, combat design, narrative design, AI programming, and so on), many parts of Valve’s <em>Half-Life 2</em> team consisted of a half-dozen multi-disciplinary small groups the company <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/classic-postmortem-the-making-of-i-half-life-2-i-">internally called “cabals.”</a></p>

          
                      
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>Each major chapter in <em>Half-Life 2</em> had its own unique four-to-five-person cabal made up of level designers and programmers. These groups built their levels largely independently, while frequently showing their work to other cabals for feedback and cross-pollination of good ideas. They all worked within constraints set in a pre-production phase that laid out elements like the main story beats, some of the weapons, and so on.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Each major chapter, like this battle-in-the-streets one toward the end of the game, was designed by a largely independent cabal.

              <span>
          Credit:

                      <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/220/HalfLife_2/" target="_blank">
          
          Valve

                      </a>
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Additionally, similarly sized design cabals worked on aspects of the game’s design that crossed multiple levels—often made with representatives from the chapter cabals—for things like weapons.</p>
<p>There was even a “Cabal Cabal” made up of representatives from each of the six chapter teams to critique the work coming from all the teams.</p>
<h3>Ruthless playtesting</h3>
<p>Many game designers—especially back in the '80s or '90s—worked largely in isolation, determining privately what they thought would be fun and then shipping a finished product to an audience to find out if it really was.</p>
<p>By contrast, Valve put a great deal of emphasis <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1plhILdjuZE">on playtesting</a>. To be clear: Valve did not invent playtesting. But it did make that a key part of the design process in a way that is even quite common today.</p>
<p>The <em>Half-Life 2</em> team would send representatives to public places where potential fans might hang out, like Electronics Boutique stores, and would approach them and say something along the lines of, “Would you like to play <em>Half-Life 2</em>?” (Most said yes!)</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      A photo from an actual early 2000s playtest of an in-development <em>Half-Life 2</em>, courtesy of a presentation slide from a Valve GDC talk.

              <span>
          Credit:

                      <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1plhILdjuZE" target="_blank">
          
          Valve

                      </a>
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>The volunteer playtesters were brought to a room set up like a real player’s living room and told to sit at the computer desk and simply play the game. Behind them, the level’s cabal would sit and watch a feed of the gameplay on a TV. The designers weren’t allowed to talk to the testers; they simply took notes.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>Through this process, they learned which designs and ideas worked and which ones simply confused the players. They then made iterative changes, playtested the level again, and repeated that process until they were happy with the outcome.</p>
<p>Today’s developers sometimes take a more sophisticated approach to sourcing players for their playtests, making sure they’re putting their games in front of a wider range of people to make the games more accessible beyond a dedicated enthusiast core. But nonetheless, But nonetheless, playtesting across the industry today is at the level it is because of Valve’s refinement of the process.</p>

<h3>The alpha wave</h3>
<p>For a game as ambitious as <em>Half-Life 2</em> was, it’s surprising just how polished it was when it hit the market. That iterative mindset was a big part of it, but it extended beyond those consumer playtests.</p>
<p>Valve made sure to allocate a significant amount of time for iteration and refinement on an alpha build, which in this case meant a version of the game that could be played from beginning to end. When speaking to other developers about the process, representatives of Valve said that if you’re working on a game for just a year, you should try to get to the alpha point by the end of eight months so you have four for refinement.</p>
<p>Apparently, this made a big impact on <em>Half-Life 2</em>’s overall quality. It also helped address natural downsides of the cabal structure, like the fact that chapters developed by largely independent teams offered an inconsistent experience in terms of difficulty curve.</p>
<p>With processes like this, Valve modeled several things that would be standard in triple-A game development for years to come—though not all of them were done by Valve first.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>For example, the approach to in-game cutscenes reverberates today. Different cabals focused on designing the levels versus planning out cutscenes in which characters would walk around the room and interact with one another, all while the player could freely explore the environment.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Nova Prospekt was one of the first levels completed during <em>Half-Life 2</em>'s development.

              <span>
          Credit:

                      <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/220/HalfLife_2/" target="_blank">
          
          Valve

                      </a>
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>The team who focused on story performances worked with level designers to block out the walking paths for characters, and the level designers had to use that as a constraint, building the levels around them. That meant that changes to level layouts couldn’t create situations where new character animations would have to be made. That approach is still used by many studios today.</p>
<p>As is what is now called <a href="https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/en-us/uefn/greyboxing-in-unreal-editor-for-fortnite">greyboxing</a>, the practice of designing levels without high-effort artwork so that artists can come in and pretty the levels up after the layout is settled, rather than having to constantly go back and forth with designers as those designers “find the fun.” Valve diddn’t invent this, but it was a big part of the process, and its in-development levels were filled with the color orange, not just gray.</p>
<h2>Finding the DNA of <em>Half-Life 2</em> in 20 years of games</h2>
<p>When <em>Half-Life 2</em> hit the market via the newly launched Steam digital distribution platform (more on that later this week), it was widely praised. Critics and players at the time loved it, calling it a must-have title and one that defined the PC gaming experience. Several of the things that came out of its development process that players remember most from <em>Half-Life 2 </em>became staples over the past 20 years.</p>
<p>For instance, the game set a new standard for character animations in fully interactive cutscenes, especially with facial animations. Today, far more advanced motion capture is a common practice in triple-A games—to the point that games that don’t do it (like Bethesda Game Studios titles) are widely criticized by players simply for not taking that route, even if motion capture doesn’t necessarily make practical sense for those games’ scope and design.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>

        
        <div>
          
          
<p>And <em>Half-Life 2</em>’s gravity gun, which dramatically built on past games’ physics mechanics, is in many ways a &nbsp;concept that developers are still playing with and expanding on today. Ultrahand, the flagship player ability in 2023’s <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em>, could be seen as a substantial evolution from the gravity gun. In addition to offering players the ability to pick and place objects in the world, it gives them the power to attach them to one another to build creative contraptions.</p>
<p>There’s also <em>Half-Life 2</em>’s approach to using environmental lines and art cues to guide the player’s attention through realistic-looking environments. The game was lauded for that at the time, and it was an approach used by many popular games in the years to come. Today, many studios have moved on to much more explicit player cues like the yellow climbing holds in so many recent AAA titles. As you’ll see in an upcoming article this week written by someone who played <em>Half-Life 2</em> for the very first time in 2024, <em>Half-Life 2</em>’s approach may have set the stage, but modern players might expect something a little different.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Environments like this were carefully designed to guide the player's eye in subtle ways. Today, many AAA games take a less subtle approach because playtesting with broader audiences shows it's sometimes necessary.

              <span>
          Credit:

                      <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/220/HalfLife_2/" target="_blank">
          
          Valve

                      </a>
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>One thing about the environment design that <em>Half-Life 2</em> was praised for hasn’t been replaced these days, though: a commitment to subtle environmental storytelling. World-building and vibes are perhaps <em>Half-Life 2</em>’s greatest achievements. From <em>BioShock</em> to <em><a href="https://www.vg247.com/half-life-2-influence-half-life-alyx">Dishonored</a></em> to <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>, this might be the realm where <em>Half-Life 2</em>’s influence is still felt the most today.</p>
<h2>A legacy remembered</h2>
<p>Looking back 20 years later, Half-Life 2 isn’t necessarily remembered for radical new gameplay concepts. Instead, it’s known for outstanding execution—and developers everywhere are still applying lessons learned by that development team to try to chase its high standard of quality.</p>
<p>Even at the time, critics noted that it wasn’t exactly that there was anything in <em>Half-Life 2</em> that players had never seen before. Rather, it was the combined force of quality, scope, presentation, and refinement that made an impact.</p>
<p>Of course, Valve and Half-Life 2 are also known for multiple memorable cultural moments, some of the industry’s most infamous controversies, and playing a big part in introducing digital distribution. We’ll explore some of those things as we count down to the "Red Letter Day" that is this Saturday.</p>


          
                  </div>

                  
          






  <div>
    

    <p>
      Samuel Axon is a senior editor at Ars Technica. He covers Apple, software development, gaming, AI, entertainment, and mixed reality. He has been writing about gaming and technology for nearly two decades at Engadget, PC World, Mashable, Vice, Polygon, Wired, and others. He previously ran a marketing and PR agency in the gaming industry, led editorial for the TV network CBS, and worked on social media marketing strategy for Samsung Mobile at the creative agency SPCSHP. He also is an independent software and game developer for iOS, Windows, and other platforms, and he&nbsp;is a graduate of DePaul University, where he studied interactive media and software development.
    </p>
  </div>


  <p>
    <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/how-valve-made-half-life-2-and-set-a-new-standard-for-future-games/#comments" title="51 comments">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 80 80"><defs><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__a"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__b"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__a)"><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__b)"><path d="M80 40c0 22.09-17.91 40-40 40S0 62.09 0 40 17.91 0 40 0s40 17.91 40 40"></path><path d="M40 40 .59 76.58C-.67 77.84.22 80 2.01 80H40z"></path></g></g></svg>
    51 Comments
  </a>
      </p>





  
              </div>
  </article>


  


  

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bethesda Workers Go On Strike Against Microsoft]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bethesda-workers-go-on-strike-against-microsoft/1100-6527751/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bethesda-workers-go-on-strike-against-microsoft.1035102/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bethesda-workers-go-on-strike-against-microsoft/1100-6527751/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527751">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Last year, quality-assurance workers at Bethesda and ZeniMax studios formed ZeniMax Workers United, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/qa-workers-at-zenimax-studios-have-become-the-gaming-industrys-largest-union/1100-6510268/" data-ref-id="1100-6510268">the largest certified video game union</a> in the United States. Now that union is putting its collective power to the test in a brief strike against Bethesda and ZeniMax's parent company, Microsoft.</p><p>ZeniMax Workers United has been attempting to negotiate a deal with Microsoft over remote-work requirements while also limiting the number of outsourced QA workers who can be brought in on Bethesda's projects. The union didn't say who Microsoft is outsourcing QA work to, but it accused the company of ignoring requests to negotiate.</p><p>"They have continually given us their first proposal again and again, and it's become obvious that our different mobilization tactics have not worked," QA test lead Rhyanna Eichnersaid told <a href="https://www.inverse.com/gaming/bethesda-strike-zenimax-xbox-microsoft" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Inverse</a>.</p><p>This one-day strike was called in an attempt to make Microsoft more receptive to addressing the union's concerns.</p><p>"Striking isn't fun or ideal, but there's a satisfaction in having a concrete physical action we can do to fight for better work conditions," noted senior QA tester Juniper Dowell. "Hopefully, we can convince them to stop dragging their feet and meet us at the table."</p><p>According to Dowell, many of the QA testers were hired during the COVID pandemic when remote work was more prevalent. Microsoft's current requirements call for QA workers to be in the office two days a week, while the union is asking for a more flexible remote policy.</p><p>After the strike began, Microsoft issued a statement affirming the company's willingness to "listen and address their concerns at the bargaining table."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/stephentotilo/status/1856757427913236783" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Quote from MS rep to me re: today's ZeniMax strike (over remote work, outsourcing): "We respect our employees’ rights to express their point of view as they have done today. We will continue to listen and address their concerns at the bargaining table.” <a href="https://t.co/pmYpUyPvS2" rel="nofollow ">https://t.co/pmYpUyPvS2</a></p>  — Stephen Totilo (@stephentotilo) <a href="https://twitter.com/stephentotilo/status/1856757427913236783?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 13, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>If the one-day strike fails to motivate Microsoft to make any concessions or changes, it could lead to a longer strike in the future. But for now, Bethesda's upcoming games, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-hands-on-preview/1100-6527431/" data-ref-id="1100-6527431">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a>, are not expected to be delayed by the strike.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 BlackCell Trailer Shows Off One Of COD's Most Impressive Operators Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-blackcell-trailer-shows-off-one-of-cods-most-impressive-operators-yet/1100-6527752/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-blackcell-trailer-shows-off-one-of-cods-most-impressive-operators-yet.1035099/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-blackcell-trailer-shows-off-one-of-cods-most-impressive-operators-yet/1100-6527752/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527752">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6's in-game store gets stocked with all manner of microtransactions tomorrow, November 14, to kick off the game's Season 1. And included among them is the BlackCell bundle, which features Goliath as its headlining hero. Goliath is one of the most unique Call of Duty operators to date.</p><p>Goliath has a "molten, crystalized skull" whose armor emits flames. As you can see in the trailer below, Goliath is a menacing force to be reckoned with.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AgDL9clbEdk" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AgDL9clbEdk" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>BlackCell bundles are Call of Duty's most expensive in-game offerings, coming in at around $30. For that price, purchasers get a new Operator, along with 20 Battle Pass tier skips, an allotment of 1,110 COD Points to spend on other stuff, and exclusive guns. For the Season 1 BlackCell DLC, this includes the "Boiling Point" assault rifle that is actually dripping with fire. It also comes with the "Who's Laughing Now" finishing move in which Goliath's hyena companion comes in and tears your enemy apart. The bundle also includes a special BlackCell clan tag to show off in lobbies and winner's cricles.</p><p>Beyond all of this, BlackCell owners get BlackCell-exclusive skins for Sev, Bayan, Bailey, Carver, Alvarez, and Stone, along with six BlackCell-exclusive weapon blueprints. People who buy the BlackCell DLC can also unlock any single page of the Battle Pass and bypass the normal requirements. What's more, there are more than 130 rewards that BlackCell owners can unlock throughout Season 1.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399179-screenshot2024-11-13at2.26.29pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4399179" data-ratio="0.55712603062426" data-width="1698" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399179-screenshot2024-11-13at2.26.29pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4399179"></a><figcaption>The new BlackCell bundle goes live on November 14</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399179-screenshot2024-11-13at2.26.29pm.png"></figure><p>If you don't want to spend $30 on the BlackCell bundle, Black Ops 6's in-game store will receive many other bundles for the Season 1 launch, including one that turns you into a shark. Check out the gallery below to see more of what's included during Season 1.</p><p>November 14 also marks the launch of Call of Duty: Warzone's new map, Area 99, and it's also when Black Ops 6 content integrates into Warzone. </p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ArenaNet To Release ‘Godspawn’ Update for Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds on November 19, Featuring New 50-Player Titan Battle and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/arenanet-to-release-godspawn-update-for-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-on-november-19-featuring-new-50-player-titan-battle-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arenanet-to-release-%E2%80%98godspawn%E2%80%99-update-for-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-on-november-19-featuring-new-50-player-titan-battle-and-more.1035087/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/arenanet-to-release-godspawn-update-for-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-on-november-19-featuring-new-50-player-titan-battle-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-finally-launched-bringing-in-housing-mechanism-new-raids-much-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds</a> will receive the Godspawn update, adding a new 50-player boss battle, a new 10-player raid, and a legendary spear.</p>
<h2>Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds is getting the first major update "Godspawn" on November 19th, expanding the story with new story chapters</h2>
<p>The MMORPG Guild Wars 2 by ArenaNet is receiving its first major update for the Janthir Wilds expansion soon. It's the first of three major updates, and it'll land on November 19. The update will add new content to the game for the players.</p>
<p>The <em>Janthir Wilds&nbsp;</em>expansion DLC was released in August this year, bringing unexplored wilds and&nbsp;<em>Homestead&nbsp;</em>for players to decorate and cultivate. With the <em>Godspawn&nbsp;</em>update, the game will bring three new story chapters to continue the adventure against the Titans. This time, ArenaNet has introduced a new 50-player battle against a Titan, who will be the reinterpretation of <em>Decima. </em>It will be similar to the boss battles as introduced in the <em>Secrets of the Obscure </em>Convergence.</p>
<p>Players can enter the battle every three hours, but private squads can start the challenge at any time. Apart from the boss battle, Guild Wars 2 will also receive a new 10-player raid, allowing players to climb Mount Balrior to battle the titans of Janthir to obtain rewards such as marquee items and cosmetics.</p>
<figure><figcaption>Image Credit: guildwars2.com</figcaption></figure>
<p>The 10-player raid will feature three bosses and several smaller battles that will allow players to enhance their coordination and adaptability. The two bosses,&nbsp;<strong>Greer&nbsp;</strong>and&nbsp;<strong>Decima</strong>, will regroup once again at Mount Balrior, stronger than before as this time they won't be alone and will also have newer abilities.</p>
<p><iframe title="Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds – &quot;Godspawn&quot;" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jrol0Nr8q_Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Several new updates are also on the way in Godspawn update, including the new Sea Wave Glass weapon, more rewards in the Wizard's Vault like skins for armor and boots, and new decorations for Homestead to customize living space. A new legendary spear, <em>Klobjarne,&nbsp;</em>will be available to players as well. The Godspawn update will be free for those who have purchased the <em>Janther Wilds&nbsp;</em>expansion. Two more updates will be released in the coming months to complete the expansion.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Classic RTS Games Warcraft and Warcraft 2 Fully Remastered And Out Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/warcraft-2-3-rts-classic-remastered-blizzard-pc-1851697730</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/classic-rts-games-warcraft-and-warcraft-2-fully-remastered-and-out-now.1035078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/warcraft-2-3-rts-classic-remastered-blizzard-pc-1851697730<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="36a921a64d7372dad3b22e6f1dd24d85" data-recommend-id="image://36a921a64d7372dad3b22e6f1dd24d85" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows an orc and human from Warcraft 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows an orc and human from Warcraft 2. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="36a921a64d7372dad3b22e6f1dd24d85" data-recommend-id="image://36a921a64d7372dad3b22e6f1dd24d85" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows an orc and human from Warcraft 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Blizzard has announced that the original <em>Warcraft</em> and <em>Warcraft 2</em>, as well as its expansions, are being remastered and re-released as part of a new Battle Chest. This new package also includes <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/warcraft-iii-reign-of-chaos&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/warcraft-iii-reign-of-chaos"><em>Warcraft 3 Reforged</em></a></span>, which has received a new update improving its visuals. And all of this is available today. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195326" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="326" data-playlist="195326,195150,195618" data-current="195326"><div><p>Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20784.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;http://<iframe width=\&quot;1730\&quot; height=\&quot;666\&quot; src=\&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0rEfOTxr59o\&quot; title=\&quot;Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct: Celebrations, Reflections, and a Look Ahead\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;0\&quot; allow=\&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share\&quot; referrerpolicy=\&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin\&quot; allowfullscreen></iframe>&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://<iframe width=&quot;1730&quot; height=&quot;666&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0rEfOTxr59o&quot; title=&quot;Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct: Celebrations, Reflections, and a Look Ahead&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen></iframe>">During Wednesday’s <em>Warcraft</em> 30th Anniversary Direct</a></span> event, Blizzard announced a series of updates to existing <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/wow-war-within-review-expansion-is-it-good-1851643832&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/wow-war-within-review-expansion-is-it-good-1851643832"><em>Warcraft</em></a></span><em> </em>games. For example, <em>Warcraft Rumble</em> is getting new heroes and will be playable on PC next month. And <em>Warcraft’</em>s spin-off card game, <em>Hearthstone, </em>is getting a <em>Starcraft </em>mini-expansion in January 2025. But the big news was the announcement and release of a new <em>Warcraft </em>RTS collection bringing remastered versions of the first three games to a new generation via a just-released updated edition of the classic Battle Chest<em>. </em></p><p>On November 13, Blizzard announced that it was remastering the first two <em>Warcraft </em>RTS games—-<em>Warcraft: Orcs and Heroes </em>and <em>Warcraft II</em> and its expansion, <em>Beyond The Dark Portal—</em>to celebrate 30 years of the franchise. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/ryZ2jiW95qo&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/ryZ2jiW95qo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Here’s the trailer</a></span> for the newly announced remasters. </p><p>As shown in the trailer above, Blizzard’s new<em> Warcraft </em>Battle Chest also includes the previously remastered <em>Warcraft 3: Reforged</em>. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/warcraft-3-reforged-isn-t-much-of-an-upgrade-1841325885?_gl=1*1ymvzon*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxNjMyNy4yOS4xLjE3MzE1MjI5NDcuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/warcraft-3-reforged-isn-t-much-of-an-upgrade-1841325885?_gl=1*1ymvzon*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxNjMyNy4yOS4xLjE3MzE1MjI5NDcuNjAuMC4w">That game launched in 2020  to negative reviews</a></span> from fans, and since then Blizzard has updated it to improve the remastered RTS. Today, as part of the new <em>Battle Chest</em>, <em>Reforged </em>is getting a new 2.0 update. This update improves the visuals and adds new options to let players use more classic art and models. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The <em>Warcraft </em>Battle Chest is now available on Battle.net</a></span> for PC and includes not only the three remastered <em>Warcraft </em>games but also the original <em>Warcraft 1 </em>and <em>2</em> as well. So if you want to replay the OG versions of these beloved strategy games, you can do that, too. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft: Classic Heads to Mists of Pandaria Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-classic-heads-to-mists-of-pandaria-next-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-warcraft-classic-heads-to-mists-of-pandaria-next-year.1035063/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-classic-heads-to-mists-of-pandaria-next-year<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">During today’s Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct, Blizzard announced its next big plans for World of Warcraft: Classic. Shocking no one, it’s planning to move onto the next expansion in 2025: Mists of Pandaria.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As with other Classic expansions, Mists of Pandaria will launch with “some changes” to its original form, but will largely retain the same  content and features from when it first released in 2012. Among other new features, Mists of Pandaria introduced the continent of Pandaria, the playable Pandaran race that could join either the Alliance or the Horde, the Monk class, pet battles, Scenarios, and flexible raiding.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Notably, though, this will be a different experience than the one offered during the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-is-revisiting-mists-of-pandaria-in-world-of-warcraft-remix">recent Mists of Pandaria: Remix event</a>, which allowed players to speed level through Pandaria with new spells and abilities, new items, and other twists on its original gameplay.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The addition of Mists of Pandaria furthers World of Warcraft: Classic’s steady march to catch up with existing World of Warcraft content. However, recently some Classic players have begun to criticize the direction of the game and lament how far away it’s gotten from the original Classic feel as expansions have been added. While Blizzard has done some things to address this, such as add new Classic modes like Hardcore and Season of Discovery, players are increasingly asking for more opportunities to replay the oldest content.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For those players, Blizzard announced that it will be adding new “vanilla” Classic realms on November 21. This will include new PvP, PvE, and new “hardcore mode” realms, which will go through the same steady cadence of patch updates as past Classic realms, with the Molten Core raid launching a few weeks after launch. These new realms (minus the Hardcore realms) will eventually progress to The Burning Crusade Classic, giving players the opportunity to start all over once more and progress through early WoW content.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">World of Warcraft: Classic’s Mists of Pandaria update will launch sometime in 2025. You can catch up with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-30th-anniversary-direct-everything-announced">everything announced from today’s Warcraft Direct right here</a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-shadow-dropped-with-improved-graphics-quality-of-life-improvements-and-other-new-features">remasters of Warcraft I and II</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-major-patch-will-finally-visit-the-legendary-goblin-capital-undermine">next patch for The War Within</a>, and teases of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-expansion-finally-adding-player-housing-after-years-of-requests-by-fans">next WoW retail expansion</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft 1 and 2 Remasters Shadow-Dropped With Improved Graphics, Quality-of-Life Improvements, and Other New Features]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-shadow-dropped-with-improved-graphics-quality-of-life-improvements-and-other-new-features</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-shadow-dropped-with-improved-graphics-quality-of-life-improvements-and-other-new-features.1035060/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-shadow-dropped-with-improved-graphics-quality-of-life-improvements-and-other-new-features<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s the 30th anniversary of Warcraft, and to celebrate, Blizzard is bringing back a couple of bonafide classics. Today, Blizzard announced it’s releasing remasters of both the original Warcraft and Warcraft 2, and they’re both out today.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">During today’s Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct stream, Blizzard unveiled both remasters, which will include fully updated graphics as well as an option to revert back to original visuals, a number of quality of life features, and improved UI and UX features. Warcraft II will also include multiplayer, with all legacy custom maps being compatible and playable.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Critically, these are both being billed as remasters rather than full-blown “reimaginings” like Warcraft III: Reforged. Fans of the original game widely panned Warcraft III: Reforged due to the many changes made from the original, technical issues, and features that were missing or degraded from the original. Our own reviewer <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-3-reforged-review">gave it a 7/10</a>, but described it as "uninspired." Upon its release, many fans expressed frustration that Blizzard had not simply remastered the original Warcraft III, which may be why Blizzard opted for a lighter touch with Warcraft I and II.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, Warcraft III: Reforged is also receiving an update today that will include a graphics overhaul and various other quality of life changes that may improve the experience. These include the ability to toggle between the game’s new graphics, old graphics, and a new remastered look that’s reminiscent of the classic look but has a higher resolution. Reforged players will also get the ability to mix and match certain UI elements in all three graphic options.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Warcraft III: Reforged will join the remasters of Warcraft 1 and 2 in a revamped “Battle Chest” hearkening back to the classic, popular bundle. The bundle’s pricing will adjust based on what games players already own, meaning if you already own Reforged, you can add the two remasters at a discount.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Warcraft I and II Remastered, Warcraft III: Reforged 2.0, and the new Battle Chest are out today. You can catch up with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-30th-anniversary-direct-everything-announced">everything announced from today’s Warcraft Direct right here</a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-major-patch-will-finally-visit-the-legendary-goblin-capital-undermine">upcoming updates to World of Warcraft</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-classic-heads-to-mists-of-pandaria-next-year">World of Warcraft: Classic</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-expansion-finally-adding-player-housing-after-years-of-requests-by-fans">teases of the next retail expansion, Midnight</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After 20 Long Years, WoW Is Getting Player Housing In Its Midnight Expansion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-20-long-years-wow-is-getting-player-housing-in-its-midnight-expansion/1100-6527718/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-20-long-years-wow-is-getting-player-housing-in-its-midnight-expansion.1035057/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-20-long-years-wow-is-getting-player-housing-in-its-midnight-expansion/1100-6527718/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527718">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a> is, at long last, getting player housing. Blizzard confirmed during its recent Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct that the long-asked-for feature will be part of the MMORPG's future Midnight expansion, saving the biggest crowd-pleasing announcement of the livestream for last.</p><p dir="ltr">In a short teaser video, a Death Knight walks into a nondescript house. Inside, the walls are adorned with the head of the dragon Onyxia, various weapons and shields, a miniature Goblin shredder mech, and more. The weary adventurer puts down their sword, settles into a chair by the fire, and takes a sip from a mug adorned with the words "Home Sweet Home."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fQXHFrLX6A4" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fQXHFrLX6A4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">That's about all there is to go on, but GameSpot did get the chance to chat with WoW game director Ion Hazzikostas prior to the anniversary livestream about the big news. He confirmed the feature has been in the works for several years.</p><p dir="ltr">"I've definitely given some cagey and evasive answers about 'housing ever?' while knowing secretly it was going to come to pass," Hazzikostas said. "We've known we've wanted to do it for real for some time. I think figuring out the how and when and making sure we can deliver something that's going to meet our players' expectations and exceed them, that's all the tricky parts to it. What we're announcing this week is a teaser, a hint, the slimmest of previews, just letting people know, 'Hey, it's coming as part of Midnight.'"</p><p dir="ltr">He said much more information will come over the course of the next year, but that the team is excited to have it out in the open so they can start to hear what players want from digital housing in Azeroth.</p><p dir="ltr">"Just excited to get that news out there and to begin a conversation so we can start hearing from players what they're hoping to see from a World of Warcraft housing system," Hazzikostas said. "Double-check it matches what we are currently cooking but also gives us some time to pivot and make sure we deliver what players are hoping for."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398397-worldofwarcraft%28modern%292025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4398397" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398397-worldofwarcraft%28modern%292025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4398397"></a><figcaption>More about Midnight will be revealed next summer, according to WoW's 2025 roadmap.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398397-worldofwarcraft%28modern%292025roadmap.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">During BlizzCon 2023, Blizzard announced the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-next-three-expansions-revealed-all-at-once-including-2024-the-war-within/1100-6518914/" data-ref-id="1100-6518914">next three WoW expansions all at once</a> and said it hoped to start delivering expansions at a faster pace than its normal two-year expansion cycle. According to Blizzard's newly revealed 2025 WoW content roadmap, Midnight is not coming next year, though more details about the expansion will be revealed next summer.</p><p dir="ltr">Hazzikostas noted that even though Midnight isn't coming next year and players will still be playing The War Within in 2025, the team is dedicated to keeping the game's update cadence going at a steady pace while still getting a full-fledged new expansion ready "in a timely manner."</p><p dir="ltr">Players housing in WoW was just one of many Warcraft-related announcements to come out of the Warcraft 30th Anniversary Stream. Blizzard additionally announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/" data-ref-id="1100-6527719">remastered versions of Warcraft 1 and 2 (available now)</a>, a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/" data-ref-id="1100-6527722">StarCraft crossover for Hearthstone</a>, and what's next for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria/1100-6527720/" data-ref-id="1100-6527720">WoW Classic</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Price Cut For The Holidays Edited Out Of New Sony Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-price-cut-for-the-holidays-edited-out-of-new-sony-trailer/1100-6527747/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-price-cut-for-the-holidays-edited-out-of-new-sony-trailer.1035051/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-price-cut-for-the-holidays-edited-out-of-new-sony-trailer/1100-6527747/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527747">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>On November 12, Sony published a marketing trailer for the PlayStation 5 that ended with the announcement that the digital PS5 Slim would be marked down for the holidays. That trailer has since been edited and re-uploaded to remove all mention of the temporary discount.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KiNPo7KvWCM" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The trailer originally stated</a> that the digital PS5 Slim would be on sale until December 24 for $380. The system originally launched for $400 before <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-slim-playstation-5-models-announced-all-digital-sees-50-price-increase/1100-6518283/" data-ref-id="1100-6518283">Sony raised the price to $450</a>.  Bringing it down to $380 for the holidays is a nice offer, and hopefully it comes back. <a href="https://x.com/Xbox/status/1855671773330579913" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Microsoft already slashed the price of the Xbox Series X by $50 for the holidays.</a></p><p>The video has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KiNPo7KvWCM" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">since been re-uploaded</a>, with many commenters poking fun at Sony for editing out mention of the deal.</p><p>GameSpot has contacted Sony to try to find out what's going on here.</p><p>Companies like Sony, Microsoft, and Nintendo typically offer discounts on their consoles and games for Black Friday and the wider holiday shopping season, and it's expected Sony will eventually roll out a PS5 discount. In other PS5 news, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/spend-1800-on-jewelry-get-a-ps5/1100-6527715/" data-ref-id="1100-6527715">if you spend $1,800 on high-end jewelry, you can get a free PS5.</a></p><p>Sony just released the PS5 Pro, but the console is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/just-who-is-the-ps5-pro-for/1100-6526452/" data-ref-id="1100-6526452">aimed at a very small tech-enthusiast market rather than the general consumer.</a> Some analysts are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kids-wants-video-games-more-than-money-for-the-holidays-study-finds/1100-6527738/" data-ref-id="1100-6527738">predicting a grim holiday for new console sales.</a></p><p>If you don't want a PS5, Nintendo just announced its own set of Black Friday deals, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-holiday-deals-2024-console-bundles/1100-6526528/" data-ref-id="1100-6526528">discounts on Switch bundles.</a> Nintendo is expected to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-confirms-switch-2-announcement-is-still-five-months-away-at-most/1100-6527576/" data-ref-id="1100-6527576">announce the Switch 2 in the next few months.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Black Friday Deals for Xbox Series X|S]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-xbox-series-xs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-black-friday-deals-for-xbox-series-x-s.1035012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-xbox-series-xs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ready for Black Friday? With Christmas just around the corner, many gamers are trying to grab the best deals possible. Like every year, Xbox has quite a few deals people can choose from. Here are the best Black Friday Deals for Xbox Series X|S.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-xbox-series-x-s-black-friday-deals">Best Xbox Series X|S Black Friday Deals</h2>



<p>Excited to find the best Xbox Series X|S deals this Black Friday? Well, Xbox will be doing quite a few deals for Xbox Series X|S systems, controllers and games.</p>



<p>However, no actual Black Friday deals have been released by the company, many are already speculating that the system will have huge bundle deals at stores like Walmart, Target, Best Buy and more.</p>



<p>Every year, too, many of these popular retail stores have a bunch of different discounts on games. With popular titles like Call of Duty just releasing a new game, gamers should expect to see deals revolving around the games to release on Black Friday.</p>







<h2 id="h-current-xbox-series-x-s-deals">Current Xbox Series X|S Deals</h2>



<p>Luckily, Xbox has a ton of deals already in its store, meaning gamers can indulge in the Black Friday festivities early on. Below is a list of current Xbox deals gamers can grab in the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/promotions/sales/sales-and-specials">Microsoft store:</a></p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/consoles/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X ($50 off)</a></li>
</ul>



<p>The page also has quite a few games for sale, too. However, the majority of these games for sale are not big titles. The big titles, like Call of Duty and more, will not be released until Black Friday.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-get-black-friday-deals">How to Get Black Friday Deals</h2>



<p>Luckily, Black Friday deals are not as difficult to come by as they were in the past when you had to wait outside a store until midnight. Many retailers, like Walmart and Target, will release their deals earlier in the day on Thanksgiving, giving consumers the chance to grab whatever their heart desires early on.</p>



<p>Still, many deals, especially on Xbox games and systems, will go incredibly fast, so be prepared to have your money out.</p>



<p>For more Insider Gaming guides, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-nintendo-switch/">best Black Friday Nintendo Switch deals.</a> </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Pokémon Card Deals I Want to See for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-card-deals-black-friday-predictions-for-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-pok%C3%A9mon-card-deals-i-want-to-see-for-black-friday.1035009/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-card-deals-black-friday-predictions-for-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Big boxes and ETBs at Black Friday prices.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">We all want to be the very best Pokémon TCG player and collector, like no was ever was. We also all know the value of a bargain on booster boxes, big box premium collections, elite trainer boxes, and more. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024">Black Friday 2024</a> should be loaded with Pokédeals, making it the best time of year to invest in some sealed products to rip open or hold on to.  </p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Pokémon Card Deal Predictions for Black Friday</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Grading Pokémon cards is also becoming more popular than ever before. Trainers won't find cards in better condition than being pack fresh, but opening packs rather than buying singles can rack up a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-most-expensive-pokemon-cards">Gollum of cash</a>. I'm a Pokémon Master, and the following products are on my radar for Black Friday 2024. Let's get into it:</p><p id="tyranitar-and-tsareena-ex-premium-co"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Tyranitar and Tsareena ex Premium Co">Big Box Deals</h2></p><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-and-violet-shro"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet and Violet Shro">Booster Bundles</h2></p><div catalogid="6d085d9e-2e49-411e-bbed-dfc088fe5390" id="210092"><div id="210092" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet and Violet Shrouded Fable Booster Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Need to complete a set sooner rather than later? Booster bundles are the offordable way to get multiple boosters to rip open in one sitting. Yes, booster boxes are ideal for collectors, but they're mostly touching or well above $100. Booster bundles have six boosters per box for just north of $20, with Black Friday bringing price points down further. Here's what I'm betting on:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/ak7g0W?object_uuid=4866ebd6-6a8d-4bb4-a2e1-614540c4fe85&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Stellar Crown booster bundle</a></li></ul></div><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violet-elite"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Elite ">Pokémon TCG Elite Trainer Boxes</h2></p><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violet-stella"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Stella">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Stellar Crown Build &amp; Battle</h2></p><p id="pokmon-iono-premium-tournament-coll"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon Iono Premium Tournament Coll">Pokémon Iono Premium Tournament Collection Box</h2></p><div catalogid="6d085d9e-2e49-411e-bbed-dfc088fe5390" id="210095"><div id="210095" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon Iono Premium Tournament Collection Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Deck Box? Check! Sleeves? Check! Four foil supporter cards (one being full art) and everything you need for a Pokémon Card battle? Check! These themed tournament collection boxes are a trainer card fan boys dream and a cheap way to get some exclusive swag for your themed deck. Here's what I'm expecting on Black Friday:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QOD0rM?object_uuid=4866ebd6-6a8d-4bb4-a2e1-614540c4fe85&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pokemon Klara Premium Tournament Collection</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/z3b6rR?object_uuid=4866ebd6-6a8d-4bb4-a2e1-614540c4fe85&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pokemon Cyrus Premium Tournament Collection
</a></li></ul></div><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violet-sleeve"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Sleeve">Booster Packs and Boxes</h2></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 13, 2024 5:00 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 5 Returns to PlayStation Plus Game Catalog for November 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-5-returns-to-playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-5-returns-to-playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-2024.1035006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-5-returns-to-playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has confirmed its PlayStation Plus Game Catalog lineup for November 2024, and it includes the return of Rockstar’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">GTA 5</a> in what's an impressive month for subscribers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a post on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/11/13/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-grand-theft-auto-v-dying-light-2-stay-human-like-a-dragon-ishin-and-more/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a>, Sony also confirmed heavy hitters <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dying-light-2">Dying Light 2: Stay Human</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/like-a-dragon-ishin">Like a Dragon: Ishin</a> join the subscription service from November 19.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the same day, five new games join PlayStation Plus Premium: PS VR2 game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/synapse">Synapse</a> and four Classics; <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/blood-omen-legacy-of-kain">Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/blood-omen-2-legacy-of-kain">Blood Omen 2</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resistance-fall-of-man">Resistance: Fall of Man</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resistance-2">Resistance 2</a>. It’s worth noting <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-2-remastered">Soul Reaver 1 &amp; 2 Remastered</a> launch next month, so these classics are well-timed. It's also worth bearing in mind that the included Resistance games are streaming only for PlayStation Plus Premium.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">PlayStation Plus Game Catalog lineup for November 2024:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium | Game Catalog</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Grand Theft Auto 5 | PS4, PS5</li><li>Dying Light 2: Stay Human | PS4, PS5</li><li>Like a Dragon: Ishin | PS4, PS5</li><li>MotoGP 24 | PS4, PS5</li><li>The Sims 4 Island Living (add-on only) | PS4</li><li>Digimon Survive | PS4</li><li>Overcooked! All You Can Eat | PS4, PS5</li><li>Stick Fight: The Game | PS4</li><li>Clash: Artifacts of Chaos | PS4, PS5</li><li>Killer Frequency | PS4, PS5</li><li>Hungry Shark World | PS4</li><li>Chivalry 2 | PS4, PS5</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PlayStation Plus Premium</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Synapse | PS VR2</li><li>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain | PS4, PS5</li><li>Blood Omen 2 | PS4, PS5</li><li>Resistance: Fall of Man</li><li>Resistance 2</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft: Remastered and Warcraft II: Remastered announced for PC, now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/warcraft-remastered-and-warcraft-ii-remastered-announced-for-pc-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-remastered-and-warcraft-ii-remastered-announced-for-pc-now-available.1035003/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/warcraft-remastered-and-warcraft-ii-remastered-announced-for-pc-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest bundle includes the full trilogy.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Blizzard Entertainment [149 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/blizzard-entertainment">Blizzard Entertainment</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Warcraft: Remastered" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/warcraft-remastered">Warcraft: Remastered</a></em> and <em><a title="Games > Warcraft II: Remastered" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/warcraft-ii-remastered">Warcraft II: Remastered</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,685 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>. Both titles are available now via Battle.net for $9.99 each. A <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest?p=1863680" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest</em></a> bundle including <em>Warcraft: Remastered</em>, <em>Warcraft II: Remastered</em>, and <em><a title="Games > Warcraft III: Reforged" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/warcraft-iii-reforged">Warcraft III: Reforged</a></em> is also available for $39.99. <span id="more-927439"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of each game, via their store pages:</p><blockquote><h2><span><em>Warcraft: Remastered</em> (<a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-1-remastered" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Battle.net</a>)</span></h2><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Warcraft-Remastered-Ann_11-13-24_WC1.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Relive the original <em>Warcraft</em> tale of <em>Orcs &amp; Humans</em>.</p><p>Journey back to the beginning of a 30-year legacy with the first <em>Warcraft</em> story created in 1994, now remastered with vivid, all-new visuals and modernized controls!</p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the inciting war between Orcs and Humans that shook Azeroth to its core. Defend the realm as the noble Alliance, or seek to conquer it as the bloodthirsty Horde across thrilling faction campaigns or custom skirmish games. Whichever side you take, there has never been a better time to charge into the legendary battles of Azeroth’s greatest heroes in the <em>Warcraft</em> universe.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Rediscover Iconic Sights and Sounds</strong> – Toggle between the classic art and the lovingly updated hand-painted artwork. Take in the full view of epic battles with widescreen support and numerous visual updates for the user interface. Enjoy the classic musical themes, now uncompressed and rebalanced.</li><li><strong>Classic Gameplay, Modern Controls</strong> – Modern improvements, such as health bars, increased unit selection, hotkey indicators, and more have been added to build a seamless experience for a modern audience.</li><li><strong>A Preservation Of History</strong> – Having excavated original concept art from 1994, <em>Warcraft: Remastered</em> includes a plethora of never-before-seen pieces that heralded the beginnings of the <em>Warcraft</em> legacy! Enjoy the lore and history as it was told in the past.</li></ul><h2><span><em>Warcraft II: Remastered</em> (<a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-2-remastered" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Battle.net</a>)</span></h2><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Warcraft-Remastered-Ann_11-13-24_WC2.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Master the tides in <em>Warcraft</em>‘s second iconic title.</p><p>Captain your own fleet in the second <em>Warcraft</em> title created in 1995, now remastered with vivid, all-new visuals and modernized controls!</p><p>War between orc and humans rages on across the seas, and the fate of the world hangs in the balance as the great tacticians of the Horde and the Alliance clash. Only one thing is certain: winning this war will demand unprecedented cunning, courage, and nerves of steel.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>The Tides of Darkness Rise Again</strong> – After you’ve experienced the campaign for Tides of Darkness, prepare to take your honed skills into the Beyond the Dark Portal campaign, which is also included in this complete <em>Warcraft II: Remastered</em> package.</li><li><strong>Rediscover Iconic Sights and Sounds</strong> – Toggle between the classic art and the lovingly updated hand-painted artwork. Take in the full view of epic battles with widescreen support and numerous visual updates for the user interface. Enjoy the classic musical themes, now uncompressed and rebalanced.</li><li><strong>Join the Frenzy</strong> – Integrated with your Battle.Net account, test your friends in <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [410 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> on classic or custom maps that support up to eight players at once! Connect globally with players around the world by hosting or joining custom game lobbies.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WoW Classic Is Finally Getting Fresh Servers As Cataclysm Players Move To Pandaria]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria/1100-6527720/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria.1035000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria/1100-6527720/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527720">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a> Classic players begging for fresh "vanilla" servers are finally getting their wish, with new servers set to go live on November 21 in celebration of WoW's 20th anniversary. Meanwhile, those playing Cataclysm Classic will progress on to Mists of Pandaria in 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard announced the news as part of its Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct, along the way confirming in advance the new vanilla servers (minus the fresh Hardcore servers that are also coming) will automatically progress to The Burning Crusade Classic when the time comes. Blizzard said that just because TBC is already confirmed doesn't necessarily mean these new servers will keep moving forward all the way to Cataclysm (the expansion players who have kept progressing from WoW Classic's 2019 launch servers are currently on), but it's hard not to get some sense of deja vu.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uYGvtbrDiiw" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/uYGvtbrDiiw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">In an interview with GameSpot, WoW Classic lead software engineer Nora Valletta and software engineer Kevin Vigue offered more details on what players starting from scratch on the fresh servers can expect, their thoughts on moving on to Mists of Pandaria, and what the team has learned from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-season-of-discovery-looks-to-make-a-20-year-old-game-surprising-again/1100-6519561/" data-ref-id="1100-6519561">more experimental swings like Season of Discovery</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard is using advances in server technology to have larger realms that can hold more players but fewer realms overall for this batch of new servers. In a departure from normal, there will not be dedicated role-playing or RPPvP servers as has usually been the case in the past, Valletta confirmed. Quality-of-life improvements, like the world buff-saving Chronoboon Displacer, faction balancing on PvP realms, and updates to make the original game's punishing Honor PvP rank system less punishing, will be present at launch for these new servers, as will a ban (at least in North America and Europe) on the controversial practice of GDKP runs--something Blizzard first implemented in Season of Discovery. In a change from 2019, the game's first raid, Molten Core, won't launch for a few weeks. The new servers will additionally have a group-finder tool (similar to one that appeared in TBC, Vigue said) to help players find groups without the need of an add-on.</p><p dir="ltr">A recent, unpopular change that saw Blizzard update the guild interface in WoW Classic and Season of Discovery to a more modern version will be reverted come the rollout of the new fresh servers, Vigue announced. Players will instead have the option of choosing between the more modern UI or its original appearance: a choice Blizzard doesn't want to make a habit of offering but said felt right in regards to guilds.</p><p dir="ltr">"We realized, especially once we saw the community reaction, 'Yeah, there is something really nostalgic about the original UI and how it's presented and what it means for that game experience,'" Vigue said.</p><p dir="ltr">Adding to the sense of we've been here before is Blizzard's announcement that Cataclysm Classic servers will move on in Summer 2025 to yet another "new" expansion, 2012's Mists of Pandaria. Players may have already revisited Mists of Pandaria as part of modern WoW's Mists of Pandaria Remix event earlier this year, but Valletta and Vigue said they think the two experiences are different enough to warrant another go around.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399083-wowclassic2025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4399083" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399083-wowclassic2025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4399083"></a><figcaption>WoW Classic's 2025 roadmap.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399083-wowclassic2025roadmap.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Mists of Pandaria Remix used the expansion as backdrop for players to collect exclusive cosmetics and gain new overpowered abilities that could almost one-shot even the game's toughest bosses, but it still played like modern WoW, with all of its current class design, talents, and abilities. Mists of Pandaria Classic will instead play as it did when it first launched over a decade ago. Vigue and Valletta also raised the point that every expansion was some WoW player's entry point into the MMORPG, and so Mists of Pandaria is, for some people, their "classic." It's an expansion that was perhaps under-appreciated in its time, but players now have fond memories of.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think the fact that MoP Remix was so well received speaks to…how much people love Pandaria as a continent and as an expansion," Vigue said.</p><p dir="ltr">As for the currently ongoing WoW Classic Season of Discovery, Blizzard's more experimental take on original WoW that was released towards the tail end of 2023, there's still some new content coming down the pike. The game's Naxxramas update will arrive later this winter. In addition to vanilla WoW's final raid, it will add new "instanced" content in the form of a new encounter against the Scarlet Crusade as well as the Karazhan Crypts, which Blizzard originally teased back when it first announced Season of Discovery at BlizzCon 2023. Vigue and Valletta wouldn't say whether the new content will be in the forms of raids, dungeons, or a combination of both, and instead said players will have to "discover" what's in store themselves.</p><p dir="ltr">Vigue and Valletta also wouldn't comment on what may come next after Season of Discovery--the "team's always cooking," Valletta said--but did say they have learned a ton from the seasonal server in regards to how to create new content for a 20-year-old game while still trying to maintain its original feeling.</p><p dir="ltr">"We've found Season of Discovery to be incredibly successful," Valletta said. "I think part of what made it successful is that sense of…[the new content] is very much down to earth. It wasn't massive, universe-ending world threats. It's you, yourself, as that character in that world…You're not some mighty fine champion hero who everybody knows and everything revolves around you, right? You exist in the world but the world is the main character, and you're part of that."</p><p dir="ltr">All the WoW Classic news was just one part of the Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct. Blizzard also launched new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/" data-ref-id="1100-6527719">remastered versions of Warcraft 1 and 2</a>, announced a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/" data-ref-id="1100-6527722">StarCraft mini-set for Hearthstone</a>, and more.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hearthstone's 2025 Roadmap Includes StarCraft Crossover, Return To Un'Goro Crater]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hearthstones-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-return-to-ungoro-crater.1034997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527722">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/hearthstone-heroes-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-176391">Hearthstone's</a> next mini-set is a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/starcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-20">StarCraft</a> crossover: one that will reimagine the various units of Blizzard's beloved sci-fi RTS in card form. In addition to this, Blizzard announced an entire year's worth of Hearthstone expansions in one go and a dramatic change to the game's Arena mode, giving players a full picture of what to expect in 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">Yes, Blizzard made the bold move of announcing a StarCraft crossover during its Warcraft 30th anniversary direct--a livestream that also celebrated 10 years of Hearthstone. The crossover is the largest mini-set Blizzard has ever done for its digital card game, with 49 total cards.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LFFB2ysJLTQ" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/LFFB2ysJLTQ" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">To learn more, GameSpot sat down with Hearthstone senior game designer Cora Georgiou and game designer Leo Robles Gonzalez ahead of the direct to talk about what it was like adapting StarCraft into card game form, the upcoming changes to Arena, and all of the expansions coming next year.</p><p dir="ltr">Gonzalez said the development team is trying to be a bit more "adventurous," given that the game is a decade old and its players are eager to see new things. That's one of the reasons it went big on the upcoming StarCraft mini-set.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think we're trying to swing pretty hard here," Gonzalez said. "It's the first time we've ever done something this deeply outside of Warcraft."</p><p dir="ltr">Different classes will be able to use a specific StarCraft hero. Each StarCraft faction will have its own set of cards, some of which can be used by any class and others that are class-specific. Warriors, Paladins, and Shamans, for example, can use Jim Raynor and take full advantage of Terran cards, while Death Knights, Hunters, Warlocks, and Demon Hunters can embrace the Zerg swarm with Kerrigan. Meanwhile, Mages, Priests, Rogues, and Druids can use the powers of Artanis, with a focus on powerful, high-mana-cost Protoss units that can be made cheaper.</p><p dir="ltr">Gonzalez said adapting StarCraft into the card game wasn't all that different from adapting Warcraft (both involve lots of research). The main difference was instead of looking to specific characters for card ideas, the team had to draw inspiration from StarCraft's iconic units. Gonzalez said it was also important to capture that feeling of StarCraft's gameplay.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398546-hsheroesofstarcraft-kerriganqueenofblades.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398546" data-ratio="1.1111715139984" data-width="3679" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398546-hsheroesofstarcraft-kerriganqueenofblades.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398546"></a><figcaption>Kerrigan will be usable by Death Knights, Hunters, Warlocks, and Demon Hunters.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398546-hsheroesofstarcraft-kerriganqueenofblades.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">"The gameplay of it--there's micro and there's macro--and it was really important to us to make sure that the macro of, 'What is your game plan overall with one of the three factions'... does that feel quintessentially like them?" Gonzalez said. "That's not something we had to super duper think about with the average Warcraft character."</p><p dir="ltr">The Heroes of StarCraft mini-set will release in January 2025, but the StarCraft crossover was just the tip of the iceberg when it came to Hearthstone announcements. Blizzard also revealed a full 2025 roadmap with three upcoming expansions, as well a major shake-up to the game's Arena mode.</p><p dir="ltr">Arena, Hearthstone's premium draft mode, has been largely unchanged since the game launched in 2014, but that will be changing soon. In the first half of 2025, Blizzard will change Arena in a big way by introducing two versions of Arena to choose from. Normal Arena will be similar to what exists now but sport faster runs while still letting players flex their competitive deck-building muscles. Another new version of the mode, the Underground Arena, will take things even further. The Underground will include players of all skill levels (in contrast to Normal Arena, which will still use a win-based matchmaking system), longer runs, and a new feature called "re-draft on loss" that lets players re-draft cards and edit their deck before going again in order to up their chances of winning. Both Arena modes will have their own ranked system.</p><p dir="ltr">Georgiou said the splitting of Arena into two modes came as a result of wanting to create an easier entry point for newer players while simultaneously giving existing Arena players more challenge and higher stakes. The mode is currently difficult for new players to dive into because of how heavy the competition can be, as many who specialize in Arena have been playing since Hearthstone first released.</p><p dir="ltr">"It was really to raise that ceiling for players who want that but also lower the floor a little bit so Arena can be a place that is welcoming for all types of players again," Georgiou said.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398547-hs_2025_roadmap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398547" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398547-hs_2025_roadmap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398547"></a><figcaption>Hearthstone's 2025 roadmap.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398547-hs_2025_roadmap.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Hearthstone's first expansion set for the new year, Into the Emerald Dream, will transport players to the idealized, natural version of Azeroth as druidic defenders of the dream battle against the forces of the Old Gods. It's something the Hearthstone team has long had in its "back pocket," Georgiou said, and always knew would eventually be an expansion. It was actually in the running to be released last year, but the team pivoted to avoid stepping on the toes of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a>: Dragonflight's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-dragonflight-heads-to-the-emerald-dream-for-its-next-update/1100-6517531/" data-ref-id="1100-6517531">Emerald Dream-themed update</a>. The expansion's mini-set, Druids of the Flame, will add the faction of corrupted elemental druids to further stoke the fires of battle.</p><p dir="ltr">Its second expansion of 2025 is actually a sequel, a first in Hearthstone history--The Shrouded City. This set picks up where 2017's Journey to Un'Goro set left off, as the explorer Elise hunts for a lost Tortollan city, with a Tortollan-themed festival mini-set coming later. The Hearthstone team actually invented the Tortollan race for the original Un'Goro set (which would later be added to WoW), and the upcoming expansion provided a great opportunity to further flesh out the backstory of the Tortollan and "peel back" some of the layers of the original Un'Goro expansion.</p><p dir="ltr">"To be able to revisit an area that is so compelling that had so much that wasn't explored before, and to be able to look at it in a new light, I think will be really, really fun," Georgiou said.</p><p dir="ltr">The third and final Hearthstone expansion for 2025, Heroes of Time, will explore alternative versions of Azeroth's past, where players will find versions of legendary heroes as players "have never seen them before." That will all lead to an epic battle at the end of time with the corrupted leader of the Infinite Dragonflight, Murozond. Given how much of an emphasis WoW has put on the Bronze Dragonflight and Chromie in recent years, it's a little surprising Hearthstone hasn't dived deep on alternate timeline shenanigans yet. But that's worked out in the team's favor.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think doing it when there is so much to pull from in Hearthstone's past feels like the perfect, pun half-intended, time to do it," Gonzalez said. "There's so many characters our fans love and characters from Warcraft that our fans might not even be super exposed to that are in that thematic bucket. It's a really rich theme."</p><p dir="ltr">In other Warcraft news, Blizzard announced as part of the direct that its newly announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/" data-ref-id="1100-6527719">remastered versions of Warcraft 1 and 2</a>, as well as a major 2.0 update for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-iii-reforged/" data-ref-id="5000-504202">Warcraft 3: Reforged</a>, are all available now.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NHL 25 Adds Professional Women's Hockey League This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nhl-25-adds-professional-womens-hockey-league-this-year/1100-6527746/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nhl-25-adds-professional-womens-hockey-league-this-year.1034991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nhl-25-adds-professional-womens-hockey-league-this-year/1100-6527746/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527746">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2024-11-13T10:32:55-0800">November 13, 2024 at 10:32AM PST</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>EA Sports has announced a multi-year deal with the Professional Women's Hockey League (PWHL) to bring the upstart league's players and teams to NHL 25.</p><p>The PWHL comes to NHL 25 on December 5 with all six teams--these include the Boston Fleet, Minnesota Frost, Montréal Victoire, New York Sirens, Ottawa Charge, and Toronto Sceptres.</p><p>These teams can be used in Play Now, Online Versus, Shootout, and Seasons. PWHL uniforms will be accessible in World of Chel and Hockey Ultimate Team. EA warned that not all player likenesses will be available right away, saying it will "continue to add more" players over time.</p><p>PWHL integration in NHL 25 also includes the Walter Cup--the PWHL's version of the Stanley Cup.</p><p>NHL 25 isn't the first NHL game to feature women, as this <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nhl-22-adds-first-ever-playable-womens-teams-in-new-update-today/1100-6499998/" data-ref-id="1100-6499998">actually began with NHL 22 when EA struck a deal with the International Ice Hockey Federation</a>. Sarah Nurse was on the cover of the following year's game, NHL 23, alongside Trevor Zegras.</p><p>EA's other sports games have added women over the years, too, now spanning EA Sports FC, UFC, and PGA Tour. The PWHL is now in its second season. The Minnesota Frost won the inaugural Walter Cup.</p><p>Beyond the introduction of the PWHL, EA is releasing a major update for NHL 25 this holiday, and one of the most exciting pieces of it is the introduction of the NHL Arcade event series. Beginning November 15 through World of Chel, this is an arcade-style, three-versus-three mode featuring a Big Head mode and power-ups like Supershot and Super Speed, along with big and small goalies.</p><p>The action takes place in a bespoke rink with no glass and no rules. It's not quite like the NHL Hitz days of yesteryear, but it might help satisfy the itch.</p><p>NHL 25 is also introducing the 4 Nations Face-Off in 2025. This is a round-robin tournament featuring players from the USA, Canada, Finland, and Sweden. There will be a dedicated mode for this, and each nation's uniforms will come to the game across a variety of modes. The real-world 4 Nations Face-Off takes place in February 2025, so the update for NHL 25 will likely go live around then.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399082-holidayupdate.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399082" data-ratio="0.56287878787879" data-width="1320" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399082-holidayupdate.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399082"></a><figcaption>NHL 25 gets a big holiday update soon.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399082-holidayupdate.jpg"></figure><p>Additionally, EA is trying to lure players back to NHL 25 by offering free content to everyone who simply logs in between November 15 and January 2. Everyone who does so will get six vanity items for the arcade mode, along with a special pack for the Road to 4 Nations content that's redeemable immediately. Players will also get a PWHL 83 OVR team building choice pack that will become redeemable when the PWHL integration goes live on December 5.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft 1 And 2 Remastered Make Up A New Warcraft Battle Chest, Available Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today.1034988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527719">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Blizzard's classic RTS titles <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-orcs-and-humans/" data-ref-id="5000-6383">Warcraft: Orcs and Humans</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-ii-tides-of-darkness/" data-ref-id="5000-2298">Warcraft 2: Tides of Darkness</a> are both getting the "remastered" treatment to celebrate the franchise's 30th anniversary, and they'll be available separately or together alongside <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-iii-reforged/" data-ref-id="5000-504202">Warcraft 3: Reforged</a> today in a new Warcraft Battle Chest.</p><p dir="ltr">The news comes as part of Blizzard's Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct, where the developer kicked things off by paying homage to the games that started the franchise and diving into what's changed, and what's stayed the same, in Warcraft 1 and 2 Remastered. While players will have the option of playing each game with their original visuals (something that can be toggled on and off in real time) the remastered versions also include new, hand-drawn visuals that help make each game's units more sharp and defined while still retaining their classic feel.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ryZ2jiW95qo" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Warcraft 1's controls have been updated to support modern-RTS staples like right click to move, box unit selection, and a faster game speed. Both games have received various UI and UX adjustments as well, like unit health bars, tooltips, increased unit selection, and a mission select. Warcraft 2 will still support multiplayer and all legacy custom maps will be fully compatible with this new version of the game.</p><p dir="ltr">Warcraft 3: Reforged, the maligned remaster that released in 2020 to negative reviews and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-3-reforged-a-victim-of-mismanagement-pressure-from-activision-and-budget-cuts-report/1100-6494287/" data-ref-id="1100-6494287">reportedly suffered from budget cuts and a rocky development</a>, is also receiving a major 2.0 update today. The update improves the game's environments and lighting, as well as overhauls its UI. It also adds hotkey customization and a revamped ladder system. Those who prefer playing Warcraft 3 with its original, non-remastered visuals will find the update adds high-rez versions for all the classic Warcraft 3 models as well, with players having the option of mixing and matching which assets, original or HD, they'd like to use.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399076-warcraft2remasteredgameplay.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399076" data-ratio="0.56133540372671" data-width="1288" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399076-warcraft2remasteredgameplay.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399076"></a><figcaption>Warcraft 1 and 2 Remastered each sport new hand-drawn visuals that can be toggled on or off.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399076-warcraft2remasteredgameplay.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Gamers who grew up playing classic Blizzard titles may remember seeing the large Warcraft and Warcraft 3 Battle Chests on store shelves that gather multiple games or expansions all together in one package. For the first time in a long time, a new Battle Chest is now available, one that includes the remastered versions of all three Warcraft RTS titles. The Battle Chest will be $40, while standalone versions of Warcraft: Remastered and Warcraft 2: Remastered will be $10 and $15 respectively.</p><p dir="ltr">For those who don't need all the new bells and whistles included in the remasters, the original versions of Warcraft 1 and 2 are available together on <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/warcraft_bundle" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GOG</a> for $15.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft finds new chief people officer in health and food exec Sébastien Froidefond]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-finds-new-chief-people-officer-in-health-and-food-exec-s-bastien-froidefond</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-finds-new-chief-people-officer-in-health-and-food-exec-s%C3%A9bastien-froidefond.1034985/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-finds-new-chief-people-officer-in-health-and-food-exec-s-bastien-froidefond<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ubisoft has found a new chief people officer, following the departure of previous CPO </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-hires-ex-uber-hr-director-as-new-chief-people-officer">Anika Grant</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> after a brief </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-s-chief-people-officer-anika-grant-departs-after-2-year-tenure">two-year stint</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. On November 20, "seasoned HR executive" </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://staticctf.ubisoft.com/8aefmxkxpxwl/RdHv3ROuzFvZ82HNVFgSh/1a30edf73780414f954302fa35a11349/APPOINTMENT_OF_NEW_CPO_-_12_Nov_2024_11122024.pdf">Sébastien Froidefond</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will take over the role.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With over 30 years of experience, his duties will include handling the studio's talent and leadership development and global recruiting, along with "ensuring that HR contributes significantly to the company's overall strategic objectives." As CPO, Froidefond will be a part of Ubisoft's executive committee and report directly to Cécile Russeil, the EVP who runs its communications, HR, and legal departments.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the announcement, Ubisoft notes his prior work "demonstrated his versatility and impact across diverse industries—whether in sectors with long, innovation-driven investment cycles, or in fast-paced environments requiring operational agility." Previously, Froidefond worked in dairy and healthcare at companies such as Lactalis Americas and Sanofi, where he managed their respective HR departments across multiple countries.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">His hiring marks the newest executive shakeup for Ubisoft this year. In April, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-appoints-c-cile-russeil-as-new-executive-vp">Russeil</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was appointed to her current position after previously operating as its chief legal advisor since 1995. That same month, publishing VP </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-appoints-publishing-vp-brenda-panagrossi-as-general-manager-for-us-market">Brenda Panagrossi</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was made general manager for its larger United States team.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Froidefond's predecessor, Grant, was brought on shortly after reports surfaced of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/new-allegations-show-the-cycle-of-abuse-and-misconduct-runs-deep-at-ubisoft">harassment and other inappropriate conduct</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> from high-level Ubisoft workers. Ubisoft then promised to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/ubisoft-undertook-profound-actions-to-address-studio-culture-concerns-says-ceo">improve its culture</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and she was said to be "instrumental" in that process.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He joins Ubisoft at an equally tumultuous time: not only is the company facing a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-tencent-and-the-guillemot-family-considering-ubisoft-buyout">potential buyout</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> between Tencent and it longtime owners, the Guillemot family, workers at its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/ubisoft-employees-in-france-called-to-strike-over-return-to-office-mandate">France</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-s-italian-staff-join-french-peers-in-striking-return-to-office-mandate">Milan</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> offices have recently gone on strike over its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-is-calling-devs-back-into-the-office-for-three-days-a-week">return-to-office mandates</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The studio has also been </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/new-lawsuit-alleges-ubisoft-shared-user-data-with-meta">twice-sued</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-sued-for-taking-the-crew-offline-and-duping-players">recent times</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and is in mid-development on its next big release, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Assassin's Creed Shadows </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">for February 2025.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>