<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 13:36:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeForce NOW Gets Native Steam Deck App]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-gets-native-steam-deck-app/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geforce-now-gets-native-steam-deck-app.1201473/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-gets-native-steam-deck-app/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NVIDIA announced today that the GeForce NOW native Steam Deck application, previously announced at CES 2025, is now <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce-now/download/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">available for download</a>.</p>
<p>It was already possible to run GeForce NOW on the Steam Deck via the built-in browser. However, that wasn't an optimal solution. Even the installation has been streamlined, as users can just download the app from the official website and follow the instructions to install it on their portable device. NVIDIA says that playing a game via its cloud gaming platform can consume up to 50% less battery life compared to running the same game natively on the Steam Deck.</p>
<p>GeForce NOW on the Steam Deck supports streaming at up to 1440p 120 FPS when connected to a<br>
monitor or 4K 60 FPS when connected to a TV. NVIDIA will further improve the GeForce NOW<br>
streaming experience and is looking to add new features, including support for 90 FPS in a future update.</p>
<p>HDR10 is supported on GeForce NOW for premium members (those subscribed to the Ultimate or Performance tier). It works when using the Steam Deck in handheld mode (provided that you've got a <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-deck-oled-announced-reservations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam Deck OLED</a>, since the original model does not support HDR10) or when connected to a TV or monitor. Of course, if you're subscribed to those tiers, you'll also enjoy RTX features such as ray tracing/path tracing, NVIDIA DLSS 4, and Reflex on supported games.</p>
<p>Speaking of games, today's GeForce NOW Thursday also reveals six new PC games to the ever-growing GeForce NOW library:</p>
<p>● Nice Day for Fishing (New release on Steam, May 29)<br>
● Cash Cleaner Simulator (Steam)<br>
● Tokyo Xtreme Racer (Steam)<br>
● The Last Spell (Steam)<br>
● Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon (Steam)<br>
● Torque Drift 2 (Epic Games Store)</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atomfall story expansion DLC ‘Wicked Isle’ launches June 3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/atomfall-story-expansion-dlc-wicked-isle-launches-june-3</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atomfall-story-expansion-dlc-%E2%80%98wicked-isle%E2%80%99-launches-june-3.1201461/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/atomfall-story-expansion-dlc-wicked-isle-launches-june-3<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Dare you visit the dark and lonely waters of the Wicked Isle?</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Survival [416 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,754 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Atomfall [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/atomfall">Atomfall</a></em> story expansion downloadable content “Wicked Isle” will launch on June 3 for $19.99, developer <a title="Companies > Rebellion Developments [78 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/rebellion-developments">Rebellion Developments</a> announced. It will add a new location, new characters, new enemies, and additional leads, weapons, skills, and items, along with multiple new endings for the main game. <span id="more-968115"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the expansion, via Rebellion Developments:</p><blockquote><p>Drawing on the folk <a title="Genres > Horror [622 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> elements of the game for inspiration, the story expansion is set on Midsummer Island. To cross to the island players must talk to the boat-keeper who can be found on the jetty in Wyndham Village. He will give you information about the island as well as your first Lead.</p><p>“Midsummer is located close to the Windscale Atom Plant and as a result the levels of infection in both the people and environment are higher than on the mainland,” explained Rebellion Developments head of design Ben Fisher. “You are going to meet new enemy factions including pirate bandits and infected druids. To help you survive there are new weapons to be found on the island including a devastating Blunderbuss shotgun, a new bow, cutlass, daggers and the Beekeeper’s Staff. You will also be able to acquire new skills which will aid you on your quest as well as an upgraded metal detector which will enable you find even more loot caches.”</p><p>The Leads you uncover in “Wicked Isle” will open a variety of story treads, some of which create new potential endings for the main <em>Atomfall</em> game.</p><p>Included in the Deluxe Edition and in the Deluxe Upgrade Pack, and available to purchase separately when released ($19.99), “Wicked Isle” will be available June 3. Game Pass subscribers will benefit from a 10 percent discount.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Atomfall</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,553 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,259 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,028 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,988 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,254 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/801800/Atomfall/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/atomfall" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/atomfall/9nc4wdl5kzbl" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>. It is also available via Game Pass.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/atomfall/may-29-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>DLC “Wicked Island” Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Atomfall - Wicked Isle DLC Trailer | Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PC, PS5 &amp; PS4" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5HdforNUuuE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_968116"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact demo launches May 30 for PC, later for PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-demo-launches-may-30-for-pc-later-for-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-demo-launches-may-30-for-pc-later-for-ps5.1201455/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-demo-launches-may-30-for-pc-later-for-ps5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Six characters, plus Battle and Training modes.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bushiroad Games [91 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bushiroad/bushiroad-games">Bushiroad Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Eighting [90 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/colopl/eighting">Eighting</a> will release a demo for fighting game <em><a title="Games > Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact">Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact</a></em> on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20250530T0100" target="_blank">May 30 at 10:00 JST</a> for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,254 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2456420/HUNTERHUNTER_NENIMPACT/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and at a later date for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,553 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, the companies <a href="https://twitter.com/hunterNI_games/status/1928016479737500097" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-968097"></span></p><p>As <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-demo-for-ps5-pc-launches-in-may">previously announced</a>, the demo will feature playable characters Gon, Killua, Leorio, Kurapika, Hisoka, and Netero, as well as access to both Battle and Training modes.</p><p><em>Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact</em> is due out for PlayStation 5, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2456420/HUNTERHUNTER_NENIMPACT/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 17.</p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These Doom: The Dark Ages Guitars Will Have You Ready To Conquer Hell]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-doom-the-dark-ages-guitars-will-have-you-ready-to-conquer-hell/1100-6531901/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/these-doom-the-dark-ages-guitars-will-have-you-ready-to-conquer-hell.1201431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-doom-the-dark-ages-guitars-will-have-you-ready-to-conquer-hell/1100-6531901/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531901">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Doom: The Dark Ages launched earlier this month, and if you've already finished the Doom Slayer's prequel journey through Hell and a bizarre cosmic dimension, you don't have to stop ripping and/or tearing just yet. Bethesda and Kramer Guitars have partnered to create three guitars based on the game, and they're every bit as flashy and intense as the Slayer--but you'll have to be lucky to get one. </p><p>The three guitars, which appear to be functionally identical and sport different Doom-related visual designs, are classic Kramer, featuring a Floyd Rose bridge and a single humbucker. The brand was well known in the '80s for its shred-friendly axes, and the aesthetic certainly pairs well with a game as violent and over the top as Doom. </p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4503506-doom-kramer.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4503506" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4503506-doom-kramer.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4503506"></a><figcaption>Glowing eyes not included</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4503506-doom-kramer.jpg"></figure><p>"The unique designs were carefully applied with multiple layers of paint across several weeks, and each focus on one of the powerful weapons in your arsenal: the Atlan, Serrat the Dragon, and the Doom Slayer himself," reads the <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/29/doom-kramer-guitars-giveaway/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">official announcement</a>. They were created by illustrator Luke Preece, whose other work includes Gears of War: E-Day and art for bands like blink-182 and Metallica. </p><p>Now comes the bittersweet part: You can't buy these guitars. Instead, Xbox will be giving them away via its Instagram accounts, with residents from the US, Canada, the UK, France, Germany, Austria, and the Netherlands eligible to win. Alongside the three guitars, you can win a copy of Doom: The Dark Ages, the game's collector's edition, or special-edition Xbox controllers. </p><p>Doom: The Dark Ages is a great addition to the legendary series, focusing on brutal counter-attacks and close-quarters chaos. In our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/doom-the-dark-ages-review/1900-6418361/" data-ref-id="1900-6418361">Doom: The Dark Ages review</a>, Alessandro Barbosa called it "a finally tuned adventure that delivers the power fantasy of ripping and tearing through thousands of demons without losing an underlying complexity that makes each encounter engaging to blast through." For more on Kramer Guitars, check out this <a href="https://www.sweetwater.com/store/detail/84HotDog--kramer-the-84-hot-dogger-electric-guitar-mustard-yellow-sweetwater-exclusive" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">hot dog monstrosity</a>, which Sweetwater has mercifully stopped offering. </p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian government call out new Russian-made Steam release as Kremlin propaganda]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ukrainian-government-call-out-new-russian-made-steam-release-as-kremlin-propaganda</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ukrainian-government-call-out-new-russian-made-steam-release-as-kremlin-propaganda.1201425/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ukrainian-government-call-out-new-russian-made-steam-release-as-kremlin-propaganda<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Devs talk up their military connections</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Zarobana Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The Ukrainian government-run Center for Countering Disinformation have <a href="https://cpd.gov.ua/en/results/rf-en/how-russia-militarizes-youth-through-computer-games/%22%22">released a warning</a> about a new free-to-play shooter, Squad 22: ZOV, which they say is a blaring propaganda instrument for the Russian military that "mythologises" the country's invasion and bombardment of Ukraine since 2022. The accusation actually dates back to February this year, but it has resurfaced and picked up pace online now that Squad 22 is actually on sale via Steam. Valve have yet to comment. </p> <!--more-->
<p>Squad 22: ZOV certainly makes no secret of its affiliations. According to the Steam page, it's "designed with insights from Russian veterans and active soldiers" and "is officially recommended by the Russian Military for use as a basic infantry tactic manual for cadet and Yunarmy training" - Yunarmy being short for Russia's state-funded Young Army Cadets National Movement. </p>
<p>On the <a href="https://squad22.online/gameteam/">official website</a>, it's further described as being "developed with information support by The Main Military-Political Directorate of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation". Developers SPN Studio cite several military consultants, including a soldier who fought in the "SMO region" between 2014 and 2024 -  SMO being short for "Special Military Operation", the Putin regime's cute little safeword for their perverse and stupid invasion, which has led to hundreds of thousands of deaths on both sides.</p>
<p>The developers have responded to the accusations of being stooges for the Russian military on <a href="https://x.com/AlexanderT68010">Xitter</a>. They appear to be enjoying the adverse reaction, predictably describing it as "free marketing" and inviting people to "put our team on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Myrotvorets">Mirotvorets</a>", the online repository of "enemies of Ukraine" set up by Ukrainian politician Georgy Tuka back in 2014. They also post a fair bit in support of Russia's assault. Of Ukrainian president Volodymyr Zelenskyy's recent declaration that Ukraine has no plans to capitulate to Russia, the developers comment snidely: "meaning, we will have a lot of content to make more missions in our game".</p>
<p>All of which makes me wonder what, exactly, Valve's policy is towards naked state-backed propaganda games on Steam, of which there are more than a few. According to the developer Twitter feed, Squad 22: ZOV <a href="https://x.com/AlexanderT68010/status/1922915188577030147">passed Steam moderation on 15th May</a>. For all the bragging about Russian heroism on social media, the game's creators strike a timid stance on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3573040/Squad_22_ZOV/">the Steam page</a>, promising only to "delve into the complexities of the 2014 and 2022-2024 events" and "gain insight into the perspectives of those who lived through these periods, understanding how these events shaped their lives and opinions". I wonder how much, if at all, they had to tweak that wording to satisfy Valve's moderators.</p>
<p>Valve don't explicitly prohibit state-sponsored propaganda on their <a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/steamdirect/">Steamworks submission page</a>, though they do prohibit hate speech, "libelous or defamatory statements", "content that violates the laws of any jurisdiction in which it will be available", and "content that is patently offensive or intended to shock or disgust viewers". If they did ban games that explicitly advance the interests of national militaries, they presumably would have taken down the page for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/203290/Americas_Army_Proving_Grounds/">America's Army: Proving Grounds</a> - the official FPS of the US Army, live on Steam since 2015 - and possibly also Pandemic's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4520/Full_Spectrum_Warrior/">Full Spectrum Warrior</a>, a 2004 tactics game which describes the U.S. Army as "the most powerful ground force in the entire world" and began life as a military training aid.</p>
<p>I make those last comparisons not for the sake of some whatabouttery argument that every side is as bad as the other - amongst the hairs we might split, neither <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/full-spectrum-warrior">Full Spectrum Warrior</a> nor <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/americas-army-proving-grounds">America's Army: Proving Grounds</a> is explicitly set in an on-going war, with the prospect of DLC obnoxiously riding on the delaying of a peace settlement - but simply as a reminder that connections between military organisations and the video games industry run deep. Squad 22: ZOV is a real piece of work, but it's far from an anomaly.</p>
<p>I've emailed Valve for comment and will update this piece as and when I receive one. In the meantime, perhaps you'd like to play <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2362070/Hollow_Home/">the demo for Hollow Home</a>, a Ukrainian-made RPG about the occupation of Mariupol, or check out Frogwares' <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sinking-city-remastered-gets-a-surprise-launch-with-a-50-discount-on-steam">recent remaster of The Sinking City</a>, or have a browse of <a href="https://indiecup.net/">the winning entries to last week's Indie Cup Ukraine competition</a>. Thanks to <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/27/russian-army-backed-military-propaganda-game-squad-22-zov-listed-on-steam">Game Informer</a> for passing this on.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Look, I Appreciate What The Ninja Turtles Tactics Game Is Trying To Do]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-tmnt-tactical-takedown-impressions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/look-i-appreciate-what-the-ninja-turtles-tactics-game-is-trying-to-do.1201419/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-tmnt-tactical-takedown-impressions<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tactical Takedown</em> came out last week and, being a turn-based tactics game, <a href="https://aftermath.site/strategy-game-turn-based-tactics-movement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I was both personally and professionally obligated</a> to try it out.</p><p>How does a series based on <em>TMNT</em>, which famously features loads of melee combat against hordes of shitty enemies, work in a tactics game, a genre usually known for cover, guns and careful planning? It embraces the chaos, asking you to take control of turn-based ninja turtles and spend a whole level running around slashing and smashing things.</p><p>To make things a little spicier than just an endless grind of close-quarters combat, <em>Tactical Takedown</em> has what I can best describe as a continually collapsing landscape, where sections of the map will disappear while others appear ahead of you. It's important to note that the game does this regardless of where you are; you don't trigger the collapse, it just happens to you in the middle of a fight, with the idea (I assume) being it continually ushers you through a level as though you were flying through a stage<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teenage_Mutant_Ninja_Turtles_(arcade_game)" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> from Konami's classic 1989 beat-em-up</a>.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Tactical Takedown - Official Launch Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/S0Ab1XckSRM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>It makes the game breathless in its own turn-based way, as you can never just bunker down behind cover and get in a leisurely shootout. Since you're always taking damage (it's melee combat against a <em>lot </em>of bad guys, you can't avoid it) you have to always be moving to kill enemies and always be jumping to grab health items and always be thinking and always worrying about the impending collapse of the tiles you're currently standing on. I dig the idea! Any attempt to try something fresh with an established genre like this should be applauded, because as you might expect given how many turn-based games are called "<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=xcom+like&amp;rlz=1C1CHBF_en-GBAU1030AU1030&amp;oq=xcom+like&amp;gs_lcrp=EgZjaHJvbWUyBggAEEUYOTIMCAEQIxgnGIAEGIoFMgwIAhAjGCcYgAQYigUyEwgDEC4YgwEYxwEYsQMY0QMYgAQyDQgEEAAYgwEYsQMYgAQyEwgFEC4YgwEYxwEYsQMY0QMYgAQyCggGEAAYsQMYgAQyDQgHEAAYgwEYsQMYgAQyEwgIEC4YgwEYxwEYsQMY0QMYgAQyCggJEAAYsQMYgATSAQgxMDgzajBqN6gCALACAA&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">XCOM-like</a>", innovation can sometimes be in short supply.</p><p>In this particular game's case, though...this is not what I play these kinds of games for. I am a languid gamer, an enjoyer of turn-based games for the serenity and contemplation they allow, and the amount of stuff <em>Tactical Takedown</em> was throwing in my face the entire time was just too much, too damn stressful. It often felt overwhelming in ways that I am actively trying to avoid with this genre, yet which in turn felt wasted on a game where everyone had to wait their turn instead of just <em>going at it</em>. </p><p>Not helping things are a lack of variety once the game's basics are laid out to you in the first couple of levels, and a few too many cut corners in terms of presentation. I'm not demanding AAA standards from my low-fi tactics games, but for something with a half-decent license, and which is drawing inspiration from one of the best-looking video games of the late 80s, the static visuals--the game looks more like a tabletop experience, with animation in short supply--were a little disappointing.</p><p>I get the design lure of bringing one game or genre's vibe into another--<a href="https://stonehandgames.com/the-great-air-race/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I've literally done this myself!</a>--and appreciate there may be many others who are far less precious about their genre expectations than I, but for me, here, the two just weren't a great fit, no mater how interesting the foundational idea might have been.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/ea-black-panther-canceled-layoffs"><h3>Another Day, Another Round Of Layoffs At EA</h3></a><p>Black Panther is canceled, and workers (once again) suffer the consequences</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/parrying-good"><h3>Parrying Is The Best Thing In Video Games</h3></a><p>Everybody’s gangsta until somebody parries your bullshit</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign And Twitch Release Exclusive Launch-Event Rewards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-and-twitch-release-exclusive-launch-event-rewards/1100-6531895/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-and-twitch-release-exclusive-launch-event-rewards.1201404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-and-twitch-release-exclusive-launch-event-rewards/1100-6531895/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531895">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign/" data-ref-id="5000-654963">Elden Ring Nightreign </a>is just hours away from release, and streaming platform Twitch is beginning to make assets and rewards available to viewers, streamers, and content creators.</p><p>By simply watching Nightreign streams, you can earn a new global emote that can be used in any creator's chat. For those who like to clip important, funny, tense, or interesting moments in their favorite streamer's content, a unique badge is available. A second, separate badge is available for streamers who join up and make use of Twitch's streaming together feature, where creators can join their Twitch chats and collaborate on stream.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4503447-nightreign-twitch-drops%281%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4503447" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4503447-nightreign-twitch-drops%281%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4503447"></a><figcaption>The three Twitch rewards for the Nightreign launch event.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4503447-nightreign-twitch-drops%281%29.jpg"></figure><p>You can earn the badges between May 29 and June 6 by doing the following:</p><ul><li>Recluse badge: Stream together for 15 minutes</li><li>Wylder badge: Download and share an Elden Ring clip</li><li>Wylder emote: A new global emote available to everyone on Twitch</li></ul><p>Alongside these assets, Twitch has also created a global death-counter widget for streamers. Content creators can find the widget and installation instructions on the Twitch <a href="https://dashboard.twitch.tv/extensions/k8d4i8j71c32z1nyqg7j39bkvl4zoj" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">creator dashboard</a>. When installed, it will show how many times Twitch streamers have collectively died in Nightreign. It does run on an honor system, so don't add a death to the counter unless you've actually died. The widget can also be toggled to show how many nights have been survived.</p><p>While it's only a few hours until you can get your hands on the game, reviews have already shown a favorable response to the new Elden Ring title. Our own <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/elden-ring-nightreign-review/1900-6418368/" data-ref-id="1900-6418368">Nightreign review</a> sees Richard Wakeling refer to the game as "fast-paced and thrilling" with an "enticing structure" and "climactic" boss fights.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/100905401902076465889?rel=author">Cheri Faulkner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Official" Russian Military game depicting invasion of Ukraine released on Steam as Yunarmy propaganda]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/official-russian-military-game-depicting-invasion-of-ukraine-released-on-steam-as-yunarmy-propaganda</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/official-russian-military-game-depicting-invasion-of-ukraine-released-on-steam-as-yunarmy-propaganda.1201401/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/official-russian-military-game-depicting-invasion-of-ukraine-released-on-steam-as-yunarmy-propaganda<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Includes real-life "historical conflicts".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>SPN Studio</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A new game was released yesterday on Steam depicting Russia's invasion of Ukraine, claiming to be "officially recommended by the Russian Military".</p>
<p>The free-to-play Squad 22: ZOV is a tactical shooter from developer SPN Studio and publisher Zarobana Entertainment and is the only release from either company.</p>
<p>The game has been widely reported as Russian propaganda, raising questions on how it's been allowed on Valve's Steam platform.</p>
<p>According to the game's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3573040/Squad_22_ZOV/">Steam description</a>, it allows players to experience the "complexities of the 2014 and 2022-2024 events through compelling campaigns". In 2014, President Putin signed the Crimea annexation, while 2022-2024 refers to the country's invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>While the game purports to be historically accurate through its basis on "people's experience and opinions during specific historical conflicts", it has also been "officially recommended by the Russian Military for use as a basic infantry tactic manual for cadet and Yunarmy training".</p>
<p>The modern Yunarmy, or the Young Army Cadets National Movement, was set up in 2015 by Putin to encourage young people to join the military. Now it appears officially recommending video games is part of this process. As shared on the game's website, Squad 22: ZOV was <a href="https://squad22.online/army2024/">exhibited at the Army 2024 event</a>.</p>
<p>The game's website also <a href="https://squad22.online/gameteam/">boasts special military consultants</a>, including "Hero of the Russian Federation" Vlad Golovin who commanded a platoon in the siege of Mariupol. This is included as a playable mission in the game, as well as the Russian Spring of 2014.</p>
<p>The ZOV in the title refers to the use of these letters on military equipment to show support for the invasion.</p>
<p>The game also allows players to "rescue hostages" and "capture prisoners", presumably from a Russian perspective, as well as "encounter and interact with civilians".</p>
<p>Incidentally, the developer has also admitted on the Steam page to using AI "as a base for work of our 2D artists and later drawn-over in order to make them genuine art".</p>
<p>Sources told Eurogamer the game presents players as Russian soldiers "liberating" real-life Ukrainian territories, adding the free-to-play game also includes paid content for specific campaigns. That means Valve is financially enabling a military-affiliated project, though it's unclear if the Russian Military is being indirectly funded through the developer's affiliation with the organisation.</p>
<p>The Steam page itself has become a hub for coordinated propaganda and hate speech. The game has a "mixed" reaction on the platform and recent reviews are predominantly negative, but older positive reviews include pro-Russian sentiment and disturbing comments.</p>
<p>A social media account linked on Steam to the game's developer includes a post suggesting Ukraine's refusal to surrender will provide "a lot of content to make more missions in our game" (thanks <a href="https://simulationdaily.com/news/steam-russian-military-propaganda-game/">Simulation Daily</a>).</p>
<p>Further, as spotted by <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/27/russian-army-backed-military-propaganda-game-squad-22-zov-listed-on-steam">Game Informer</a>, the <a href="https://cpd.gov.ua/en/results/how-russia-militarizes-society-through-computer-games/">Ukrainian Centre for Countering Disinformation</a> has already had its eye on Squad 22: ZOV, describing it as "a key element in brainwashing the population, reflecting the Russian government's version of events regarding the invasion of Ukraine and glorifying military service".</p>
<p>Back in 2018, <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/1666776116200553082">Steam stated</a> its approach to content on its platform was "to allow everything onto the Steam Store, except for things that we decide are illegal, or straight up trolling". Instead, its focus is on giving users "control over what kinds of content they see".</p>
<p>Eurogamer has contacted Valve for details on what moderation checks were taken ahead of Squad 22: ZOV's release, and whether the game will remain on the platform.</p>
<p>Valve has recently removed some controversial games from its Steam platform, including a game which described itself as "address[ing] the Israel x Palestine conflict from a Palestinian perspective" that was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/uk-counter-terrorism-unit-demands-steam-withdraw-controversial-shooter-from-sale">removed from sale in the UK following demands by the UK's counter-terrorism unit</a>.</p>
<p>More recently, the game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-quietly-removes-explicit-game-featuring-extreme-sexual-violence-from-steam-in-uk">No Mercy was removed following widespread criticism</a> of its content depicting explicit sexual violence.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune: Awakening's Mid-to-Endgame Gameplay Revealed With Just 5 Days to Go for 'Head Start' Players]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakenings-mid-to-endgame-gameplay-revealed-with-just-5-days-to-go-for-head-start-players</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakenings-mid-to-endgame-gameplay-revealed-with-just-5-days-to-go-for-head-start-players.1201398/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakenings-mid-to-endgame-gameplay-revealed-with-just-5-days-to-go-for-head-start-players<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Funcom asked us to "<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-delayed-by-three-weeks-to-implement-changes-discovered-during-its-beta"><u>let them cook</u></a>," and going on last night's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dune-awakening"><u>Dune: Awakening</u></a> showcase, the developers did. With just a few days to go before early access players get their "head start," <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2470698095" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Funcom put on a livestream</u></a> showing off Dune: Awakening's mid-to-endgame, and a wide tour of the Hagga Basin "to emphasize the size and variety players can expect," including the "lush O’odham, the forbidding Hagga Rift, the tall spires and imposing rock formations of Jabal Eifrit, to name just a few."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Inspired by Denis Villeneuve and Legendary Entertainment’s blockbuster films, Dune: Awakening lets players explore Arrakis in an open-world game for the first time ever. Up until now, even beta players have only seen around 25% of Hagga Basin, so the stream showcased "these huge and diverse landscapes" in all their glory.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Before even considering the vast dunes and dangers of the Deep Desert, players will experience a full-scale survival game," Funcom teased.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"They will rise through the ranks of the Atreides or Harkonnen; build powerful strongholds; brave Imperial Testing Stations; craft advanced schematics; explore and harvest in a variety of vehicles, and much, much more." Furthermore, the "Landsraad feature allows anyone to contribute in the effort to impact their entire faction, whether they prefer PvE or PvP."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dune: Awakening is an open-world survival MMO set on the most dangerous planet in the universe. You'll learn to survive the desert by learning the ways of the Fremen, and expand your potential through combat, spice, building, and trade. It's set to release on June 10, 2025, on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X and S <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-delayed-by-three-weeks-to-implement-changes-discovered-during-its-beta"><u>after a three-week delay to fix issues identified during its beta testing</u></a>. Players with an "early start," however, get to play five days early from June 5.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"As a longtime fan of Dune, it also just feels so good to explore and learn more about a world that I’m quite fond of, and Funcom has clearly put a ton of effort into worldbuilding and lore, even despite taking quite a bit of creative liberty by placing Awakening within a parallel reality and canon than the books/movies," we wrote in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakenings-first-20-hours-are-damn-impressive-despite-loads-of-bugs-closed-beta-impressions"><u>IGN's Dune: Awakening closed beta impressions preview</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"There are little details that have a massive impact on gameplay. I won’t go into spoilers, but this kind of attention to detail touches just about every aspect of the world, including the factions and characters you meet along the way, which should be a treat for any fan of the setting."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, check out details on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-dev-says-its-release-date-is-the-full-launch-and-while-theres-no-subscription-there-will-be-optional-dlcs"><u>the MMO's business model and post-launch plans</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death end re;Quest: Code Z Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/29/death-end-request-code-z-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-end-re-quest-code-z-review.1201392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/29/death-end-request-code-z-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/29/death-end-request-code-z-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Death end re;Quest: Code Z Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Miguel Moran">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-05-29">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-05-29">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>I love Idea Factory, but the long-running Japanese game developer has had far more misses than hits lately. While a couple truly incredible JRPGs make up part of their lengthy list of releases, a majority of their output consists of half-baked spinoffs and undercooked genre shifts that even the most diehard of fans have struggled to enjoy. Amongst all that, though, I’ve always been impressed by the newly blossoming <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/08/14/death-end-request-2-review/">Death end re;Quest&nbsp;series</a>. Two releases in, these grim, gruesome JRPGs come with a unique gameplay twist and a focus on layered world-building that always kept me intrigued. I was excited to see Death end re;Quest: Code Z continue that streak of success, but unfortunately the third time is not the charm.</p>
<p><iframe title="Death end re;Quest: Code Z - Official Gameplay Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1cvAuFb4Mds?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Instead of being a full-on sequel, Death end re;Quest: Code Z is a spinoff story laying down some potential groundwork for where a third full entry might go, but it expects you to be exhaustively familiar with the two prior games from the get-go. I can only barely remember the events of the last two games, leaving me with far more questions than I was comfortable with when hopping into this one.</p>


<p>In a way, the game is built to parallel that lack of knowledge – new protagoninst Sayaka is a blank slate in a strange alternate version of Earth that runs on binary code, the powers of mysterious entities known as Ludens, and the whims of a seemingly all-powerful cyber goddess named Iris. Unfortunately, instead of using our uninformed hero as a way to deliver helpful info to the player, characters hint at important things yet dodge Sayaka’s questions repeatedly. On top of that, the game incorporates a frequent fourth-wall break where the cast regularly acknowledges and talks to the player directly. It only serves to muddy the agency of Sayaka even more, and makes it clear that this game is more focused on delivering callbacks and easter eggs to well-informed fans than it is in crafting a cohesive story experience. It’s a huge departure from the approach to storytelling that the prior games had – two JRPGs that start out as standalone horror experiences before slowly unraveling into wild scifi narratives of AI-sentience and parallel worlds.</p>


<p>There isn’t just a major shift in the approach to storytelling, but in gameplay as well. Rather than the Hyperdimension Neptunia&nbsp;inspired turn-based combat of yore, this game plays out as a top-down grid-based dungeon crawler in the vein of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/03/05/pokemon-mystery-dungeon-rescue-team-dx-review/">Pokémon Mystery Dungeon</a> and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/02/23/shiren-the-wanderer-the-mystery-dungeon-of-serpentcoil-island-review/">Shiren The Wanderer</a>.&nbsp;I was honestly so excited about this switch-up, as I’ve been itching for more mystery dungeon experiences after loving the latest Shiren The Wandered.</p>
<p>For the most part, the mystery dungeon gameplay in Death end re;Quest: Code Z is… fine. Your build options and item variety are pretty limited, but there’s still enough going on that makes running through dungeons pretty engaging. The default difficulty option strips away the item and money loss on death, which neuters the roguelike risk-reward that is kind of necessary in a game like this.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, two specific gameplay mechanics bring the entire experience down from “just fine” to borderline unplayable. The first are Death Ends – these gruesome death scenes typically come with unique art CGs and visceral writing, but they are also your primary source of upgrade points in Death end re;Quest: Code Z.&nbsp;A pretty cool idea at first, but eventually you’ll be forced to grind out missing Death Ends by purposefully dying to fodder enemies or replaying dungeons far more times than I would have liked.</p>

<p>There’s also the Sanity meter – every action you take or damage you suffer lowers this meter, and at zero you can’t see anything and your character begins attacking themself. The only way to restore Sanity is through a healing item you have very rare and random odds of encountering. If you’re trying to die to a specific lower-level enemy for a Death End, you’ll almost constantly die from Sanity self-harm before the enemy can actually land the killing blow. It’s an absurd mix of clashing underbaked systems that soured the entire experience for me.</p>
<p>I’m so into the idea of a sci-fi horror mystery dungeon game, but Death end re;Quest: Code Z just isn’t it. Diehard fans will probably enjoy the focus on character interaction and deeper worldbuilding in this game, but the amount of frustrating gameplay hurdles you need to jump through to experience it all just doesn’t feel worthwhile. I would love to see this gameplay improved and expanded on for a sequel, but knowing Idea Factory’s track record, we likely never will.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Death end re;Quest: Code Z is a major fumble for what has so far been Idea Factory's most promising franchise yet. The idea of a sci-fi horror mystery dungeon adventure is right up my alley, but confusing writing and frustrating gameplay mechanics hold this one back and make it one of the most frustrating games I've played all year.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Gorgeous character art</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Jump to mystery dungeon game style</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Clashing, frustrating gameplay mechanics</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Confusing and uninviting narrative</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Needlessly forced dungeon replays</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2: On the Beach May Not Get Any Additional Episodic DLC, as Hideo Kojima Thinks Releasing This Type of Content Has Become Outdated]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-no-dlc-plans/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-may-not-get-any-additional-episodic-dlc-as-hideo-kojima-thinks-releasing-this-type-of-content-has-become-outdated.1201389/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-no-dlc-plans/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Kojima Productions currently has no plans to release episodic DLC content for Death Stranding 2: On the Beach, as Hideo Kojima thinks releasing this type of content is no longer a trend.</p>
<p>Speaking during the 19th episode of his KOJI10 radio show, as reported on X by <a href="https://x.com/naven0m" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NV</a>, the legendary game designer discussed the possibility of the second entry in the series getting paid DLC expansions after launch, confirming that there are currently no plans for this sort of content, as he thinks it is no longer a trend to release this sort of content. Plans, however, may change in the future in this regard. For now, Kojima-san revealed that the studio plans to support the game after launch with bug fixes and improvements, possibly adding something that didn't exist in the first entry in the series.</p>
<p>During the latest episode of the KOJI10 radio show, Hideo Kojima also revealed that Death Stranding 2: On the Beach originally featured some sort of hair system. This system involved Sam cutting his hair and shaving his beard, which would both grow back as time passed. Players could trim the beard, dye the hair, and so on by standing in front of a dedicated mirror. The system, however, eventually ended up getting scrapped as Sam isn't just a customizable, player-created avatar.</p>
<p>During the radio show, Hideo Kojima also discussed the original concept of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach, which he confirmed <a href="https://wccftech.com/kojima-gaming-hardware-will-ultimately-vanish-death-stranding-2-was-rewritten-to-resonate-more-with-players/">a few years back</a> to have changed following the COVID pandemic in 2020. Initially, he planned on releasing a 1.5 expansion of the original that would be centered around exploring the other continents in a world where flight is impossible. As the idea of DLC became outdated, however, the plan was scrapped, and he began working on a full-fledged sequel that was also scrapped due to the pandemic, and the only thing that has been kept of the original concept is the opening, which was originally meant to be something like a post-credits scene for Death Stranding Director's Cut to bridge the gap between the first and the second entry in the series.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Episode 19 of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KOJI10?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#KOJI10</a> «Let’s Answer Questions About Death Stranding 2»</p>
<p>Hair System Removed, Pre-COVID Storyline, DLCs? <a href="https://t.co/CG2frbVZz0">pic.twitter.com/CG2frbVZz0</a></p>
<p>— NV (@naven0m) <a href="https://twitter.com/naven0m/status/1927303228393148572?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 27, 2025</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach launches on PlayStation 5 on June 26th.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona 4 remake is on the way, according to one annoyed voice actor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/persona-4-remake-is-on-the-way-according-to-one-annoyed-voice-actor</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-4-remake-is-on-the-way-according-to-one-annoyed-voice-actor.1201386/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/persona-4-remake-is-on-the-way-according-to-one-annoyed-voice-actor<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A voice actor who featured in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/persona-4-golden">Persona 4</a> has let slip that a remake of the school days <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-11-best-jrpgs-on-pc-in-2024">JRPG</a> is in the works, mostly because he's frustrated the developers don't want him back to perform as his original character. Yuri Lowenthal, who played clumsy bicycle crasher Yosuke in the original 2008 game, expressed some revealing annoyance with developers Atlus in <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/yurilowenthal.bsky.social/post/3lqad6pjmrs2r">a post</a> on social media that has since been deleted.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"And for those who keep asking, no, I will not be returning as Yosuke for the Persona 4 remake," he said. "I asked. Maybe I even begged, but they don’t want me to come back."</p>
<p>That's not an undeniable signal fire proving the remake's existence, but it is some very billowy smoke. Lowenthal has appeared in the Persona series before, and he was the voice of Eiichiro in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/persona-3-reload">Persona 3 Reload</a>, the recent remake of that entry. So he's close enough to the studio to maybe know a thing or two about what's going on. He's also voiced a certain neighbourhood webslinger in various Spider-Man games over the years, as well as Mylo from Arcane, and absolute sidequest liability <a href="https://finalfantasy.fandom.com/wiki/Johnny_(Final_Fantasy_VII)">Johnny</a> in the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/final-fantasy-vii">Final Fantasy VII</a> remakes. </p>
<p>He's not the only one seemingly snubbed by Atlus. Erin Fitzgerald, the voice of Chie, has also complained of the developers' reluctance to have her return, as noticed by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/persona/former-persona-4-actors-seemingly-keep-revealing-a-new-jrpg-remake-from-atlus-by-confirming-they-wont-be-in-it-i-have-not-been-asked-to-reprise-my-role/">Gamesradar</a>. 

</p><p>"For those asking, I have not been asked to reprise my role as Chie Satonaka in the Persona 4 remake," she said in <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/erinfitzgerald.bsky.social/post/3lqbi6257w22d">her own post</a>. "I am blessed to have recorded as many Persona 4 games as I did playing her."</p>
<p>Hopes for a Persona 4 remake have persisted among fans, I'm told, since the third game got its makeover. Meanwhile, many folks are doubtless frothing at the mouth for a Persona 6 announcement, which has yet to materialise, with Atlus instead announcing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yet-another-persona-5-spinoff-is-launching-next-month-this-time-a-gacha-game-with-a-new-group-of-phantom-thieves">yet another Persona 5 spinoff</a> earlier this month. </p>
<p>Whether a remake is strictly necessary is another thing. A PC remaster of Persona 4 came out in 2020 in the form of Persona 4 Golden, which our Edwin called "a twisting tale of dreams gone rogue in a town sapped of purpose" in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/persona-4-golden-review">his review</a>. If you want a second opinion, my cousin - who just phoned me to chat and who delayed this article from being written by at least one hour - instructed me to review all Persona games with the following single-sentence summary: "Too much text." And you know what? I might agree. 100 hours to complete a game? Please. I barely think I have 100 hours left to live.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2 Is Probably Further Away Than You Hope]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2-is-probably-further-away-than-you-hope/1100-6531896/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2-is-probably-further-away-than-you-hope.1201374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2-is-probably-further-away-than-you-hope/1100-6531896/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531896">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Earlier this week, CD Projekt Red confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2-is-officially-the-2077-sequels-name-at-least-for-now/1100-6531871/" data-ref-id="1100-6531871">the Cyberpunk 2077 sequel is now in pre-production</a>. For the moment, the project is also being internally called <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6526333/">Cyberpunk 2</a>. However, the newfound foreword momentum doesn't mean that Cyberpunk 2 will be arriving anytime soon. CDPR co-CEO Michał Nowakowski has indicated that the sequel may be years away from release.</p><p>"Our journey from the pre-production to the final release date takes four to five years on average," Nowakowski said during <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/-nOVGBRC3N0?si=MjhFgWy8svAGR2X4&amp;t=1268" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CD Projekt Red's investor presentation</a> (via <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/cyberpunk/asked-about-cyberpunk-2-release-date-cdpr-boss-reiterates-our-journey-from-the-pre-production-to-the-final-release-takes-4-to-5-years-on-average-but-each-project-is-unique/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GamesRadar</a>). "Having said that, and keeping in mind that each project is unique and there are many variables that influence the final outcome, I will not lead you into specific years."</p><p>If that leads Cyberpunk 2 to a 2030 or 2031 release date, that means it would arrive a decade or longer after <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/cyberpunk-2077-review/1900-6417622/" data-ref-id="1900-6417622">Cyberpunk 2077</a> was released. It's also likely to fall in the next generation of consoles, presumably on PlayStation 6 and whatever comes after Xbox Series X|S.</p><p>The bulk of CDPR's resources currently appears to be focused on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-witcher-4-release-date-trailer-news/2900-5228/" data-ref-id="2900-5228">The Witcher 4</a>, which only started pre-production late last year. CD Projekt Red North America is working on Cyberpunk 2, and a recent job posting for the game suggested that the developer wants the sequel to have "<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cd-projekt-red-wants-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-to-have-most-realistic-crowds-ever/1100-6529613/" data-ref-id="1100-6529613">the most-realistic crowds ever</a>."</p><p>Mike Pondsmith--the creator of the Cyberpunk franchise--isn't directly working on Cyberpunk 2. But Pondsmith has disclosed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-will-feature-a-second-city/1100-6531705/" data-ref-id="1100-6531705">there will be a second city featured in the sequel</a> beyond Night City, the setting of the first game.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-on-switch-2-cd-projekt-acknowledges-development-challenges/1100-6531129/" data-ref-id="1100-6531129">Cyberpunk 2077 Ultimate Edition</a> will be <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-nintendo-switch-2-launch-game/2900-6401/" data-ref-id="2900-6401">a launch title for Nintendo Switch 2</a>. It will be released approximately one month after Switch 2's debut on June 5.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona 4 Remake Won’t See the Return of Another Beloved Voice Actress]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-wont-see-the-return-of-another-beloved-voice-actress/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-4-remake-won%E2%80%99t-see-the-return-of-another-beloved-voice-actress.1201371/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-wont-see-the-return-of-another-beloved-voice-actress/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The rumored Persona 4 remake will likely feature an entirely new voice cast, as another actress won't be returning to voice one of the main characters.</p>
<p>Speaking on Bluesky, Erin Fitzgerald, who voiced Chie Satonaka in every Persona 4 game except the original PlayStation 2 release, confirmed they were not asked to reprise the role. With Yuri Lowenthal also <a href="https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-seemingly-confirmed-by-spider-man/">confirmed</a> not to play Yosuke in the remake, it's looking more and more like the remake will have a brand new voice cast, which wouldn't be surprising, considering the same happened in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/persona-3-reload-review/">Persona 3 Reload,</a> the remake of the third entry in the series developed by ATLUS released last year.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:ww224eri4xcmzrjaoc3ijje4/app.bsky.feed.post/3lqbi6257w22d" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreic3etwz7clazoedao6oc7j3zdz2i6d72xwplcjkymvwhtkthqnzdq" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system">
<p lang="en">For those asking, I have not been asked to reprise my role as Chie Satonaka in the Persona 4 remake.</p>
<p>RIP 😭😭😭😭😭😭</p>
<p>I am blessed to have recorded as many Persona 4 games as I did playing her.</p>
<p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ww224eri4xcmzrjaoc3ijje4/post/3lqbi6257w22d?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p>
<p>— Erin Fitzgerald still on strike (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ww224eri4xcmzrjaoc3ijje4?ref_src=embed">@erinfitzgerald.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ww224eri4xcmzrjaoc3ijje4/post/3lqbi6257w22d?ref_src=embed">May 29, 2025 at 2:39 AM</a></p></blockquote>

<p>A Persona 4 remake has been rumored to be in the works for a while, but an official announcement has yet to be made. If the game is launching before Persona 6, however, it will likely be announced before long, possibly during any of the upcoming not-E3 summer showcases. These include the annual Summer Game Fest showcase on June 6th, of which the series' publisher SEGA is one of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/summer-game-fest-has-record-setting-60-partners-for-this-years-showcase/">partners</a>, and the Xbox Games Showcase on June 8th.</p>
<p>According to rumors, the Persona 4 remake isn't the only project that will bring back older entries of the series to modern gaming platforms. A remaster of Persona 2 is <a href="https://wccftech.com/persona-4-remake-persona-2-remaster-development/">reportedly</a> also in the works, and it will feature not only both entries in the series, Innocent Sin and Eternal Punishment, but also a new translation. This remaster should be released on all current generation consoles, including the Nintendo Switch 2.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Rumored to Be Laying Off Another 400 Developers]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ea-rumored-to-be-laying-off-another-400-developers/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-rumored-to-be-laying-off-another-400-developers.1201365/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ea-rumored-to-be-laying-off-another-400-developers/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, Electronic Arts (EA) <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-report-reveals-ea-canceled-black-panther-game-and-shut-down-cliffhanger-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the closure of Cliffhanger Games, a Seattle-based studio <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-new-studio-led-by-middle-earth-shadow-of-mordor-veteran-kevin-stephens/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">founded</a> six years ago by Kevin Stephens, who previously worked as Vice President and Studio Head on Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor. Cliffhanger Games was working on an original Black Panther game.</p>
<p>Exactly a month ago, EA <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-has-canceled-another-incubation-project-at-respawn-layoffs-reportedly-hit-the-apex-legends-star-wars-jedi-and-incubation-teams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">laid off</a> around 300–400 employees at Respawn Entertainment, too, and it may not be over yet. <a href="https://x.com/eXtas1stv/status/1927820651370271111?t=55cOa-shSeAFKbqb3REK9A&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">According to the Spanish insider eXtas1s</a>, the publisher could be preparing to shut down Codemasters' central headquarters, removing another 400 developers or so.</p>
<p><em>I have learned that around 400 more layoffs are coming at EA, the total closure of Codemasters' headquarters, and that those developers will be integrated into EA Sports (F1) and a new Need For Speed that is already in development.</em></p>
<p>This would be another major blow to the games industry, which has suffered many closures and layoff rounds in the first half of 2025 after a couple of tough years.</p>
<p>EA <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-might-be-actually-acquired-by-ea-instead-of-take-two-according-to-a-new-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">surpassed</a> Take-Two as the buyer of Codemasters on the finishing line. Take-Two had offered nearly a billion dollars, but Electronic Arts closed the deal at $1.2 billion. After the acquisition, Codemasters CEO Frank Sagnier <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-ceo-ea-is-like-our-cinderella-shoe-a-perfect-fit-they-listen-but-dont-force-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">claimed</a> Electronic Arts was a perfect fit.</p>
<p>However, Codemasters suffered major restructuring in the last four years at the hands of its new owner. Three years ago, the Cheshire-based team <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-cheshire-will-join-criterion-to-work-on-need-for-speed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">was merged with Criterion</a> to work on Need for Speed. In late 2023, EA <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-world-interactive-suffers-embracers-restructuring-codemasters-also-hit-by-layoffs-at-ea/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">performed</a> a first round of layoffs at Codemasters. Just a few weeks, we also <a href="https://wccftech.com/codemasters-shows-off-f1-25-gameplay-confirms-wrc-games-are-on-pause/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">learned</a> that the studio won't be making any more WRC games, as the license was reacquired by <a href="https://wccftech.com/nacon-is-once-again-publishing-wrc-games-new-wrc-series-in-development/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nacon</a>.</p>
<p>It appears that EA is positioning Codemasters to be solely focused on making new Formula 1 games. On that note, F1 25 was just released, and you can read Chris Wray's take on it <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/f1-25-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>:</p>
<p><em>F1 25 is a good game, make no mistake about that. With a near-flawless presentation, improved my team mode, and additional features, there's a lot to do. There are a few pitfalls here and there, but nothing that takes away from what is another genuinely good release by Codemasters.</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo updates mobile app ahead of Switch 2 launch, adding GameChat and screenshot upload]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-updates-mobile-app-ahead-of-switch-2-launch-adding-gamechat-and-screenshot-upload</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-updates-mobile-app-ahead-of-switch-2-launch-adding-gamechat-and-screenshot-upload.1201353/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-updates-mobile-app-ahead-of-switch-2-launch-adding-gamechat-and-screenshot-upload<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Zelda Notes still to come.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nintendo has updated its mobile app ahead of the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a>'s launch, including GameChat functionality and its improved screenshot upload feature.</p>
<p>Previously known as the Nintendo Switch Online mobile app, it's now named Nintendo Switch App in line with the change.</p>
<p>The Album feature is particularly welcome, as screenshots and videos taken on a Switch 2 console will be automatically uploaded to the app ready to be saved and shared.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Legend of Zelda games – Nintendo Switch 2 Editions &amp; ZELDA NOTES – Overview Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dmDD7JSfhcE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Legend of Zelda games – Nintendo Switch 2 Editions &amp; ZELDA NOTES – Overview Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dmDD7JSfhcE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dmDD7JSfhcE?autoplay=1" title="The Legend of Zelda games – Nintendo Switch 2 Editions &amp; ZELDA NOTES – Overview Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Legend of Zelda games – Nintendo Switch 2 Editions &amp; ZELDA NOTES – Overview Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dmDD7JSfhcE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Previously, players would need to scan a QR code on the console to link to their mobile device, which was a clunky process. Now it will work just like the PlayStation and Xbox equivalent apps.</p>
<p>GameChat notifications have also been added to the app. This is the new social feature on Switch 2 that allows players to voice or video chat with each other while playing.</p>
<p>Notifications for GameChat will now appear on the app, letting you know you've been invited to a call.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo / Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Another inclusion on the app will be the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/achievements-can-be-earned-in-switch-2-editions-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom">Zelda Notes feature</a>, used in both <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-breath-of-the-wild-walkthrough-guide-tips-4857">Breath of the Wild</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-walkthrough-tips-9343">Tears of the Kingdom</a>. This will include achievements, a voice navigation guide, and all-new voice memories not in the original versions.</p>
<p>Though featured on the app, Zelda Notes will be added on Switch 2 release day - 5th June.</p>
<p>Last week, we reported <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2s-gamechat-feature-requires-a-mobile-phone-number">GameChat will require users to register a phone number</a> to use. The GameChat website states as an "additional security measure" text message verification "is required to set up GameChat".</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-reportedly-already-out-in-the-wild-but-needs-a-day-one-update-to-function">Some Switch 2 consoles are now out in the hands of the public</a> ahead of its release next week, with videos appearing online of the console being unboxed and its initial startup menus - though they're no longer available to view online. However, the console requires a day one update to function, meaning it's not yet playable.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2 is now in pre-production, CDPR confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/29/cyberpunk-2-is-now-in-pre-production-cdpr-confirms/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2-is-now-in-pre-production-cdpr-confirms.1201350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/29/cyberpunk-2-is-now-in-pre-production-cdpr-confirms/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>CD Projekt Red has announced that Cyberpunk 2 is entering into pre-production, ditching its ‘Project Orion’ codename that was used since <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/10/04/a-full-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-is-planned-by-cd-projekt-red/">the project was confirmed back in 2022</a>.</p>
<p>CDPR has to give regular updates to investors, and in the latest report, the studio has now confirmed the latest progress – this follows on from a March update where Project Orion was said to be nearing the end of its concept phase and heading into pre-production “in the coming weeks”.</p>


<p>With the jump, the game’s development is now being branded as Cyberpunk 2, though that isn’t necessarily what the game will be called upon release. Speaking to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/675651/cd-projekt-red-cyberpunk-2-project-orion">The Verge</a>, this “just means it’s another game in the Cyberpunk universe.”</p>
<p>The Cyberpunk 2 team will likely start to grow pretty quickly over the coming months, as it’s now 94-strong (up from 84 earlier this year). This is the CD Projekt Red North America team, combining locations in Vancouver and Boston (which was founded in 2022/3). Separately, the 422-strong Polish team is hard at work on The Witcher 4, and there’s other smaller teams working on Project Sirius and Project Hadar.</p>
<p>Somewhere within all of that, CDPR’s also been producing the Nintendo Switch 2 port of Cyberpunk 2077 internally. That is set to launch alongside the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> next week on 5th June.</p>

<p><em>via <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/675651/cd-projekt-red-cyberpunk-2-project-orion">The Verge</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077's sequel is now Cyberpunk 2, and is therefore about burial mounds, bows and pottery]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-sequel-is-now-cyberpunk-2-and-is-therefore-about-burial-mounds-bows-and-pottery</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077s-sequel-is-now-cyberpunk-2-and-is-therefore-about-burial-mounds-bows-and-pottery.1201347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-sequel-is-now-cyberpunk-2-and-is-therefore-about-burial-mounds-bows-and-pottery<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Project now in pre-production</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/CD Projekt RED</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a>'s sequel has shed its Project Orion codename and will now be known as... Cyberpunk 2. CD Projekt revealed the name change in their <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/media/news/cd-projekt-wraps-up-the-beginning-of-2025/">latest earnings results</a>, according to which the new Cyberpunk <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> has just entered pre-production - roughly defined, the point in a game's gestation when designers, artists, programmers and so forth meet to flesh out the concept, but before they've actually started making anything that's supposed to form part of the finished game. There are now 96 people working on the thing, versus 422 for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a>, 49 on multiplayer Witcher spin-off Project Sirius, and 19 for an unannounced original game, Project Hadar.</p>
<p>The grousing, dilettante reader will object that this is scant material for a news post, especially given that CD Projekt are offering no guarantees that "Cyberpunk 2" will be the project's final name - as they commented to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/675651/cd-projekt-red-cyberpunk-2-project-orion">Verge</a>, Cyberpunk 2 "just means it's another game in the Cyberpunk universe." But the dextrous maven of online news-mongering will notice that "Cyberpunk 2" is, in fact, an extremely compact and subtle piece of worldbuilding.</p> <!--more-->
<p>After all, Cyberpunk 2077 is set in the year 2077 CE. By logical extrapolation, Cyberpunk 2 is set in the year 2. Combine that with a hint from Cyberpunk tabletop creator Mike Pondsmith that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-sequel-will-see-you-return-to-night-city-and-head-to-a-new-city-described-as-chicago-gone-wrong">nu-Cyberpunk will take place in Chicago</a>, and we can make deductions about Cyberpunk 2's setting by copy-pasting bits of this randomly googled <a href="http://livinghistoryofillinois.com/pdf_files/Timeline%20of%20Illinois%20History.pdf">Living History Of Illinois</a>, with its trust-inspiring emblem of a sickly and loquacious bald eagle attempting to disentangle itself from a discarded shield.</p>
<p>Here is what the nauseous avian scholars of the Living History of Illinois think occurred in the years 500 BC to 900 AD: maize agriculture, village-building, burial mounds, pottery, and the invention of the bow and arrow. That's pretty much a video game, right there. But is it a Cyberpunk game? I have now completed a forensic control+F search on that PDF several hundred times, and can disclose zero mention of "ripperdocs", "braindancing", or "taxi missions that are secretly better than the main storyline". If the indigenous peoples who lived on the banks of what would later be called the Mississippi River had access to aerodynes and quickhacking, they kept it on the down-low. Possibly instead of aerodynes they had barfing bald eagles.</p>
<p>CD Projekt have yet to explicitly confirm anything about the new Cyberpunk's setting, beyond saying that they <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-project-devs-want-to-call-out-big-problems-like-homelessness-and-the-wealth-gap-in-cyberpunk-2077-sequel">want to explore problems like homelessness and the wealth gap</a>. I'd email them a link to this report, asking for a statement, but I love CD Projekt like my very own children, and do not wish to encumber them with some abject nonsense. You, on the other hand, are welcome to leave a comment.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today Is Your Last Day To Play Dauntless]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/today-is-your-last-day-to-play-dauntless/1100-6531892/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/today-is-your-last-day-to-play-dauntless.1201341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/today-is-your-last-day-to-play-dauntless/1100-6531892/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531892">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Today is the last day you can play <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/dauntless/" data-ref-id="5000-460162">Dauntless</a> before it shuts down for good. The free-to-play monster hunting game has been around since 2019, but after a change in studio ownership and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fae-farm-and-dauntless-developer-lays-off-majority-of-the-studio/1100-6529054/" data-ref-id="1100-6529054">sweeping layoffs</a>, Dauntless will no longer be playable in any form after today.</p><p>Often compared to Monster Hunter, but more beginner-friendly, Dauntless was generally well-reviewed when it first released in 2019 after just over a year in early access. The game was an early adopter of cross-progression and cross-play, initially releasing across PC, PS4, and Xbox One.</p><p>In 2023, developer Phoenix Labs was quietly acquired by blockchain company Forte Labs, around the same time as the company <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dauntless-developer-is-the-latest-studio-to-suffer-significant-layoffs/1100-6513740/" data-ref-id="1100-6513740">laid off around 9% of its workforce</a>. Further layoffs and a game cancellation followed in 2024, and most recently the company <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fae-farm-and-dauntless-developer-lays-off-majority-of-the-studio/1100-6529054/" data-ref-id="1100-6529054">laid off the majority of its workforce</a>, shortly before it was announced that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/another-live-service-game-is-shutting-down-with-dauntless-going-offline-soon/1100-6529683/" data-ref-id="1100-6529683">Dauntless would be shutting down</a>.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="384628928" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6457516,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Dauntless%20%7C%20Reach%20of%20Radiance%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:78,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/dauntless-reach-of-radiance-trailer\/2300-6457516\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6457516\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6457516\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6457516\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6457516&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6457516,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531892&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;dauntless&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-4,xbox-one,nintendo-switch,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;phoenix-labs,epic-games&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6457516},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6457516\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/3948415-untitled%281%29.png&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2022\/03\/03\/trailer_dauntless_reachofradiance_700,1000,1800,2500,3200,5000,8000,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_dash&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2022\/03\/03\/trailer_dauntless_reachofradiance_700,1000,1800,2500,3200,5000,8000,master.mpd&quot;,&quot;adaptive_hd&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2022\/03\/03\/trailer_dauntless_reachofradiance_8000,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_high&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2022\/03\/03\/trailer_dauntless_reachofradiance_2500,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_low&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2022\/03\/03\/trailer_dauntless_reachofradiance_700,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_restricted&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2022\/03\/03\/trailer_dauntless_reachofradiance_700,1000,1800,2500,master.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1646330340,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="DH5jomTE" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6457516" data-src="/videos/dauntless-reach-of-radiance-trailer/2300-6457516/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Dauntless | Reach of Radiance Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>Originally an Epic Games Store exclusive for PC, Dauntless released on Steam in late 2024 in a move that saw the title being review-bombed on the Valve storefront. The release coincided with the launch of the Dauntless: Awakening update, which <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/331370/Dauntless/#app_reviews_hash" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">players described</a> as a "monetization playground" due to new in-game transactions.</p><p>Dauntless still has mostly negative reviews on Steam, though recent reviews are mixed with long-term players leaving positive memories of the game in anticipation of its shutdown. On the Epic Games Store, where it was available for a far longer period of time, Dauntless has a 4.5-star rating.</p><p>Dauntless will be shut down for good at 11:45 PM PST tonight, May 29. Phoenix Labs' <a href="https://x.com/PlayDauntless/status/1894090939267702888" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announcement</a> of the shutdown says the game will "no longer be available to play" after this point, so it's unlikely the developers are planning to offer an alternative offline version of the game.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Katowice in Poland is aiming to become a global gaming industry giant]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/29/how-katowice-in-poland-is-aiming-to-become-a-global-gaming-industry-giant/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-katowice-in-poland-is-aiming-to-become-a-global-gaming-industry-giant.1201335/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/29/how-katowice-in-poland-is-aiming-to-become-a-global-gaming-industry-giant/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>You might not have heard of Katowice. It was, for many years, the industrial heart of Poland, specialising in steel and coal mining, a place where the natural resources were tapped into, smelted, refined and shipped off across Europe. It has a reputation as being a tough, grimy, polluted area, but in 2025, that couldn’t be further from the truth.</p>
<p>In the modern day, it’s an economic, educational and industrial centre within the country. Gorgeously green and leafy in the late May sunlight, a culture hub that’s been built on the former site of a coal mine is a clear visual and ideological indication of the city’s changing outlook. Crucially, it showcases the transition that the area is undergoing, from its previous, traditional focus on heavy manufacturing and mining, to new technologies, including gaming.</p>
<p>Education lies at the centre of that step into the future. There are now 12 universities based here, 7 of which offer game industry-specific courses. Their integration into the local and national economy ensures that Katowice is a city that is focused on the future. In particular, the city’s leaders that we’re meeting with are keen to emphasise the area’s knowledge and proficiency in the sciences, and the awards and accolades that Katowice, and the wider Silesian area has accrued, including its most recent inclusion in the Top 10 Large European Cities of the Future 2025.</p>



<p>We’re here for gaming, though. We were able to spend time with the Katowice team from Keywords Studios, a global support and publishing company that’s tapping into the local talent here, and locally-based Anshar Studio, whose burgeoning publishing business sits alongside their well-established development team. There are 50 game dev and esports companies in the Silesian area, with 22 of those based in Katowice itself, making up around 10% of the entire country’s gaming industry.</p>

<p>Lukasz Szewczyk, QA Manager at Keywords Studios, tells us, “We work with the biggest publishers in the world, through to small companies, and we support them through the whole development process; testing, translating, and testing the localisation. There’s actually three Keywords Studios entities in Poland now.” I asked the team whether this is a good time to be in Katowice, and Michal Niechial, their QA Project Manager, was frank, telling me, “10 years ago, I wouldn’t say it was a desert for Polish game dev here, but it was definitely behind cities like Krakow and Warsaw. Once we came here, a lot of things started to gain momentum, and other local studios like Anshar started to grow as well.” When you see their brand new offices looking out across the entirety of Katowice and the surrounding countryside – there’s a slide from one floor to another, a cinema room, rows of PlayStation 5s in a shared gaming space and even rooms to take a nap in – you can see that business is good.</p>
<p>They’re tapping into local talent here as well, with many students from local universities working at Keyword part-time as QA testers. It’s clearly a great entry point into the industry, and for many gamers it sounds like it’s almost a perfect job. Lukasz laughs, “I wish that everyone knew that working in QA, testing games, is not playing games!” The whole team are very clear, though, that the collaboration between their company and the universities works both ways, with internships and visits ensuring that they’re helping to develop the games industry professionals of the future, while creating the kind of studio environment that’s perfectly in tune with Gen Z.</p>
<p>Katowice’s transformation is an ongoing project. Beginning in the 1990s, with the fall of communism in the region, and the country’s subsequent membership in the EU, Katowice’s transformation has been years in the making, but that is now being reflected in its accolades, first with its certification as a UNESCO City of Music in 2015, and continuing through to 2024’s title as Poland’s City of Science. Alexander Szlachetko calls this “Starting a new part of our story”, and it’s obvious that there’s a real sense of pride with what has been achieved, and what is still to come.</p>

<p>An all-new Gaming Technology hub is being built, once more, on the site of a former mine – Katowice had a lot of mines – and it’s due to open in 2028, with a huge, 4 stage plan to turn the 31 square kilometre area into a modern and forward-thinking zone for the gaming industry. 200 million Euros of initial investment are going into this area, and they’re already fielding interest from local, national and global partners.</p>
<p>Unknown to me, Katowice is also one of the world’s esports landmarks. ESL, the world’s #1 tournament organiser, alongside gaming platform FACEIT, lead the way globally in putting on some of the biggest tournaments and events in the world. Dreamhack is also based here, a gaming lifestyle festival that operates multiple events around the world each year.</p>
<p>ESL itself is based out of EFG Poland, a massive hub here that’s built around gaming, TV and the wider media, with 8000 m<sup>2</sup> of office space and five TV studios, that allows companies a complete esport production package, from organisation for events through to management and hosting.</p>
<p>IEM (Intel Extreme Masters) Katowice, one of the world’s biggest, most iconic events – hosted at the instantly recgonisable Spodek arena – has happened here since 2013, making Katowice the capital of esports, and a place that fans from around the world have descended on each year. Aleksander Szlachetko, Managing Director of the ESL FACEIT Group laughs, saying, “The only difference is that the tickets to the arena sell out quicker each year!”.</p>

<p>It’s clear that Katowice, and the larger Silesian area, is of huge importance to Poland’s position within the global gaming market. It’s investing, building and tailoring the area to make it as attractive as possible for companies and startups looking for a progressive and technologically and economically supportive area. That’s further helped by the region’s position as a Special Economic Zone, and one which has been ranked in first place within Europe multiple times in the past decade.</p>
<p>It feels as though Poland is ready to become a true leader in the global gaming industry. Proven successes from the country, such as The Witcher 3, Cyberpunk, Dying Light and Frostpunk, are showcasing the talent and creativity that’s here, while also attracting developers and publishers from around the world. Katowice may not be a name that everybody in the industry knows in this moment, but it feels as though that’s all about to change.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Sony Exec Labels Microsoft’s Approach to Gaming Subscriptions as ‘Dangerous’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/former-sony-exec-labels-microsofts-approach-to-gaming-subscriptions-as-dangerous/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-sony-exec-labels-microsoft%E2%80%99s-approach-to-gaming-subscriptions-as-%E2%80%98dangerous%E2%80%99.1201332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/former-sony-exec-labels-microsofts-approach-to-gaming-subscriptions-as-dangerous/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Former Sony executive Shuhei Yoshida was interviewed by the website <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/shuhei-yoshida-warns-subscription-services-could-become-dangerous-for-developers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Game Developer</a> during the recent Gamescom LATAM event, where he spoke, among other things, about the different approaches that Microsoft and Sony have to gaming subscriptions like Game Pass and PlayStation Plus. Yoshida, who was president of Sony's Worldwide Studios group for eleven years (2008-2019) and <a href="https://wccftech.com/shuhei-yoshida-leaving-sony-interactive-entertainment-on-january-15-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">left the company in January,</a> called Microsoft's stance 'dangerous' for developers:</p>
<p><em>If the only way for people to play games is through subscriptions that's really dangerous, because what type of games can be created will be dictated by the owner of the subscription services. That's really, really risky because there always must always be fresh new ideas tried by small developers that create the next wave of development. But if the big companies dictate what games can be created, I don't think that will advance the industry.</em></p>
<p><em>I believe the way Sony approached subscriptions is healthier. You know, not to overpromise and to allow people to spend money to buy the new games. After a couple of years, there won't be many people willing to buy those games at that initial price, so they'll be added to the subscription service, and there'll be more people to try those products in time for the next game in the franchise to come out.</em></p>
<p>Of course, it's unsurprising that he would align more with Sony's policy against adding day-one first-party games to subscriptions. However, it should be noted that Microsoft has stressed on many occasions that they have absolutely no intention of ever removing the customer's ability to purchase games separately from Game Pass. It was always designed as an additive way to engage, not a complete replacement of direct purchases.</p>
<p>Following his departure from Sony, Yoshida also talked about other topics. A few months ago, he <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-studios-ceo-is-not-forcing-teams-to-work-on-live-service-games-shuhei-yoshida-says/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stressed</a> that the man who replaced him as the head of PlayStation Studios, Hermen Hulst, isn't forcing any of the first-party studios to work on live service games.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, he <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-will-be-even-better-than-tsushima-says-shuhei-yoshida/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> that he played quite a bit of Ghost of Yōtei before leaving Sony, and it's shaping up to be even better than Ghost of Tsushima. Ghost of Yōtei is now set to <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launch</a> on October 2.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Debugging Hero is a cute hack n' slash where you tweak enemy stats on the fly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/debugging-hero-is-a-cute-hack-n-slash-where-you-tweak-enemy-stats-on-the-fly</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/debugging-hero-is-a-cute-hack-n-slash-where-you-tweak-enemy-stats-on-the-fly.1201329/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/debugging-hero-is-a-cute-hack-n-slash-where-you-tweak-enemy-stats-on-the-fly<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I've never been so happy to see a spike trap as I was in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/debugging-hero">Debugging Hero</a>. At the start of each combat encounter, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3406850/Debugging_Hero/">the demo</a> for this <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelite</a> hack n' slash hands you several numeric cards and lets you pause the game to view both your and your enemies' stats: health, damage, and durability. You then drag the cards on to the relevant stat to modify it, then unpause to continue real-time combat.</p>
<p>It's a cute gimmick, letting you knock down high health enemies to a manageable number, or kill weak ones outright, or heal yourself. But it felt a tad shallow to carry a whole game, even one with dodges and parries in its real-time combat. Then, I entered a room with a trap tile that thrust sharpened spikes upwards at timed intervals, and realised I could manipulate the timer. I tuned it right down, and raucously chortled like a portly racoon at the bakery bins as it pneumatically skewered my idiot attackers.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Debugging Hero Demo Store Video English" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PYCpZRatE4Y?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Debugging Hero Demo Store Video English</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PYCpZRatE4Y?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PYCpZRatE4Y?autoplay=1" title="Debugging Hero Demo Store Video English">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PYCpZRatE4Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>When I fought the first boss, I noticed I could also slow down his attack intervals, letting me poke with relative impunity for long stretches. You can also mess with projectiles like arrows, slowing them down or reducing their damage. Whether Debugging Hero stays interesting is definitely going to rely on how many new ideas it introduces past the demo - even then, I don't think it's going for something like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/have-you-played-baba-is-you">Baba Is You</a>'s depth. But, being the Adorno to Edwin's Benjamin in the seminal Marge Simpson School Of Potato Critique, I am compelled to award Debugging Hero our most prestigious accolade: it's neat. The game's out tomorrow, May 30th.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA shut down studio they opened less than two years ago, cancel Black Panther game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-shut-down-studio-they-opened-less-than-two-years-ago-cancel-black-panther-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-shut-down-studio-they-opened-less-than-two-years-ago-cancel-black-panther-game.1201320/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-shut-down-studio-they-opened-less-than-two-years-ago-cancel-black-panther-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>To "put our creative energy behind the most significant growth opportunities," says president</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Square Enix</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>In 2023 EA opened a new studio named Cliffhanger Games, led by former Monolith head Kevin Stephens, and announced a new third-person, singleplayer game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-and-marvel-announce-a-black-panther-game-set-in-wakanda">starring Marvel's Black Panther</a>. They've now cancelled that game and shut down that studio, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cancels-black-panther-game-closes-cliffhanger-games">IGN report</a>.</p>
<p>According to EA Entertainment president Laura Miele, via an email sent to employees, this has been done to "sharpen our focus and put our creative energy behind the most significant growth opportunities."</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Additionally, both EA's mobile and central teams will see an unconfirmed number of layoffs - understood by IGN to be less than <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/respawn-reportedly-lay-off-staff-across-apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-teams-cancel-two-incubation-projects">the 300 workers laid off in April</a>. From the report:</p>
<blockquote>"These decisions are hard," Miele wrote. "They affect people we’ve worked with, learned from, and shared real moments with. We’re doing everything we can to support them — including finding opportunities within EA, where we’ve had success helping people land in new roles.</blockquote>
<p>EA are reportedly making efforts to find affected workers other roles within the company, via an internal placement programs. "Our partnership with Marvel remains strong and our multi-title, long-term collaboration continues," Miele told IGN, while also saying in the original email that EA would be focusing on Battlefield, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/video-game-franchises/the-sims">The Sims</a>, Skate, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a> going forward.</p>
<p>EA employees were left "upset and confused" at a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-employees-upset-and-confused-at-return-to-office-mandate">return to office mandate</a> earlier this month. In-person work, said CEO Andrew Wilson in an email to employees, leads to "a kinetic energy that fuels creativity, innovation, and connection, often resulting in unexpected breakthroughs that lead to incredible experiences for our players". Last year, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ceo-andrew-wilson-tells-ea-staff-5-of-them-will-be-laid-off-via-empty-and-infuriating-email">EA laid off 5% of their workforce</a>, (around 670). Despite these recent layoffs, the company now employs 800 more people than this time last year, <a href="http://www.gamefile.news/p/wait-a-minute-eas-headcount-rose">report Game File</a> (paywalled). IGN note this is likely due to EA increasing the size of core teams, which scans with Miele's stated focus on a few select game series.</p>
<p>Between them, Andrew Wilson and Laura Miele <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-execs-earned-60-million-in-2024-despite-layoffs-and-office-closures">took home around $40 million</a> in 2024.</p>
<p>Here's a <a href="https://youtu.be/EGpW3RvZP2o">good video on the EA-published Spore</a> I watched some of last night. When <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/spore">Spore</a> was released, it shipped with some undisclosed dodgy DRM software named Securom that limited each copy to three device installs via a code. If you happened to upgrade your hardware during this time, there's a chance you would have been locked out of playing the game you bought. Partly as a result, Spore remains one of the most pirated games of all time, although whether you should pirate every product Andrew Wilson has a hand in from now until the end of time is the sort of question you'll have to answer yourself.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>