<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:08:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 New Video Provides New in-Depth Look at the Motherboard; GPU Design Is Closer to an Ada Architecture GPU]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-motherboard-video/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-new-video-provides-new-in-depth-look-at-the-motherboard-gpu-design-is-closer-to-an-ada-architecture-gpu.1183200/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-motherboard-video/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new look at the Nintendo Switch 2's motherboard and SoC has arrived today, thanks to a new video shared online which also provides some very interesting data.</p>
<p>In a new video shared today, 极客湾Geekerwan provided a new look at a real Nintendo Switch 2 motherboard and SoC, which have been removed from a unit sold on the black market before release, essentially confirming earlier rumors that suggested it was possible to get a unit way ahead of launch for <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-units-sold-40000/">exorbitant prices</a>.</p>
<p>Besides showing the Nintendo Switch 2 motherboard, 极客湾Geekerwan also conducted an interesting analysis of the SoC, summarized by ResetERA forums member <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-teardown-video.1183101/post-139626573">R3ndezvous</a>, confirming that it is not only twice as large as the original Tegra X1 20nm SoC - 207mm² vs. 118mm² - but also larger than the RTX 3050 Ti mobile GPU. Tapeout year of the SoC is 2021, as annotated on the die, which also confirms <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-node-4-5-teraflops/">rumors</a> that suggested the system has been ready for release for a while. Additionally, the chip's process node is not exactly <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-8nm-soc-ampere-efficiency-goals/">8nm</a>, and in some respects, it is closer to Samsung's 10nm process.</p>
<p>Regarding the Nintendo Switch 2 GPU, 极客湾Geekerwan highlighted how it's clearly an Ampere architecture design, though it seems closer to the Ada Lovelace architecture, with an unusual layout. The YouTuber also confirmed the GPU's 6 TPC, 2SM/TPC, and 1536 CUDA Cores, a typical design for mid-range and mobile Turing and Ampere architectures. What this means for performance remains to be seen, but it's an interesting fact nonetheless that makes it difficult to predict what the console will deliver based only on PC hardware with similar specs.</p>
<p><iframe title="全球首开Switch 2芯片！性能到底有多强？" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kXX9n62N72s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 launches on June 5th worldwide. You can learn more about the system by checking out <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-hands-on-impressions/">Nathan's preview</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[teamLFG Is a New PlayStation Studio Staffed by Ex-Bungie Devs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/teamlfg-playstation-studios-ex-bungie</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/teamlfg-is-a-new-playstation-studio-staffed-by-ex-bungie-devs.1183197/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/teamlfg-playstation-studios-ex-bungie<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>PlayStation Studios has announced the formation of teamLFG, a brand new studio comprising ex-Bungie staffers and "developers from across the industry", and the studio is already hard at work on its first game.</p>

<p>As revealed in a PlayStation Blog <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/05/07/welcome-teamlfg-to-the-playstation-studios-family/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a>, teamLFG "originated at Bungie", but it's now a separate entity that's working on what Sony Interactive head Hermen Hulst describes as "an ambitious incubation project that [he's] very excited about".</p>

<p>Just in case you're wondering, yes, the "LFG" in teamLFG's name stands for "Looking for Group", MMORPG-style. The studio says it's "driven by a mission to create games where players can find friendship, community, and belonging", hence the name.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/destiny-2-teamlfg-playstation-studios.jpg?itok=TGyMDIDC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/destiny-2-teamlfg-playstation-studios.jpg?itok=MSEYX2WM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Staffers at teamLFG have worked on&nbsp;<em>Destiny</em>,&nbsp;<em>Halo</em>,&nbsp;<em>Fortnite</em>, and other games.</figcaption></figure><p>In the PlayStation Blog announcement, teamLFG says its debut project is "a team-based action game that draws inspiration from fighting games, platformers, MOBAs, life sims, and frog-type games". It'll all take place in a "lighthearted, comedic world".</p>

<p>If that wording sounds familiar to you, it's probably because the exact same project was "announced" by Bungie <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bungie-teases-new-team-based-action-game-set-in-lighthearted-science-fantasy-universe" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">in August 2023</a>, and it was still classed as an "incubation" project then, too. Looks like the game may still be some way away from being officially revealed.</p>

<p>According to teamLFG, its goal is not only to react to player feedback "in our lead-up to launch" (although it feels a little premature for the studio to say that when the game hasn't even been revealed yet), but also "throughout live service", so it sounds like this'll be yet another live-service experiment for Sony.</p>

<p>It'd be remiss of me not to once again bring up&nbsp;<em>Concord&nbsp;</em>here; the first-person shooter was a hugely costly endeavor for Sony, but it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/concord-shutting-down-refunds" rel="nofollow">closed its doors</a> within just weeks of its launch, resulting in the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-shuts-down-two-studios-including-concord-creator" rel="nofollow">closure of its developer</a>. I'm not sure yet another live-service game is the way to go, but hey, I'm not Sony.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marathon-bungie-playstation-studios.jpg?itok=YJSd8EUE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marathon-bungie-playstation-studios.jpg?itok=Br3HrOUx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Bungie, from which teamLFG is a spinoff, is currently gearing up for the release of extraction shooter reboot&nbsp;<em>Marathon</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>The new studio's game will also find itself entering a landscape occupied by Bungie's next major live-service project, extraction shooter reboot&nbsp;<em>Marathon</em>, which is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marathon-release-date-gameplay-revealed" rel="nofollow">due to launch in September</a>.</p>

<p>Whether or not&nbsp;<em>Marathon&nbsp;</em>succeeds could well inform whether teamLFG's game manages to see the light of day, or whether it gets canned in a similar manner to the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/respawn-layoffs-project-cancellations" rel="nofollow">two Respawn incubation projects</a> which were shut down recently. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Could We Be About To Enter A Skippable Boss Fight Utopia?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/skip-boss-fight-button-south-of-midnight-soulslike-1851779333</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/could-we-be-about-to-enter-a-skippable-boss-fight-utopia.1183191/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/skip-boss-fight-button-south-of-midnight-soulslike-1851779333<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In a gaming world increasingly built out of Soulslikes, where the concept of the boss battle becomes the central game mechanic, some of us have been left behind. I have always <em>hated</em> boss fights, and while I have no interest in convincing anyone else to agree with me, I have long lamented the lack of accommodation made for the many other people who are already with me. But, sniff the air, something’s changing.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195922" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="390" data-playlist="195922,196345,196470" data-current="195922"><div><p>Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21438.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>I recently loaded <em>South of Midnight</em>, interested to check out such a gorgeous-looking game, and was immediately delighted by the art and the extraordinary performances in the cutscenes, but then—<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/south-of-midnight-game-pass-xbox-series-pc-south-review-1851775149&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/south-of-midnight-game-pass-xbox-series-pc-south-review-1851775149">as Zack warned us</a></span>—I was immediately underwhelmed by the repetitive combat. However, while idly fiddling through the game’s settings to see what was what, I saw a toggle I absolutely was not expecting: “Boss skip option.”</p><figure id="" data-id="756874d3132bc7b0e487eca26639cdf3" data-recommend-id="image://756874d3132bc7b0e487eca26639cdf3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An options menu in South of Might, with Boss skip toggled on." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An options menu in South of Might, with Boss skip toggled on." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Compulsion Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="756874d3132bc7b0e487eca26639cdf3" data-recommend-id="image://756874d3132bc7b0e487eca26639cdf3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An options menu in South of Might, with Boss skip toggled on." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>In 2017, I wrote one of the most controversial articles of my career. A piece for which I received literal death threats, alongside hundreds of more banal insults and wishes for my imminent demise. As someone battle-hardened by Gamergate, it takes quite a bit for the scale of a backlash to take me by surprise, and while I knew it would piss some people off, I didn’t predict the volume. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-origins-tourism-difficulty&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-origins-tourism-difficulty" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">I wrote an article suggesting that boss fights should be skippable</a></span>.  Imagine my temerity.</p><p>There are so many games I’ve never seen the end of (but for YouTube, I suppose), because I just wasn’t physically capable of completing the later bosses. I’ve never finished a <em>Metroid Prime</em> game, for instance, despite it being one of my all-time favorite gaming series. There are other games I’ve been enjoying so, so much, but just had to abandon because every so often there would be a difficulty spike of such enormous disproportion that eventually I’d lose all will to try. And to be abundantly clear, this isn’t just about my incompetence. There are, obviously, a billion boss fights I’ve successfully completed, but almost none I’ve even vaguely enjoyed. For me (and millions of others), they are mostly tedious obstacles that get in the way of enjoying the rest of the game.</p><p>So, it struck me, why not just let me skip past them? Who loses out? Well, it turns out the answer to that question in 2017 was: <em>very angry people</em>. For reasons never quite comprehensively elucidated, my being able to carry on playing a game I like without finishing a specific fight causes them great personal injury. To skip over a boss is, I was told, both a moral and physical affront, and the addition of such an option would very likely destroy video games, if not all of society.</p><p>And yet, in the month since <em>South of Midnight</em> released, I have yet to witness the collapse of humanity. In fact, I’ve heard <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://aftermath.site/south-of-midnight-difficulty&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://aftermath.site/south-of-midnight-difficulty" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">only very few people talking about it</a></span>.</p><figure id="" data-id="b850e513344892e86d89249ce619be82" data-recommend-id="image://b850e513344892e86d89249ce619be82" data-format="jpg" data-width="998" data-height="562" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Fighting a queen in Metroid Prime, and no, I didn't find this bit too hard." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Fighting a queen in Metroid Prime, and no, I didn't find this bit too hard." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b850e513344892e86d89249ce619be82" data-recommend-id="image://b850e513344892e86d89249ce619be82" data-format="jpg" data-width="998" data-height="562" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Fighting a queen in Metroid Prime, and no, I didn't find this bit too hard." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This is not the very first time a game has offered a way past tough spots. A fair few big-name games have had options to let you skip entire missions should you fail them enough, <em>Red Dead Redemption 2 </em>and <em>Days Gone</em> for instance, while many others will offer to lower the difficulty if you’re flailing. But it’s still vanishingly rare, and <em>South of Midnight</em> is the only instance of specifically being able to skip the bosses that I’m aware of. (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/botherer.bsky.social&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://bsky.app/profile/botherer.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Let me know</a></span> of other examples!)</p><p>And it harms no one. Not even <em>that guy</em>, you know, Dave, the one who still unironically says “git gud.” It just lets more people play more games the way they want to.</p><p>But you know what, it used to be <em>commonplace</em>. It was incredibly rare that a game didn’t ship with a suite of hidden cheat codes! You’d find them in the next edition of your favorite gaming magazine, and then type them in to become invincible, or have infinite ammo, and then blitz through the boss that was troubling you. And yet the schools remained open, the supermarkets still had toilet paper on sale, everything was still OK. If anything, not being able to cheat past an impossible boss is the crime against nature.</p><figure id="" data-id="467ec1c843797fd7d49dbda85a1386b4" data-recommend-id="image://467ec1c843797fd7d49dbda85a1386b4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Hazel sits cross-legged, looking worried." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Hazel sits cross-legged, looking worried." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Dave’s face reading this article.</figcaption><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Compulsion Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="467ec1c843797fd7d49dbda85a1386b4" data-recommend-id="image://467ec1c843797fd7d49dbda85a1386b4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Hazel sits cross-legged, looking worried." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>I’m fairly certain this has appeared in <em>South of Midnight</em> as a consideration for accessibility, and that’s wonderful. (It’s worth noting the game even lets you skip combat, although given how dull it is, this seems to fix another issue entirely.) In the last few years, we’ve seen a dramatic change in how AAA games are being made, with the needs of  players put front and center. Few big-name games launch these days without offering a wealth of incredibly specific options, allowing people to tailor games to their specific requirements. Which is all well and good, until you reach a difficulty spike boss fight in which all such amenities seem to get thrown out of the window. Oi, you, be good enough at this bit, no matter your specific situation, or you’re done playing.</p><p>But could <em>South of Midnight</em> be the start of a trend? And no, Dave, I don’t mean I’m demanding that Soulslike games, in which the entire point is mastering the techniques required for all eight trillion bosses, all let me skip over every moment. (I mean, it’d be <em>brilliant</em> if they did! I’d <em>love</em> to explore the Lands Between because that place looks amazing, if not for all the immediate death.) As games superbly copy one another with their accessibility options, could we start to see the boss fight skip button become standard?</p><p>It’s an impossible thing to believe in, because we’re never allowed nice things. The gatekeeping around the topic is about as fierce as anything gets in this hobby, so many Daves horrified that others might enjoy a part of a game for which they have not demonstrated their worth. But I still allow myself a glimmer, to stare through the crack in the wall <em>South of Midnight</em> has offered at the beautiful, sunlit fields beyond.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Passes $100 Billion Market Valuation Ahead Of Switch 2 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-passes-100-billion-market-valuation-ahead-of-switch-2-launch/1100-6531358/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-passes-100-billion-market-valuation-ahead-of-switch-2-launch.1183176/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-passes-100-billion-market-valuation-ahead-of-switch-2-launch/1100-6531358/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531358">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Wario must be proud, because Nintendo is now worth more than $100 billion based on share prices. <a href="https://nintendowire.com/news/2025/05/05/nintendo-is-set-to-become-japans-6th-largest-company-as-it-passes-100-billion-in-value/" rel="nofollow ">Nintendo Wire</a> spotted that the house of Mario hit the market-cap milestone (again) and now sits as the seventh-largest Japanese company from the same criteria.</p><p dir="ltr">It would seem that the upcoming launch of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/">Switch 2</a>--alongside <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/">Mario Kart World</a>--has propelled Nintendo's market cap for this year so far. For instance, <a href="https://www.financecharts.com/stocks/NTDOY/summary/market-cap" rel="nofollow ">FinanceCharts.com</a> shows that the company had roughly a $76 billion <a href="https://www.fidelity.com/learning-center/trading-investing/market-cap" rel="nofollow ">market cap</a> (outstanding shares multiplied by stock price) to start 2025. While we knew Nintendo had a Switch successor in the works, it wasn't until January 16 that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-revealed-launch-date/1100-6528762/">Switch 2 was revealed</a>.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1352744847" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465857,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20System%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:330,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-official-system-overview-trailer\/2300-6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465857&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531358&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;mario-kart-world&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;nintendo&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;mario-kart&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;mario&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465857\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4469338-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/P7d0cUEb.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1743603600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="P7d0cUEb" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch 2 – Official System Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">In February, Nintendo surpassed a $100 billion market valuation for the first time ever, hitting an all-time high of roughly $107 billion on February 19, per <a href="https://www.financecharts.com/stocks/NTDOY/summary/market-cap" rel="nofollow ">FinanceCharts</a>. There have been some notable fluctuations since then. As an example, Nintendo's market cap was $83 billion mere weeks ago on April 23. That date stands out for being <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">Switch 2 preorder eve</a> in the US. The system sold out immediately on April 24.</p><p dir="ltr">While $100 billion is nothing to sneeze at, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apple-becomes-first-company-to-be-worth-3-trillion-heres-how-that-compares-to-other-giants/1100-6499286/">Apple actually became the first company to be worth $3 trillion</a> in 2022. Keep in mind, though, that numbers don't just continue going up like a RPG character's level. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/AAPL" rel="nofollow ">CNBC</a> shows that Apple's market cap is currently below that threshold at roughly $2.96 trillion, while Xbox parent <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/MSFT" rel="nofollow ">Microsoft</a> has a $3.2 trillion market valuation.</p><p dir="ltr">Switch 2 is set to launch June 5 for $450. Mario Kart World will come out alongside the system <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-game-prices-reach-staggering-80/1100-6530563/">for $80</a>, sparking spirited debates about the increase in game prices. Microsoft has since announced that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-consoles-games-and-accessories-see-price-increases-starting-today/1100-6531257/">select first-party games for Xbox will cost $80 beginning this holiday season</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony founds new studio teamLFG from former Bungie incubation project]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/sony-founds-new-studio-teamlfg-from-former-bungie-incubation-project/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-founds-new-studio-teamlfg-from-former-bungie-incubation-project.1183167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/sony-founds-new-studio-teamlfg-from-former-bungie-incubation-project/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sony has announced the founding of teamLFG, a new studio within PlayStation Studios that’s formed around an incubation project and team that was formerly a part of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/bungie">Bungie</a>.</p>
<p>While the team is formed around that core of ex-Bungie developers, PlayStation Studios boss Hermen Hulst explains that it “has also rallied developers from across the industry”.</p>


<p>Furthermore, teamLFG explains a little of what their game will be. Their first title will take inspiration from “fighting games, platformers, MOBAs, life sims, and frog-type games. Players will inhabit a lighthearted, comedic world set in brand-new, mythic, science-fantasy universe.”</p>
<p>Here’s teamLFG’s announcement letter:</p>
<p>“Hello, world. It’s a delight to meet you, and we’re very grateful to be joining PlayStation Studios.</p>

<p>Our studio is headquartered in Bellevue, WA, with team members working both on-site and remotely throughout the U.S. and Canada. We are a team composed not just of industry veterans who have shipped titles like Destiny, Halo, League of Legends, Fortnite, Roblox, and Rec Room, but also industry newcomers with fresh creative perspectives and skills. We are passionate about exceptional action-based gameplay, moment-to-moment game feel, and richly social virtual worlds.</p>
<p>The “LFG” in “teamLFG” stands for “Looking For Group.” We are driven by a mission to create games where players can find friendship, community, and belonging. We want our players to feel excited when they log on to discover their teammates already hanging out online. We want our players to recognize familiar names and to make myths and memes out of each other. We want our players to love remembering that one time where they pulled off That Play that changed the whole story of the match. As we say on the team – dat’s da good stuff.</p>
<p>We will make immersive multiplayer worlds propelled by action games that players can learn, play, and master for countless hours. We want to build our games with our communities, inviting players to be a part of our development process through early access playtests. It’s critical that we stay nimble enough to react to player feedback, not just in our lead-up to launch, but throughout live service as we continue to grow the game and community for years to come.</p>
<p>Our first game is a team-based action game that draws inspiration from fighting games, platformers, MOBAs, life sims, and frog-type games. Players will inhabit a lighthearted, comedic world set in brand-new, mythic, science-fantasy universe. We can’t wait to reveal more.</p>
<p>‘Til then, we’ll do our best! Thanks for reading.”</p>
<p>– teamLFG</p>
<p>This new studio branched off from Bungie last August, amidst turmoil at the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/destiny-2">Destiny 2</a> developer. With Destiny 2 underperforming and a good long time still to go before the release of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/marathon">Marathon</a> – now set for release in a few months from now – <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/02/reports-destiny-spin-off-cancelled-and-the-final-shape-underperformed-but-bungie-layoffs-were-always-planned/">Bungie CEO Pete Parsons enacted a round of layoffs</a> that cut hundreds of jobs and moved even more across to the rest of PlayStation Studios. One Destiny 2 spin-off, codenamed Payback, was cancelled at that time, while a team of around 40 were to form a new studio and continue working on an “incubation project”. That team has now become teamLFG.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/05/07/welcome-teamlfg-to-the-playstation-studios-family/">PlayStation Blog</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EVE Online/Frontier/Vanguard Fanfest 2025 Q&A with CCP CEO Hilmar Veigar Pétursson]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/eve-online-frontier-vanguard-fanfest-2025-qa/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eve-online-frontier-vanguard-fanfest-2025-q-a-with-ccp-ceo-hilmar-veigar-p%C3%A9tursson.1183164/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/eve-online-frontier-vanguard-fanfest-2025-qa/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At EVE Fanfest 2025, CCP Games unveiled plenty of news for its popular sci-fi franchise. From the latest EVE Online expansion, <a href="https://wccftech.com/eve-online-legion-expansion-revealed-out-on-may-27-eve-vanguard-to-get-public-test-on-september-16-ahead-of-summer-2026-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Legion</a>, to the launch window of the MMOFPS <a href="https://wccftech.com/eve-vanguard-will-bring-the-mmorpgs-legendary-betrayals-to-a-shooter-game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vanguard</a> and even the survival-like Frontier, fans were treated to lots of announcements and info dumps.</p>
<p>We were on the show floor, having been invited by CCP, and had the chance to interview CEO Hilmar Veigar Pétursson about all these games to understand what the developer has planned for them.</p>
<p><iframe title="Legion | Expansion Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k1AbLH_uGLw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>It's been more than five years since I spoke with CCP, and that was back at G-Star 2019 in Busan, shortly after Pearl Abyss <a href="https://wccftech.com/pearl-abyss-to-acquire-eve-onlines-ccp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired the company</a>. Can you talk about that partnership and how the acquisition has been going for you?</strong></p>
<p>It's been going great. We've largely just been doing our own thing. They're doing Black Desert and Crimson Desert and we're doing EVE. They are very nice people. There's a lot to learn from Koreans, who are extremely hardworking. You don't have an appreciation for what it is to be hardworking until you work with Koreans. I think we've learned a lot from each other. We've both been doing MMOs very differently, even if Black Desert and EVE Online are probably so far apart they're starting to be similar on some level. Both are very complicated.</p>
<p><strong>After March's GPU-driven Carbon update, capsuleers reported performance being cut by as much as 50% across Intel and Apple Silicon devices. What steps is CCP Games taking to help assure players that performance will improve alongside the graphic overhauls?</strong></p>
<p>Yeah, I think we're largely dealing with a specific use case involving running multiple clients on the same machine, which is something we're researching. Generally, we're seeing a performance increase across more normal use cases. I think we're making good progress in tracking this down.</p>
<p>For sure, we will update our processes to better account for this multi-boxing use case, which is even sometimes called giga-boxing when you go with about 30 clients running on the same machine. It is something we don't really test properly for, and we should both trace down this and update our processes for that.</p>
<p><strong>Have there ever been any concerns about leaving behind players who haven't upgraded their systems in a number of years?</strong></p>
<p>EVE will turn 22 next week. I think there are computers from 2003 that don't run EVE anymore, which is good. At some point, you have to do that because otherwise it limits how much you can push into the future.</p>
<p><strong>Among corporations, there was The Initiative reset towards the beginning of the year. EVE Online hasn't seen any major conflicts in 2025 beyond a few minor skirmishes here and there. How long do you expect this tentative peace to last before another large scale battle breaks out?</strong></p>
<p>It's very hard for me to comment on EVE politics. You need an EVE political scientist to have any informed views on this, but I would say that at the start of the year, there was quite a lot going on, and generally, that does need some time to settle. Sometimes, wars in EVE Online are a little bit triggered around updates, and obviously, we are planning a major update now, which we're announcing here.</p>
<p>Often, when we do updates like that, it triggers something in the ecosystem. It doesn't always happen, but often it does. I wouldn't be surprised if there's going to be a perking up on the war front over the Summer, but I base that only on decades of observing the meta trends. If you were to base it on something that's actually going on in politics right now, I would talk to Peter Farrell in our community team. He has the finger on the politics.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'With Frontier, we have a unique opportunity to experiment with some violent ideas which are hard to experiment with in EVE, which is a deadly serious business. It's a little less serious right now in Frontier because it's a new game and it's not that serious. It's an Alpha, and we're doing a lot of modifications, so we have a unique opportunity to push pretty aggressively on some things we have been hesitant to do on Eve, and messing with the tick rate is one. Based on how that plays out, for the benefit of doing it and the increased overhead of doing it, then absolutely, once we've proven these things out, we will look into what of this makes sense to bring back to EVE.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/ccp-games-announce-new-title-eve-frontier-same-universe-as-eve-online/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EVE Frontier</a> has been one of your big showcases lately. Is CCP Games hoping that Frontier could replace online over time, or are there plans to have both titles coexist?&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely to coexist. I think we have several examples where things can very happily coexist. I remember many people being concerned when the iPad came out that the MacBook would disappear. I think Apple sold the most MacBooks when the iPad came out.</p>
<p>Generally, it has been a good addition to the ecosystem. I think we've seen things like in World of Warcraft, with modern and Classic, RuneScape Old School, RuneScape, and now <a href="https://wccftech.com/runescape-dragonwilds-has-suddenly-launched-on-steam-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">they have released a new survival game</a>. Lineage one and two are also great examples. We have several examples where many ways to experience an IP have absolutely coexisted and added to each other.</p>
<p><strong>Do you believe both titles are aimed at similar players, or do you think there are enough people in the world to populate both?</strong></p>
<p>We have a group of players who played EVE at some point but are no longer playing, and that group is about 20 million people. You basically have 20 million people who are not returning to EVE, and often, when we survey those 20 million people, they are looking for something new, fresh, and enigmatic to get that experience again.</p>
<p>We are largely calling back on the people who played EVE Online at some point and are currently not playing it. We're absolutely not looking for people to switch. People playing EVE Online today should absolutely continue playing;&nbsp;there's a lot of amazing stuff coming there.</p>
<p>But this group of 20 million people who were interested in the franchise at some point, we're calling those back. I think we can see some examples from when WoW Classic came out, where it was like a big reactivation campaign for the game. We were quite inspired by that.</p>
<p>And then we have this lingering impression around EVE Online that, because it's been going on for over 20 years, it's somehow too late to join. Even if it isn't the case, people have this kind of impression, so launching something where everyone is starting from an even base is a useful thing for us to do to see how that plays out with regards to that impression.</p>
<p><strong>For EVE Frontier, you promise a tick rate four times that of what EVE Online currently features. Could this be implemented back into EVE Online, or would that be unfeasible,&nbsp;given how time dilation plays a major part in battles?</strong></p>
<p>With Frontier, we have a unique opportunity to experiment with some violent ideas that are hard to experiment with in EVE, which is a deadly serious business. It's a little less serious right now in Frontier because it's a new game and it's not that serious. It's an Alpha, and we're doing a lot of modifications, so we have a unique opportunity to push pretty aggressively on some things we have been hesitant to do on Eve, and messing with the tick rate is one.</p>
<p>Based on how that plays out, for the benefit of doing it and the increased overhead of doing it, then absolutely, once we've proven these things out, we will look into what of this makes sense to bring back to EVE. One of the key elements, and we've actually been talking about it here at Fanfest, is that we upgraded Frontier to Python 3. EvVE currently runs on Python 2.7, a 15-year-old version of Python. It was about 1 million lines of C++ code and 4 million lines of Python code, and it took 2 years.</p>
<p>It took 4 weeks to get stable, but now we have achieved that in Frontier. We can now look at streaming that back into EVE, which is another big project. Still, we're doing that project now because we at least know that it can be done, even if there's a huge amount of additional work to bring it back.</p>
<p>I would never describe it as EVE 2. I would rather describe it as EVE 1 than EVE 2. It is weirdly more like EVE 1, and EVE today is more like 2. That's why it's not classic. It would not scratch the same itch as the original. When it came out, because it was so unprecedented, weird, and enigmatic, nobody knew, not even us, where it would go.</p>
<p>I can assure you, everyone who plays Frontier, and there are tens of thousands of people that have done that, they say 'what the actual fuck is going on here?'</p>
<p><strong>Looking at this from the view of an American, this is very much American frontierism, the manifest destiny. It's essentially a brand new frontier that you are going to stake your place in.</strong></p>
<p>It's very much like that. EVE had some of that feeling, but the premise wasn't quite there. It was a bit of a metropolis kind of feeling; now, it's very much a survival kind of feeling. Everything is ruined. It's post-apocalyptic. You need to rebuild a broken world, so we lean heavily on that.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'I would never describe EVE Frontier as EVE 2. I would rather describe it as EVE 1 than EVE 2. It is weirdly more like EVE 1, and EVE today is more like 2. That's why it's not classic. That would not scratch the same itch as the original. When it came out, because it was so unprecedented and weird and enigmatic, nobody knew, not even us, where it would go. I can assure you, everyone who plays Frontier, and there are tens of thousands of people that have done that, they say 'what the actual fuck is going on here?''</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>It's going to be a learning experience for anyone, whether they're a veteran EVE player or coming in brand new and learning how to play by the new rules in Frontier.</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. And also for us. I think we're surprised at least once a year by stuff that the EVE online community does. The frequency and degree of surprise we witness from the Frontier community is just a lot. There's a certain amount of incredulity on our part when we see what the players get up to, but they also have much more agency to get up to stuff, being able to modify the server.</p>
<p><strong>Yeah, you have the building blocks there with the smart assemblies. Being able to essentially modify the servers can be a very interesting concept for players to get into. I think there could be the possibility of manipulation if a corporation allies itself with using the smart assemblies to corner the market on a particular resource, perhaps, but we'll see.</strong></p>
<p>Yeah, we'll see indeed.</p>
<p><strong>Are there plans for freelance operations to be the main way new EVE Online players acclimate to that title?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. Everyone who has watched EVE over these two decades knows we struggle with onboarding new people into the game. The most successful way has always been to use the current social infrastructure to onboard players, so now we're equipping those entities, the corporations, with better tools to recruit people.</p>
<p>This is a way for players to start working for a corporation without formally joining it, which often seems like a big step for people. Some people don't want to join a group without knowing something about them. This is a way to achieve that. We have high hopes that this will be the missing link to catch new players. Lots of people come to EVE Online for the first time every single year.</p>
<p><strong>With the freelance system, what mechanics are in place to prevent players from taking multiple jobs off the board and not completing them?</strong></p>
<p>Wow, you're going quite nitty-gritty.</p>
<p><strong>Griefing is always a concern with online games. It's human nature to kind of bend the rules.</strong></p>
<p>I will trust my design team, particularly the designer who made this, a legendary player in his own right, to have considered that while creating systems that are easy to understand but difficult to abuse. We have trained ourselves quite a bit in this. I don't know what the exact implementation is. He could give you the details about how he thought about that, but I can assure you he's very passionate about this particular system.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'I will trust my design team, particularly the designer who made the freelance jobs, a legendary player in his own right, to have considered that while creating systems that are easy to understand but difficult to abuse. We have trained ourselves quite a bit in this. I don't know what the exact implementation is. He could give you the details about how he thought about that, but I can assure you he's very passionate about this particular system.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Do you know if multiple players can accept the same job?</strong></p>
<p>I don't know.</p>
<p><strong>I know this is kind of a buzzword that's always tough to bring up, but blockchain technology has unfortunately been tainted with low-effort cash grabs and Web3 games that promise residual wealth and never deliver. What kind of real world applications does Web3 offer CCP Games?</strong></p>
<p>Weirdly enough, when we chose to use a database to make EVE Online, I got similar questions. They were like, databases are slow, they're mostly about banks, and they're boring, and like, why are you using a database to make a game? And I said, well, I'm making a persistent online game and I'm gonna make sure everything is properly stored and it's not going to get lost. Seems like a database is a good implementation.</p>
<p>And then we used the database and nobody thinks much of it today. We don't really sell EVE Online as like, the first database game. It was literally the first database game. Now there's another database, so to speak. And what we like about this database is that you can decentralise the database. We talk a lot about this kind of forever thing, and the centralization of data is a risk factor in anything forever. Anything centralised is more prone to a single point of failure than something that is decentralised.</p>
<p>The Internet itself is very decentralised for fault tolerance, so we like that aspect. Then we like the aspect of the blockchains that have been running now... I mean, let's look at Ethereum. It's been running since 2014, so it's over a decade, and it has open development on top of it in an adversarial framework. So, if somebody develops an application on Ethereum, they are in a way in competition with all the other applications on Ethereum.</p>
<p>So we want it, and it's largely held up technically on that level. We wanted to use that aspect to make a mod platform out of an MMO so that you could mod the server side of an MMO with both reads and writes. Because what we have seen in EVE Online where we have an API where people have built amazing things on top, largely by just reading data (you can actually write a little bit, but we are very careful about allowing writes because it's hard to manage it properly). But we wanted to build a platform where people could mod the server side of an MMO so that everyone could use the mod.</p>
<p>And when you run through the stack of things, that has to be true about any technology that allows for these two things: fault tolerant through decentralization, adversarially sound for economic warfare. Then you eventually end up with something like a blockchain.</p>
<p>I actually made that decentralised computing architecture in the 90s. It was my first gig coming out of university, which was to make a VRML browser in the late 90s in Iceland, actually, and we made a peer-to-peer system. Didn't have the cryptography, and thus we couldn't really make the transaction sound. We wanted to experiment. Can we supercharge the third party development/modding? Can we achieve fault tolerance through decentralization? Those are the reasons we're using it, and so far, so good.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'Eventually, blockchain will absolutely be able to replay big EVE battles. There will be a footprint record of the blow-by-blow. You would just actually read the blockchain on your own note. You would just run a note and you could play through the state and make your own visualisation of that.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Many players hear about these legendary EVE Online corporation battles after the fact in news stories and videos. Could blockchain technology record a battle and let players watch a battle play out in real time?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. Eventually, it will absolutely be able to do that. There will be a footprint record of the blow-by-blow. You would just actually read the blockchain on your own note. You would just run a note and you could play through the state and make your own visualisation of that.</p>
<p><strong>For EVE Vanguard, how have the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ccp-working-on-new-ue4-powered-fps-for-pc-as-dust-514-is-discontinued/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">previous failed attempts</a> at making an MMOFPS influenced this new take?</strong></p>
<p>There's a huge stack of stuff to that. I think probably the biggest lesson is that Dust 514 was a very big game. There were a lot of features, there was a lot of gameplay in the game. It was like a huge horizontal slice of a game, and because it was so big, we did not really have the time to make all aspects of it good. Now we're very much focused on that, on every single thing in Vanguard to be very good. All things are around gunplay and experience, moment to moment.</p>
<p>The shooter should just really be a great shooter. It should not lean on a crutch and because it has all these extra things, you can maybe excuse the shooting a little bit. I think that was the fundamental lesson. Another lesson is on the platform. It took a long time to get the performance where wanted on the PlayStation 3, which delayed it at the end of the cycle. The platform of choice now being PC, it's an easy thing to see after the fact. Doing it on a PC, which is our home ground, and making sure that every aspect of the game is rock solid before we start to scale up gameplay.</p>
<p>I think these are the primary points of what to learn from what didn't work out. Then, on the other side, what did work out is that people are still clamoring for Dust to come back, because this experience of playing a part in a grand adventure rather than just being a lobby shooter, nobody has delivered on that since Dust 514. You are taking part in a big, persistent, strategic war that's going to go on for decades.</p>
<p>By the way, I give Sony's massive props. We got waivers for everything under the sun to use our development methods on the PlayStation 3, and I think it actually taught Sony a lot about their own policies from working with us. Dust 514 was the first free-to-play game released on a Sony PlayStation console. There was a lot of trailblazing. Obviously, some of it was good and not all of it was good. We are ensuring we maintain what was good and address what was not.</p>
<p><strong>One of the aspects that I think drew a lot of players in was the promise that what you did in Dust 514 would be carried forward into EVE Online. So, can players expect further integration?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. What you do in Vanguard will echo in EVE forever.</p>
<p><strong>Can you share some examples of what might transfer between the two?</strong></p>
<p>If we think more of a future state, because this will take a while to work into, just like achieving the kind of Guinness World Record fleet fights we have now in EVE, it took a decade for players to organise themselves up until the point of getting thousands of people to fight together.</p>
<p>It's a major logistics, so in the future, we're planning for such logistics to span the solar system and the planets in the solar system to conquer territory in EVE Online. So, to conquer territory, you will have to go planet by planet to conquer the solar system. That means if you were a mercenary corporation in Vanguard, a single shot from one of your soldiers might topple an empire.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'The shooter should just really be a great shooter. It should not lean on a crutch and because it has all these extra things, you can maybe excuse the shooting a little bit. I think that was the fundamental lesson. Another lesson is on the platform. It took a long time to get the performance where wanted on the PlayStation 3, which delayed it at the end of the cycle. The platform of choice now being PC, it's an easy thing to see after the fact. Doing it on a PC, which is our home ground, and making sure that every aspect of the game is rock solid before we start to scale up gameplay.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Do you feel that comparisons to Vanguard being an extraction shooter are apt, or would you consider it to be something else?</strong></p>
<p>Vanguard will feature a series of game modes. Some might be extraction-like, and some might be different. Right now, I don't know how many game modes we have. There are quite a few we're working on. The second tool that made it into the game wasn't even a gun; it was a mining laser. It speaks volumes that it's more than just about a combat experience.</p>
<p>The victory conditions of each mode will evolve drastically over time, because to play a part in the territorial conquest of EVE Online, you will need several types of commissions that you will need to implement in several game modes.</p>
<p>We don't even really think of them as game modes internally. They're more like a platform for gameplay experiences. It's a sandbox environment, and there are various reasons to enter it and various player motivations or purposes once you're inside it. Some are more combat-oriented, and some will have, as someone says, different victory conditions.</p>
<p><strong>Will corporations from EVE Online play a big part in Vanguard?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. You were talking about the freelance jobs earlier. Imagine some of the freelance jobs being for Vanguards. In the corporations, you'll have a whole suite of jobs you're delegating to all sorts of people all over space and on the ground.</p>
<p><strong>With the skinner system for ships, can you use those same colour palettes in Vanguard?</strong></p>
<p>I think eventually, what works in EVE will be brought to Vanguard and vice-versa, what makes sense, and I think the corporation palettes for sure. I think it will be a smashing success, but we will always base it on what really gets traction and usually what happens is that people start to request that to be brought to another game.</p>
<p><strong>Speaking of bringing games elsewhere, has CCP Games considered bringing their PlayStation VR 1 catalog games, such as <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/sparc-virtual-sport-of-the-future/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sparc&nbsp;</a>and <a href="https://wccftech.com/eve-valkyrie-project-arena-vr-hands-on-gamescom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EVE Valkyrie</a>, to either the PlayStation VR 2 or the Meta Quest?</strong></p>
<p>We consider this every year, but right now we have our hands full with the games we're making. We just don't have the bandwidth to do with one.</p>
<p>For example, there was a period of time when CCP didn't have an active FPS that the public was aware of. That didn't necessarily mean that our ambitions to have an FPS in EVE had ever gone away. It's the exact same thing with this.</p>
<p>There's always something brewing at CCP, I can assure you.</p>
<p><strong>Who would win 100 new pros or a Titan?</strong></p>
<p>It should be such that 100 new pros can take down a Titan. It should be like that. It is a bit of a design premise of EVE that a bunch of new players should be able to take down any veteran in any circumstance. Whether it is practically like that right now, I think it depends a lot on the new pros. There are probably tactics where it could work, so the new pros would have to know about those. I think that absolutely virgin players off the street might struggle, but if players who really knew the game were to make a new character, they should be able to do it. If it isn't the case, then that is something to look into.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact US Age Verification to Kick In Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-us-age-verification-to-kick-in-later-this-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-us-age-verification-to-kick-in-later-this-month.1183161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-us-age-verification-to-kick-in-later-this-month<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HoYoverse has announced that all US&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>players will soon be required to verify their age if they wish to continue playing the gacha action RPG.</p>

<p>Per an <a href="https://genshin.hoyoverse.com/en/news/detail/155805" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">announcement</a> on its official website, HoYoverse will require you to go through its age verification process to play <em>Genshin Impact</em>. The process&nbsp;will be rolled out to everyone across the US by May 20th.</p>

<p>You'll need to provide your age information by July 18th. Failure to do so will, according to HoYoverse, result in account suspension and "in-game friends and chat records" being deleted, as well as "no further notifications", since you won't be able to access your account anymore.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/genshin-impact-us-age-verification-escoffier.jpg?itok=Jcl-vpYm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/genshin-impact-us-age-verification-escoffier.jpg?itok=ehjY6iKQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>will soon require you to verify your age to play.</figcaption></figure><p>What's more, if you don't verify your age by July 20th next year, your HoYoverse account's personal information "will be deleted permanently", so naturally, that's a fate you'll want to avoid.</p>

<p>This requirement likely comes as a result of <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2025/01/genshin-impact-game-developer-will-be-banned-selling-lootboxes-teens-under-16-without-parental" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a decision</a> made by the FTC back in January, wherein the commission found that HoYoverse "violated a children's privacy law and deceived children and other users" about in-game transaction costs and rare prizes in&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact</em>'s gacha system.</p>

<p>The decision required HoYoverse to cease selling "loot boxes" to children under 16 without their parents' consent and also to pay a $20 million fine to "settle FTC charges". It's likely the new age verification process is a direct result of that ruling.</p>

<p>Despite the fact that the gacha systems in&nbsp;<em>Honkai: Star Rail&nbsp;</em>and<i>&nbsp;Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</i>are very similar to those found in&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact</em>, it doesn't seem that the ruling applies to those games; it's likely they'd need to be assessed as their own cases.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-hoyoverse-genshin_0.jpg?itok=qJQQ2IHf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-hoyoverse-genshin_0.jpg?itok=FR76BZ_c 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>It doesn't seem&nbsp;<em>Honkai: Star Rail&nbsp;</em>or&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero&nbsp;</em>players will be required to disclose their age.</figcaption></figure><p>As for what's next for&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact</em>, the game's next major update, Version 5.6, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-56" rel="nofollow">launches today</a>. It takes you back to the land of Mondstadt, where your adventure began, in order to enjoy an "interlude chapter" before the next story chunk proper gets going.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Bucks Industry Trend And Says It Has No Plans to Increase Video Game Prices]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-bucks-industry-trend-and-says-it-has-no-plans-to-increase-video-game-prices</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-bucks-industry-trend-and-says-it-has-no-plans-to-increase-video-game-prices.1183152/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-bucks-industry-trend-and-says-it-has-no-plans-to-increase-video-game-prices<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Our business is very different today than it was even just 10 years ago," says CEO</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Publisher/ developer <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/producer/electronic-arts"><u>EA</u></a> has confirmed it has no plans to raise the price of its games even as the likes of Microsoft and Nintendo jump to $80.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Addressing investors in its latest financial call, CEO Andrew Wilson said the company's focus was to "deliver incredible quality and exponential value for our playerbase," such as its hit co-op adventure <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/boundary-pushing-co-op-adventure-split-fiction-nears-4-million-sales"><u>Split Fiction, which has now sold 4 million copies</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"In terms of pricing power, our business is very different today than it was even just 10 years ago," Wilson explained. "In a world where everything we did 10 years ago was about selling shiny discs in plastic boxes in retail shelves — well, that’s still a <em>part</em> of our business, it’s a significantly smaller part of our business, and we now have pricing representing everything from free-to-play all the way to deluxe editions and beyond.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"At the end of the day, whether we're doing something that costs a dollar, or we're doing something that costs $10, or we're doing something that costs $100, our objective is always to deliver incredible quality and exponential value for our playerbase," said Wilson. "And what we've discovered over the course of time is [when] we can marry quality and value together, our business is strong, resilient, and continues to grow."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"From a guidance perspective [...] we have reflected no changes in our current [pricing] strategy at this point," added CFO Stuart Canfield.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It'll be welcome news to some, given just last week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-raises-the-price-of-all-xbox-series-consoles-xbox-games-confirmed-to-hit-80-this-holiday"><u>Microsoft confirmed it was raising Xbox prices</u></a> as well as increasing the cost of controllers, headsets, and some games. The price hike for consoles and accessories has already taken effect, and while game prices will stay the same for now, we should expect to see Xbox charging $79.99 for new, first-party games around the holiday season.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It follows a broader trend in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-raising-prices-new-first-party-games-xbox-series-70-2023-redfall-starfield"><u>AAA gaming that has seen prices jumping from $60 to $70</u></a> in just the last five years, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/switch-2-exclusive-mario-kart-world-justifies-its-80-price-tag-nintendo-insists-in-first-comments-addressing-cost-controversy"><u>Nintendo going with $80 for upcoming Switch 2 exclusive Mario Kart World and some other Switch 2 Edition games</u></a>. The Switch 2 itself was recently revealed to be launching at $450, a price that drew criticism from Nintendo fans even as analysts admitted such a high price was likely <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/heres-why-the-nintendo-switch-2-mario-kart-world-and-everything-around-them-is-so-expensive"><u>inevitable amid current economic conditions</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Given EA's comments, we can expect the next EA Sports FC, Madden, and Battlefield games to stick to the $70 standard edition pricing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last week, IGN reported <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn"><u>EA cut around 100 jobs at Apex Legend developer Respawn Entertainment</u></a>, as well as making wider cuts across its organization, impacting around 300 individuals in all.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Interactive Entertainment establishes teamLFG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/sony-interactive-entertainment-establishes-teamlfg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-interactive-entertainment-establishes-teamlfg.1183149/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/sony-interactive-entertainment-establishes-teamlfg<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Bungie offshoot working on team-based action game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,988 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/05/07/welcome-teamlfg-to-the-playstation-studios-family/" target="_blank">announced</a> the establishment of <a title="Companies > teamLFG [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/teamlfg">teamLFG</a>, a new studio under <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [47,527 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Studios headquartered in Bellevue, Washington. <span id="more-963654"></span></p><p>teamLFG originated at <a title="Companies > Bungie [226 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/bungie">Bungie</a>, but has also rallied developers from across the industry to bring to life an “ambitious incubation project,” which it describes as “a team-based <a title="Genres > Action [2,713 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> that draws inspiration from fighting games, <a title="Genres > Platformer [670 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a>s, MOBAs, life sims, and frog-type games,” based in “a lighthearted, comedic world set in brand-new, mythic, science-fantasy universe.”</p><p>Here is a message from the studio on its establishment:</p><blockquote><p>“Hello, world. It’s a delight to meet you, and we’re very grateful to be joining PlayStation Studios.</p><p>“Our studio is headquartered in Bellevue, [Washington], with team members working both on-site and remotely throughout the [United States] and Canada. We are a team composed not just of industry veterans who have shipped titles like <em>Destiny</em>, <em>Halo</em>, <em>League of Legends</em>, <em><a title="Games > Fortnite [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Roblox [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/roblox">Roblox</a></em>, and <em>Rec Room</em>, but also industry newcomers with fresh creative perspectives and skills. We are passionate about exceptional action-based gameplay, moment-to-moment game feel, and richly social virtual worlds. </p><p>“The ‘LFG’ in ‘teamLFG’ stands for ‘Looking For Group.’ We are driven by a mission to create games where players can find friendship, community, and belonging. We want our players to feel excited when they log on to discover their teammates already hanging out online. We want our players to recognize familiar names and to make myths and memes out of each other. We want our players to love remembering that one time where they pulled off That Play that changed the whole story of the match. As we say on the team—dat’s da good stuff.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>“We will make immersive multiplayer worlds propelled by action games that players can learn, play, and master for countless hours. We want to build our games with our communities, inviting players to be a part of our development process through early access playtests. It’s critical that we stay nimble enough to react to player feedback, not just in our lead-up to launch, but throughout live service as we continue to grow the game and community for years to come. </p><p>“Our first game is a team-based action game that draws inspiration from fighting games, platformers, MOBAs, life sims, and frog-type games. Players will inhabit a lighthearted, comedic world set in brand-new, mythic, science-fantasy universe. We can’t wait to reveal more.</p><p>“‘Til then, we’ll do our best! Thanks for reading.”</p><p>—teamLFG</p></blockquote><p>Visit the studio’s official website <a href="https://teamlfg.com/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mamorukun ReCurse! announced for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/mamorukun-recurse-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mamorukun-recurse-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-switch-and-pc.1183146/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/mamorukun-recurse-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-switch-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publishers <a title="Companies > City Connection [186 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/city-connection">City Connection</a> and <a title="Companies > Clear River Games [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/clear-river-games">Clear River Games</a>, and developers <a title="Companies > G.rev [50 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/g-rev">G.rev</a> and TAKE x <a title="Games > OFF [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/off">OFF</a> have officially announced <em><a title="Games > Mamorukun ReCurse! [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mamorukun-recurse">Mamorukun ReCurse!</a></em>, a remastered version of vertical-scrolling <a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [779 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">shoot ’em up</a> <em>Mamorukun Curse!</em> It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,414 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,156 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,975 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,046 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,077 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam in 2025 worldwide. <span id="more-963629"></span></p><p>The updated release was <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/04/mamorukun-curse-coming-to-ps5-xbox-switch-and-pc-in-2025">first confirmed</a> at <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,095 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">Shooter</a>s Fes in April 2024, but today’s announcement marks the game’s official reveal.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Clear River Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Mamorukun ReCurse!</em> is a modern remaster of cult classic arcade shooter <em>Mamorukun Curse!</em>, originally developed by G.rev for Japanese <a title="Platforms > Arcade [377 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">arcades</a> in 2008, and brought back to life by TAKE x OFF, the team behind this year’s highly-regarded <em><a title="Games > Under Defeat (2024) [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/under-defeat-2024">Under Defeat</a></em> port. This new version of the game now supports widescreen format, and adds game changing modern twin-stick controls, alongside the original control scheme, so players can pick the best way to play.</p><p>In this adorably cute vertical-scrolling shoot ’em up, players use Curse <a title="Companies > Bullets [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bullets">Bullets</a> to fuel intense risk-reward gameplay, dynamically altering the difficulty as they play. Players can take out smaller enemies and clear projectiles from the screen, or choose to power up larger enemies to make them harder to defeat. The stronger the foe, the higher the score, and players can even curse themselves to take more damage.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Drawing inspiration from traditional Japanese mythology in a family-friendly package, <em>Mamorukun ReCurse!</em> sees players take on the role of Mamoru, who wakes up in the Netherworld following his untimely death. In order to stop the Netherworld being consumed by the dark, Mamoru and a group of new friends must seal the gate to The World of Darkness.</p><p>Packed with content, <em>Mamorukun ReCurse!</em> includes Story Mode, <a title="Genres > Arcade [77 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">Arcade</a> Mode, Challenge Courses, alternative costumes, and a new Gallery Mode. The game also includes all previously-released downloadable content characters, giving players plenty of reasons to play again and again.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>An arcade classic <em>ReCursed!</em> for modern platforms.</li><li>Use Curse Bullets to adjust the game’s difficulty on the fly!</li><li>Story Mode, Arcade Mode, or Challenge Courses? The choice is yours!</li><li>Multiple characters, alternate costumes, and an extensive Gallery Mode!</li><li>Original compositions by Yosuke Yasui, plus arranged music from previous releases.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View a set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/mamorukun-recurse/may-7-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Mamorukun ReCurse! - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dFBZHGIp6zA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_963636"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Mirror: Bandersnatch interactive special leaving Netflix]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/black-mirror-bandersnatch-interactive-special-leaving-netflix</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-mirror-bandersnatch-interactive-special-leaving-netflix.1183143/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/black-mirror-bandersnatch-interactive-special-leaving-netflix<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Bandersnatch - the interactive special from the Black Mirror team with a video game theme - is leaving Netflix.</p>
<p>Bandersnatch is about a young programmer who starts to lose his grip on reality as he sets to work adapting a dark fantasy novel into a video game. Set in the 1980s, Bandersnatch is described as a "mind-bending tale", which features multiple endings depending on the viewer's decisions.</p>
<p>It is a pretty interesting form of media which can get quite meta, and one that I restarted just now to have on in the background as I write this article.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fixed Camera Angles in Horror Games Are Scarier - Hear Me Out..." data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PTnVyB1BkvQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fixed Camera Angles in Horror Games Are Scarier - Hear Me Out...</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PTnVyB1BkvQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PTnVyB1BkvQ?autoplay=1" title="Fixed Camera Angles in Horror Games Are Scarier - Hear Me Out...">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Fixed Camera Angles in Horror Games Are Scarier - Hear Me Out... <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PTnVyB1BkvQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Anyway, if you too want to relive the Emmy-winning Bandersnatch, you best do it sooner rather than later, because - as reported by <a href="https://www.whats-on-netflix.com/leaving-soon/black-mirror-bandersnatch-and-unbreakable-kimmy-schmidt-interactive-specials-leaving-netflix/">What's On Netflix</a> - removal notices have appeared on both Black Mirror: Bandersnatch and Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt: Kimmy vs. the Reverend. These last remaining interactive specials are set to leave Netflix on 12th May.</p>
<p>In November of last year, a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-removing-almost-all-of-its-interactive-specials-but-dont-worry-bandersnatch-is-safe">Netflix spokesperson confirmed to Eurogamer that "almost all" of its interactive titles would be leaving the service that December</a>. "Only four will remain: Black Mirror: Bandersnatch, Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt: Kimmy vs. the Reverend, Ranveer vs. Wild with Bear Grylls, and You vs. Wild," Netflix told us at the time.</p>
<p>According to What's On Netflix, the company is going to be rolling out a UI redesign across various devices in the near future. Reportedly this redesign, which is still in the testing phase, is the reason Netflix has been phasing out its interactive specials.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, it is unclear whether or not Bandersnatch will return to the service in some sort of non-interactive form, like the previously removed Bear Grylls specials which were <a href="https://www.whats-on-netflix.com/news/netflix-re-releases-bear-grylls-interactive-specials-as-linear-specials/">re-released on Netflix with a linear format</a>.</p>
<p>Eurogamer has reached out to Netflix for further comment on Bandersnatch's upcoming removal from the service.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Netflix</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The seventh season of Black Mirror recently made its debut. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/balatro-now-canonically-in-black-mirror">Along with a nod to Balatro</a>, the latest season also has its own crossover moment in the form of Thronglets, a companion mobile game tied to the episode Plaything.</p>
<p>"Thronglets, to me, feels like the gaming future Netflix wants," our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-new-netflix-black-mirror-series-has-another-bandersnatch-like-gaming-crossover-moment-but-you-might-not-even-notice-it">Bertie wrote after having a go with Thronglets</a>. "It's a fine example of how an additive brand-related gaming experience can be done."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spiritfall Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/spiritfall-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spiritfall-review.1183122/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/spiritfall-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/spiritfall-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Spiritfall Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Adrian Burrows">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-05-07">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-05-07">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Have you ever wondered what would happen if Super Smash Bros. was made into a roguelite? How would the chaotic arena battling of Nintendo’s finest platform brawler work within the rinse and repeat loop of Indie developer’s favourite genre? Those seem to be the questions Gentle Giant Games asked themselves. Their answer? Spiritfall.</p>
<p><iframe title="Spiritfall Console Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rSJdbb7kHrA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>With a bold Saturday-morning cartoon aesthetic, Spiritfall instantly charms the eyeballs. You play as a little dead dude with a flaming head who must battle and defeat a whole bunch of creatures and bosses to free the realm from bad stuff. Or something. Look, I have to admit, the plot held my attention for about as long as a TikTok video. It’s generic and hardly compelling, but thankfully it doesn’t get in the way and can mostly be ignored whilst you crack on with all the beat ‘em up fun.&nbsp;And what stupendously enjoyable gameplay it is!</p>


<p>From a map screen, you’ll choose which arena you want to enter next, mostly by appraising which of the many exciting rewards on offer will help you to complete your run. With that decision made, you’re straight into the action. Played from a 2D perspective, combat is fast, frantic, responsive and oh-so-silky smooth. Enemies will spawn and you get to hitting them with an abundance of style, as if Devil May Cry’s Dante went 2D. The more you hit your foes, the higher your combo meter builds and the more your victims bounce around the arena, obliterating themselves against walls, plunging off the edge of the level, or – even better – taking out a few of their evil chums in a satisfying chain reaction of explosions. Just like Super Smash Bros. it’s all about controlling the space, using your directional attacks and charged specials to send enemies flying before they can surround and overwhelm you.</p>


<p>Enemy types are wide and varied, each working with the other in interesting variations of attack pattens to try and catch you out. You thankfully have a very effective dash that will help you reposition to strike from safety, perhaps from a platform above or below, or with an arena wall to your back. The enemy hordes are constantly probing for a weakness in your strategy, leading to demanding dynamic combat encounters that keeps your fingers clicking and your eyes from never blinking. Frankly, it’s ridiculously addictive and kept me coming back for more as the hours rolled by.</p>
<p>This being a roguelite, there’s a conglomeration of power-ups that you get to keep for the run, and a whole bunch of collectibles you can gather to unlock permanent upgrades in the central hub. Spiritfall is delightfully generous in the rapid pace of the progress the player makes, as you are always rewarded with something by the spirits you meet. From damage-dealing dashes, the ability to shoot lightning bolts, or to set fire to the many minions you face, the configuration of character builds is bewildering in its vastness. Overall, the difficulty is configured just right for that one-more-run buzz, with upgrades coming thick and fast, ensuring you make enough progress each time to feel compelled to try again, rather than dispirited and put off by the reset back to the start.</p>

<p>Like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/09/17/hades-review-switch-pc/">Hades</a>, there’s an entire armoury of weapons to unlock, each one encouraging a different playstyle and approach. There’s something for everyone, from a straightforward hammer, to a quartet of rapid-punching fists, a bow with long distance attacks or a very complicated chain scythe thingy. I’m sure in the hands of someone more skilled that latter would be deadly, however, in my clumsy hands things got very messy, so I went back to the safe embrace of the hammer instead.</p>
<p>Whilst the gameplay is thrilling and eminently addictive, the characters you meet are bland and empty merchants. Unlike the best examples of this form, there are no intriguing relationships to build here, everyone you come across has just a few limited text boxes to offer by way of characterisation, but little else. Thankfully the combat, pace, and deliriously compelling roguelite loop more than make up for this, resulting in a game that is perfect for the Switch and for facing another train delay with a smile on your face. After all, the lack of a train driver means there is time for another run after all.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Spritifall is a stupendous roguelite that feeds on Smash Bros. style brawling. Brilliant fun from beginning to end, Gentle Giant have crafted one of the best recent entries in the genre.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Charming visuals</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Smooth, responsive platform fighter</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Addictive gameplay</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Hundreds of builds and tactical options</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Forgettable plot</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Characters have little personality</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
								
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter Release Date Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/trails-in-sky-1st-chapter-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-release-date-revealed.1183119/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/trails-in-sky-1st-chapter-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Nihon Falcom and publisher GungHo Online Entertainment have seemingly revealed the&nbsp;<em>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter&nbsp;</em>release date, with the JRPG remake getting a worldwide release later this year.</p>

<p>Back in December, the two studios <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/trails-in-sky-1st-chapter-simultaneous-global-release-2025" rel="nofollow">announced</a> that the game would be getting a simultaneous global launch sometime in 2025, and now, thanks to Japanese news publication <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202505/40940" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Famitsu</a> (via leaker <a href="https://ryokutya2089.com/archives/86204" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Ryokutya2089</a> and news platform <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-launches-september-19" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Gematsu</a>), we know the date, at least for Japan: it's coming on September 19th.</p>

<p>Technically, publisher GungHo hasn't revealed a Western release date for&nbsp;<em>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter&nbsp;</em>yet, but there's no reason to believe the aforementioned simultaneous worldwide release isn't still going ahead, at least for now.</p>

<p>As previously revealed, the game will be getting a release on PC and PlayStation 5 as well as Nintendo Switch. It'll be available in two different editions: the standard version and the Bracer Box edition, although we don't yet know what comes as part of the latter.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-release-date-combat.jpg?itok=7Pcdz7o4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-release-date-combat.jpg?itok=RKVN5pmc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter&nbsp;</em>launches in September.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</em>, it's a remake of the original&nbsp;<em>The Legend of Heroes: Trails in the Sky</em>, which is itself part of the wider&nbsp;<em>The Legend of Heroes&nbsp;</em>series (which has been running for much longer than you'd imagine).</p>

<p>The game will tell the same story as the original; it'll follow the adventures of Estelle and Joshua Bright, two "bracers" (think problem-solving bounty-hunter types) who are quickly drawn into a "conspiracy that threatens the very heart of their homeland", according to Falcom.</p>

<p>Since it's a remake, though, you can look forward to improved visuals across the board, plus "refined gameplay" that will allow you to choose between turn-based combat and real-time fighting.</p>

<p>You can also expect new voiceovers in English and Japanese, and, of course, you'll have the option of choosing which one of the two you want, so you don't have to suffer through the English dub if you don't want to. I'm sure it's perfectly fine, but I'll be picking Japanese. Sorry.</p>




<p><em>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter&nbsp;</em>launches on September 19th for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3375780/Trails_in_the_Sky_1st_Chapter/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10013078" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and Nintendo Switch.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earthion is a brand new shoot ’em up coming to consoles… and the Sega Mega Drive]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/earthion-is-a-brand-new-shoot-em-up-coming-to-consoles-and-the-sega-mega-drive/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/earthion-is-a-brand-new-shoot-%E2%80%99em-up-coming-to-consoles%E2%80%A6-and-the-sega-mega-drive.1183092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/07/earthion-is-a-brand-new-shoot-em-up-coming-to-consoles-and-the-sega-mega-drive/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>We just had to write this one up, because it’s not every day that you find out there’s going to be a new game for the Mega Drive – or Genesis if you’re of the American persuasion. Yes folks, someone has decided that releasing games on modern consoles is too passé, too easy, and instead decided that they’d bring a new title to a console that’s been dead and buried for nearly three decades. That game? Earthion, an old-school scrolling shoot ’em up, which will release on physical cartridge for the Sega Mega Drive/Genesis, alongside PC, PS4, PS5, Xbox Series X|S and Nintendo Switch.</p>
<p><iframe title="Earthion Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PP59afi7FD8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Even more exciting than a new cartridge, is the fact that it also boasts a 27-track soundtrack from legendary composer Yuzo Koshiro, whose previous works include Streets of Rage, ActRaiser and The Revenge of Shinobi. So, not only is it going to look like the 90s and come on a 90s cartridge, it’s going to sound like the 90s as well.</p>
<p>Earthion has been created by Japanese dev team Ancient Corporation – owned, in fact by Yuzo Koshiro – and it’s a space-themed 2D side scrolling shooter that sees you taking control of ace pilot Azusa Takahashi through 8 levels of space mayhem, each with unique environments, enemies and huge, screen-filling bosses.</p>


<p>This being a modern retro title, players will be able to configure scanlines and emulate CRT TVs when playing on modern platforms. Mega Drive players should be just fine without. There will also be mutiple difficulty levels, a challenge mode, a level password system and online leaderboards, though here the Mega Drive meets its match, and you’ll just have to get your friends round to compete against like in the good old days.</p>
<p>Earthion is due to arrive later this year for PC, PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch and Sega Mega Drive/Genesis. You can wishlist it now on Steam!</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Split Fiction Sales Top 4m, New Battlefield and Skate Due Before March]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-sales-4m-battlefield-skate</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/split-fiction-sales-top-4m-new-battlefield-and-skate-due-before-march.1183089/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-sales-4m-battlefield-skate<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>EA has announced that Hazelight's co-op platformer&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>has reached another big sales milestone, and the studio has also provided updates on when we can expect the next&nbsp;<em>Battlefield&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>games to arrive.</p>

<p>As part of its 2024-25 earnings report, EA reveals that&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>has sold "nearly four million units" since launching in March, although developer Hazelight <a href="https://x.com/HazelightGames/status/1919852640189456892" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">subsequently said</a> it had passed that mark.</p>

<p>This figure means&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>has racked up another two million sales for itself since the beginning of March; the game reached the two million mark <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-sales-2m" rel="nofollow">inside a single week</a>, having already reached a million sales <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-sales-1m-48-hours" rel="nofollow">within its first 48 hours</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/split-fiction-sales-4m-battlefield-skate-ea-co-op.jpg?itok=w-I7X2zv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/split-fiction-sales-4m-battlefield-skate-ea-co-op.jpg?itok=c8TLidtv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>continues to sell well for EA.</figcaption></figure><p>The news will no doubt please not only EA, but also the folks currently working on the&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>movie, which was first <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-movie-report" rel="nofollow">mooted in March</a> and which will star&nbsp;<em>Madame Web&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-movie-sydney-sweeney" rel="nofollow">alum Sydney Sweeney</a>&nbsp;(presumably as Zoe, although apparently, Sweeney's character hasn't been decided yet).</p>

<p>As well as a sales update for&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction</em>, EA also revealed when we can apparently expect new&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Battlefield&nbsp;</em>games to arrive; both are due to land in the 2025-26 fiscal year, which means EA has until March 2026 to release them.</p>

<p>EA has already been drip-feeding information about the new&nbsp;<em>Battlefield&nbsp;</em>via its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/battlefield-labs-announced-ea" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Battlefield Labs initiative</a>, whereby it continuously requests community feedback in order to shape and inform the development of the game.</p>

<p>As for&nbsp;<em>Skate</em>, EA originally announced it was coming to Early Access in 2025 <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/skate-reboot-early-access-2025" rel="nofollow">last year</a>, although when it does, it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-skate-reboot-no-offline-mode" rel="nofollow">won't be launching with any kind of offline mode</a>, unfortunately. You'll have to look to Activision's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-and-4-remasters" rel="nofollow">upcoming&nbsp;<em>Tony Hawk&nbsp;</em>remasters</a> if you want offline skating sims.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ea-skate-2025-26.jpg?itok=pQDf7NVI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ea-skate-2025-26.jpg?itok=UTeMR9qY 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>EA's&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>reboot is due in or before March 2026.</figcaption></figure><p>You can check out EA's <a href="https://s204.q4cdn.com/701424631/files/doc_financials/2025/q4/Q4-FY25-Earnings-Slides-FINAL.pdf" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">full earnings report here</a> if you want to see how the studio has been doing, although its earlier admission that big releases&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>EA Sports FC 25&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-veilguard-ea-sports-fc-25-underperformed" rel="nofollow">flopped</a> should clue you in on that front.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 9 Netflix Series Characters Crazier Than You's Joe Goldberg]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/joe-goldberg-you-netflix-squid-game-house-of-cards-1851778476</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-9-netflix-series-characters-crazier-than-yous-joe-goldberg.1183086/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/joe-goldberg-you-netflix-squid-game-house-of-cards-1851778476<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="e33360c4d85fd36cf227318e301e0430" data-recommend-id="image://e33360c4d85fd36cf227318e301e0430" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Scary Netflix characters looking terrifying" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="e33360c4d85fd36cf227318e301e0430" data-recommend-id="image://e33360c4d85fd36cf227318e301e0430" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Scary Netflix characters looking terrifying" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>You</em>’s Joe Goldberg (Penn Badgley) is many things, but he’s definitely not the worst. Let me explain. Joe is a psychotic serial killer and stalker who makes the title “hopeless romantic” an eerie prophecy. He’s trapped the boyfriend of the woman he loves in a creepy basement cage before poisoning him, killed his wife (who definitely tried killing him), broke into a woman’s home and sniffed her panties, and abandoned his son so he could fake his death. This man is a walking red flag, but he wouldn’t even crack the top 10 of craziest characters to ever appear in a Netflix Original Series.</p><p>He’s never flooded a country with cocaine, or tried to kill his kid in a murder-suicide attempt, or trapped people’s consciousness in a digital prison, or become President of the United States and stayed insane. With the <em>You</em> series coming to a climatic and dick-print-less end, it’s a perfect time to reflect on the list of Netflix maniacs that Joe will be joining in infamy.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="0f7eb57f3802c751ec2af8305325f19f" data-recommend-id="image://0f7eb57f3802c751ec2af8305325f19f" data-format="jpg" data-width="7200" data-height="3068" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Silco looking at a drug" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Silco looking at a drug" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Netflix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0f7eb57f3802c751ec2af8305325f19f" data-recommend-id="image://0f7eb57f3802c751ec2af8305325f19f" data-format="jpg" data-width="7200" data-height="3068" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Silco looking at a drug" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Joe may kill for love, and even jump off a bridge in a suicide attempt over his guilt, but he would never inject himself with a strength-building toxic drug just to manipulate a society into using it and build himself an army of unstoppable fighters. That’s where tyrannical revolutionary Silco (Jason Spisak) from Netflix’s animated series <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/arcane-season-1-recap-netflix-league-of-legends-1851689099&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/arcane-season-1-recap-netflix-league-of-legends-1851689099"><em>Arcane</em></a></span> comes in. He’s tested the drug, known as Shimmer, on children to refine its manipulative powers, groomed a young girl into becoming an unhinged walking weapon named Jinx (Ella Purnell), and likely killed more people than Joe has ever met. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="d383d65aa91ec30614c510ce8cfd4b3e" data-recommend-id="image://d383d65aa91ec30614c510ce8cfd4b3e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1400" data-height="700" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Robert Daly holding someone's future" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Robert Daly holding someone's future" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Netflix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d383d65aa91ec30614c510ce8cfd4b3e" data-recommend-id="image://d383d65aa91ec30614c510ce8cfd4b3e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1400" data-height="700" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Robert Daly holding someone's future" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>I wouldn’t say Jesse Plemons is type-casted to play emotionally stunted sociopathic characters, but he’s mastered those roles in a disturbingly realistic way. As digital captain and lethally awkward computer programmer Robert Daly on the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-mirror-netflix-striking-vipers-hang-the-dj-1851770891&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-mirror-netflix-striking-vipers-hang-the-dj-1851770891"><em>Black Mirror</em></a></span> episodes “USS Callister” and “USS Callister: Into Infinity” you forget he’s not a masochist. Don’t talk to me about Joe trapping people in cages that they usually talk their way out of when Daly is stealing people’s DNA from coffee cups to trap their digital clones with full consciousness in a video game that he controls. The man once erased someone’s face causing them to perpetually suffocate but not die for as long as he wanted. What’s a serial killer to a digital god? </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="46c24e07934832526dcec0992235e16c" data-recommend-id="image://46c24e07934832526dcec0992235e16c" data-format="webp" data-width="996" data-height="647" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Eddie Kemper looking into someone's soul" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Eddie Kemper looking into someone's soul" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Netflix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="46c24e07934832526dcec0992235e16c" data-recommend-id="image://46c24e07934832526dcec0992235e16c" data-format="webp" data-width="996" data-height="647" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Eddie Kemper looking into someone's soul" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>I’ve never had a nightmare about Joe Goldberg. Eddie Kempler (Cameron Britton), unsettingly articulate serial killer from Netflix’s drama series <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://www.avclub.com/dawn-of-the-dead-mindhunter-takes-us-back-to-the-start-1819447951&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.avclub.com/dawn-of-the-dead-mindhunter-takes-us-back-to-the-start-1819447951"><em>Mindhunter</em></a></span>, has terrorized my nights many times. Based on a real killer of the same name, Kempler would describe killing his grandmother just to know what it was like to kill someone with the type of methodical tone usually reserved for explaining a casserole recipe. Joe also had chillingly pragmatic reasonings for his murders, but he’s lost his cool on a number of occasions, showing the vulnerable humanity submerged under his psychosis. Kempler came across less as a sane human and more of a body that only exists to fulfill its murderous desires.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="99ddfcf1dc8e403f43c9e756bad74055" data-recommend-id="image://99ddfcf1dc8e403f43c9e756bad74055" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Erzsebet Báthory looking devilish" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Erzsebet Báthory looking devilish" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Netflix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="99ddfcf1dc8e403f43c9e756bad74055" data-recommend-id="image://99ddfcf1dc8e403f43c9e756bad74055" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Erzsebet Báthory looking devilish" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This isn’t really a fair fight. How much evil can a simple human like Joe do compared to an animated vampire goddess who can turn blood into deadly weapons like Erzsebet Báthory (Franka Potente) in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/netflix-castlevania-nocturne-season-2-erzsebet-bathory-1851738621&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/netflix-castlevania-nocturne-season-2-erzsebet-bathory-1851738621"><em>Castlevania: Nocturne</em></a></span>? Joe is perpetuating incel behavior and toxic masculinity masked as love at a murderous level. Erzsbet is channeling ancient dark energy, usually from the blood of towns she’s had massacred, with the intent on bringing the apocalypse. She once burned a priest in front of his congregation just to prove she was more powerful than the god they prayed to. That’s evil on a biblical scale. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="90db7f5384a27d17dafdbc55b354fb75" data-recommend-id="image://90db7f5384a27d17dafdbc55b354fb75" data-format="webp" data-width="1000" data-height="563" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Pablo Escobar looking menacingly " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Pablo Escobar looking menacingly " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Netflix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="90db7f5384a27d17dafdbc55b354fb75" data-recommend-id="image://90db7f5384a27d17dafdbc55b354fb75" data-format="webp" data-width="1000" data-height="563" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Pablo Escobar looking menacingly " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>It doesn’t matter if you’re talking about Pablo Escobar the man or Pablo Escobar (Wagner Moura) the character in <em>Narcos, </em>he’s a maniac who would do anything to feed his power addiction. I wouldn’t say one life is more valuable than another, but the deaths of certain people do come with different consequences than the death of others. So, when Pablo had the depraved confidence to assassinate politicians knowing the governmental battle that would follow, it showcased a thirst for control that was dangerously blinding. If we’re talking evil, I would say flooding the home country you claim to love with a deadly drug, and even deadlier foot soldiers enforcing your rules to protect that drug empire is pretty evil. Joe’s killings were one at a time. Pablo bombed an entire flight that killed over 100 people, including children, without blinking an eye.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="0324c4985d922bdbd47df8e6e6845493" data-recommend-id="image://0324c4985d922bdbd47df8e6e6845493" data-format="jpg" data-width="1486" data-height="991" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Vecna ready to attack" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Vecna ready to attack" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Netflix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0324c4985d922bdbd47df8e6e6845493" data-recommend-id="image://0324c4985d922bdbd47df8e6e6845493" data-format="jpg" data-width="1486" data-height="991" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Vecna ready to attack" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Similar to <em>Castlevania: Nocturne</em>’s Erzsebet Báthory, Joe is no match for a telepathic, otherworldly demon that can kill you without touching you. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-season-5-vecna-secrets-netflix-game-vr-1849752681&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-season-5-vecna-secrets-netflix-game-vr-1849752681"><em>Stranger Things</em></a></span><em> </em>baddie Vecna’s (Jamie Campbell Bower) killings were disturbing because of how inhumane they looked. He had an innocent cheerleader psychically paralyzed and floating in the air before he had her bones twisted into ways no human body should ever be twisted in. Joe’s a monster in the disturbed criminal sense. Vecna is a monster in every sense you can and don’t want to think of.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="0ee9a3af407e6e3fa8dce0138f3fd2cb" data-recommend-id="image://0ee9a3af407e6e3fa8dce0138f3fd2cb" data-format="jpg" data-width="3600" data-height="1506" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Jeffrey Dahmer being arrested" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Jeffrey Dahmer being arrested" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Netflix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0ee9a3af407e6e3fa8dce0138f3fd2cb" data-recommend-id="image://0ee9a3af407e6e3fa8dce0138f3fd2cb" data-format="jpg" data-width="3600" data-height="1506" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Jeffrey Dahmer being arrested" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Penn Badgley once <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://people.com/tv/penn-badgley-talks-netflix-jeffrey-dahmer-fascination-tells-fans-to-look-inside/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://people.com/tv/penn-badgley-talks-netflix-jeffrey-dahmer-fascination-tells-fans-to-look-inside/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">called out Netflix</a></span> for inspiring viewers to love Jeffrey Dahmer when watching <em>Monster: The Jeffrey Dahmer Story</em>. Although he admits <em>You </em>does the same with Joe Goldberg, he implies the difference is Joe’s a fictional character, whereas Dahmer did unspeakably evil acts that should never be given any love. In the show, Dahmer dismembers bodies and kept skulls as weird keepsakes. The man stored body parts in a freezer like frozen blueberries, and even admitted to eating some of them. Killing was a science and an art to Dahmer. It was a tool for Joe. It’s the killer who revels in the murder long after its served its initial purpose that has hit a depth of evil Joe hasn’t even scratched.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e6d3241c913cbb6c060ddd086bd54a2a" data-recommend-id="image://e6d3241c913cbb6c060ddd086bd54a2a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2951" data-height="1968" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Front Man looking crazy" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Front Man looking crazy" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Netflix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e6d3241c913cbb6c060ddd086bd54a2a" data-recommend-id="image://e6d3241c913cbb6c060ddd086bd54a2a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2951" data-height="1968" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Front Man looking crazy" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Life and death are not games, unless you’re as evil as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/squid-game-season-2-netflix-kim-jun-hee-gi-hun-1851728874&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/squid-game-season-2-netflix-kim-jun-hee-gi-hun-1851728874"><em>Squid Game</em></a></span>’s Front Man (Lee Byung-hun). In the series centered on a gruesome winner-take-all competition between destitute and desperate people, The Front Man monitored and orchestrated every nuance like a sadistic god entertained by the torture of his subjects. He shot his own brother in cold blood after the man uncovered the truth, choosing loyalty to a murderous system over family.  This sicko loved the thrill of murder so much he disguised himself as a contestant in his twisted game only to shoot the same contestants he endeared himself to. Joe romanticized his killings almost as narrative tropes in a trashy romance novel, a perspective that led to further delusions. The Front Man saw human life as expendable as that of a video game character.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8d19bbf53bf3c37524d5639e37eed69f" data-recommend-id="image://8d19bbf53bf3c37524d5639e37eed69f" data-format="jpg" data-width="873" data-height="634" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Frank Underwood holding court" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Frank Underwood holding court" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Netflix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8d19bbf53bf3c37524d5639e37eed69f" data-recommend-id="image://8d19bbf53bf3c37524d5639e37eed69f" data-format="jpg" data-width="873" data-height="634" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Frank Underwood holding court" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Netflix’s early dominance was built on Frank Underwood’s (Kevin Spacey) blood-soaked hands that were probably just getting done with strangling a journalist. Joe Goldberg was a sadistic serial killer, stalker, and terrible erotica writer, but at least he didn’t have the governmental power to gut Social Security funds for millions or almost started a war with Russia to improve his public approval. Frank would probably be jealous of Joe trapping people in a soundproof cage, but what made Frank crazier than Joe was his willingness to treat millions of lives with reckless abandon and emotional indifference. Joe was a serial killer who confused obsession with love. Frank was a monster who knew the difference and relished in every death he caused. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Rebirth New Mod Adds Highly Requested Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-new-mod-requested-feature/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-new-mod-adds-highly-requested-feature.1183065/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-new-mod-requested-feature/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Final Fantasy VII Rebirth mod that's now available for download for free introduces a highly requested feature that is only available in a limited capacity in the vanilla game.</p>
<p>The Dresscode mod developed by YIIS, which can be downloaded from <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/finalfantasy7rebirth/mods/1062?tab=description" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nexus Mods</a>, introduces a system that lets users change character outfits and weapons in-game dynamically. The tool not only supports all the base game outfits, requiring <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/finalfantasy7rebirth/mods/1071">another mod</a> to unlock those not normally available via the changing booth, but also modded outfits, of which quite a few are available online. Before downloading the mod, you can check it out in action in the video below.</p>
<p><iframe title="FF7R Dresscode Mod" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EbOMnUSq_UM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Though the Final Fantasy VII Rebirth modding scene is not as big as that of other titles, plenty of great mods have been developed since the game's PC launch early this year. While the first few mods were, unsurprisingly, on the simple side, the unofficial additions made to the second entry in the remake trilogy have gradually become better and better, and have gone as far as adding completely new <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-new-mods-new-playable-characters/">playable characters</a>, such as the Turks Rude and Reno.</p>
<p>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth is now available on PC and PlayStation 5 worldwide. You can learn more about one of the best role-playing games released this generation by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will GTA 6 Be S-Tier? Rank Every Rockstar Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/will-gta-6-be-s-tier-rank-every-rockstar-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/will-gta-6-be-s-tier-rank-every-rockstar-game.1183062/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/will-gta-6-be-s-tier-rank-every-rockstar-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Which Rockstar game do you think is the greatest?</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">A new GTA 6 trailer is here and, in case you missed it, we <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/89-details-from-the-gta-6-trailer-2"><u>broke down all of the secrets and details</u></a> from it. Sadly, though, we’re going to have to wait until May 26, 2026, to actually play Lucia and Jason’s story. So, in the meantime, why don’t we think about all of the Rockstar games we’ve already enjoyed over the years and rank them for fun?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar has developed and released over 30 games since its creation in 1998, and is responsible for famous series such as Grand Theft Auto, Red Dead Redemption, and Manhunt. But which comes out on top? Just to clarify, you won’t see the likes of LA Noire or Max Payne 2 here, as we’ve strictly gone with Rockstar-developed games, rather than ones the studio has published. I’ve had a go at ranking them via one of our IGN Tier Lists, purely taking into account my personal enjoyment of each game over the years. Take a look at my tier list here:</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/07/screenshot-2025-05-07-at-12-08-59-1746616161781.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Red Dead Redemption 2 is simply my favourite game of all time, so it was a pretty easy S-tier pick for me if I’m honest. It’s (perhaps unsurprisingly) joined its predecessor and GTA 5 in that category – both pioneers of the cinematic open world genre. I also have a particular soft spot for Max Payne 3 and its bullet time ballet, as well as GTA San Andreas (a game I played at a way too young age). Down at the bottom in the D-tier, we have the likes of Austin Powers: Oh, Behave! and Welcome to My Underground Lair!, a game that literally nobody in their right mind wants to play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Don’t agree with me? Think that Vice City is better than GTA 4? Well, why not have a go at ranking all of Rockstar’s games yourself in a tier list below, where you can compare your own S, A, B, C, and D tiers with the whole of the IGN community.</p><div id="every-rockstar-game-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Every Rockstar Game Tier List</h3><h3>Every Rockstar Game Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">We may have only seen two trailers so far, but where do you think GTA 6 will end up ranking when all is said and done? Let us know in the comments, as well as why you’ve ranked the games in the order you’ve chosen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With GTA 6 Trailer 2 Out in the Wild, the Fan Theories Are Coming Thick and Fast — and Some Sound Pretty Plausible]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/with-gta-6-trailer-2-out-in-the-wild-the-fan-theories-are-coming-thick-and-fast-and-some-sound-pretty-plausible</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/with-gta-6-trailer-2-out-in-the-wild-the-fan-theories-are-coming-thick-and-fast-%E2%80%94-and-some-sound-pretty-plausible.1183059/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/with-gta-6-trailer-2-out-in-the-wild-the-fan-theories-are-coming-thick-and-fast-and-some-sound-pretty-plausible<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">GTA 6 Trailer 2 is packed full of details (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/89-details-from-the-gta-6-trailer-2">we spotted 89!</a>), but it has also sparked an explosion of fan theories as the community analyze each frame for clues on what to expect when the most anticipated game in the world eventually comes out in May 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GTA fans across social media, Discord, forums, reddit, and elsewhere are putting forward their speculation, with Trailer 2 the most up to date reference point they have.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s start with a fun reference to Red Dead Redemption 2 that has some, once again, theorizing that the worlds of GTA and Red Dead exist within the same universe. Eagle-eyed fans spotted that the presidents on the cash seen in a screenshot of the club in GTA 6 are the same as those from Red Dead Redemption 2’s cigarette cards (Thaddeus Waxman and Franklin Hardin).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting this is an incidental detail, and GTA and Red Dead existing in the same universe does not amount to much at the end of the day (although some are now suggesting Jason may be a descendant of Arthur Morgan, given the two look sort of alike). But it shows that there are connections between the two Rockstar IPs that may be strengthened further when GTA 6 comes out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now onto some juicy stuff. There is a brief moment in the trailer early on when Jason walks into his house, and the camera moves into what looks like an over the shoulder, third-person perspective. There is little sign of gameplay in Trailer 2, but fans are theorizing that this cutscene may seamlessly transition into the beginning of GTA 6, with players thrust into controlling Jason as he walks around his house.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If true, it may be the case that GTA 6 features two of these sections: one for Jason and one for Lucia, the game’s second playable protagonist. The theory here is that GTA 6 will feature a similar transition into gameplay moment for Lucia, helping the player get to grips with the dual protagonist gameplay ahead of the time-skip to when Lucia leaves prison.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Moving on, fans are focusing their attention on an image transition on the recently updated official GTA 6 website, which sees the camera swing around from spotlighting Jason to spotlighting Lucia as they share an embrace.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Some are wondering if this is a character select screen that might display when you load the game. The expectation is you’ll be able to swap between Jason and Lucia during gameplay, but perhaps GTA 6 gives you the chance to pick between the two upon getting back into the game, and if so, this could be what we’ll see.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are all sorts of theories on the nature of Jason and Lucia’s relationship and where the story will take it. I’ve seen everything from speculation that Jason is an undercover cop to either Jason or Lucia or perhaps even both dying at the end of the story. Most seem convinced either Jason or Lucia betrays the other at some point, which would be criminal. Perhaps we’ll get to choose via an optional ending system.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just a note on the Jason is a cop theory: Jason tells the prison security guard, when picking up Lucia, that he might have been there before. In what capacity? Later, an older cop says, “Us cops, we’ve got to protect each other,” before the trailer cuts to Jason shooting at a moving car.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This leads on to a theory that GTA 6 may feature a third playable character that Rockstar is keeping secret so it’s a surprise to fans, and that this older cop may be it. Could you shift perspective to a cop hunting down Jason and Lucia during the story?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, this is a brilliantly silly fan theory: previous GTA games are <em>films</em> in the world of GTA 6. Phil Cassidy, the arms dealer from Vice City and GTA 3, is at the heart of this theory. In those games he’s missing an arm, but there is a character seen on Jason’s TV during the GTA 6 trailer that looks a lot like Cassidy — except he has both arms.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, what’s happening here? If this is indeed Cassidy, then how does he have both arms? Could the GTA 6 Cassidy be Phil Cassidy’s son? Or his grandson?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Adding to the confusion is GTA's seperated universes structure. The GTA series is divided into three distinct parallel universes, officially named by Rockstar North as the "2D Universe", "3D Universe," and the "HD Universe."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The 2D Universe includes the original top-down GTA games developed by DMA Design. The 3D Universe starts with GTA 3 and includes its prequels, such as Vice City. And the HD Universe starts with GTA 4 and includes GTA 5, GTA Online, and the upcoming GTA 6, with each game set in the same year it was released. Following this, GTA 6 will be set in 2026, aka the modern day.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, while these are meant to be distinct parallel universes, there is a lot of crossover between them, with shared place names, characters, some lore, and more besides. But certainly no-one was expecting Phil Cassidy from Vice City to pop up in GTA 6, as it makes the 'distinct parallel universes' thing even trickier.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, perhaps having GTA’s 3D Universe games as films in the ongoing HD Universe would help resolve these issues. We do see what looks like Phil Cassidy on Jason's TV, after all. Or, this Phil Cassidy has nothing more than a fun Easter egg Rockstar added to GTA 6 to spark exactly this kind of speculation. This is Rockstar, after all!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Trailer 2 has also reinforced existing theories that GTA 6 will feature heists, and that there is a heavy influence from the Fast &amp; Furious movies. At one point we see a truck with a vault attached to it, similar to the Fast 5 scene that does pretty much the same thing.</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Marvrassiczilla 🅰️🦖🦎🦍 (@Movie__Fans) <a href="https://twitter.com/Movie__Fans/status/1919772545617952866?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">May 6, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">More GTA 6 fan theories are popping up all the time as people dig into Trailer 2. Expect plenty more in the year we have to wait until GTA 6 comes out.</p><div id="every-rockstar-game-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Every Rockstar Game Tier List</h3><h3>Every Rockstar Game Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Reacts To $80 Games, Isn't Planning To Follow Suit Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-reacts-to-80-games-isnt-planning-to-follow-suit-yet/1100-6531352/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-reacts-to-80-games-isnt-planning-to-follow-suit-yet.1183053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-reacts-to-80-games-isnt-planning-to-follow-suit-yet/1100-6531352/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531352">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>With Nintendo announcing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/did-nintendo-justify-mario-kart-worlds-80-price/1100-6530956/">Mario Kart World as an $80 launch game</a> for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/">Switch 2</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-consoles-games-and-accessories-see-price-increases-starting-today/1100-6531257/">Microsoft also confirming</a> that its first-party titles will be sold at the same price, it looks like gaming is about to get a lot more expensive. Similarly to how base video game prices increased from $60 to $70 starting in 2020, other publishers will likely start to charge more for their products, but EA isn't currently planning to join this trend.</p><p>During a Q&amp;A session of its Q4 and FY2025 earnings conference call, EA was asked whether it would adopt a similar approach to other companies and adjust its "pricing power" for key IP in the future. "Our business is very different today than it was even just 10 years ago," EA CEO Andrew Wilson explained.</p><p>"In a world where everything we did 10 years ago was about selling shiny discs in plastic boxes in retail shelves, well that's still a part of our business. It's a significantly smaller part of our business, and we now have pricing representing everything from free-to-play all the way to deluxe editions and beyond. At the end of the day, whether we’re doing something that costs a dollar, or we're doing something that costs $10, or we're doing something that costs $100, our objective is always delivering incredible quality and exponential value to our player base. And what we've discovered over the course of time is whether we can marry quality and value together, our business is strong, resilient and continues to grow."</p><p>"From a games perspective, we have reflected no changes in our current strategy at this point," EA CFO Stuart Canfield added. It's worth noting that EA makes a <em>lot </em>of money from microtransactions. EA recorded $5.34 billion in this department in its 2025 financial year, and in comparison, video game sales brought in $2 billion in sales.</p><p>These comments come on the back of EA's publication of its fourth-quarter results for the three months ending on March 31, 2025. Wilson said that the company "significantly exceeded expectations" thanks primarily to games like EA Sports FC in Q4, The Sims, and Split Fiction. Live-service revenue also increased by 1% to $1.42 billion during this quarter, The Sims experienced the best growth in the history of the franchise, and total Split Fiction sales are nearly double what EA expected from the Hazelight Studios-developed game.</p><p>At the same time, it hasn't been smooth sailing at EA, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-studio-cancels-two-incubation-projects-lays-off-staff-amid-big-ea-shakeup/1100-6531200/">as hundreds of workers were laid off</a> and two "early-stage" incubation projects at Respawn Interactive were canceled.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Payday 3 Just Underwent A Major Change]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-3-just-underwent-a-major-change/1100-6531354/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/payday-3-just-underwent-a-major-change.1183050/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-3-just-underwent-a-major-change/1100-6531354/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531354">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Payday 3 developer Starbreeze Studios has announced that it has reached an agreement with Plaion to acquire the publishing rights to the game. The company says that this deal will allow it to accelerate its content-development plans for Payday 3, and "pursue broader strategic opportunities" for the Payday franchise.</p><p>To secure the deal, Starbreeze issued $3.4 million in new shares--representing 10% of its outstanding share capital--with the bulk of the sales going toward repaying Plaion under its previous Payday 3 agreement and settling "certain outstanding" claims. Interestingly, <a href="https://www.starbreeze.com/news/starbreeze-enters-into-agreement-regarding-the-publishing-rights-for-payday-3-and-carries-out-a-directed-share-issue-of-class-b-shares-amounting-to-sek-33-million/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Starbreeze has hinted</a> at new Payday projects in its announcement, as it'll continue to work with Plaion on "future Payday franchise" projects as part of its long-term strategy.</p><p>Following on the heels of the successful Payday 2, Payday 3 got off to a rocky start when it launched in 2023. The game was beset with various technical issues, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-3-sales-and-player-numbers-significantly-lower-than-hoped-for/1100-6521109/">low player numbers</a>, and a mandatory online-only requirement that proved to be very unpopular with the Payday community. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-ceo-is-gone-after-games-bad-start-and-low-player-numbers/1100-6521797/">Starbreeze's CEO Tobias Sjogren left the company in 2024</a> and the studio <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-3-developer-knows-you-arent-satisfied-with-the-game-and-will-show-a-plan-next-month/1100-6520387/">announced plans to improve the game</a> through <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/payday-3-developer-knows-you-arent-satisfied-with-the-game-and-will-show-a-plan-next-month/1100-6520387/">various patches</a> as part of an effort titled Operation: Medic Bag.</p><p>Beyond Payday, Starbreeze is also working on a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-dungeons-dragons-game-is-a-multiplayer-co-op-adventure-from-the-makers-of-payday/1100-6519684/">Dungeons &amp; Dragons game for all major platforms</a>. Not much is known about the game, but it is expected to be released in 2026.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531357&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/netflix-layout-getting-a-major-overhaul-with-a-dedicated-tab-for-games\/1100-6531357\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531267&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-made-a-key-change-to-the-switch-eshop-that-you-might-have-missed\/1100-6531267\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531306&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/thunderbolts-success-shows-just-how-big-a-minecraft-movie-was\/1100-6531306\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531263&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/obilivion-remastered-is-hiding-a-character-voiced-by-todd-howard-just-like-the-original\/1100-6531263\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531307&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fallout-1-and-2-source-code-wasnt-destroyed-after-all\/1100-6531307\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531295&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/game-pass-just-added-another-call-of-duty-game\/1100-6531295\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6476419&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/free-games-epic-games-store\/1100-6476419\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527851&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-18-batman-animated-movies-on-blu-ray-for-only-45-for-a-limited-time\/1100-6527851\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531270&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-up-to-18-steam-games-for-as-low-as-2-85-each-with-fanaticals-latest-bundle\/1100-6531270\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531296&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-complete-fortnites-secret-star-wars-story-quests\/1100-6531296\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531298&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sims-4-needs-and-motives-how-to-keep-your-sims-happy-and-alive\/1100-6531298\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531314&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gears-of-war-reloaded-remaster-coming-this-august-to-xbox-playstation-and-pc\/1100-6531314\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531315&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-lawsuit-continues-as-judge-rejects-bungies-use-of-youtube-videos-and-wikis\/1100-6531315\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531312&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/next-assassins-creed-shadows-update-announced-adds-new-story-mission-and-fixes-a-deer-problem\/1100-6531312\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531313&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hello-kitty-island-adventure-is-celebrating-spring-with-an-egg-celent-free-content-update\/1100-6531313\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531309&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-episode-5-will-finally-introduce-one-of-the-games-most-challenging-elements\/1100-6531309\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531310&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-a-massive-discount-on-apples-newest-mac-mini-at-amazon\/1100-6531310\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531228&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-splintered-fate-collectors-deluxe-edition-amazon-preorder\/1100-6531228\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531287&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-collectors-edition-is-50-off\/1100-6531287\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531297&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/halo-infinite-is-adding-one-of-halos-most-absurd-and-incredible-looking-guns-to-date\/1100-6531297\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>