<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:37:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ArenaNet To Release ‘Godspawn’ Update for Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds on November 19, Featuring New 50-Player Titan Battle and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/arenanet-to-release-godspawn-update-for-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-on-november-19-featuring-new-50-player-titan-battle-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arenanet-to-release-%E2%80%98godspawn%E2%80%99-update-for-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-on-november-19-featuring-new-50-player-titan-battle-and-more.1035087/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/arenanet-to-release-godspawn-update-for-guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-on-november-19-featuring-new-50-player-titan-battle-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-2-janthir-wilds-finally-launched-bringing-in-housing-mechanism-new-raids-much-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds</a> will receive the Godspawn update, adding a new 50-player boss battle, a new 10-player raid, and a legendary spear.</p>
<h2>Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds is getting the first major update "Godspawn" on November 19th, expanding the story with new story chapters</h2>
<p>The MMORPG Guild Wars 2 by ArenaNet is receiving its first major update for the Janthir Wilds expansion soon. It's the first of three major updates, and it'll land on November 19. The update will add new content to the game for the players.</p>
<p>The <em>Janthir Wilds&nbsp;</em>expansion DLC was released in August this year, bringing unexplored wilds and&nbsp;<em>Homestead&nbsp;</em>for players to decorate and cultivate. With the <em>Godspawn&nbsp;</em>update, the game will bring three new story chapters to continue the adventure against the Titans. This time, ArenaNet has introduced a new 50-player battle against a Titan, who will be the reinterpretation of <em>Decima. </em>It will be similar to the boss battles as introduced in the <em>Secrets of the Obscure </em>Convergence.</p>
<p>Players can enter the battle every three hours, but private squads can start the challenge at any time. Apart from the boss battle, Guild Wars 2 will also receive a new 10-player raid, allowing players to climb Mount Balrior to battle the titans of Janthir to obtain rewards such as marquee items and cosmetics.</p>
<figure><figcaption>Image Credit: guildwars2.com</figcaption></figure>
<p>The 10-player raid will feature three bosses and several smaller battles that will allow players to enhance their coordination and adaptability. The two bosses,&nbsp;<strong>Greer&nbsp;</strong>and&nbsp;<strong>Decima</strong>, will regroup once again at Mount Balrior, stronger than before as this time they won't be alone and will also have newer abilities.</p>
<p><iframe title="Guild Wars 2: Janthir Wilds – &quot;Godspawn&quot;" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jrol0Nr8q_Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Several new updates are also on the way in Godspawn update, including the new Sea Wave Glass weapon, more rewards in the Wizard's Vault like skins for armor and boots, and new decorations for Homestead to customize living space. A new legendary spear, <em>Klobjarne,&nbsp;</em>will be available to players as well. The Godspawn update will be free for those who have purchased the <em>Janther Wilds&nbsp;</em>expansion. Two more updates will be released in the coming months to complete the expansion.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Classic RTS Games Warcraft and Warcraft 2 Fully Remastered And Out Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/warcraft-2-3-rts-classic-remastered-blizzard-pc-1851697730</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/classic-rts-games-warcraft-and-warcraft-2-fully-remastered-and-out-now.1035078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/warcraft-2-3-rts-classic-remastered-blizzard-pc-1851697730<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="36a921a64d7372dad3b22e6f1dd24d85" data-recommend-id="image://36a921a64d7372dad3b22e6f1dd24d85" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows an orc and human from Warcraft 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows an orc and human from Warcraft 2. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="36a921a64d7372dad3b22e6f1dd24d85" data-recommend-id="image://36a921a64d7372dad3b22e6f1dd24d85" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows an orc and human from Warcraft 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Blizzard has announced that the original <em>Warcraft</em> and <em>Warcraft 2</em>, as well as its expansions, are being remastered and re-released as part of a new Battle Chest. This new package also includes <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/warcraft-iii-reign-of-chaos&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/warcraft-iii-reign-of-chaos"><em>Warcraft 3 Reforged</em></a></span>, which has received a new update improving its visuals. And all of this is available today. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195326" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="326" data-playlist="195326,195150,195618" data-current="195326"><div><p>Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20784.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;http://<iframe width=\&quot;1730\&quot; height=\&quot;666\&quot; src=\&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0rEfOTxr59o\&quot; title=\&quot;Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct: Celebrations, Reflections, and a Look Ahead\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;0\&quot; allow=\&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share\&quot; referrerpolicy=\&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin\&quot; allowfullscreen></iframe>&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://<iframe width=&quot;1730&quot; height=&quot;666&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0rEfOTxr59o&quot; title=&quot;Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct: Celebrations, Reflections, and a Look Ahead&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen></iframe>">During Wednesday’s <em>Warcraft</em> 30th Anniversary Direct</a></span> event, Blizzard announced a series of updates to existing <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/wow-war-within-review-expansion-is-it-good-1851643832&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/wow-war-within-review-expansion-is-it-good-1851643832"><em>Warcraft</em></a></span><em> </em>games. For example, <em>Warcraft Rumble</em> is getting new heroes and will be playable on PC next month. And <em>Warcraft’</em>s spin-off card game, <em>Hearthstone, </em>is getting a <em>Starcraft </em>mini-expansion in January 2025. But the big news was the announcement and release of a new <em>Warcraft </em>RTS collection bringing remastered versions of the first three games to a new generation via a just-released updated edition of the classic Battle Chest<em>. </em></p><p>On November 13, Blizzard announced that it was remastering the first two <em>Warcraft </em>RTS games—-<em>Warcraft: Orcs and Heroes </em>and <em>Warcraft II</em> and its expansion, <em>Beyond The Dark Portal—</em>to celebrate 30 years of the franchise. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/ryZ2jiW95qo&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/ryZ2jiW95qo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Here’s the trailer</a></span> for the newly announced remasters. </p><p>As shown in the trailer above, Blizzard’s new<em> Warcraft </em>Battle Chest also includes the previously remastered <em>Warcraft 3: Reforged</em>. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/warcraft-3-reforged-isn-t-much-of-an-upgrade-1841325885?_gl=1*1ymvzon*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxNjMyNy4yOS4xLjE3MzE1MjI5NDcuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/warcraft-3-reforged-isn-t-much-of-an-upgrade-1841325885?_gl=1*1ymvzon*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxNjMyNy4yOS4xLjE3MzE1MjI5NDcuNjAuMC4w">That game launched in 2020  to negative reviews</a></span> from fans, and since then Blizzard has updated it to improve the remastered RTS. Today, as part of the new <em>Battle Chest</em>, <em>Reforged </em>is getting a new 2.0 update. This update improves the visuals and adds new options to let players use more classic art and models. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The <em>Warcraft </em>Battle Chest is now available on Battle.net</a></span> for PC and includes not only the three remastered <em>Warcraft </em>games but also the original <em>Warcraft 1 </em>and <em>2</em> as well. So if you want to replay the OG versions of these beloved strategy games, you can do that, too. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft: Classic Heads to Mists of Pandaria Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-classic-heads-to-mists-of-pandaria-next-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-warcraft-classic-heads-to-mists-of-pandaria-next-year.1035063/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-classic-heads-to-mists-of-pandaria-next-year<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">During today’s Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct, Blizzard announced its next big plans for World of Warcraft: Classic. Shocking no one, it’s planning to move onto the next expansion in 2025: Mists of Pandaria.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As with other Classic expansions, Mists of Pandaria will launch with “some changes” to its original form, but will largely retain the same  content and features from when it first released in 2012. Among other new features, Mists of Pandaria introduced the continent of Pandaria, the playable Pandaran race that could join either the Alliance or the Horde, the Monk class, pet battles, Scenarios, and flexible raiding.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Notably, though, this will be a different experience than the one offered during the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-is-revisiting-mists-of-pandaria-in-world-of-warcraft-remix">recent Mists of Pandaria: Remix event</a>, which allowed players to speed level through Pandaria with new spells and abilities, new items, and other twists on its original gameplay.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The addition of Mists of Pandaria furthers World of Warcraft: Classic’s steady march to catch up with existing World of Warcraft content. However, recently some Classic players have begun to criticize the direction of the game and lament how far away it’s gotten from the original Classic feel as expansions have been added. While Blizzard has done some things to address this, such as add new Classic modes like Hardcore and Season of Discovery, players are increasingly asking for more opportunities to replay the oldest content.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For those players, Blizzard announced that it will be adding new “vanilla” Classic realms on November 21. This will include new PvP, PvE, and new “hardcore mode” realms, which will go through the same steady cadence of patch updates as past Classic realms, with the Molten Core raid launching a few weeks after launch. These new realms (minus the Hardcore realms) will eventually progress to The Burning Crusade Classic, giving players the opportunity to start all over once more and progress through early WoW content.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">World of Warcraft: Classic’s Mists of Pandaria update will launch sometime in 2025. You can catch up with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-30th-anniversary-direct-everything-announced">everything announced from today’s Warcraft Direct right here</a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-shadow-dropped-with-improved-graphics-quality-of-life-improvements-and-other-new-features">remasters of Warcraft I and II</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-major-patch-will-finally-visit-the-legendary-goblin-capital-undermine">next patch for The War Within</a>, and teases of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-expansion-finally-adding-player-housing-after-years-of-requests-by-fans">next WoW retail expansion</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft 1 and 2 Remasters Shadow-Dropped With Improved Graphics, Quality-of-Life Improvements, and Other New Features]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-shadow-dropped-with-improved-graphics-quality-of-life-improvements-and-other-new-features</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-shadow-dropped-with-improved-graphics-quality-of-life-improvements-and-other-new-features.1035060/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-shadow-dropped-with-improved-graphics-quality-of-life-improvements-and-other-new-features<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s the 30th anniversary of Warcraft, and to celebrate, Blizzard is bringing back a couple of bonafide classics. Today, Blizzard announced it’s releasing remasters of both the original Warcraft and Warcraft 2, and they’re both out today.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">During today’s Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct stream, Blizzard unveiled both remasters, which will include fully updated graphics as well as an option to revert back to original visuals, a number of quality of life features, and improved UI and UX features. Warcraft II will also include multiplayer, with all legacy custom maps being compatible and playable.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Critically, these are both being billed as remasters rather than full-blown “reimaginings” like Warcraft III: Reforged. Fans of the original game widely panned Warcraft III: Reforged due to the many changes made from the original, technical issues, and features that were missing or degraded from the original. Our own reviewer <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-3-reforged-review">gave it a 7/10</a>, but described it as "uninspired." Upon its release, many fans expressed frustration that Blizzard had not simply remastered the original Warcraft III, which may be why Blizzard opted for a lighter touch with Warcraft I and II.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, Warcraft III: Reforged is also receiving an update today that will include a graphics overhaul and various other quality of life changes that may improve the experience. These include the ability to toggle between the game’s new graphics, old graphics, and a new remastered look that’s reminiscent of the classic look but has a higher resolution. Reforged players will also get the ability to mix and match certain UI elements in all three graphic options.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Warcraft III: Reforged will join the remasters of Warcraft 1 and 2 in a revamped “Battle Chest” hearkening back to the classic, popular bundle. The bundle’s pricing will adjust based on what games players already own, meaning if you already own Reforged, you can add the two remasters at a discount.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Warcraft I and II Remastered, Warcraft III: Reforged 2.0, and the new Battle Chest are out today. You can catch up with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-30th-anniversary-direct-everything-announced">everything announced from today’s Warcraft Direct right here</a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-major-patch-will-finally-visit-the-legendary-goblin-capital-undermine">upcoming updates to World of Warcraft</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-classic-heads-to-mists-of-pandaria-next-year">World of Warcraft: Classic</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-expansion-finally-adding-player-housing-after-years-of-requests-by-fans">teases of the next retail expansion, Midnight</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After 20 Long Years, WoW Is Getting Player Housing In Its Midnight Expansion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-20-long-years-wow-is-getting-player-housing-in-its-midnight-expansion/1100-6527718/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-20-long-years-wow-is-getting-player-housing-in-its-midnight-expansion.1035057/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-20-long-years-wow-is-getting-player-housing-in-its-midnight-expansion/1100-6527718/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527718">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a> is, at long last, getting player housing. Blizzard confirmed during its recent Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct that the long-asked-for feature will be part of the MMORPG's future Midnight expansion, saving the biggest crowd-pleasing announcement of the livestream for last.</p><p dir="ltr">In a short teaser video, a Death Knight walks into a nondescript house. Inside, the walls are adorned with the head of the dragon Onyxia, various weapons and shields, a miniature Goblin shredder mech, and more. The weary adventurer puts down their sword, settles into a chair by the fire, and takes a sip from a mug adorned with the words "Home Sweet Home."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fQXHFrLX6A4" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fQXHFrLX6A4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">That's about all there is to go on, but GameSpot did get the chance to chat with WoW game director Ion Hazzikostas prior to the anniversary livestream about the big news. He confirmed the feature has been in the works for several years.</p><p dir="ltr">"I've definitely given some cagey and evasive answers about 'housing ever?' while knowing secretly it was going to come to pass," Hazzikostas said. "We've known we've wanted to do it for real for some time. I think figuring out the how and when and making sure we can deliver something that's going to meet our players' expectations and exceed them, that's all the tricky parts to it. What we're announcing this week is a teaser, a hint, the slimmest of previews, just letting people know, 'Hey, it's coming as part of Midnight.'"</p><p dir="ltr">He said much more information will come over the course of the next year, but that the team is excited to have it out in the open so they can start to hear what players want from digital housing in Azeroth.</p><p dir="ltr">"Just excited to get that news out there and to begin a conversation so we can start hearing from players what they're hoping to see from a World of Warcraft housing system," Hazzikostas said. "Double-check it matches what we are currently cooking but also gives us some time to pivot and make sure we deliver what players are hoping for."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398397-worldofwarcraft%28modern%292025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4398397" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398397-worldofwarcraft%28modern%292025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4398397"></a><figcaption>More about Midnight will be revealed next summer, according to WoW's 2025 roadmap.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398397-worldofwarcraft%28modern%292025roadmap.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">During BlizzCon 2023, Blizzard announced the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-next-three-expansions-revealed-all-at-once-including-2024-the-war-within/1100-6518914/" data-ref-id="1100-6518914">next three WoW expansions all at once</a> and said it hoped to start delivering expansions at a faster pace than its normal two-year expansion cycle. According to Blizzard's newly revealed 2025 WoW content roadmap, Midnight is not coming next year, though more details about the expansion will be revealed next summer.</p><p dir="ltr">Hazzikostas noted that even though Midnight isn't coming next year and players will still be playing The War Within in 2025, the team is dedicated to keeping the game's update cadence going at a steady pace while still getting a full-fledged new expansion ready "in a timely manner."</p><p dir="ltr">Players housing in WoW was just one of many Warcraft-related announcements to come out of the Warcraft 30th Anniversary Stream. Blizzard additionally announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/" data-ref-id="1100-6527719">remastered versions of Warcraft 1 and 2 (available now)</a>, a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/" data-ref-id="1100-6527722">StarCraft crossover for Hearthstone</a>, and what's next for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria/1100-6527720/" data-ref-id="1100-6527720">WoW Classic</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Price Cut For The Holidays Edited Out Of New Sony Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-price-cut-for-the-holidays-edited-out-of-new-sony-trailer/1100-6527747/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-price-cut-for-the-holidays-edited-out-of-new-sony-trailer.1035051/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-price-cut-for-the-holidays-edited-out-of-new-sony-trailer/1100-6527747/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527747">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>On November 12, Sony published a marketing trailer for the PlayStation 5 that ended with the announcement that the digital PS5 Slim would be marked down for the holidays. That trailer has since been edited and re-uploaded to remove all mention of the temporary discount.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KiNPo7KvWCM" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The trailer originally stated</a> that the digital PS5 Slim would be on sale until December 24 for $380. The system originally launched for $400 before <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-slim-playstation-5-models-announced-all-digital-sees-50-price-increase/1100-6518283/" data-ref-id="1100-6518283">Sony raised the price to $450</a>.  Bringing it down to $380 for the holidays is a nice offer, and hopefully it comes back. <a href="https://x.com/Xbox/status/1855671773330579913" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Microsoft already slashed the price of the Xbox Series X by $50 for the holidays.</a></p><p>The video has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KiNPo7KvWCM" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">since been re-uploaded</a>, with many commenters poking fun at Sony for editing out mention of the deal.</p><p>GameSpot has contacted Sony to try to find out what's going on here.</p><p>Companies like Sony, Microsoft, and Nintendo typically offer discounts on their consoles and games for Black Friday and the wider holiday shopping season, and it's expected Sony will eventually roll out a PS5 discount. In other PS5 news, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/spend-1800-on-jewelry-get-a-ps5/1100-6527715/" data-ref-id="1100-6527715">if you spend $1,800 on high-end jewelry, you can get a free PS5.</a></p><p>Sony just released the PS5 Pro, but the console is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/just-who-is-the-ps5-pro-for/1100-6526452/" data-ref-id="1100-6526452">aimed at a very small tech-enthusiast market rather than the general consumer.</a> Some analysts are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kids-wants-video-games-more-than-money-for-the-holidays-study-finds/1100-6527738/" data-ref-id="1100-6527738">predicting a grim holiday for new console sales.</a></p><p>If you don't want a PS5, Nintendo just announced its own set of Black Friday deals, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-holiday-deals-2024-console-bundles/1100-6526528/" data-ref-id="1100-6526528">discounts on Switch bundles.</a> Nintendo is expected to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-confirms-switch-2-announcement-is-still-five-months-away-at-most/1100-6527576/" data-ref-id="1100-6527576">announce the Switch 2 in the next few months.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Black Friday Deals for Xbox Series X|S]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-xbox-series-xs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-black-friday-deals-for-xbox-series-x-s.1035012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-xbox-series-xs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ready for Black Friday? With Christmas just around the corner, many gamers are trying to grab the best deals possible. Like every year, Xbox has quite a few deals people can choose from. Here are the best Black Friday Deals for Xbox Series X|S.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-xbox-series-x-s-black-friday-deals">Best Xbox Series X|S Black Friday Deals</h2>



<p>Excited to find the best Xbox Series X|S deals this Black Friday? Well, Xbox will be doing quite a few deals for Xbox Series X|S systems, controllers and games.</p>



<p>However, no actual Black Friday deals have been released by the company, many are already speculating that the system will have huge bundle deals at stores like Walmart, Target, Best Buy and more.</p>



<p>Every year, too, many of these popular retail stores have a bunch of different discounts on games. With popular titles like Call of Duty just releasing a new game, gamers should expect to see deals revolving around the games to release on Black Friday.</p>







<h2 id="h-current-xbox-series-x-s-deals">Current Xbox Series X|S Deals</h2>



<p>Luckily, Xbox has a ton of deals already in its store, meaning gamers can indulge in the Black Friday festivities early on. Below is a list of current Xbox deals gamers can grab in the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/promotions/sales/sales-and-specials">Microsoft store:</a></p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/consoles/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X ($50 off)</a></li>
</ul>



<p>The page also has quite a few games for sale, too. However, the majority of these games for sale are not big titles. The big titles, like Call of Duty and more, will not be released until Black Friday.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-get-black-friday-deals">How to Get Black Friday Deals</h2>



<p>Luckily, Black Friday deals are not as difficult to come by as they were in the past when you had to wait outside a store until midnight. Many retailers, like Walmart and Target, will release their deals earlier in the day on Thanksgiving, giving consumers the chance to grab whatever their heart desires early on.</p>



<p>Still, many deals, especially on Xbox games and systems, will go incredibly fast, so be prepared to have your money out.</p>



<p>For more Insider Gaming guides, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-nintendo-switch/">best Black Friday Nintendo Switch deals.</a> </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Pokémon Card Deals I Want to See for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-card-deals-black-friday-predictions-for-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-pok%C3%A9mon-card-deals-i-want-to-see-for-black-friday.1035009/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-card-deals-black-friday-predictions-for-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Big boxes and ETBs at Black Friday prices.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">We all want to be the very best Pokémon TCG player and collector, like no was ever was. We also all know the value of a bargain on booster boxes, big box premium collections, elite trainer boxes, and more. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024">Black Friday 2024</a> should be loaded with Pokédeals, making it the best time of year to invest in some sealed products to rip open or hold on to.  </p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Pokémon Card Deal Predictions for Black Friday</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Grading Pokémon cards is also becoming more popular than ever before. Trainers won't find cards in better condition than being pack fresh, but opening packs rather than buying singles can rack up a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-most-expensive-pokemon-cards">Gollum of cash</a>. I'm a Pokémon Master, and the following products are on my radar for Black Friday 2024. Let's get into it:</p><p id="tyranitar-and-tsareena-ex-premium-co"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Tyranitar and Tsareena ex Premium Co">Big Box Deals</h2></p><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-and-violet-shro"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet and Violet Shro">Booster Bundles</h2></p><div catalogid="6d085d9e-2e49-411e-bbed-dfc088fe5390" id="210092"><div id="210092" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet and Violet Shrouded Fable Booster Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Need to complete a set sooner rather than later? Booster bundles are the offordable way to get multiple boosters to rip open in one sitting. Yes, booster boxes are ideal for collectors, but they're mostly touching or well above $100. Booster bundles have six boosters per box for just north of $20, with Black Friday bringing price points down further. Here's what I'm betting on:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/ak7g0W?object_uuid=4866ebd6-6a8d-4bb4-a2e1-614540c4fe85&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Stellar Crown booster bundle</a></li></ul></div><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violet-elite"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Elite ">Pokémon TCG Elite Trainer Boxes</h2></p><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violet-stella"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Stella">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Stellar Crown Build &amp; Battle</h2></p><p id="pokmon-iono-premium-tournament-coll"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon Iono Premium Tournament Coll">Pokémon Iono Premium Tournament Collection Box</h2></p><div catalogid="6d085d9e-2e49-411e-bbed-dfc088fe5390" id="210095"><div id="210095" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon Iono Premium Tournament Collection Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Deck Box? Check! Sleeves? Check! Four foil supporter cards (one being full art) and everything you need for a Pokémon Card battle? Check! These themed tournament collection boxes are a trainer card fan boys dream and a cheap way to get some exclusive swag for your themed deck. Here's what I'm expecting on Black Friday:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QOD0rM?object_uuid=4866ebd6-6a8d-4bb4-a2e1-614540c4fe85&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pokemon Klara Premium Tournament Collection</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/z3b6rR?object_uuid=4866ebd6-6a8d-4bb4-a2e1-614540c4fe85&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pokemon Cyrus Premium Tournament Collection
</a></li></ul></div><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violet-sleeve"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet Sleeve">Booster Packs and Boxes</h2></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 13, 2024 5:00 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 5 Returns to PlayStation Plus Game Catalog for November 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-5-returns-to-playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-5-returns-to-playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-2024.1035006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-5-returns-to-playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has confirmed its PlayStation Plus Game Catalog lineup for November 2024, and it includes the return of Rockstar’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">GTA 5</a> in what's an impressive month for subscribers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a post on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/11/13/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-grand-theft-auto-v-dying-light-2-stay-human-like-a-dragon-ishin-and-more/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a>, Sony also confirmed heavy hitters <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dying-light-2">Dying Light 2: Stay Human</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/like-a-dragon-ishin">Like a Dragon: Ishin</a> join the subscription service from November 19.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the same day, five new games join PlayStation Plus Premium: PS VR2 game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/synapse">Synapse</a> and four Classics; <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/blood-omen-legacy-of-kain">Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/blood-omen-2-legacy-of-kain">Blood Omen 2</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resistance-fall-of-man">Resistance: Fall of Man</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resistance-2">Resistance 2</a>. It’s worth noting <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-2-remastered">Soul Reaver 1 &amp; 2 Remastered</a> launch next month, so these classics are well-timed. It's also worth bearing in mind that the included Resistance games are streaming only for PlayStation Plus Premium.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">PlayStation Plus Game Catalog lineup for November 2024:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium | Game Catalog</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Grand Theft Auto 5 | PS4, PS5</li><li>Dying Light 2: Stay Human | PS4, PS5</li><li>Like a Dragon: Ishin | PS4, PS5</li><li>MotoGP 24 | PS4, PS5</li><li>The Sims 4 Island Living (add-on only) | PS4</li><li>Digimon Survive | PS4</li><li>Overcooked! All You Can Eat | PS4, PS5</li><li>Stick Fight: The Game | PS4</li><li>Clash: Artifacts of Chaos | PS4, PS5</li><li>Killer Frequency | PS4, PS5</li><li>Hungry Shark World | PS4</li><li>Chivalry 2 | PS4, PS5</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PlayStation Plus Premium</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Synapse | PS VR2</li><li>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain | PS4, PS5</li><li>Blood Omen 2 | PS4, PS5</li><li>Resistance: Fall of Man</li><li>Resistance 2</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft: Remastered and Warcraft II: Remastered announced for PC, now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/warcraft-remastered-and-warcraft-ii-remastered-announced-for-pc-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-remastered-and-warcraft-ii-remastered-announced-for-pc-now-available.1035003/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/warcraft-remastered-and-warcraft-ii-remastered-announced-for-pc-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest bundle includes the full trilogy.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Blizzard Entertainment [149 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/blizzard-entertainment">Blizzard Entertainment</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Warcraft: Remastered" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/warcraft-remastered">Warcraft: Remastered</a></em> and <em><a title="Games > Warcraft II: Remastered" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/warcraft-ii-remastered">Warcraft II: Remastered</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,685 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>. Both titles are available now via Battle.net for $9.99 each. A <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest?p=1863680" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest</em></a> bundle including <em>Warcraft: Remastered</em>, <em>Warcraft II: Remastered</em>, and <em><a title="Games > Warcraft III: Reforged" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/warcraft-iii-reforged">Warcraft III: Reforged</a></em> is also available for $39.99. <span id="more-927439"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of each game, via their store pages:</p><blockquote><h2><span><em>Warcraft: Remastered</em> (<a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-1-remastered" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Battle.net</a>)</span></h2><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Warcraft-Remastered-Ann_11-13-24_WC1.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Relive the original <em>Warcraft</em> tale of <em>Orcs &amp; Humans</em>.</p><p>Journey back to the beginning of a 30-year legacy with the first <em>Warcraft</em> story created in 1994, now remastered with vivid, all-new visuals and modernized controls!</p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the inciting war between Orcs and Humans that shook Azeroth to its core. Defend the realm as the noble Alliance, or seek to conquer it as the bloodthirsty Horde across thrilling faction campaigns or custom skirmish games. Whichever side you take, there has never been a better time to charge into the legendary battles of Azeroth’s greatest heroes in the <em>Warcraft</em> universe.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Rediscover Iconic Sights and Sounds</strong> – Toggle between the classic art and the lovingly updated hand-painted artwork. Take in the full view of epic battles with widescreen support and numerous visual updates for the user interface. Enjoy the classic musical themes, now uncompressed and rebalanced.</li><li><strong>Classic Gameplay, Modern Controls</strong> – Modern improvements, such as health bars, increased unit selection, hotkey indicators, and more have been added to build a seamless experience for a modern audience.</li><li><strong>A Preservation Of History</strong> – Having excavated original concept art from 1994, <em>Warcraft: Remastered</em> includes a plethora of never-before-seen pieces that heralded the beginnings of the <em>Warcraft</em> legacy! Enjoy the lore and history as it was told in the past.</li></ul><h2><span><em>Warcraft II: Remastered</em> (<a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/warcraft-2-remastered" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Battle.net</a>)</span></h2><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Warcraft-Remastered-Ann_11-13-24_WC2.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Master the tides in <em>Warcraft</em>‘s second iconic title.</p><p>Captain your own fleet in the second <em>Warcraft</em> title created in 1995, now remastered with vivid, all-new visuals and modernized controls!</p><p>War between orc and humans rages on across the seas, and the fate of the world hangs in the balance as the great tacticians of the Horde and the Alliance clash. Only one thing is certain: winning this war will demand unprecedented cunning, courage, and nerves of steel.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>The Tides of Darkness Rise Again</strong> – After you’ve experienced the campaign for Tides of Darkness, prepare to take your honed skills into the Beyond the Dark Portal campaign, which is also included in this complete <em>Warcraft II: Remastered</em> package.</li><li><strong>Rediscover Iconic Sights and Sounds</strong> – Toggle between the classic art and the lovingly updated hand-painted artwork. Take in the full view of epic battles with widescreen support and numerous visual updates for the user interface. Enjoy the classic musical themes, now uncompressed and rebalanced.</li><li><strong>Join the Frenzy</strong> – Integrated with your Battle.Net account, test your friends in <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [410 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> on classic or custom maps that support up to eight players at once! Connect globally with players around the world by hosting or joining custom game lobbies.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WoW Classic Is Finally Getting Fresh Servers As Cataclysm Players Move To Pandaria]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria/1100-6527720/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria.1035000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria/1100-6527720/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527720">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a> Classic players begging for fresh "vanilla" servers are finally getting their wish, with new servers set to go live on November 21 in celebration of WoW's 20th anniversary. Meanwhile, those playing Cataclysm Classic will progress on to Mists of Pandaria in 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard announced the news as part of its Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct, along the way confirming in advance the new vanilla servers (minus the fresh Hardcore servers that are also coming) will automatically progress to The Burning Crusade Classic when the time comes. Blizzard said that just because TBC is already confirmed doesn't necessarily mean these new servers will keep moving forward all the way to Cataclysm (the expansion players who have kept progressing from WoW Classic's 2019 launch servers are currently on), but it's hard not to get some sense of deja vu.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uYGvtbrDiiw" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/uYGvtbrDiiw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">In an interview with GameSpot, WoW Classic lead software engineer Nora Valletta and software engineer Kevin Vigue offered more details on what players starting from scratch on the fresh servers can expect, their thoughts on moving on to Mists of Pandaria, and what the team has learned from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-season-of-discovery-looks-to-make-a-20-year-old-game-surprising-again/1100-6519561/" data-ref-id="1100-6519561">more experimental swings like Season of Discovery</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard is using advances in server technology to have larger realms that can hold more players but fewer realms overall for this batch of new servers. In a departure from normal, there will not be dedicated role-playing or RPPvP servers as has usually been the case in the past, Valletta confirmed. Quality-of-life improvements, like the world buff-saving Chronoboon Displacer, faction balancing on PvP realms, and updates to make the original game's punishing Honor PvP rank system less punishing, will be present at launch for these new servers, as will a ban (at least in North America and Europe) on the controversial practice of GDKP runs--something Blizzard first implemented in Season of Discovery. In a change from 2019, the game's first raid, Molten Core, won't launch for a few weeks. The new servers will additionally have a group-finder tool (similar to one that appeared in TBC, Vigue said) to help players find groups without the need of an add-on.</p><p dir="ltr">A recent, unpopular change that saw Blizzard update the guild interface in WoW Classic and Season of Discovery to a more modern version will be reverted come the rollout of the new fresh servers, Vigue announced. Players will instead have the option of choosing between the more modern UI or its original appearance: a choice Blizzard doesn't want to make a habit of offering but said felt right in regards to guilds.</p><p dir="ltr">"We realized, especially once we saw the community reaction, 'Yeah, there is something really nostalgic about the original UI and how it's presented and what it means for that game experience,'" Vigue said.</p><p dir="ltr">Adding to the sense of we've been here before is Blizzard's announcement that Cataclysm Classic servers will move on in Summer 2025 to yet another "new" expansion, 2012's Mists of Pandaria. Players may have already revisited Mists of Pandaria as part of modern WoW's Mists of Pandaria Remix event earlier this year, but Valletta and Vigue said they think the two experiences are different enough to warrant another go around.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399083-wowclassic2025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4399083" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399083-wowclassic2025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4399083"></a><figcaption>WoW Classic's 2025 roadmap.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399083-wowclassic2025roadmap.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Mists of Pandaria Remix used the expansion as backdrop for players to collect exclusive cosmetics and gain new overpowered abilities that could almost one-shot even the game's toughest bosses, but it still played like modern WoW, with all of its current class design, talents, and abilities. Mists of Pandaria Classic will instead play as it did when it first launched over a decade ago. Vigue and Valletta also raised the point that every expansion was some WoW player's entry point into the MMORPG, and so Mists of Pandaria is, for some people, their "classic." It's an expansion that was perhaps under-appreciated in its time, but players now have fond memories of.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think the fact that MoP Remix was so well received speaks to…how much people love Pandaria as a continent and as an expansion," Vigue said.</p><p dir="ltr">As for the currently ongoing WoW Classic Season of Discovery, Blizzard's more experimental take on original WoW that was released towards the tail end of 2023, there's still some new content coming down the pike. The game's Naxxramas update will arrive later this winter. In addition to vanilla WoW's final raid, it will add new "instanced" content in the form of a new encounter against the Scarlet Crusade as well as the Karazhan Crypts, which Blizzard originally teased back when it first announced Season of Discovery at BlizzCon 2023. Vigue and Valletta wouldn't say whether the new content will be in the forms of raids, dungeons, or a combination of both, and instead said players will have to "discover" what's in store themselves.</p><p dir="ltr">Vigue and Valletta also wouldn't comment on what may come next after Season of Discovery--the "team's always cooking," Valletta said--but did say they have learned a ton from the seasonal server in regards to how to create new content for a 20-year-old game while still trying to maintain its original feeling.</p><p dir="ltr">"We've found Season of Discovery to be incredibly successful," Valletta said. "I think part of what made it successful is that sense of…[the new content] is very much down to earth. It wasn't massive, universe-ending world threats. It's you, yourself, as that character in that world…You're not some mighty fine champion hero who everybody knows and everything revolves around you, right? You exist in the world but the world is the main character, and you're part of that."</p><p dir="ltr">All the WoW Classic news was just one part of the Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct. Blizzard also launched new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/" data-ref-id="1100-6527719">remastered versions of Warcraft 1 and 2</a>, announced a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/" data-ref-id="1100-6527722">StarCraft mini-set for Hearthstone</a>, and more.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hearthstone's 2025 Roadmap Includes StarCraft Crossover, Return To Un'Goro Crater]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hearthstones-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-return-to-ungoro-crater.1034997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527722">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/hearthstone-heroes-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-176391">Hearthstone's</a> next mini-set is a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/starcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-20">StarCraft</a> crossover: one that will reimagine the various units of Blizzard's beloved sci-fi RTS in card form. In addition to this, Blizzard announced an entire year's worth of Hearthstone expansions in one go and a dramatic change to the game's Arena mode, giving players a full picture of what to expect in 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">Yes, Blizzard made the bold move of announcing a StarCraft crossover during its Warcraft 30th anniversary direct--a livestream that also celebrated 10 years of Hearthstone. The crossover is the largest mini-set Blizzard has ever done for its digital card game, with 49 total cards.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LFFB2ysJLTQ" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/LFFB2ysJLTQ" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">To learn more, GameSpot sat down with Hearthstone senior game designer Cora Georgiou and game designer Leo Robles Gonzalez ahead of the direct to talk about what it was like adapting StarCraft into card game form, the upcoming changes to Arena, and all of the expansions coming next year.</p><p dir="ltr">Gonzalez said the development team is trying to be a bit more "adventurous," given that the game is a decade old and its players are eager to see new things. That's one of the reasons it went big on the upcoming StarCraft mini-set.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think we're trying to swing pretty hard here," Gonzalez said. "It's the first time we've ever done something this deeply outside of Warcraft."</p><p dir="ltr">Different classes will be able to use a specific StarCraft hero. Each StarCraft faction will have its own set of cards, some of which can be used by any class and others that are class-specific. Warriors, Paladins, and Shamans, for example, can use Jim Raynor and take full advantage of Terran cards, while Death Knights, Hunters, Warlocks, and Demon Hunters can embrace the Zerg swarm with Kerrigan. Meanwhile, Mages, Priests, Rogues, and Druids can use the powers of Artanis, with a focus on powerful, high-mana-cost Protoss units that can be made cheaper.</p><p dir="ltr">Gonzalez said adapting StarCraft into the card game wasn't all that different from adapting Warcraft (both involve lots of research). The main difference was instead of looking to specific characters for card ideas, the team had to draw inspiration from StarCraft's iconic units. Gonzalez said it was also important to capture that feeling of StarCraft's gameplay.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398546-hsheroesofstarcraft-kerriganqueenofblades.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398546" data-ratio="1.1111715139984" data-width="3679" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398546-hsheroesofstarcraft-kerriganqueenofblades.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398546"></a><figcaption>Kerrigan will be usable by Death Knights, Hunters, Warlocks, and Demon Hunters.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398546-hsheroesofstarcraft-kerriganqueenofblades.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">"The gameplay of it--there's micro and there's macro--and it was really important to us to make sure that the macro of, 'What is your game plan overall with one of the three factions'... does that feel quintessentially like them?" Gonzalez said. "That's not something we had to super duper think about with the average Warcraft character."</p><p dir="ltr">The Heroes of StarCraft mini-set will release in January 2025, but the StarCraft crossover was just the tip of the iceberg when it came to Hearthstone announcements. Blizzard also revealed a full 2025 roadmap with three upcoming expansions, as well a major shake-up to the game's Arena mode.</p><p dir="ltr">Arena, Hearthstone's premium draft mode, has been largely unchanged since the game launched in 2014, but that will be changing soon. In the first half of 2025, Blizzard will change Arena in a big way by introducing two versions of Arena to choose from. Normal Arena will be similar to what exists now but sport faster runs while still letting players flex their competitive deck-building muscles. Another new version of the mode, the Underground Arena, will take things even further. The Underground will include players of all skill levels (in contrast to Normal Arena, which will still use a win-based matchmaking system), longer runs, and a new feature called "re-draft on loss" that lets players re-draft cards and edit their deck before going again in order to up their chances of winning. Both Arena modes will have their own ranked system.</p><p dir="ltr">Georgiou said the splitting of Arena into two modes came as a result of wanting to create an easier entry point for newer players while simultaneously giving existing Arena players more challenge and higher stakes. The mode is currently difficult for new players to dive into because of how heavy the competition can be, as many who specialize in Arena have been playing since Hearthstone first released.</p><p dir="ltr">"It was really to raise that ceiling for players who want that but also lower the floor a little bit so Arena can be a place that is welcoming for all types of players again," Georgiou said.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398547-hs_2025_roadmap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398547" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398547-hs_2025_roadmap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398547"></a><figcaption>Hearthstone's 2025 roadmap.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398547-hs_2025_roadmap.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Hearthstone's first expansion set for the new year, Into the Emerald Dream, will transport players to the idealized, natural version of Azeroth as druidic defenders of the dream battle against the forces of the Old Gods. It's something the Hearthstone team has long had in its "back pocket," Georgiou said, and always knew would eventually be an expansion. It was actually in the running to be released last year, but the team pivoted to avoid stepping on the toes of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a>: Dragonflight's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-dragonflight-heads-to-the-emerald-dream-for-its-next-update/1100-6517531/" data-ref-id="1100-6517531">Emerald Dream-themed update</a>. The expansion's mini-set, Druids of the Flame, will add the faction of corrupted elemental druids to further stoke the fires of battle.</p><p dir="ltr">Its second expansion of 2025 is actually a sequel, a first in Hearthstone history--The Shrouded City. This set picks up where 2017's Journey to Un'Goro set left off, as the explorer Elise hunts for a lost Tortollan city, with a Tortollan-themed festival mini-set coming later. The Hearthstone team actually invented the Tortollan race for the original Un'Goro set (which would later be added to WoW), and the upcoming expansion provided a great opportunity to further flesh out the backstory of the Tortollan and "peel back" some of the layers of the original Un'Goro expansion.</p><p dir="ltr">"To be able to revisit an area that is so compelling that had so much that wasn't explored before, and to be able to look at it in a new light, I think will be really, really fun," Georgiou said.</p><p dir="ltr">The third and final Hearthstone expansion for 2025, Heroes of Time, will explore alternative versions of Azeroth's past, where players will find versions of legendary heroes as players "have never seen them before." That will all lead to an epic battle at the end of time with the corrupted leader of the Infinite Dragonflight, Murozond. Given how much of an emphasis WoW has put on the Bronze Dragonflight and Chromie in recent years, it's a little surprising Hearthstone hasn't dived deep on alternate timeline shenanigans yet. But that's worked out in the team's favor.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think doing it when there is so much to pull from in Hearthstone's past feels like the perfect, pun half-intended, time to do it," Gonzalez said. "There's so many characters our fans love and characters from Warcraft that our fans might not even be super exposed to that are in that thematic bucket. It's a really rich theme."</p><p dir="ltr">In other Warcraft news, Blizzard announced as part of the direct that its newly announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/" data-ref-id="1100-6527719">remastered versions of Warcraft 1 and 2</a>, as well as a major 2.0 update for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-iii-reforged/" data-ref-id="5000-504202">Warcraft 3: Reforged</a>, are all available now.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NHL 25 Adds Professional Women's Hockey League This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nhl-25-adds-professional-womens-hockey-league-this-year/1100-6527746/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nhl-25-adds-professional-womens-hockey-league-this-year.1034991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nhl-25-adds-professional-womens-hockey-league-this-year/1100-6527746/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527746">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2024-11-13T10:32:55-0800">November 13, 2024 at 10:32AM PST</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>EA Sports has announced a multi-year deal with the Professional Women's Hockey League (PWHL) to bring the upstart league's players and teams to NHL 25.</p><p>The PWHL comes to NHL 25 on December 5 with all six teams--these include the Boston Fleet, Minnesota Frost, Montréal Victoire, New York Sirens, Ottawa Charge, and Toronto Sceptres.</p><p>These teams can be used in Play Now, Online Versus, Shootout, and Seasons. PWHL uniforms will be accessible in World of Chel and Hockey Ultimate Team. EA warned that not all player likenesses will be available right away, saying it will "continue to add more" players over time.</p><p>PWHL integration in NHL 25 also includes the Walter Cup--the PWHL's version of the Stanley Cup.</p><p>NHL 25 isn't the first NHL game to feature women, as this <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nhl-22-adds-first-ever-playable-womens-teams-in-new-update-today/1100-6499998/" data-ref-id="1100-6499998">actually began with NHL 22 when EA struck a deal with the International Ice Hockey Federation</a>. Sarah Nurse was on the cover of the following year's game, NHL 23, alongside Trevor Zegras.</p><p>EA's other sports games have added women over the years, too, now spanning EA Sports FC, UFC, and PGA Tour. The PWHL is now in its second season. The Minnesota Frost won the inaugural Walter Cup.</p><p>Beyond the introduction of the PWHL, EA is releasing a major update for NHL 25 this holiday, and one of the most exciting pieces of it is the introduction of the NHL Arcade event series. Beginning November 15 through World of Chel, this is an arcade-style, three-versus-three mode featuring a Big Head mode and power-ups like Supershot and Super Speed, along with big and small goalies.</p><p>The action takes place in a bespoke rink with no glass and no rules. It's not quite like the NHL Hitz days of yesteryear, but it might help satisfy the itch.</p><p>NHL 25 is also introducing the 4 Nations Face-Off in 2025. This is a round-robin tournament featuring players from the USA, Canada, Finland, and Sweden. There will be a dedicated mode for this, and each nation's uniforms will come to the game across a variety of modes. The real-world 4 Nations Face-Off takes place in February 2025, so the update for NHL 25 will likely go live around then.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399082-holidayupdate.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399082" data-ratio="0.56287878787879" data-width="1320" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399082-holidayupdate.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399082"></a><figcaption>NHL 25 gets a big holiday update soon.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399082-holidayupdate.jpg"></figure><p>Additionally, EA is trying to lure players back to NHL 25 by offering free content to everyone who simply logs in between November 15 and January 2. Everyone who does so will get six vanity items for the arcade mode, along with a special pack for the Road to 4 Nations content that's redeemable immediately. Players will also get a PWHL 83 OVR team building choice pack that will become redeemable when the PWHL integration goes live on December 5.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft 1 And 2 Remastered Make Up A New Warcraft Battle Chest, Available Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today.1034988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527719">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Blizzard's classic RTS titles <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-orcs-and-humans/" data-ref-id="5000-6383">Warcraft: Orcs and Humans</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-ii-tides-of-darkness/" data-ref-id="5000-2298">Warcraft 2: Tides of Darkness</a> are both getting the "remastered" treatment to celebrate the franchise's 30th anniversary, and they'll be available separately or together alongside <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-iii-reforged/" data-ref-id="5000-504202">Warcraft 3: Reforged</a> today in a new Warcraft Battle Chest.</p><p dir="ltr">The news comes as part of Blizzard's Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct, where the developer kicked things off by paying homage to the games that started the franchise and diving into what's changed, and what's stayed the same, in Warcraft 1 and 2 Remastered. While players will have the option of playing each game with their original visuals (something that can be toggled on and off in real time) the remastered versions also include new, hand-drawn visuals that help make each game's units more sharp and defined while still retaining their classic feel.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ryZ2jiW95qo" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Warcraft 1's controls have been updated to support modern-RTS staples like right click to move, box unit selection, and a faster game speed. Both games have received various UI and UX adjustments as well, like unit health bars, tooltips, increased unit selection, and a mission select. Warcraft 2 will still support multiplayer and all legacy custom maps will be fully compatible with this new version of the game.</p><p dir="ltr">Warcraft 3: Reforged, the maligned remaster that released in 2020 to negative reviews and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-3-reforged-a-victim-of-mismanagement-pressure-from-activision-and-budget-cuts-report/1100-6494287/" data-ref-id="1100-6494287">reportedly suffered from budget cuts and a rocky development</a>, is also receiving a major 2.0 update today. The update improves the game's environments and lighting, as well as overhauls its UI. It also adds hotkey customization and a revamped ladder system. Those who prefer playing Warcraft 3 with its original, non-remastered visuals will find the update adds high-rez versions for all the classic Warcraft 3 models as well, with players having the option of mixing and matching which assets, original or HD, they'd like to use.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399076-warcraft2remasteredgameplay.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399076" data-ratio="0.56133540372671" data-width="1288" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399076-warcraft2remasteredgameplay.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399076"></a><figcaption>Warcraft 1 and 2 Remastered each sport new hand-drawn visuals that can be toggled on or off.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399076-warcraft2remasteredgameplay.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Gamers who grew up playing classic Blizzard titles may remember seeing the large Warcraft and Warcraft 3 Battle Chests on store shelves that gather multiple games or expansions all together in one package. For the first time in a long time, a new Battle Chest is now available, one that includes the remastered versions of all three Warcraft RTS titles. The Battle Chest will be $40, while standalone versions of Warcraft: Remastered and Warcraft 2: Remastered will be $10 and $15 respectively.</p><p dir="ltr">For those who don't need all the new bells and whistles included in the remasters, the original versions of Warcraft 1 and 2 are available together on <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/warcraft_bundle" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GOG</a> for $15.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft finds new chief people officer in health and food exec Sébastien Froidefond]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-finds-new-chief-people-officer-in-health-and-food-exec-s-bastien-froidefond</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-finds-new-chief-people-officer-in-health-and-food-exec-s%C3%A9bastien-froidefond.1034985/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-finds-new-chief-people-officer-in-health-and-food-exec-s-bastien-froidefond<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ubisoft has found a new chief people officer, following the departure of previous CPO </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-hires-ex-uber-hr-director-as-new-chief-people-officer">Anika Grant</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> after a brief </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-s-chief-people-officer-anika-grant-departs-after-2-year-tenure">two-year stint</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. On November 20, "seasoned HR executive" </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://staticctf.ubisoft.com/8aefmxkxpxwl/RdHv3ROuzFvZ82HNVFgSh/1a30edf73780414f954302fa35a11349/APPOINTMENT_OF_NEW_CPO_-_12_Nov_2024_11122024.pdf">Sébastien Froidefond</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will take over the role.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With over 30 years of experience, his duties will include handling the studio's talent and leadership development and global recruiting, along with "ensuring that HR contributes significantly to the company's overall strategic objectives." As CPO, Froidefond will be a part of Ubisoft's executive committee and report directly to Cécile Russeil, the EVP who runs its communications, HR, and legal departments.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the announcement, Ubisoft notes his prior work "demonstrated his versatility and impact across diverse industries—whether in sectors with long, innovation-driven investment cycles, or in fast-paced environments requiring operational agility." Previously, Froidefond worked in dairy and healthcare at companies such as Lactalis Americas and Sanofi, where he managed their respective HR departments across multiple countries.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">His hiring marks the newest executive shakeup for Ubisoft this year. In April, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-appoints-c-cile-russeil-as-new-executive-vp">Russeil</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was appointed to her current position after previously operating as its chief legal advisor since 1995. That same month, publishing VP </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-appoints-publishing-vp-brenda-panagrossi-as-general-manager-for-us-market">Brenda Panagrossi</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was made general manager for its larger United States team.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Froidefond's predecessor, Grant, was brought on shortly after reports surfaced of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/new-allegations-show-the-cycle-of-abuse-and-misconduct-runs-deep-at-ubisoft">harassment and other inappropriate conduct</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> from high-level Ubisoft workers. Ubisoft then promised to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/ubisoft-undertook-profound-actions-to-address-studio-culture-concerns-says-ceo">improve its culture</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and she was said to be "instrumental" in that process.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He joins Ubisoft at an equally tumultuous time: not only is the company facing a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-tencent-and-the-guillemot-family-considering-ubisoft-buyout">potential buyout</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> between Tencent and it longtime owners, the Guillemot family, workers at its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/ubisoft-employees-in-france-called-to-strike-over-return-to-office-mandate">France</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-s-italian-staff-join-french-peers-in-striking-return-to-office-mandate">Milan</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> offices have recently gone on strike over its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-is-calling-devs-back-into-the-office-for-three-days-a-week">return-to-office mandates</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The studio has also been </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/new-lawsuit-alleges-ubisoft-shared-user-data-with-meta">twice-sued</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-sued-for-taking-the-crew-offline-and-duping-players">recent times</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and is in mid-development on its next big release, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Assassin's Creed Shadows </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">for February 2025.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard's Warcraft 1 & 2 remasters are official and out now on PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/blizzards-warcraft-1-2-remasters-are-official-and-out-now-on-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blizzards-warcraft-1-2-remasters-are-official-and-out-now-on-pc.1034982/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/blizzards-warcraft-1-2-remasters-are-official-and-out-now-on-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Plus, Warcraft 3: Reforged gets 2.0 update.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WC_Remastered_BattleChest_BnetShop_FeatureImage-WC1_1920x1080.png.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Blizzard Entertainment</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Almost exactly eight years since Blizzard <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/blizzard-isnt-planning-to-remaster-warcraft-1-and-2">said</a> it wasn't planning to remaster Warcraft 1 &amp; 2 because they're "just not that fun any more", the studio has announced it's doing just that - and both spruce-ups are available today as part of Warcraft's 30th anniversary celebrations.
</p>
<p>
The original Warcraft helped catapult Blizzard into the big leagues when it launched back in 1994, with Warcraft 2 quickly emerging to sate its growing fanbase the following year. And the studio's newly announced remasters promise a range of enhancements to the games' classic real-time strategy action, starting with new hand-drawn visuals - said to capture the originals' art style - which can be toggled on and off in real-time.
</p>
<p>
As for Warcraft 1 specifically, Blizzard has added "modern controls", including right-click move, bounding box select, and a faster game speed. That's on top of the UI and UX improvements - including tool tips, health bars, mission select screens, and increased unit select - that've been implemented across both titles. Additionally, Warcraft 2 Remastered retains the original's multiplayer, and all legacy custom maps are fully compatible and playable in the new version.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ryZ2jiW95qo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Warcraft 1 Remastered and Warcraft 2 Remastered are available for PC via Battle.net right now (there's no word on whether they might eventually show up on other stores), costing <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-gb/product/warcraft-1-remastered">$9.99</a> and <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-gb/product/warcraft-2-remastered">$14.99</a> respectively. Additionally, there's a <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-gb/product/warcraft-remastered-battle-chest">Battle Chest bundle</a>, priced at $39.99, featuring the new remasters and Blizzard's much-maligned <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/warcraft-iii-reforged">Warcraft 3: Reforged</a>. 
</p><p>
Despite the latter's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/warcraft-3-reforged-houses-a-fantastic-rts-but-blizzard-has-fluffed-the-remake">terrible launch reception</a>, Blizzard has continued to improve the title since its arrival in 2020, with today bringing a new 2.0 update for all players. This includes overhauled environments and lighting, a revamped UI, up-rezzed HD versions of all classic Warcraft assets, plus a range of quality of life improvements - in-game hockey customisation and revamped ladder were mentioned - and "much, much more".
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s Hardest Choice Has Fans Scouring For A Way Out]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-harding-davrin-death-alive-survive-1851697615</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard%E2%80%99s-hardest-choice-has-fans-scouring-for-a-way-out.1034958/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-harding-davrin-death-alive-survive-1851697615<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="9126c6383481fceb02ac9dd0eebe44a8" data-recommend-id="image://9126c6383481fceb02ac9dd0eebe44a8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Emmrich, Bellara, Rook, Neve, and Davrin look at something off-screen with concerned expressions." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Emmrich, Bellara, Rook, Neve, and Davrin look at something off-screen with concerned expressions." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->BioWare / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9126c6383481fceb02ac9dd0eebe44a8" data-recommend-id="image://9126c6383481fceb02ac9dd0eebe44a8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Emmrich, Bellara, Rook, Neve, and Davrin look at something off-screen with concerned expressions." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-4-review-dreadwolf-rook-action-rpg-1851681954&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-4-review-dreadwolf-rook-action-rpg-1851681954"><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em></a></span><em> </em>is a game about choice and consequence. One of the decisions that has the most immediate impact happens at the beginning of the game’s final quest. The effect <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-team-decision-davrin-harding-save-1851694983&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-team-decision-davrin-harding-save-1851694983">this decision</a></span> has on the remainder of the game and, presumably, any future <em>Dragon Age</em> games, has devastated fans in the kind of “hurts so good” way hard choices in video games do. But some fans are not so sure things are as they seem at the end of the game. Is it cope, or is there reason to believe an affected character could still appear in a future <em>Dragon Age</em>?</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196742" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="254" data-playlist="196742,196452,195150" data-current="196742"><div><p>What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22297.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><figure id="" data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="12f821ede41b262ecb452e949c764807" data-recommend-id="image://12f821ede41b262ecb452e949c764807" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Rook addresses the team on a beach." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Rook addresses the team on a beach." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->BioWare / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="12f821ede41b262ecb452e949c764807" data-recommend-id="image://12f821ede41b262ecb452e949c764807" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Rook addresses the team on a beach." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>If you’ve finished <em>The Veilguard</em>, then you know we’re talking about party members <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-best-companions-lucanis-taash-neve-1851688830&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-best-companions-lucanis-taash-neve-1851688830">Davrin and Harding</a></span>. At the beginning of the game’s final set of missions, the player will choose either the elven warrior or dwarven rogue to lead a second team as the party assaults the tyrannical elven gods’ base on Tearstone Island. Eventually, as you finish a boss fight against the blighted elven god Ghilan’nain, the leader you choose will sacrifice themself to create an opening for the killing blow. They’re impaled by the elf’s tentacles and fall into a chasm,presumably killed in action. Some fans, however, are holding onto hope that the doomed character could be found alive in the next <em>Dragon Age</em> based on a few key clues.</p><p>The main reason for this is because the game itself gives BioWare an out to bring either character back. There are references to there being “no trace” of a body after the fight, implying that they might have survived and disappeared somehow. Could they have been scooped up by some other entity we don’t know about? Maybe they patched themselves up and are alone trying to make their way back to the team? It’s certainly possible, but all we can do is speculate right now, and that’s enough to give <em>Dragon Age </em>fans some hope.</p><p>Some datamined content also gives fans another reason to hold out hope. Dataminers have found letters you seemingly were able to read at some point after this quest that imply that no matter the choice you make, someone is hopeful that Davrin or Harding is alive and out there. A letter Harding sends to her mother if Davrin sacrificed himself hopes that he and his griffon son are “not dead, just gone, for now.” The letter you get if Harding leads the team is from her mother, who says she has to believe she’ll “see [her] daughter walk through [her] front door again. One day.” As of this writing, these are presumed cut or bugged, but they’re a slight glimmer of hope that Davrin or Harding could show up in whatever the fifth <em>Dragon Age </em>game turns out to be.</p><p>It’s an interesting theory, and it would be a compelling spin on the final hours of <em>The Veilguard</em>, which can end with any combination of your party dying in the last mission. In a roundabout way, the one “death” that seems unpreventable could turn out to be the thing that ensures they make it to the next game. But it’s all speculation and we’ll have to sit with it for a while because BioWare <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/dragon-age-the-veilguard-john-epler-interview-1235147001/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/dragon-age-the-veilguard-john-epler-interview-1235147001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">has no plans to make DLC for <em>The Veilguard</em></a></span><em> </em>as it focuses on the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-teaser-n7-day-andromeda-1850999958&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-teaser-n7-day-andromeda-1850999958">fifth <em>Mass Effect</em></a></span>. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Black Friday Deals for PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-ps5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-black-friday-deals-for-ps5.1034946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-ps5/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Black Friday is just a few weeks away, and gamers are already trying to get the best deals for PS5s, PS5 games and more. Here is a list of the best Black Friday deals for PS5s.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-best-ps5-black-friday-deals">Best PS5 Black Friday Deals</h2>



<p>Earlier, PlayStation accidentally leaked that it may be including a PS5 Slim deal on Black Friday, which would be a huge win for those looking to purchase the popular system. The leak revealed that the PS5 Slim would be brought down to $379.99 USD on Black Friday, which is $70 cheaper than regular.</p>



<p>However, there have been no actual released Black Friday deals for PlayStation yet, but there are plenty of <em>early </em>Black Friday PS5 deals to hop on.</p>







<hr>



<h2 id="h-early-black-friday-deals">Early Black Friday Deals</h2>



<p>At the moment, PlayStation has already released quite a few different deals, including discounts on systems, controllers games and more. </p>



<p><strong>Below is a list of PlayStation equipment players can buy for a discount ahead of Black Friday:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.very.co.uk/playstation-5-dualsense-wireless-controller-cosmic-red/1600606102.prd?utm_campaign=content&amp;awc=3090_1731520102_9f50a49d7d677fdeca573d72ac3f2f4f&amp;aff=awin&amp;affsrc=201309&amp;cm_mmc=awin-_-201309-_-Editorial+Content-_-0_0&amp;utm_source=awin&amp;utm_medium=affiliate&amp;utm_term=http%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Eindependent%2Eco%2Euk%2F_201309&amp;utm_content=na">DualSense Wireless Controller – Cosmic Red</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.very.co.uk/playstation-5-dualsense-edge-wireless-controller/1600858327.prd?utm_campaign=content&amp;awc=3090_1731520156_0882e3c2db4f1309d76e158c758adf15&amp;aff=awin&amp;affsrc=201309&amp;cm_mmc=awin-_-201309-_-Editorial+Content-_-0_0&amp;utm_source=awin&amp;utm_medium=affiliate&amp;utm_term=http%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Eindependent%2Eco%2Euk%2F_201309&amp;utm_content=na">PS5 DualSense Edge controller</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D94PQMTX?tag=theindep0f-20&amp;ascsubtag=IN%7C2645497%7CB0D94PQMTX&amp;geniuslink=true&amp;th=1">‘EA Sports FC 25’, PS5</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Sony-PlayStation-5-PS5-Digital-Console-Slim/5113183757?wmlspartner=wlpa&amp;selectedSellerId=1925&amp;adid=222222222275113183757_1925_159242499817_21216985852&amp;wl0=&amp;wl1=g&amp;wl2=c&amp;wl3=697220472402&amp;wl4=pla-2296985376173&amp;wl5=9007527&amp;wl6=&amp;wl7=&amp;wl8=&amp;wl9=pla&amp;wl10=115068521&amp;wl11=online&amp;wl12=5113183757_1925&amp;veh=sem&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAiAudG5BhAREiwAWMlSjMPcPeqelQ9wKS4vygxBNYq9xqTC12mxKVei3B64iZXu09co_Qs57xoCJ-UQAvD_BwE">PS5 Digital Slim</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Many other sites include potential deals, too, so keep your eye out when web surfing. There will also be quite a few deals in stores, too.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-ps5-black-friday-predictions">PS5 Black Friday Predictions</h2>



<p>While we do not know of too many PlayStation deals yet, could only be assumed that a variety of PS5 bundles will be on sale.</p>



<p>Also, many stores usually include sales of games, including Walmart, Amazon, Target, Best Buy and more. One game to watch out for is Call of Duty: Black Ops 6, as the game seems to always drop in price for Black Friday every year.</p>



<p>Your best bet is to keep your eye out on websites and stores as more and more will begin releasing PS5 Black Friday information soon.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming guides, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-nintendo-switch/">the best Black Friday deals for Nintendo Switch.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PWHL Coming To EA Sports NHL 25]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pwhl-coming-to-ea-sports-nhl-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pwhl-coming-to-ea-sports-nhl-25.1034943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/pwhl-coming-to-ea-sports-nhl-25/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>EA Sports and the Professional Women’s Hockey League (PWHL) <a href="https://www.thepwhl.com/en/news/2024/november/13/pwhl-to-be-featured-in-ea-sports-nhl-25" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">have announced</a> that the league will be coming to NHL 25 in December.</p>



<p>Starting December 5, all six PWHL teams — Boston Fleet, Minnesota Frost, Montréal Victoire, New York Sirens, Ottawa Charge, and Toronto Sceptres — will be added to the game to play in a number of modes. Those include Play Now, Online Versus, Shootout and Season. In addition to being playable in modes, PWHL content will be added to the World of Chel as well Hockey Ultimate Team (HUT).</p>



<p>The launch comes alongside the start of the PWHL’s second season.</p>



<p>“We are thrilled to bring the PWHL into NHL 25 as part of a massive holiday update, giving players all-new ways to play, starting in a couple of days with the frenetic energy of NHL Arcade through to the launch of 4 Nations Face-Off in the New Year,” NHL 25 Executive Producer Bill Dollar said.</p>



<p>Women’s hockey has been a growing presence in the EA Sports NHL series for a number of years with international teams being a part of the last handful of games. The PWHL marks the first women’s league to be added to the franchise. In the past, EA Sports did speak with the NWHL about possible inclusion, but no deal was ever reached.</p>



<p>As far as this update is concerned, not all likenesses will be scanned and into the game when the update comes. That said, there is a plan to add more via updates to NHL 25.</p>



<p>In addition to the PWHL, EA Sports announced that the Four Nations Tournament and a new Arcade mode are both coming to NHL 25.</p>



<p>What do you think of the PWHL coming to NHL 25? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the 16 games coming to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-16-games-in-november/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Plus Game Catalog in November</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake Review - All That Glitters Are Pixels]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-review-all-that-glitters-are-pixels</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-review-all-that-glitters-are-pixels.1034928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-review-all-that-glitters-are-pixels<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>To the average gamer, 1988’s <em>Dragon Quest III: The Seeds of Salvation</em> may seem like just another <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/history-dragon-quest" rel="nofollow"><em>Dragon Quest</em></a> game that was released for the NES. In fact, the original "<em>Dragon Warrior III,</em>" as it was known in the West, didn’t really take off outside of Japan, but the game’s impact on the future of gaming is significant. It was the first mainstream game to have such a versatile job system, feature a day and night cycle, and let you swap your party members in and out.</p>

<p>As a newcomer that’s been a fan of the franchise since <em>Dragon Quest XI</em>, the NES trilogy has been one that I’ve never been able to get into. While grinding for hours to level up and clear a dungeon was the norm back in those days, it’s an absolute slog to do so today. And so, I moved onto trying out the more recent titles and remasters.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241025214621_1.jpg?itok=gaBryHuW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241025214621_1.jpg?itok=Geq7gWKk 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>I was elated beyond measure when <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> was announced. The <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/octopath-traveler-ii-review" rel="nofollow"><em>Octopath Traveler</em></a> series is one I hold close to my heart, so <em>Dragon Quest III</em> getting the HD-2D treatment felt perfect. Not to mention, <em>Dragon Quest</em> fans have been getting crumbs in the form of low-budget <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/dragon-quest-treasures-review" rel="nofollow">spinoffs</a>. A remake was definitely in order. Needless to say, I went into <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> with a lot of excitement and expectations, but what was to follow was pretty…underwhelming.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There’s no doubt about the fact that graphically, this game is gorgeous. The HD-2D look is a wonderful visual facelift from <em>Dragon Quest III</em>’s 16-bit pixel art. From the very moment you’re plopped into the game as the main character, you’re surrounded by lush greenery and flowing waterfalls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A mysterious voice asks you some very thorough questions to determine your character, and by thorough, I mean questions like, “Do you believe the world to be filled with more sadness than with joy?” I was not expecting to be asked that on a Tuesday morning, that’s for sure. Depending on your characters, you get assigned a personality type, something that’s significant to the way your character’s abilities grow, but more on that later.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241025223449_1.jpg?itok=MHTUuzhK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241025223449_1.jpg?itok=KemdvhRv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>You later awake on your 16th birthday, and have an audience with the King of Aliahan. Your father is the legendary warrior, Ortega, but after he perishes in his quest to destroy the evil Baramos, it’s time that you assume his mantle. And so, you go and find some party members to recruit, or in my case, create.</p>

<p>The original <em>Dragon Quest III</em> was praised for letting you choose which class of characters you could hire. Later, once they reach level 20, you can change their class again and go back to level 1 while still retaining your spells and abilities. <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> takes this a step further and gives you 5 additional seeds with which you can increase their default stats. Additionally, the remake gives you the option of the new monster wrangler class. I had a monster wrangler in my party throughout the game, and they definitely became my most useful character.</p>

<p>Back to the personality type system, it felt like more of a hindrance than anything, as it added nothing to the game apart from changing how your character’s stats evolved. You’ll be able to randomly find books in chests and bookshelves throughout the game, and having a character read them will alter their personality, but you don’t get to know how that affects their stats. I ended up just giving my characters books to read according to what personalities I had imagined them to have. Yes, you can even change the protagonist’s personality, so the quiz in the beginning feels a bit redundant.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241025233728_1.jpg?itok=v02lvbas 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241025233728_1.jpg?itok=pheuSFSz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>I don't want to sugarcoat it, this game is an absolute snoozefest when it comes to combat. I mentioned earlier that the NES games were simply too boring for me to get into. Well, <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> follows the same framework of the original’s combat. Turn-based combat and random encounters are really no problem for me when it’s well-executed, but <em>Dragon Quest III</em>’s combat feels ancient. I was really hoping that the remake would bring some intuitiveness into the game, such as <em>Dragon Quest XI</em>’s pep powers, but it’s barebones traditional JRPG combat.</p>

<p>While that wouldn’t be so bad, there’s a bunch of quality-of-life improvements that are definitely missing. For starters, the lack of a turn indicator is a huge inconvenience, especially when a single enemy can end up attacking three turns in a row and kill your healer. Any strategies that you might want to execute just end up being thrown to the winds.</p>

<p>Also, the fact that you need to assign items to your party members is a completely unnecessary chore. The item bag exists for a reason! It makes complete sense to be able to use it in combat, but I guess I’ll die just because I didn’t have any medicine on me at the time. Sure, there are other quality-of-life features, such as being able to adjust the battle speed and three different difficulty settings, but the game definitely needs a lot more to make the combat palatable for the modern day.&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241111182315_1-large.jpg?itok=hAJ0Dnqe 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241111182315_1-large.jpg?itok=UaiVaEid 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>There are also monster arenas where you can make the monsters you’ve rescued take place in tournaments against other monsters, but even that ended up being a bit of a disappointment. You can only advise your monsters as to how they should fight, so one might have to ‘Fight wisely’ while the other needs to ‘Focus on healing.’ These weren’t particularly fun as I would much rather be able to give them commands à la Pokemon, so I only went to the arenas a couple of times when I needed the money to buy some new equipment.</p>

<p>There’s not really a whole lot of changes going on in the story department either. <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> follows the same story as the original with a few additional scenes featuring the Hero and their father. For how long this game is, I was really hoping it wasn’t just tidbits of story every 10 hours or so. I can see how narratively all the twists and turns in the game would have made this game a real masterpiece in 1988. Even for today’s standards, it’s a decent story, but nothing to write home about.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The atmosphere of the game sort of makes up for that though, as it’s a beautiful world to be in. I had a blast exploring each town and taking in the details. The little birds that fly away as you walk near them, the glowing plants at night in the Faerie Village, and even the damp caves that lurk below. The addition of voice acting is welcome, and whether big character or NPC, the performances are superb. While all of the music is reused from the original, the symphonic arrangements are soothing, although the battle theme did get on my nerves around the 20-hour mark.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241110193454_1.jpg?itok=TmXVl6tn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241110193454_1.jpg?itok=Ets3bWnc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2><em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>There's a lot to love in <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em>. The spritework is fantastic, the music is soothing, and it's a world that you want to live in and explore. That being said, there's just as much to loathe. Given the number of random encounters you'll have to face, the combat holds back the game a lot. It also feels like a missed opportunity to expand upon the original's story. By today's standards, the game feels dated, much unlike the game from 1988 that lit a fire under gamers and developers alike.</p>

<p>Everyone’s expectations for remakes are, of course, different, but I was hoping for more than just a fresh coat of paint from the <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em>. For fans of the original, I’m sure the game will meet their wishes, but it’s not a game I’d recommend to newer fans or to today’s JRPG aficionados looking to get into the franchise.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Dragon Quest III HD-2D</strong> Remake was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the publisher over the course of 40 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Workers at Bethesda parent company strike over remote work policies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295556/video-game-developer-strike-zenimax-microsoft</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/workers-at-bethesda-parent-company-strike-over-remote-work-policies.1034925/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295556/video-game-developer-strike-zenimax-microsoft<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The members of ZeniMax Workers United-CWA, one of the largest video game unions in the United States, have gone on strike. The action involves workers in ZeniMax offices in Texas and Maryland, who do quality assurance work for games including<em> Fallout</em> and <em>Elder Scrolls</em>. Workers are striking over claims that ZeniMax leadership has failed to address employee issues regarding remote work and outsourcing. </p><p>“Today, we are on strike,” <a href="https://x.com/ZeniMaxWorkers/status/1856714377992278336">ZeniMax Workers United posted on X</a>. “We are not afraid to do what’s necessary to make sure that Microsoft meets us at the bargaining table over key issues like remote work options and outsourcing.”</p><div><p>ZeniMax Workers United is made up of approximately 300 quality assurance testers. When the union <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/1/3/23537455/microsoft-has-formally-recognized-the-zenimax-union">was formally recognized in January 2023</a>, it became parent company <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/12/5/23495139/microsoft-union-zenimax-bethesda-cwa">Microsoft’s first union</a> and, at the time, was the largest video game union in the United States. Just a few months later in March, that title was eclipsed by the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/8/24094602/activision-blizzard-qa-workers-unionizing-microsoft">600 members of Activision Quality Assurance United</a>, another union under Microsoft’s corporate umbrella.</p></div><p>Remote work policies seem to be a major sticking point for Microsoft’s video game unions. In the immediate outbreak of the covid-19 pandemic, many video game companies instituted flexible work-from-home policies that they’ve <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24290345/return-to-office-mandates-amazon-productivity-remote-work-hybrid-decoder-podcast">recently begun rolling back</a>. In October of this year, Activision Quality Assurance United held a rally outside their offices in Texas, California, and Minnesota <a href="https://cwa-union.org/news/cwa-members-activision-qa-rally-remote-work-options">to protest Microsoft’s restrictive return-to-office polic</a>y that, according to workers, failed to accommodate workers with medical issues or doctor recommendations. The Communications Workers of America (CWA), the organizing committee that supports ZeniMax Workers United along with multiple video game unions in the US, has also filed an unfair labor complaint with the National Labor Relations Board over contracting out work without notifying the union.</p><p>There have been several video game-related strikes in the US in recent year. In 2021, workers at Raven Software — a subsidiary of Activision Blizzard before its eventual acquisition by Microsoft — participated in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820549/activision-blizzard-raven-software-layoffs-walkout-call-of-duty">a walkout</a> that turned into a five-week strike after several employee contracts were not renewed. After that strike, workers at Raven Software <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/21/22894964/activision-blizzard-raven-software-employees-create-game-workers-alliance-union">organized and won one of the first video game unions at a AAA game publisher</a> in the country.</p><p>In July of this year, voice actors and motion performers covered under SAG-AFTRA’s interactive media agreement <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/25/24206357/video-game-performer-strike-sag-aftra">went on strike</a> to protest <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/5/24213808/video-game-voice-actor-strike-sag-aftra">worker protections regarding AI</a>. While SAG-AFTRA and the video game companies that make up the interactive media agreement bargaining committee <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/15/24270821/sag-aftra-video-game-voice-actor-strike-resume-negotiations">have returned to the negotiation table</a>, the strike continues. </p><p>ZeniMax Workers United strike will not last as long as SAG-AFTRA’s or Raven Software’s, with workers striking today until 6PM ET. In a statement to <em>The Verge</em>, Microsoft spokesperson Becca Dougherty wrote, “We respect our employees’ rights to express their point of view as they have done today. We will continue to listen and&nbsp;address their concerns at the bargaining table.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Boss Says No 'Red Line' With Exclusives, Including Even Halo]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-boss-spencer-halo-ps5-switch-exclusive-no-red-line-1851697549</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-boss-says-no-red-line-with-exclusives-including-even-halo.1034922/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/xbox-boss-spencer-halo-ps5-switch-exclusive-no-red-line-1851697549<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Earlier this year, Xbox brought some of its games to PlayStation 5 and Switch. Apparently that worked pretty well, as<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-phil-spencer-layoffs-hi-fi-rush-studios-closed-1851461546&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-phil-spencer-layoffs-hi-fi-rush-studios-closed-1851461546"> Microsoft’s CEO of gaming Phil Spencer</a></span> says more of its games are coming to other platforms, and that might even include the Xbox’s crown jewels, like the next <em>Halo </em>game. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,196230,197298" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>In February 2024, the first <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-starfield-ps5-hi-fi-rush-sea-of-thieves-1851225324&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-starfield-ps5-hi-fi-rush-sea-of-thieves-1851225324">reports surfaced</a></span> claiming <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-games-rumored-for-playstation-and-switch-1851239628&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-games-rumored-for-playstation-and-switch-1851239628">Xbox was planning</a></span> to bring some of its previously Xbox-exclusive games to other consoles. The news led to an <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-fans-content-creators-ps5-ports-starfield-rumors-1851230962?_gl=1*6ndmfk*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxNjI0MS4yOS4wLjE3MzE1MTYyNDEuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-fans-content-creators-ps5-ports-starfield-rumors-1851230962?_gl=1*6ndmfk*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxNjI0MS4yOS4wLjE3MzE1MTYyNDEuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank">Xbox fan community meltdown.</a></span> Eventually, four games—<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hifi-rush-pentiment-xbox-multiplatform-1851262144&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hifi-rush-pentiment-xbox-multiplatform-1851262144" target="_blank"><em>Sea of Thieves, Grounded, Penteniment, </em>and <em>Hi-Fi Rush</em></a></span>—made the leap to PlayStation and Nintendo Switch. Then in August, Xbox revealed that the Bethesda-published <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-game-pass-ps5-exclusive-1851626140&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-game-pass-ps5-exclusive-1851626140"><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em></a></span> would land on PS5 in Spring 2025, after being announced as an Xbox console exclusive. And if you thought that was the end of the Xbox games going multiplatform, you were very wrong.</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-13/microsoft-s-gaming-chief-is-still-looking-for-acquisitions-sees-future-growth?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTczMTQ5OTU0MSwiZXhwIjoxNzMyMTA0MzQxLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTTVcxQ01UMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.UjaVdB-1hJKO1VKY0-vUQaOjf2cpmUgGaLSXNqqYnHU&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-13/microsoft-s-gaming-chief-is-still-looking-for-acquisitions-sees-future-growth?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTczMTQ5OTU0MSwiZXhwIjoxNzMyMTA0MzQxLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTTVcxQ01UMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.UjaVdB-1hJKO1VKY0-vUQaOjf2cpmUgGaLSXNqqYnHU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In a November 13 Bloomberg interview</a></span>, Phil Spencer talked about the future of Xbox and the company’s plans for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/microsoft-xbox-pc-gaming-handheld-steam-deck-game-pass-1851697278&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-xbox-pc-gaming-handheld-steam-deck-game-pass-1851697278">a handheld Steam Deck-like device</a></span>. In the the conversation, Spencer also said he was “pleased” with the results of bringing Xbox games to other consoles and confirmed <em>any</em> game could make the leap. </p><p>“I do not see sort of red lines in our portfolio that say ‘thou must not,’” Spencer told <em>Bloomberg</em>. He also suggested that even <em>Halo </em>could make the leap, adding:  ‘It’s too early to make any sort of decision on the next version of <em>Halo</em>.” </p><p>That’s not a yes, but the fact that he’s openly talking about <em>Halo </em>on PlayStation is pretty remarkable considering how important the franchise has been to Microsoft for over 20 years. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-microsoft-ceo-halo-ps5-more-multiplatform-games-1851482805&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-microsoft-ceo-halo-ps5-more-multiplatform-games-1851482805">A report in May</a></span> claimed that Microsoft’s CEO, Satya Nadella, was pushing for more Xbox games to make the transition to PlayStation and Switch. Reportedly, after buying <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/microsoft-activision-blizzard-acquisition-game-pass-1850923561&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-activision-blizzard-acquisition-game-pass-1850923561">Activision for $69 billion</a></span>, the leadership at Microsoft was now watching Xbox very closely and wanted more growth. According to Spencer, “The Xbox business has never been more healthy.” But there’s always room for more growth and bigger numbers when you are part of a massive corporation. And if that means putting Master Chief on PS5, then that will happen sooner rather than later. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Brings Back Grand Theft Auto V And A Bunch Of Other Big Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-new-games-november-2024-gta-5-dying-light-2-1851697560</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-brings-back-grand-theft-auto-v-and-a-bunch-of-other-big-games.1034919/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-new-games-november-2024-gta-5-dying-light-2-1851697560<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="d7e4a6c3abc0dcc14d087443cf19c8e5" data-recommend-id="image://d7e4a6c3abc0dcc14d087443cf19c8e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1393" data-height="783" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Rockstar Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d7e4a6c3abc0dcc14d087443cf19c8e5" data-recommend-id="image://d7e4a6c3abc0dcc14d087443cf19c8e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1393" data-height="783" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The last few months of PlayStation Plus’ subscription catalog have been a  rollercoaster ride of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-premium-extra-games-september-plucky-squire-ps5-1851645955&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-premium-extra-games-september-plucky-squire-ps5-1851645955">great new additions</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-ps5-october-2024-red-dead-2-kingdom-hearts-gta-1851672709&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-ps5-october-2024-red-dead-2-kingdom-hearts-gta-1851672709">some big departures</a></span>. November continues the whiplash with a bunch of big names joining the paid service including <em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> and <em>Dying Light 2</em>. If you’ve somehow managed to go 11 years without ever dipping your toes into Rockstar Games’ open-world hit, opportunity has once again come knocking. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196230" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="217" data-playlist="196230,196447,195410" data-current="196230"><div><p>This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21779.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Sony announced the full list of new PS Plus games for November 2024 in both the Extra and Premier tiers—the more expensive all-you-can-eat buffets rather than the monthly a-la-carte deals. In addition to<em> GTA V</em> and the parkour zombie RPG, <em>Like a Dragon: Ishin</em> and <em>Digimon Survive</em> are also joining the Netflix-like library, while <em>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain </em>and <em>Resistance: Fall of Man</em> join the ranks of the PlayStation classics section. </p><p>Here’s the full list:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p><strong>PS Plus Extra</strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Dying Light 2: Stay Human</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Like a Dragon: Ishin</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>MotoGP 24 </em>| PS4, PS5</li><li><em>The Sims 4 Island Living</em> (Add-on only) | PS4</li><li><em>Digimon Survive </em>| PS4</li><li><em>Overcooked! All You Can Eat</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Stick Fight: The Game</em> | PS4</li><li><em>Clash: Artifacts of Chaos</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Killer Frequency</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Hungry Shark World </em>| PS4</li><li><em>Chivalry 2 </em>| PS4, PS5</li></ul><p><strong>PS Plus Premier</strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>﻿Synapse </em>| PS VR2</li><li><em>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Blood Omen 2 </em>| PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Resistance: Fall of Man</em> | Streaming from PS3</li><li><em>Resistance 2 </em>| Streaming from PS3</li></ul></blockquote><p>Personally, I’m most excited for <em>Digimon Survive</em>. The 2022 hybrid between a visual novel and tactical RPG got mixed reviews, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/digimon-survive-rpg-visual-novel-review-1849377900&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/digimon-survive-rpg-visual-novel-review-1849377900">including from <em>Kotaku</em></a></span>, but I’m looking forward to giving it a low-stakes, no-strings-attached second chance. <em>Blood Omen 1</em> and <em>2 </em>are also arriving just in time for the <em>Soul Reaver 1 &amp; 2 Remastered </em>collection next month, providing much-needed backstory to the PS2 follow-ups.</p><p>It’s also nice to see the first two<em> Resistance</em> shooters—memorable games from Insomniac about a mid-WWII alien invasion—joining the classics collection, though having them relegated to cloud streaming because of the lack of PS3 backwards compatibility or emulation remains a drag. We probably won’t see it anytime soon, but the whole <em>Resistance</em> trilogy deserves a remaster collection on modern platforms.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>