<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:25:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Transport Fever 3 Preview – Getting the goods from Mardi Gras to Woodstock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/transport-fever-3-preview-getting-the-goods-from-mardi-gras-to-woodstock/</link>
            <guid>1439482</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Coming up on a decade since the debut of Transport Fever, Urban Games have figured a few things out about their transport simulation series. Years of post-launch support, added features and working with their community is leading to their most ambitious game yet, when Transport Fever 3 launches this year.</p>
<p><iframe title="Transport Fever 3 - First Look: Infrastructure" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eyDKt6C1kC0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Sticking with their in-house game engine, they’re able to roll a bunch of features and ideals from where Transport Fever 2 has ended up into Transport Fever 3 on day one. That means that this will be a fully synchronous release across PC, PS5 and Xbox Series X|S, when TF2 rolled into the console station a few years after PC, and it also means that cross-platform modding, which was only added to TF2 in 2024, will also be there on day one.</p>


<p>If you’re in it for the economic simulation, then Transport Fever 3 promises even greater depths than before. There’s over a century of transportation history here, starting in 1900 with the city, buildings and cars you see all changing and evolving as you carry on through to 2030. That means there’s over 290 vehicles, ranging from buses and trucks, through ships, planes, trains and even new cargo trams and helicopters. Cargo trams are a particularly interesting one, having been used in Eastern Europe to bring cargo into city centres instead of noisy, smelly trucks –&nbsp;something you’ll need to keep tabs on now, as every citizen in the map is fully simulated with places to work, shop and live, and their happiness will depend on pollution, noise levels and traffic jams.</p>
<p>And you’ll have a fresh appreciation for cargo in this game, as there are now 35 cargo types and it is now no longer handled automatically. If TF2 was all about money, then in TF3 it’s just one of many things to manage.</p>


<p>All of this will add new depths to the transport simulation sandbox, but TF3 will lean further into the tycoon gameplay and story objectives to overcome through a campaign of eight maps. Each one picks a particular period in history and takes inspiration from real events, using these missions as a way to introduce new concepts and keep things varied –&nbsp;there could be competition against an AI, a countdown mission with a timer, and more.</p>
<p>We sampled two of the levels, first heading to Mardi Gras in 1906, but finding that the city has been partially flooded and ruined by a storm. This is purely a narrative conceit here –&nbsp;while this game now has a day/night cycle and weather effects, they are purely cosmetic so as not to add crazy variables to the simulation – but it means that Mayor LaFontaine, the helpful Andrew and Miss Baker are banding together to rescue this year’s festival. LaFontaine wants a new hotel, while Miss Baker pushes him and you to help represent the black community and less wealthy, and Andrew’s just happy to be helpful.</p>

<p>Setting up transport routes, repairing roads and bridges and shuffling the good around that each objective needs gradually gets you used to the user interface, though it’s initially a little unclear how to go about certain tasks. I accidentally clicked through and sold off a couple horse and carts when cancelling an unneeded line, instead of having them sent back to the depot, and when I wanted a ship to go between collecting fish and shrimp, returning to dock between each, it took me a moment to realise I couldn’t drag the stops into a different order and had to set things up a different way.</p>
<p>But with Mardi Gras rescued, I could turn my attention to another festival in need, some sixty years later, with a somewhat legally distinct rendition of Woodstock. Now it’s a local sheriff and an enthusiastic rock organiser who will have to put aside any of the very surface level differences to make this a success, oh and Andrew’s still there to help out, though he’s now a bit of an old-timer.</p>

<p>The objectives have grown in scale by this point, so you need a bunch more wood to construct the stage, and the growing encampment needs plenty of food (and veggie food too, please) which is over on the other end of the map. Do you just get a truck to drive it across, or use the port nearby to ship it to the nearest town for trucks to pick up? It all builds up to a festival that’s as successful as you can make it accommodate people.</p>
<p>I feel that these narrative missions and tycoon gameplay will really help make Transport Fever 3 more accessible. I often find myself at a bit of a loose end when simply presented with a sandbox, so while that absolutely remains, having both a way to ease players into the simulation, and to give objectives in an intelligent way that keeps you more engaged will be great.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/transport-fever-3-preview-getting-the-goods-from-mardi-gras-to-woodstock/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heartwarming 2025 Gem 'Goodnight Universe' Finally Gets Switch 2 Camera Support]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/heartwarming-2025-gem-goodnight-universe-finally-gets-switch-2-camera-support</link>
            <guid>1439476</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Blink and you'll miss it</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="44c983db61caa"><a title="Goodnight Universe" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/44c983db61caa/goodnight-universe.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Skybound Games</em></figcaption></figure><p>We really liked <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/goodnight-universe">Goodnight Universe</a>, Nice Dream's follow-up to GoodbyeWorld's award-winning <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/before_your_eyes">Before Your Eyes</a>. But for the Switch 2 version, there was one big thing absent that players on Steam had — camera support. Eye-tracking and facial recognition is a big part of the game, but with the feature missing at launch on the hybrid console, we just had to be patient.</p>
<p>Fortunately, for those of you who have been holding off or who have been dying to replay the game as-intended, camera support is finally here! So, as long as you have the Switch 2 version of the game and a compatible USB camera (or the official one), then you're game.</p><div><figure data-videoid="8i2vvu-qeBQ" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8i2vvu-qeBQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt8i2vvu-qeBQ" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8i2vvu-qeBQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8i2vvu-qeBQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed4c3af8jqphwx&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Accompanied by a cute little visual to show you the best way to set up the camera for optimal eye-tracking magic, today's update also includes a little visual fidelity boost for the newest console.</p>
<p>As for setting the camera up, publisher Skybound Games recommends you play using this method in a well-lite space, with the camera positioned around 18-24 inches in front of you, with your face fully visible. You'll be able to test this all in-game before you start.</p>
<figure data-uuid="36eb7a64f6bbc"><a title="Goodnight Universe camera set-up" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/36eb7a64f6bbc/goodnight-universe-camera-set-up.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Skybound Games</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Well, time for us to dust the ol' Switch 2 camera off then. If you happened to miss Goodnight Universe last year, then prepare yourself for a beautiful narrative adventure.</p>
<p>The game has you control a six-month-old named Isaac — that's the age where you don't really understand <em>anything</em> and you're trying to get to grips with limbs, movement, all sorts of weird things! Oh, Isaac is <em>also</em> developing psychic powers, and a tech corporation has found out about that. So that's just an extra thing on top of everything else. Fun!</p>
<p>We scored the original release <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/goodnight-universe">a 7/10 back in November 2025</a>, but even without the camera implementation, we thought the game was solid: "Isaac’s supernatural adventures are as entertaining as they are heartwarming, and though it isn't terribly long, it makes full use of every moment."</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Have you played Goodnight Universe yet? Will you be grabbing the game now it has camera support? Cry out in the comments and let us know.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193446 @ 1771433103 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/heartwarming-2025-gem-goodnight-universe-finally-gets-switch-2-camera-support]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Freight-eningly good – Transport Fever 3 (PC) Hands-On Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/freight-eningly-good-transport-fever-3-pc-hands-on-preview/</link>
            <guid>1439473</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Wccftech recently had the pleasure of taking part in the first North American hands-on for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3493540/Transport_Fever_3/">Transport Fever 3</a>, an opportunity that was previously exclusive to Gamescom and TGS attendees. During this preview event, we got a first look at their brand new campaign as well as hands-on with the updated Free Game mode.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Climate-Zone-Dry-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<p>Urban Games started with a bit of a look at the history of the studio, discussing how Transport Fever 3 has been a title the team has been working on for almost six years, and is the first time that they’ve attempted self-publishing their signature franchise; <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/transport-fever-2-review/">Transport Fever 2</a> was published by Good Shepherd Entertainment for the PC release and Nacon for the PlayStation/Xbox console versions. By the numbers, Transport Fever 2 was the transport management simulation genre’s best-selling entry with two million copies sold.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For this year’s numbered entry, Transport Fever 3 is aiming to expand the focus on both the Tycoon mode and the late-game, something that fans have both been asking for. By giving players more mid-game goals beyond just hitting capital targets, Urban Games is hoping to make the third title more than just a train ride to maximum profits. For those with a more casual focus in mind, the sandbox mode allows players to build their enterprise from the ground up without having to worry about financial limits.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Lane-Management-Tool-Junction-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<p>By the numbers, Transport Fever 3 is aiming to have more than three hundred vehicles, thirty-five industries, and over forty types of cargo. Rather than having ships be limited to the latter parts of a campaign, as in Transport Fever 3, this year’s entry wants to give players more of a reason to integrate ships into their logistics; one reason given was the introduction of both sub-arctic and offshore industries.</p>



<p>For the preview event, Urban Games permitted us to either play through two of the eight playable campaign missions (Mardi Gras in 1906 New Orleans and Woodstock’s Summer of Love festival in the mid-60’s) or dive right into the sandbox mode and develop freely. I opted for the latter, mixing different attributes together to get a 1980’s bubble era Japan with desert biomes and limited resources. Some of the other campaign missions teased were Norway’s oil rush in the 1970’s, Manila at the turn of the millennium, and a futuristic mission set in the early 2030’s that they’re keeping under wraps for now.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Road-Crossing-at-Dawn-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<p>As someone who’s not routinely a simulation player of this nature (SimAnt and RollerCoaster Tycoon/OpenRCT2 are probably the ones I’ve dabbled with the most), diving into Transport Fever 3 required having the kiddie wings on for a little bit before I could head into the deep end. The whole menu-driven formula to Transport Fever 3 does take some getting used to at first, realizing that players need to go into one menu to build out roads, taking into consideration the number of lanes, noise levels, traffic mitigation, et cetera. Once a road is drafted up, it needs to get populated with points like bus stops or logistics routes to move goods along the road. Then a third menu to purchase a vehicle to put it on the route. Then, a fourth menu to select what goods to transport on the route. Then, the consideration of adding maintenance or supply depots along the route to keep the vehicles in top condition and the goods flowing.</p>



<p>For the average player, it’s a lot to take in all at once. For a good ten minutes, I had tanker ships doing a route between two oil derricks and a processing plant back on land, with nothing being accomplished other than paying the salaries of captains who spent eight hours a day sailing around in circles. It wasn’t until I had one of the developers point out that I needed to manually select what the ships were supposed to pick up and drop off, in this case, oil, before they would actually contribute something of value. It wasn’t like the earlier industries I was working on, where transporting vegetables from a farm in one direction or meat in another way was done automatically once a supply route was established.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Highway-Under-Construction-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<p>Thankfully, Transport Fever 3 has a novel notification system of urgently colored messages notifying me if there’s something in my logistics network in need of attention. When it was all said and done, my army of thirty-some Japanese Kei trucks was putting in long hours, sending processed oil all across the countryside, and constantly sending out day laborers as needed to help tend these oil fields or processing plants. In the end, I felt like a proper zaibatsu tycoon managing all of these different industries, all from the comfort of my desk.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Transport Fever 3 - First Look: Infrastructure" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eyDKt6C1kC0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>To cap off the event, I sat down with Nico, Publishing Manager for Urban Games, with a brief Q&amp;A of questions sourced directly from the passionate Transport Fever community on Reddit. The interview is still being actively transcribed by yours truly, so look forward to seeing his remarks shortly!</p>



<p>Transport Fever 3 is intended for a simultaneous release across PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, and PC with a targeted release later this year.</p>



<p><em>[Editor’s Note: Urban Games provided travel and accommodations to attend this preview event.]</em></p>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/freight-eningly-good-transport-fever-3-pc-hands-on-preview/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE 2K26 Release Date & Exact Start Times]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-release-date-exact-start-times/</link>
            <guid>1439461</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The WWE annual cycle is circling back around again, and the release of WWE 2K26 is on the horizon, with not much longer to wait until the bell rings.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/wwe-2k26-2/" id="174969" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WWE 2K26</a> is the latest entry in the long-running franchise from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/2k-sports/" id="1233" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2K Sports</a>, bringing CM Punk back to adorn the cover after a great year for the World Heavyweight Champion.</p>



<p>Keeping tabs on all the release dates as the year enters a busy period can be tricky, but Insider Gaming is here to help with all the release date and start time details for WWE 2K26.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-wwe-2k26-coming-out-release-date-explained">When is WWE 2K26 Coming Out? Release Date, Explained</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Best in the world. Image by 2K</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>WWE 2K26 has an official release date of Friday, March 13, though the exact date varies based on time zones.</strong></p>



<p>The release of WWE 2K26 comes as part of the frenzy of Wrestlemania season, due to take place in Las Vegas in mid-April, and lands just a few weeks after Elimination Chamber.</p>



<p>This gives players the opportunity to jump into a new WWE 2K title at the busiest time of the year for wrestling fans, allowing you to tweak the script or follow along as real-life events happen.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-wwe-2k26-early-access">When is WWE 2K26 Early Access?</h2>



<p><strong>Early access for WWE 2K26 begins on Friday, March 6, giving eligible players a full week extra to jump into the game.</strong></p>



<p>Landing the week after Elimination Chamber in Chicago, it’s the perfect time for gamers to jump in and start to build out their stories using the new features in Universe Mode. </p>



<p>However, it comes at a cost, as early access is limited to those who purchase a premium edition of the game.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming: </strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-mygm-features-extended-season-and-new-match-types/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WWE 2K26 MyGM Features Extended Season and New Match Types</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-what-are-the-wwe-2k26-start-times">What Are The WWE 2K26 Start Times?</h2>



<p><strong>WWE 2K26 releases at 12 AM local time on the above dates, depending on the edition you have purchased. However, there are some ways to access the game early.</strong></p>



<p>As WWE 2K26 has a staggered release window, players in New Zealand will be the first to jump into the game, while those in the Pacific regions of the United States theoretically have to wait longer. Fortunately for anyone who is impatient, modern gaming allows you to tweak your region and benefit from early access.</p>



<p>There are some caveats, however, as Nintendo Switch 2 players will have to purchase WWE 2K26 in the region of early access, and Steam players have no alternative options.</p>



<p>The table below outlines the start times for WWE 2K26, covering both the general release and early access, and what time the doors open for anyone utilizing the New Zealand trick.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">WWE 2K26 Start Time</th><th data-align="center">NZDT Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM</td><td data-align="center">3 AM</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM</td><td data-align="center">5 AM</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM</td><td data-align="center">6 AM</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM</td><td data-align="center">11 AM</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM</td><td data-align="center">10 PM</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<hr>



<p>What are you most excited for in WWE 2K26? Share your thoughts with other players in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more WWE 2K26, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-universe-mode-wizard-lets-you-control-everything/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wealth of changes in Universe Mode</a>, and check out details of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-introduces-nintendo-switch-2-exclusive-creation-tools/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2-exclusive creation tools</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-release-date-exact-start-times/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty ad banned by UK regulator after investigation determined it "trivialised sexual violence"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-ad-banned-by-uk-regulator-after-investigation-determined-it-trivialised-sexual-violence</link>
            <guid>1439440</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Complaints about "drug use" not upheld.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-banned-ad.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-banned-ad.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-banned-ad.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-banned-ad.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-banned-ad.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-banned-ad.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-banned-ad.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-banned-ad.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-banned-ad.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Activision Blizzard</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
An advert released to promote <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a> has been banned after the UK's Advertising Standards Authority upheld complaints that it "trivialised sexual violence" following an investigation.
</p>
<p>
As detailed in a <a href="https://www.asa.org.uk/rulings/activision-blizzard-uk-ltd-g25-1319083-activision-blizzard-uk-ltd.html">ruling shared on the regulator's website</a> (thanks <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/call-of-duty-advert-banned-in-the-uk-for-trivialising-sexual-violence-">Game Developer</a>), the advert - which began airing on YouTube and Video on Demand channels last November - focused on an airport security check where two security officers were, according to dialogue, "Off playing the new Call of Duty: Black Ops 7." Standing in for the officers were two "replacers".
</p>
<p>
"A male member of the public was then shown to be passing through the metal detector," the ASA description continues. "A male security officer said, 'You've been randomly selected to be manhandled – face the wall!' and turned the man around. The female security officer was then shown to be licking her teeth while picking up a prescription container and shaking it, before showing it to the male officer who winked back at her.
</p>
<p>
"The male officer then told the man, 'I'm gonna need you to remove your clothes, everything but the shoes.' The woman then put on a pair of gloves and said, 'Time for the puppet show!' A post-credit scene showed the male officer putting a hand-held metal detector in the man's mouth and said, 'Bite down on this, she's going in dry.'" 
</p><p>
The ASA says it received a total of 11 complaints about the advert. Nine believed it "trivialised sexual violence" and "challenged whether the ad was irresponsible and offensive", while two believed the ad "encouraged or condoned drug use" and "challenged whether the ad was irresponsible".
</p>
<p>
During the ASA's investigation, Activision Blizzard UK told the regulator the advertisement had been reviewed by Clearcast (a non-governmental organisation which pre-approves British TV advertising) which gave it an "ex-kids" timing restriction, meaning it could not be broadcast during or around children's programming or content likely to appeal to under-16s.</p>
<p>Activision also argued the ad "depicted a deliberately implausible, parodic scenario that bore no resemblance to real airport security procedures" and that previous ASA rulings "recognised that ads containing obviously absurd or parodied scenarios reduced the likelihood of being interpreted literally or being viewed as behaviour to emulate."</p>
<p>Addressing complaints of "trivialised sexual violence", the publisher insisted the advert "did not sexualise the act of performing searches and contained no implication that the acts were sexual in nature." It similarly argued the ad did "not depict illegal drugs or misuse of prescription medication."
</p><p>
Despite Activision's assertions, however, the ASA noted that while the advert contained no explicit imagery and while "most viewers would understand the ad was intended to be humorous", the humour was "generated by the humiliation and implied threat of painful, non-consensual penetration of the man, an act associated with sexual violence." It also felt that the officers' "confident and joking demeanour presented this [act] in a humorous manner."</p>
<p>"Because the ad alluded to non-consensual penetration, and framed it as an entertaining scenario," the regulator concluded, "we considered that the ad trivialised sexual violence and was therefore irresponsible and offensive." However, it did not uphold complaints regarding drug use, determining the advert was "unlikely to be understood as encouraging or condoning drug use" and was therefore "not irresponsible on that basis."
</p>
<p>
Ultimately, the ASA ruled - as a result of the upheld complaints - that the Call of Duty advert "must not appear again in its current form". Activision Blizzard UK was also told to ensure its ads were "socially responsible and did not cause serious offence, for example by trivialising sexual violence". At present, the airport security spot is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FH1csdj8oMk">viewable as a video on the official Call of Duty channel</a>.
</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-ad-banned-by-uk-regulator-after-investigation-determined-it-trivialised-sexual-violence]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill: Townfall looks to be a PS5 console launch exclusive, according to official website]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-townfall-looks-to-be-a-ps5-console-launch-exclusive-according-to-official-website</link>
            <guid>1439437</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silent-hill-townfall_qk4p7AE.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silent-hill-townfall_qk4p7AE.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silent-hill-townfall_qk4p7AE.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silent-hill-townfall_qk4p7AE.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silent-hill-townfall_qk4p7AE.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silent-hill-townfall_qk4p7AE.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silent-hill-townfall_qk4p7AE.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silent-hill-townfall_qk4p7AE.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silent-hill-townfall_qk4p7AE.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Screen Burn/Konami</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-townfall">Silent Hill: Townfall</a>, the upcoming entry in Konami's legendary horror series, looks to be a console launch exclusive on the PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>This stems from <a href="https://www.konami.com/games/silenthill/townfall/us/en/">the game's official website</a>, on which only three platforms are listed: Steam, the Epic Games Store, and PS5. There's no mention at all of the Xbox Series X/S, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, or older consoles.</p>
<p>The game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-our-first-proper-look-at-silent-hill-townfall">recently got a story trailer</a> revealed at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-state-of-play-february-2026-everything-announced">Sony's State of Play</a>, showcasing the Scottish town of St. Amelia. Developed by Glasgow-based Screen Burn, it follows the tale of SImon Ordell as he navigates the mysterious town with his CRTV, a small electronic device he seems glued to for better or worse.</p>
<p>The game also got a further explanation courtesy of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OPE5XdS1OBw">a Silent Hill Transmission</a> hosted by Konami on the 12th February. This gave a further look on how the game will work, its mechanics and story, by the developers at Screen Burn.</p><p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-townfalls-announcement-trailer-has-a-secret-message-hidden-inside-it">The game was first announced back in 2022</a>, and is one of multiple big SIlent Hill projects that have seen the light of day recently. Obviously there was the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-2-remake">Silent Hill 2 Remake</a> which <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-review">was a great release from Bloober Team</a>, but also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-f">Silent Hill f</a> <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-f-review">which also stole the hearts of many horror fans</a>.</p>
<p>Are you excited for Silent Hill: Townfall? Let us know below, as well as what platform you'll be picking it up on.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-townfall-looks-to-be-a-ps5-console-launch-exclusive-according-to-official-website]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss Gameplay Trailer Debuted Ahead of Steam Next Fest Demo Release]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cthulhu-the-cosmic-abyss-gameplay-trailer-ahead-of-steam-next-fest-demo/</link>
            <guid>1439419</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Publisher <strong>Nacon</strong> and developer <strong>Big Bad Wolf</strong> have debuted a new gameplay trailer for <strong>Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss</strong>, just ahead of when players will get a chance to try out the game themselves when a demo is released as part of <strong>Steam Next Fest</strong> on <strong>February 23, 2026.</strong></p>



<p>The trailer digs into one of the game's core mechanics, investigations, as the player character <strong>Noah</strong> investigates an underwater mining station that, at least at first glance, seems to be abandoned. The trailer showcases the dark corridors of the mining station and shows Noah exploring the hallways, scanning and analyzing clues, before cutting to a montage of some of the more terrifying aspects of the game.</p>



<p>Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss is set to arrive on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S on <strong>April 16, 2026,</strong> and it's one of at least two Lovecraftian, Cthulhu-based games set to arrive this year alongside <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-mound-omen-of-cthulhu-gameplay-nacon-ace-team/">The Mound: Omen of Cthulhu</a></strong>, which is due to arrive sometime in Summer 2026.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss | Investigation Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iyYlAQ1b74o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>What we'll be able to play through in the Steam Next Fest demo is currently unclear, though a press release for today's new trailer says that players can check the demo out "<em>to discover the unique atmosphere and original mechanics of this narrative investigation game before its release on April 16</em>."</p>



<p>This is the latest game from Big Bad Wolf after its 2018 mystery title, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-council-episode-1/">The Council</a></strong>, and its 2022 RPG, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/vampire-the-masquerade-swansong-vampires-make-for-excellent-investigators/">Vampire: The Masquerade - Swansong</a></strong>. This sci-fi Lovecraftian horror was also identified by Wccftech as one of our <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftech-most-anticipated-adventure-games-of-2026-against-fire-air-water-mind/">Most Anticipated Adventure Games of 2026</a>, and it's exciting to see that we'll be able to get our hands on it to test if we were correct in spotting it as a game to pay attention to.</p>



<p>We'll have some coverage of other demos to pay attention to with Next Fest kicking off this coming Monday, February 23, but in the meantime, <a href="https://wccftech.com/luna-abyss-hands-on-preview-doom-returnal-a-good-time/">you can check out our preview for <strong>Luna Abyss</strong></a>, another game due to arrive in 2026 that'll be participating in Next Fest that put its demo out early.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/cthulhu-the-cosmic-abyss-gameplay-trailer-ahead-of-steam-next-fest-demo/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gorgeous Pixel Art Cyberpunk Game Replaced Delayed At The Last Minute After Steam Demo Feedback]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/replaced-steam-demo-delayed-cyperpunk-2000670668</link>
            <guid>1439410</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The long wait for <a href="https://kotaku.com/replaced-release-date-cyberpunk-pixel-art-batman-arkham-2000620061"><em>Replaced</em> was almost over</a>, until now. The beautiful pixel art action platformer’s March launch has been pushed back by the developers following feedback on a recent Steam demo. “The response to our Steam demo has been the ultimate fuel for us,” Sad Cat Studios wrote on Wednesday.</p> <p>“As a small team working on our very first title, we’ve poured everything we have into this project,” reads the <a href="https://x.com/REPLACEDGame/status/2024122392310591889">studio’s announcement</a>. “While the game is technically finished, reaching this final stretch has shown us that we need just a few more weeks to ensure the experience is exactly what you deserve. We want the version of <em>Replaced</em> you play on day one to be polished, stable, and true to the vision we’ve shared with you. Instead of March 12, the Game Pass release will now arrive on April 14.</p>

  <p><em>Replaced</em> began development back in 2018, was revealed at E3 2021, and promised for a 2022 launch. Lofty ambitions and things like the Russia-Ukrainian War torpedoed those plans. After waiting an extra four years, what’s one more month?</p> <p>The action-adventure’s Steam demo has gotten generally positive feedback. The 2.5D art, cinematics, and mood have all been praised. The combat, however, might leave something to be desired. According to some demo reactions at least,<em> Replaced</em>‘s mechanics might be a bit repetitive and undercooked compared to its visual aesthetic. If accurate, it wouldn’t be a huge surprise for a game like this.</p>

 <p>But sometimes style and vibes are enough. I hope that’s the case with <em>Replaced</em>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/replaced-steam-demo-delayed-cyperpunk-2000670668]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Steam Deck Alternatives In 2026—Best Handheld Gaming Consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-steam-deck-alternatives-in-2026-best-handheld-gaming-consoles/</link>
            <guid>1439407</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>When it comes to handheld gaming, the Steam Deck handheld and its variants are easily at the top of the market, though they’re so popular that they’re often sold out in 2026.</p>



<p>There are various reasons for this, with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-deck-out-of-stock-alerts-ram-shortage/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-deck-out-of-stock-alerts-ram-shortage/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">RAM and storage shortages</a> the main culprits, but thankfully, there are plenty of other options out there for handheld enthusiasts. From systems that offer a PC-like experience to retro classics, here are some great alternatives to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/steam-deck/" id="489" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam Deck</a> during its supply shortages.</p>







<h2 id="h-6-best-steam-deck-alternatives-in-2026">6 Best Steam Deck Alternatives In 2026</h2>



<p>Before diving into the list, it’s important to note that everyone will have their own specific preferences for what they look for in a handheld device. Make sure you know exactly why you might have wanted a Steam Deck, and compare them to the options down below to figure out which might be best for you.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-deck-out-of-stock-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-deck-out-of-stock-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">When Will Steam Deck Consoles Be Back In Stock?</a></li>
</ul>



<p>With that out of the way, here are six great alternatives to the Steam Deck and its variants in 2026.</p>



<h3 id="h-lenovo-legion-go-s">Lenovo Legion Go S</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Portable PC. Image by Lenovo.</figcaption></figure>



<p>There’s an argument to be made that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/lenovo-legion-go/" id="1113" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lenovo Legion Go S</a> is a better Steam device than the Steam Deck itself. It supposedly runs titles faster than Valve’s own device, and it’s just as comfortable in the hand—an often overlooked aspect of handheld gaming.</p>



<p>There are plenty of variations to the Lenovo Legion, too. The Legion Go S is arguably the most affordable entry-level system, but if you’ve got the cash to spare, the newly-released Legion Go Gen 2 packs an even beefier punch.</p>



<p>If you’re interested, check out their line of products <a href="https://www.lenovo.com/gb/en/legion/?orgRef=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F&amp;srsltid=AfmBOopf8AInfuRFzvVzxkQZh_HDx-_6gwcqFBBaaT42e7ge5pXBQ4hC&amp;visibleDatas=2795%3AHandheld" id="https://www.lenovo.com/gb/en/legion/?orgRef=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F&amp;srsltid=AfmBOopf8AInfuRFzvVzxkQZh_HDx-_6gwcqFBBaaT42e7ge5pXBQ4hC&amp;visibleDatas=2795%3AHandheld" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>.</p>



<h3 id="h-asus-rog-xbox-ally-x">Asus ROG Xbox Ally X</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Anything is an Xbox. Image by Asus.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Despite the name, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/asus-rog-xbox-ally/" id="165877" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Asus ROG Xbox Ally X</a> isn’t a portable Xbox. Instead, it’s a more powerful ROG Ally X, with the standout being the upgraded processor.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/reviews/asus-rog-xbox-ally-x-review-powerhouse-portable/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/reviews/asus-rog-xbox-ally-x-review-powerhouse-portable/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming has a comprehensive Asus ROG Xbox Ally X review</a>, where it was praised for running any title, both old and new, with ease, whilst the Xbox integration never feels disruptive or pointless. Any title with the Xbox Play Anywhere tag can be accessed on the device, and it’s ultimately a great competitor to the Steam Deck.</p>



<p>If you’re interested, check out their line of products <a href="https://rog.asus.com/uk/gaming-handhelds-group/" id="https://rog.asus.com/uk/gaming-handhelds-group/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>.</p>



<h3 id="h-nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2 </h3>



<figure><figcaption>Snap! Image via Nintendo</figcaption></figure>



<p>Now, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2/" id="908" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2</a> likely needs no introduction. It serves as both a home console and handheld device, but it’s a very different system that’s built for an entirely separate purpose from the Steam Deck.</p>



<p>The Switch 2 is not a portable PC in any shape or form, nor does it try to be. It won’t run games as well as the Steam Deck, and of course, you’ll be limited to the library available to Nintendo instead of Steam. However, what it does offer is easy functionality, accessibility, and a wide range of console exclusives that are some of the best in their genres.</p>



<p>If you’re interested, check out their line of products <a href="https://store.nintendo.co.uk/en/nintendo-switch-2?gclsrc=aw.ds&amp;source=ppc&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gad_campaignid=23210908699&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiA49XMBhDRARIsAOOKJHZMZLx80Cc2bGycN_ZbALvvmchWpWn078K7A1rnozAQ3yf222eyjg0aAolLEALw_wcB" id="https://store.nintendo.co.uk/en/nintendo-switch-2?gclsrc=aw.ds&amp;source=ppc&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gad_campaignid=23210908699&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiA49XMBhDRARIsAOOKJHZMZLx80Cc2bGycN_ZbALvvmchWpWn078K7A1rnozAQ3yf222eyjg0aAolLEALw_wcB" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>. </p>



<h3 id="h-msi-claw-8-ai">MSI Claw 8 AI+</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Sleek design. Image by MSI.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Back to portable PCs, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/msi-claw-8/" id="3610" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MSI Claw 8 AI+</a> is another solid entry into the realm of handheld gaming. It’s a capable device that more than delivers the promise of PC gaming on the go, though it does have a few minor drawbacks.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-machine-everything-to-know-about-valves-new-system/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-machine-everything-to-know-about-valves-new-system/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam Machine—Everything To Know About Valve’s New System</a></li>
</ul>



<p>The main one is certainly the large screen size. You’d think that a larger screen would equal a better experience, but it can hamper the comfort when using it for extended periods of time. However, it does offer experimental AI that can adjust your game’s settings for optimal performance, which can be handy for new users.</p>



<p>If you’re interested, check out their line of products <a href="https://uk.msi.com/Handhelds/Products#?tag=Claw-Series" id="https://uk.msi.com/Handhelds/Products#?tag=Claw-Series" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>.</p>



<h3 id="h-playstation-portal">PlayStation Portal</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Astro on the go. Image by PlayStation.</figcaption></figure>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/playstation-portal/" id="165643" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Portal</a> is an incredibly unique device, as it doesn’t operate like most handhelds. Instead of running games natively on the system, it relies on streaming games from the Cloud all through an internet connection.</p>







<p>Therefore, it’s not a great device if you’re planning to game on the go, but if you’re settled somewhere with a strong connection? It could be one of the best in the business, especially for PS5 owners. It’s as great and comfortable to hold as a DualSense controller, and considerably cheaper than other alternatives. If you’re a fan of the PlayStation library, the Portal should be on your radar—with an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-portal-oled-scheduled-for-2026-its-claimed/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-portal-oled-scheduled-for-2026-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OLED version rumoured for 2026</a>.</p>



<p>If you’re interested, check out their line of products <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/accessories/playstation-portal-remote-player/" id="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/accessories/playstation-portal-remote-player/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>.</p>



<h3 id="h-r38s-handheld-game-console">R38S Handheld Game Console</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Huge potential in a tiny package. Image by Game Console.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Admittedly, this entry is a bit of a gimmicky one, but when you’re talking about handheld gaming, it’s hard to ignore the glory days of the Game Boy and PSP. Through the power of emulation, an admittedly grey area in the realm of video games, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/r38s/" id="3609" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">R38S</a> brings the golden age back to the small screen.</p>



<p>With over 15,000 games packed into the device from the get-go, you’ll be spoilt for choice the moment you unbox it. From the NES to the PS1, N64 to the Nintendo DS, it’s an emulation powerhouse. Of course, you won’t be playing the likes of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a> or <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/battlefield-6/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/battlefield-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6</a> on this thing, but if you’re a big retro fan, it’s definitely a system worth picking up.</p>



<p>If you’re interested, check out their line of products <a href="https://r36sgameconsole.com/" id="https://r36sgameconsole.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you thinking of picking up one of these devices? If you’ve got any more questions regarding any of them, don’t be afraid to ask away in the official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" id="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>!</p>



<p>For more lists and recommendations, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-upcoming-soulslike-games-2026/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-upcoming-soulslike-games-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the 7 biggest upcoming soulslike games of 2026</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-open-world-rpg-games-releasing-2026/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/best-open-world-rpg-games-releasing-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the 9 open-world RPGs you need to play in 2026.</a></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/best-steam-deck-alternatives-in-2026-best-handheld-gaming-consoles/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: What's Your Favourite Gen 5 Pokémon?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-whats-your-favourite-gen-5-pokemon</link>
            <guid>1439392</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Unova one</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="9905e20379f68"><a title="Pokemon White 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9905e20379f68/pokemon-white-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Jim Norman / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Pokémon turns 30 on 27th February, and in honour of this momentous anniversary, we're running a series of polls leading up to the big day, asking you to vote for your favourite Pokémon from each generation. The nine winners will then go head-to-head in a final poll at the end of the month.</p>
<p>We're covering a generation a day until we've ticked off all nine, leading up to the ultimate showdown. <strong>Each poll will be open for five days</strong>.</p>
<p>It's Day Five, and Gen V (or 5 if the Roman numerals are a bit fancy-pants for your tastes) is up, meaning 'mon from Unova and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_diamond_and_pearl">Pokémon Black &amp; White</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_black_and_white_2">Black &amp; White 2</a>. Let's check in with Team NL for their underdog picks.</p><div><figure data-videoid="Mh1U8qC_TUE" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mh1U8qC_TUE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytMh1U8qC_TUE" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Mh1U8qC_TUE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mh1U8qC_TUE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed38e70btwyklu&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>




<p>Let's crack on. We've got a chunky 156 new Pokémon this generation, listed in National Dex order (use the search bar to quickly find a specific Pokémon). As always, <strong>you can only choose one!</strong></p>

<hr>
<p><em>Thanks for voting! Keep an eye out for further generations in the coming days as we cruise towards Pokémon's 30th anniversary.</em></p>
<p><em>And if you missed Gens 1, 2, 3, or 4, those polls are still live:<br></em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:197281,197283,197402,197536,197566 @ 1771434022 --></section></article><div><p>Gavin first wrote for Nintendo Life in 2018 before joining the site full-time the following year, rising through the ranks to become Editor. He can currently be found squashed beneath a Switch backlog the size of Normandy.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/dartmonkey"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('dartmonkey');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-whats-your-favourite-gen-5-pokemon]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People of Note Preview - Measuring Up Nicely]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/people-of-note-preview</link>
            <guid>1439389</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I played <em>Guitar Hero 3: Legends of Rock</em> constantly as a kid. I was hopeless using the guitar controller, and even had to use a standard controller. But what I remember most was how it introduced me to so many different songs. It was my first introduction to rock artists like Rage Against the Machine, and an obvious love letter to the whole art form. I got similar vibes from my hour and a half hands-on demo and preview event with <em>People of Note</em>.&nbsp;</p><p>A turn-based RPG all about music, Cadence and her band use the power of music while traversing the aptly-named land of Note. After my time with the game, I'm intrigued by the high notes, but worried by a few miscues.</p><h2>Systems That Sing</h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/measures-pon-1.jpg?itok=gtRNko7w 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/measures-pon-1.jpg?itok=hsCvSO3M 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>It should be noted first and foremost, as it was at our preview event, that <em>People of Note </em>is a music RPG, not a rhythm RPG. Other games, like the recent <em>UNBEATABLE</em>, have music as a part of the plot and heavily as part of the gameplay. <em>People of Note </em>is all about music, but in the gameplay itself, rhythm is about as present as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review-french-revolution" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="07f3b1f2-234f-4782-8556-c21c1fb23302" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a><em> </em>attacks.</p><p>For a game all about creativity, I found the more technical parts of the game to be where it shone brightest. In the game's combat, I was really impressed by the game's turn order system. In a mechanic that <em>Final Fantasy X </em>seemed to solve, I felt there were some really creative things happening in <em>People of Note</em>.</p><p>Turns are measured in stanzas, and each turn is a measure. The number of turns you get is determined by a "time signature," where the top number is the amount of turns for your team and the bottom is for the enemy. Later fights in the demo even had modifications made to select measures. What at first seems to be a cosmetic choice seems to actually be one of its best mechanical ideas.</p><p>Management outside of combat allows a lot of creativity as well. <em>People of Note</em>'s Songstone system is a near one-to-one rip of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/ranking-all-of-magic-gathering-final-fantasy-legendary-creatures-part-2" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="83fd60e7-1407-46f1-ac0b-60b876ec8285" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Final Fantasy 7</em></a>'s Materia. That's not a bad thing at all, as it lets you build characters exactly as you want. Even in my hour and a half playtime, I was able to build characters with clear archetypes, with pop star Cadence as my primary damage dealer and the rocker Fret playing support with stat boosts and healing.</p><p>Speaking of characters, the character design is superb. The way Cadence's popstar look clashes with the rock-themed land the demo takes place in makes me really excited about the characters we've yet to meet. The developer at our preview event mentioned that each area in the game is themed after a different genre, and I'm really hoping we get to see a Classical crew decked out with powdered wigs and everything.</p><h2>A Few Sour Notes</h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freebird-people-of-note-1.jpg?itok=fRe82oO5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freebird-people-of-note-1.jpg?itok=AcBAziUR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>Outside of the combat, there were a few places that felt like a miss. The dungeon in the demo felt very ho-hum, and navigating it was a real chore. With a good amount of backtracking required, it was easy to get disoriented in similar looking rooms, and the environmental puzzles were pretty by the numbers. It was nice to look at, but it was mostly repetitive and frustrating.</p><p>My other gripe was with the humor. There are puns <em>everywhere </em>in Note, and they start as fun and make some great environmental gags. In dialogue and songs themselves, though, they don't land quite as well. It's clear there's a sincerity behind the jokes, but it just feels like they're far too frequent. Though perhaps it's a little fitting that a love letter to music has band kid humor.</p><h2>People of Note Preview | Final Thoughts</h2><p><em>People of Note </em>went from a relative unknown for me to a game I'm at least intrigued by. I could see its dungeon design and punny dialogue wearing me down quite a bit during its runtime. However, I think its sincerity and sharp systems are interesting and rife with potential.</p><p><em>Guitar Hero </em>was always a love letter to rock. <em>People of Note </em>is striving to be a love letter not to a genre, but to a medium, complete with full musical numbers and loads of variety. It's a huge undertaking, and a big swing for a small team to take. The one certainty I have after my time with <em>People of Note</em>: it's ambitious as hell, and that's enough for me to see it through.</p><hr><p><em><strong>People of Note</strong> was previewed on PC using a copy provided by the publisher over the course of an hour and a half of gameplay.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Parker is a freelance writer based in Iowa, and the co-founder and editor of gaming satire site Palette Swap. Before Palette Swap, he was an editor at Hard… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/parker-johnson">More about Parker</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/people-of-note-preview]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Love Eternal Review - Centuries of Damn]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/love-eternal-review-centuries-of-damn</link>
            <guid>1439386</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p dir="ltr" id="docs-internal-guid-f7cce43c-7fff-fe01-2497-c7469a27d0e0">One thing that constantly persisted in my playthroughs of&nbsp;<em>Love Eternal</em>, the self-proposed “horror platformer” published by Ysbryd Games and developed by Brika, was a perversion of wanting. What I wanted wasn’t entirely clear, whether it was an answer, a challenge, cohesion, or even attrition, and even now, 3 playthroughs later, what&nbsp;<em>Love Eternal</em>&nbsp;*<strong>is</strong>* doesn’t necessarily aim itself towards any of those. Could it? Should it? Well, let’s delve deeper.</p><p dir="ltr">What is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/love-eternal-preview-stunning-precision-platformer" rel="nofollow"><em>Love Eternal</em></a>? Well, in many ways, it’s in the title, but to whom and to what end? Well, all manner of things, if you will. To companionship, creation, celebration, confusion, continuation, cycles, chores, and condemnations. As a product, it’s a buckling beast of wrath, all of it housed inside the cozy visual package of a freeware platformer from the Flash era.</p><p dir="ltr">It’s very unabashed about its inspirations, namely titles like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/i-wanna-be-guy-remastered-fans-developer-blessing" rel="nofollow"><em>I Wanna Be The Guy</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/celeste" rel="nofollow"><em>Celeste</em></a>, as well as PICO-8 platformers like <em>Pullfrog </em>and… well, <em>Celeste</em>, I suppose, and its slew of mods. Narratively, it seeks to emulate elements of David Lynch’s work, while also somewhat unintentionally running parallel to Joe Dante’s segment in the&nbsp;<em>Twilight Zone</em>&nbsp;movie, which is enticing, but horse before the cart, eh?</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/loveeternal_level.jpg?itok=wrnPtgma 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/loveeternal_level.jpg?itok=ml_jh8W2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr"><em>Love Eternal</em> itself is an expansion of Brika’s previous hardcore platformer simply titled <em>Love </em>– not to be confused with Fred Wood’s 2008 2D platformer <em>Love</em>. While the latter is much more straightforward, Brika’s <em>Love</em>, and <em>Love Eterna</em>l, have a sneaky ace up their sleeve. At the push of a button, whether stationary or in mid-air, your character will invert their gravity and use the ceiling as their new platform.</p><p dir="ltr">How the game approaches this gimmick is largely through the use of increasing the length of stringing together how many times you can invert in one floating period through the use of red crystals, which refresh your one-time use. There are hazards like spikes and lasers, and these, in turn, close the timings tighter until it becomes more masochistic than precision. A meeting of the minds between its two main inspirations.</p><p dir="ltr">On the whole, this is the game. It is a maximum of three hours of this mechanic stretched to an atomically small width, where the margins get tighter, and the line of red crystals becomes longer. Is it fun? It is initially, before repeat playthroughs, which, due to the narrative, are outright encouraged, undermine how reliant the game is solely on one element of <em>Love Eternal</em>'s platforming possibilities. Instead, what we have is a story to sink our teeth into.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/loveeternal_dog.jpg?itok=clKsZBku 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/loveeternal_dog.jpg?itok=WleH1JOg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">You play as Maya, a young girl seemingly at odds with everything in her life, from her family and what they eat for dinner, to her friends and their failure to show up for events Maya’s scheduled. Her reactionary anger to friends like Lacey for failing to show up at an event with Maya, brings the wrath of a selfish god who, unbeknownst to Maya, invites her into a castle hosted of her memories, as fractured and as alien to Maya, as much as they are to the God itself.</p><p dir="ltr">What follows is a spotty, but nonetheless, consistently fascinating string of scenes detailing a lot of this nefarious God’s activity, and a lip service treatment of Maya’s history. Why she’s chosen is just down to bad luck on her part, and as such, <em>Love Eternal </em>is much more interested in detailing how this God interacts with the world around Maya – their new plaything – and their history of previous playthings. The result as a whole, is a memetic experience that is alluring, but aggravatingly impenetrable.</p><p dir="ltr">It’s branded as “an experimental narrative”, but in reality, it is an abstract story, almost completely detached from gameplay, and contextualized through two decades of internet history. If the screenshots fail to garner a reaction other than “buh?”, then just know that they DO make sense, in one very acute angle of how this game structures its writing. Otherwise, you mostly fall prey to this God's absurdist reactions to a world that has gone from temples to touchpads, the Baby Boomer to end all Baby Boomers.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/loveeternal_shout.jpg?itok=JC2NGDQf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/loveeternal_shout.jpg?itok=bfxSM_QF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">It’s almost pointless trying to adequately compose a consistent chain of events that would make this even remotely make sense. The somewhat garbled memories of Maya intersecting with a previous victim of the God, Divesh, and why the two meet so frequently, when, even when it’s shown, Divesh shows nowhere near the same amount of ire towards his contemporaries like Maya does. Instead, what <em>Love Eternal</em> focuses on is Dadaism.</p><p dir="ltr">Watch! As the God assumes Maya is a girl wholly inspired by the use of 2010 rage comics, one Memebase watermark short of a negative vote rating on 9gag. Gasp! As they react to manga as if it is a coloring book! Chuckle! As the ending of&nbsp;<em>The Blair Witch Project</em>&nbsp;is referenced multiple times in the same scene, but with an irreverence of dopiness behind it! And finally, analog horror jumpscares that shut the game down when finished.</p><p dir="ltr">It should be noted that all of this takes place when the platforming is discarded for a genre switch to a point ‘n click, which falls just shy of being the worst kind of visual novel. Save for an ending which, without spoiling, throws an entirely new angle of commentary towards the player, the platforming element becomes a branch of the statement Brika is trying to make… I think.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/loveeternal_meme.jpg?itok=p84nw1Yr 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/loveeternal_meme.jpg?itok=Uz-Econt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">Is the mare meant to race? Should the child be coached? What follows these questions are historical context that no longer applies when we, as a collective, have fallen past the need for it. Marriage is no longer a bond of religious intent, but one with protections and privy to the human condition, ultra-modernized. A statement is a JPEG, a playground is a platformer, and you are still you, getting older, and with it, more despondent to a world that doesn’t want you. So you want it, more than food or water. You want it, never need it.</p><p dir="ltr">If that is the intent, it’s an absorbing diatribe, which deserves something a bit more welcoming to synchronicity. Towards the end, Brika seems to lament their creative intent, anger as progression is pushed into the player without the player actively engaging in it, almost furious that there’s a cage around them. Like all animals, they buckle, but to what end? Just living.</p><h2><em>Love Eternal </em>Review | Final Verdict</h2><p dir="ltr">I won’t say that <em>Love Eternal</em> is a great game. Despite its cost-effective batch of content, the reliance on its legitimately bewitching gimmick being one broad stroke of challenge leaves the player desiring more. While the story is a legitimately enthralling aspect, it betrays the supposed experimentation by just sitting alongside the gameplay, and never the two shall meet.</p><hr><p><em><strong>Love Eternal </strong>was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the publisher over the course of 8 hours of gameplay. All screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Blair is a trans writer who got their start in 2016 by writing too many words about Tom Clancy’s The Division. What follows until now is a journey spent… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/blair-bishop">More about Blair</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/love-eternal-review-centuries-of-damn]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Feds Reportedly Want Discord, Reddit, And Others To Doxx Users Who Criticize ICE]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ice-reddit-discord-doxxing-dhs-subpoena-2000670648</link>
            <guid>1439374</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>As the Trump administration continues to ramp up ICE raids across the country, the Department of Homeland Security is increasingly trying to subpoena personal information on anonymous internet users who are trying to protest the agency, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/02/13/technology/dhs-anti-ice-social-media.html">according to <em>The New York Times</em></a>.</p> <p>It reports that Google, Reddit, Discord, and Meta have received hundreds of administrative subpoenas from the Department of Homeland Security in recent months. The goal is to get information on the identities of people behind accounts found to be tracking ICE agent movements or criticizing the group as it carries out its operations, during which officers have <a href="https://www.americanimmigrationcouncil.org/blog/ice-deaths-shootings-2026/">killed at least two people so far in 2026</a>.</p>

 <p><em>The New York Times</em> claims that Google, Meta, and Reddit have complied with “some” of the requests. It’s unclear if Discord has done the same.</p> <p>The gaming platform has frequently been subpoenaed by publishers looking for details on users sharing confidential information or pirating games. One of those was <em>Arc Raiders</em> distributor Nexon. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/16/24271854/discord-nexon-dmca-subpoena-copyright-piracy">Discord argued in legal filings back in 2024</a> that user privacy was legally protected by the constitution. Complying with the order, the company wrote, could violate its users’ “decisions to remain anonymous, an aspect of their freedom of speech protected by the First Amendment.”</p>

 <p>Reddit, on the other hand, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/minnesota/comments/1qd6qir/ice_trackers/">has been flooded</a> with people sharing information about ICE movements and facilities in their communities as people are disappeared off the streets. While agents remain masked and their identities kept hidden, ICE has been using <a href="https://www.404media.co/ice-is-using-a-new-facial-recognition-app-to-identify-people-leaked-emails-show/">facial scanning technology</a> and other surveillance tools to <a href="https://www.mprnews.org/story/2026/01/13/ice-using-private-data-to-intimidate-observers-and-activists-advocates-say">doxx people they don’t like in real time</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ice-reddit-discord-doxxing-dhs-subpoena-2000670648]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Officially Drops Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles Booster Boxes to Just $125.99 to Preorder, Just Weeks Before Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-officially-drops-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-booster-boxes-to-just-12599-to-preorder-just-weeks-before-release</link>
            <guid>1439368</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> is getting its new <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-where-to-buy-updated-2026"><u>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles set</u></a> next month (with prerelease even sooner), but Amazon isn’t waiting to drop the price of booster boxes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After some price fluctuations, the retailer has finally confirmed that the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aB8dVV?object_uuid=b9bab191-75c7-4dca-b294-39cdb5d1c031&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TMNT Play Booster Box will be sold for $125.99</u></a>, which is only a dollar more than its all-time lowest price of $124.99 that we saw <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtle-preorders-drop-to-new-record-low-price-amazon-just-weeks-after-last-discount"><u>a few weeks ago</u></a> as a sale item.</p><div id="235624"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="235624" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>TMNT Play Booster Box</h3></p></div></span></p></div><h2 data-cy="title2">The New Price For TMNT Play Boosters Is Almost Their Lowest Ever</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">With 30 packs per box of Play Boosters, you’re getting each one for $4.19, a discount that adds up and should give you a sizeable collection of TMNT cards right from the jump.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As a reminder, the set’s rarest alternative treatments will more likely be found in Collector Boosters (more on those in a moment), but Amazon setting this price means it should be relatively easy to get up to speed and build something playable for your next Magic night.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The price confirmation follows the arrival of Collector Boosters on the store, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-collector-booster-boxes-are-in-stock-right-now"><u>which are (somehow) still available at the time of writing</u></a>, as well as discounts on a variety of TMNT Magic: The Gathering products, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-set-launches-next-month-and-the-bundle-is-discounted-already"><u>the bundle</u></a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-next-precon-deck-is-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtle-themed-and-its-already-discounted-just-a-few-weeks-from-launch"><u>newest Commander Deck ‘Turtle Power’</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-tmnt-draft-night-box-back-in-stock-and-discounted-at-amazon"><u>even the new Draft Night set</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more on Magic’s Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtle crossover, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tmnt-magic-card-is-a-dream-for-artifact-creature-decks-like-warhammer-40ks-necron-dynasties"><u>a card that pairs nicely with Warhammer 40K Necrons</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-tmnt-commander-deck-is-a-video-game-homage-packed-with-classic-characters"><u>our early thoughts on the Commander precon</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can also read my colleague Scott's deep-dive on the set <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-preview">in his full preview</a>, including the unique 'Turtle Team Up' co-op boxed game that's part of the lineup above.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.
</p></div></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-officially-drops-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-booster-boxes-to-just-12599-to-preorder-just-weeks-before-release]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People of Note launches April 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/people-of-note-launches-april-7</link>
            <guid>1439365</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Musical turn-based RPG dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Turn-based <a title="Genres > RPG [18,048 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > People of Note [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/people-of-note">People of Note</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,451 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,753 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [1,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,535 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1626170/People_of_Note/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/people-of-note-e50325" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/people-of-note/9nb2tf2p011b" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on April 7 for $24.99 with a 10 percent-off launch discount, publisher <a title="Companies > Annapurna Interactive [198 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/annapurna-interactive">Annapurna Interactive</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Iridium Studios [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/iridium-studios">Iridium Studios</a> announced. <span id="more-1025976"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Annapurna Interactive:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In this bold <a title="Genres > Turn-Based RPG [1,415 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/turn-based-rpg">turn-based RPG</a>, where musical numbers meet thrilling combat, join pop singer Cadence on her quest for stardom.</p><p><strong>Take the Stage</strong></p><p>After being shut out of the Noteworthy Song Contest, Cadence realizes that her solo act might not be enough for the judges. As she travels across Note to the Rock City of Durandis, the EDM City of <a title="Games > Lumina" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lumina">Lumina</a>, and more, Cadence fills out her band with eclectic and powerful musicians from lands afar. But something’s brewing in the distance…the Harmonic Convergence is playing havoc with the world’s musical energies, and dark forces are working behind the scenes to disrupt Note’s natural harmonies. It wasn’t in the set list, but Cadence and the others need to step up and make sure music itself still has a future on stage.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In <em>People of Note</em>, experience turn-based combat like never before: each battle is an interactive musical performance with evolving combat conditions, real-time rhythm-based attacks, and genre-bending mashup attacks!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Enjoy full-length cinematic musical sequences spanning a wide variety of musical genres, performed by our main cast of characters.</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [215 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> turn-based <a title="Genres > Action [3,413 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> combat as a dynamic, interactive musical performance.</li><li>Tempo-Based <a title="Genres > Rhythm [223 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rhythm">Rhythm</a> Combat: Time your attacks to the beat of the music for amplified damage against opponents.</li><li>Dynamic Combat Conditions: As the music in battle changes in real-time, strategize your attacks to synchronize with the current genre.</li><li>Musical <a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>hups: Combine the unique musical genres of your team members to unleash electrifying musical mashup attacks.</li><li>Explore Note, a massive world where each genre of music is represented by a completely unique environment and culture.</li><li>Dive into vibrant dungeons full of offbeat enemies and clever environmental puzzles.</li><li>Play it your way: Don’t like environmental puzzles? Turn ‘em off. Not into turn-based combat? Don’t worry, we got you. The entire experience of <em>People of Note</em> is completely customizable.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="People of Note | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8aM8gYssblw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/people-of-note-launches-april-7]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frontier Legends launches in Early Access this spring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/frontier-legends-launches-in-early-access-this-spring</link>
            <guid>1439362</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Wild West open-world survival crafting adventure game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Wild West <a title="Genres > Open-World [831 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> survival <a title="Genres > Crafting [49 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,893 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Frontier Legends" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/frontier-legends">Frontier Legends</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,535 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3032150/Frontier_Legends/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [356 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store this spring, developer <a title="Companies > Neojac Entertainment" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neojac-entertainment">Neojac Entertainment</a> announced. It will also be part of Steam Horse Fest between February 19 and 23 ahead of a new demo due out in March. <span id="more-1027304"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3032150/Frontier_Legends/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Frontier Legends</em> is an open-world adventure that combines survival, crafting and exploration in a Wild West setting. You arrive as a new settler on the frontier and are left to fend for yourself as you learn the ways of the West. Tend to your needs, manage resources and explore the wilderness; you just might unravel some of the land’s mysteries along the way.</p><p>Over time, you can build your own settlement, defend yourself from outlaws and bandits, form alliances, forge a reputation for good and bad and shape the path that will make you a legend. Do you have what it takes?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Build Your Own Frontier</strong> – Start with a small camp and grow it into a thriving frontier settlement shaped by your leadership. Recruit NPC settlers and assign daily work, farming, crafting, gathering and defense, to keep your town running. Lead well and your community thrives; neglect it and the frontier will catch up.</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Survival [511 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> on the Edge of Civilization</strong> – The frontier is unforgiving. <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge core needs and resources as you brave a harsh wilderness where the elements, wildlife and outlaws can turn a day trip into a fight for survival. Dynamic weather, day-night cycles and changing conditions require you to adapt every time you ride out.</li><li><strong>Forge Your Own Path</strong> – Live your Wild West fantasy your way. Become a hunter, trader, builder, bandit, lawman or something in between. Your choices shape your reputation in the frontier.</li><li><strong>Tame and Ride Wild Horses</strong> – Discover wild horses roaming the land, then tame and train them into trusted companions. Each horse has unique attributes and abilities, making them valuable allies and key for traveling, surviving and thriving in the frontier. When in danger, a good mount can be the difference between making it home or meeting the business end of a barrel.</li><li><strong>Explore and Uncover <a title="Games > Myst (2020) [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/myst-2020">Myst</a>eries</strong> – Push beyond your settlement to explore the unknown and uncover the hidden secrets of the frontier. Take on quests, solve puzzles and hunt legendary treasures as you explore ancient ruins and forgotten camps. Every discovery can change your fate and get you closer to becoming a legend yourself.</li><li><strong>Work Together or Turn on Each Other</strong> – Team up with others to trade, build and survive, or take the darker route: raid, betray and fight your way to a bigger slice of the frontier. Embark on your adventure with other players via <a title="Genres > Co-Op [376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative multiplayer</a>, participate in community events and compete in seasonal challenges to earn unique rewards and recognition.</li></ul><p>Are you ready to become a legend in the Wild West? Forge your path, conquer the frontier and write your own story in <em>Frontier Legends</em>.</p></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/frontier-legends-launches-in-early-access-this-spring]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["We weren't really paying attention" The Witcher's lead story designer reveals why the first game's final CG cutscene didn't involve the story team]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-1-lead-story-designer-talks-final-cg-cutscene</link>
            <guid>1439359</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt Red</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The long-awaited <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-remake">remake of the first Witcher game</a> is seemingly on the back-burner as CD Projekt Red has reportedly added support studio Fool's Theory to the massive development effort of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a>. Moreover, there have been recurring <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/witcher-3-expansion-rumours-analyst-100-percent-certain-cd-projekt-red-will-release-significant-new-content-this-year">rumours of an all-new Witcher 3 DLC</a> made by the same studio. Meanwhile, original lead story designer Artur Ganszyniec has been revisiting Geralt of Rivia's first big RPG adventure, giving longtime fans all-new insights into the game's making.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@artur-ganszyniec">Ganszyniec's YouTube channel</a> already houses his complete playthrough of the game with valuable commentary, so we highly recommend diehards to slowly chew through it if they have the time. That said, the story designer's most shocking revelation (hat tip to <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/that-was-a-mistake-i-think-the-witcher-1s-lead-writer-says-the-story-team-didnt-know-about-its-twist-ending/">VGC</a>) came near the very end, during the 26th and final episode of the series, which you can watch below:</p> <figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Ep. 26 –The Witcher with a designer's commentary: Epilogue" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fwRtKBkq0N8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Ep. 26 –The Witcher with a designer's commentary: Epilogue</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fwRtKBkq0N8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fwRtKBkq0N8?autoplay=1" title="Ep. 26 –The Witcher with a designer's commentary: Epilogue">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fwRtKBkq0N8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>At the 1:30:22 mark, once the 'artwork cutscene' in line with the rest of the game's ends, he talks about what happened between the story team and the rest of the studio. Apparently, a final CG cutscene (which is part of the game as we all know it) was added without the team knowing it. "That's where we wanted the game to end, with an open question and open future... But while we were finishing the game, someone decided – the board decided or Michał Kiciński (co-founder of CDPR) decided – that we needed an animated outro for the game," Ganszyniec says.</p>
<p>The CG cutscene introduced the idea of Witchers that are hunting down kings, which led directly into <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-2-assassins-of-kings">The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings</a>. "The script for what we're seeing now, this animation, was created not really involving the story team. It was sort of... we weren't really paying attention," the lead story designer adds before elaborating on what the story team's original plans were. "That's why the second Witcher is very political and there's not really room for exploring who Geralt is, his family, his history and stuff like this." If you've played through the entire Geralt trilogy, the shift is obvious, but having more clarity on what went down behind the scenes definitely helps after all these years.</p><p>Regardless, even Ganszyniec concludes he's excited to see how the remake turns out. As for the different route The Witcher 2 took, it could be argued <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">The Witcher 3: The Wild Hunt</a> went back to a more personal story with Geralt and his family at the centre of a high-stakes epic.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-1-lead-story-designer-talks-final-cg-cutscene]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Anniversary Update has arrived alongside the PS5 release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/avowed-anniversary-update-has-arrived-alongside-the-ps5-release/</link>
            <guid>1439332</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Marking the first birthday of Obsidian’s <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/avowed">Avowed</a>, the game is out now for PlayStation 5, and a meaty anniversary update has been released for the game on PC and Xbox Series X|S. The game is also now available through the regular <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Xbox Game Pass</a> tier, having originally been tied to ‘Day One’ elligible tiers.*</p>
<p><iframe title="Avowed Anniversary Update" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NO_uAjEhEpU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>On a high level, the anniversary update has added three new races that you can create your character as – dwarves, orlan and aumaua – and there’s a new quarterstaff weapon that you can adopt.</p>
<p>While the game wasn’t designed with it in mind, New Game Plus has also been added for anyone that has a save that’s passed the point of no return and beaten the game. Starting over, the only real caveat is that weapon levelling will not persist, but that’s fine because you’ll be nice and mighty in other ways.</p>
<p>And you can show off how mighty you are with a photo mode to capture specific moments while you’re playing.</p>

<p>Avowed was one of the highlights for Xbox and PC gamers last year, though one a little overlooked for launching in February and perhaps not being as broad as some might have liked, following on from the PIllars of Eternity games. “Avowed is an incredible RPG,” we said in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/13/avowed-review/">our review</a>. “Its vibrant world and stellar cast make every moment a joy to take part in, enhanced by a script that gives equal measure to drama, action and humour. Coming hot on the heels of Indiana Jones and The Great Circle, Microsoft’s software revival is well underway.”</p>



<p><wbr><br>
<b>New Game&nbsp;Plus</b>&nbsp;is now available after completing the main story. This mode is designed to reward mastery, experimentation,&nbsp;and making the all-powerful build.&nbsp;<wbr><br>
<b>When starting a New Game&nbsp;Plus&nbsp;save,&nbsp;players will bring along with them:</b>&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>All&nbsp;unlocked abilities (with the exception of&nbsp;godlike abilities which are gained through story progression/world exploration)&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All spent attribute points&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All unique weapons and armors—but they are reset to level 1&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All unlocked enchantments&nbsp;remain&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All unique gloves and boots&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All necklaces, all rings, and all trinkets&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Any&nbsp;<i>equipped</i>&nbsp;Common Weapons or Armor items are kept, but they are reset to level 1&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>The following&nbsp;are&nbsp;removed from the player at the start of a New Game Plus:</b>&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>All common weapons and armor that&nbsp;<i>aren’t</i>&nbsp;equipped&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Companions must be picked up via story progression&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Companions keep their talent points and start at level 1&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li><b>All resources that had been collected</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>Gold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Upgrade materials&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Enchanting materials&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Food ingredients&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>All consumables that had been collected</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>All potions&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All food&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>All quest items&nbsp;</b><wbr></li>
<li><b>All god totems/trinkets&nbsp;</b><wbr></li>
<li><b>Fast travel points/fog of war&nbsp;</b><wbr></li>
<li><b>The&nbsp;aforementioned godlike&nbsp;abilities</b>&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li><b>To ensure challenge scales alongside player power:</b>&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Enemy stats are increased across the board&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Enemies now have a chance to have modifiers applied to them&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Elemental Modifiers&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Fire: Immune to Fire damage and accumulation. Attacks also now deal Fire damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Frost: Immune to Frost damage and accumulation. Attacks also now&nbsp;deal&nbsp;Frost damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Shock: Immune to Shock damage and accumulation. Attacks also now deal Shock damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Poison: Immune to Poison damage and accumulation. Attacks also now&nbsp;deal&nbsp;Poison damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Bleed: Immune to Bleed damage and accumulation. Attacks also now&nbsp;deal&nbsp;Bleed damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Physical Modifiers&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Haste: Increased movement speed, attack speed, and reduced cooldown timers<wbr></li>
<li>Glass Cannon: Increased damage dealt and damage received&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Colossal: Increased maximum health&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Life Steal: Attacks restore the enemy’s health by a percentage of the damage dealt&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Crippled: Reduced movement speed and attack speed&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Sturdy: Increased stability&nbsp; making it harder for them to be stunned<wbr></li>
<li>Natural Immunity: Immune to all status accumulations&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Forceful: Increased impact on attacks&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Vindictive: Increased damage dealt based on the amount of health lost&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Attribute&nbsp;stat cap&nbsp;rises&nbsp;from&nbsp;<b>15 to&nbsp;30</b>&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>An important note for those who have already completed&nbsp;<i>Avowed</i></b>: Since New Game Plus is being added post release and the game was not initially designed with it in mind, a completion save will be necessary&nbsp;in order to&nbsp;take advantage of the mode. You will need to load a point of no return save or later and beat the game to make a proper New Game Plus save.&nbsp;<wbr></p>

<p>Included in the anniversary update is a major expansion to character creation:&nbsp;<b>three new playable species</b>&nbsp;join the existing Humans and Elves.&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Dwarves</b>&nbsp;–&nbsp;The most well-traveled species in Eora, the stout dwarves are known for their great strength and tenacity.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li><b>Orlans</b>&nbsp;–&nbsp;Their two-toned skin, prominent ears,&nbsp;and&nbsp;hirsute bodies all in the smallest size of Kith&nbsp;make them stand&nbsp;outs&nbsp;in Eora.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li><b>Aumaua</b>&nbsp;– Towering, powerfully built, and physically imposing.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p>Not only do the&nbsp;different species&nbsp;change how you look,&nbsp;the team&nbsp;has also added in stat bonuses for all species adding another layer to character creation.&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Humans</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+1 Might&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>+1 Resolve&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>Elves</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+1 Dexterity&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>+1 Perception&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>Aumaua</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+2 Might&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>Dwarves</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+1 Might&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>+1 Constitution&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>Orlans</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+1 Perception&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>+1 Resolve&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, players will receive stat bonuses depending on their chosen background.<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Arcane Scholar</b> – +2 to Intellect<wbr></li>
<li><b>Court Augur</b> – +2 to Resolve<wbr></li>
<li><b>Noble Scion</b> – +2 to Perception<wbr></li>
<li><b>Vanguard Scout</b> – +2 to Dexterity<wbr></li>
<li><b>War Hero</b> – +2 to Constitution<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Improved Character Creation</b><wbr><br>
Added new Godlike features, color variants, and presets<br>
<wbr></p>

<p>For players who want even finer control,&nbsp;<i>Avowed&nbsp;</i>now includes&nbsp;custom difficulty modifiers, allowing you to tune the&nbsp;game’s&nbsp;systems to your preferred experience.&nbsp;These new options are found by scrolling down through the “Game” tab of the settings menu.<wbr><br>
<b>Adjust player:&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Damage dealt&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Health, stamina, and&nbsp;essence&nbsp;resources&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Elemental status effect threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Health and essence regeneration rates&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Potion and food restoration rates&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Interrupt or knockdown ease&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Second Wind cooldown time&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Carry capacity&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Parry window&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Adjust enemy:&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Damage output&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Health&nbsp;pool&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Stun, interrupt, or knockdown ease&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Attack speed&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Elemental status effect threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Aggro&nbsp;threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Adjust companion:&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Damage&nbsp;dealt&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Health max&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Elemental status effect threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Aggro&nbsp;threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>As well as general adjustments:&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li><b>M</b>erchant prices&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Equipment upgrade material costs&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fall damage&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Trap damage&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Item quality damage reduction&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Important note: While changing these options will not negate&nbsp;most&nbsp;achievements that you may be hunting down, they will&nbsp;invalidate a Path of the Damned achievement.&nbsp;That achievement must be done&nbsp;without&nbsp;use of&nbsp;the custom game options.&nbsp;</b><wbr><br>
<b></b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Photo Mode</b><wbr><br>
Capture your envoy, companions, and the Living Lands from any angle and share your journey. Includes a free or fixed camera, filters, character rotation and toggle, post-process effects, and gradients. Photo Mode is accessed from the pause menu.<wbr><br>
<b></b></li>
<li><b>New Weapon</b><wbr><br>
A&nbsp;brand new&nbsp;weapon type is joining the arsenal with the quarterstaff. Designed with&nbsp;the&nbsp;archmage&nbsp;fantasy&nbsp;in mind, the quarterstaff&nbsp;is a new&nbsp;bludgeoning&nbsp;weapon that&nbsp;comes complete with wand style stun finishers.&nbsp;Unleash brutal physical&nbsp;combos along with a fury of spells that&nbsp;would make&nbsp;even&nbsp;Concelhaut&nbsp;jealous.<wbr><br>
<b></b></li>
<li><b>New Stun Finishers</b><wbr><br>
New stun finishers added for One-Handed Weapons and Two-Handed Weapons.<wbr><br>
<b></b></li>
<li><b>Respawning Encounters</b><wbr><br>
Respawning encounters have been added to Dawnshore, Emerald Stair, Shatterscarp, and Galawain’s Tusks.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>New Quality of Life Features</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Players can now change their Envoy’s appearance after character creation via the mirror in the party camp.<wbr></li>
<li>Newly placed workbenches allow players to upgrade gear without returning to party camp.<wbr></li>
<li>All player Backgrounds now have an added attribute bonus.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Added option to end dream conversations early.<wbr></li>
<li>Powder keg chain reactions now occur with a short delay, instead of all exploding simultaneously.<wbr></li>
<li>Increased max Controller Vibration Intensity (in the Controller Settings menu) from 1.0 to 2.0.<wbr></li>
<li>Added keyboard-based turning in accessibility options.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Improvements to Lighting</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>The lighting has been improved across all regions.<wbr></li>
<li>Improved the lighting in conversations.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Graphics</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Updated XeSS to 2.1. Xe Frame Generation, Xe Super Resolution, and Xe Low-Latency mode are now available to more GPUs.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><wbr><br>
<b>All Bug Fixes</b><wbr><br>
<wbr><br>
<b>Crashes and stability</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>The game should now longer crash after Fog of War has been cleared.<wbr></li>
<li>Addressed an issue causing Barbaric Smash killing blow VFX to remain on the player indefinitely<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue when creating save games that could cause NPCs to be stuck when reloading<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Performance and Optimizations</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Resolved an issue where NVIDIA Reflex Low Latency was missing “Off” option while upscaling is disabled.<wbr></li>
<li>Ray tracing is now off by default on Handheld PCs.<wbr></li>
<li>Added Mid Luminance values to HDR settings.<wbr></li>
<li>Various performance improvements.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Animation</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue with the Two-Handed Axe special attack not being aligned while in third person view.<wbr></li>
<li>Companion animations no longer stutter during conversations and exploration.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Audio</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>All audio should now play properly when cooking.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Quests &amp; Conversations</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Decals for puzzle in Sallow Steppe should now render properly.<wbr></li>
<li>The camera should behave normally during conversation with Tazaraak.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>UI/UX</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Ability and Grimoire Cost Discounts are now shown in the Character tab of the Ledger, as well as the maximum (-90%) available.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed Tanglefoot’s icon on Player’s and enemy’s HUD.<wbr></li>
<li>New Icon added to help distinguish Flurry of Blows on enemy’s HUD.<wbr></li>
<li>Text should no longer overlap tabs in certain languages.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed description for several active abilities that were incorrectly labeled as passive.<wbr></li>
<li>Resolved an issue where “confirm override” pop-up was not showing while switching presets in the Extras tab.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Marius’ Hunter Sense disappeared from hotbar after leaving Party Camp.<wbr></li>
<li>Vital bars are showing proper preview values for some skills when upgraded.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where “Survivalist” ability did not reflect additional bonuses in UI.<wbr></li>
<li>Blunted hits no longer include blood VFX when “Combat Blood” is disabled.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Combat/Systems Fixes</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed issue where various Area of Effect sources like Arcane Veil interfered with aiming player spells.<wbr></li>
<li>Swinging guillotines in the Garden remain disabled after loading a save.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Yatzli’s Explosive Blast did not break destructibles.<wbr></li>
<li>Some unique weapon enchantments now work properly while Dual Wield Mastery is active.<wbr></li>
<li>Already broken destructibles no longer receive damage numbers.<wbr></li>
<li>Loot now directly drops at the feet of a shattered frozen enemy.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>* If you need Xbox Game Pass tiers to be explained for being too complicated, then I suggest writing to your MP and Satya Nadella to complain.</em></p>
<p><em>via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2457220/view/511857117305504147">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/avowed-anniversary-update-has-arrived-alongside-the-ps5-release/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skyrim Switch 2 Update 1.2 brings proper performance fixes and a 60fps mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/skyrim-switch-2-update-1-2-brings-proper-performance-fixes-and-a-60fps-mode/</link>
            <guid>1439329</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Bethesda has released update 1.2 for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/skyrim">Skyrim</a> on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, fully addressing the woeful performance that blighted the game’s latest port. It follows on from an update shortly after its December release that quickly removed the frame rate cap to improve latency, but now tackles this with a full 60fps performance mode, fixes to visual glitches, and more.</p>
<p>The game performance is the most significant improvement, a new toggle under the Display settings letting you prioritise visuals or performance. This tweaks visual settings and resolution targets in order to deliver 60fps, which from anecdotal online accounts seems to be pretty solid. Additionally, the 30fps visuals have been locked back to this frame rate and the graphics tweaked to give steadier performance.</p>


<p>It’s a huge shame that the game couldn’t have had this degree of performance and refinement at its original release, as it led to a lot of bad reviews – we ended up having to give it <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/11/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-anniversary-edition-switch-2-review/">a 5/10 because of the issues</a>. However, it does give a glimmer of optimism for the Fallout 4 port to Switch 2 which is set to drop next week.</p>
<p>The Skyrim Switch 2 Update 1.2 patch notes are as follows</p>
<p><strong>Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Added a 60 Hz mode under Display settings that allows players to toggle between “Prioritize Visuals” or “Prioritize Performance”.</li>
<li>In addition, frame rate has been locked at 30 Hz in “Prioritize Visuals” mode for smoother gameplay.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Crashes and Performance Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed a crash that occurred when reading “The Crimson Dirks Vol. 4” book for the “Tilted Scales” quest in German.</li>
<li>Fixed an audio-related crash.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash, infinite load, and game freeze that sometimes occurred when rapidly selecting “Load” multiple times in the pause menu.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash that occurred when the “Transmute Ore” spell was repeatedly cast outside of the Haltered Stream Camp.</li>
<li>Improved FPS performance drops that occurred in the following locations:
<ul>
<li>during the Hide and Seek quest in Kynesgrove</li>
<li>during combat at Secunda’s Kiss</li>
<li>when discovering the “Drelas’ Cottage” location</li>
<li>when engaged in combat with a giant at the Talking Stone Camp.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Visuals Issues Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Viewing water planes from a distance or within menus caused them to shift up and down.</li>
<li>Distant aspen trees appeared with a blue tint.</li>
<li>Transitioning out of caves caused an outline of the entrance to linger during the fade-to-back loading screen.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>User Interface Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Switching between mouse and controller mode while in dialogue or the Help menu, caused different options to be highlighted.</li>
<li>Switching between mouse and controller mode while in help menus or user hints, did not dynamically update callout prompts.</li>
<li>The “Ready/Sheathe” option was missing from the Joy-Con 2 Mouse Controls menu.</li>
<li>The “Delete” prompt remained grayed-out within the Load menu when swapping between mouse and controller mode.</li>
<li>Deleting a save in the Save/Load menus reset the highlighted selection to the top of the menu list.</li>
<li>While in mouse mode, the cursor remained stuck within a smaller section of the screen when changing between docked/undocked modes or interfacing with GameChat.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Controls Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The “Eagle Eye” Archery perk remained active after switching between mouse and controller mode.</li>
<li>Holding down the Right Joystick while reassigning a button caused that button to disappear from the Controls list.</li>
<li>The Joy-Con 2 controllers provided haptic feedback while in mouse mode.</li>
<li>Buttons became unresponsive when controls were remapped while moving the Joy-Con 2 controllers in mouse mode.</li>
<li>Rotating the map in mouse mode was slower and less smooth than in controller mode.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Audio Issue Fix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Scrolling SFX continued to play while holding up or down on the Left Joystick or buttons at the top or bottom of the Save/Load menus.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Localization Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>“Amiibo” appeared as plural in Spanish.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Miscellaneous:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added new translations for the features listed above and UI updates.</li>
<li>Updates were made to the game credits.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: a social media hellhole we won’t link to.</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/skyrim-switch-2-update-1-2-brings-proper-performance-fixes-and-a-60fps-mode/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>