<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:39:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodlines 2 Combat Is Shaping Well Based on the Latest Dev Diary]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bloodlines-2-combat-is-shaping-well-based-on-the-latest-dev-diary/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloodlines-2-combat-is-shaping-well-based-on-the-latest-dev-diary.1097220/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/bloodlines-2-combat-is-shaping-well-based-on-the-latest-dev-diary/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Chinese Room has just <a href="https://www.paradoxinteractive.com/games/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2/news/dev-diary-advanced-combat-and-weapons" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published</a> the latest developer diary focused on Bloodlines 2 combat. It's a bit late on the schedule (it was originally meant to go live on January 29), but its content is well worth the wait, as the UK-based studio has provided several glimpses of what combat will look like when the first-person roleplaying game <a href="https://wccftech.com/bloodlines-2-tentatively-slated-for-first-half-of-2025-but-paradox-intends-to-license-out-a-potential-sequel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">releases later this year</a>.</p>
<p>To begin with, Senior Game Designer Max Bottomley revealed that the team has taken care to make dedicated melee animations for each of the playable clans. Banu has a sharp and quick style, Ventrue's is firm and precise, Tremere has a greater reach since they like to have some space between them and their foes, and Brujah is more brutally straightforward.</p>
<p><iframe title="1. clan attacks" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/1051169795?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture; clipboard-write; encrypted-media"></iframe></p>
<p>Regardless of which clan you'll pick, a Dashing ability is always available to Phyre. Not only is it useful to dodge attacks, but it can even be utilized aggressively, as dashing just as an enemy is attacking will break their attack and set them up for a counterattack.</p>
<p>Kicks are available, too, and there are even multiple types. Players can opt for a big swinging roundhouse if they're dealing with a group of enemies, while a powerful back-kick is ideal to send a single enemy flying, as shown below.</p>
<p><iframe title="2. counter attack" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/1051169861?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture; clipboard-write; encrypted-media"></iframe></p>
<p>Telekinesis is also an extremely useful tool in the Bloodlines 2 combat system. Phyre can employ it to grab an enemy and feed upon them, as shown below, or to manipulate the environment. Things like bottles and ashtrays can be thrown to make a noise to distract enemies as part of the stealth toolset, while throwing explosives such as a gas tank is a more destructive way to deal with enemy groups.</p>
<p>Telekinesis can also pick up weapons from the dead, from knives to sniper rifles. This is where things can get interesting if mixing in Discipline abilities. For example, Brujah's taunting ability, when used with mass manipulation, lets Phyre force enemies to drop their weapons and literally turn on them. When using Possession, the lead character can take control of a foe and drop them from a building.</p>
<p><iframe title="3. tk enemy to feed" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/1051169920?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture; clipboard-write; encrypted-media"></iframe></p>
<p>The Bloodlines 2 combat system will be augmented by four Elixirs that can be found and collected by playing the game. The Mending Elixir instantly restores health, while the Blood Elixir restores Blood Points to Phyre's abilities, which is particularly useful for combo chains. The Strength Elixir boosts damage done for some time, while the Fortitude Elixir reduces damage taken.</p>
<p>When the game launches, there will be three difficulty settings available to players: Easy, Normal, and Hard. The next developer diary, which will focus on the Masquerade in Seattle, is due on February 12.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warner and DC Smash 'em up MultiVersus joins the pile of dead live service games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warner-and-dc-smash-em-up-multiversus-joins-the-pile-of-dead-live-service-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warner-and-dc-smash-em-up-multiversus-joins-the-pile-of-dead-live-service-games.1097217/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warner-and-dc-smash-em-up-multiversus-joins-the-pile-of-dead-live-service-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/MultiVersus_Primary_Key_Art.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Warner Bros</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Warner Bros' licensed free-to-play fighting game <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/multiversus">MultiVersus</a> - aka, the one where Velma Dinkley and Arya Stark can team up to kick Superman's face in - will no longer be playable online as of 30th May. It'll be pulled from Steam, the Epic Games Store and the PlayStation and Xbox stores at the end of its next season, though you'll still be able to get your fill of Bugs Bunny bashing offline against either friends or bots.</p><!--more-->
<p>Season 5 is due to run from 4th February. It introduces DC's Aquaman and Looney Tunes's Lola Bunny - which, without wishing to rile up the Aquaman stans, strikes me as going out with a whimper. In-game real money transactions have been suspended as of today, but you have until 30th May to spend any in-game Gleamium currency or character tokens you already own. Players will be able to earn the new season 5 characters in-game: Aquaman is the first tier battlepass reward, while Lola is the daily calendar login reward.</p>
<p>They've put together a little guide to playing MultiVersus offline once the servers are pulled. Here it is:</p>
<blockquote><p>All online features will continue to be available until Season 5 concludes on May 30 at 9 a.m. PST. At that point, there will be an option to play MultiVersus offline via the local gameplay mode, either solo against A.I. opponents or with up to three friends. To do this, you'll need to install/download the latest version of the game and log in during Season 5, any time between February 4 at 9 a.m. PST and May 30 at 9 a.m. PST. After logging in, a local save file will be automatically created connected to your PlayStation Network, Microsoft Store, Steam, or Epic Games Store account, allowing you to enjoy the game offline with all earned and purchased content moving forward.</p></blockquote>
<p>As snarky as I may sound here, the RPS hivemind was reasonably keen on MultiVersus for a time. It once appeared on our lists of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-free-pc-games">best free PC games</a>, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-co-op-games">best co-op games</a>, and the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-multiplayer-games-on-pc">best multiplayer games</a>. You can still trace its presence there, clinging on determinedly by way of the article tags.</p><p>Writing about the open beta <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/multiversus-lacks-that-nintendo-polish-but-its-still-a-slick-smash-bros-like-in-open-beta">back in July 2022</a>, Ed Thorn (RPS in peace) summarised MultiVersus as follows: "learn to cut through its barrage of boxes and cooldowns, and you're left with a cracking fighting game that's only going to evolve over the coming months." Alas, no more.</p>
<p>It's not clear what all this means for developers Player First Games, who were acquired by Warner Bros last year. Warner's games division have not been in the pink lately, with Rocksteady's Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/suicide-squad-failed-for-all-the-reasons-you-could-have-guess-it-failed-report-says">cratering</a> at launch and receiving its final update this month. As with MultiVersus, Rocksteady at least took the time to add an <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/action/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-is-now-officially-finished-as-its-final-update-goes-live/">offline mode</a> before calling it a night.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Does Cross-Platform Play Work In Sniper Elite: Resistance?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-cross-play-xbox-pc-ps5-ps4-1851752736</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-does-cross-platform-play-work-in-sniper-elite-resistance.1097202/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-cross-play-xbox-pc-ps5-ps4-1851752736<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="1c0c5212e456aa4cdd576bcf96d4e1a8" data-recommend-id="image://1c0c5212e456aa4cdd576bcf96d4e1a8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A sniper overlooks a dam." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A sniper overlooks a dam." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Rebellion</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1c0c5212e456aa4cdd576bcf96d4e1a8" data-recommend-id="image://1c0c5212e456aa4cdd576bcf96d4e1a8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A sniper overlooks a dam." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>There aren’t really many shooters out there as dedicated to realistic sniping as the Sniper Elite franchise. That dedication continues in the all-new<em> Sniper Elite: Resistance</em>, which puts you in the boots of an entirely new protagonist and sends you off to pop Nazi noggins. But while its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-how-long-campaign-difficulty-1851749581&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-how-long-campaign-difficulty-1851749581">campaign is a stealthy good time</a></span>, you may be interested in checking out the game’s various multiplayer options, too, leaving you to wonder if it offers cross-platform support. <br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195734" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: What’s Coming Out Beyond Cyberpunk 2077: Phantom Liberty" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="157" data-playlist="195734,196411,195189" data-current="195734"><div><p>The Week In Games: What’s Coming Out Beyond Cyberpunk 2077: Phantom Liberty</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195734/195734_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195734/195734_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195734/195734_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195734/195734_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21246.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h118000"><a id="play"></a>Does <em>Sniper Elite: Resistance</em> have cross-platform support?</h2><p>Let’s get to the quick and easy answer: <strong>Yes, <em>Sniper Elite: Resistance</em> offers cross-platform support</strong>. </p><p>You can play any type of multiplayer mode with players from any other platform. <strong>This functionality includes playing the game’s campaign in co-op</strong>, all competitive multiplayer modes, and invading other players (or fending off their invasions).</p><h2 id="h118001"><a id="prog"></a>Does Sniper Elite: Resistance have cross-progression?</h2><p>While it’s great news that you can play with your friends on any platform, you unfortunately can’t carry over your own saves if you’re the type to switch between platforms. <strong><em>Sniper Elite: Resistance</em> does not feature cross-progression</strong>. Whatever platform you purchase the game on is the only platform your save will ever function on. </p><hr><p><em>Sniper Elite: Resistance</em> is available now on PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X/S, Xbox One, and PC. If you’re just now diving in, make sure to check out our <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-tips-ping-health-noise-1851749709&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-tips-ping-health-noise-1851749709">starter tips for the game</a></span> to get a leg up on the Nazi scum standing in your way.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle PC Specs—How To Play The Sims 1 and 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle-pc-specs-how-to-play-the-sims-1-and-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle-pc-specs%E2%80%94how-to-play-the-sims-1-and-2.1097196/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle-pc-specs-how-to-play-the-sims-1-and-2/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-87297">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>EA has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-sims-1-and-2-re-released-by-ea-as-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">officially announced</a> and launched the re-release of both The Sims 1 and The Sims 2 as part of The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle. This bundle brings two classic titles—along with all expansions and DLC—to current-day players with modern PCs. </p>



<p>As far as running the games on your machine, it won’t take a high-powered machine. That said it will have some updates including an updated rendering engine as well as a “more versatile pixel resolution scaling on large monitors”. But just how modern does your PC need to be?</p>



<h2>The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle PC Specs</h2>



<p>EA has revealed that both The Sims 1 and 2 will work on hardware as old as 2012. The minimum system requirements go as far back as the Nvidia GTX 600 or AMD Radeon HD 7000 for graphics and AMD FX6300 or Intel i3 3220 for CPU. The game also won’t take up much space if that’s something you’re concerned about.</p>



<p>Check out the full minimum requirements for yourself, below.</p>



<h3>The Sims: Legacy Collection PC Specs</h3>



<ul>
<li>OS: Windows 10</li>



<li>CPU: AMD Ryzen 3 1200, AMD FX6300, or Intel i3 3220</li>



<li>Memory (RAM): 4GB</li>



<li>GPU: AMD Radeon HD 7000 or Nvidia GTX 600</li>



<li>Online Connection Requirements: Purchase, Install, Register</li>



<li>Hard Drive Space: 16GB</li>
</ul>



<h3>The Sims 2: Legacy Collection PC Specs</h3>



<ul>
<li>OS: Windows 10</li>



<li>CPU: i3 3220, Ryzen 3 1200, AMD FX6300</li>



<li>Memory (RAM): 4GB</li>



<li>Hard Drive Space: 16GB</li>



<li>GPU: NVIDIA: GTX 600 series or later or AMD: Radeon HD 7000 series or later or Intel HD Graphics 620 series or later</li>
</ul>



<p>What are your thoughts on the PC specs needed to run The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/news/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all of the latest news</a> you need to know. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date/">Monster Hunter Wilds Release Date—Release Time, Platforms, Editions, and Price</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The popular legacy of the MH series continues with Monster Hunter Wilds, so let’s check out its release date, different editions and more.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-mission-3-sonderzuge-sabotage-workbenches-sniper-elite-resistance/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-mission-3-sonderzuge-sabotage-workbenches-sniper-elite-resistance/">All Mission 3 Sonderzüge Sabotage Workbenches in Sniper Elite Resistance</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sniper Elite Resistance Mission 3 is Sonderzüge Sabotage and its Workbenches can be a pain in the hinter to find!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-play-sniper-elite-resistance-co-op-multiplayer/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-play-sniper-elite-resistance-co-op-multiplayer/">How To Play Sniper Elite Resistance Co-op Multiplayer With Friends</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Multiplayer and co-op is a big aspect of Sniper Elite Resistance, so let’s walk you through putting together a lobby and playing together.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-5-ps5-release-period-release-times/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-5-ps5-release-period-release-times/">Forza Horizon 5 PS5 Release Period—Release Times Details &amp; New Horizon Realms Content</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Forza Horizon 5 on PS5 is finally confirmed and we have the latest details on its release as its arrival speeds onto the PlayStation scene.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[25 Years Later, Nintendo Switch Online Brings Back This Classic N64 Racing Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/25-years-later-nintendo-switch-online-brings-back-this-classic-n64-racing-game/1100-6529175/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/25-years-later-nintendo-switch-online-brings-back-this-classic-n64-racing-game.1097193/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/25-years-later-nintendo-switch-online-brings-back-this-classic-n64-racing-game/1100-6529175/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529175">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It's been a long time since there's been a new game in Namco's Ridge Racer series, and it's anyone's guess if the franchise will make a comeback. But in the interim, Ridge Racer 64--which was originally released in February 2000--has made a welcome return on Nintendo Switch. As seen in the announcement trailer below, Ridge Racer 64 still has that classic arcade-style charm a quarter century later.</p><p>Unfortunately, this game isn't available as a standalone purchase. It was re-released earlier today exclusively for Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack subscribers--which costs $50 per year for individuals and $80 for families in exchange for access to N64, Sega Genesis, and Game Boy Advance games as well as select DLC for modern titles.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="906142201" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465652,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%20Online%20-%20Nintendo%2064%20Update%20%7C%20Ridge%20Racer%2064&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:60,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-online-nintendo-64-update-ridge-racer-64\/2300-6465652\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465652\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465652\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465652\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465652&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465652,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6529175&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;ridge-racer-64&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-64,nintendo-switch&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;nintendo&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;ridge-racer&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;ridge-racer&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465652},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465652\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4436662-22.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/TVodmAzC.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1738334640,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="TVodmAzC" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch Online - Nintendo 64 Update | Ridge Racer 64</p>
      </div>
<p>Ridge Racer 64 includes a Quick Play option for anyone who just wants a fast run through the Revolution Novice course. Veteran drivers can try their hand on the Grand Prix and choose from nine different race tracks.</p><p>The game also includes Car Attack, Time Attack, Battle Mode, Stage Mode, and Team Mode. The trailer also confirms the return of the game's multiplayer option for up to four drivers at once. This might be the best way to experience any Ridge Racer game, especially since <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-feature-packed-ridge-racer-arcade-cabinet-is-only-300/1100-6509498/" data-ref-id="1100-6509498">Arcade1Up's Ridge Racer cabinet</a> is long out of production.</p><p>Nintendo Switch Online recently opened its vault and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-adds-fatal-fury-2-and-other-snes-hidden-gems-to-nintendo-switch-online/1100-6529006/" data-ref-id="1100-6529006">expanded its SNES lineup</a> with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fatal-fury-2/" data-ref-id="5000-6879">Fatal Fury 2</a>, Sutte Hakkun, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/super-ninja-boy/" data-ref-id="5000-17695">Super Ninja Boy</a>. Late last year, Nintendo Switch Online also offered <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-adds-three-genesis-games-including-some-leaving-steam/1100-6528102/" data-ref-id="1100-6528102">a handful of Sega's older games</a>, including ToeJam &amp; Earl in Panic on Funkotron, Vectorman, and Mercs.</p><p>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four Years Later, 60fps Bloodborne Patch Gets Taken Down By Sony]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/four-years-later-60fps-bloodborne-patch-gets-taken-down-by-sony/1100-6529174/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/four-years-later-60fps-bloodborne-patch-gets-taken-down-by-sony.1097187/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/four-years-later-60fps-bloodborne-patch-gets-taken-down-by-sony/1100-6529174/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529174">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sony has filed a DMCA takedown of a fan-made <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bloodborne-60fps-patch-released-by-hacker/1100-6487299/" data-ref-id="1100-6487299">Bloodborne 60 frames per second patch</a> nearly four years after its release.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/bloodborne/" data-ref-id="5000-285291">Bloodborne</a> is a beloved From Software action-RPG that's only officially available on PS4, running at a frame rate of 30fps. In 2020, Lance McDonald revealed a 60fps patch for Bloodborne that he was working on, and it got a wide release on February 21, 2021. While players needed to go through extra steps, like jailbreaking their PS4, to access this patch's enhancements, it quickly gained notoriety in lieu of an official enhanced PC and PS5-enhanced port of Bloodborne by Sony.</p><p>Sony let this fan-made patch be for around four years, but it's now no longer available. McDonald took to X (formerly Twitter) today, January 31, and revealed that he complied with a Sony request to remove any links to their 60fps Bloodborne patch. This makes the process of finding and downloading the 60fps Bloodborne patch significantly more difficult than it was before.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/manfightdragon/status/1885347693125566806" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">On February 21st, 2021, I created and released a patch for Bloodborne which makes the game run at 60fps. Today I received a DMCA takedown notification on behalf of Sony Interactive Entertainment asking that I remove links to the patch I posted on the internet, so I've now done so</p>  — Lance McDonald (@manfightdragon) <a href="https://twitter.com/manfightdragon/status/1885347693125566806?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>It's unclear why Sony's legal action against this 60fps patch was so belated. While many fans, including <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/mega-streamer-kai-cenat-is-streaming-bloodborne-to-call-attention-to-fan-demand-for-a-pc-port-playstation-fromsoft-this-is-one-of-the-most-highly-requested-games-for-a-remaster-and-a-pc-version/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kai Cenat</a>, have requested Bloodborne ports of PC and PS5, Sony has not publicly announced any plan to do so. It recently toyed with fans of Bloodborne by showing footage of the FromSoftware title behind the statement "it's about persistence" in its 30th Anniversary celebratory video. If you want to play Bloodborne, the PS4 version of it is part of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-playstation-plus-january-2025-games-for-premium-and-extra-subscribers/2900-6131/" data-ref-id="2900-6131">PlayStation Plus Extra</a> game catalog.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529091&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-essential-free-games-for-february-2025\/1100-6529091\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529101&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-moving-away-from-monthly-ps4-games\/1100-6529101\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529086&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-lunar-new-year-event-returns-this-time-with-an-even-bigger-xp-buff\/1100-6529086\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529076&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/one-of-wow-most-famous-pieces-of-cut-content-is-playable-today\/1100-6529076\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529150&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-division-2s-next-dlc-will-bring-the-series-to-brooklyn-later-this-year\/1100-6529150\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529148&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps5s-classic-anniversary-themes-are-leaving-but-wont-be-gone-forever\/1100-6529148\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529081&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-is-now-live-will-test-cross-play-and-split-screen-co-op\/1100-6529081\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529156&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/forza-horizon-5-is-the-next-xbox-game-to-speed-onto-playstation-5\/1100-6529156\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528799&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-limited-edition-4k-steelbook-preorders-discounted-at-amazon\/1100-6528799\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529088&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/despite-xboxs-struggles-in-hardware-microsoft-was-reportedly-the-top-video-game-publisher-in-december\/1100-6529088\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529098&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-loses-legal-battle-with-an-unexpected-super-mario\/1100-6529098\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529100&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-is-offering-some-sweet-treats-if-you-play-its-pc-games-with-a-psn-account\/1100-6529100\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529157&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/your-landlord-can-force-mandatory-isp-service-on-you-fccs-new-chair-says\/1100-6529157\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528994&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-open-beta-test-set-for-february\/1100-6528994\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529053&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-massive-4k-blu-ray-collection-compiling-all-six-lord-of-the-rings-and-hobbit-films-launching-in-march\/1100-6529053\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529105&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/after-dragon-age-the-veilguard-comes-up-short-bioware-undergoes-changes\/1100-6529105\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529135&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-will-get-several-substantial-updates-in-2025\/1100-6529135\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529137&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battletech-anniversary-edition-gets-new-expansion-and-miniatures-packs\/1100-6529137\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 1 & 2 re-releases are out now, and you can get both for £35]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-2-re-releases-are-out-now-and-you-can-get-both-for-25</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-1-2-re-releases-are-out-now-and-you-can-get-both-for-%C2%A335.1097178/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-2-re-releases-are-out-now-and-you-can-get-both-for-25<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-sims-1-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
After a bit of cheeky teasing earlier in the week that had <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/video-game-franchises/the-sims">The Sims</a> fans positively salivating, EA has turn speculation into truth: <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims">The Sims 1</a> &amp; 2 are getting re-releases to celebrate the series' 25th anniversary. And better yet, they're out today on PC.
</p>
<p>
The Sims 1 &amp; 2 have, of course, long been unavailable in an official capacity on PC, with the 25-year-old original never getting a digital release and its sequel's short-lived Ultimate Collection being yanked from Origin in 2018. A report earlier this week, however - which coincided with some not-entirely-subtle teasing from EA - suggested <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-2-reportedly-getting-pc-re-releases-this-week">that was about to change</a>. 
</p>
<p>
And now it's official. The Sims: Legacy Collection and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-2">The Sims 2</a>: Legacy Collection are both available for purchase on PC from today, each providing access to their respective base game and all subsequent expansions. Additionally, EA has released The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle, containing both Legacy Collections and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-4">The Sims 4</a> base game.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Sims &amp; The Sims 2 Legacy Collections - Official Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QQUMkHngWjA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Sims &amp; The Sims 2 Legacy Collections - Official Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QQUMkHngWjA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QQUMkHngWjA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Sims &amp; The Sims 2 Legacy Collections reveal trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QQUMkHngWjA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
If you're ready to be catapulted back to the year 2000, The Sims: Legacy Collection costs £17.99 and includes The Sims 1, plus its Living' Large, House Party, Hot Date, Vacation, Unleashed, Superstar, and Makin' Magic packs. It also comes with the Throwback Fit Kit for The Sims 4. The Sims 2: Legacy Collection, meanwhile, costs £24.99 and includes the 2005 base game, The Sims 4's Grunge Revival Kit, plus all the following The Sims 2 expansion packs:
</p>
<ul>
<li>The Sims 2: University</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Nightlife</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Open for Business</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Pets</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Bon Voyage</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Seasons</li>
<li>The Sims 2: FreeTime</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Apartment Life</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Holiday Party Pack</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Family Fun Stuff</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Glamour Life Stuff</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Happy Holiday Stuff</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Celebration! Stuff</li>
<li>The Sims 2: H&amp;M Fashion Stuff</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Teen Style Stuff</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Kitchen &amp; Bath Interior Design Stuff</li>
<li>The Sims 2: Mansion &amp; Garden Stuff</li>
</ul>
<p>
And if you want to go all-in, The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle is £34.99. All packs are available for purchase on Steam, the EA App, and The Epic Games Store, and EA Play Pro members on the EA App get access to both collections from today.
</p><p>
All this arrives as part of EA's 25th anniversary celebrations for The Sims, which climaxes next Tuesday, 4th February, with a 25-hour livestream. A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-4-marking-series-25th-anniversary-with-huge-free-update-adding-70-new-items">"huge" free 25th anniversary update</a> for The Sims 4 - adding 70+ new items and a new limited-time event - arrives on the same day, and the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/it-looks-like-2007s-surprisingly-alright-the-sims-spin-off-mysims-is-heading-to-switch">MySims: Cozy Bundle that released on Switch last year</a> is coming to PC on 18th March. Now we just need something <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-3">The Sims 3</a>-related and the celebrations will be complete.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taking a trip to Tramau in City Transport Simulator: Tram]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/31/city-transport-simulator-tram-first-impressions-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/taking-a-trip-to-tramau-in-city-transport-simulator-tram.1097163/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/31/city-transport-simulator-tram-first-impressions-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Trams. The trains of the streets. Once a staple of British cities, first as horsedrawn trams and eventually electricity as the dominant power method, the rise of the motorcar and busses (and even trolley busses) saw basically all of our tram tracks ripped up by the 1960s. Now they’re oddities with limited routes in Croydon, Manchester, Nottingham, Edinburgh and a few other cities in the UK.</p>
<p>Over on the continent, though? Well, Vienna’s trams are iconic, and there’s large networks in Cologne, Berlin, Milan, Budapest and beyond that never went away, living alongside busses, metros and trains. They often have the best of all worlds, serving inner cities, having large raised platforms, and minimal air pollution.</p>
<p>So anyway, trams are pretty neat if you’re a public transport user, and the team at ViewApp agree. A few years on from the TramSim games, they’ve now released City Transport Simulator: Tram, bringing the game out of Steam Early Access this week.</p>
<p><iframe title="City Transport Simulator: Tram - Out Now! (PEGI)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iwU99WshX2U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>I’ll be honest, the simulator craze has largely passed me by, but I’ve got childhood memories of catching trams in Vienna or Budapest on holiday, and there’s always a tram ride or two each year at Gamescom. but City Transport Simulator: Tram doesn’t take you to any of the real cities. Instead, there’s the German/Austrian-like fictional city of Tramau.</p>

<p>As the intro cinematic tells you, this city has always had plenty of trams, but as the years have gone by, the network has lost some of its vim and vigour. So the mayor has bought trams from all over the world to turn Tramau into the living tram museum of a tram-lover’s dreams.</p>

<p>The career mode gives you the whole network of trams to manage, with limited resources to start that you need to build up as you craft a hustling, bustling public transport network, customising the tram liveries along the way. You’ll obviously be able to drive the trams as well, like you’re a CEO on Undercover Boss or something.</p>
<p>But you don’t have to engage with that management side of things if you’d rather just drive some trams. Once you’ve completed the tutorial that runs you through the basics, you can easily just pick a tram and route to drive, or have the game pick for you with a Quick Play option.</p>
<p>Driving a tram is pretty straightforward. You’re on tracks, so all you have to worry about there is setting the throttle, minding the speed limits and traffic lights (there’s tram-specific lights at many junctions), and coming to a stop for each station. You’ll quickly get the hang of pulling away from a station or junction, quickly toggling the throttle back to neutral to manage the top speed, and then slowing at the station to hit the mark. I do wish it was a little more naunced, though. Especially on keyboard, it feels very digital and having some additional throttle stops for 25% and 50% would help with that more graceful arrival into a station or maintaining a speed through a curve or hill.</p>

<p>I also wish there was a little more of a helping hand in certain key areas. You can settle for simplified controls that peel away needing to fuss with doors and signalling, but it would be great to have distant traffic lights highlighted and enlarged in the UI. You have the speed limits in the speedometer, and can zoom your view quite a lot, but I missed a bunch of overhead traffic lights on my first couple efforts.</p>
<p>The game has that rather clean and pristine look that you’ll be used to from simulator games, but aside from the trams that have been recreated in fine detail, I like the look of Tramau as a place. It really captures the feel of a European city, with the pastel rendered buildings, the blocks of buildings, the mix of classic architecture and modern flat faces, the narrower streets, the way that tram tracks and car lanes blend together and separate. It’s a great stand-in for the many cities that have these tram networks.</p>
<p>Of course, there’s a lot of Vienna that the game is trying to mimic. Depending on the version of the game you get – from £20 Standard Edition to the £40 Collector’s Edition – there’s up to 7 trams, and over half of them are from the Viennese network, including the modern vehicles and the classic E1, which looks as old and retro as you’d hope.</p>

<p>You’ll mainly be looking around the driver’s cabin of each, and there’s all the buttons and toggles that you’d expect. More than you’ll typically need, to be fair, so there’s interactive toggles for heating and defrosting the windscreen on the old E1. Mostly it’s just drive, signalling and managing the doors for people to get on and off. Also some quick camera view swaps from cockpit to passenger area and a follow cam.</p>
<p>Disappointingly, I ran into some slightly annoying bugs in my first little foray with the game. Setting a name for my person, I couldn’t call him ‘Stefan Strassenbahn’ getting a complaint about using special characters, even without the ß. But that’s fine. More frustrating were instances where the simulation broke down. At one semi-pedestrianised station, pedestrians would just walk into my stationary tram and clip through before disappearing into nothingness, so that every time I tried to drive off, I’d get a warning about hitting people. Coming to the final stop, all the traffic (including another tram up ahead of me) was completely stuck in place despite the lights cycling multiple times. Bored, I stepped out of the driver’s cabin, the tram started moving on its own, and I was clipped outside of it. Then the game crashed.</p>
<p>That’s more than a few rough edges that I’d have hoped the stint in Early Access would have helped to stamp out. It’s a shame, because what’s there feels like it should really appeal to tram and sim enthusiasts. With a few patches, this could still become a tram-filled paradise.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 1 and 2 Re-Released for Franchise's 25th Anniversary]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/the-sims-1-and-2-re-released</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-1-and-2-re-released-for-franchises-25th-anniversary.1097160/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/the-sims-1-and-2-re-released<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>EA has shadow-dropped re-releases for&nbsp;<em>The Sims 1&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>2&nbsp;</em>as part of the franchise's 25th anniversary, and you can pick both of them up right now on PC.</p>

<p>Starting from today,&nbsp;<em>The Sims Legacy Collection&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>The Sims 2 Legacy Collection&nbsp;</em>are both available on PC via Steam, Epic, and the EA app, although you will need to install and use EA's proprietary software on Steam and Epic to play them.</p>

<p>Both packs bundle in&nbsp;the base games and all of the expansions released for both of them throughout their lifetimes, as well as&nbsp;<em>Sims 4</em>-themed bonus content to sweeten the deal. It's a deal that might need quite a bit of sweetening, too, given that the first&nbsp;<em>Sims</em>&nbsp;will set you back $20 and the second will cost $30 (although there's also a $40 bundle).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-sims-1-and-2-re-released-sims-2.jpg?itok=bh8deMti 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-sims-1-and-2-re-released-sims-2.jpg?itok=vcPPqQbh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You can now say "sul sul" to the first two&nbsp;<em>Sims&nbsp;</em>games on PC.</figcaption></figure><p>Aside from the included bonus content, it seems like these aren't remasters of&nbsp;<em>The Sims&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>The Sims 2</em>, but re-releases, which means you shouldn't expect too much in the way of revamped visuals and gameplay.</p>

<p>Still, if you're looking for some nostalgic retro thrills and you're yearning for a return to the days when not everything in&nbsp;<em>The Sims&nbsp;</em>was sold via DLC or microtransaction, then you'll definitely want to pick these re-releases up.</p>

<p>You can check out the (rather disturbing) launch trailer for&nbsp;<em>The Sims&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>The Sims 2&nbsp;</em>right here. Be aware that it contains at least one clown.</p>




<p>These re-releases harken back to a simpler time, when the direction EA was taking with&nbsp;<em>The Sims&nbsp;</em>was perhaps a bit simpler and more conventional.</p>

<p>Back in September, the studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-no-plans-the-sims-5" rel="nofollow">revealed that it has no plans</a> to create&nbsp;<em>The Sims 5&nbsp;</em>anytime soon, and that the focus is instead on creating more content for&nbsp;<em>The Sims 4</em>, as well as updating the game to ensure it keeps up with modern standards.</p>

<p>If you wish the series would return to traditional flagship games rather than this live service-adjacent model, then it looks like&nbsp;<em>The Sims 1&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>2</em>'s re-releases may be where you get your money's worth. They're both available now on Steam, Epic, and the EA app.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7's post-launch plans include free multiplayer and Age features and paid Ada Lovelace]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-7s-post-launch-plans-include-free-multiplayer-and-age-features-and-paid-ada-lovelace</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-7s-post-launch-plans-include-free-multiplayer-and-age-features-and-paid-ada-lovelace.1097157/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-7s-post-launch-plans-include-free-multiplayer-and-age-features-and-paid-ada-lovelace<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Carthage, Britain, Nepal and Bulgaria coming down the pipe after release</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_bxMwncu.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>2K Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The post-launch update and DLC schedule for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Sid Meier's Civilization VII</a> slightly discombobulates me, because the image above is weirdly reminiscent of Civ 7's own historical Age progression screens. But that uncanny similarity also pleases me, because I can now do the intro joke "all roadmaps lead to Rome".* 
</p>
<p>
In case you missed it, the new 4X <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy</a> jobbo is out 11th February. Developers Firaxis have now sketched out plans for updating it, which extend from the usual balancing and bug fixes to a variety of new map types, possible multiplayer features and Age settings.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
All that's from <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1295660/view/508445172204306615?l=english">a Steam post</a> which comments that the developers have "a seemingly endless list of ideas". I too have endless ideas - becoming an expert on toadstools, writing a feature film inspired by both Event Horizon and the Oresteia, inventing the Hammer of Dawn weapon from Gears Of War so that I can write evil slogans on my local football pitch, finishing this news post before 5pm. But as we all know, human beings are not endless, and it's possible some of the Civilization 7 team's grand plans won't come to fruition.
</p>
<p>
"The first set of updates we'll be providing are those that directly target the game as it currently stands," the Steam post comments. "There will be some bugs to fix, plenty of balance changes to make, and we know there are spots in the gameplay and user interface that can be enhanced with any number of quality-of-life improvements. You'll see regular updates from us in all of these areas."
</p>
<p>
Beyond these routine tune-ups, they're prioritising the below "features that didn't quite make it in for our initial launch". They don't have arrival dates, but there are definitely developers working on them.
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>
- Adding Teams to multiplayer games so we can let you play cooperatively
</p>
<p>
- Expanding to 8 players for multiplayer in all Ages through refinements to our Distant Land system
</p>
<p>
- Allowing you to pick your starting and ending Age to allow for single or double Age games
</p>
<p>
- Providing a wider variety of map types
</p>
<p>
- Adding in hotseat multiplayer
</p></blockquote>
<p>
The post also goes over some of the forthcoming paid additions to the forthcoming nation-nurser. They'll be grouped into themed "content collections" that encompass new leaders, civilisations and wonders of the world - all to be released "over the course of a few months" rather than in one dollop.
</p><p>
The first of these boutique-sounding groupings is the Crossroads of the World collection, which will roll out in March 2025. It'll arrive in two doses, the first of which includes "long-standing favourites" Carthage and Great Britain, plus the new leader Ada Lovelace, "who has a way of mastering a game world unlike any other". Some sort of analog AI revolution, perhaps? The second Crossroads of the World drop adds Simón Bolívar and the all-new civs Bulgaria and Nepal.
</p>
<p>
The full Steam post also discusses the game's victory types, and how they mesh with the new Age system. It's been a while since I properly played Civ - I think Civ 5 was the last one I really sold my soul to. I'm curious to see how Ages change things in practice, though I am disappointed to learn that the new 4X makes use of ye scurvy Denuvo DRM.
</p>
<p><em>*It's probably been done before</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 1 and 2 Re-released By EA As The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-sims-1-and-2-re-released-by-ea-as-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-1-and-2-re-released-by-ea-as-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle.1097151/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-sims-1-and-2-re-released-by-ea-as-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The first two The Sims games are back. EA has announced—and re-released—both The Sims 1 and The Sims 2 for PC as part of a new collection called The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle. </p>



<p>The news <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-sims-re-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirms reports</a> from earlier this week that EA was set to announce the release of both games on Friday.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Sims &amp; The Sims 2 Legacy Collections - Official Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QQUMkHngWjA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>“{We’re] taking it back to where it all began with the launch of<em>&nbsp;</em>The Sims 25<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;Birthday Bundle,” EA <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/the-sims/news/the-birthday-bundle" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said in the announcement.</a> “You’ve been asking for it, and we’re thrilled to finally return to the days when we first reimagined the ways people play with life.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The games will be available to purchase in three different bundles: The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle, The Sims: Legacy Collection, and The Sims 2: Legacy Collection.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle-includes">What The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle Includes</h2>



<p>Retailing for $39.99, The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle includes both games along with all released DLC. If you just want one game or the other, those will set you back $19.99 for The Sims: Legacy Collection and $29.99 for The Sims 2: Legacy Collection.</p>



<p>As far as DLC is concerned, The Sims: Legacy Collection comes with the following:</p>



<ul>
<li>The Sims: Livin’ Large</li>



<li>The Sims: House Party</li>



<li>The Sims: Hot Date</li>



<li>The Sims: Vacation</li>



<li>The Sims: Unleashed</li>



<li>The Sims: Superstar</li>



<li>The Sims: Makin’ Magic</li>



<li>The Sims 4: Throwback Fit&nbsp;Kit</li>
</ul>



<p>For The Sims 2: Legacy Collection, you’ll get:</p>



<ul>
<li>The Sims 2: University</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Nightlife</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Open for Business</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Pets</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Bon Voyage</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Seasons</li>



<li>The Sims 2:&nbsp;FreeTime</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Apartment Life</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Holiday Party Pack</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Family Fun Stuff</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Glamour Life Stuff</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Happy Holiday Stuff</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Celebration! Stuff</li>



<li>The Sims 2: H&amp;M Fashion Stuff</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Teen Style Stuff</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Kitchen &amp; Bath Interior Design Stuff</li>



<li>The Sims 2: Mansion &amp; Garden Stuff</li>



<li>The Sims 4: Grunge Revival&nbsp;Kit.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-your-old-saves-work">Your Old Saves Work</h2>



<p>If you happen to still play The Sims 1/2 or just happen to have an old save file, EA says that players will be able to bring their old saves into the newly released versions of the game. Both titles will also support original mods, but EA did make it clear that they haven’t all been tested to guarantee they work.</p>



<p>“It’ll be up to individual Mod creators to ensure Mods work with the new version,” EA said.</p>



<p>Are you going to dive into the first games in the classic franchise? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-is-officially-shutting-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MultiVersus shutting down</a>&nbsp;for good&nbsp;and check out the first set of post-launch&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/civilization-7-dlc-and-roadmap-revealed-by-developers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DLC for Civilization 7.</a>&nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Release Date—Release Time, Platforms, Editions, and Price]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date%E2%80%94release-time-platforms-editions-and-price.1097145/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>2025 is going to be supersized thanks to the presence of a new Monster Hunter game. Capcom is back with Monster Hunter Wilds, and the monster-slaying sequel has a release date, along with information on its platforms, price, and many more mammoth details.</p>



<p>Monster Hunter Wilds is looking to outdo the enormous success of 2018’s Monster Hunter World. The franchise has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-series-hits-100-million-in-cumulative-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sold millions</a> upon millions of copies and has a worldwide fanbase. It might be because it’s Capcom, or possibly because slaying oversized creatures after a minutes-long struggle is exhilarating—and few do it better.</p>



<p>It’s probably safe to say Monster Hunter Wilds is one of 2025’s biggest games, and I wanna dive into the good stuff.</p>



<h2 id="h-monster-hunter-wilds-release-date">Monster Hunter Wilds Release Date</h2>



<figure><figcaption>You’re a bit big. Credit to Capcom</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Monster Hunter Wilds has a February 28 release date.</strong></p>



<p>This means it’s coming into direction competition with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pga-tour-2k25-release-date-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PGA Tour 2K25</a>, but they’re very different games with unique audiences. <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> is one of February 2025’s biggest launches, and its January 28 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date-february-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date</a> can’t come soon enough!</p>



<h2 id="h-monster-hunter-wilds-release-time">Monster Hunter Wilds Release Time</h2>



<p><strong>It’s unlikely Monster Hunter Wilds will release simultaneously for everyone, so expect a worldwide midnight launch on release day.</strong></p>



<p>This means New Zealand gets its hands on Monster Hunter first, with America, and other regions, needing to wait a bit longer. The footage and what we’ve seen suggests any extra wait is worth it. Just be sure to <strong>stay off social media for spoilers</strong> as you never know who’s going to leak what details!</p>



<h2 id="h-monster-hunter-wilds-platforms">Monster Hunter Wilds Platforms</h2>



<p><strong>It’s a full-on current-gen release for Monster Hunter Wilds with PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC launches.</strong></p>



<p>A game with the scale of Monster Hunter Wilds was always going to suggest the PS4 and Xbox One were missing out. It’s sad, given the impact of the two consoles, but they’re quickly becoming outdated and unable to run more modern games with great efficiency. </p>



<p>The Nintendo Switch is also another notable (but expected) omission—but the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2</a> could get a port down the line.</p>



<h2 id="h-monster-hunter-wilds-price-amp-editions">Monster Hunter Wilds Price &amp; Editions</h2>



<p><strong>Monster Hunter Wilds Standard Edition is £69.99 and £64.99, whereas you’re looking at $89.99 and £79.99 for the Deluxe Edition, and $109.99 and £99.99 for the luxury of the Premium Deluxe Edition.</strong></p>



<p>These are the recommended retail prices and digital figures. If you’re buying a physical edition of Monster Hunter Wilds, online and in-store retailers should have offers and various discounts to bring this eye-watering cost done.</p>



<hr>



<p>How much are you looking forward to hacking and slashing away at monsters? Is there any realm where Capcom fails to deliver on the enormous expectations and hype?</p>



<p>If you can’t wait for Monster Hunter Wilds, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-how-to-join-dates-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Open Beta</a> might be something you need to check out and get involved with.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 1 and 2 Return to PC at Last Today via The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sims-1-and-2-return-to-pc-at-last-today-via-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-1-and-2-return-to-pc-at-last-today-via-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle.1097142/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sims-1-and-2-return-to-pc-at-last-today-via-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA and Maxis are celebrating the 25th anniversary of The Sims franchise with a truly excellent surprise. Today, both The Sims 1 and The Sims 2 are available on PC once again via two Legacy Collections and The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA has announced that it's releasing The Sims: Legacy Collection and The Sims 2: Legacy Collection today on PC. The two are available separately as well as combined for $40 in The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Both games include all expansions and <em>almost</em> all stuff packs, as it looks like The Sims 2: Legacy Collection is missing the IKEA Home Stuff pack from 2008. But otherwise, everything's there. In fact, both collections include some bonus content, with The Sims 1 getting something called Throwback Fit Kit and The Sims 2 receiving a Grunge Revival Kit on top of all the other add-ons.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA's re-release of the two older The Sims games marks the first time in over a decade that both gave have been readily available to play. The Sims 1 was only ever released on disc, so for years now unless you were able to track down an old physical copy and somehow make it run on a modern Windows machine, there was just no way to get ahold of it (and that doesn't even include the expansion packs!). The Sims 2 was available more recently in 2014 via an Ultimate Collection on EA's Origin store, but the Ultimate Collection was taken down a while ago. So unless you took advantage of it at the time, The Sims 2 remained unavailable to you unless you could similarly find a physical disc. With these two new collections, all four The Sims games are now easily purchaseable and playable again through digital storefronts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We gave <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2000/02/05/the-sims-6">The Sims 1 a 9.5/10</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2005/10/28/the-sims-2-2">The Sims 2 an 8.5/10</a> waaaaay back in the day when we first reviewed them both. While the series has added numerous new features and ironed out a lot of kinks since then, the originals are still worth checking out for their goofiness, relative simplicity, challenge, and legacy. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Sims: Legacy Collection and The Sims 2: Legacy Collection are both available now on Steam, the Epic Games Store, and through the EA app.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creator of Bloodborne 60fps Patch Says Sony Has Sent Him a DMCA Takedown — but Why Now?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/creator-of-bloodborne-60fps-patch-says-sony-has-sent-him-a-dmca-takedown-but-why-now</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/creator-of-bloodborne-60fps-patch-says-sony-has-sent-him-a-dmca-takedown-%E2%80%94-but-why-now.1097136/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/creator-of-bloodborne-60fps-patch-says-sony-has-sent-him-a-dmca-takedown-but-why-now<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The creator of the high-profile Bloodborne 60fps patch has said he’s received a DMCA takedown from Sony.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lance-mcdonald-hacker-story-pt-god-of-war-bloodborne">Well-known video game tinkerer Lance McDonald</a> announced the news in a <a href="https://x.com/manfightdragon/status/1885347693125566806" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet</a>, saying he received a takedown notification on behalf of Sony Interactive Entertainment “asking that I remove links to the patch I posted on the internet, so I've now done so.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">McDonald then pointed to one of his <a href="https://youtu.be/i0tqppZDYxw?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube videos</a> on the Bloodborne 60fps patch, which he released in 2021, and recounted a meeting with former PlayStation executive Shuhei Yoshida in which he mentioned he made the 60fps mod for Bloodborne.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I met @yosp and said to him ‘I make mods for PlayStation games’ and he said ‘oh!.’ And I said ‘I made the 60fps mod for Bloodborne’ and he laughed so hard.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bloodborne is of course one of the biggest conundrums in the video game industry. The FromSoftware masterpiece launched on PS4 to critical and commercial acclaim, but since then Sony hasn’t touched it. Fans are desperate for an official next-gen patch that would make the game run at 60fps, up from 30fps, but there are also calls for a remaster and a sequel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That leaves it to the likes of McDonald to plug the gap. But more recently, fans managed to get PS4 emulators to deliver something akin to a remaster on PC. The tech experts at <a href="https://youtu.be/-zjzBbdl7hk?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Foundry released a video</a> covering “a breakthrough in PS4 emulation” via ShadPS4, which means Bloodborne is now fully playable start to finish in 60fps. Could this breakthrough have triggered an aggressive response from Sony? IGN has asked Sony for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-hasnt-sony-done-anything-more-with-bloodborne-playstation-legend-shuhei-yoshida-has-a-personal-theory">Yoshida delivered his Bloodborne no-show theory</a> in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/jMsGB2PItes?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>an interview with Kinda Funny Games</u></a>:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Bloodborne has always been the most asked thing,” Yoshida began. “And people wonder why we haven’t really done anything, even an update or a remaster. Should be easy, right? The company is known for doing so many remasters, right, some people get frustrated.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I have only my personal theory to that situation. I left first-party so I don’t know what’s going on, but my theory is, you know because I remember, you know, Miyazaki-san really, really loved Bloodborne, you know, what he created. So I think he is interested, but he’s so successful and he’s so busy, so he doesn’t want, he cannot do himself, but he does not want anyone else to touch it. So that’s my theory. And the PlayStation team respect his wish. So that’s my guess, right? Theory. I am not revealing any secret information, to be clear.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The upshot is Bloodborne remains dormant nearly 10 years after the first game came out. But is there hope? In interviews, Miyazaki often deflects questions about Bloodborne, pointing to the fact FromSoftware does not own the IP. But in February last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fromsoftwares-miyazaki-responds-to-calls-for-bloodborne-remake-on-ps5"><u>Miyazaki at least admitted the game would benefit from a release on more modern hardware</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard for PlayStation 5 Drops to Its Lowest Price Ever at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-playstation-5-amazon-deal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-for-playstation-5-drops-to-its-lowest-price-ever-at-amazon.1097130/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-playstation-5-amazon-deal<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Save $45 off its usual price.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/games-for-25-gamestop-dragon-age-super-mario-call-of-duty">GameStop's $25 sale on select video games</a>, Amazon's joining in on the fun by matching the price of <a href="https://zdcs.link/a0XoEN?object_uuid=7cb6546a-dc83-425b-9556-b210ef114e04&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DCMN43SC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Dragon Age: The Veilguard for PlayStation 5</a>, dropping its price to $24.99. This is 64% off its list price of $69.99, allowing you to pocket a whopping $45. That's an excellent deal to take advantage of, and according to price tracker <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/product/B0DCMN43SC" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">camelcamelcamel</a> it also marks the 2024 game's lowest price yet. No better time than now to scoop it up if you've had your eye on it.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Get 64% off Dragon Age: The Veilguard for PlayStation 5 at Amazon</h2><div catalogid="5c4662f1-651b-4646-b42c-9add9fb85d7a" id="211158"><div id="211158" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Dragon Age: The Veilguard - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're still on the fence about Dragon Age: The Veilguard, it's worth noting that we had very high praise for it in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-review">review</a>. Writer Leana Hafer said, "Enjoyable action combat, a fantastic cast of allies with sweeping story arcs all their own, top-notch cinematics, and moving, nuanced character writing are the wings on which this triumphant dragon soars, pulling out all the stops in a whirlwind tour of Northern Thedas and capping it with a terrific finale that’s built on memorably tough choices and consequences."</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">More Gaming Deals Available Now</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">As mentioned earlier, if you're looking for even more game deals, it's worth checking out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/games-for-25-gamestop-dragon-age-super-mario-call-of-duty">GameStop's sale that features select games down to just $25</a>. Alongside Dragon Age, this includes Super Mario RPG, EA SPORTS College Football 25, Call of Duty: Modern Warfare III and quite a few more. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's also worth having a look at our individual roundups of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-playstation-ps5-deals">best PlayStation deals</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals">best Xbox deals</a>, and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-deals">best Nintendo Switch deals,</a> if you have a preferred platform you'd rather look at to see the best discounts available at the moment. For an overall look at the highlights for each console, check out our roundup of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-game-deals">best video game deals</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 31, 2025 3:30 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scar-Lead Salvation for PC coming west on May 29]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/scar-lead-salvation-for-pc-coming-west-on-may-29</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/scar-lead-salvation-for-pc-coming-west-on-may-29.1097127/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/scar-lead-salvation-for-pc-coming-west-on-may-29<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>No information to share about the PlayStation versions.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Idea Factory International [391 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/idea-factory-international">Idea Factory International</a> will release <a title="Companies > Compile Heart [1,211 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/compile-heart">Compile Heart</a> and <a title="Companies > Neilo [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neilo">Neilo</a>‘s <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/scar-lead-salvation-debut-trailer-gameplay-details-and-screenshots">newly announced</a> science-fiction <a title="Genres > Roguelite [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> <a title="Genres > Third-Person Shooter [1,273 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/tps">third-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Scar-Lead Salvation [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/scar-lead-salvation">Scar-Lead Salvation</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,241 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam on May 29, day and date with its Japanese release, the company announced. <span id="more-941678"></span></p><p>While the game will be launching for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,749 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,646 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> alongside PC in Japan, an Idea Factory International representative told <a title="Companies > Gematsu" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gematsu">Gematsu</a> that currently only the PC version is planned for release in the west, and that it has no information to share on the <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,837 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> versions at the moment.</p><p>The PC version will feature both English and Japanese voice-overs, as well as English, French, Spanish, Japanese, Traditional Chinese, and Simplified Chinese subtitle options. It is currently unclear whether the PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4 versions will feature these same language options.</p><p>If you missed our previous coverage, read more about the game’s story, characters, and gameplay mechanics <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/scar-lead-salvation-debut-trailer-gameplay-details-and-screenshots">here</a>. Visit the newly launched English teaser website <a href="https://ifi.games/scarleadsalvation/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alienware RTX 50-Series Gaming PCs Are Up For Preorder For A Small Fortune]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/alienware-rtx-50-series-gaming-pcs-are-up-for-preorder-for-a-small-fortune/1100-6529159/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alienware-rtx-50-series-gaming-pcs-are-up-for-preorder-for-a-small-fortune.1097124/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/alienware-rtx-50-series-gaming-pcs-are-up-for-preorder-for-a-small-fortune/1100-6529159/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529159">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nvidia's newly released <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/geforce-rtx-50-series-gpus-launched-today-but-its-not-easy-to-grab-one/1100-6528684/" data-ref-id="1100-6528684">GeForce RTX 5090 and 5080 GPUs</a> are difficult to find in stock at the moment. We would expect stocks to fluctuate over the coming weeks as the first wave of these graphics cards slowly make it to store shelves. However, if you're interested in upgrading all of your components and willing to wait a bit longer, you can preorder a <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-12839518%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fcty%2Fpdp%2Fspd%2Falienware-area-51-aat2250-gaming-desktop&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Falienware-rtx-50-series-gaming-pcs-are-up-for-preorder-for-a-small-fortune%2F1100-6529159%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">prebuilt Alienware Area-51 gaming PC</a> equipped with an RTX 5080 through Dell's online store. The Alienware Area-51 5080 PCs start at $4,450 and are expected to arrive on March 25. While that's much more expensive than the 5080's $1,000 MSRP, if you were thinking of getting a new gaming desktop, the Area-51 is equipped with top-notch components.</p><div title="6529159 - Alienware's Area-51 Prebuilt PCs with Nvidia GeForce RTX 5080 GPU" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="3122" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6529159 - Alienware's Area-51 Prebuilt PCs with Nvidia GeForce RTX 5080 GPU" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-100770772-12839518?sid=subid_value&amp;url=https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/cty/pdp/spd/alienware-area-51-aat2250-gaming-desktop" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.dpbolvw.net\/click-100770772-12839518?sid=subid_value&amp;url=https:\/\/www.dell.com\/en-us\/shop\/cty\/pdp\/spd\/alienware-area-51-aat2250-gaming-desktop&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-100770772-12839518?sid=subid_value&amp;url=https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/cty/pdp/spd/alienware-area-51-aat2250-gaming-desktop">Alienware Area-51 Prebuilt PCs with Nvidia GeForce RTX 5080 GPU</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-100770772-12839518?sid=subid_value&amp;url=https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/cty/pdp/spd/alienware-area-51-aat2250-gaming-desktop" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.dpbolvw.net\/click-100770772-12839518?sid=subid_value&amp;url=https:\/\/www.dell.com\/en-us\/shop\/cty\/pdp\/spd\/alienware-area-51-aat2250-gaming-desktop&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-100770772-12839518?sid=subid_value&amp;url=https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/cty/pdp/spd/alienware-area-51-aat2250-gaming-desktop">Starts at $4,450 | Releases March 25</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>Dell says Alienware Area-51 models with the RTX 5090 will also be available soon. For now, there are multiple RTX 5080 hardware configurations available to preorder. Here are the options:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Alienware Area-51 Gaming PC with RTX 5080 GPU, Intel Core Ultra 9 285K, 32GB DDR5 memory, and a 2TB NVMe M.2 PCIe Gen4 SSD -- $4,450</li><li dir="ltr">Alienware Area-51 Gaming PC with RTX 5080 GPU, Intel Core Ultra 9 285K, 64GB DDR5 memory, and a 4TB NVMe M.2 PCIe Gen4 SSD -- $5,050</li></ul></div>                      </div><p dir="ltr">Both models feature Alienware's Area-51 ATX motherboard and the Area-51 PC case, which includes a tempered glass panel door, built-in cable management, and a dedicated daughterboard for easily plugging in lights and system fans. It also has three M.2 expansion slots if you want to add more SSD storage.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition to those internal hardware specs, both PCs run Windows 11 and come with a mouse and keyboard.</p><hr><h2 dir="ltr">Where to Find Nvidia GeForce RTX 5090 and 5080 GPUs</h2><p dir="ltr">While the Alienware Area-51 gaming PCs are a solid way to ensure you get an RTX 5080 within the next few months, they're quite a bit more expensive than buying the new Nvidia GPUs by themselves. If you're willing to try your luck, you can wait for the GPUs to come back in stock which would save you quite a bit compared to buying an entire pre-built PC, and--assuming you snag one in time before they sell out again--potentially get you the new GPU even sooner.</p><p dir="ltr">You'll find listings for the RTX 5080 and 5090 listings at multiple retailers in the links below. They're still sold out at the time of writing, but keep checking to see if they're back in stock. The RTX 5070 isn't available to buy yet, but the "budget" 50-Series GPU is expected to release in February.</p><h3 dir="ltr">Nvidia RTX 50-Series Restock Tracker</h3><ul><li><a href="https://howl.link/mtmjt8revfrlh?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17382497956399?u1=subid_value" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Check stock at Best Buy</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DVCH9WJH,B0DQSLHSP2,B0DQSMMCSH,B0DTJFSSZG,B0DTYCPM5Y,B0DVCF7XDF,B0DTJF8YT4,B0DTY2P2ZK,B0DTJDR3V9,B0DTJFZ4YS,B0DVCGBPL9&amp;tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Check stock at Amazon</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgo.skimresources.com%3Fid%3D225336X1707200%26xs%3D1%26xcust%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fpromotions.newegg.com%2Fnvidia%2F25-0017%2Findex.html%3Fcm_sp%3DHomepage-Top2021-_-top-_-nvidia%252F25-0017-_-%252F%252Fpromotions.newegg.com%252Fnvidia%252F25-0017%252F1150x320.jpg%26icid%3D781305&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Falienware-rtx-50-series-gaming-pcs-are-up-for-preorder-for-a-small-fortune%2F1100-6529159%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Check stock at Newegg</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-15324736%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.antonline.com%2Fnvidia%2Fgeforce-rtx50&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Falienware-rtx-50-series-gaming-pcs-are-up-for-preorder-for-a-small-fortune%2F1100-6529159%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Check stock at Antonline</a></li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-mario-world-lego-set-is-discounted-at-amazon-but-probably-not-for-long/1100-6525283/">Super Mario World Lego Set Is Discounted At Amazon, But Probably Not For Long</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-festival-riffmaster-wireless-guitar-controller-gets-rare-discount/1100-6528970/">Fortnite Festival Riffmaster Wireless Guitar Controller Gets Rare Discount</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-25-on-donkey-kong-country-returns-hd-for-nintendo-switch/1100-6524388/">Save 25% On Donkey Kong Country Returns HD For Nintendo Switch</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/last-chance-to-grab-3-movies-on-4k-blu-ray-for-only-33-at-amazon/1100-6528683/">Last Chance To Grab 3 Movies On 4K Blu-Ray For Only $33 At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-ps5-reprint-restocked-at-amazon/1100-6528630/">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Physical Edition Gets PS5 Reprint - Snag It While You Can</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-2500-piece-legend-of-zelda-lego-set-is-now-available-at-amazon/1100-6523747/">The 2,500-Piece Legend Of Zelda Lego Set Is Now Available At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-lego-sets-are-available-now-check-out-all-six-in-the-launch-lineup/1100-6528603/">Mario Kart Lego Sets Are Available Now - Check Out All Six In The Launch Lineup</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-lego-sets-launch-at-major-retailers-including-amazon-and-walmart/1100-6528629/">Fortnite Lego Sets Launch At Major Retailers, Including Amazon And Walmart</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529091&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-essential-free-games-for-february-2025\/1100-6529091\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529101&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-moving-away-from-monthly-ps4-games\/1100-6529101\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529086&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-lunar-new-year-event-returns-this-time-with-an-even-bigger-xp-buff\/1100-6529086\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529076&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/one-of-wow-most-famous-pieces-of-cut-content-is-playable-today\/1100-6529076\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529150&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-division-2s-next-dlc-will-bring-the-series-to-brooklyn-later-this-year\/1100-6529150\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529148&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps5s-classic-anniversary-themes-are-leaving-but-wont-be-gone-forever\/1100-6529148\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529081&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-is-now-live-will-test-cross-play-and-split-screen-co-op\/1100-6529081\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529156&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/forza-horizon-5-is-the-next-xbox-game-to-speed-onto-playstation-5\/1100-6529156\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528799&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-limited-edition-4k-steelbook-preorders-discounted-at-amazon\/1100-6528799\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529088&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/despite-xboxs-struggles-in-hardware-microsoft-was-reportedly-the-top-video-game-publisher-in-december\/1100-6529088\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529098&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-loses-legal-battle-with-an-unexpected-super-mario\/1100-6529098\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529100&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-is-offering-some-sweet-treats-if-you-play-its-pc-games-with-a-psn-account\/1100-6529100\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529157&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/your-landlord-can-force-mandatory-isp-service-on-you-fccs-new-chair-says\/1100-6529157\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528994&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-open-beta-test-set-for-february\/1100-6528994\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529053&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-massive-4k-blu-ray-collection-compiling-all-six-lord-of-the-rings-and-hobbit-films-launching-in-march\/1100-6529053\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529105&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/after-dragon-age-the-veilguard-comes-up-short-bioware-undergoes-changes\/1100-6529105\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529135&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-will-get-several-substantial-updates-in-2025\/1100-6529135\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529137&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battletech-anniversary-edition-gets-new-expansion-and-miniatures-packs\/1100-6529137\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Killing Floor 3 Launches In March, Closed Beta Coming In February]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/killing-floor-3-launches-in-march-closed-beta-coming-in-february/1100-6529171/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/killing-floor-3-launches-in-march-closed-beta-coming-in-february.1097121/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/killing-floor-3-launches-in-march-closed-beta-coming-in-february/1100-6529171/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529171">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Tripwire Interactive has announced that Killing Floor 3 will launch on March 25 for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. There will also be a closed beta test for the game that runs from February 20-24.</p><p>Those who are interested in the closed beta will need to sign up via the Killing Floor 3's <a href="https://killingfloor3.com/#signup" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">official website</a>. Killing Floor 3 takes place in 2091, 70 years after the events of Killing Floor 2. The mega-corporation Horzine has created Zeds, a race of subservient and bioengineered zombies. A rebel group called Nightfall must fight back against the Zeds in order to save humanity.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1191626822" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465650,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Killing%20Floor%203%20-%20Closed%20Beta%20Announcement%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:30,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/killing-floor-3-closed-beta-announcement-trailer\/2300-6465650\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465650\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465650\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465650\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465650&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4436667-55.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/OMIDw9RV.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1738334640,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="OMIDw9RV" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Killing Floor 3 - Closed Beta Announcement Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p><span>Tripwire Interactive also revealed a revamped version of the </span><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/killing-floor-3-siren-enemy-reveal-trailer/2300-6465651/" data-ref-id="2300-6465651">Siren</a><span> enemy in a new trailer. This sound-based monstrosity uses sonic disruption technology to attack and defend itself.</span></p><p>Killing Floor 3 can be played solo or with up to five other people, and the game offers <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/killing-floor-3-release-date-confirmed-for-march-2025/1100-6528441/" data-ref-id="1100-6528441">cross-play across all platforms</a>.</p><p>There will be several editions of Killing Floor 3 for purchase. The $40 standard edition in North America includes two different preorder bonuses depending on the retailer: the limited timed-exclusive Clamefield Patrol Specialist skins pack or the Flatline Tactical Bundle. Outside of North America, the Day 1 Edition includes both the skins pack and the tactical bundle.</p><p>As for the digital storefronts, the Deluxe Edition costs $60 and includes the Shadow Agent Specialist and Weapon Skin Sets, as well as the Launch Nightfall Supply Pass and 1000 credits. The $80 Elite Nightfall Edition contains everything from the Deluxe Edition and adds on the Year 1 Premium Nightfall Supply Pass Access (holds four passes), and 3000 credits.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation takes aim at Bloodborne 60fps mod released in 2021]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-takes-aim-at-bloodborne-60fps-mod-released-in-2021</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-takes-aim-at-bloodborne-60fps-mod-released-in-2021.1097115/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-takes-aim-at-bloodborne-60fps-mod-released-in-2021<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Creator Lance McDonald says he has agreed to comply.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Bloodborne-Lady-Maria.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
A high-profile mod that allows Bloodborne to run at 60fps has been hit by a legal takedown notification from PlayStation, its creator has said. 
</p>
<p>
Noted modder Lance McDonald revealed the legal request from Sony Interactive Entertainment today via a post on social media. 
</p>
<p>
The takedown specifically targets McDonald's famous Bloodborne patch that ups the game's frame-rate, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bloodborne-modder-releases-60fps-patch">released back in early 2021</a>. It's unclear why PlayStation has finally decided to take action now, four years later.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Bloodborne 60fps Hack Tested! 1080p, 900p, 720p - Can We Lock to 60fps?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6hDIvDPRcPA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Bloodborne 60fps Hack Tested! 1080p, 900p, 720p - Can We Lock to 60fps?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6hDIvDPRcPA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6hDIvDPRcPA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Digital Foundry dissects the Bloodborne 60fps hack and discusses it - and the game engine - in depth with Lance McDonald.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6hDIvDPRcPA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"On 21st February 2021, I created and released a patch for Bloodborne which makes the game run at 60fps," McDonald wrote this afternoon.</p>
<p>"Today I received a DMCA takedown notification on behalf of Sony Interactive Entertainment asking that I remove links to the patch I posted on the internet, so I've now done so."
</p>
<p>Eurogamer has contacted PlayStation for comment.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">On February 21st, 2021, I created and released a patch for Bloodborne which makes the game run at 60fps. Today I received a DMCA takedown notification on behalf of Sony Interactive Entertainment asking that I remove links to the patch I posted on the internet, so I've now done so</p>— Lance McDonald (@manfightdragon) <a href="https://twitter.com/manfightdragon/status/1885347693125566806?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
McDonald first announced <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/modder-plans-to-release-a-bloodborne-60fps-patch-but-will-give-sony-a-chance-to-go-first-on-ps5">plans to upgrade Bloodborne's frame-rate</a> by, essentially, hacking the game back in 2020. Initially, however, McDonald held off as hoped Sony would update FromSoftware's beloved Soulslike itself. 
</p>
<p>
However, Sony has never issued a 60fps patch for Bloodborne, or shown any inclination of wanting to do so. Infamously, there's been no word of a PS5 version of the game, either.
</p>
<p>
"There's a real opportunity here for a genuinely crowd-pleasing piece of back-compat magic from Sony," Digital Foundry's John Linneman wrote in a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2020-bloodborne-60fps-hack-tested-the-complete-story">deep-dive into how the Bloodborne 60fps patch worked</a> with McDonald himself. "The question is whether the platform holder has any appetite at all to revisit the game."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony DMCAs Unofficial Bloodborne 60FPS Patch]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bloodborne-60fps-patch-dmca</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-dmcas-unofficial-bloodborne-60fps-patch.1097094/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bloodborne-60fps-patch-dmca<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony has issued a DMCA takedown against a fan-made patch that allowed 2015 action RPG&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>to run at 60FPS, sparking fresh speculation that a remaster of the game could be in the works.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/manfightdragon.bsky.social/post/3lh2cipa4rk2v" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">modder Lance McDonald</a>, who's also one of the most prominent members of the&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>community, Sony asked him to "remove links to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bloodborne-60fps-patch-dropping-this-month" rel="nofollow">the patch</a> [he] posted on the internet" via DMCA notice, which means it's no longer available for download.</p>

<p>In the replies, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/powerful.crabf.art/post/3lh2eegkh4c2x" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">users</a> are <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/turbohotdog.bsky.social/post/3lh2eg7nc3s2e" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">speculating</a> that Sony's sudden flurry of activity aimed at the patch could mean that the company is working on its own version of&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>that runs at 60FPS.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bloodborne-60fps-patch-dmca-old-hunters.jpg?itok=Q6hcoT7F 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bloodborne-60fps-patch-dmca-old-hunters.jpg?itok=n1bloLO- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Sony has DMCA'd a 60FPS&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>patch, but does that mean anything?</figcaption></figure><p>There is precedent for this standpoint. Back in 2022, Konami <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-leak-dmcad-by-konami" rel="nofollow">issued a DMCA notice</a> against a leak for a then-upcoming&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill&nbsp;</em>game, and that game subsequently turned out to be&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill: The Short Message</em>, so that DMCA was issued in order for Konami to get ahead of the leaks.</p>

<p>Of course, the obvious (and unfortunate) fallacy in the argument is that companies don't always issue DMCA takedowns because they're planning on creating something similar to what's been taken down.</p>

<p>Studios like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/take-2-dmcas-gta-mods-save-file" rel="nofollow">Take-Two</a> are extremely <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/take-two-issues-another-wave-of-dmcas-for-gta-mods" rel="nofollow">au fait</a> with DMCA takedown notices, and often, those takedowns are issued simply because the company is protective of its IP and doesn't want anyone else coming within sniffing distance of making money from that IP.</p>

<p>It's entirely possible that Sony has only just become aware of the&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>60FPS patch and that it has no intention of doing anything with the IP; it just doesn't want anyone else doing anything with it either.</p>




<p>It's a shame if the DMCA is purely for IP protection reasons, because&nbsp;a&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>remaster is frequently requested by fans thanks to the game's popularity (as well as its relatively shoddy performance in its current state).</p>

<p>Sony <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/playstation-state-of-play-february-2023-here-are-all-news-announcements" rel="nofollow">has been known</a> to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/playstation-state-of-play-january-2024-recap-heck-out-all-news-trailers-and-reveals" rel="nofollow">hold State of Play presentations</a> around this time of year, though, so with all that said, it is possible we could be about to learn that a&nbsp;<em>Bloodborne&nbsp;</em>remaster is indeed in the works.</p>

<p>For now, you'll have to content yourself with <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/bloodborne/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">picking up the original on PS4</a>. It's also playable on PS5 via backwards compatibility, of course.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Is Making A Life-Sized Gardevoir Plush, May God Have Mercy On Us All]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-life-sized-gardevoir-plush-import-center-buy-1851752663</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-is-making-a-life-sized-gardevoir-plush-may-god-have-mercy-on-us-all.1097085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/pokemon-life-sized-gardevoir-plush-import-center-buy-1851752663<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="1a9d05203ae177d23b9d2d59c5700c66" data-recommend-id="image://1a9d05203ae177d23b9d2d59c5700c66" data-format="jpg" data-width="1999" data-height="1124" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A person is shown standing next to the Gardevoir plush and patting it on the head." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A person is shown standing next to the Gardevoir plush and patting it on the head." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Pokémon Company</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1a9d05203ae177d23b9d2d59c5700c66" data-recommend-id="image://1a9d05203ae177d23b9d2d59c5700c66" data-format="jpg" data-width="1999" data-height="1124" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A person is shown standing next to the Gardevoir plush and patting it on the head." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Look, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-dlc-van-gogh-go-remote-raids-1851128900&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-dlc-van-gogh-go-remote-raids-1851128900">The Pokémon Company is a giant company that can do whatever it wants</a></span>. Still, however, one must ask: Is releasing a life-sized posable plush of Gardevoir, the psychic/fairy-type Pokémon who you should never Google without SafeSearch on, perhaps a callous use of one’s power? Is it an example of being so preoccupied with whether or not you could that you didn’t stop to think if you should? Well, we’re past pontificating because they’re doing it, and the internet is preparing for the inevitable horrors that will be inflicted upon these inanimate objects.</p><p>If you’ve somehow never seen a Gardevoir before, the Pokémon is a humanoid, alien-like creature with notably feminine features from a green <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/fuck-ass-bob&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/fuck-ass-bob" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fuck ass bob</a></span> to a dress that flows from its waist. Since its debut in <em>Pokémon Ruby </em>and <em>Sapphire </em>back in 2002, the internet has done what the internet does and created untoward fan art and memes about it. That history feels like it’s reaching its natural endpoint as The Pokémon Company has announced it’s creating a life-sized plush of the character, and the internet is living in fear of what might happen to these plushes when they’re out in the wild.</p><p>The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.pokemoncenter-online.com/?p_cd=4521329424057&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.pokemoncenter-online.com/?p_cd=4521329424057" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Japanese Pokémon Center</a></span> store sells the Gardevoir plushes for 49,500 yen, roughly equivalent to $319 USD. But no price is too much for the kind of person who wants this. There don’t appear to be plans to release the Gardevoir plush in other territories at the moment, so if you’re going to import it, please do not buy it secondhand. But if you just want to see what it looks like, feel free to click through the slides.</p><p>In other <em>Pokémon </em>news, Pokémon Day is coming up. The February 27 “holiday” commemorates the anniversary of the original <em>Red </em>and <em>Green </em>versions launching in Japan back in 1996, and is usually accompanied by a stream about the series’ upcoming projects. It’s likely we’ll see <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-predictions-mega-evolution-kalos-1851316456&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-predictions-mega-evolution-kalos-1851316456"><em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em></a></span><em> </em>there, as the game is set to launch on the Switch later this year.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>