<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 15:09:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World's Cow Is A Bigger Hit Than Nintendo Imagined, May Not Be A Cannibal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-cow-is-a-bigger-hit-than-nintendo-imagined-may-not-be-a-cannibal/1100-6532020/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-worlds-cow-is-a-bigger-hit-than-nintendo-imagined-may-not-be-a-cannibal.1205700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-cow-is-a-bigger-hit-than-nintendo-imagined-may-not-be-a-cannibal/1100-6532020/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532020">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Besides the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-defends-mario-kart-worlds-80-price-tag/1100-6530643/" data-ref-id="1100-6530643">$80 price point</a>, one of the biggest talking points about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/" data-ref-id="1100-6528874">Mario Kart World</a> for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Switch 2</a> has been the Cow. Producer Kosuke Yabuki has now reacted to the excitement about the Cow, and re-confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-cow-can-eat-burgers-and-steak/1100-6530642/" data-ref-id="1100-6530642">the Cow does in fact eat burgers</a>, but they may not be real-beef burgers.</p><p>"The decision to include Cow was something that we considered in terms of if we added that, I think people would be really happy about it. And so we did," <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/does-cow-eat-beef-we-asked-the-mario-kart-world-producer" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yabuki told IGN</a>. "But honestly, the reaction to that by the public was much bigger than we possibly could have anticipated. So that was a wonderful surprise."</p><p>As discussed previously, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-a-silly-sketch-led-to-cow-becoming-a-pivotal-character-in-mario-kart-world/1100-6531712/" data-ref-id="1100-6531712">a "silly sketch" led to the creation of the Cow</a>, who has become one of the game's most popular characters in the lead up to release.</p><p>Yabuki went on to say that the Cow "really opened the floodgates" for Nintendo because it inspired the developers to wonder, "'Well, maybe we should just add who we can.'" Thinking this way, the developers also chose to add the Penguin and Pokey.</p><p>"Because all of these characters came in such a rush as the designers were getting kind of carried away, it's actually a little hard for me to remember which specific character would've come immediately next in the sequence after Cow," Yabuki said. "Because honestly, I have this memory of approving the concept for Cow, and then maybe the next day I had 10 proposals for other characters on my desk."</p><p>Given that Mario Kart World has a new mechanic that lets players stop at roadside restaurants and grab a bite to eat, many have been wondering if the Cow can stop for a burger or steak. The creature can, but that doesn't mean it's necessarily eating its own kind. Asked if the Cow specifically consumers beef or veggie burgers, Kabuki said, "Sorry that's top secret. I can't say."</p><p>Mario Kart Word releases on June 5 as a<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-nintendo-switch-2-launch-game/2900-6401/" data-ref-id="2900-6401"> launch title</a> for the Switch 2. You can save on the game by purchasing the $500 Switch 2 bundle that comes with Mario Kart World <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">if you can find one in stock.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Software Promises Enhanced Boss Fights, Duo Expeditions For Elden Ring Nightreign]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/06/03/from-software-promises-enhanced-boss-fights-duo-expeditions-for-elden-ring-nightreign</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/from-software-promises-enhanced-boss-fights-duo-expeditions-for-elden-ring-nightreign.1205697/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/06/03/from-software-promises-enhanced-boss-fights-duo-expeditions-for-elden-ring-nightreign<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>From Software’s latest game, the multiplayer co-op <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>, launched last week, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/30/elden-ring-nightreign-hits-2-million-players-in-just-one-day">welcoming 2 million players in less than 24 hours</a>. Today, publisher Bandai Namco revealed the player count has leaped to 3.5 million alongside news that duo expeditions are coming to the game in the future.</p><p>The team also says that in addition to DLC releasing later this year, new things will be added to Nighreign, like enhanced boss fights against Nightlords starting this month.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pRhcXR-1SeY"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pRhcXR-1SeY" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>“On the dawn of the fifth day, 3.5 million Nightfarers took up arms against the Night in Elden Ring Nightreign. We are ever grateful for your passion,” a <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1929780349380223096">post</a> from the Elden Ring X account reads. “But the night is far from over. In addition to the DLC releasing later this year, new additions will be gradually implemented, including enhanced fights against existing Nightlords starting this month, as well as Duo Expeditions at a later date. Thank you for your support.”</p><p>Confirming that duo expeditions are coming to Nightreign is exciting, especially as matchmaking for trios is tough, and playing solo is even tougher. <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/06/02/new-elden-ring-nightreign-patch-makes-solo-play-easier-alongside-balance-changes-and-bug">From Software released a patch yesterday</a> that should make the latter easier, though.</p><p>For more, read <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/elden-ring-nightreign/encapsulating-efficiency"><em>Game Informer’s</em> Elden Ring Nightreign review</a>, and then check out <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/tips-tricks/2025/05/29/elden-ring-nightreign-beginner-tips-and-tricks"><em>Game Informer’s</em> Elden Ring Nightreign beginner tips and tricks</a>. After that, read about how <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/23/elden-ring-live-action-movie-in-the-works-with-ex-machina-annihilation-director-alex">a live-action Elden Ring movie</a> in development is <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/29/alex-garlands-elden-ring-film-will-reportedly-star-heartstoppers-kit-connor">circling <em>Heartstopper’s</em> Kit Connor as its lead</a>.</p><hr><p><em>Do you want duo expeditions? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 4's northern setting revealed in new Unreal livestream]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4s-northern-setting-revealed-in-new-unreal-livestream</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-4s-northern-setting-revealed-in-new-unreal-livestream.1205694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4s-northern-setting-revealed-in-new-unreal-livestream<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt Red</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a> will be set in the far northern region of Kovir, not yet seen in the previous games.</p>
<p>Earlier today, we saw a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-unreal-tech-demo-was-running-on-a-standard-ps5-at-60fps-with-ray-tracing">first in-game look at CD Projekt Red's forthcoming Ciri-starring sequel</a> at the State of Unreal livestream. It showed off how the studio is using Unreal's technology, but also hinted at the game's location.</p>
<p>The end of the trailer shows a first look at Lan Exeter, the winter capital of the Kovir region. In a press release, the studio has confirmed the sequel will take place in Kovir.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="State of Unreal 2025 Official 4K Livestream I Unreal Fest Orlando" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AjikvaR0i34?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>State of Unreal 2025 Official 4K Livestream I Unreal Fest Orlando</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AjikvaR0i34?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AjikvaR0i34?autoplay=1" title="State of Unreal 2025 Official 4K Livestream I Unreal Fest Orlando">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>State of Unreal 2025 Official 4K Livestream I Unreal Fest Orlando<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AjikvaR0i34" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The kingdom of Kovir and Poviss is to the far north of the world, beyond the Dragon Mountains. It's fitting, then, that as Ciri peers out to the city beyond snow-capped mountains, a dragon flies overhead.</p>
<p>Earlier, the tech demo showed the city of Valdrest, which appears to be a new creation by the studio.</p>
<p>If Kovir sounds familiar, it's referenced in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">The Witcher 3</a> by Triss as she's asked to be court advisor to King Tancred in Kovir. Geralt is less keen to settle down in the region, though.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>That's Lan Exeter in the distance. | <span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt Red</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>But perhaps he does ahead of The Witcher 4? Fans have speculated he may be the leader of the new Lynx Witcher school, from which Ciri learns her skills. And when that lynx medallion was first revealed it was in the snow, perhaps foreshadowing the cold northern region in which the game will take place.</p>
<p>The trailer also revealed Ciri's horse Kelpie, just like in the books.</p>
<p>CD Projekt Red stated the game was running on a base PS5 at 60fps with ray tracing turned on. Here's a look at some screenshots:</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Thanks for tuning in to The Witcher 4 — Unreal Engine 5 tech demo and joining us during the State of Unreal 2025! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UnrealFest?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#UnrealFest</a></p><p>The full presentation will be uploaded and shared with everyone later today, but in the meantime, here's four screenshots straight from the demo to tide… <a href="https://t.co/LL7bJH1biV">pic.twitter.com/LL7bJH1biV</a></p></div>— The Witcher (@thewitcher) <a href="https://twitter.com/thewitcher/status/1929897644127641662?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 3, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>In the company's financial call in March, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-wont-be-out-until-after-2026-so-could-it-be-a-next-generation-game">CD Projekt Red stated The Witcher 4 won't be out until after 2026</a>, suggesting it could even be a next-generation game.</p>
<p>The Witcher 3 recently celebrated its 10th anniversary: here's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-worked-in-the-witcher-3-and-what-didnt-looking-back-on-a-landmark-rpg-with-cd-projekt-red">a look back at the landmark RPG</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pioner Demo Confirmed for Steam Next Fest]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/pioner-demo-confirmed-for-steam-next-fest/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pioner-demo-confirmed-for-steam-next-fest.1205691/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/pioner-demo-confirmed-for-steam-next-fest/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Serbian developer GFA Games announced that the upcoming massively multiplayer online first-person shooter game Pioner will be playable next week from June 9 to 16 as part of the upcoming Steam Next Fest.</p>
<p>The demo will offer access to the full prologue of the game, the central player hub, the Wanderer Pass and five unique quests. Players will also be able to take part in multiplayer activities, including a cooperative raid.</p>
<p>We've been covering Pioner for several years now and also <a href="https://wccftech.com/pioner-qa-2-devs-reveal-pve-pvp-mechanics-of-this-stalker-like-mmofps-confirm-beta-in-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interviewed</a> the developers twice. At long last, the game will be released later this year on PC, with consoles to follow at a later date. Even if you can't play next week, GFA Games confirmed that an Open Beta will take place later this Summer.</p>
<p><iframe title="PIONER - Steam Next Fest Open Demo" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qr2yutiQBwE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Here's an overview of Pioner from the latest official fact sheet:</p>
<p>Pioner is a post-apocalyptic MMO shooter set on the mysterious Soviet-era island of Tartarus, offering a vast open world spanning over 50 square kilometers. Blending intense PvE and PvP action with player-driven storytelling, the game features faction missions, hidden dungeons, and dynamic environments. Realism takes center stage, replacing traditional health bars and levels with immersive mechanics. High-risk zones like the "Shadowlands" push PvP to the extreme, allowing for chaotic, high-reward battles where alliances are key — or optional.</p>
<p>Key Features:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Immersive,</strong> <strong>Grim</strong> <strong>Open</strong> <strong>World</strong> – Explore an alternate reality inspired by the Soviet era, filled with atmospheric landscapes, unique architecture, and captivating lore.</li>
<li><strong>Rich</strong>, <strong>Sci</strong>-<strong>Fi</strong>-<strong>Influenced</strong> <strong>Lore</strong> – Delve into a narrative deeply influenced by classic science fiction, with complex characters, powerful artifacts, and mysterious anomalies shaping the story.</li>
<li><strong>Story</strong> <strong>Campaign</strong> – Embark on a story-driven campaign, providing rich lore and engaging quests.</li>
<li><strong>A</strong> <strong>Unique</strong> <strong>Progression</strong> <strong>System</strong> – Grow your influence by completing quests, defeating monsters, and exploring. A more significant influence makes merchants more inclined to sell you better items, allow higher quality materials to drop, and even allow you to improve your non-combat abilities.</li>
<li><strong>Diverse</strong> <strong>Game</strong> <strong>Activities</strong> – Engage in a range of activities, including PvE missions, PvP arenas, events, story-driven locations, and engaging mini-games like fishing and casino games.<br>
Shadowlands Extraction Shooter Mode – Enter the intense "Shadowlands" mode, an extraction shooter experience within PIONER, for high-stakes survival and treasure hunting.</li>
<li><strong>Factions</strong> <strong>with</strong> <strong>Unique</strong> <strong>Personalities</strong> – Align with charismatic factions, each offering distinct characters, viewpoints, and special rewards.</li>
<li><strong>Extensive</strong> <strong>Weapon</strong> <strong>Customization</strong> – Customize militarized weapons with a wide array of unique modules and designs never seen before in MMO games.</li>
<li><strong>Realistic</strong> <strong>Survival</strong> <strong>Mechanics</strong> – Maintain your character’s strength by managing hunger, rest, and resources, adding a strategic layer to survival.</li>
<li><strong>In</strong>-<strong>Depth</strong> <strong>Crafting</strong> <strong>System</strong> – Utilize artifacts, anomaly energy, and scavenged materials to craft powerful weapons and equipment at workbenches.</li>
<li><strong>Clan</strong>-<strong>Based</strong> <strong>Social</strong> <strong>Gameplay</strong> – Form clans, communicate through emotes and chat, and compete on clan leaderboards, building strong community dynamics.</li>
<li><strong>Raids</strong> <strong>and</strong> <strong>Directed</strong> <strong>Missions</strong> – Experience six distinct raids, blending open-world and structured missions that challenge teamwork and strategy.</li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic is making it easier to create MetaHumans]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/678403/epic-games-metahumans-unreal-engine</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-is-making-it-easier-to-create-metahumans.1205688/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/678403/epic-games-metahumans-unreal-engine<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Epic Games’ hyperrealistic MetaHuman characters are seriously impressive, and now the company is making it easier for developers to incorporate them into their projects. At its State of Unreal show on Tuesday, Epic announced that the MetaHuman Creator is now embedded within Unreal Engine as part of Unreal Engine 5.6.</p><p>The company is also bringing its face-authoring tools for MetaHumans’ faces to bodies, meaning developers will be able to create faces and bodies with fine-tuned parameters for their games or applications. Developers will be able to sell their MetaHumans on Epic’s Fab marketplace for digital assets, too, so they can be used in other games or projects.</p><p>Onstage, Epic showed how the MetaHuman tools could be used to animate a character in real time — and using just a consumer webcam to capture the actor’s facial movements. It was pretty cool.</p><p>Epic also has new licensing options that allow MetaHumans to be used with other game development engines or creative software. That means that creators will be able to use MetaHumans in rival development platforms like Unity and Godot and in creative software such as Maya, Houdini, and Blender.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic showed off Unreal Engine 5 with an impressive Witcher 4 tech demo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/678463/unreal-engine-5-witcher-4-tech-demo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-showed-off-unreal-engine-5-with-an-impressive-witcher-4-tech-demo.1205682/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/678463/unreal-engine-5-witcher-4-tech-demo<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-webster">Andrew Webster</a> <span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>An ongoing tradition at Epic’s big keynotes is a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/20/18273832/epic-unreal-engine-demo-troll-rebirth-ray-tracing-gdc-2019">gorgeous</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/13/21256079/epic-unreal-engine-5-playstation-5-demo-next-gen-graphics-release-date">tech demo </a>that shows off what its game engine is capable of. For this year’s State of Unreal, the company turned to <em>The Witcher</em> and <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> developer CD Projekt Red. This new demo a beautiful glimpse at its fantasy world, filled with blood, fire, and monsters — and more importantly, a new horse.</p><p>The demo was built using Unreal Engine 5.6, and shows new protagonist Ciri exploring some forested lands and a marketplace known as Valdrest. Epic says the demo is designed in part to show off how the latest iteration can handle both bustling scenes and foliage in an open-world setting. It also shows how much horse technology has improved since <em>The Witcher 3</em>. Epic says that the demo is running on a base model PS5 at 60 frames per second, with raytracing enabled, and the presentation included a live demonstration, with the developers playing the game on stage. You can check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AjikvaR0i34">the full keynote here</a>, just scroll back to the beginning to watch the <em>Witcher 4</em> segment.</p><p>Here’s a look at the intro:</p><p>Some horseback gameplay:</p><p>And a handful of images from the demo:</p><div><p>We’ve known that CDPR had switched to UE5 for its next <em>Witcher</em> game <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/3/21/22989313/cd-projekt-red-new-witcher-game-unreal-engine-5-announcement">as far back as 2022</a>, when it announced a partnership with Epic, likely as a result of the technical issues <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/25/22199768/cdprojekt-cyberpunk-2077-lawsuit-launch">that plagued <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>’s launch</a>. Last year <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24320092/the-witcher-4-trailer-game-awards-2024">the developer officially revealed <em>The Witcher 4</em></a> — with Ciri replacing Geralt in the lead — with a cinematic trailer. There’s no word yet on when the game will be launching.</p></div><p>The 5.6 version of Unreal Engine, meanwhile, is available to developers starting today.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World's Open World Isn't What You Think It Is]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-open-world-isnt-what-you-think-it-is</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-worlds-open-world-isnt-what-you-think-it-is.1205670/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-open-world-isnt-what-you-think-it-is<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">I may only have played three hours of it, but I’m already starting to get the feeling that Mario Kart World should really be called Mario Kart Knockout Tour. The new last-one-standing race mode, really is the star of the show, adding yet another layer of tension and mayhem to the already chaotic kart racer, and such a new addition deserves to have its name up in lights. And so I find it a curious decision that Nintendo has settled on the Switch 2 launch game’s open world as the main draw. I get it on an optics level – a Mario Kart unbound from the confines of pre-determined tracks has been long desired by fans – but after getting my hands on its free roam offering recently, it sadly left me feeling underwhelmed. Let me explain why.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When thinking of an open-world racing game, it's by no means unfair to make comparisons with Forza Horizon. Developer Playground Games has mastered this specific subgenre, even earning itself an IGN Game of the Year award with its most recent effort. Each game in the series features a delicately sculpted open world that packs in challenge, wonder, and, most importantly, fun. I’d be lying if I said I found much of any of those qualities in the roughly half an hour I spent speeding around Mario Kart World’s sizeable map. It’s largely empty, lacks atmosphere, and feels bizarrely devoid of activities to get stuck into.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Much of my time in free roam consisted of dashing along expanses of flat grassland, desert, or lightly choppy seas, looking for something to do. There are some challenges to get your teeth stuck into, but I found them largely repetitive and little more than trivial distractions. They mainly consist of P Switch challenges which, when activated, create short time trials to complete. I found these fun at first, but quickly realised they’re mostly rinse and repeat efforts involving collecting a certain amount of coins or whizzing through checkpoints within a time limit. And when these rarely take more than 10 or 15 seconds to finish, they soon lose all novelty. It’s not a promising sign to walk away from a demo feeling as if you’ve already exhausted the amount of entertainment you can get from a game’s side activities. And while I do hope that a more in-depth scouring of the world reveals more hidden fun, there’s another factor that has me concerned about how it all plays out. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You do get rewarded with a shiny new sticker to place on your chosen kart when completing these P Switch challenges, but this is pretty much as far as unlockables go. It feels weird that progression is still largely locked behind the series’ long-term tradition of racing in Grand Prixs, as this open world seems the perfect opportunity to hide new characters and karts in secret corners. New outfits can be found by driving through one of Yoshi’s many restaurants on the island, but they’re just as, if not more accessible, in race scenarios.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>That sense of wonder you so often feel when discovering something off the beaten track just doesn’t seem to exist here.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Barn finds – explorative missions in Forza Horizon that involve hunting down a hidden vehicle within a section of the map like a piece of buried treasure – are some of my favourite things to do in Playground’s series. If there really isn’t anything similar in the final game (and, unfortunately, no signs at my preview event suggest there is), then it feels like a missed opportunity, especially when 3D Mario platformers are so packed with secrets. That sense of wonder you so often feel when discovering something off the beaten track just doesn’t seem to exist here; instead, the closest I ever got in this demo was stumbling across a big green warp pipe that did nothing more than send me 20 metres down the road. Why don’t these lead to hidden areas with challenges of their own to complete?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s this apparent lack of any sort of progression or meaningful activities that has me wondering how little time I’ll actually spend in this open world. Yes, there are Peach Medallions to collect, which can prove a fun challenge to reach – you’ll need to demonstrate a mastery of the new rail grinding and wall riding mechanics – but, again, they can only unlock stickers. This in itself isn’t an issue (fun for fun’s sake is largely the name of the game for Nintendo), but I can’t help but feel like I would like something more substantial to use them on, such as how excess moons can be used on cosmetics in one of Super Mario Odyssey’s many stores.</p><div id="nintendo-series-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Nintendo Series Tier List</h3><h3>Nintendo Series Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Maybe I’m just a grumpy man disillusioned with the world he lives in now that he’s hit his mid-thirties, though. Because, despite these grumbles, I do need to remind myself that kids big and small will have a great time roaming around this colourful paradise, zooming around and taking in the sights of its sandy beaches and winding city streets. Plus, I’d be lying if the seven-year-old part of my brain didn’t activate when I drove into the back of a massive truck,  took over its controls Cappy-style, and wreaked havoc by ploughing into every other vehicle and breakable coin-filled brick in sight. It was a rare moment of wonder and Nintendo creativity that seems worryingly lacking elsewhere. Yes, there’s a dynamic weather system, day/night cycle, and morphing toe-tapping soundtrack that shifts depending on what biome you’re in, but none of these delightful presentation touches truly added to the fun factor.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The open world is crucial to Mario Kart World outside of its free roam mode, though, and that can’t be ignored. The way these open spaces connect tracks together is very clever, and allows for more varied course combinations to be created. Plus, the exciting new Knockout Tour just wouldn’t be the same without it. The way it snakes cross-country through the many different environments is impressive, and I could see this mode being nowhere near as fun if it took place on an extensive number of laps of the same track. This world does have its merits, it’s just not in the exploration of it. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">When treated like a toy box, as opposed to an open world on the scale of Forza Horizon or even Burnout Paradise, there is some joy to be found in Free Roam. I just wouldn’t go in expecting that open world to leave a lasting impression – perhaps a hard pill to swallow considering the $80 price tag. The racing is still the highlight of Mario Kart, and the new Knockout Mode makes it feel as exciting as it has in a long time. So much so that it really deserves to be placed front and center, and not buried in its relatively underwhelming world.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World: The Final Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-the-final-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-the-final-preview.1205667/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-the-final-preview<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Mario Kart World is just two days away, and fan expectations are rightfully high. It’s the flagship launch game for Nintendo Switch 2, the first open world in the series, the follow-up to the hugely successful Mario Kart 8 Deluxe, and on top of all that, it’s Nintendo’s first $80 game since the N64 days, which has caused no shortage of internet discourse. There’s a lot riding on this one, so I’m pleased to report that after spending roughly five hours with unrestricted access to the final build, I’m confident Mario Kart World’s thrilling racing will kick off Nintendo’s eighth generation with a rocket start, even if I’m still not completely sold on its open-world exploration.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">My <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-for-nintendo-switch-2-first-hands-on-preview"><u>first hands-on preview</u></a> back in April was very limited. Steering assist was turned on, the demo was locked to 100cc, and we only got to see a couple of modes. But this time, the training wheels came off and I played what appeared to be the version you’ll be able to buy on June 5, complete with an enormous roster of characters (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-producer-says-cow-opened-the-floodgates-for-the-wacky-npc-filled-character-roster">including everyone’s favorite, Cow</a>) and freedom to choose any mode or settings I wanted.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mario Kart World Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So I first chose to play as Mario (basic, I know) and swapped between multiple karts – including the <em>incredible </em>R.O.B. bike – to try out Free Roam, which is still the biggest question surrounding Mario Kart World. In a series first, Free Roam takes the spotlight off of racing and shines it directly on exploration, allowing players to drive across the wide, interconnected highways. Nintendo promised hundreds of P Switch missions in Free Roam, and while I won’t spoil the final total, I can confirm that it only takes a few seconds of driving in any direction to spot one of these challenges. They are littered everywhere, and after worrying they’d all be too easy based on the footage Nintendo has released so far, I was pleasantly surprised that I failed a couple of the P Switch missions on my first attempt – by either running out of time or missing a key jump – and some of them felt like they demanded mastery of Mario Kart World’s new Tony Hawk-inspired parkour mechanics. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>P Switch challenges are littered everywhere, and after worrying they’d all be too easy based on the footage Nintendo has released so far, I was pleasantly surprised that I failed a couple of them on my first attempt.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">One mission in the Bowser’s Castle area had me driving on walls and flipping off the side at the right moment to transform into an airplane, and the timing was genuinely tricky – but you’re thankfully given the option to retry a challenge immediately after failing rather than having to drive back to the start on your own. P Switch missions can also summon temporary objects and creatures to the terrain, like one where I had to steer my airplane around a few dinosaurs that showed up. I only tried a handful of the hundreds of challenges that await, and I’m not entirely sure the novelty will last through the time required to tackle them all, but I’ve enjoyed what I’ve seen to this point.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mario Kart World: Character Select Screens</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Sadly, the rest of Free Roam hasn’t gripped me yet. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-open-world-isnt-what-you-think-it-is">IGN’s Simon Cardy wrote a feature sharing his concerns about the open-world mode</a>, and while I think I’m a <em>little </em>higher on it than he is so far, I agree with the general sentiment that there’s just not that much to do outside of the P Switches. There are collectibles scattered throughout by way of Peach Medallions and ? Block Panels that unlock one of hundreds of stickers you can slap on the side of your kart, but the ones I found felt neither special nor difficult to discover, and I missed the feeling of surprise and delight that other Nintendo games like Tears of the Kingdom and Super Mario Odyssey completely nailed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even driving around itself can feel a bit too slow when you go off road into grass or sand. This limitation makes sense for the racing in Mario Kart where veering off the intended path without a Mushroom has punishing consequences, but the feeling of diminished speed across tougher terrain made me less inclined to explore. I’ve still barely sunk my teeth into Free Roam, so maybe there’s a game-changing discovery waiting to be found, but I’m not counting on it. So far, Free Roam feels decidedly like a side dish rather than the meaty, transformative open-world experience many are hoping for.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And perhaps that’s fair, because the main course of Mario Kart World was always going to be the racing, which felt completely right the second I started my first lap on 150cc. The turning, drifting, and boosting all feels as tight as you’d hope, and the open-world design fully shines in this bold new take on the formula. Knockout Tour remains the star of the show, as driving cross-country against 23 other players while doing everything you can to stay out of the bottom four before the next cutoff point is <em>exhilarating.</em> Every shell I threw felt critically important, and whether I was in the front or the back of the pack, my heart was pounding as I desperately tried to qualify for the next segment. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">These six-part races take place almost exclusively on the highways in between Mario Kart World’s dedicated courses, and as I passed through fun reimaginings of returning tracks like Mario Kart 7’s Shy Guy Bazaar and brand-new locations like the adventurous, Uncharted-like Great ? Block Ruins, I began to recognize the impressive amount of alternate paths that I’m excited to perfect once the full game is out. A well-timed Golden Mushroom can catapult you from the back to 1st in the blink of an eye, as some of the shortcuts presented on the highways allow you to cut a huge amount of the track. I can already tell that hardcore players (myself included) are going to have a blast finding the optimal routes and pushing these courses to their limits.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ve been concerned that the long stretches of very wide straightaways – present in both Knockout Tour and the revamped Grand Prix – could be boring compared to the twists and turns of the courses, but Nintendo has covered the interstate with cars to avoid, enemies that spew projectiles, and plenty of opportunities to grind on rails and make use of the new Charge Jump technique to reach optional areas. In most straightaway sections, there was always something demanding my attention – although there were a few select times I was just holding A and not doing much else, and the wide road design made things feel a bit slow compared to the close-quarters racing on the dedicated courses. Still, my fears have <em>largely</em> been squashed, and now I’m just waiting to see how these sections will hold up over dozens of repeat play sessions.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Nintendo has covered the interstate with cars to avoid, enemies that spew projectiles, and plenty of opportunities to grind on rails and make use of the new Charge Jump technique to reach optional areas.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">For all you Mario Kart purists who just want to do three laps around the 30+ courses in Mario Kart World, that classic option is one of the main draws of VS Race and Time Trials, and I was very satisfied to find that the quality track design fans have come to expect hasn’t been sacrificed in favor of the open-world elements. The reimagined Peach Beach took me through familiar waterfront straight from Double Dash before exploring an entirely new village, while DK Spaceport is a fantastic homage to the arcade game that started it all – complete with final lap music any Donkey Kong fan will feel nostalgic for. If you’ve been worried the courses wouldn’t feel as special as in past Mario Kart games, I think you can breathe a sigh of relief.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of the music, Mario Kart World might just have one of the greatest soundtracks in Nintendo history. Each course has its own dedicated theme as usual, but beyond that, the remixes that play during Free Roam and Knockout Tour make Mario Kart World feel like a proper celebration of Super Mario’s 40th anniversary. In my short time with the game I heard references to Super Mario Bros., Yoshi’s Island, Donkey Kong Country, Super Mario 3D World, Captain Toad: Treasure Tracker, pretty much every past Mario Kart, and a lot more. Each track I heard was beautifully remixed to fit Mario Kart World’s adventurous road trip vibe, and I can’t wait to hear every tune it has to offer. And I won’t have to wait long, because Mario Kart World and Nintendo Switch 2 will be here in less than 48 hours. Stay tuned later this week for our review in progress followed by our full review of Mario Kart World as we get more laps under our belts. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Logan Plant is the host of Nintendo Voice Chat and IGN's Database Manager &amp; Playlist Editor. The Legend of Zelda is his favorite video game franchise of all time, and he is patiently awaiting the day Nintendo announces a brand new F-Zero. You can find him online @LoganJPlant.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Wait for Mass Effect 5, Director Seemingly Confirms Returning Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-wait-for-mass-effect-5-director-seemingly-confirms-returning-feature</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amid-wait-for-mass-effect-5-director-seemingly-confirms-returning-feature.1205661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-wait-for-mass-effect-5-director-seemingly-confirms-returning-feature<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Glaring omission. </h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">As fans wait for a crumb of news on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mass-effect-next-chapter">Mass Effect 5</a>, the game's director has suggested at least one small returning feature will remain in the upcoming sequel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A small team at BioWare is now in the early stages of work on the next Mass Effect, following the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-ceo-says-dragon-age-the-veilguard-failed-to-resonate-with-a-broad-audience-gamers-increasingly-want-shared-world-features">disappointing launch</a> of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dragon-age-the-veilguard">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams">subsequent downsizing of the studio</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-developers-reveal-theyve-been-laid-off-after-bioware-puts-full-focus-on-mass-effect">which included layoffs</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mass Effect 5 was first announced years ago, of course, via an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-mass-effect-revealed">eye-catching trailer released back in December 2020</a>. But the project has remained very much on the back burner since then, while <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-bioware-finally-got-dragon-age-to-the-finish-line-after-a-tumultuous-decade">The Veilguard struggled through its rocky development</a>. Now, it is BioWare's sole focus — but updates on its progress remain few and far between.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This is the background, then, to a fan's plea for confirmation that Mass Effect 5 would once again feature the series' bombastic lens flare. And lo, Mass Effect 5 director Mike Gamble has sought to answer this plea on social media — albeit with a single emoji.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Mass Effect 5 better stick to tradition and have an excessive amount of lens flare," wrote Mass Effect fan Specre_Gray on social media — to which Gamble responded with an "OK" emoji.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="art" dir="ltr">👌🏻 <a href="https://t.co/FNXq5S9XcD" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/FNXq5S9XcD</a></p>— Michael Gamble (@GambleMike) <a href="https://twitter.com/GambleMike/status/1928978870159683597?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 1, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Over the years, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-teased-with-a-mysterious-piece-of-concept-art-on-n7-day">BioWare has issued repeated teasers</a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-a-new-poster-teases-the-future-of-mass-effect">artwork stuffed full of Easter eggs and secrets hinting at Mass Effect 5's eventual story</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">BioWare has suggested that the game will be set hundreds of years after the original Mass Effect trilogy, with a story that spans the events of both the Milky Way and the Andromeda galaxy featured in the series' fourth main game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's no word yet on when Mass Effect is likely to launch, but with production still in its early phases, it seems likely the game is still years away. When it does arrive, however, we at least know that lens flare will be included.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Confirms State of Play PlayStation Showcase for Tomorrow, Will Last 40+ Minutes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-confirms-state-of-play-playstation-showcase-for-tomorrow-will-last-40-minutes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-confirms-state-of-play-playstation-showcase-for-tomorrow-will-last-40-minutes.1205655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-confirms-state-of-play-playstation-showcase-for-tomorrow-will-last-40-minutes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Here are all the details.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has confirmed a State of Play showcase for tomorrow, June 4.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/03/state-of-play-returns-june-4/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog post</a>, Sony Interactive Entertainment content communications manager Tim Turi said fans will get "news and updates on must-play games coming to PS5." Turi continued: “The show highlights a selection of great games from creators across the globe.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The 40+ minute show begins June 4 at 2pm PT / 5pm ET / 11pm CEST.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s not much to go on, but it seems likely we’ll see more of Sucker Punch’s PlayStation 5 exclusive sequel, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a>, which launches in October.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Could we also see Insomniac’s Wolverine game, or what’s next from Sony’s other development studios, such as God of War maker Sony Santa Monica, Days Gone developer Bend Studio, and Horizon studio Guerrilla, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/live-service-game-horizon-online-reportedly-guerrillas-next-project-horizon-3-might-be-a-ways-off">which is working on a multiplayer spin-off</a>?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony-owned Bungie also has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marathon">Marathon</a> in development, although the extent to which Bungie will be willing to show the game off following its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fans-discuss-marathon-developer-bungies-future-after-yet-another-plagiarism-row-rocks-studio-make-no-mistake-this-is-an-existential-struggle-for-bungie-at-this-point">art plagiarism scandal</a> remains to be seen, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fairgame">Fairgames</a> — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-live-service-woes-continue-as-playstation-executive-jade-raymond-exits-fairgames-developer-after-external-test-sparked-concern">without Jade Raymond at the helm</a> — is still in the works. Last month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-teamlfg-a-new-playstation-studio-spun-out-of-bungie-thats-making-a-team-based-action-game-inspired-by-fighting-games-mobas-and-frog-type-games">Sony announced a new PlayStation studio called teamLFG and teased its debut game</a>, which is a live service incubation project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We may also see games from external developers Sony has signed to publish, such as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/phantom-blade-zero">Phantom Blade Zero</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadcam, a Found-Footage '90s-Inspired Horror Game, Announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deadcam-a-found-footage-90s-inspired-horror-game-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deadcam-a-found-footage-90s-inspired-horror-game-announced-for-pc.1205649/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/deadcam-a-found-footage-90s-inspired-horror-game-announced-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Solo developer Joure Nisser, creator of last year's Don't Scream, has announced Deadcam, a new "analog survival horror" game that uses a '90's found-footage VHS camcorder aesthetic to scare you through a series of files (i.e. encounters). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Built in Unreal Engine 5, Deadcam features three weapons in the first file: a katana, a shotgun, and a pistol. Each file is built to be completed in about one hour. There is replayability baked in, though, as there are three different endings available, but, Nisser notes, "only one unlocks the full 100% playback percentage — the 'good' ending."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Deadcam - First Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nisser offers this gameplay description: "Deadcam's found footage recordings see players through different stories; each file features its own setting, narrative, and gameplay mechanics tailored to the tone of the story. Across each file, retro UI elements monitor haunted activity in the area, including the size and speed of nearby enemy mobs."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Deadcam launches into Steam Early Access on June 23 with its first file, a J-horror inspired story set in an abandoned school, and four more files will be added over the course of the Early Access period. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2660830/DEADCAM__ANALOG_o_SURVIVAL_o_HORROR/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a> it on Steam if you're interested.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another Day, Another Hollow Knight: Silksong Steam Update — Could We Finally Get a Release Date This Week?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/another-day-another-hollow-knight-silksong-steam-update-could-we-finally-get-a-release-date-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/another-day-another-hollow-knight-silksong-steam-update-%E2%80%94-could-we-finally-get-a-release-date-this-week.1205646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/another-day-another-hollow-knight-silksong-steam-update-could-we-finally-get-a-release-date-this-week<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Another day, another Hollow Knight: Silksong SteamDB update that's whipped information-starved Hollow Knight fans into a frenzy. Could this one finally be the one?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Overnight, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/hollow-knight-silksong"><u>Hollow Knight: Silksong</u></a> was quietly updated on Steam, with <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1030300/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>SteamDB</u></a> noting that one package received its first update in over a year (thanks, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-steam-update-ignites-perfectly-reasonable-shadow-drop-hopes" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Eurogamer</u></a>). It immediately sent the rumor mill into overdrive, with players speculating that something's afoot. Will we finally see more at Summer Game Fest? Could it be part of the Xbox Showcase? Or could we even get a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2"><u>Nintendo Switch 2</u></a> <a href="https://x.com/Papa_Kutz/status/1929773856367300618" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>shadow drop</u></a>…?!</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Hollow Knight: Silksong received updates to its packages tonight on SteamDB (one apparently receiving an update for the first time in 15 months) <a href="https://t.co/DJz9ebnffg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/DJz9ebnffg</a><a href="https://t.co/THPp2luYgp" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/THPp2luYgp</a> <a href="https://t.co/9RvHY290ez" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/9RvHY290ez</a></p>— Wario64 (@Wario64) <a href="https://twitter.com/Wario64/status/1929769954494025999?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 3, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, fans immediately began scouring the updates for clues. And while some have been hurt before by a flurry of nothingburger, this update is particularly exciting because <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1l2278w/the_game_has_been_uploaded_to_the_steam_servers/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>several</u></a> <a href="https://steamdb.info/sub/342712/apps/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>fans</u></a> believe we have proof Hollow Knight: Silksong — or at least some version of it — has "been uploaded to the Steam servers."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"[Is this R]eal?" <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1l25j2q/comment/mvqbab1/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>asked</u></a> one fan hopefully. "Real," the OP <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1l25j2q/comment/mvqbg6x/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>replied</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Team Cherry has always done things on its own timescales, and is notoriously tight-lipped, leaving us speculating over the tiniest, and sometimes silliest, details. Now, however, it <em>really</em> feels like there's something coming… here's hoping we find out what it is sooner rather than later. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Team Cherry’s sequel is one of the most anticipated games in the world right now, topping the Steam wishlist charts for years. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-makes-brief-appearance-during-nintendo-switch-2-direct-to-secure-2025-release-window"><u>Silksong made a brief appearance at Nintendo’s Switch 2 Direct in April</u></a>, and soon after Team Cherry nailed down the 2025 release window, much to the relief of its very patient fans. And now, given <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-will-be-playable-in-september-2025-at-an-australian-museum">we know it will be playable for those who can be at Australia’s national museum of screen culture, ACMI, from September 18</a>, some are speculating that we could be looking at a launch before then… although nothing's confirmed as yet, of course.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN recently exclusively shared a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-sprite-sheet-has-players-wondering-what-calls-for-hornet-to-remove-her-cloak-like-an-exhausted-dad-home-from-work"><u>Silksong sprite sheet and… well, the internet internet-ed</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 GameChat Feels Better Than It Looks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-gamechat-feels-better-than-it-looks/1100-6532016/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-gamechat-feels-better-than-it-looks.1205631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-gamechat-feels-better-than-it-looks/1100-6532016/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532016">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">It's fair to say that GameChat, one of Nintendo's purported marquee features for the upcoming Switch 2, did not show well when it was first revealed. The introduction to the feature in the Switch reveal trailer looked choppy and poor quality. While I and others gave them credit for showing the feature in a "warts and all" state, it was a confusing choice to center so much of the presentation around a video-sharing function that looked, well, bad. Having now spent some time with GameChat at an extensive hands-on preview, I can't say I'm confident that the final quality will be any better than we saw--but I am sure that the ease of use and system integration make it a nicer prospect than it first appeared.</p><p dir="ltr">Unlike our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-hands-on-more-of-the-same-but-it-can-still-surprise-you/1100-6530580/">first hands-on with the Switch 2</a>, GameChat was fully enabled for this session, which meant I was free to poke around the options and see how it all worked. GameChat is a main-menu option right alongside others like the Nintendo eShop and controller settings, so it's easy to find even without the dedicated button. But the C button does call up the menu quickly, which is nice for toggling its various options on and off.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="454531420" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466023,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20-%20Nintendo%20Switch%20Online%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:281,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-nintendo-switch-online-overview-trailer\/2300-6466023\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466023\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466023\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466023\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466023&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466023,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6532016&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466023},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466023\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4502938-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/IE9MSMAj.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1748464440,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="IE9MSMAj" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch 2 - Nintendo Switch Online Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Those options include voice, video, and game sharing--the latter being the less-than-stellar game feed from your friends. You can turn on any combination of these options, and as promised, you can bring up your friend's game screen to watch them. It came up after a short delay and ran more smoothly than the choppy video shown in the Direct, when it was the main video feed. I should say, though, that the game being showcased for this feature was Zelda: Four Swords Adventures running through the GBA Classics app, so it wasn't exactly a game that was taxing system resources like Mario Kart World. The connection was also running via LAN rather than Wi-Fi, so that could have also conceivably improved my experience.</p><p dir="ltr">We played a short tutorial of Four Swords Adventures across multiple consoles with GameChat on, and we were allowed to toggle whichever features we liked, as well as explore some of the various options. If you just want to chat and don't care about sharing video, you can go full-screen and still see your friends' voices lighting up in the corner when they speak. You can turn on voice-to-text and see a text box offering what is at least a close approximation (with some understandable typos) of what they've said, identified with their usernames. That feature is offered as an accessibility option but could also be useful for those of us who play with the volume low when family members are asleep. The system also does a decent job automatically raising and lowering the game volume to accommodate voices, if you have that option selected.</p><p dir="ltr">It also seems smartly targeted at ease of use and families, which you'd expect from Nintendo, and the company commented on it when it first debuted the feature. You can quickly turn off individual shared screens--for example, if a friend is playing an M-rated game and your young children enter the room. Nintendo has also detailed some of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-parental-controls-let-you-block-kids-from-using-video-in-gamechat/1100-6531978/">kid-safe features</a> to make sure your children are only interacting with whitelisted contacts. And if you see your friend playing a game you don't recognize, it's easy to hop into its game page for more information.</p><p dir="ltr">None of these features are exactly revolutionary, and in many ways GameChat and GameShare represent Nintendo catching up to the norms of online play on other platforms. But it is smartly implemented and user-friendly in a way that feels characteristic for Nintendo's general sense of ease, if not its history with online connectivity. I'm still not convinced GameChat is a marquee feature for the Nintendo Switch 2. But after eight years of playing on the first Switch, it's a solid nice-to-have that makes the successor that much more appealing.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Fantastic Game Is Disappearing Soon -- "We Know This Sucks," Publisher Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-fantastic-game-is-disappearing-soon-we-know-this-sucks-publisher-says/1100-6532017/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-fantastic-game-is-disappearing-soon-we-know-this-sucks-publisher-says.1205625/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-fantastic-game-is-disappearing-soon-we-know-this-sucks-publisher-says/1100-6532017/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532017">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Poinpy, a platformer from developer Ojiro Fumoto AKA Moppin and published by Devolver, launched in 2022 exclusively through Netflix, but it's going away soon. The game will be removed on June 9, according to a disclaimer in the Netflix mobile app.</p><p>A spokesperson for Devolver <a href="https://discord.com/channels/439391039720259585/439391040508657666/1372345262772584548" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said on Discord</a> that the company's deal with Netflix is ending, which is why Poinpy is leaving the Netflix catalog.</p><p>"The deal with Netflix has expired, so as you already know, Poinpy will leave Netflix very soon. For the time being, Poinpy will become unavailable, and we know this sucks," the person, Modkiq, said. "With how these integrations work, Poinpy will require further development in order to be releasable in other stores, and realistically we do not know when we would have time in between other projects."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6kKWuKXHyfw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6kKWuKXHyfw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>What this means in essence is that when Poinpy leaves Netflix, it won't be available anywhere until it is potentially brought to another system--but there is no guarantee that will ever happen. It's not clear what will happen if you already have Poinpy installed on your mobile device after it's removed from the catalog.</p><p>Poinpy isn't the first game to leave the Netflix catalog, as Grand Theft Auto 3 - The Definitive Edition and Grand Theft Auto: Vice City - The Definitive Edition left in 2024. GTA: San Andreas - The Definitive Edition remains available on Netflix, however.</p><p>"Just like with series and film, games will be removed from Netflix as licenses expire," a Netflix representative <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/two-grand-theft-auto-games-are-leaving-netflixs-game-library-soon/1100-6527923/" data-ref-id="1100-6527923">confirmed in 2024.</a></p><p>Netflix's library of games can be played on mobile devices by way of downloads or streamed over the internet on your TV or browser. There are no microtransactions or in-game ads for any of the games.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GOG lays out the business case for robust game preservation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gog-lays-out-the-business-case-for-robust-game-preservation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gog-lays-out-the-business-case-for-robust-game-preservation.1205622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gog-lays-out-the-business-case-for-robust-game-preservation<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Are video game preservation and the video game business at odds? According to groups like the Entertainment Software Association, the answer is "yes." Its lawyers argue that making older games publicly available through digital libraries would harm the commercial interests of IP holders, who it says are </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/u-s-copyright-office-rejects-dmca-exemption-to-support-game-preservation">the true arbiters of preservation</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But according to Marcin Paczyński, senior business development manager at GOG, the answer is "no."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In a conversation at the 2025 Game Developers Conference, Paczyński explained that preservation is becoming the backbone of the CD Projekt-owned storefront. In November 2024 the company unveiled the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gog-expands-preservation-program-to-protect-delisted-games">GOG Preservation Platform</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, an initiative to ensure games sold through the platform will be backwards compatible on every PC in the years ahead.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Preservation Platform isn't just a label on the storefront. GOG engineers are working hard behind the scenes to solve compatibility bugs on every game run through the program using a custom DirectX wrapper to ensure a game released for MS-DOS will work on all future versions of Windows by translating the game purely to DirectX instead of Vulkan, the format used by XVK. Using the wrapper also allows GOG engineers to solve compatibility errors by fixing the wrapper itself, instead of making updates game-by-game.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/with-an-ipo-on-the-way-let-s-dig-into-discord-s-revenue-strategy" target="_self" data-discover="true">Discord's rumored IPO has us digging into its revenue strategy</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As long as Microsoft maintains support for DirectX, all games that possess the wrapper will be backward compatible. (Mac and Linux support is hopefully on the way).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Developing and maintaining that wrapper costs money, with 15 years of development already invested in its functionality. Paczyński said that it was only early last year that deploying it on a large scale became commercially feasible, thanks to tooling advancements and sufficient revenue through GOG.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As he described it, a commercial venture targeting preservation isn't just good business for GOG and publishers with back catalogues—it's vital for keeping classic video games available to the public.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="&quot;Compatibility is deteriorating.&quot;">"Compatibility is deteriorating."</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Preservation Program came to life after the team at GOG had two major assumptions upended. First, they assumed the majority of games sold on GOG were fully compatible with modern machines.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nope. Only thirty percent were fully up-to-par. Players were purchasing classic games and just not reporting any issues if they ran into a compatibility error.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Second, they assumed the public—and publishers listing games on the platform—knew that GOG was maintaining about 4,000 of the 11,000 games on the marketplace.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-was-really-wearing-people-down-the-funding-challenges-that-followed-runaway-success-another-crab-s-treasure" target="_self" data-discover="true">'It was really wearing people down:' The funding challenges that followed 'runaway success' Another Crab's Treasure</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nope. They did market research and found people had zero idea about their hard work. Everyone thought the games it worked on were being maintained by the original developers. "That was like a bucket of cold water," Paczyński said with a groan. "That's one of the reasons that that we're addressing with this." When players ask "why should I buy a game on GOG and not on Steam?," he wants there to be a clear answer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now that answer is this: Steam is a great place to buy new games, and GOG is a great place to buy "back catalogue" games. "There is no way in heaven that Steam will spend resources of fixing other people's games," he said.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Publishers have also warmed up to this pitch since GOG doesn't charge any extra money for this maintenance. It's funded by the storefront fees taken from every game purchase. It's not "free," but it's not a service developers have to budget for. "We are crazy like that," admitted Paczyński.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">GOG's DRM-free business model was the spark that lit the fire of this project. Because DRM will inevitably stop working, only DRM-free games can be truly preserved. Sometimes publishers strip away DRM years after a game's initial launch, but if a publisher goes under, there's no one left to do that task.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The game industry's adoption of DRM in the 2000s has created a ticking clock. "Compatibility is deteriorating," Paczyński claimed. He pointed to the differences among versions of games listed on the Preservation Program versus versions that live on Steam and other platforms. Developers and players can view the changelogs GOG publishes that document updates. If a game is sold on Steam and sold on GOG, the version sold on Steam won't have the compatibility improvements made possible by the DirectX wrapper.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bloober-ceo-creating-a-safe-sustainable-workplace-takes-priority-in-studio-leadership" target="_self" data-discover="true">Bloober CEO: creating a 'safe,' sustainable workplace takes priority in studio leadership</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's this process that Paczyński believes makes true preservation possible. "Preservation is not only about you having a physical copy somewhere in the closet. It's about keeping those games available and maintaining them. And because maintenance is a continuous process. It never ends."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With funding for video game preservation already tenuous, GOG's commercial venture is what's making that continuous process possible.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="There are still major hurdles to solve in commercial game preservation">There are still major hurdles to solve in commercial game preservation</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Paczyński is optimistic about the progress made preserving games on GOG. The company is using a "dream list" to solicit votes from players on what they want added to the program, and more publishers are signing off on having their games included. Back catalogues are key for driving revenue between game releases, and GOG has opened the door for more diversified sales.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But not </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>every</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> publisher is excited about this. GOG Game Preservation launched with a promise to fully preserve the first two Warcraft games made by Blizzard Entertainment. Weeks later, the Microsoft-owned company delisted </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gog.com/en/news/warcraft_12_will_be_delisted_from_gogwhat_does_this_mean_in_regard_to_the_gog_preservation_program">Warcraft: Orcs and Humans</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gog.com/en/news/warcraft_12_will_be_delisted_from_gogwhat_does_this_mean_in_regard_to_the_gog_preservation_program"> and </a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gog.com/en/news/warcraft_12_will_be_delisted_from_gogwhat_does_this_mean_in_regard_to_the_gog_preservation_program">Warcraft 2 </a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gog.com/en/news/warcraft_12_will_be_delisted_from_gogwhat_does_this_mean_in_regard_to_the_gog_preservation_program">from GOG</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Players who already owned the games will have their copies preserved in perpetuity thanks to the DirectX wrapper, but future players will have to go to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/article/24055599/get-warcraft-orcs-humans-on-battle-net-now">Battle.net</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "It wasn't a good day... when we heard that news," Paczyński said delicately. "But this is not new for GOG. Games are delisted for many different reasons. We have no control over that... because it's our partner's decision and responsibility."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">GOG also has to step carefully when obtaining older games and putting them up for sale. That's true even if a developer or publisher closed its doors years and years ago and a game could be considered "abandonware." </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Someone</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> still owns the rights to a game, and the company has had to fend off lawsuits from law firms fishing for clients who may not be aware they even own those rights. Tracking down those rights and getting all the contracts signed is time-consuming and costs money.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On a more positive note, Paczyński said GOG is looking at methods for preserving classic mods. Steam did its own version of this years ago through Steam Workshop, but not all developers include Steam Workshop support for their games. That means players who want to play say, the original Long War mod for Firaxis' </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>XCOM: Enemy Unknown</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have to go through a complicated process of installing different files instead of just clicking a single button like they can for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>XCOM 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There's also the fact that, if it wasn't for modding communities, many games would already be lost to the sands of time. "A lot of those classic games—classic meaning they were made ten [or more] years ago—are being kept alive because of the amazing modding communities," Paczyński said. GOG's preservation mission wouldn't be possible if it wasn't for modders tinkering away for free.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">All of these variables are the reason Paczyński sees game preservation as a commercial process—one that benefits GOG, publishers, and the nonprofit archival community alike.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It's a continuous effort but because it's connected to business, we are actually able to make it happen."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer and GDC are sibling </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">organizations</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> under Informa.</span></span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div data-testid="contributor-summary-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Follow Bryant Francis, Senior Editor, on </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/bryantfrancis.me">Bluesky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> or </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryant-francis-99898b29">LinkedIn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate 2 Launches Into 1.0 This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/06/03/splitgate-2-launches-into-10-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/splitgate-2-launches-into-1-0-this-week.1205616/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/06/03/splitgate-2-launches-into-10-this-week<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>1047 Games has revealed that its portal-infused Halo-like shooter, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/splitgate-2">Splitgate 2</a>, will launch into 1.0 this week after a short beta period last month. More specifically, Splitgate 2 will launch on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC via the Windows Store and Epic Games Store on Friday, June 6.</p><p>Alongside this news, 1047 Games says it has a “major surprise” in store for <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/26/the-2025-summer-showcase-schedule">Summer Game Fest</a>, which takes place this Friday at 2 p.m. PT/5 p.m. ET. The developer says this reveal is the “biggest part” of Splitgate 2.</p><p>To celebrate the release date news, the team has released a trailer about being an ace in the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2024/07/18/splitgate-2-leaps-out-of-a-new-portal-next-year">futuristic portal-y world of Splitgate 2</a>. <strong>Check it out below:</strong></p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AdpTm9qfCGE"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AdpTm9qfCGE" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>“Would-be aces can also jump into Splitgate 2’s final open beta, going on now through launch, to get a taste of some of what the futuristic portal shooter will offer on June 6 – a metric ton of maps, weapons, and modes are all there for the taking,” a press release reads.</p><p>Like the previous betas, it’s free to hop into this one (and the full 1.0 game will be free, as well). Plus, there’s a Beta Battlepass available to get some unlockable cosmetics early in your Splitgate 2 playtime. 1047 Games says progression will not reset when Splitgate 2 launches.</p><hr><p><em>Are you going to hop into Splitgate 2 this week? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CD Projekt Red claims stunning The Witcher 4 Unreal tech demo was running on standard PS5 at 60FPS with ray tracing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-unreal-tech-demo-was-running-on-a-standard-ps5-at-60fps-with-ray-tracing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cd-projekt-red-claims-stunning-the-witcher-4-unreal-tech-demo-was-running-on-standard-ps5-at-60fps-with-ray-tracing.1205613/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-unreal-tech-demo-was-running-on-a-standard-ps5-at-60fps-with-ray-tracing<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>We can't Kelp-ie but be intrigued.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A first look at in-game gameplay of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a> has just been shown off during today's State of Unreal stream.
</p><p>
During its time on the stage, we saw some in-game cinematics of a monster attacking a wagon, and Ciri coming across the scene some time later. It then transitioned into gameplay, with Kajetan Kapuscinski cinematic director at CD Projekt Red playing through it.

</p><p>All this while Wyeth Johnson, senior director and project strategy at Epic Games, and Sebastian Kalemba, VP and game director at CD Projekt Red, narrated what we were seeing. This build was running on a standard PS5 at 60fps with ray tracing enabled, according to those on stage.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="State of Unreal 2025 Official 4K Livestream I Unreal Fest Orlando" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AjikvaR0i34?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>State of Unreal 2025 Official 4K Livestream I Unreal Fest Orlando</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AjikvaR0i34?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AjikvaR0i34?autoplay=1" title="State of Unreal 2025 Official 4K Livestream I Unreal Fest Orlando">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>You can watch the full State of Unreal stream here.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AjikvaR0i34" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>We see some horse riding courtesy of Ciri's horse Kelpie. Kelpie has realitic muscles and skin movement thanks to the Unreal Chaos Flesh Solver and machine-learned deformations, so the horse will look natural without performance issues. We also see Nanite Foliage in action, which according to senior director Wyeth Johnson allows for fast-rendering high quality shrubbery and scenery.
</p>
<p>Ciri eventually comes to the city of Vargrest, filled with lots of NPCs rushing around and doing their own thing, be it looking at a bear or shopping at stalls. The build shows Ciri transition smoothly from gameplay to another in-game cinematic, leaning on a fence while talking to a quest giver.
</p>
<p>From here, the trio pull away from Ciri and look around the town some more, zooming in at NPCs chatting about fish with various nifty bits of tech at work. The idea expressed by Kalemba is that the difference between Ciri and your regular old NPC isn't too drastic.
</p>
<p>The build then has a circus added, with its crowd ramped up with an increasing number of NPCs reacting to the show without any visual stuttering or lag. Following this, Kalemba pulls back to Ciri one final time stating, "We're making this game to be the most immersive and ambitious open world Witcher game ever, and we're making this a reality thanks to our work on Unreal with the team at Epic."
</p>
<p>Recently in a CD Projekt financial report, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cd-projekt-shares-witcher-and-cyberpunk-project-updates-announces-partnership-with-mobile-developer-scopely">we learned development progress on The Witcher 4 was well underway</a>. We also know <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-wont-be-out-until-after-2026-so-could-it-be-a-next-generation-game">The Witcher 4 won't be out until 2026</a>, so consider this an early technical peak at what's to come.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World – The Final Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/03/mario-kart-world-the-final-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-%E2%80%93-the-final-preview.1205610/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/03/mario-kart-world-the-final-preview/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Mario Kart World is an inevitability. After Mario Kart 8 Deluxe became an almost mandatory purchase for the Nintendo Switch, Nintendo is banking on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> holding the same position for the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Switch 2</a>. There’s some big, bold new ideas that look to make this feel like a new generation of kart racer, most notably the jump to racing through an open world.</p>
<p><iframe title="Mario Kart World – The Final Preview" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ph5G4poDlS4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>With the Switch 2 launching later this week, we’ve been able to spend a few hours with Mario Kart World at a preview event ahead of time. That’s let us dip into a bunch of the standard tracks, mess about with the many, many characters in the game, the open world and its P-Switch challenges, and the Knockout Tour elimination mode.</p>


<p>There’s some great touches throughout the game and it’s clear that, with Nintendo having first thought of trying to bring this game’s open world vision to the original Switch, they pushed on in what they were trying to do when shifting focus to the Nintendo Switch 2. So there’s some key things like being able to shift seamlessly from the main menu to driving around in the open world – no loading screens, just start driving from where that camera is pointing – and a mini-map that is a little birds eye view camera of the world, instead of an outline map. More fundamentally, there’s the wave simulations that roll through the large bodies of water that, while we’ve absolutely seen this kind of wave tech before – famously with Wave Race 64 – can be a taxing computational element to feature when also doing open world and fast multiplayer racing with larger lobbies. Maybe this could all have worked on the original Switch, but not when pushing 60fps or when pushing four-player local split-screen.</p>


<p>Of course, it really is the core Mario Kart racing that matters the most here, and there’s that immediate familiarity that you’ll feel in nailing that boost start timing and setting off to drift through corners and fling items at your rivals. It’s Mario Kart through and through… but it’s also a little bit different in ways that will challenge your muscle memory.</p>
<p>In particular, the new wall-riding and rail-grinding additions add new opportunities to the sides of tracks and through key areas. They’re tricky to pull off, and if you miss the start of a rail, you need to do a large jump to get up onto it. This move has you&nbsp;hold the right shoulder button and no directional inputs, fighting against the now instinctive way that you hop into a drift around a corner. Worse, any directional movement will still hop into a drift, which might be the last thing you want to do. It takes time, thought and effort to learn this after so many games learning this behaviour.</p>
<p>For the most part, these additional movement types are a nice extra. Grinding on the rail doesn’t increase your speed, but does give the opportunity to trick and gain mini boosts for a marginal advantage, and it seems that there’s almost always a secondary drop-down area if they are the primary route through an area.</p>

<p>The jump across to open world has brought other big changes to the game. There’s all these race tracks dotted across the world, some new, some returning, and they can all be raced in a traditional fashion… or you can race between them. In Grand Prix cups, the first race is always at a track, but each race after starts at the previous circuit, races to the next track, and finishes off with one or a few laps of it. It’s a huge change that makes the point-to-point racing that was a rare highlight of previous games into the main event of Mario Kart World. That’s before you consider the Knockout Tour, which joins up the open world roads through a bunch of circuits, knocking out the last four racers at each checkpoint and building up the pressure section-by-section.</p>
<p>It creates this odd blend of bespoke circuits that can be tight and twisty, lean in on certain ideas and themes, but that are then joined up by these big broad roadways. There’s huge banks of item boxes that are impossible to miss, there’s long straights and gently twisting sections that provide minimal challenge, but that doesn’t make them boring to drive. After all, there’s always the chaos of items coming your way, while road traffic that comes with ramps, cannons, has Hammer Bros. flinging hammers off the back of the truck, and more. Maybe it’s a wide open sea that you sail across, bouncing over waves and tricking constantly to get every slight advantage that you can.</p>

<p>That open world is, of course, completely open for you to explore at your leisure, whether when playing solo, or when waiting for your lobby of friends to fill up and the host to select the game mode. It’s interesting to see how Nintendo has tried to fill in the blank areas with P-Switches, giving mini missions and challenges that test your driving skill. Race around and collect blue coins, whizz through checkpoints, link together rail grinds, jumps and more with perfect timing, you know what to expect. The handful that I saw weren’t mind-blowing, but they’re going to be fun to find, and can scratch that same itch that all high score and skill check challenges do.</p>
<p>I almost feel that Nintendo is embracing some of the quirky messiness that open world racers can have, doing so out of necessity. There’s bound to be boring patches of the open world, weird end points like a pipe at the end of a corkscrew road that just spits you back out to go the other way, and the ability to just fling yourself across rooftops and other areas that were not intended for you to visit. So Nintendo has had to just roll with it in some areas, and embrace it in others, like the character roster.</p>
<p>All the main cast have been lavished with love, given multiple costume variants to find by driving through and using meal items when racing, and all the animations that you’d expect. Then there’s the sensation and delight of Cow being a playable character, having adorable little animations while jumping that have made her an immediate fan favourite. And then there’s the third tier, with characters that just… well, that just don’t make much sense. How can Sidestepper drive? This big-eyed crab just sits in a car with both claws up in the air, and just has feet dangling off the sides of a bike, with a kind of out of control horror in their eyes as they look out from the screen at you. And then Fish Bone, which can have even less contact between its fishy skeleton and your chosen vehicle. I love that they’re there, and they’re hilarious to see for the first time in the character select screen, but they also feel a bit like Nintendo kind of gave in to the concept, when they’re usually the ones in complete control.</p>

<p>Regardless, this is both a bold new direction for this series, and yet one that remains familiar. You can still just race around tracks if you wish and ignore the open world races, or you can race point-to-point races that you won’t see within the main Grand Prix or Knockout Tour mode. And there’s also Battle Mode, which has the usual mix of of bespoke arenas and repurposed track sections to race through. This is also a lot of fun in split-screen, and if you have the Switch 2 camera set up and everyone’s mug on screen to highlight your human rivals, the competitiveness that everyone feels when playing Mario Kart shines through.</p>
<p>We won’t have to wait too long before we see how all of this comes together. Mario Kart World is out in just two days alongside the Nintendo Switch 2, and it’s bound to be the first game that almost anyone that buys this console plays, maybe even the only game for the first first months.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour – Will it be worth the entry fee?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/03/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-will-it-be-worth-the-entry-fee/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-%E2%80%93-will-it-be-worth-the-entry-fee.1205607/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/03/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-will-it-be-worth-the-entry-fee/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>With Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour, one thing that you cannot accuse Nintendo of is not finding inventive ways to explore all the hardware capabilities of their new generation console.</p>
<p>The game takes you to a gigantic museum of a <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, giving your tiny ant-like avatar all the different parts of the new console to explore and learn about. Starting from the left Joy-Con 2, skating across the slick touchscreen of the Switch 2 itself, and even descending down into the inner electronics, Nintendo illustrates what makes their console tick in a bunch of different ways.</p>
<p><iframe title="Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour –&nbsp;The Final Preview" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Pwh5e-v_Rw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Every feature has been explored in minute detail, whether it’s a new concept or something that’s also common to the Nintendo Switch and smartphones and tablets in general. So, you have the gyroscope within the body of the Switch tablet, and with the now fully adjustable kickstand (adapted from the Switch OLED to the Switch 2), that combines for a game where you try to set out angles as precisely as possible – turns out I’m damn good at knowing what a 30º, 45º and other angles look like. Or there’s a game of Twister for your fingers, where you have to try and put all ten of the digits on your hand on screen with randomised colour assignments.</p>
<p>Then there’s demos of HDR, pushing the maximum brightness of modern TV screens, of 120Hz refresh rates, or of HD Rumble and how it can replicate different feelings as you wave the Joy-Con 2 around. And every facet of the console’s hardware is detailed in informative pop-ups that, yes, you will be quizzed on later. Did you know that the Switch 2’s built-in speakers are the same modules as in the Switch OLED, but a mixture of tweaks to how they’re installed and software wizardry should make them sound better.</p>


<p>It’s an experience that taps into a very particular type of curiosity, saying that desire to know how things have been put together and what those features allow you to do, and that will speak to a particular kind of person. And if that concept gets you through the door, then there’s the allure of the high score chases, of earning medals to open up minigame variants and test yourself against those as well.</p>
<p>There’s a playfulness to even the simplest of ideas, such as when you play a level from Super Mario Bros. in 4K, but with pixels at 1:1 scale. You’ll see just how that entire level can fit onto a full 4K screen with room to spare, while dropping down a pipe to a sub-level does exactly what you’d expect and hope, slotting that screen down under the main stage. Simple, but joyful.</p>

<p>Yet through it all there is just that feeling that this could maybe have been a pack-in title. It’s obviously Nintendo’s choice whether they want to charge for this kind of experience, but this feels like an educational tool, almost. It’s something that parents can play through with their kids to learn about technology, making it clear that game consoles and phones aren’t filled with fairy dust, but have a different kind of magic making them work. And when that’s £8, I fear that it’s going to lose out to the immediacy of Mario Kart World or the countless other games that will come in the months and years that follow.</p>
<p>Nintendo Switch 2: Welcome Tour might not be an essential purchase for the Switch 2’s launch, but it still has that glimmer of Nintendo magic that could be well worth exploring, and there’s the capacity for this to surprise us as we explore later areas and experiences. We look forward to playing more in the next few days.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unreal Engine 5.6 Is Now Available, Featuring Enhanced Hardware Ray Tracing and Other Improvements for the Creation of Open-Worlds Running at 60 FPS o]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/unreal-engine-5-6-now-available-open-worlds-60-fps-ray-tracing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/unreal-engine-5-6-is-now-available-featuring-enhanced-hardware-ray-tracing-and-other-improvements-for-the-creation-of-open-worlds-running-at-60-fps-o.1205604/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/unreal-engine-5-6-now-available-open-worlds-60-fps-ray-tracing/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Unreal Engine 5.6 is now available, introducing many improvements that will aid developers in creating high-fidelity open worlds running at 60 frames per second on current generation hardware.</p>
<p>The new features of the latest version of the engine have been revealed during this year's edition of State of Unreal, and summarized in a video which showcases hardware ray tracing enhancements that boost Lumen Global Illumination performance, faster geometry streaming for smoother loading of massive static worlds, an intuitive redesign of Motion trails, revamped Tween Tools and redesigned Curve editor, procedural physics via the new Physics Control rig, MetaHuman creation tools now being embedded in the engine with brand-new features, simplified user interface and more, and smoother and more efficient GPU spawning at runtime.</p>
<p><iframe title="Unreal Engine 5.6 Feature Highlights" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eOX40-hZtMM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>A first in-game look at some of the Unreal Engine 5.6 features summarized in the video above was provided earlier today with the first-ever <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-new-trailer-ps5-60-fps-ray-tracing/">The Witcher IV gameplay</a>. While the footage may be a little lacking in terms of action, it does an excellent job showcasing some of the new technology CD Projekt Red is developing together with Epic that will make the game one of the most immersive open-world RPGs ever, such as Nanite Foliage, which allows the developer to create dense foliage without having a major impact on performance.</p>
<p>Additional information on Unreal Engine 5.6 can be found on its <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/news/unreal-engine-5-6-is-now-available">official website.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales Of Kenzera Developer Announces New Horror Game, Dead Take, Coming To PC In 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/tales-of-kenzera-developer-announces-new-horror-game-dead-take-coming-to-pc-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tales-of-kenzera-developer-announces-new-horror-game-dead-take-coming-to-pc-in-2025.1205601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/tales-of-kenzera-developer-announces-new-horror-game-dead-take-coming-to-pc-in-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Surgent Studios, the team behind <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/tales-of-kenzera-zau-review-spiritual-healing/">Tales of Kenzera: ZAU</a>, has announced its next project, a horror game called Dead Take.</p>
<p>Instead of working with EA again with Dead Take being another EA Originals project, Dead Take will be published by Pocketpair Publishing, and is due to arrive on just PC for now, sometime in 2025. It's unclear if there are plans to bring the game to consoles sometime later on.</p>
<p>The story of Dead Take sees you put into the shoes of an actor who begins to get "<em>uneasy</em>" per the game's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3352690/Dead_Take/">Steam page</a> when they can't get their friend on the phone. Dead Take seems to be all about the entertainment industry, going behind the "<em>glittering facade to expose its darkest secrets,</em>" according to a press release.</p>
<p><iframe title="DEAD TAKE | Teaser | Surgent Studios" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_1dJASFBl3w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>All together, the teaser trailer and everything we've seen about Dead Take so far doesn't give us a lot to go on, but that's by design, according to chief executive officer and studio founder Abubakar Salim.</p>
<p>"<em>We're being secretive for a reason</em>," Salim said in a press release. "<em>The subject matter of this game is delicate, and it hits close to home. When it comes out, and it won't be long until it does, I want players to think, 'I can't believe they actually did this'.</em>"</p>
<p>As a debut project for a new indie team, Tales of Kenzera: ZAU showed that Surgent Studios is a talented team that's capable of telling emotionally resonant stories in games. It's exciting to see them take on a horror project, and hopefully, Salim is right when he says it won't be too long before we get the chance to play it ourselves.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher IV Gets Gorgeous New Trailer and Stunning Gameplay Running on Base PlayStation 5 At 60 FPS with Ray Tracing]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-new-trailer-ps5-60-fps-ray-tracing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-iv-gets-gorgeous-new-trailer-and-stunning-gameplay-running-on-base-playstation-5-at-60-fps-with-ray-tracing.1205598/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-new-trailer-ps5-60-fps-ray-tracing/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-showcased-state-of-unreal/">The Witcher IV trailer</a> was shared today, alongside impressive gameplay footage running on base PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>The new trailer, which was shown at the beginning of this year's State of Unreal presentation and can be watched below, is the first in-engine look at the next entry in the series by CD Projekt Red and sets the stage for the first impressive gameplay showcase which the development studio used to show some of the new technology that will power the game setting out to be the most ambitious entry in the series, and one that will bring open-world RPGs to the next generation.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Witcher 4 - Cinematic Trailer | State of Unreal 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i_aRhNcHryA?start=115&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The gameplay showcase features Ciri as she travels to a village in Kovir together with her horse Kelpie, allowing the developers to show multi-character motion matching for Ciri and Kelpie, machine learning deformation to realistic render the horse's muscle with limited impact on performance, as well as Nanite Foliage, which solved the issue of needing dense foliage without impacting performance and allowed the developers to surpass the LOD tricks that have been used so far. Once Ciri reaches the village, it becomes clear how immersive The Witcher IV's world will be, as everything will be massively responsive, and there will sometimes be chain reactions between different elements. At the end of the showcase, we also got the first look at Lan Exeter, the winter capital and a major port city in Kovir. The gameplay showcase can be checked out below, courtesy of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@GamersPrey" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GamersPrey</a>.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Witcher 4 Gameplay Tech Demo Unreal Engine 5" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SwjLeGh_3qA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Witcher IV will not launch until 2027 at the earliest. A precise release window has yet to be confirmed.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playstation is holding its State of Play summer showcase this week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/669527/playstation-state-of-play-summer-2025-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-is-holding-its-state-of-play-summer-showcase-this-week.1205595/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/669527/playstation-state-of-play-summer-2025-ps5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sony has announced it will hold a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/03/state-of-play-returns-june-4/">summer State of Play presentation</a> on Wednesday, June 4th, making this first week of June an all-timer for the video game industry. Not only do we have the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/674887/nintendo-new-era-switch-2-next-gen">Switch 2 launching this week</a>, but all the video game showcases are dropping at once, because while E3 is a thing of the past, we still need an excuse to party.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/675716/summer-game-fest-might-have-a-lot-of-games">Summer Game Fest</a>, affectionately (or not) known as Keigh-3, kicks off Friday, June 6th. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/645779/xboxs-next-major-games-showcase-streams-in-june">Xbox</a> will host its showcase on Sunday, June 8th. Epic has its State of Unreal <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/677653/epic-games-unreal-fest-2025-orlando-news-announcements">going on right now</a>. And now PlayStation will join the slate of summer programming with its own showcase on <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/playstation">Twitch</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/PlayStation">YouTube</a> starting at 5PM ET / 2PM PT.</p><p>According to the announcement, we can expect a 40-minute livestream featuring updates on forthcoming PlayStation 5 titles and possibly a few surprises. The biggest game that seems possibly set to make an appearance is <em>Death Stranding 2: On The Beach </em>from Metal Gear Solid maestro Hideo Kojima. Sucker Punch’s <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/654227/ghost-of-yotei-ps5-release-date-trailer">Ghosts of Yotei</a></em> will also likely get a brief update, whetting the appetite of those waiting on its October 2nd release date.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shooter dev "gaslights" players about fake Space Whales for seven years, then sneaks them into the game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shooter-dev-gaslights-players-about-fake-space-whales-for-seven-years-then-sneaks-them-into-the-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shooter-dev-gaslights-players-about-fake-space-whales-for-seven-years-then-sneaks-them-into-the-game.1205592/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shooter-dev-gaslights-players-about-fake-space-whales-for-seven-years-then-sneaks-them-into-the-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"People weren't sure what was true anymore"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Pixeljam</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Every few moments in the current build of arcade space shooter <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nova-drift">Nova Drift</a> there's a chance the game will spawn a Cargo Train. Whenever the game decides to spawn a Cargo Train, there's a 1/7777 chance it will spawn a Space Whale instead. "Nonsense," you bellow. "Space Whales are a myth. Designer Jeffrey Nielson has been telling us they're not real ever since the original Kickstarter in 2017." Ah, you poor, unsuspecting mooncalf. You chirpy little starfish. Consider the subtleness of the sea; how its most dreaded creatures glide treacherously hidden inside downloadable software packages. Nielson has been telling you porkies.</p>
<p>He did, in fact, surreptitiously add a Space Whale to the game shortly before <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arcade-shooter-nova-drift-is-a-petri-dish-in-which-to-spawn-the-daftest-deadliest-spaceship">Nova Drift's 1.0 release back in August 2024</a>, after years of conspiracy theories. This, friends, is the good kind of lie, the kind of lie that makes combing through a million changelogs for potential headlines worthwhile.</p><!--more-->
<p>Nielson has posted <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/858210/view/536603447519086520?l=english">a full account of the running gag on Steam</a>, beginning with the first Discord "space whale" gags back in 2017. With speculation at fever-pitch, he started baiting the whale-watchers with mock community rules insisting that Space Whales aren't real. Finally, he created a "Miniature Space Whale" companion as an April Fool's joke in 2023. </p>
<p>Said Miniature Space Whale update was heavily positioned as a wind-up with arch allusions to predatory monetisation mechanisms, aka "pay-to-win-dark-patterns-bullshit", but some players took it seriously regardless. The Whale had, by this point, navigated the twisting currents of Ironic Process Theory and coasted into the balmy latitudes of the Streisand Effect. It <em>had</em> to become real. It had to have <em>always already</em> been real.</p>
<p>So Nielson sneakily began breeding a Space Whale. "I started work on this shortly after, but it got sidetracked, so the assets were in the game for a while before I actually made it possible for the whale to spawn in game," he writes in the post.</p>
<p>Having the assets in-game obviously meant that players could discover them. But Nielson foresaw this possibility, and eventually made it part of the fable.</p>
<p>"Knowing that my players love to data mine, I gave the files confusing names as an attempt at plausible deniability, but it was not enough," he goes on. "Players used the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/undertale">Undertale</a> mod tools to rip the sprites and then assemble them into something approximating a whale, but I expected this. I claimed that putting them in the engine was the easiest way for me to spoof that April Fool's day shot. But mostly I tried to stay out of the conversation. I'd muddied the waters enough that, with the help of the other community members, people weren't sure what was true anymore. Perfect."</p>
<p>Good heavens! What a magnificent bastard.</p>
<p>If you encounter the whale in Nova Drift, you'll find it to be non-hostile and "almost indestructible". It's a real boon for early-game players, steadily emitting XP orbs while in motion. If that sounds like it's going to wreck the balance, rest easy in the knowledge that the odds of spawning mean you'll probably only ever encounter a whale every few hundred hours.</p>
<p>"My plan was that it'd be just rare enough that players couldn't be sure whether evidence was doctored," Nielson adds. "After all, the art had existed in the game files quite a while before anyone captured it in a screen shot. This was of course unsustainable as video evidence did eventually appear, but by the time it did, we were way past the truth mattering. I'd just claim the video wasn't playing or that Discord was busted. Or I'd just act really impressed at their forgery skill." </p>
<p>I guess it's possible that there are still no Space Whales in the game and that this Steam blog is a continuation of the conspiracy. Still, fun story! Let's see if we're still laughing as and when Nielson goes into politics. Just think: if he joined some sleazy electoral social engineering firm, I could write about it and deploy the only other Moby Dick joke I can think of here, "call me Phishmael".</p>
<p>I like when developers tell fibs to their players, providing it's stuff like this rather than lying to you about data collection, or deleting half the workforce from the credits. It makes the "live service" thing feel almost playful, rather than a glassy-eyed eternity of intravenous content attrition. Besides which, all of these shenanigans will ultimately operate to the benefit of living, non-digital whales. Nielson is apologising for "gaslighting" his players by donating 20% of the game's sales to the WDC Whale and Dolphin Conservation charity as part of <a href="https://games.whales.org/world-ocean-day-festival-2025/">World Ocean Day Festival 2025</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Reveals Last-Minute PlayStation Showcase Ahead Of Summer Game Fest]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/playstation-ps5-summer-showcase-state-play-wolverine-1851783458</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-reveals-last-minute-playstation-showcase-ahead-of-summer-game-fest.1205580/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/playstation-ps5-summer-showcase-state-play-wolverine-1851783458<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="45a237032253a9739a7b586282b7240b" data-recommend-id="image://45a237032253a9739a7b586282b7240b" data-format="png" data-width="1072" data-height="604" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="PS5 consoles appear in different colors. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="PS5 consoles appear in different colors. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="45a237032253a9739a7b586282b7240b" data-recommend-id="image://45a237032253a9739a7b586282b7240b" data-format="png" data-width="1072" data-height="604" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="PS5 consoles appear in different colors. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Just when it seemed like Sony might be ditching the not-E3 festivities this year, it announced a new 40-minute State of Play will be airing tomorrow on June 4. The PlayStation showcase arrives in a packed week that includes the launch of the Switch 2, Summer Game Fest Live on Friday, and the Xbox summer showcase on Sunday. It feels like the gaming days of yore. Almost. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197567" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Nintendo Switch 2 Price Is Set at $450 for Now, But Could Go Higher" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="104" data-playlist="197567,196181,196230" data-current="197567"><div><p>Nintendo Switch 2 Price Is Set at $450 for Now, But Could Go Higher</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197567/197567_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197567/197567_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197567/197567_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23091.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>What can we expect from this new State of Play livestream? Sony was cagier than usual. “Watch live for news and updates on must-play games coming to PS5,” the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/03/state-of-play-returns-june-4/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/03/state-of-play-returns-june-4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PS Blog reads</a></span>. “The show highlights a selection of great games from creators across the globe.” Normally the company calls out VR games as well, so maybe this means the show will be strictly focused on upcoming PlayStation 5 releases. <br></p><p>Despite <em>Grand Theft Auto 6</em> being delayed until May 2026, it’s becoming a decently packed fall for Sony between first-party exclusives like <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> and <em>Marathon</em> and third-party blockbusters like <em>Borderlands 4</em>.<em> Mafia: The Old Country </em>and <em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em> also drop in August. Could there be a few more big fall releases that we haven’t officially heard about yet? <em>Resident Evil 9</em> is already <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1l1r9lw/mp1st_corroborates_resident_evil_9_reveal_for/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1l1r9lw/mp1st_corroborates_resident_evil_9_reveal_for/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">heavily rumored</a></span> to be appearing at Geoff Keighley’s Summer Game Fest. Maybe it’ll get previewed first by Sony. </p><p>The rest of Sony’s first-party plans remain up in the air. Following the cancellation of a number of live-service projects, including games being worked on at Bend Studio and Bluepoint Games, as well as the recent apparent setback of <em>FairGame$</em>, it’s not clear what releases PlayStation Studios might have  ready to go in the next 12 months. Insomniac’s&nbsp;<em>Wolverine</em> game was first revealed back in 2021 but lost its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamefile.news/p/wolverine-perfect-dark-brian-horton-playstation-xbox&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/wolverine-perfect-dark-brian-horton-playstation-xbox" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">creative director just last year</a></span>. Maybe we’ll see more of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/saros-release-date-trailer-gameplay-roguelike-1851762075?_gl=1*1wzxypv*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDg5NTgwNTUkbzExNSRnMSR0MTc0ODk1OTA4NyRqNTgkbDAkaDA.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/saros-release-date-trailer-gameplay-roguelike-1851762075?_gl=1*1wzxypv*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDg5NTgwNTUkbzExNSRnMSR0MTc0ODk1OTA4NyRqNTgkbDAkaDA.">Housemarque’s <em>Saros</em></a></span>, a new sci-fi roguelite in the vein of <em>Returnal</em>. The State of Play will begin streaming on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;http://play.st/YouTube&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://play.st/YouTube" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;http://play.st/twitch&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://play.st/twitch" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitch</a></span> starting at 5:00 p.m. ET.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>