<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 11:56:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World doesn't have a 200cc mode, but producer not ruling it out for down the road]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mario-kart-world-doesnt-have-a-200cc-mode-but-producer-not-ruling-it-out-for-down-the-road</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-doesnt-have-a-200cc-mode-but-producer-not-ruling-it-out-for-down-the-road.1206513/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/mario-kart-world-doesnt-have-a-200cc-mode-but-producer-not-ruling-it-out-for-down-the-road<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> won't include a 200cc mode for faster racing, but producer Kosuke Yabuki hasn't ruled it out for a post-launch addition. </p>
<p>Mario Kart World is the next entry in Nintendo's long standing series, however unlike the games that have gone before, this time the team is mixing things up with the introduction of a roamable interconnected, well, world.</p>
<p>But, while the upcoming release will feature some newness on its debut, that 200cc is one feature from previous series entry <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-kart-8">Mario Kart 8</a> that will not arrive on launch.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mario Kart World Gameplay Preview - Is It Good?" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9ZyFEGFn19Q?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mario Kart World Gameplay Preview - Is It Good?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9ZyFEGFn19Q?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9ZyFEGFn19Q?autoplay=1" title="Mario Kart World Gameplay Preview - Is It Good?">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Mario Kart World Gameplay Preview - Is It Good? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9ZyFEGFn19Q" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>This mode is often seen as a higher difficulty level for players as it can result in more frantic races due to the increased speed and power of karts. It's a lot of fun, especially after the comparatively tame 50, 100 and 150cc modes.</p>
<p>But, even though 200cc won't be available on launch, fret not. The 200cc mode was introduced to World's predecessor as part of an update following the game's initial launch, and the same may well happen again here.</p>
<p>"Some players are really happy with the addition of high difficulty modes like this," Mario Kart World's producer told <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/mario-kart-world-switch-2-nintendo-kosuke-yabuki-1235350685/">Rolling Stone</a>, before coyly adding:</p>
<p>"However, does that mean we're going to consider adding engine sizes that are larger than 150cc to Mario Kart World? I'm afraid I can't say just yet."</p>
<p>Is this something you hope to see added to Mario Kart World further down the road?</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For more on Mario Kart World, be sure to check out Chris Tapsell's preview: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/after-a-couple-of-hours-mario-kart-worlds-open-world-left-me-slightly-underwhelmed-but-is-there-more-to-it">After a couple of hours, Mario Kart World's open world left me slightly underwhelmed - but is there more to it?</a></p>
<p>As for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a>, that's coming out tomorrow, with launch titles including Mario Kart World, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/split-fiction">Split Fiction</a> and more. You can find our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/all-nintendo-switch-2-launch-games">handy guide to all Nintendo Switch 2 launch games here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CDPR Clarifies That the Demo Was Not The Witcher 4 Gameplay, Confirms There Were No Changes to Ciri’s Design]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cdpr-clarifies-that-the-demo-was-not-the-witcher-4-gameplay-confirms-there-were-no-changes-to-ciris-design/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cdpr-clarifies-that-the-demo-was-not-the-witcher-4-gameplay-confirms-there-were-no-changes-to-ciri%E2%80%99s-design.1206510/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/cdpr-clarifies-that-the-demo-was-not-the-witcher-4-gameplay-confirms-there-were-no-changes-to-ciris-design/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Only a short time after the third installment's tenth anniversary, yesterday was a great day for The Witcher fans as CD Projekt RED <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-new-trailer-ps5-60-fps-ray-tracing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">took the stage</a> during the State of Unreal presentation in Orlando, Florida. The footage included a live demo of sorts, but a CD Projekt RED spokesperson <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/witcher-4-tech-demo-shows-the-game-running-at-60-fps-with-ray-tracing-on-base-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">clarified</a> to VideoGamesChronicle that it should not be confused with The Witcher 4 gameplay.</p>
<p><em>This is a tech demo, and a first look at the cutting-edge technology powering The Witcher 4 – but not The Witcher 4 itself. It showcases the powerful foundation we’re building in close collaboration with Epic Games to push open-world design further than ever before and the core systems and features we’re developing using Unreal Engine 5. We’re really proud of this early milestone and excited to give you a sneak peek at some of the cool tech, like UAF, Nanite Foliage, Smart Objects, ML Deformer, and FastGeo Streaming, that are helping shape the future of The Witcher.</em></p>
<p>This is perhaps unsurprising, given that the studio previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-wont-launch-until-2027-says-cd-projekt-red/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> that The Witcher 4 won't be released before 2027. As such, it's a little too early to see actual gameplay.</p>
<p>The Polish developer had <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-next-game-announced-unreal-engine-5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> its decision to switch from their proprietary RED Engine to Unreal Engine 5 back in 2022. Since the beginning, the claim was that CDPR would help improve the open world game development experience even for other developers. Indeed, what we saw yesterday was impressive, especially considering that the footage was captured on a base PlayStation 5 console that ran the demo at 60 frames per second with ray tracing enabled.</p>
<p>On another note, some fans thought that Ciri looked a bit different in the new video compared to the <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-gets-first-trailer-showing-off-cirilla/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">previous trailer that aired during The Game Awards 2024</a>. Again, a CDPR spokesperson addressed this feedback in a quote <a href="https://kotaku.com/witcher-4-ciri-trailer-gameplay-ue5-tech-demo-1851783467" target="_blank" rel="noopener">provided to Kotaku</a>:</p>
<p><em>It’s the same character model used in the 2024 trailer. Ciri’s face is a direct copy of The Witcher 3 model, adapted to work with the latest MetaHuman technology. Two subtle changes were made to improve animation quality: slightly raised eyebrows, and a more relaxed eye area—the latter was present in the trailer but has since been removed.</em></p>
<p>During the State of Unreal presentation, Epic Games also <a href="https://wccftech.com/unreal-engine-5-6-now-available-open-worlds-60-fps-ray-tracing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the public availability of Unreal Engine 5.6, which brings several enhancements for developers.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["A boys' club above the law": former Ubisoft execs in court for alleged sexual harassment and abuse]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-boys-club-above-the-law-former-ubisoft-execs-in-court-for-alleged-sexual-harassment-and-abuse</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-boys-club-above-the-law-former-ubisoft-execs-in-court-for-alleged-sexual-harassment-and-abuse.1206504/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-boys-club-above-the-law-former-ubisoft-execs-in-court-for-alleged-sexual-harassment-and-abuse<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Back in 2023, several <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-ubisoft-executives-taken-into-custody-over-sexual-abuse-claims-according-to-reports">former Ubisoft executives were taken into custody</a> by French police, following <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-vow-to-investigate-allegations-of-sexual-harrassment-and-abuse">allegations of sexual harassment, workplace abuse, sexism and violence</a> in 2020. Now, some of those executives have appeared in court in Bobigny, Seine-Saint-Denis to defend their alleged role in cultivating a workplace where women were frequently assaulted or humiliated by senior members of staff.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The former Ubisoft executives in question are Serge Hascoët, former chief creative officer, who resigned after the 2020 allegations, and is accused of sexual harassment and bullying. According to his lawyer, he "denies any knowledge of reprehensible acts committed by collaborators at Ubisoft and did not receive any reports of this." Former vice-president of editorial and creative services Tommy François is also accused of sexual harassment, bullying and attempted sexual assault. He denies all charges. Former game director Guillaume Patrux, finally, is accused of sexual harassment and bullying. He, too, denies all charges.</p>
<p>As reported by the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jun/02/ubisoft-trial-france-accused-sexual-harassment-video-games-me-too">Guardian</a>, the court proceedings include more details about the allegations against the three executives, and what one Ubisoft staffer characterised as a "boys' club above the law". All the events in question were said to have taken place between 2012 and 2020.</p>
<p>Amongst other accusations, one woman was reportedly informed that wearing a coat with a red lining was "an invitation to rape", while another was told that her outfit had given somebody an erection. The most serious allegations include tying a female employee to a chair with a roll of tape and pushing her into an elevator. The same woman allegedly had her face drawn on with a marker pen and was forced to attend a meeting without washing it off. Some men are said to have been targeted, with one office game involving touching their genitals through their trousers.</p>
<p>There are also claims of religious hatred. A Muslim developer reports being ostracised after the 2015 jihadist Bataclan concert hall attacks in Paris. She also allegedly found bacon sandwiches placed on her desk or thrown at her during Ramadan. </p>
<p>During the court proceedings, a few of the individual alleged abuses were attributed to the three former Ubisoft executives on trial. Hascoët is said to have told staff that he should have sex with a colleague in a meeting room in front of everyone "to show how to calm her". François is accused of trying to kiss a woman on the mouth while his colleagues restrained her by the arms and back at an office Christmas party in 2015. François reportedly told the court this week that "I never tried to harm anyone" and that there had been a "culture of joking around."</p>
<p>As for Patrux, the allegations against him include miming physical attacks on staff, throwing equipment across an open plan office space, drawing swastikas on a woman's notebook during a meeting, and cracking a whip near colleagues' faces.</p>
<p>Back in 2020, Ubisoft apologised to "everyone affected" by the reported harassment and abuse, and announced plans to audit "our existing policies, processes, and systems to understand where these have broken down, and to ensure we can better prevent, detect, and punish inappropriate behaviour." In November 2021, current and former Ubisoft staff <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-employee-group-launch-petition-seeking-public-support-for-demands">launched a public petition</a> condemning the company for a lack of meaningful or transparent progress on this front.</p>
<p>In 2022, CEO Yves Guillemot <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/ubisoft-ceo-defends-company-against-criticism-of-reforms-but-campaigners-demand-deeper-change/">responded</a> to criticism of Ubisoft's efforts to make amends by saying "we have done a lot and I think we are a company that can be proud of itself", pointing to the swift dismissal of certain reported offenders, including Patrux. Ubisoft have yet to respond to this week's revelations.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Devs Tear Up the Rulebook, Let the Bulwark Class Use a Thunder Hammer 'Only Because We Think It Will Be Very Cool']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-devs-tear-up-the-rulebook-let-the-bulwark-class-use-a-thunder-hammer-only-because-we-think-it-will-be-very-cool</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-devs-tear-up-the-rulebook-let-the-bulwark-class-use-a-thunder-hammer-only-because-we-think-it-will-be-very-cool.1206501/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-devs-tear-up-the-rulebook-let-the-bulwark-class-use-a-thunder-hammer-only-because-we-think-it-will-be-very-cool<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The developers of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> have essentially said "it’s what the Emperor would have wanted" and made a big weapon change in the game not for balance reasons, but because it’s just really, really cool.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Saber Interactive released <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/221-pts-patch-notes-8-0-siege-update" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">patch notes</a> for the Siege Update (Patch 8), which is available now on the Public Test Realm (PTS) for PC players, and in those confirmed it had extended the weapon arsenal in PvE to add the Thunder Hammer for the Bulwark class.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Thunder Hammers are perfect for bonking the crap out of Tyranids and Chaos Marines with wide, swinging attacks that have great reach, but the weapon type is limited to the Assault class. The Bulwark class is also great, with its huge shield and overpowered, game-saving abilities. But up to this point the Bulwark was unable to wield a Thunder Hammer. It made sense that it couldn’t, given you need two hands to bring a Thunder Hammer to bear on a heretic’s noggin, and you can’t do that while holding a Storm Shield.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, a Bulkwark can equip a Thunder Hammer, but there is an understandable catch: if the Bulwark uses a Thunder Hammer, it can’t also use a Storm Shield. This significantly changes what the Bulwark is all about, which is being a Space Marine who hunkers down for proper last stand stuff. The class has various abilities tied to using the Storm Shield, such as Shield Bash, which when using a Thunder Hammer are no longer available.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What I love is the patch notes explanation from Saber Interactive justifying this change. It basically amounts to an admission that it doesn’t make a great deal of sense lore wise, but they’re doing it anyway for FUN.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We are adding this option only because we think it will be very cool and it's a shame that only one class can use the Thunder Hammer,” Saber explained. “We are not done with Bulwark, more interesting gameplay things are to come.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As a result, the Bulwark’s perks have been updated, which you can find detailed in the patch notes below.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Siege Mode Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere, there is a hugely exciting tease for expanded customization options coming to Space Marine 2, one that’s already got fans hyped for what’s to come in future patches. </p><blockquote>We are preparing a very big update for customisation, players will be able to reuse chapter champion armour parts on other classes (with lore accuracy, clipping and technical restrictions). While it's not going to be in this patch, we wanted to mention this in this patch notes to assure you that we are going to continue expanding our customization system.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">The patch notes do not reveal any new weapons or Operations mode maps, so it seems the focus here is squarely on Siege, which arrives in fully fleshed out form as part of Patch 8 on June 26. But Saber has confirmed new content is set to hit the game, including a new class. Season 4 also includes a new game mode for PvP and a new Chaos enemy. Check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-developer-saber-interactive-answers-igns-burning-questions-on-siege-mode-dreadnoughts-and-future-seasons">IGN’s exclusive interview with Saber on Space Marine 2’s Siege mode</a> for more information.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s a lot happening in the world of Space Marine 2, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-3-announced-development-officially-begins-at-saber-interactive"><u>despite the surprise announcement that development of Space Marine 3 development had begun</u></a>. Space Marine 2’s year one roadmap remains in place, and a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/original-warhammer-40000-space-marine-gets-surprise-master-crafted-edition-on-pc-and-xbox-game-pass-but-theres-no-ps5-version">Master Crafted Edition of Space Marine 1 is about to launch</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Patch 8 Siege Update PTS patch notes:</h2><h2 data-cy="title2">New Features</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>New PvE Mode — Siege</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Siege Mode expands on our PvE operations, emphasizing endless enemy waves that challenge even the strongest teams. When overwhelmed, players may call reinforcements for assistance. Engage in intense battles across three distinctive sectors, each requiring strategic adaptation. Side objectives emerge during combat, providing essential resources used to summon elite Space Marines or a formidable Dreadnought, drastically shifting battlefield dynamics.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>The Battlefield</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The battle unfolds within a fortified Imperial stronghold on Kadaku, relentlessly attacked by endless waves of Tyranid and Thousand Sons enemies. The fortress has three rotating sectors: Defensive Positions, the Arsenal, and the Control Room. In each sector, you will face five waves of enemies before your squad advances to the next sector, ultimately cycling back to reinforce earlier positions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Survival Against Waves</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Face increasingly challenging enemy waves, with direct assaults from Tyranids and cunning sabotage by Chaos forces. Brief (1 minute) intermissions between waves offer strategic opportunities, clearly indicated through UI notifications.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Side Objectives</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dynamic tasks such as capturing strategic points or retrieving Data-slates from fallen allies deepen tactical gameplay and supply critical resources essential for continued survival.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Shop and Reinforcements</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earn Siege Mode resources through successful combat and Side Objective completion. You can spend these resources at the fortress Shop. You can:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">1) Buy ammunition, medicae stimms, equipment, armour boosts, guardian relic (these items have the same exact behaviour as in Operations Mode).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">2) Summon specialized Space Marines providing targeted support and bonuses. Each player can have only one summoned Space Marine.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">3) Deploy Cadian Troopers to provide additional firepower.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">4) Collectively pool your resources to unleash the devastating power of a Dreadnought.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Boss Encounters</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Every fifth wave introduces formidable boss battles, occasionally facing multiple elite foes simultaneously. Triumph in these encounters to progress to new fortress sectors.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Infinite Waves</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">If your resolve endures through fifteen brutal waves, prepare for endless combat of increasing difficulty, reduced resources, and shorter preparation times. Even the Primarch of the Ultramarines understands that ultimate victory here is unlikely — but your bravery will echo through the halls of eternity."</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added option to<strong> disable bots spawn in Private Mode.</strong></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Perfect if you’re looking for a challenge</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>RTAO</strong> experimental feature added — enables in in-game video settings</li><li><strong>DLSS 4</strong>  — better upscale for 50xx series cards.</li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>New Season Pass Content</strong></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Added White Scars Chapter Champion. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Added White Scars Chapter Weapon Skin Pack. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Added White Scars Chapter Customisation Pack. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Added Blood Angels Customisation Pack.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">GAMEPLAY AND BALANCING TWEAKS</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Extended Weapon arsenal in PvE </h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added <strong>Thunder Hammer for Bulwark</strong>. Picking this weapon <strong>will prevent you from using the Storm Shield</strong>.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>We are adding this option only because we think it will be very cool and it's a shame that only 1 class can use the Thunder Hammer. We are not done with Bulwark, more interesting gameplay things are to come.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>New Finishers for Bulwark</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adding new finishers for Bulwark with shield — 1 for Hormagaunts and 1 for Tzaangors.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Terminus Update for Absolute Difficulty</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>A second Terminus can now appear during a mission.</li><li>The Terminus's HP has been increased by 66% and additional enemy packs will appear upon its spawn and again when its HP is reduced to 50%</li><li>These additional packs are now slightly more challenging featuring more Extremis enemies</li><li>Mission with final bosses can now also spawn Terminus enemies (previously, missions like “Decapitation” didn't allow any Terminus spawns)".</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>This change is made according to the community poll that we made a while ago. We think that Absolute difficulty wasn't that hard to begin with and now with a slight power creep of constant weapons buffs, perk buffs and prestige perks the situation is much worse.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>After doing multiple test we have scrapped the idea of having 2 Terminus enemies in Operations mode at the same time (except in Siege mode), because this meant that you would have to encounter them all of the time, otherwise one run with dual terminus spawns would be much harder than a run with 2 Terminus enemies spawning one by one. </em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Instead we've tried to make Terminus spawns harder and more intense. We are going to continue to monitor how Absolute Difficulty is, and make necessary tweaks.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Prestige Perks Class Update</strong></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Bulwark Prestige Perks Update</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>“Rally Point”</strong>: The perk has been reworked. The new perk is <strong>“Emboldened Stand”</strong>.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>“Chapter Banner additionally removes negative Status Effects while active.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>: <em>“When the Chapter Banner is active, all Squad Members do not lose control upon taking Heavy Hits and cannot be knocked back within its zone.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Assault Prestige Perks Update</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Boosted Recharge"</strong>: The perk has been reworked. The new perk is <strong>“Unyielding Oath”</strong>.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>“Collecting an Armour Boost restores Ability Charge by 100%.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>: <em>"When charging a Ground Pound, you become Invulnerable for 3 seconds."</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Sniper Prestige Perks Update</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>​"Boosted Recharge"</strong>: The perk has been reworked. The new perk is <strong>“Materiel Upgrade”</strong>.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>“Collecting an Armour Boost restores Ability Charge by 100%.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>:<em> "Equipment Damage radius increases by 15%."</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Heavy Prestige Perks Update</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>“Restorative Capacity”</strong>: The perk has been reworked. The new perk is<strong> “Honed Precision”</strong>.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>”Activating Iron Halo removes negative Status Effects.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>: <em>"Equipped Weapon's Maximum Spread decreases by 25% when firing without aiming."</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Tactical Prestige Perks Update</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Skilled Supplier"</strong>:  Fixed a bug preventing the player from getting the maximum ammo.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Class Perks Updates</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Bulwark Perks Update </h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Perks have been updated to reflect the addition of the Thunder Hammer to the Bulwark’s arsenal.</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Forward Momentum"</strong>: The perk has been updated. </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>“After a Shield Bash, Melee Damage increases by 30% for 10 seconds.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>:<em> "After a Shield Bash or Thunder Hammer Pommel Smash, Melee Damage increases by 30% for 10 seconds".</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Concussive Force"</strong>: The perk has been updated.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>“Shield Bash deals 200% more Damage.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>: <em>"Shield Bash deals 200% more Damage. Thunder Hammer Pommel Smash deals 100% more Damage and deals area-of-effect Damage within a 7-metre radius. Cooldown is 5 seconds."</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Merciless Resolve"</strong>: The perk has been updated.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>“After a Shield Bash, Melee Damage increases by 15%, you do not lose control upon taking Heavy Hits and you cannot be knocked back for 10 seconds.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>: <em>"After a Shield Bash or Thunder Hammer Pommel Smash, Melee Damage increases by 15%, you do not lose control upon taking Heavy Hits, and you cannot be knocked back for 10 seconds".</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Focused Restoration"</strong>: The perk has been buffed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“Every 40 seconds, all Squad Members automatically restore 1 Armour Segment “</em> -&gt;  Cooldown <strong>decreased from</strong> <strong>40 to 30 seconds</strong>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Tactical Perks Update</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Final Shot"</strong>: The perk has been reworked.The new perk is <strong>“Emperor’s Judgement”</strong>.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>“After a Finisher, the equipped Ranged Weapon reloads automatically.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>: <em>"After a Finisher, the equipped Ranged Weapon reloads automatically, and your Primary Weapon deals 20% more Damage for 10 seconds".</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Communion of Fire"</strong>: The perk has been reworked. The new perk is <strong>“Secure Stockpile”</strong>.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>“Recoil is reduced by 25% and Ranged damage against Extremis-level enemies is increased by 10% for all Squad Members.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>: <em>“Equipment Charge is restored by 1 for all Squad Members. Cooldown is 60 seconds.”</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Steady Aim"</strong>: The perk has been buffed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“Weapon Spread and Recoil is reduced by 20% and Ranged Damage against Terminus-level enemies is increased by 10%”</em> -&gt; Ranged Damage bonus <strong>increased from 10% to 15%</strong>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Assault Perks Update</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Winged Fury"</strong>: The perk has been buffed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“Damage from Melee Attacks executed while sprinting or dashing increases by 40%.” </em>-&gt; Damage <strong>increased from 40% to 100%</strong>.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Hammer of Wrath"</strong>: The perk has been buffed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“After a Ground Pound, you take 15% less Ranged Damage, do not lose control upon taking Heavy Hits and you cannot be knocked back for 10 seconds”</em> -&gt; Damage reduction <strong>increased from 15% to 20%</strong>. Knock back immunity duration <strong>increased from 10 to 15 seconds</strong>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Vanguard Perks Update</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Moving Target"</strong>: The perk has been buffed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“Each Melee Attack you land reduces the Ranged Damage you take by 2% (up to 20%). If you do not land a Melee Attack for 5 seconds, the effect ends.”</em> -&gt;  Consecutive hit multiplier<strong> increased from 2% to 5%</strong>. Max bonus<strong> increased from 20% to 30%</strong>.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Retribution"</strong>: The perk has been buffed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“After you are grabbed or knocked back, you deal 25% more Melee Damage for 15 seconds.” </em>-&gt; Bonus damage <strong>increased from 25% to 30%</strong>. Duration<strong> increased from 15 to 20 seconds</strong>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Sniper Perks Update</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Precision Targeting"</strong>: The perk has been buffed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“Weapon Spread is reduced by 25% and Ranged Damage against Extremis-level enemies is increased by 10% for all Squad Members.”</em> -&gt; Ranged Damage <strong>increased from 10 to 15%</strong>.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Dexterous Hands"</strong>: Instigator Bolt Carbine is now also affected.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“Bolt Carbines reload 20% faster, and their Weapon Spread and Recoil are reduced by 15%.”</em></p><h2 data-cy="title2">Weapon Perks Update</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Inferno Pistol Perk Update</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Know no fear"</strong>: The perk has been reworked. </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>Old</u>: <em>“When your Health is below 10%, Reload Speed increases by 30%.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u>New</u>: <em>“If your Armour is fully depleted, Reload Speed increases by 20%.”</em></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Neo-Volkite Pistol Perk Update</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>"Combustive momentum"</strong>: The perk has been buffed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“After a Gun Strike, heating speed increases by 30% for 6 seconds.” </em>-&gt; Duration <strong>increased from 2 to 6 seconds.</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Combat QoL</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>If a Sniper type enemy aims at you, using <strong>Assault’s Jump Pack</strong> ability will allow you to dodge the shot. The sniper will shoot instantly, but the shot will miss.</li><li>Fixed an issue where <strong>Neurothropes' Warp Storm afterblasts could stun-lock the player with heavy hits</strong>. Now, afterblasts will damage the player but not control them. Additionally, <strong>Neurothropes' shots now have a slightly longer delay between them.</strong></li><li>Fixed a lot of minor issues improving overall combat responsiveness</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Firearms (PvE Only)</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>There are not many weapon balance tweaks in this patch because our statistics show that usage and win rate for all weapons is in a good spot right now. With the next big update we are going to focus on weapon versions balance inside each archetype, because this is where we see a big room for improvements.</em></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Bolt Pistol</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Hip-Fire <strong>spread decreased by 50%</strong>. </li><li>Velocity of spread increasing in minizoom state is <strong>decreased by 15%.</strong></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Inferno Pistol</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Gun Strike Damage<strong> increased by 20%</strong>.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PvP</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>With the next patch we are going to take a closer look at PvP weapon balance.</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Large amount of small fixes in level geometry collision.</li><li>Lots of minor fixes for private lobbies gameplay modificators.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">AI</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Spore Mines</strong>: Explosion damage is <strong>reduced by 55%</strong>.</li><li><strong>Neurothrope</strong>: Temporary invulnerability is <strong>replaced with high damage resistance</strong> when it flies up from the ground.</li><li>Lots of minor animation fixes for various enemies.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Customisation</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>We are preparing a very big update for customisation, players will be able to reuse chapter champion armour parts on other classes (with lore accuracy, clipping and technical restrictions). While it's not going to be in this patch, we wanted to mention this in this patch notes to assure you that we are going to continue expanding our customization system.</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added Red, White and Blue weapon skins as Siege mode rewards</li><li>Added Prestige reward shoulder pad on left shoulder as well.</li><li>Added left pauldron decal "Ultramarine Sergeant".</li><li>Lots of other minor fixes for customizations of armour parts and emblems.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Levels</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Large amounts of small fixes in level geometry collision and Terminus enemies getting stuck in some areas.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">General Fixes</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where spore mines could spawn on top of the player.</li><li>Fixed several cases where contested health may decrease while performing a finisher.</li><li>Fixed: Combining Sniper's prestige perk "<strong>Emperor's Grace</strong>" with "<strong>Lingering Concealment</strong>" perk drains the ability charge while linger is active</li><li>Fixed: Weapon perk "<strong>Reloaded Restauration</strong>" was not activated by the Sniper's perk "<strong>Efficient Readiness</strong>".</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Bulwark perk’s “<strong>Intimidating Aura</strong>” was not triggering with a Perfect Block.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Intimidating Aura is probably the most overpowered perk right now, but we think that it should still work independently from selected weapon</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed a bug with the “<strong>Final Shot</strong>” perk not increasing damage in some cases.</li><li>Fixed a bug affecting Heavy's “<strong>Bonds of brotherhood</strong>” perk not granting full health when the player is revived by a bot.</li><li>Fixed an issue where some pick ups were inaccessible as a consequence of the interaction button failing to appear. </li><li>Fixed rare camera bugs after finisher.</li><li>Lots of minor animation fixes for the player.</li><li>Minor UI, sound and VFX fixes and improvements</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Tech</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Crash fixes and general stability improvements.</li><li>Matchmaking and network stability fixes.</li><li>Minor memory optimization. </li><li>Improvements to game modding capabilities.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Main Known Issues</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>PvE Quick Match</strong> - Returning to the Battle Barge from a PvE mission in Quick Match makes the game switch to Offline.</li><li><strong>Performances</strong>: Horde Mode - FPS drops may occur.</li><li><strong>PvP</strong> - The players are assigned to a random server instead of the one closest to them, which may result in higher latency than usual.</li><li><strong>Localization is not fully integrated in other languages than English.</strong></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horror Hit Phasmophobia the Next Game to Get a Hollywood Movie Adaptation From Blumhouse]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/horror-hit-phasmophobia-the-next-game-to-get-a-hollywood-movie-adaptation-from-blumhouse</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horror-hit-phasmophobia-the-next-game-to-get-a-hollywood-movie-adaptation-from-blumhouse.1206495/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/horror-hit-phasmophobia-the-next-game-to-get-a-hollywood-movie-adaptation-from-blumhouse<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Kinetic Games' terrifying ghost investigation game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/phasmophobia">Phasmophobia</a>, is getting the Hollywood treatment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Horror specialist <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/producer/blumhouse-productions"><u>Blumhouse</u></a> — the credits of which include <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/five-nights-at-freddys"><u>Five Nights at Freddy's,</u></a> <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/the-conjuring"><u>The Conjuring</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/m3gan"><u>M3gan</u></a> — has partnered with the UK developer to create a feature film adaptation. At the moment, nothing else is known, so we're not yet sure who'll be writing or directing it, let alone starring in the movie.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It’s a big moment for the whole Kinetic team, and the start of something really exciting,” said Daniel "Dknighter" Knight, director of Kinetic Games. “We never could’ve imagined the incredible heights this game would reach when it launched five years ago, and we’re so thankful to our amazing community for the lasting impact Phasmophobia has had in the gaming space and beyond. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Working with Blumhouse and Atomic Monster marks an incredible new chapter for the game, and we can’t wait to share more as the project develops.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Phasmophobia is a four-player online co-op psychological horror where you and your team of paranormal investigators enter haunted locations filled with spooky activity and gather as much evidence of the paranormal as you can. Since it launched in early access in 2020, spawning a new genre of ghost hunting games, it's passed 23 million sales thanks to its blend of co-op horror and investigative gameplay. Later this month, we'll get the Chronicle update, which overhauls evidence, the journal, and levelling and progression.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Phasmophobia even made <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-horror-games"><u>IGN's 25 best horror games ever made</u></a> list… do you agree with our placement?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We didn't have a great time with Blumhouse's last big horror game adaptation; <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/five-nights-at-freddys-review">we gave Five Nights at Freddy's a 4/10</a>: "This big-screen take on the indie-horror sensation has too much plot and not enough of the game's primal security-cam thrills." <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/five-nights-at-freddys-2">A second Freddy's move is out in December 2025</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phasmophobia film adaptation by Blumhouse announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/phasmophobia-film-adaptation-by-blumhouse-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phasmophobia-film-adaptation-by-blumhouse-announced.1206489/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/phasmophobia-film-adaptation-by-blumhouse-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Produced by Blumhouse and Atomic Monster.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>A feature film adaptation of <a title="Genres > Co-Op [275 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> psychological <a title="Genres > Horror [626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > Phasmophobia [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/phasmophobia">Phasmophobia</a></em> is currently in development at horror film studio Blumhouse, developer <a title="Companies > Kinetic Games [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kinetic-games">Kinetic Games</a> announced. <span id="more-969488"></span></p><p>The film will be produced by Blumhouse, known for horror movies like <em>M3GAN</em>, <em>The Black Phone</em>, and <em>Five Nights at Freddy’s</em>, alongside Atomic Monster, James Wan’s production company behind <em>Annabelle</em>, <em>The Nun</em>, and <em>The Conjuring</em> universe.</p><p>“We’re thrilled to officially announce that a <em>Phasmophobia</em> film adaption is in development—it’s a big moment for the whole Kinetic team, and the start of something really exciting,” said Kinecti Games director and <em>Phasmophobia</em> lead developer Daniel Knight in a press release. “We never could’ve imagined the incredible heights this game would reach when it launched five years ago, and we’re so thankful to our amazing community for the lasting impact <em>Phasmophobia</em> has had in the gaming space and beyond. Working with Blumhouse and Atomic Monster marks an incredible new chapter for the game, and we can’t wait to share more as the project develops.”</p><p><em>Phasmophobia</em> is currently available in Early Access for PlayStation 5, PlayStation VR2, Xbox Series, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/739630/Phasmophobia/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. It has sold 23 million copies since its Early Access launch in 2020. The latest update, “<a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/phasmophobia-chronicle-update-launches-june-24">Chronicle</a>,” is due out on June 24.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo belatedly adds much-needed feature to Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-belatedly-adds-much-needed-feature-to-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-belatedly-adds-much-needed-feature-to-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom.1206477/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-belatedly-adds-much-needed-feature-to-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>If at first you don't succeed, Tri again.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nintendo is currently in full swing gearing up for the launch of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a>, and part of that has seen the company update a number of its original Switch games for the newer model. While many of these updates are along the lines of 'added support', Nintendo has gone a bit further with Legend of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom">Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</a> - there's finally a more streamlined way to find favourite Echoes no matter which console you play on.</p>
<p>Echoes, for those unfamiliar with the game already, are essential items (or creatures) Zelda can copy and paste into the world, and use to her advantage. For example, once Zelda learns a bed Echo, she can use imitations of this object to create a bridge. An <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/best-echoes-to-get-early-zelda-of-wisdom">Echo of the classic Legend of Zelda enemy the Peahat</a>, meanwhile, can be deployed during any confrontation and steadily use its spikes to jab your foes into oblivion. However, they could sometimes take a while to find during gameplay, given in total there are <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/all-echoes-locations-abilities-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-listed">127 Echoes to eventually choose from</a> all in one long list to scroll through. </p>
<p>Thankfully, Nintendo has heard our outcries (I am sure I am not the only one who has cried out...) about this. Now, those playing Echoes of Wisdom will find a new feature which displays "only favourited echoes in the list of echoes after 30 or more echoes have been learned". Huzzah! My word, I would have really loved this when I played the game on its release last year.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom Review" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xRTsMUzj4Vs?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom Review</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xRTsMUzj4Vs?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xRTsMUzj4Vs?autoplay=1" title="The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom Review">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom review. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xRTsMUzj4Vs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>This Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom update is known as Ver. 1.1.0, and additionally has optimised visuals for Switch 2, as well as some adjustments which will "create a smoother gaming experience". You can read the <a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/66454/~/how-to-update-the-legend-of-zelda%3A-echoes-of-wisdom">full Echoes of Wisdom update notes here</a>.</p>
<p>Other games to receive some free optimising Switch 2 updates include the likes of:</p>
<ul>
<li>ARMS</li>
<li>Big Brain Academy: Brain vs. Brain</li>
<li>Zelda: Link's Awakening</li>
<li>Pokémon Scarlet and Violet</li>
<li>Game Builder Garage</li>
<li>Club House Games: 51 Worldwide Classics</li>
<li>New Super Mario Bros. U Deluxe</li>
<li>Captain Toad: Treasure Tracker</li>
<li>Super Mario Odyssey</li>
<li>Super Mario 3D World + Bowser's Fury</li>
</ul>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Switch 2 is set to release tomorrow, on 5th of June. Eurogamer's former editor Tom Phillips has already been hands-on with Nintendo's upcoming console. You can <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-hands-on-reveals-a-proper-generational-upgrade-though-its-biggest-new-idea-remains-unproven">read his Switch 2 impressions here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 76: Gone Fission is Now Available For Free, Introducing Fishing, Combat and Perks Changes and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fallout-76-gone-fission-is-now-available-for-free-introducing-fishing-combat-and-perks-changes-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-76-gone-fission-is-now-available-for-free-introducing-fishing-combat-and-perks-changes-and-more.1206474/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fallout-76-gone-fission-is-now-available-for-free-introducing-fishing-combat-and-perks-changes-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/fallout-76/">Fallout 76</a> free update called Gone Fission is now live, introducing a slew of new features marking the beginning of Season 21.</p>
<p>The biggest feature introduced to the game by the Gone Fission update is fishing, which can be done in any water where swimming is possible. 30 new fish can now be caught, and it is also possible to cook new recipes using them. Before you can start enjoying this new pastime in the world of Fallout 76, however, you will first have to complete the Casting Off new questline, where you will receive a working Fishing Rod, which can also be upgraded by completing the new fishing challenges and daily fishing quests.</p>
<p>The Fallout 76: Gone Fission update also introduces 12 Axolotls to find, one available to catch every month throughout the year. The update also introduces Local Legends, new C.A.M.P. items related to the newly introduced fishing challenges, some combat changes, perk tweaks and rebalancing, and more. You can catch the full update notes <a href="https://fallout.bethesda.net/en/article/2fsxzAz2icHeeJYGR37kQs/fallout-76-gone-fission-release-notes">here</a> and check out a quick overview of the new content introduced by the latest update in the trailer below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Fallout 76 - Season 21: Gone Fission" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GJyGMIgxHPs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Fallout 76 is now available on PC, PlayStation 4, and Xbox One. The Gone Fission free update and Season 21 are also live on all formats.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subnautica 2 will have a bigger map and a silent protagonist, say devs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-will-have-a-bigger-map-and-a-silent-protagonist-say-devs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/subnautica-2-will-have-a-bigger-map-and-a-silent-protagonist-say-devs.1206471/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-will-have-a-bigger-map-and-a-silent-protagonist-say-devs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Get yer flip-flops out and dust last year's sand off the boogie board. <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/subnautica-2">Subnautica 2</a>'s world map will be bigger than previous games in the soaking survival series. At least that's what the developers say in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NbvNYN76ArQ">a recent Q &amp; A video</a>. They've also said they're returning to the storytelling style of the first game, with a silent protagonist and "player discovery" being the big driver of the story. </p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Subnautica 2 - Waterside Q&amp;A" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NbvNYN76ArQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Subnautica 2 - Waterside Q&amp;A</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NbvNYN76ArQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NbvNYN76ArQ?autoplay=1" title="Subnautica 2 - Waterside Q&amp;A">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NbvNYN76ArQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"The playable map size will be bigger than what we originally launched in early access on the original <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/subnautica">Subnautica</a>, and even Below Zero's early access release," says creative producer Scott MacDonald in the video. "But just how big and how deep you'll be able to go over the course of early access, we're not exactly sure yet."</p>
<p>"The entire world is being handcrafted by a talented team of world designers and environment artists," he said, "and they're pouring everything into the world right now. We're aiming for this to be the biggest and most exciting Subnautica game ever once we hit 1.0 in a few years time."</p>
<p>It's not totally surprising for Unknown Worlds to go bigger for the sequel. But outright saying so may be reassuring to those players who complained that Below Zero's map felt smaller and shallower than the original survival splashabout. One player, for example, made comparison images to show <a href="https://imgur.com/xewdhVK">the difference in map size between games</a>.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Krafton</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I wasn't that bothered, to be honest. Much of the first game's map is open expanse and empty ocean - good for evoking a sense of vastness but not necessarily required in Below Zero's frosty ice fields.  The cold spinoff was still <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-below-zero-review">beautiful and inviting</a>, even if all the bitter snowstorms raged in a tighter space. But hey, I get why people are endlessly hungry for more watery depths to explore. The original Subnautica remains one of our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-survival-games-on-pc">best survival games</a>. </p>
<p>The devs cover some other common queries. They say a lot of players want to go back to the environmental storytelling basics of the first game. So the game is "returning to having a silent protagonist", rather than a tailored protagonist as in Below Zero. "But that doesn't mean that we won't have the opportunity to showcase some amazing voice acting in PDA entries and in other areas," says MacDonald. </p>
<p>But not everything is returning to tradition. The vehicles you'll get here won't include the nippy Seamoth submersible or hulking Cyclops submarine from the first game, we're told, because the team want to make "new vehicles that are designed in the same spirit, just more suited to the brand new environment". Meanwhile full character customisation won't be available from the first moments of early access, they say, but it will get added later.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phasmophobia is being turned in to a movie after topping 23 million sales]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/phasmophobia-is-being-turned-in-to-a-movie-after-topping-23-million-sales</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phasmophobia-is-being-turned-in-to-a-movie-after-topping-23-million-sales.1206462/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/phasmophobia-is-being-turned-in-to-a-movie-after-topping-23-million-sales<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Horror movie specialist Blumhouse is bringing Phasmophobia to the silver screen.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Kinect Games, the UK indie studio behind the wildly successful horror title, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.kineticgames.co.uk/blog/phasmophobia-film-adaptation-blumhouse">shared the news in a blog post</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and confirmed the movie will be produced by Blumhouse and Atomic Monster.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We're thrilled to officially announce that a Phasmophobia film adaption is in development—it's a big moment for the whole Kinetic team, and the start of something really exciting," said Kinect Games director Daniel Knight.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We never could've imagined the incredible heights this game would reach when it launched five years ago, and we're so thankful to our amazing community for the lasting impact Phasmophobia has had in the gaming space and beyond. Working with Blumhouse and Atomic Monster marks an incredible new chapter for the game, and we can’t wait to share more as the project develops."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Blumhouse is the film, television, and video game production company behind movies such as M3GAN, The Black Phone, and Five Nights at Freddy's.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Atomic Monster, founded by horror movie director James Wan, is the production company responsible for creating successful horror franchises such as Annabelle, The Nun, and The Conjuring.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Phasmophobia has sold over 23 million copies worldwide since making its early access debut in 2020 and continues to receive support in the form of robust updates.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/wizards-of-the-coast-announces-publishing-deal-with-giant-skull-for-dungeons-and-dragons-games" target="_self" data-discover="true">Wizards of the Coast teams with Giant Skull on 'epic' single-player Dungeons &amp; Dragons game</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It becomes the latest in a growing number of video games to cross the multimedia divide amid a transmedia boom, with indie studios and major publishers (and those in-between) looking to reach new audiences by expanding the reach of their cherished franchises.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Last of Us, Fallout, Elden Ring, Uncharted, Minecraft, Halo, Sonic the Hedgehog, and Super Mario Bros. are just some of the franchises to have made the transmedia leap—and a recent spate of deals means they'll soon be joined by the likes of Elden Ring, Death Stranding, Pacific Drive, Ghost of Tsushima, Kingmakers, and more.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign director claims to have beaten everything solo and without relics, but can he do it with a saxophone?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-nightreign-director-claims-to-have-beaten-everything-solo-and-without-relics-but-can-he-do-it-with-a-saxophone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-director-claims-to-have-beaten-everything-solo-and-without-relics-but-can-he-do-it-with-a-saxophone.1206459/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-nightreign-director-claims-to-have-beaten-everything-solo-and-without-relics-but-can-he-do-it-with-a-saxophone<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Let's talk about sax, baby!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>FromSoftware / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The director of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a> has claimed he was able to beat the game solo and without relics, that it's very possible to do so, and wants players to have the confidence to try it themselves.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/gaming/elden-ring-nightreign-director-interview-if-he-can-solo-every-boss-so-can-you/">In an interview with CNET</a>, director Junya Ishizaki was asked about how many bosses he had beaten himself, to which he responded: "I can hopefully give you reassurance to know that I have beaten all of the game's bosses. I've seen everything it has to offer, both in multiplayer and as a solo player. So I want you and players to know that this is very possible, and I want you to have the confidence to give it a try yourself. "</p>
<p>In a quick follow up, Ishizaki was asked if he'd solo'd every boss in the game too, to which he confirmed: "Yes. And without relics."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Elden Ring Nightreign Review - An Authentic Souls Experience" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ixEcYgheHc0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Elden Ring Nightreign Review - An Authentic Souls Experience</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ixEcYgheHc0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ixEcYgheHc0?autoplay=1" title="Elden Ring Nightreign Review - An Authentic Souls Experience">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Watch our Elden Ring Nightreign video review here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ixEcYgheHc0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-nightreign-is-now-easier-for-solo-players">Elden Ring Nightreign was made easier for solo players last week</a>, acting as a salve for those who felt the solo experience was too daunting compared to the difficulty level experienced in groups of three. FromSoftware also announced a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-nightreign-two-player-mode-confirmed-as-fromsoftware-celebrates-35m-players">duo-mode is in development in response to player feedback</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, while many are struggling still and Ishizaki has politely laid out a "Git Gud" to folks, one player has already jazzed up a regular Nightreign run by beating Gaping Jaw with a saxophone controller. This player - Dr. Doot - previously <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wg3RS_vYxpM">beat Elden Ring with a saxophone without being hit</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/this-years-agdq-included-someone-speedrunning-elden-ring-bosses-with-a-saxophone">and finished the game on the sax in less than 30 minutes at ADGQ this year</a>.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>So what I'm wondering is, when is Ishizaki busting his sax out? If he can't crack it, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/twitch-streamer-missmikkaa-completes-elden-ring-dlc-shadow-of-the-erdtree-on-a-dance-mat">a DDR mat would also suffice</a>.</p>
<p>Elden Ring Nightreign has proven to be a solid success despite its drastic departure from FromSoftware norms,<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-nightreign-two-player-mode-confirmed-as-fromsoftware-celebrates-35m-players"> surpassing 3.5 million players yesterday</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy Tactics Remaster May Be Revealed During Today’s State of Play]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-tactics-remaster-revealed-state-of-play/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-tactics-remaster-may-be-revealed-during-today%E2%80%99s-state-of-play.1206453/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-tactics-remaster-revealed-state-of-play/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The long-rumored Final Fantasy Tactics remaster could be announced during today's PlayStation State of Play, judging from some recent happenings.</p>
<p>Shortly after the announcement of the new presentation that will air later today, as reported on the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/jason-schreier-might-be-teasing-an-upcoming-final-fantasy-tactics-remaster-announcement-plus-yasumi-matsuno-retweeted-the-state-of-play-tweet.1206009/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ResetERA forums</a>, Yasumi Matsuno, director and writer of the game, retweeted the announcement, suggesting that something he has worked on would be shown during the presentation, later deleting the retweet. In addition, well-known reporter Jason Schreier talked about the game shortly after the announcement of the State of Play on Bluesky, later correcting a user talking about a remake, saying that it is a remaster.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp/app.bsky.feed.post/3lqptcfid4c2r" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreicz34dptjn7tp7r33oawxpzgbatmfnsp2gs4kikci4fu3zlx66wrq" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system">
<p lang="en">Remaster</p>
<p>— Jason Schreier (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp?ref_src=embed">@jasonschreier.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp/post/3lqptcfid4c2r?ref_src=embed">June 3, 2025 at 7:36 PM</a></p></blockquote>

<p>The Final Fantasy Tactics remaster has been rumored for a long time, and there's very little doubt that it is real and coming at some point. The game was originally revealed alongside a slew of other Square Enix projects via a massive <a href="https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-leak-lists-final-fantasy-vii-ix-remake-half-life-2-remastered-mgs2-hd-and-lots-more/">GeForce NOW leak</a>, and every leaked title from the publisher eventually turned out to be real, except for the Final Fantasy IX remake, which has yet to be announced, much like the Final Fantasy Tactics Remaster.</p>
<p>Despite rumors of its development making the rounds for years, we have no idea if the Final Fantasy Tactics remaster will be a simple remaster, or something in the vein of Tactics Ogre Reborn, which introduced a lot of gameplay changes that ultimately make the remaster a more enjoyable experience than the PSP release, as I highlighted in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/tactics-ogre-reborn-review/">review</a>. Hopefully, it won't take too long to learn more about this, and if one infamous character will end up making every other unit obsolete when he joins Ramza in his quest as he does in the original PlayStation release.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeForce Hotfix Display Driver 576.66 Fixes Crashes in Dune Awakening, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33, and EA Sports FC 25]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/geforce-hotfix-display-driver-576-66-fixes-crashes-in-dune-awakening-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-ea-sports-fc-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geforce-hotfix-display-driver-576-66-fixes-crashes-in-dune-awakening-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-ea-sports-fc-25.1206450/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/geforce-hotfix-display-driver-576-66-fixes-crashes-in-dune-awakening-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-ea-sports-fc-25/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A few hours ago, NVIDIA released a new GeForce Hotfix Display Driver (version 576.66). This hotfix resolves crashing issues in popular games that are already out, such as the football game EA Sports FC 25 and the turn-based JRPG <a href="https://wccftech.com/33-days-after-launch-clair-obscur-expedition-33-reaches-3-3-million-copies-sold/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, as well as the upcoming survival MMO-like game <a href="https://wccftech.com/dune-awakening-surprisingly-adds-private-servers-at-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dune Awakening</a>, which will officially launch on June 10 but will be playable starting tomorrow for those who purchased the Deluxe or Ultimate edition.</p>
<p>There are a couple more things in this GeForce Hotfix Display Driver release, as you can read from the official changelog:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dune: Awakening may crash during gameplay [5273568]</li>
<li>EA Sports FC 25 may crash during gameplay [5251937]</li>
<li>[RTX 50 series] Dragons Dogma 2 displays shadow flicker [5252205]</li>
<li>[RTX 50 series] Video playback in a web browser may show brief red/green flash corruption [5241341]</li>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 may crash [5283401]</li>
</ul>
<p>Unlike regular GeForce Game Ready drivers, a GeForce Hotfix Display Driver cannot be downloaded via GeForce Experience or the recently released NVIDIA app. You'll have to get it manually <a href="https://nvidia.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/5667" target="_blank" rel="noopener">from this support page on NVIDIA's website</a>. Of course, if you're not encountering those issues and/or are not playing those games, you can skip the download. It will be rolled into the next major GeForce Game Ready driver release anyway, which is probably not far off.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 System Software Update 25.04-11.40.00 is Now Live; Full Update Notes Inside]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-system-software-update-25-04-11-40-00/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-system-software-update-25-04-11-40-00-is-now-live-full-update-notes-inside.1206447/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-system-software-update-25-04-11-40-00/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new PlayStation 5 system software update is now available, bringing a small number of improvements to the system.</p>
<p>As a minor update, system software 25.04-11.40.00 doesn't introduce any major new features, focusing on improving message and usability on some screens, according to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/support/hardware/ps5/system-software-info/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official update notes</a> shared on the PlayStation official website. No other change or improvement is mentioned, so we will have to wait for the next update for the usual<a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-system-software-update-25-01-10-60-00/"> system stability improvements</a> often implemented in system software updates.</p>
<p>The latest major PlayStation 5 system software update went live back in April, bringing back the beloved PlayStation 30th anniversary UI some months after it went live and was later taken down when the 30th anniversary celebrations ended. The 25.03-11.20.00 also introduced the Audio Focus feature, a feature only available when using headphones that supports broader accessibility and allows players to hear quiet sounds and voice chat more clearly in games. Rounding up the changes and improvements introduced in the latest major update were the usual system software performance and stability improvements.</p>
<p>The new PlayStation 5 system software update 25.04-11.40.00 will be downloaded by the system automatically.&nbsp;<span>You can download the latest system software update&nbsp;<a href="https://pc.ps5.update.playstation.net/update/ps5/official/tJMRE80IbXnE9YuG0jzTXgKEjIMoabr6/image/2025_0529/sys_c81ab2031ccdaec9c83dcb1918d5051e3c6e988a5c6dba135cf238aa944072ed/PS5UPDATE.PUP" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here </a>if you want to update it manually</span>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stop right there, Oblivion Remastered modders have made the Imperial Watch a proper joinable faction with new quests and a corruption system for crimi]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stop-right-there-oblivion-remastered-modder-imperial-watch-proper-joinable-faction-new-quests-and-a-corruption-system</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stop-right-there-oblivion-remastered-modders-have-made-the-imperial-watch-a-proper-joinable-faction-with-new-quests-and-a-corruption-system-for-crimi.1206444/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stop-right-there-oblivion-remastered-modder-imperial-watch-proper-joinable-faction-new-quests-and-a-corruption-system<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bethesda/VG247</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion">Oblivion</a> is really a game about the Imperial Watch. Forget all the Mehrunes Dagon stuff and that Hero of Kvatch - the real stars of the show are the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-asks-please-tell-me-your-stupidest-oblivion-remastered-anecdotes-so-far">stupid</a> guards who pop out of the ether to tell you it’s time to pay the fine for your long list of misdeeds or head off to jail.</p>
<p>One <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remake">Oblivion Remastered</a> modder clearly feels the same way, as they’ve just fleshed out the Imperial Watch and Forestry divisions into joinable factions, via the addition of some new radiant quests and systems. These kinds of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oblivion-remastered-best-mods">mods</a> have become a bit of a hobby for the modder in question, ColdTyrant, and I <a href="https://www.vg247.com/oblivion-remastered-coldtyrant-modder-interview-evil-faction-quests">spoke to them about it</a> pretty recently.</p>
<!--more-->
<p><a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/4225?tab=description">The latest project</a> in their ‘Infinitum’ series of faction mods focuses on the Imperial Legion, and it looks like it offers a roleplaying experience I’ve been craving for years. You’re offered the choice by an NPC called Field Officer Leveilleur of becoming one of the potato-faced Imperial guards that patrol Cyrodiil or one of the rangers that help keep the wilderness in check.</p>
<p>The former is the option I’m most interested in, as it means you can earn gold and promotions by completing radiant arrest warrant quests. These task you with hunting down wanted criminals, stopping them in their criminal scummy ways, and demanding they make the infamous decision that’s usually facing your character - come quietly or resist arrest. Hilariously, the wording of what you say to them is exactly the same, so you can properly embrace the memeiness of your new vocation.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, folks who choose forestry are tasked with hunting down bandits at randomly selected camps. The mod doesn’t leave it there, also giving you the chance to go a bit bad and abuse your guardly powers. Both branches render you able to impose fines on the regular citizens of Cyrodiil, and if you want, you can extort them for money like a certain Ulrich of Cheydinhal.</p>
<p>ColdTyrant’s created a system to track this, which I’ll let them explain: “If you choose to do this, your Corruption Level will increase by 10 for each illegally-demanded fine, and the game will inform you of your current Corruption level whenever it increases or decreases.</p>
<p>“If you really go out of control, and manage to reach a Corruption Level of 100, you will be permanently expelled from The Imperial Legion. This will remove any pending warrants or bounties, strip you of your ranks, and remove all Imperial Legion Infinitum content from the game, as well as slam you with an extremely heavy bounty.” So yup, another stat to try and max out if you’re a morally ambiguous completionist.</p>
<p>Don’t worry, though, the modder adds that you can gradually get back on the good path by going back to lawfully arresting and bounty hunting. If you want to give the mod a go, you’ll need to grab <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/32">UE4SS</a> and the <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/1272">TesSyncMapInjector</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[God of War 2.5D Metroidvania Spin-off Could Be Announced Today]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-2-5d-metroidvania-spin-off-could-be-announced-today/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/god-of-war-2-5d-metroidvania-spin-off-could-be-announced-today.1206441/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-2-5d-metroidvania-spin-off-could-be-announced-today/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://x.com/_Tom_Henderson_/status/1929890398236774904" target="_blank" rel="noopener">According</a> to insider Tom Henderson, Sony might announce a new God of War game later today during the <a href="https://wccftech.com/40-minute-playstation-state-of-play-announced-for-tomorrow/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">State of Play live stream</a>. However, this won't be the next installment in the main series; on the other hand, the report says it will be a 2.5D Metroidvania-inspired game set in ancient Greece. Henderson even added that it sounds smaller scale than he previously thought, so don't expect a sizable experience.</p>
<p>Still, it could be an interesting one, not unlike Ubisoft's Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown. That game was successful among critics (it <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-who-needs-sands-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">earned</a> a 9/10 score here on Wccftech) and fans, but it <a href="https://wccftech.com/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-sequel-isnt-happening-due-to-low-sales-ubisoft-disbanded-the-team/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">did not sell enough to warrant a sequel.</a> In the case of God of War, it might be a stopgap release while Sony Santa Monica is busy with something else.</p>
<p>As far as we know, they have two main teams, and their next release from Cory Barlog's team is <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-developer-might-be-making-a-new-ip/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rumored</a> to be a new IP, possibly set in a sci-fi universe. Of course, there will eventually be a new mainline God of War game, but it wouldn't be too surprising if it only arrived on PlayStation 6, given the increasingly long development times of a triple-A game.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, there were also <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-greek-saga-remasters-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rumors</a> that Sony Santa Monica would be remastering the Greek trilogy. It is unclear whether that was indeed true and the announcement has been delayed, or perhaps insiders got slightly misleading information and their sources were referring to this 2.5D Metroidvania spin-off instead. Regardless, we should learn more about it in around twelve hours or so.</p>
<p>As a reminder, the developer is also <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-series-officially-coming-from-amazon-prime-video/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">working</a> with Amazon Prime Video on a live action TV series adaptation of the Norse trilogy. However, production was delayed due to a major change: showrunner Rafe Judkins was <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-series-starts-from-scratch-with-battlestar-galactica-for-all-mankind-producer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">replaced</a> by Ronald D. Moore, who is credited for Star Trek: Next Generation, Battlestar Galactica, For All Mankind, and Outlander.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Invisible Inc spiritual successor Cyber Knights: Flashpoint has released from early access]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/invisible-inc-spiritual-successor-cyber-knights-flashpoint-has-released-from-early-access</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/invisible-inc-spiritual-successor-cyber-knights-flashpoint-has-released-from-early-access.1206429/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/invisible-inc-spiritual-successor-cyber-knights-flashpoint-has-released-from-early-access<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>One of the cyberpunk nicknames in the trailer is 'Kindle'</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Trese Brothers</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I currently do not have time to play <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cyber-knights-flashpoint">Cyber Knights: Flashpoint</a>, the game Katherine (RPS in peace) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-spiritual-successor-to-invisible-inc-is-finally-here">called </a> a "spiritual successor" to (unbelievably good stealth tactics game) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/invisible-inc">Invisible Inc</a>. So, I'm writing about its release from early access as a sort of vicarious joy substitute. Because, boy, does it tick several big honking megaboxes for me. The idea is that you'll be pulling off cyberpunky heists with a squad of mercs, planning and executing while keeping the future fuzz off your backs. There's also lots of dense <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> multiclassing stuff I'll talk about in a second. Here's a launch trailer.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Cyber Knights: Flashpoint - Official Full Launch Trailer - Squad Tactics Heist RPG!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bzToChIOp2A?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Cyber Knights: Flashpoint - Official Full Launch Trailer - Squad Tactics Heist RPG!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bzToChIOp2A?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bzToChIOp2A?autoplay=1" title="Cyber Knights: Flashpoint - Official Full Launch Trailer - Squad Tactics Heist RPG!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bzToChIOp2A" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"A modern tactical RPG with some of our favorite elements: gridless movement, environmental cover, specialized overwatch, initiative manipulation and more," begins the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1021210/Cyber_Knights_Flashpoint/">Steam description</a>. More of this, please. Don't tell me how immersed I'll be in your visceral yet cerebral yet emotional journey that represents a bold evolution of (genre). Tell me about the specific (genre) design you're personally into and are very excited about having shoved into your game. There's more. Customisable weapons. Faction reputation. 40 multiclass combinations. A variety of admirable hairdos. There's even some <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/deus-ex">Deus Ex</a> Human Revolution style hacking minigames.</p>
<p>I am chuffed this exists, evidently, although I am just trailer-gawking. For a more sober and detailed take, do read <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rally-point-cyber-knights-flashpoint-is-both-worth-playing-and-worth-waiting-for-a-little-longer">Sin's Rally Point on the game</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The design goal is, I think, to represent stealth as vital, but not the entirety of your tactics. If you're feeling spicy you can hit a job loud, counting on speed and firepower over waiting for the sentry to chase the shiny penny. Almost all gunfights should feature rolling, repositioning, moving towards a target or shooting your way out before reinforcements catch up. Rather than a stealth/combat binary there's room for degrees of both, sometimes simultaneously.</p></blockquote>
<p>Bah! I am already <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/battle-prose">managing one party of mercs regularly</a>, but it now seems like I'll need to make room in my life for another.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Glory Holes Of Oblivion lets your weapons and spells fire through gates]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/glory-holes-of-oblivion-lets-your-weapons-and-spells-fire-through-gates</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/glory-holes-of-oblivion-lets-your-weapons-and-spells-fire-through-gates.1206426/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/glory-holes-of-oblivion-lets-your-weapons-and-spells-fire-through-gates<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>and also lets your enemies do the same</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bethesda/Virtuos</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/4010">Glory Holes Of Oblivion</a> is an <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remake">Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a> mod that lets you shoot arrows and cast spells through holes in gates, and also allows your enemies to do the same. Cheers <a href="https://www.exresearch.co/">Ex Research</a> for the spot. NexusMods lists Glory Holes Of Oblivion as containing 'adult content'. This is surely because they're not scholars of glassblowing or drawers. More on this in a second. First, here's a good skeleton demonstrating the use of the mod.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>electionis</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Right: etymology time, buckaroos. Whoop whoop. This is a good one, too. The <a href="https://www.etymonline.com/word/glory%20hole">original meaning </a>of the term 'glory hole' seems to be "a drawer or box where things are heaped together in a disorderly manner". This pleases me because I've spent my entire life just calling them 'stuff drawers". I have one to my right as I'm typing this. It contains: Post-it notes, batteries, guitar picks, a single micro USB cord, Hall's Soothers, some screws, and a small remote for a lamp I'll never use because I only like one of its changeable hues. According to the (single, repeated around the internet a lot, might be therefore be bollocks) source, the use of 'glory' here likely comes from the Scottish 'glaur' - "to make muddy, dirty, defile".</p>
<p>Yes, skeleton. I'll be with you in a second.</p>
<p>For our next glorious fact, you need to pop yourself over to the 1849 book <a href="https://www.google.co.uk/books/edition/Curiosities_of_Glass_Making/OI80AQAAMAAJ">Curiosities of Glass Making (With Details of the Processes and Productions of Ancient and Modern Ornamental Glass Manufacture)</a>. On page 65, you'll find an illustration of today's subject, described as "the mouth of a pot heated by beech-wood, and called the Glory Hole". This was used to reheat large objects following the processing of 'annealing', or slowly cooling to remove internal stresses. According to our first source, this likely comes from a different  'glory' - which had come to suggest a "circle or ring of light" by the 1690s.</p>
<p>As for modernity, its earliest recorded usage is in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glory_hole#History">a 1707 court case</a>, with the rise of the glory hole coinciding with the need to be discreet in a society that simply refused to be normal about queer people. Luckily, things are fine now, providing you eat this delicious meal of black mould J.K Rowling has prepared for you like it's the introduction to Resident Evil 7, and ask absolutely no follow up questions.</p>
<p>None of this information is, I imagine, factored into this mod. But this means little to the skeleton, who is still doomed. Lmao.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Strange Antiquities is the first game in a while that treats magical objects like magical objects]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/strange-antiquities-is-the-first-game-in-a-while-that-treats-magical-objects-like-magical-objects</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/strange-antiquities-is-the-first-game-in-a-while-that-treats-magical-objects-like-magical-objects.1206423/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/strange-antiquities-is-the-first-game-in-a-while-that-treats-magical-objects-like-magical-objects<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>We do not sell McGuffins in this store</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Iceberg Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I need help identifying an Ossic Ring. Whatever an Ossic Ring is, it's related to a serpent goddess and is great at keeping away vermin. Legend holds that you can hear it hissing. I'm not sure if the Ossic Ring is an actual ring, and if so, whether it's a ring for your finger or a ring necklace or a ring design found on something unhelpfully nonringular.</p>
<p>With time running short (I am playing the demo for Bad Viking's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/strange-antiquities">Strange Antiquities</a> on the train), I grab weird knick knacks from my shelves at random and thrust them imperiously at the customer. Perhaps this berringed corpse's hand? No? How about this iron band enclosing a blue crystal tear? I get it wrong three times in a row and my character's brain saturates with Dread. To dispel the Dread, I must play a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Farkle">farkle</a>-style dice game, matching faces to sigils before my soul collapses. Ah, this is just like recommending guest beers at the gastropub I worked in before getting my first job in the shitpost business. Do Strange Ales next, Bad Viking.</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Strange Antiquities - Gameplay Reveal" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5YravLrvr6o?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Strange Antiquities - Gameplay Reveal</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5YravLrvr6o?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/5YravLrvr6o?autoplay=1" title="Strange Antiquities - Gameplay Reveal">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5YravLrvr6o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>As you may guess from the title, Strange Antiquities is essentially 2022's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/strange-horticulture">Strange Horticulture</a> but you are running a magic antiquarian store rather than a magic garden centre. I haven't played much of Strange Horticulture, but the broad strokes of Strange Antiquities seem identical to those of the verdant puzzler Alice B (RPS in peace) described as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/strange-horticulture-review">"quiet, meticulous, delightful, dark, and beguiling"</a>. Ding the bell and customers materialise from the green streets of Undermere to ask for a particular item - a bony emblem to aid with the hunt, for example, or a Moon Heart to provide solace for a lonely grandmother. You then work out which of your initially unlabelled commodities fits the bill.</p>
<p>First, you look up the name in an illustrated antiquarian's guide. Then you try to find an artefact that has the right shape, texture, material composition, temperature, smell, sound and psychic resonance. Perhaps you also refer to your book of symbols, which is otherwise used when writing labels. According to Alice B, there was a reward in Strange Horticulture for labelling things very precisely, and I imagine the same is true here.</p>
<p>The appeal of Strange Antiquities, for me, is that it cuts against the disposability of so-called magical artefacts in many other games. Today's RPG-flavoured free-to-play or live service offerings especially are larded with eldritch geegaws, frou-frous and doodads that exist to be fed continually into progression systems. They are glittering sequins on the face of a slot machine.</p>
<p>Strange Antiquities wants you to run curious hands over every dusty Ascendant Shard or poundshop Holy Grail and diagnose its aura. There's a patent loveliness to this. Between sales, you'll also investigate the interior of the shop, which is full of locked compartments and peculiar mechanisms. As in Horticulture, there's a wider world to glean from customer requests, troubled dreams, and expeditions to recover artefacts that take place on a paper map.</p>
<p>My chief criticism, I guess, is that the occult elements don't feel very occluded. Yes, you have to figure out the lore, but there's no doubt that everything in stock is a potential Lament Configuration. I think the game would be more engrossing if the objects at your disposal appeared mostly or entirely devoid of supernatural import, and you had to impose and cultivate those associations by striving to fulfil orders. But that would be a very different game. This one will probably be quite enchanting enough if you adored Horticulture. The demo launches on 5th June. Find out more on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2885870/Strange_Antiquities/">Steam</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As if sweary Darth Vader wasn't enough, Fortnite developer Epic will soon be letting players create their own "AI-powered NPCs"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/as-if-sweary-darth-vader-wasnt-enough-fortnite-developer-epic-will-soon-be-letting-players-create-their-own-ai-powered-npcs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/as-if-sweary-darth-vader-wasnt-enough-fortnite-developer-epic-will-soon-be-letting-players-create-their-own-ai-powered-npcs.1206420/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/as-if-sweary-darth-vader-wasnt-enough-fortnite-developer-epic-will-soon-be-letting-players-create-their-own-ai-powered-npcs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Oh boy. Remember the AI-voiced Darth Vader NPC Epic recently added to Fortnite? The one that very quickly had to patched because it wouldn't stop <a href="https://www.vg247.com/fortnite-darth-vader-ai-chatbot-why-does-this-exist">saying bad words</a>, and has since become the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/video-game-voice-actor-union-takes-fortnites-darth-vader-chatbot-to-court">subject of action</a> from the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sag-aftra">SAG-AFTRA</a> union? Well, it'll be getting some AI NPC siblings later this year, with Epic planning to give creators the tools to create their own.</p>
<p>AI Vader, which was created in collaboration with the family of actor James Earl Jones, got its own streamer reaction montage at the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AjikvaR0i34">State of Unreal showcase</a> during which these upcoming AI NPC tools were announced - one that naturally didn't feature any of the clips of it swearing or saying slurs.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>"As game developers, our job is to entertain players and AI is ultimately a tool to make games more fun and immersive," said Epic's Fortnite ecosystem EVP Saxs Persson, "It enables infinite possibilities for two-way dialogue just like we saw with Darth Vader, and as the next step we want to take what we've learned and share the underlying technology with you."</p>
<p>In practice, players will mess around with a new "Persona Device" to create AI NPCs, picking the type of voice and delivery they want for the character, as well as its "characteristics". This was demoed on stage via an AI NPC taking on the role of "a mysterious cosmic entity named Mr Buttons", tasked with persuading the player to press a big red button with "comedic finesse". It'd have earned surreal points with me was I not a bit preoccupied with the ethics of using AI to voice NPCs.</p>
<p>After all, this is just the latest chapter in the ongoing debate over the ethics of using generative AI for voice acting. The aforementioned SAG-AFTRA and a host of voice actors have opposed it, arguing that it poses a potential threat to human VAs' livelihoods, with the union having called a strike that's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/following-the-nightmare-footage-of-ai-loy-horizon-actor-ashly-burch-shares-her-stance-on-the-whole-debacle">still ongoing</a> as of writing. SAG-AFTRA, meanwhile, has <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/actors-union-sag-aftra-strike-deal-to-allow-ai-voice-replicas-and-video-game-stars-are-understandably-pissed">drawn some criticism</a> of its own for striking deals with a companies which employ generative AI.</p>
<p>I'd say being sworn at by Darth Vader isn't that immersive. Then again, I struggle to get too hung up on immersion in games that can see you be 360 no-scoped by Mace Windu, who then promptly hits the griddy and gets obliterated by the OP combat skills of Sabrina Carpenter or a sentinent banana. If you want a more nuanced, in-depth view on the genAI in games debate, it's worth checking out Michael Cook's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/electric-nightmares">Electric Nightmares essay series</a> on the issue.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jagex Announces Layoffs, Pauses RuneScape ‘Project Zanaris’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/jagex-announces-layoffs-pauses-runescape-project-zanaris/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jagex-announces-layoffs-pauses-runescape-%E2%80%98project-zanaris%E2%80%99.1206417/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/jagex-announces-layoffs-pauses-runescape-project-zanaris/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>British developer Jagex announced a round of layoffs. Community Manager JagexHooli <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/runescape/comments/1l1fut4/comment/mvkxroe/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> it earlier this week with the following Reddit comment:</p>
<p><em>Yes, there have unfortunately been job reductions at Jagex. These have been made as part of changes in a company restructure as Jagex puts more emphasis on RuneScape games and community growth. The majority of roles are from non-game dev and non-player facing areas. There are some exceptions within the RS team as part the company's focus on a streamlined development approach.</em></p>
<p><em>I’m sure many of you are concerned about what this means for RuneScape 3. This is not a change in direction from what Mod North has said before – we are still committed to growing this game and investing in it. Our Roadmap won’t change because of these job reductions, and we’ll continue the great path we’ve been on with our content. We will talk to you about this when the time is right.</em></p>
<p><em>What matters most right now are the people affected by this change. The studio’s focus is to support those affected, as is mine. Now is the time we put them first and do everything we can to help them out.</em></p>
<p>At the same time, work on 'Project Zanaris', whose objective was to allow private servers for Old School RuneScape, has been paused. On this note, Jagex <a href="https://secure.runescape.com/m=news/pausing-project-zanaris--whats-next?oldschool=1#_ga=2.197087977.499468828.1749024097-1248850839.1749024095" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a>:</p>
<p><em>After careful consideration, we've decided to pause work on Zanaris indefinitely. We're committed to delivering the best possible Old School RuneScape experience. With a renewed focus and continued support from our incredible team, we're excited to keep making OSRS even better for everyone.</em></p>
<p><em>We understand that feelings around the project were mixed, and many of the concerns raised were fair. The truth is, there are other areas of the core Old School experience that deserve more attention right now. While Zanaris was ambitious and innovative, it wouldn't have met expectations until much later in development. Rather than stretch our focus, we want to prioritise the things that matter most to you today.</em></p>
<p>Jagex recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/runescape-dragonwilds-has-suddenly-launched-on-steam-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> RuneScape: Dragonwilds, a survival cooperative multiplayer game, on Steam Early Access. According to Steam data, it was purchased by 550K, 789K, or 842K users, depending on the analytics website (VG Insights, Gamalytic, PlayTracker).</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Scarlet and Violet's Switch 2 Upgrade Is Massive – and it Bodes Well for Legends Z-A]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-scarlet-and-violets-switch-2-upgrade-is-massive-and-it-bodes-well-for-legends-z-a</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-scarlet-and-violets-switch-2-upgrade-is-massive-%E2%80%93-and-it-bodes-well-for-legends-z-a.1206393/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-scarlet-and-violets-switch-2-upgrade-is-massive-and-it-bodes-well-for-legends-z-a<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch 2’s launch is imminent, and with it, free Switch 2 updates for more than ten existing games from the original Switch’s library. A pair of these are Pokémon Scarlet and Pokémon Violet, which are pretty widely criticized for their relatively poor performance on the Switch. I got to play the newly updated Pokémon Scarlet on the Nintendo Switch 2 for thirty minutes, and the Switch 2 upgrades are <em>incredibly</em> clear. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/gaming-systems/switch-2/transfer-guide/games-with-free-updates/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>official Nintendo website</u></a> says the free Switch 2 updates for Pokémon Scarlet and Pokémon Violet include: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>“Visuals: Optimized for the Nintendo Switch 2 display and high-resolution TVs for improved image quality.”</li><li>“Frame rate: Improved for smoother movement on Nintendo Switch 2.”</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">The vague description definitely put me off at first, but now I know Pokémon Scarlet and Pokémon Violet on the Nintendo Switch 2 run in 4K at 60FPS. Or, at least, those are the settings–I didn’t have the equipment to measure if that 60FPS is indeed steady–but by the naked eye, I can still recognize it as markedly improved. As soon as I loaded into the game, on a huge 4K TV, I was stunned by how nice everything looked. No jagged pixelated edges on blades of grass, or even Pokémon, here. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Switch 2 updates have also increased the number of Pokémon that can appear on screen, and from a further distance. For instance, flying over Casseroya Lake on the Switch 2 was a drastically different experience compared to on the Switch: I saw numerous Pokémon swim along the surface from a distance and didn’t experience any noticeable stuttering once I began to swim. Even when it began to rain, Pokémon Scarlet on the Switch 2 still didn’t struggle even a little. In fact, it continued playing like normal, as if the weather effects were meant to just… work. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Even when it began to rain, Pokémon Scarlet on the Switch 2 still didn’t struggle even a little.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The framerate improvements are especially immediately obvious when viewing faraway moving objects, like the windmills by West Province (Area One) - Central, or distant Pokémon and people. I also didn’t experience stalling or glitches when in a raid battle or when Terastalizing. I didn’t get to play online or co-op, however, so we’ve yet to see if the updates improved those aspects (that desperately need it.) </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Visuals are subjective, so there’s only so much I can say to emphasize that the difference is certainly noticeable, but you can watch the comparison video on this page.  I can also report on some favorable loading time comparisons that will let you judge for yourself. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">These approximate comparisons are between Pokémon Violet running on a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/nintendo-switch/Nintendo_Switch_Longer_Battery_Release_Date_and_Model_Details"><u>V2 Switch</u></a> (the Monster Hunter Rise special edition, specifically) in 1080p, and Pokémon Scarlet running on a brand new Nintendo Switch 2 in 4K. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Loading from title screen:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Switch: </strong>19 seconds</li><li><strong>Switch 2: </strong>5 seconds </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Fast travel from North Province (Area One) to Casseroya Lake:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Switch: </strong>9 seconds</li><li><strong>Switch 2: </strong>4 seconds</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Fast travel from Blueberry Academy to Paldea: </strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Switch: </strong>17 seconds </li><li><strong>Switch 2: </strong>5 seconds</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Besides the fast travel loading time improvements, the menus are also <em>so</em> much snappier. Models in menus load in pretty much immediately, a stark contrast to the agonizing seconds you’d have to wait on the original Switch between trying on clothes in the menu; or hairstyles or accessories in stores. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/pokmon-scarlet-and-pokmon-violet-nintendo-switch-2-screenshot-1-1748992124427.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Nintendo Switch 2 screenshot.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">To be completely honest, the performance of these games didn’t prevent me from enjoying them the first time around. I still appreciated the new open-world format, more fleshed-out characters, and never-before-seen new Pokémon friends, lag be damned. I certainly was frustrated enough that I avoided switching out Pokémon because of how <em>long</em> it took, sure, but overall, Pokémon Scarlet and Violet were fun for me regardless. However, now that I’ve played it on the Switch 2, the performance and visual issues of the original are certainly less ignorable, and thankfully I never need to play it on an original Switch again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To neatly sum it up, Rebekah Valentine in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-scarlet-and-violet-review"><u>IGN’s original Pokémon Scarlet and Pokémon Violet review</u></a> said: “Let’s talk about the Donphan in the room here: these games run like garbage.”  </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/pokmon-scarlet-and-pokmon-violet-nintendo-switch-2-screenshot-2-1748992154761.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Nintendo Switch 2 screenshot.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This, I’m relieved to say, isn’t the case on the Switch 2. Sure, they’re still not perfect–I did experience <em>one</em> stutter when dashing on Koraidon, and there are still texture issues and texture pop-ins–but the visuals and performance are far from garbage. They’re so much better, in fact, that I’m tempted to say the free Switch 2 updates are closer to a <em>light </em>remaster than just an optimization – even though it really should’ve just run better to begin with. I’m that impressed, but to be fair, I <em>did</em> go in with somewhat low expectations–how much better could a simple update make a game that ran with so many issues in 1080p on the original Switch?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just how well Scarlet runs on the Switch 2 makes me question if this iteration of Pokémon was planned for the Switch 2 all along. The update does this much and is <em>free? Suspicious. </em></p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Conspiracy theories aside, if the performance of Scarlet and Violet on the original Switch turned you off from playing, it’s absolutely worth giving them another shot on the Switch 2. I’m certainly going to go back and play more of the Indigo Disk DLC with these updates intact. These games are right at home on the Switch 2 and feel like they should have been here all along, and this gives me so much hope for the performance of the Switch 2 version of Pokémon Legends: Z-A later this year. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">These were my first impressions from just thirty minutes of hands-on play, so there could certainly be issues I missed or that reveal themselves later, but I encountered <em>significantly </em>less issues in these thirty minutes on the Switch 2 compared to the thirty minutes on the original Switch I spent capturing the comparison footage. You’ll be able to see the differences between the Pokémon Scarlet and Pokémon Violet Switch versions for yourself once the free updates are out on June 5, alongside the launch of the Switch 2. Simply connect your Switch 2 to the internet and perform a system update to download free updates.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ll also begin a mini review update for Pokémon Scarlet and Violet on the Switch 2, so look out for that evaluation after playing for longer in the near future! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you do decide to jump into Paldea on the Switch 2, don’t miss our thorough <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-scarlet-violet"><u>Pokémon Scarlet and Pokémon Violet Guide</u></a>, with a handy <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-scarlet-violet/Walkthrough"><u>Scarlet and Violet golden-path walkthrough</u></a>, a complete <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-scarlet-violet/Pokedex_-_All_Pokemon_in_Scarlet_and_Violet"><u>Scarlet and Violet Pokédex</u></a>, and more. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Casey DeFreitas is a deputy editor on the guides team at IGN who has always loved Pokémon. Catch her on socials @ShinyCaseyD</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phasmophobia Movie Coming From Blumhouse To Haunt Theaters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/phasmophobia-movie-coming-from-blumhouse-to-haunt-theaters/1100-6532047/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phasmophobia-movie-coming-from-blumhouse-to-haunt-theaters.1206378/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/phasmophobia-movie-coming-from-blumhouse-to-haunt-theaters/1100-6532047/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532047">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/phasmophobia/" data-ref-id="5000-509328">Phasmophobia</a>, the popular ghosthunting sim from Kinetic Games, is being turned into a horror movie. The film is coming from Blumhouse, a production company that has made a great number of horror movies in recent years, including Five Nights at Freddy's, Paranormal Activity, The Purge, and Insidious, among many more. James Wan's company, Atomic Monster, is also attached to the project.</p><p>The game studio's director and lead developer, Daniel Knight, said in a press release that the team is "thrilled" to announce the movie is in the works. "We never could’ve imagined the incredible heights this game would reach when it launched five years ago, and we’re so thankful to our amazing community for the lasting impact Phasmophobia has had in the gaming space and beyond," Knight continued. "Working with Blumhouse and Atomic Monster marks an incredible new chapter for the game, and we can’t wait to share more as the project develops."</p><p>Phasmophobia launched as a Steam Early Access game in 2020 and quickly became a hit for friend groups looking for a fun (and terrifying) co-op game during the pandemic. It's gone on to sell more than 22 million copies, and last year debuted on Xbox and PlayStation.</p><p>The next major update for the game is called Chronicle and seeks to overhaul the game's leveling system and in-game rewards. Sometime next year, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/for-phasmophobia-to-be-so-terrifying-the-devil-is-in-the-details/1100-6527456/" data-ref-id="1100-6527456">already-frightening game</a> is meant to get even scarier with its Horror 2.0 update.</p><p>No release window for the Phasmophobia movie was announced, and it's worth noting that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/video-game-movies-in-the-works/2900-5059/" data-ref-id="2900-5059">video game movies get announced</a> much more often than they get made. However, given the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/five-nights-at-freddys-movie-succeeded-beyond-my-wildest-dreams-creator-says/1100-6518853/" data-ref-id="1100-6518853">Five Nights at Freddy's movie's success</a>, one could argue Blumhouse knows how to get these projects to the finish line--a sequel to that one is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/five-nights-at-freddys-2-gets-a-creepy-new-teaser-image/1100-6532000/" data-ref-id="1100-6532000">set to arrive later this year</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Violet and Scarlet’s Switch 2 update is as good as it looks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/679031/pokemon-violet-scarlet-switch-2-update-hands-on</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-violet-and-scarlet%E2%80%99s-switch-2-update-is-as-good-as-it-looks.1206375/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/679031/pokemon-violet-scarlet-switch-2-update-hands-on<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>I recently did something sort of unusual: I went to a preview event for a game that’s been out for almost three years.</p><p>I’ve played around 400 hours of <em>Pokémon Scarlet</em>, according to my Nintendo Switch, since it was released in late 2022. It’s safe to say I know the game pretty well. And yet, when I was invited to preview <em>Pokémon Scarlet</em> and <em>Violet</em> on <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/638604/nintendo-switch-2-direct-news-trailers-stream">the Nintendo Switch 2 ahead of the new console’s launch</a>, I gladly took the opportunity to see three-year-old games I already own. I wanted to find out just how much they’d improved.</p><p>I have a high jank tolerance with games — it builds character — but I’m well aware of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23462858/pokemon-violet-scarlet-review-nintendo-switch"><em>Scarlet</em> and <em>Violet</em>’s shortcomings on the original Switch</a>. There’s lag. The frame rate is… inconsistent. There are online connectivity issues. For a lot of people, performance problems overshadowed what was otherwise a great new generation of <em>Pokémon </em>games. With the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/653010/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-tips-tricks-release-date-price-availability-how-to-buy">release of the Nintendo Switch 2</a>, and the accompanying free performance update for <em>Scarlet</em> and <em>Violet</em>, that might finally change.</p><p>Starting up the demo of <em>Pokémon Scarlet</em> on the Switch 2 at The Pokémon Company International’s office in Bellevue, Washington, I knew immediately where I wanted to go first: Casseroya Lake, sometimes called “Lag Lake,” where the games’ graphical issues are most apparent. On the original Switch, the game <em>really</em> chugs when you’re on the lake; the frame rate takes a dive, and it struggles to render more than a handful of pokémon in your immediate vicinity. Exploring the liveliest open areas and encountering the pokémon that populate them is one of <em>Scarlet</em> and <em>Violet</em>’s biggest strengths, but on the Switch, Casseroya Lake is dull and empty at best and impossible to navigate at worst.</p><p>Playing on the Switch 2, however, Casseroya Lake ran beautifully. There were far more pokémon in view (and I was immediately accosted by a torpedo-like Veluza, same as it ever was), and the lag and stuttering I’d come to expect were nonexistent. I battled that Veluza with no problems. I stumbled upon a Slowpoke outbreak and sent out my Clodsire to auto-battle them — no lag. I found a wild Tera Pokémon and watched the Tera animation play out, looking sharper than I’d ever seen it. (I was playing in docked mode at a station set up by TPCi, so maybe that last one could be credited to the TV. But still.)</p><p>It was the same case everywhere I went during my 30-minute demo: a stable and smooth frame rate, significantly faster load times, and far more pokémon populating the world. The Switch 2 update is not a complete overhaul of the graphics themselves — the grass textures looked just as unremarkable as always to my eye, for example — but it does seem to eliminate the performance issues that have dragged <em>Scarlet</em> and <em>Violet</em> down for nearly three years. It’s a noticeable improvement in the world, in battle, in Tera raids, and even in menus.</p><p>Is it praiseworthy for a game to simply run well? Maybe not. I don’t pretend to know how games are made on a technical level, or really any level, but I know they’re not <em>easy</em> to make. And I had enough fun with <em>Pokémon Scarlet</em> to play for 400 hours without the performance issues bothering me much. But it did feel bittersweet, briefly, to think how much more these games could have shone if they’d run well in the first place. </p><p>Then, in the last five minutes of my demo, as I waded in a different body of water to confirm that it too ran smoothly, I saw it: among the pods of Buizel dotting the shore, a shiny. </p><p>A good portion of my 400 hours in <em>Scarlet</em> were spent shiny hunting, because even though the alternate-color versions of pokémon are not quite as hard to find as they were in previous games, I get excited every time I see one, without fail. It’s the perfect encapsulation of the kind of joy <em>Scarlet </em>and <em>Violet</em> have to offer: exploring a lively area and finding something special. I caught the shiny Buizel despite knowing that it wasn’t my save file and not mine to keep.</p><p>The Switch 2 update is arguably arriving a bit late for my <em>Scarlet</em> save file, depending on how many hours you think are reasonable to spend playing this game. But I also own <em>Violet</em>, and I have played about two hours of that version total. Looking at the shiny Buizel I didn’t get to keep, I realized I was really excited to have a reason to play <em>Violet</em> finally — to rediscover what I liked most about these games, in a state that does them justice.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 4: The People, Places, and Secrets of the Tech Demo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-4-the-people-places-and-secrets-of-the-tech-demo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-4-the-people-places-and-secrets-of-the-tech-demo.1206327/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-4-the-people-places-and-secrets-of-the-tech-demo<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">In a huge reveal at this week’s Unreal Fest Orlando, Epic Games and developer CD Projekt Red showcased a technical demonstration of The Witcher 4. Built in Unreal Engine 5 using many of the latest tools and technologies, it offers a window into the future of The Witcher; not just in terms of what Ciri’s saga will (hopefully) look like, but also the people we’ll meet, the places we’ll go, and the general vibe of the game we’ll one day get our hands on. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There was plenty to see in the 14 minutes of demonstration footage, so we’re here to break it down with the help of CD Projekt Red and Epic Games. Here are the 10 most important things we’ve learned about The Witcher 4 and its new tech demo. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/1-1748994597533.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">1. The Demo is Not Gameplay</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The demo we saw was played live on stage by CD Projekt Red’s Cinematic Director, Kajetan Kapuściński. But while Kapuściński was literally moving Ciri around the game world, the studio is keen to emphasise that the demo is not a true slice of the game. While the mountain region, forest, and port town you saw will be part of The Witcher 4, the quest being played and the characters Ciri interacts with may not be featured in the final game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As Kapuściński explains to me, this “was a demo that [CD Projekt Red and Epic Games] crafted so both companies can work on some technology that will be powering The Witcher 4 in the future. So it's not gameplay of The Witcher 4, per se.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So if it’s not gameplay, what can we learn from it? “It shows our artistic direction and how we would like to approach some things,” Kapuściński explains. And so everything you see – the scope of the world, the density of the foliage, the way Ciri and NPCs react to each other, and how cinematic cutscenes blend with the interactive parts – is CD Project Red’s ambition. It’s how the studio currently envisions the game and what the team is working towards.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“But everything you saw is subject to be changed, because that is a snippet of what we have now,” Kapuściński says. In short, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-4-tech-demo-does-not-fully-represent-the-final-game-cd-projekt-clarifies-visuals-reflect-the-direction-were-taking">this is not a full representation of the final version of The Witcher 4</a>. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/2-1748994615376.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">2. Will The Witcher 4 Look Like That?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The visual quality of this tech demo is astonishing, but we’ve been here before. Many people will remember the first footage of The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt or Cyberpunk 2077, which turned out to be more ambitious, at least visually, than the final product. In The Witcher 4’s case, it’s especially easy to be skeptical, as this demonstration was running on a regular PlayStation 5 (not even a PS5 Pro!) at 60 frames per second. I asked Wyeth Johnson, Senior Director of Product Strategy at Epic Games, if this quality was genuinely something players could expect to experience on a base PS5. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Oh absolutely. We can't lie here,” he says. “I mean the technology that we're making has to be directly relevant for what players expect, and players across the entire hardware spectrum are asking for amazing 60 frames per second gameplay.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The new advancements in Unreal Engine 5.6 are allowing developers to run complex tech more efficiently. As explained in <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/news/unreal-engine-5-6-is-now-available" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">an Unreal blog post</a>, “The Hardware Ray Tracing (HWRT) system enhancements are designed to deliver even greater performance for Lumen Global Illumination. By eliminating key CPU bottlenecks, you can author more complex scenes while maintaining a smoother 60 FPS frame rate.” The promise of all this is that the experiences that are currently typically locked behind a 30 frames-per-second ‘Quality’ mode will be available at 60fps – all without requiring new hardware. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The goal that we set at the very beginning, to make this demo and play it live on a standard PlayStation 5 in 60 frames per second, that was a challenge on its own,” says Kapuściński. “And pushing towards that allowed us to achieve these optimizations that allow us to use technology on a bigger scale.”</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/3-1748994636968.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">3. We're Headed North. Very North</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The technical demo takes place in Kovir, a region in the very north of The Continent, the world in which The Witcher takes place. It’s situated north-west of the lands of Redania and Temeria, locations you’ll be familiar with from The Witcher 3. Its mountainous terrain is resource-rich, and so mining is one of the kingdom’s key industries. Kovir is the world’s leading exporter of minerals, and among those minerals is salt; you’ll have noticed that Ciri’s quest in this demonstration is to investigate a salt merchant’s missing cargo. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans of The Witcher books have waited a long time to visit Kovir, but creating it for a video game is no easy task. As Game Director Sebastian Kalemba explained as part of the demonstration, “So much of The Witcher world is natural, organic, especially Kovir with its dense forests and wild nature.” The Witcher 3 featured some grand woodland environments that remain impressive even 10 years later, but the forest shown in this demo is a league ahead of them. It stretches as far as the eye can see, with detailed pine trees creating a blanket of green through the mountain’s ravine. Both vertically and horizontally, there’s an astonishing amount of foliage detail. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I think for the Witcher franchise, the forest is definitely the soul of the game,” says Charles Tremblay, VP of Technology at CD Projekt Red. “And this is something that we were struggling [with] since the beginning of the project. How are we going to make the next generation of foliage?” The answer was Nanite Foliage, a new Unreal technology that has a whole new approach to how assets like leaves, flowers, and pine needles are loaded into the environment. It allows for a much more detailed natural world without the need for constant load times and pop-in – and it was that that has helped CD Project Red work on a seamless forest environment that is so richly detailed. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/4-1748994655628.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">4. A Horse Named Kelpie</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">For hundreds of hours we travelled around The Continent on a very beloved steed. But Roach was Geralt’s horse. Ciri needs her own mount, and luckily she has one. Kelpie is a black horse and we can see her in action for the first time in this tech demo. While Kelpie is new to the games, this horse has roots in The Witcher books. Originally belonging to a member of the Guild of Merchants named Hotspurn, Ciri took ownership of Kelpie when he died. Recognised as a magnificent horse wherever she goes, Kelpie’s best trick is that she can be summoned by rubbing a magical bracelet (it’s as if she were written to be a video game horse).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the books, Kelpie is said to be able to jump over seven-foot-tall walls with ease. Anyone who’s played The Witcher 3 will tell you that’s an impossibility with Roach – he’s more likely to disappear and end up on a roof. And so all this begs the question: will Kelpie be easier and more enjoyable to control than Geralt’s old steed? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“No offense to Roach, but when you have this jank it can get you out of the immersion, that's for sure,” admits Tremblay. “We want [players] to explore the world with [Kelpie] as a companion and it has to be close to perfection, for sure.” New tech like Unreal’s multi-character motion matching should hopefully ensure riding Kelpie is a smooth experience. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Like so many of The Witcher’s creatures, Kelpie has a mythological connection. In Scottish folklore, a Kelpie is a shape-shifting water spirit that has the ability to disguise itself as a horse when on dry land. Could this name hint at Kelpie also being able to take Ciri across spans of water? We’ll just have to wait and see.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/5-1748994679277.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">5. The Quest and The Manticore</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As we’ve established, this showcase is a technical demonstration rather than a slice of the game, and so there’s not really a quest to see, at least not in the game sense of the word. But Kalemba wanted to ensure the demo had a sense of narrative running through it – this is CD Projekt Red, after all.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The big challenge was how to make a tech demo, but in a way that we'll also be able to incorporate story and bits and pieces from this world,” he explains. “I love that narrative layer in this entire piece, [it] actually even helps to boost the technical achievements behind the entire demo.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In that narrative layer, we see that Ciri has taken on a classic bit of Witcher work. She’s accepted a contract from a salt merchant to find his missing cargo and crew. Unluckily for him, both his salt and men are long gone. Luckily for Ciri, their grisly fate arrived via the blood-soaked jaws of a manticore. And, as we all know, killing monsters is exactly what Witchers are known for. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a pleasant surprise to see a manticore in this demo. Production materials that were leaked during the development of The Witcher 3 suggested that manticores were planned to be part of Wild Hunt, but they were cut from the final game. While this tech demonstration is by no means confirmation of anything appearing in The Witcher 4, we at the very least have been able to see one of the beasts rendered in Unreal Engine 5. Hopefully we’ll get to fight it in the final version of the game. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Including this quest was important to Kalemba. “One of the common denominators between the writing [in the] books and the games is a cocktail of genres. It's a cocktail of experience,” he says. The reveal trailer shown at The Game Awards last year, he explains, was a more “grounded” experience that showed the ugly realities of living in the world of The Witcher. “Here you have this adventurous vibe, you know what I mean?”</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/6-1748994708913.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">6. Welcome to Valdrest, Population: Over 300</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As Ciri adventures through Kovir, she returns to Valdrest, the port town that’s home to the trader who gave her the salt contract. It’s also home to over 300 other people, thanks to a whole host of tech optimisations and Unreal Engine’s new animation framework. That means larger, more realistic crowds – Novigrad will hopefully feel primitive in comparison. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Among the town’s population we see men, women, and children, a marketplace full of traders and guards, several dwarves, a few sex workers, entertainers, and a number of different animals, including a tamed bear. Perhaps most impressive is the variety of body types and unique animations on display; it feels like everyone is an individual, something emphasised by unique characteristics, such as a disabled man walking with a crutch, or a mother wrapping her arm around her child. It’s an example of Epic’s metahuman technology bringing ever-increasingly lifelike and varied characters to video games. Something that can also be seen in the way they interact with each other…</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/7-1748994730356.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">7. A Responsive, Living World</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The NPCs in Valdrest are interesting for many reasons beyond just their visual variety. As Kalemba explained during the demo, “Notice how responsive the world is. Character actions directly affect what happens around you, sometimes even setting off chain reactions. Everything is working together.” We see this in action as Ciri bumps into a merchant carrying a crate of apples, which causes him to lose balance and drop his fruit all over the floor. The apples, fully rendered with physics, begin to roll down the hill. A nearby chicken, startled by the noise, clucks and flaps away. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We also see how NPCs can react to Ciri – upon spotting her, a guard says “Oh bugger, not her again,” and spits at Ciri as she walks past. It’s reactive behaviour like this that helps sell a Witcher’s shadowy reputation. Many people are prejudiced against these mutated monster hunters. “The idea is that there are physical interactions that when you get poked at, you get a reaction to it in a way that feels plausible to you,” says Johnson. “All of these things keep you in the world.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are a number of other cool events we see, such as a man being thrown out of a tavern (apparently for cheating at Gwent – does this mean our beloved card game will be back for another round?). It’s unclear if these behaviours are scripted or dynamic based on schedules or routines à la The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion, and when asked, CD Projekt Red would not say what its ambitions were there. But the goal is a living, breathing world. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“For us, the world words we are creating, it's super important for us to actually make them as vivid and as believable as possible,” says Kapuściński. “Naturally behaving, properly looking NPCs are an important part of it. So yeah, we've proved that with previous games, and we're not aiming any lower than that.”</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/8-1748994748239.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">8. Seamless Cinematics</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Because this is a technical demonstration and not actual gameplay, we didn’t see a lot of “game” – you’ll no doubt have noticed how the camera swung away from Ciri’s conversation with the merchant before any kind of dialogue system and UI could be shown. But what we did see is a vision of how dialogue sequences in The Witcher 4 will begin, and it’s completely seamless. The Witcher 3 featured brief loading screens as it transitioned from the gameplay camera to the cinematic camera, but all that’s gone now thanks to Unreal Engine’s tools. Now, as Ciri approaches the geographic trigger point for a dialogue – in this case, a balustrade – the camera automatically ‘unhooks’ itself from its regular game position behind Ciri and begins to frame the scene as required for the cinematic. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">CD Projekt Red first achieved seamless game-to-cinematic transitions in Cyberpunk 2077, where it was vital to maintaining the first-person immersion. While things are a little different here, thanks to the third-person perspective, it’s cool to see the studio’s vision for keeping the experience flowing naturally. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/9-1748994763959.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">9. A Small Gift for All Witcher Fans</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Right at the end of the demo, Kalemba said that the demo was going to finish with “a small gift for all Witcher fans.” That gift was a first look at Lan Exeter. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While it is briefly mentioned by characters in both The Witcher 3 and its expansion, Blood and Wine, this is the first time we are seeing this grand city rendered for a video game. Lan Exeter is a port city in Kovir and the kingdom’s winter capital (there is also a summer capital, called Pont Vanis) that features in Andrzej Sapkowski’s Witcher books. With no pedestrian walkways, the only way to navigate Lan Exeter is via its canal network. Unsurprisingly, the city is essentially a wintry, fantasy Venice. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Great Canal that runs through Lan Exeter leads to a number of important places, but the most important of them all is Ensenada Palace; the residence of the King of Kovir and Poviss. On the boat ride to the palace, a visitor would also be able to see the grand homes of many admirals and business magnates. It seems a sure bet that we’ll be visiting at least one or two of those estates when we visit Lan Exeter in The Witcher 4. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/03/10-1748994779998.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">10. The Next Generation of Open World RPGs</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As the demo draws to a close, Kalemba says, “I think what we’re doing together [with Epic Games] is going to bring in a new generation of open world RPGs.” But what exactly does that mean?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“For us, story [and] quest is always key,” says Tremblay. “And now with the immersion, we want people to experience this world, but the technology should not be in the way. We want people to feel like they belong to this world, they interact with the world, that they can experience the emotion of the character, feeling that they are connected to the story. With our partnership and all the tools we build and all the technology, I think it'll be yet another level for us going forward.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“For us, we don't want to get in the way of artistic vision,” says Johnson. “We want everybody who uses Unreal Engine to come at the tools and the technology unburdened by what they imagine and believe that it can't do. We want [them] to come to the technology with a vision of ‘Here's what we want to achieve. We're going to dream big, and we hope that the engine moves out of our way as efficiently and effectively as possible and allows us to achieve it.’” </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Senior Features Editor. </em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>