<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:19:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard update 1.0.4 adds FoV sliders and fixes some crash issues]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/30/highguard-update-1-0-4-adds-fov-sliders-and-fixes-some-crash-issues/</link>
            <guid>1420924</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Wildlight Entertainment has released patch 1.0.4 for its free to play hero shooter Highguard, with the update adding field of view sliders for console players, and addressed some bug and crash issues. Highguard was released earlier this week and since launch the game has received a mixed response. You can check out Highguard update 1.0.4 patch notes below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Gameplay Launch Trailer | Highguard" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gqFccBZyTaA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<h2>Highguard 1.0.4 update patch notes</h2>

<p><i>Note: in an effort to release these changes to our players as quickly as possible, a number of menu options are not yet localized in languages other than English. Properly localized settings will be prepared for a future patch.</i><wbr><wbr></p>

<ul>
<li>Added the ability to set Crouch to Hold or Toggle for all platforms.<wbr></li>
<li>Added the ability to set Aim Down Sights to Hold or Toggle for PC only (for now).<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><i>Toggling into ADS then tapping Sprint (shift on PC, left stick on controller) will swap your scope. This is disorienting on controller. PC players are recommended to rebind scope swap if using Toggle ADS. We will continue to look into adding this for console players who can’t rebind buttons yet, but we will need more time.</i><wbr><wbr></p>

<ul>
<li>Console users can now adjust FoV to 110.<wbr></li>
<li>Low scalability settings for shadows and reflections are tuned for even more performance at the cost of some image quality.<wbr></li>
<li>Low shadow setting now also disables volumetric fog.<wbr></li>
<li>Added a new “View Distance Quality” setting that controls skeletal mesh LODs, which can be another useful control to tune GPU and CPU usage.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p>Players now have the ability to toggle the following features on or off, irrespective of other quality options:<wbr></p>

<ul>
<li>Anisotropic Materials<wbr></li>
<li>Chromatic Aberration<wbr></li>
<li>Bloom<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><i>Motion Blur and Depth of Field need more testing to disable safely. Look for these options very soon.</i><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>DLSS users now have the ability to select a DLSS preset.&nbsp;<i>More presets and better descriptions are coming in the next patch.</i><wbr></li>
<li>Players can now select&nbsp;<i>Off</i>&nbsp;to disable Global Illumination entirely.<wbr></li>
<li>Resolved an engine bug which could inadvertently throttled laptop users to 60 FPS regardless of frame rate settings.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Crash and Bug Fixes</b><wbr></p>
<p>This patch resolves crashes that could occur in the following scenarios<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Leaving a match on PS5 with an unexpected input state.<wbr></li>
<li>Loading into matches on machines with slower storage devices.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p>A number of other bugs related to online user presence and matchmaking were also resolved.<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Friends now appear online correctly after accepting requests, and Xbox presence updates properly. Major crash fixes have reduced crashes by 90%, significantly improving stability.<wbr></li>
<li>Friend status is fixed – players now appear online correctly and Xbox presence updates reliably. Our top crash issues are gone resulting in a 90% crash reduction.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/28/highguard-review-in-progress/">Highguard Review in Progress</a></h2>
<p>While we haven’t got a full review for Highguard yet, Dom gave some early impressions saying, <em>“Highguard’s first steps into the PvP arena are confident and unashamed, despite what the angry voices on the internet might tell you. The slightly odd mix of Apex Legends, Rainbow Six and He-Man actually makes for a good time, and there’s so much room for more to happen here. That will take time, and I hope that it finds the audience it needs to thrive.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/4128260/view/538877446766723947">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/30/highguard-update-1-0-4-adds-fov-sliders-and-fixes-some-crash-issues/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Download: 30th January (North America)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/nintendo-download-30th-january-north-america</link>
            <guid>1420921</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="2121cbce1a896"><a title="The Perfect Pencil" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2121cbce1a896/the-perfect-pencil.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Studio Cima</em></figcaption></figure><p><em>The latest Nintendo Download update — albeit a day late, but hey, we were <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-nintendo-direct-every-announcement-how-would-you-rate-it">living the dream</a> — for North America has arrived, and it's bringing new games galore to the eShop in your region.</em></p>
<p><em>As always, be sure to drop a vote in our poll and comment down below with your potential picks for the week. Enjoy!</em></p>
<h2>Switch 2 eShop - New Releases</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/4pgp-nintendo-switch-2-edition">4PGP – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a></strong> <em>(3goo, 4th Feb, $24.99)</em> - From beginners to experts, fun for everyone! Singleplayer: Championship, Quick Race, and Time Attack. Split-screen multiplayer with up to four players. 19 unique cars based on real formula cars. 14 different circuits from around the world that can also be played in reverse. Four difficulty levels: ROOKIE, NOVICE, VETERAN, and EXPERT. Gyroscopic controls and Assist mode for beginners. Learn how to play with an extensive tutorial mode! 60FPS in TV, Handheld, and Tabletop Mode.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067mxgyvp&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/dispatch-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Dispatch Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a></strong> <em>(AdHoc Studio, 28th Jan)</em> - Dispatch is a superhero workplace comedy set in modern day Los Angeles from the writers and directors of Tales from the Borderlands and The Wolf Among Us, and features an all-star cast including Aaron Paul, Laura Bailey, and Jeffrey Wright. You play as Robert Robertson, AKA Mecha Man, whose mech-suit is destroyed in a battle against his nemesis, forcing him to take a job at a superhero dispatch center: not as a hero, but a dispatcher. As their dispatcher, you take charge of a team of ex-supervillains given a shot at redemption. - <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/dispatch-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Read our Dispatch Nintendo Switch 2 Edition review</a></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-download/related-articles:196446 @ 1769784303 -->
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/grid-legends-deluxe-edition">GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition</a></strong> <em>(Feral Interactive, 29th Jan, $39.99)</em> - GRID Legends marks the return of Codemasters’ premium racing franchise to Nintendo as the much-anticipated sequel to the phenomenally successful GRID Autosport on Switch. GRID Legends is an all-out racer for Switch 2 that delivers pin-sharp visuals, great performance, and a huge range of cars that will go wheel-to-wheel in 10 high-octane motorsport disciplines across 24 stunning locations. - <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/grid-legends-deluxe-edition">Read our GRID Legends: Deluxe Edition review</a></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-download/related-articles:196273 @ 1769784303 -->
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/run-for-money-hunter-vs-runner-which-side-will-you-win-with">“Run for Money”: Hunter VS Runner! Which Side Will You Win With!?</a></strong> <strong>[Switch 2]</strong> <em>(D3Publisher, 29th Jan, $29.99)</em> - The super popular "Run for Money" game is coming to Nintendo Switch™ 2 ! Experience your very own "Run for Money"!! Clear all the mission and aim to make a successful escape!! This latest edition also brings enhanced multiplayer features! All 5 original stages are available for local and online multiplayer matches! In online battles, the new "Hunter VS Runaway Mode" lets up to 12 players (4 Hunters, 8 Runaways) face off! Let's all have a blast playing Run for Money!</p>
<h2>Switch eShop - New Releases</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/4pgp">4PGP</a></strong> <strong>[Switch 1]</strong> <em>(3goo, 4th Feb, $19.99)</em> - Race Together! Share the excitement with friends and family playing split-screen multiplayer. Hop in a formula car and race on unique tracks from around the world. With its multiple difficulty settings and accessibility options such as assist mode and gyroscopic controls, 4PGP can be enjoyed by everyone from beginners to experts.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/astro_party_ex">Astro Party EX</a></strong> <em>(Wild Rooster, 27th Jan, $0.00)</em> - Astro Party EX is a chaotic local multiplayer space brawler. Blast enemy ships, run over pilots, and laugh while you do it. The twist? Ships can only turn right. (whaaaaa?)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/card_quest">Card Quest</a></strong> <em>(BD Games, 29th Jan, $9.99)</em> - A deeply strategic game featuring an adorable feline hero! Dive into rich elemental builds, face randomized gear upgrades and breakthroughs, and master a unique core mechanic in every character.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/celestial_ascend">Celestial Ascend</a></strong> <em>(EpiXR Games, 29th Jan, $9.99)</em> - Rise above the clouds and follow a solitary traveler on a quest that blends graceful platforming with peaceful exploration. Each level is a dreamlike chapter of a larger tale about loss, resolve, and the hope of earning a second chance for humanity. Glide across floating islands, scale soaring structures, and navigate shifting gravity as friendly spirit guides share fragments of the story and teach you new abilities.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/chrono_ark_deluxe_edition">Chrono Ark Deluxe Edition</a></strong> <em>(PLAYISM, 29th Jan, $39.99)</em> - Recruit up to 4 companions and build the strongest party based on their skills and abilities. The skills of Lucy, the protagonist, and her companions are available as cards. Your choices determine what skills they learn! Defeat is nothing to fear Unlike traditional RPGs, everything resets when your party gets defeated, and new companions and skills become available. Perfect your strategy with each iteration.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/clover_cove">Clover Cove</a></strong> <em>(Downmeadowstreet, 30th Jan, $4.99)</em> - Clover Cove is a peaceful, exploration-driven walking simulator that invites you to wander across a colossal island dominated by a towering ancient castle. Discover quiet beaches, hidden groves, abandoned locations, mysterious ruins, and countless other hand-crafted locations—all at your own pace. There are no enemies, no combat, and no pressure. Just curiosity, atmosphere, and the joy of uncovering a world that feels alive, forgotten, and waiting for you.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/countless_army">Countless Army</a></strong> <em>(Dos Estrellas, 29th Jan, $9.99)</em> - Have you ever dreamed of being the villain in a Tower Defense? Be the one who sends waves and waves of troops to break through the enemy defenses in this Reverse Tower Defense. Summon, conquer and upgrade your troops to dominate the whole world! Summon your troops and conquer! Choose the troops, the order and the path you’ll send in each wave. Think of your strategies to conquer each map. Invade countless maps! Play through the kingdoms, each with their own features.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/crosak">Crosak</a></strong> <em>(Wild Sphere, 29th Jan, $14.99)</em> - Do you like platforming, exploration, and plumbing. . . ? Uh, I mean. . . play-dough? ! Well, we may not have pipes, but we can give you 64 reasons to join Crosak’s daring adventures. Become a real caveman jumping and clubbing your way through a multi-gravity universe made of sticky play-dough: six open worlds full of secrets plus three special worlds with everything a galaxy could wish for.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/delivery_of_us">Delivery of Us</a></strong> <em>(Afil Games, 4th Feb, $4.99)</em> - This relaxing logic and movement-based puzzle game combines smooth mechanics, strategic planning, and calm visuals. Each level challenges you to find the most efficient path to every mailbox while avoiding walls, hazards, and obstacles along the way.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/dispatch">Dispatch</a></strong> <em>(AdHoc Studio, 28th Jan, $29.99)</em> - Dispatch is a superhero workplace comedy set in modern day Los Angeles from the writers and directors of Tales from the Borderlands and The Wolf Among Us, and features an all-star cast including Aaron Paul, Laura Bailey, and Jeffrey Wright. You play as Robert Robertson, AKA Mecha Man, whose mech-suit is destroyed in a battle against his nemesis, forcing him to take a job at a superhero dispatch center: not as a hero, but a dispatcher. As their dispatcher, you take charge of a team of ex-supervillains given a shot at redemption. Manage and level up your roster, all while navigating office relationships and romances, and rebuilding your suit for a shot at revenge!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/diver_catch_and_cook_simulator">Diver, Catch &amp; Cook Simulator</a></strong> <em>(Burgeq Media Games, 30th Jan, $9.99)</em> - Diver, Catch &amp; Cook Simulator lets you explore the ocean’s depths by day and run a sushi restaurant by night. Hunt fish and strange marine creatures using harpoons, weapons, and underwater tools, then turn your catch into delicious dishes to earn profits and upgrade your gear. Manage oxygen, face unknown threats, and dive deeper to discover rare species and hidden zones.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/drop_pop">Drop Pop</a></strong> <em>(Soroka Games, 24th Jan, $7.99)</em> - Drop Pop is an addictive and relaxing game that is easy to play and hard to stop. Drop colorful balls, connect the same ones, and watch them turn into bigger balls. Every move feels satisfying and rewarding. Enjoy smooth and calming gameplay with no pressure, no timers, and no stress. Play at your own pace - relax for a few minutes or spend hours having fun and improving your skills.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/eggconsole_wonderland_of_carbuncle_msx2">EGGCONSOLE WONDERLAND OF CARBUNCLE MSX2</a></strong> <em>(D4 Enterprise, 29th Jan, $6.49)</em> - This title is a unique shooting game that was included in "Disk Station #25," released by Compile in 1991. Players control Carbuncle to collect falling apples, and the stage is cleared once they defeat the boss that appears at the end.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/escape_game_r00m09">Escape game R00M09</a></strong> <em>(AlignmentSharp, 29th Jan, $1.00)</em> - Move through 3D space to find hints, solve mysteries and escape from the room. Anyone can play to the end because you can see hints and answers.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/escape_game_the_museum_of_memories">Escape Game The Museum of Memories</a></strong> <em>(Regista, 29th Jan, $4.99)</em> - A classic escape game set in an art museum hosting an exhibition of past works!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/everwarder">Everwarder</a></strong> <em>(indie.io, 29th Jan, $9.99)</em> - In Everwarder there's you, and a procedurally-generated world covered in darkness. Touch it - and it will spawn a creature that will try to destroy your most precious thing – a crystal with your friend trapped inside.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/habitat_shapes">Habitat Shapes</a></strong> <em>(Afil Games, 29th Jan, $4.99)</em> - Enjoy the relaxing puzzle of Habitat Shapes by organizing spaces for three animal families – mammals, birds, and reptiles – using Fence/Wall pieces to keep them separated. Watch out: different families cannot touch, and any attempt triggers a funny “fight cloud,” sending the last piece back to the conveyor.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/horizon_drift_unlimited_2026">Horizon Drift Unlimited 2026</a></strong> <em>(Evgheni Carasiov, 26th Jan, $14.99)</em> - Step into a world of pure driving pleasure where the road is your only destination. Horizon Drift Unlimited 2026 delivers a visually stunning open driving experience inspired by the beauty, speed, and atmosphere of modern automotive culture.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/i_hate_this_place">I Hate This Place</a></strong> <em>(Feardemic, 29th Jan, $29.99)</em> - Inspired by Skybound’s Eisner award-nominated comic book series created by writer Kyle Starks and artist Artyom Topilin, I Hate This Place plunges players deep into a supernatural world where the rules of reality come undone. In an all-new isometric survival horror experience, delivered in a striking visual style drenched in bold, vivid colours and retro ‘80s comic book aesthetics, each location is lovingly crafted to tell its own disturbing story through stylish visuals that blur the line between reality and nightmare in a world where everything wants you dead.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/jimmy_and_the_pulsating_mass">Jimmy and the Pulsating Mass</a></strong> <em>(Penguin Pop Games, 4th Feb, $19.99)</em> - One day, Jimmy looked inside. The game takes place in the dream of an eight-year-old boy. When an alien entity appears and threatens his family and the stability of the dream world itself, Jimmy sets out on an adventure to save his family and eradicate the threat of the Pulsating Mass. Along the way, Jimmy will have to work with his family, confront his own shortcomings, and brave the creeping nightmares of his subconscious.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/knight_castle_defender">Knight Castle Defender</a></strong> <em>(Eathrabaria, 26th Jan, $4.99)</em> - Command your warriors and stop the orcs and villains from raiding your stronghold. With 100 action-packed levels, 11 unique defensive forces, 3 powerful abilities, and an engaging power-up system, your castle stands ready for the ultimate battle!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/long_run_2">Long Run 2</a></strong> <em>(Entity3, 24th Jan, $0.99)</em> - This high-energy hyper-casual runner expands the original experience with faster movement, smoother visuals, and a new wave of dynamic obstacles. Players charge through the tracks while growing a trailing line of followers, multiply your numbers through colour-coded gates, and avoid hazards designed to tear your chain apart. The bigger your trail, the more power you carry into the explosive end-of-run finale.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/majotori">Majotori</a></strong> <em>(Mameshiba Games, 29th Jan, $5.99)</em> - Lariat the witch will make your wish will come true if you win a game of trivia, but if you lose, something dark will happen instead. How many lives will your ignorance ruin? Majotori is a narratrivia, an original little game that combines an interactive narrative with a quiz game.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/nickelodeon_splat_pack">Nickelodeon Splat Pack</a></strong> <em>(Limited Run Games, 30th Jan, $14.99)</em> - Relive the 90s in this collection of classic Nickelodeon games! Includes GUTS, Rocko's Modern Life: Spunky's Dangerous Day, and AAAHH!!! Real Monsters. In addition to the games themselves, several extra features are included:<br>
Rewind: Made a mistake? Don't worry! You can rewind to try again. Save Anywhere: Need a break? Bring up the menu and save your game whenever you want. Music Player: Just want to listen to the great music in these games? We've got you covered!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/nyan_nyan_nyan_nyan_nyan">nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan</a></strong> <em>(MASK, 29th Jan, $3.99)</em> - In this lively illustration filled with many characters and objects, your task is to find the specified paw print within the time limit. Enjoy an easy and fun brain-training game!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/offroad_truck_4x4_dirt_simulator_-_rally_racing_game">Offroad Rally Racing</a></strong> <em>(Pix Arts, 30th Jan, $5.99)</em> - Gear up for the ultimate offroad experience in "Offroad Truck 4X4 Dirt Simulator - Rally Racing Game"! Embark on a thrilling adventure across two distinct locations, the scorching Desert and the untamed Woodland. Each area presents unique challenges, formidable obstacles, and exhilarating jumps that will push your offroading skills to the limit. Choose from a diverse range of offroad vehicles, including rugged cars, powerful trucks, and versatile SUVs.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/our_burial_dolls_remastered">Our Burial Dolls Remastered</a></strong> <em>(ROSEVERTE, 30th Jan, $4.99)</em> - The beloved classic returns in a remastered edition, featuring improved visuals and enhanced atmospheric presentation. Some background images have been replaced with new assets, giving the game a distinctly different visual impression from the original. The user interface has been redesigned for improved readability and usability. New text dialogues sounds enhance immersion in the story.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/parkour_simulator_2026">Parkour Simulator 2026</a></strong> <em>(Lu Ming trading as Shane Game, 3rd Feb, $9.99)</em> - Step into the shoes of a professional freerunner and conquer urban landscapes like never before! In Parkour Simulator 2026, master jumps, flips, wall-runs, and vaults as you navigate rooftops, alleys, and obstacles with precision and style.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/run-for-money-hunter-vs-runner-which-side-will-you-win-with">“Run for Money”: Hunter VS Runner! Which Side Will You Win With!?</a></strong> <strong>[Switch 1]</strong> <em>(D3Publisher, 29th Jan, $29.99)</em> - The hit Japanese game show “Run for Money” is coming to Nintendo Switch™! The game retains the show’s signature runner mechanics, and for the first time in the series, this edition introduces the all-new “Hunter Mode”! Not only can you play as a runner escaping from hunters, you can also become a hunter and capture the runners! This edition features five original stages: “Wonderland,” “Airport,” “Harbor,” “Fantasy,” and “Diver City.”Just like in the TV show, runners will face a variety of missions during each stage! Clear all the mission and aim to make a successful escape!!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/running_fable_petite_party">Running Fable Petite Party</a></strong> <em>(Seashell Studio, 30th Jan, $13.99)</em> - Outrun your friends. Outsmart your rivals. Out-chaos them all! From the makers of Running Fable comes Petite Party, a wild and unpredictable spin-off that cranks up the chaos. Battle through 16 competitive mini-games and dominate the tabletop party board where anything goes.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/simpli_casa">Simpli Casa</a></strong> <em>(REDDEER.GAMES, 29th Jan, $8.99)</em> - Tired of clutter? Ready to create spaces that are effortlessly stylish? Forget bulky, outdated furniture—your canvas awaits sleek lines, natural textures, and a calming, contemporary aesthetic. Design Your Dream Spaces.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/perfect_pencil">The Perfect Pencil</a></strong> <em>(Studio Cima, 29th Jan, $19.99)</em> - Lost in the kingdom of the white beast, will you find your way out? The Perfect Pencil is a story-driven action platformer that throws you into the innermost depths of the human mind. The Perfect Pencil is a surreal action platformer which tells the tale of personal development and the psychology of fear. Join protagonist John as he awakens in a bizarre hand-drawn kingdom and comes face-to-face with the terrors that dwell in the last place he'd have thought to look...</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tiny_biomes">Tiny Biomes</a></strong> <em>(eastasiasoft, 4th Feb, $4.99)</em> - Tiny Biomes is a relaxing yet challenging tile-rotation puzzle game where you must guide the flow of water, snow or lava to bring life back to the biomes, each consisting of 50 unique levels of gradually increasing complexity and challenge.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/torees_3d_platformer_collection">Toree’s 3D Platformer Collection</a></strong> <em>(Diplodocus Games, 30th Jan,)</em> - Toree and his friends invite you to jump through four colourful and varied 3d platformer games. Toree's 3D Platformer Collection includes the following four titles: Toree 3D (incl. Toree Jumbled Jam extra levels), Toree 2 (incl. winter-themed extra levels), Macbat 64 and Regina &amp; Mac. Additionally, you can unlock a secret extra game.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/whispers_of_winter_blossom">Whispers of Winter Blossom</a></strong> <em>(moesoft, 31st Jan, $24.99)</em> - That winter, I met a girl with silver hair. As the seasons quietly changed, two closed-off hearts began to connect through a single “story.” Each time the snow fell, the world was wrapped in silence, and unspoken feelings quietly piled up. In a quiet corner of the academy begins a gentle yet heartrending tale that weaves the soul—of solitude, hope, and rebirth. Just like snow softly covering everything, this story may quietly settle in someone’s heart as well. Your words might be able to change someone’s future.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/world_of_unlit">World of Unlit</a></strong> <em>(Mad Jackal Games, 4th Feb, $9.99)</em> - World of Unlit is a fast paced, first person movement shooter where your goal is to utilize your grapple hook, melee weapons, guns and bows to destabilize a culture. Fight your way through Unlit territory and destroy all the statues you find along your way, the unique and skill demanding movement is your best tool to complete your mission.</p>

<p><em>So that's your lot for this week's North American Nintendo Download. Go on, be a sport and drop a vote in the poll above, and comment below with your hot picks!</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/nintendo-download-30th-january-north-america]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Pokémon Company Apologizes For Listing Fan Meet-Up At One Of Japan’s Most Controversial Sites]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-apology-japan-yasukuni-shrine-2000664540</link>
            <guid>1420912</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Sad Pikachu.</span> © The Pokémon Company / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>The Pokémon Company has issued an apology after a listing appeared on its official site for a&nbsp;<em>Pokémon TCG</em> event said to be taking place at the Yasukuni Shrine. This controversial site has repeatedly caused consternation in Japan when visited by political figures, and even by previous Pokémon employees, and once again people were upset to see the location listed as the site of a TCG tournament.</p> <p>The Yasukuni Shrine commemorates the Japanese people who died in conflicts from 1869 to 1954, and thus includes the soldiers who died as part of Japan’s forces fighting for the Axis powers in World War II, many of whom were charged with the most serious of war crimes. As such, it’s a very controversial site, both within and without the country, and it causes serious stirs whenever anyone of prominence chooses to make a public visit. Indeed, The Pokémon Company discovered this for itself in 2019 when a number of employees from Creatures visited the Shinto shrine for its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hatsum%C5%8Dde"><i>hatsumōde</i></a>.</p>

 <p>Given its hugely complicated politics and the controversies that arise every time it’s visited, TPC clearly doesn’t want it used as the site of a <em>PTCG</em> event. However, live events are added to the company’s site by those with an official <em>Pokémon&nbsp;</em>Play certification, rather than by TPC itself. It works the same all around the world—if you want to find a local Play event near you, <a href="https://events.pokemon.com/EventLocator/?locale=en-us">you can look them up on the U.S. version of the site</a>. So it seems someone with such a certification in Japan added the event to the vast numbers listed for the country.</p> <p>“On the event search page of the ‘Pokémon Card Game Trainers Website’ operated by our company,” <a href="https://corporate.pokemon.co.jp/media/news/detail/368.html">begins a statement on&nbsp;<em>Pokémon</em>‘s corporate site</a> (via machine translation), “information about an event scheduled to be held at Yasukuni Shrine was posted.” The statement goes on to call allowing this Yasukuni Shrine event to be listed the result of a “lack of due diligence,” adding, “even though it should not have been held in the first place.”</p>

 <p>The event was canceled once discovered, say TPC, adding an apology (again, via machine translation). “We have received feedback and opinions from various parties since the information about this event was released, and we sincerely apologize for this.” The company adds that it will “fundamentally change and strengthen the review system and confirmation process for event information” to prevent something like this happening again.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-apology-japan-yasukuni-shrine-2000664540]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest VII Reimagined Release Date Countdown & Exact Start Times]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-release-date-start-times/</link>
            <guid>1420909</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Over 25 years since its initial release, Dragon Quest VII Reimagined provides players with a huge modernization of the classic game, and the release date is right around the corner.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/genres/rpg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">RPG</a> title was a huge hit when it was initially released at the turn of the millennium, and the remastered version is one of the most eagerly anticipated titles releasing in the early part of 2026.</p>



<p>If you’re on the hunt for all the release date and start time details for Dragon Quest VII Reimagined, Insider Gaming has you covered.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-the-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-release-date">What is The Dragon Quest VII Reimagined Release Date?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Back again. Image via Square Enix</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined is set for launch on February 5, though the date may vary based on your region and the platform you are playing on.</strong></p>



<p>For those that purchase the Digital Deluxe Edition, 48 hours of early access are available as an incentive.</p>



<p>Dragon Quest VII Reimaged is available across multiple platforms, but the release time and date vary across them; however, for the vast majority, it will be February 5 when you can start playing.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-are-the-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-start-times">What Are The Dragon Quest VII Reimagined Start Times?</h2>



<p><strong>The start time for Dragon Quest VII Reimagined varies based on platform, with a 12 AM PT release on consoles, and a 9 AM PT release on Steam.</strong> <strong>Those with early access can jump in up to 48 hours before these times. </strong></p>



<p>As is customary for platforms like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation 5</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/xbox-series-x/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Series X</a>|S, Dragon Quest VII Reimaged has a staggered release date, which means that you can play early in your time zone if you adjust your settings accordingly, which is very easy to do on Xbox.</p>



<p>For <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a> players, however, the release time is global and set in stone, with a morning release for those in the United States, while European players have to wait until the afternoon, and other regions may need to wait until the early hours of the morning on February 6.</p>



<p>The table below shows the start times for Dragon Quest VII Reimagined on Steam and consoles.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Console Start Time</th><th data-align="center">Steam Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM – Feb. 5</td><td data-align="center">9 AM – Feb. 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM – Feb. 5</td><td data-align="center">11 AM – Feb. 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM – Feb. 5</td><td data-align="center">12 PM – Feb. 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM – Feb. 5</td><td data-align="center">5 PM – Feb. 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (AET)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM – Feb. 5</td><td data-align="center">4 AM – Feb. 6</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<hr>



<p>What platform will you be playing Dragon Quest VII Reimagined on? Share your plans in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, check out all the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pubg-blindspot-platforms-xbox-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">platform details for PUBG: Blindspot</a>, and find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-to-beat-cairn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how long it takes to beat Cairn</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-release-date-start-times/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Skyrim Lead Says Elder Scrolls TV Show Wouldn’t Work]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/former-skyrim-lead-elder-scrolls-tv-show-not-work/</link>
            <guid>1420906</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Bethesda Game Studios has seen immense success with the delivery of the Fallout television show. It has won awards, pulled millions of eyes to the Fallout universe, and opened the door to collaborations across the ecosystem. But would that success roll over into The Elder Scrolls if <strong>that franchise </strong>were to be adapted into a live-action production?</p>



<p>According to Bruce Nesmith, former design lead on The Elder Scrolls IV: Skyrim, and a quest writer on Fallout 3 (amongst other things), a live-action adaptation of The Elder Scrolls <strong>probably wouldn’t work</strong>.</p>











<p>Nesmith worked at Bethesda Game Studios for several years, leaving in 2021 to chase new horizons. But before he departed, he offered key contributions to some of the company’s most ambitious projects, including 2011’s Elder Scrolls game, <strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-is-being-released-again/">Skyrim</a></strong>. It’s widely considered one of the best games ever made, and he played a pivotal part in bringing it to life.</p>



<p>In a recent interview with <a href="https://www.pressboxpr.co.uk/news/bruce-nesmith-exclusive-skyrims-design-lead-on-where-he-would-set-the-elder-scrolls-6-and-what-to-expect-from-the-future-of-fallout" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Press Box PR</a>, Nesmith spoke at length about Fallout, The Elder Scrolls, and the world around him and what he has created – and continues to create.</p>



<p>One segment turned to talking about the Fallout TV show and the success it has seen since debuting in April 2024.</p>



<p>The interviewer asked Nesmith if he could see The Elder Scrolls receiving the live-action treatment, but the former Bethesda Game Studios developer was sceptical and pretty on the money with his opinion:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Do they really need marketing for Elder Scrolls 6?</p>



<p>There’s something very special and different and unique about Fallout that lends itself to becoming a TV or movie experience whereas The Elder Scrolls is trying to be a standard kind of fantasy. That’s not as interesting.</p>



<p>You look at Fallout, everything is special about it. There is nothing like the Fallout universe anywhere else in gaming.</p>



<p>That makes it easy to make a TV show and draw eyeballs as opposed to going into a fantasy world where I’ve got elves and people throwing spells around. You’d have to raise those stakes. There’s a dragon? I’ve seen dragons 20 times before. What are you giving to viewers that’s new?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don’t know that The Elder Scrolls would fit that media well. Maybe a movie but I would struggle to see a TV show.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s a good point. Nesmith pointed to brands like Game of Thrones and Lord of the Rings, which could be seen as very Elder Scrolls-coded. There are plenty of television shows and movies with fantasy themes, even adaptations like The Witcher walk a close line to the Bethesda-backed brand, for instance.</p>



<p>It’s highly unlikely Bethesda Game Studios will turn anything other than Fallout into a show, especially as the series could run <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-tv-show-could-run-more-than-a-decade/">for up to a <strong>decade</strong></a>, all being well.</p>



<p>Now, if we could just start talking about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bethesda-wants-play-fallout-5-600-hours-rookie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">making Fallout 5 a reality</a>…</p>







<p>Do you think you’d watch an Elder Scrolls TV show? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-has-reportedly-surpassed-20-million-copies-sold/">Helldivers 2 might have sold 20 million copies</a></p>






        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/former-skyrim-lead-elder-scrolls-tv-show-not-work/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Censored Hogs, GDC Cancellations & Amazon Layoffs: All The News From January 28-30]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/video-game-news-roundup-january-2026/</link>
            <guid>1420903</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
      
    <div data-post-hero="fullwidth-image">

    <div data-post-hero-content="">
          

      

        <p>Also: Valve is facing a $900 million lawsuit</p>

        
    </div>

      <figure>
          <picture>
  <source srcset="https://aftermath.site/content/images/size/w320/format/webp/2026/01/hog.jpg 320w, https://aftermath.site/content/images/size/w640/format/webp/2026/01/hog.jpg 600w, https://aftermath.site/content/images/size/w960/format/webp/2026/01/hog.jpg 960w, https://aftermath.site/content/images/size/w1280/format/webp/2026/01/hog.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1023px) 90vw, 1200px" type="image/webp">
  
</picture>
        <figcaption><span>Please note: I made this, I have no idea if this is what the censored scenes in Dispatch actually look like or not, but I really hope they do look like this</span></figcaption>
      </figure>

  </div>

<div data-post-info="">
      <p><span>Published:</span>
        <time datetime="2026-01-30T10:06:06">January 30, 2026, 10:06 am</time>
      </p>
    </div>
    <article>
      <p>Welcome to Recap, our twice-weekly feature on Aftermath where we round up what’s been going on around video games, the internet and beyond.</p><hr><p>GDC released its annual 'State of the Game Industry' survey results, and they're about as grim as you'd expect, with ONE THIRD of American respondents saying they'd been laid off in the last two years. </p><figure><a href="https://gdconf.com/article/gdc-2026-state-of-the-game-industry-reveals-impact-of-layoffs-generative-ai-and-more/?_mc=edit_gdcsf_gdcsf_rp_x_em1_soti_2026&amp;utm_source=other&amp;utm_medium=x&amp;utm_campaign=soti&amp;utm_term=em1&amp;utm_content=rp_"><div><p>GDC 2026 State of the Game Industry Reveals Impact of Layoffs, Generative AI, and More</p><p>Discover key insights from the 2026 State of the Game Industry report, covering layoffs, generative AI, unionization, platform trends, and more. Download the free report now!</p><p><span>Beth ElderkinShareshare</span></p></div></a></figure><hr><p>In news harking back to the Nintendo of the 90s, we learned this week that the Switch 1 &amp; 2 versions of <em>Dispatch</em> will be censored. Other editions on other platforms have the option to hide stuff like full-frontal nudity, but the Switch ones will have no such toggle. </p><figure><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dispatch-switch-switch-2-censored-adhoc-comment?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>“The core narrative and gameplay experience remains identical” AdHoc reassures Dispatch players on Switch as it confirms Nintendo platform versions are censored</p><p>Dispatch is gearing up for its debut on Switch later today, however there will be some censorship differences on Nintendo’s consoles.</p><p><span>Eurogamer.net</span><span>Victoria Phillips Kennedy</span></p></div></a></figure><hr><p>Comcept, the studio founded by Mega Man's Keiji Inafune back in 2010 (and probably best known for <em>Mighty No. 9</em>), closed its doors for good this week. </p><figure><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/comcept-shuts-down?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>comcept shuts down</p><p>comcept, the company founded by Keiji Inafune in December 2010, was officially dissolved by a shareholders’ resolution on January 13, according to a notice published in today’s Japanese…</p><p><span>Gematsu</span><span>Sal Romano</span></p></div></a></figure><hr><p>The head of Amazon Game Studios has left, right at the same time the wider company lays off <em>16,000 people</em>. </p><figure><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-amazon-game-studios-boss-is-leaving-the-company?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>Report: Amazon Game Studios boss is leaving the company</p><p>Amazon Game Studios boss Christoph Hartmann, formerly head of 2K, is reportedly leaving the company as Amazon continues to invest in cloud gaming.</p><p><span>Game Developer</span><span>Diego Argüello</span></p></div></a></figure><hr><p>Valve is facing a £656 million&nbsp;lawsuit in the UK (USD$900 million), accused of "abusing its market dominance by imposing restrictive terms on game publishers and locking players into using Steam". The suit was filed at the Competition Appeal Tribunal in London, and is particularly taking aim at Valve's 30% cut of all Steam sales. </p><figure><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2g1md0l23o?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>UK legal action against Valve over Steam prices gets go ahead</p><p>Millions of gamers could get compensation if the lawsuit - which accuses Valve of charging inflated prices - succeeds.</p><p><span>BBC News</span></p></div></a></figure>
    </article>

        

      

          

  
  
  
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/video-game-news-roundup-january-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo’s Third Nintendo Direct Event of 2026 Will Reportedly be a Partner Showcase Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendos-third-nintendo-direct-event-of-2026-will-reportedly-be-a-partner-showcase-next-week/</link>
            <guid>1420894</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p><strong>Nintendo</strong> is due to have its third <strong>Nintendo Direct event</strong> of the year <strong>next week</strong> on <strong>Thursday, February 5, 2026</strong>, and it'll be a <strong>Partner Showcase Direct</strong>, if multiple reports surrounding this rumour are to be believed.</p>



<p>After first coming from known insider <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JwMQiG9bc4c">NateTheHate</a> (who has also predicted that a <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-state-of-play-february-2026/"><strong>PlayStation State of Play</strong> is on the horizon for <strong>February</strong></a>), their report about a coming Nintendo Direct was corroborated by <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/2016969052132962528">GameXplain</a>, who then added that it would be a Partner Showcase, which was corroborated by NateTheHate, and as of today, both rumours have been corroborated by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/a-nintendo-direct-is-reportedly-coming-next-week-dedicated-to-partner-games/">VGC</a>.</p>



<p>Next Thursday is the predicted date, and if it is indeed a Partner Showcase, that means we can only expect to see <strong>third-party related</strong> announcements, which means we likely won't get any news at all regarding what Nintendo has coming. Instead, it'll be about what the rest of the industry is bringing to the <strong>Nintendo Switch</strong> and <strong>Nintendo Switch 2</strong>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>If this Direct event does happen next week, it'll already be the <strong>third</strong> Nintendo Direct event of 2026, after the year began with the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/super-mario-galaxy-movie-direct-nintendo-direct-2026/">Super Mario Galaxy Movie Direct</a></strong> that revealed a first proper look at <strong>Yoshi</strong> in the film, followed by a Direct event dedicated to <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K_0kl1WiSPg">Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream</a></strong>.</p>



<p>But if you're not looking forward to either the film or Tomodachi Life, then next week's rumoured Direct is likely the first one you might actually tune in for. We could get another look at Switch 2 exclusive titles like <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/fromsoftware-the-duskbloods-gameplay-leak/">The Duskbloods</a></strong>, and upcoming Switch 2 ports like <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-tarnished-edition-nintendo-switch-2-delayed-into-2026/">Elden Ring: Tarnished Edition</a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-nintendo-switch-2-delayed-pre-orders-cancelled/">Borderlands 4</a>,</strong> and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/007-first-light-release-date-delayed-two-months-may-2026/">007: First Light</a></strong>. </p>



<p>This may even be the event where we finally see <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-direct-partner-showcase-tomorrow/"><strong>Call of Duty</strong> announced for the Nintendo Switch 2</a>, and those are just some guesses at some of the bigger announcements we could see. There are also scores of potential indie game reveals that could happen at this rumoured event.</p>



<p>But Nintendo has to confirm it's actually happening before we can really start to speculate at what will be there. The last Partner Showcase Nintendo hosted <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-direct-partner-showcase-tomorrow/">was in <strong>July 2025</strong></a>, and it announced the event the day before it happened. If Nintendo sticks to that same strategy, then we should expect a reveal next <strong>Wednesday</strong>. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendos-third-nintendo-direct-event-of-2026-will-reportedly-be-a-partner-showcase-next-week/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Nintendo Direct Rumors Point To An Incoming Flood Of Switch 2 Ports]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/february-nintendo-direct-switch-2-3d-mario-2000664537</link>
            <guid>1420885</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The usual suspects are buzzing about an upcoming Nintendo Direct to kick off February. This one will reportedly be a Partner Showcase, so while I wouldn’t expect teases for anything wild like a new <em>3D Mario</em> game, we’ll probably got a healthy influx of new <a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-ports-cyberpunk-2077-ps4-ps5-xbox-dlss-outlaws-1851782817">Switch 2 ports</a> to help button down the first half of the platform’s year.</p> <p>Nintendo traditionally holds a February showcase to preview what’s coming and help fill in release calendar slots for its loyal fans. Podcasting insider <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/2016962284921249815">NateTheHate</a> and YouTube channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QKp9okfMtdI">GameXplain</a> have both suggested 2026 will follow a similar pattern, though the event will be a Partner Showcase rather than a full-blown first-party Direct. <em><a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/a-nintendo-direct-is-reportedly-coming-next-week-dedicated-to-partner-games/">VGC</a></em> was also able to corroborate those claims. So expect a new Nintendo Direct somewhere around February 3-5.</p>

 <p>But what is Nintendo likely to show? Well, we’re still waiting on firm release dates for <em>Elden Ring</em> and <em>Borderlands 4</em> on Switch 2. The latter was recently rumored to be coming near the end of February. There’s also been plenty of smoke about <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> making it over to Nintendo’s latest console, as well as the port for <em>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</em> coming sooner than expected. <em>Metaphor: Refantazio</em>, <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>, and <em>Final Fantasy XVI</em> also seem like potential candidates.</p> <p>I’m more curious to see where this missing Microsoft support for the Switch 2 is. Some version of <em>Call of Duty</em> is rumored to be coming to the platform this spring and the company still hasn’t confirmed a <em>Halo: Combat Evolved</em> remake port for the Switch 2. There’s also plenty of lower-hanging fruit like<em> Sea of Thieves</em>, <em>Diablo 4</em>, and <em>Avowed</em>, which is coming to PS5 next month. <em>Starfield</em> would also be a big get. Is a Switch 2 port part of the game’s rumored 2.0 plans? Hopefully.</p>

 <p>Announcements for new games would also be nice. We know we’re getting FromSoftware’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-duskbloods-elden-ring-hidetaka-miyazaki-switch-2-1851774753">multiplayer action game <em>Duskbloods</em></a> sometime this year. It’ll be interesting to see if any other major studios reveal exclusive side-projects for the Nintendo platform. But in the new era of every game being playable on every device, that seems less likely than a slew of new AAA ports.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/february-nintendo-direct-switch-2-3d-mario-2000664537]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond Good & Evil 2 Director Reaffirms the Game is ‘Unaffected’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/beyond-good-evil-2-director-reaffirms-the-game-is-unaffected/</link>
            <guid>1420882</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2’s director has put fans’ minds at ease, reaffirming that the game remains unaffected despite the recent restructuring. </p>



<p>Insider Gaming had <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-beyond-good-evil-2-survives-ubisofts-project-purge/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusively revealed</a> last week that, despite being one of Ubisoft’s longest in-development projects, Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 had survived the recent organizational, operational, and portfolio reset. A spokesperson later confirmed that the game remained a priority for them within their strategy, centred on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisofts-new-model-will-focus-on-open-world-adventures-and-gaas-native-experiences/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">open-world adventures</a>. </p>







<h2 id="h-beyond-good-amp-evil-2-game-and-team-unaffected">Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 Game and Team Unaffected</h2>



<p>In a recent <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7421227406130335744/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">LinkedIn</a> post, Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 director Fawzi Mesmar reaffirmed that he, the team, and the game “are unaffected by the recent changes.” Mesmar also spoke about the remaining cancellations and studio closures, encouraging people to support those affected in whatever way they can. Check out the complete statement below: </p>



<blockquote>
<p>Thank you for everyone who has reached out to me over the past few days in regards to recent news at Ubisoft. </p>



<p>Myself, my team and our project Beyond Good and Evil 2 are unaffected by the recent changes. I would direct you to the official press release for more information around the latest organisational structure. </p>



<div><p>Needless to say, I am saddened by the cancellations that has affected my colleagues in other parts of Ubisoft and the industry. I urge everyone – myself included – to offer support whenever and however they can during these times.</p><p>We remain committed and focused on delivering a remarkable game for our players to enjoy.</p></div>
</blockquote>



<p>For those who may not be aware, Ubisoft’s restructuring has resulted in the cancellation of the highly anticipated&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Prince of Persia Remake</a>, along with five other games. The new operating model will prioritize open-world adventures and experiences designed for Games as a Service (GaaS), featuring&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisofts-new-operation-model-features-5-creative-houses/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">five creative divisions</a>. This restructuring has already caused a&nbsp;significant decline in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-shares-crash-by-30-after-restructure-news/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">company’s share price</a>.</p>







<p>In other news, the Black Flag Remake was likely <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-flag-remake-delayed-by-up-to-one-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">delayed by up to </a><span><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-flag-remake-delayed-by-up-to-one-year/" target="_blank">1 year</a>&nbsp;f</span>ollowing the recent restructuring. Additionally, Ubisoft has revealed intentions to make Far Cry, Assassin’s Creed, and Rainbow Six ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-assassins-far-cry-rainbow-six-billionare/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">annual billionaire brands</a>.’  What are your thoughts on the Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 director reaffirming the team and project’s status? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-has-reportedly-surpassed-20-million-copies-sold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Helldivers 2 surpassing 20 million copies sold</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/beyond-good-evil-2-director-reaffirms-the-game-is-unaffected/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is PUBG: Blindspot on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S or Nintendo Switch? All Platforms, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pubg-blindspot-platforms-xbox-ps5/</link>
            <guid>1420879</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new entry in the PUBG universe is on the horizon with the release of PUBG: Blindspot into early access, though questions are naturally being asked about the available platforms.</p>



<p>The 5v5 top-down tactical <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/genres/fps/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shooter</a> is bringing an entirely new approach for PUBG fans, and there’s a strong audience to appeal to, given the vast success of PUBG over the years.</p>



<p>If you want to know whether PUBG: Blindspot is available on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation 5</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/xbox-series-x/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Series X</a>|S, or <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch</a>, Insider Gaming has all the details.</p>







<h2 id="h-can-you-play-pubg-blindspot-on-ps5">Can You Play PUBG: Blindspot On PS5?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>No luck. Image via PUBG</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No, PUBG: Blindspot will not be available on PlayStation 5 when it launches on February 5, and there’s no end in sight for PS5 players.</strong></p>



<p>PUBG: Blindspot’s early access period is exclusive for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PC</a>, but, potentially more significant is that there have been no details of a planned release on PS5.</p>



<p>The top-down shooter is an entirely different genre from the main PUBG title, and may not adapt well to PS5, which could explain its absence.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-pubg-blindspot-on-xbox-series-x-s">Can You Play PUBG: Blindspot On Xbox Series X|S?</h2>



<p><strong>No, similar to the situation with PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S players will not be able to play PUBG: Blindspot on the February 5 launch date.</strong></p>



<p>Again, the early access launch is for PC only, and there is no news on a potential Xbox Series X|S launch in the future, but it is still early days for the game.</p>



<p>More details about any plans for console releases could come deeper into PUBG: Blindspot’s lifespan, with the early access release merely marking the next step on a long journey.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-pubg-blindspot-on-nintendo-switch-or-switch-2">Can You Play PUBG: Blindspot On Nintendo Switch or Switch 2?</h2>



<p><strong>No, PUBG: Blindspot is not available on the Nintendo Switch family of consoles at launch, though this isn’t surprising given the overall platform status.</strong></p>



<p>Given that PUBG: Blindspot isn’t on PlayStation 5 or Xbox Series X|S, it shouldn’t be much of a surprise that there is no Switch launch, and, of all the platforms the title could come to in the future, the Nintendo platform is likely at the bottom of the list.</p>







<hr>



<p>What platforms do you want to see PUBG: Blindspot playable on? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>Done reading? Now check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-to-beat-cairn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how long it takes to beat Cairn</a>, and take a look at all the details on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-season-1-season-2-start-dates-times/">Battle</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-season-1-season-2-start-dates-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">f</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-season-1-season-2-start-dates-times/">ield 6 Season 2 launch</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pubg-blindspot-platforms-xbox-ps5/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CM Punk Revealed as WWE 2K26 Cover Star]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cm-punk-revealed-as-wwe-2k26-cover-star/</link>
            <guid>1420876</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>CM Punk is on the cover of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/wwe-2k26/" id="3461">WWE 2K26.</a></p>



<p>During the Royal Rumble coverage on ESPN 2, WWE CM Punk is the cover star of the standard edition of WWE 2K26. Pre-orders are now open, and the release is set for March 13 worldwide.</p>



<p>Currently, the WWE World Heavyweight Champion, CM Punk, is on the cover of a WWE video game for the first time since WWE ’13 back in 2012. Of course, Punk left the WWE for 10 years after a dispute with Vince McMahon and Triple H, which was spurred on by exhaustion and frustration with the direction of his career.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-cm-punk-showcase-mode/">Insider Gaming exclusively reported </a>that Punk would be the centerpiece of this year’s 2K Showcase. Not only will players be able to relive some of CM Punk’s classic career moments, but there will also be the opportunity to play through some dream matches that could have happened had CM Punk not left WWE in 2014.</p>



<figure></figure>







<h2 id="h-more-details-on-what-s-new-in-wwe-2k26">More Details on What’s New in WWE 2K26</h2>



<p>Additionally, Insider Gaming reported that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-new-match-types/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new match types are coming to WWE 2K26</a>. Of the four game modes, the Dumpster Match is debuting; the other three, Inferno Matches, “I Quit” Matches, and 3 Stages of Hell, make their return.</p>



<p>The Island also returns in WWE 2K26 built around a new storyline concerning three factions. Learn more from our exclusive report <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-island-returns-wwe-2k26-new-story/" id="170633">here</a>.</p>







<h3 id="h-this-is-the-only-cover-not-featuring-triple-h">This Is the Only Cover Not Featuring Triple H</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>All three higher-priced editions of WWE 2K26 will feature Triple H on the cover in some respect. The Monday Night War Edition is slated to provide the most content access. It is also expected to be the most expensive. Learn more about pricing for all editions of WWE 2K26 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-pricing-revealed-for-all-editions/" id="172964">here</a>.</p>



<p>WWE has said that gameplay footage will drop during the Royal Rumble on January 31. Insider Gaming will keep you up-to-date with the latest WWE 2K26 news.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the cover featuring CM Punk? Are you planning to pick up WWE 2K26 in any capacity? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cm-punk-revealed-as-wwe-2k26-cover-star/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demon Kill Demon: Yomi 1984 teaser trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/demon-kill-demon-yomi-1984-teaser-trailer</link>
            <guid>1420873</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Dystopian dungeon RPG due out on May 28 in Japan.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Experience [213 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> has released a teaser trailer for dystopian <a title="Genres > Dungeon RPG [90 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/dungeon-rpg">dungeon RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Demon Kill Demon: Yomi 1984 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/demon-kill-demon-yomi-1984">Demon Kill Demon: Yomi 1984</a></em>, which is due out for <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,258 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on May 28 in Japan. <span id="more-1022823"></span></p><p>As <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/demon-kill-demon-yomi-1984-launches-for-switch-on-may-28-in-japan">previously announced</a>, the game is set in 1984, five years after the events of <em><a title="Games > Undernauts: Labyrinth of Yomi [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/undernauts-labyrinth-of-yomi">Undernauts: Labyrinth of Yomi</a></em>. The story is set in Yomi once again. Players will use the power of the dreadful “Demon” that dwells within them to move forward and survive the dangerous dungeon.</p><p>Watch the teaser trailer below.</p><h2><span>Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Switch 『デモンキルデモン ～黄泉１９８４～』　ティザーPV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J0fjPDePL9k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/demon-kill-demon-yomi-1984-teaser-trailer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo comments on Dispatch's Switch censorship]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-comments-on-dispatchs-switch-censorship</link>
            <guid>1420867</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Getting things off its chest.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Project-(17).jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Project-(17).jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Project-(17).jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Project-(17).jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Project-(17).jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Project-(17).jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Project-(17).jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Project-(17).jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Project-(17).jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nintendo has released a statement regarding the recent censorship of AdHoc's Dispatch on Switch and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a>.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Dispatch released on Switch consoles. However, many were disappointed to learn there would be some censorship differences on Nintendo's platforms. In versions of the game as it appears on other platforms, there is an option for players to toggle censorship of  explicit content on or off. In the case of Nintendo, though, players were not given this choice, with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dispatch-switch-switch-2-censored-adhoc-comment">explicit content censorship being implemented in Dispatch as standard</a>. This saw black boxes covering characters' exposed breasts and penises, while noises of sexual pleasure were toned down.</p>
<p>At this time, AdHoc said this would not impact Dispatch's gameplay or narrative, stating these "core" experiences remain "identical to the original release".</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>Nintendo has now shared its own statement regarding the Dispatch discourse. "Nintendo requires all games on its platforms to receive ratings from independent organisations and to meet our established content and platform guidelines," a company spokesperson said in a statement shared with <a href="https://www.gonintendo.com/contents/57182-nintendo-shares-statement-on-dispatch-censorship-debacle-and-it-doesn-t-explain-much">GoNintendo</a>.</p>
<p>"While we inform partners when their titles don't meet our guidelines, Nintendo does not make changes to partner content. We also do not discuss specific content or the criteria used in making these determinations."</p>
<p>When it first came to attention that Dispatch would be automatically censored on Switch consoles, many were keen to point out that other games which also featured displays of nudity had not been met with the same stipulations. Games such as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, in which players can customise their Vs genitalia and more, are not censored on Switch consoles in the way Dispatch has been.</p><p>That being said, a specific Japanese version of Cyberpunk 2077 was released separately from the game's standard version, which removed nudity and decapitations. Therefore, some have speculated Dispatch's censorship issues may have come down to AdHoc not wishing to create a separate release of the game for Japan only. Again, though, this is speculation.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>AdHoc</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Many of us here at Eurogamer are big fans of Dispatch, and we are far from alone. Soon after its initial release last year, AdHoc announced <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/is-episodic-gaming-back-on-the-map-ex-wolf-among-us-devs-superhero-workplace-comedy-dispatch-sells-big-to-become-a-well-deserved-smash">Dispatch had sold over 1m copies in just 10 days</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks to this success, the studio is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dispatch-dev-adhoc-set-on-season-2-but-has-difficult-second-album-problem">now considering a second season</a> (perhaps one with more sex scenes, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dispatch-writer-regrets-cutting-sex-scenes">given the "ravenous" response to the first season</a>).</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-comments-on-dispatchs-switch-censorship]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon Journey lets you explore the real Mars today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/30/horizon-journey-lets-you-explore-the-real-mars-today/</link>
            <guid>1420846</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Survival games are not a rare commodity, nor are games set on Mars, but what if you could explore the real surface of the Red Planet in a simulation game? That’s the premise for Horizon Journey, which launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1769960/Horizon_Journey/">Steam Early Access</a> today, 30th January 2026.</p>
<p><iframe title="Horizon Journey - Anouncement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7lb32WTnYZs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The game has been built using NASA-based environmental data and has you facing the extremes you would find on Mars, from drastic temperature variations to fierce dust storms. These are on top of all the usual survival game requirements such as food and health. </p>
<p>“During your journey you’ll discover and expand the N16 base using modular corridor systems, including Labs, Storage, and Crafting modules. Plus, you’ll have the chance to utilise rovers and drones to scan the terrain and navigate the mysteries hidden within the Martian landscape,” say Redivded Studios. </p>

<p>The Early Access version will give you a 4km² region of Mars to explore with a focused narrative that requires the player to investigating a sudden loss of communication with the Endeavor-16 expedition. The full game will launch later this year with a global terraforming system, expanded colony infrastructure, and a Sandbox Mode.</p>

		
		

<p><em>Source: Press release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/30/horizon-journey-lets-you-explore-the-real-mars-today/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google's 'Project Genie' Is Basically A Huge Plagiarism Tool, So When Will Nintendo's Legal Ninjas Strike?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/googles-project-genie-is-basically-a-huge-plagiarism-tool-so-when-will-nintendos-legal-ninjas-strike</link>
            <guid>1420840</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>...or have they been in touch already?</p>
</section><section>
<figure data-uuid="a9785c624173f"><a title="Google's 'Project Genie' Is Basically A Massive Plagiarism Tool, So When Will Nintendo's Legal Ninjas Strike? 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a9785c624173f/googles-project-genie-is-basically-a-massive-plagiarism-tool-so-when-will-nintendos-legal-ninjas-strike-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:s5xvwzyhy352e3yguorxm53o/post/3mdldcqidoc2o">Jay Peters</a></em></figcaption></figure><p>Google – a company so addicted to AI it's pushing it into places it's <a href="https://www.rd.com/article/google-gemini-is-reading-your-emails/">simply not wanted</a> – has just lifted the lid on Project Genie, a new Generative AI tool which is able to create playable 'gaming worlds' thanks to the fact that it has been trained (without permission, on the most part) on the billions of hours of footage that has been uploaded by users to YouTube over the decades.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/openai-is-trying-to-get-sued-nintendo-ip-floods-sora-2-video-generation-app">As was discovered when OpenAI released its Sora video creation tool a while back</a>, it's laughably easy to get Project Genie to spit out copyright-infringing footage.</p>
<p>As highlighted by <a href="https://kotaku.com/google-ai-genai-nintendo-zelda-breath-wild-mario-64-project-genie-2000664227">Kotaku</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/869726/google-ai-project-genie-3-world-model-hands-on?view_token=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJpZCI6ImZCakl0bmxFNGwiLCJwIjoiL25ld3MvODY5NzI2L2dvb2dsZS1haS1wcm9qZWN0LWdlbmllLTMtd29ybGQtbW9kZWwtaGFuZHMtb24iLCJleHAiOjE3NzAxNDAwNTYsImlhdCI6MTc2OTcwODA1OH0.q5OBTD_V36-65oc1EGqPxKYCZF00c7ODvifvagVcwbA&amp;utm_medium=gift-link">The Verge's Jay Peters</a> – who has been given early access to the tool – has gleefully posted that he was able to "generate a bunch of Nintendo-inspired games. Including one featuring Link with a paraglider!" The footage, as you can clearly see, is so close to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Breath of the Wild</a> it's <em>almost</em> funny.</p>

<p>The reaction online has been predictably negative.</p>



<p>Interestingly, Peters notes that there <em>are</em> guardrails present in Project Genie, and he wasn't able to rip off any old video game.</p>
<p>"Project Genie wouldn’t generate a world that I prompted with the scenario of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/kingdom_hearts_-_hd_1_5_plus_2_5_remix_-_cloud_version">Kingdom Hearts</a>," he explains. "When I removed the specific names of characters and wrote descriptions of them instead, Project Genie generated a thumbnail preview of the world featuring characters that were dead ringers for Sora (the series’ protagonist), Donald, Goofy, Jack Skellington, and Cloud. But when I tried to generate the actual experience, Project Genie blocked me."</p>
<p>He therefore quizzed Google on why the tool was perfectly happy to plagiarise Nintendo's IP without permission but not Disney's, and was told:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Project Genie is an experimental research prototype designed to follow prompts a user provides. As with all experiments, we are monitoring closely and listening to user feedback."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Peters adds that he was told that the tool is “trained primarily on publicly available data from the web,” which is almost certainly behind one of the big surprises in his Zelda video, as he explains:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"This probably partially explains why Link deployed his paraglider in my test, which surprised me. At a high level, the Genie model is constantly trying to predict the next frame, and I’m sure there are <em>many</em> videos of people jumping in <em>Breath of the Wild</em> and then gliding forward, which the model probably learned from."</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>Peters also notes that "shortly before publishing this article, Project Genie stopped letting me generate worlds based on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/super_mario_64">Super Mario 64</a> due to “interests of third-party content providers."</p>
<p>Perhaps Nintendo's legal team is already in touch, but it's nonetheless amazing that a company like Google is prepared to risk a battle of that stature when it launches new products like Project Genie.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:188848,193520,192960 @ 1769784305 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/googles-project-genie-is-basically-a-huge-plagiarism-tool-so-when-will-nintendos-legal-ninjas-strike]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MindsEye Will Reportedly Drop Publisher IO Interactive Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-dropping-io-interactive-report</link>
            <guid>1420837</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new report has emerged which claims that poorly-received actioner <em>MindsEye </em>could be about to drop its publisher, <em>Hitman </em>studio IO Interactive, with publishing duties to be handled by developer Build a Rocket Boy in future.</p><p>That's according to Insider Gaming's <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/build-a-rocket-boy-io-interactive/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Tom Henderson</a>, who cites "sources close to the impending news" and says that the decision is Build a Rocket Boy's rather than IO Interactive's.</p><p>According to Henderson, Build a Rocket Boy wants to "gain more control over its future" and "bring its publishing in-house", as well as continuing to work on updates and patches for <em>MindsEye </em>to improve the player experience. Apparently, that's not something the developer wants IO Interactive to be involved in.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mindseye-dropping-io-interactive-publisher-shooting.jpg?itok=SHZ2yNHV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mindseye-dropping-io-interactive-publisher-shooting.jpg?itok=UeKOv7DX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption><em>MindsEye </em>will reportedly drop IO Interactive as its publisher soon.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As part of the impending publisher split (which, it's worth noting, still hasn't been officially confirmed yet), <em>MindsEye</em>'s upcoming <em>Hitman </em>crossover, which was revealed <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/summer-game-fest-2025-recap" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="45995c50-0a0e-42c9-88b2-fd8ecef35756" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">during last year's Summer Game Fest</a>, will apparently be canceled.</p><p>Even if the decision to split with IO Interactive isn't being driven by the <em>Hitman </em>studio, I can't imagine the Danish publisher is too cut up about it. Back in September, IO <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/io-interactive-mindseye-third-party-publishing" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="d1ad39f7-38ad-44f2-9a4e-5aff2e0ed71d" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">indicated it might be done with third-party publishing</a> after <em>MindsEye</em>, so this is probably a boon as far as IO is concerned.</p><p>In case you need a reminder, <em>MindsEye </em>launched back in June last year, and its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-launch-messy" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="090d2e26-517c-4b1d-81d8-0c4c40228804" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">launch was chaotic, to say the least</a>. Players demanded refunds within hours of picking the game up, and sponsorships with streamers were pulled at the last second.</p><p>Developer Build a Rocket Boy subsequently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-build-a-rocket-boy-layoffs-report" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="cc20a09e-a602-4466-a53f-4fb3ccf68d58" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">laid off a wave of employees</a> just a few days after the game's release, and a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-failure-new-report" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="59a77c58-1d39-4df1-bb46-f97e1f2b82f7" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">BBC report in October</a> saw former BARB staff accusing the developer of excessive crunch and having "no coherent direction" during development.</p>
<p><em>MindsEye </em>is available to check out right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3265250/MindsEye/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/mindseye/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/store/mindseye/9PJ9WXK3V9FN" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and you can read our review of the game from back at launch <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/mindseye-review-mideye" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="43daca71-9368-49cb-b5cd-71e0fd646ef8" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">right here</a>.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mindseye-dropping-io-interactive-report]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bad Vibes]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/bad-vibes/</link>
            <guid>1420834</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<div>
					
					
					

					<article>
	
	<div>
		<p><em>"Operation Midway Blitz." "Operation Catch of the Day." "Operation Metro Surge." </em></p><p><em>These sound like moments from history that Rob would spend 10 minutes explaining to the rest of us on a podcast, when, in fact, it's the history that we're living through, the most thoroughly public display of state power and violence from the Trump administration—yet.</em></p><p><em>Where is hope in moments like this? How do you move through the day when the news endlessly loops clips of an American citizen being killed? </em></p><p><em>In a letter series written both in, around, and after the murders of Renee Nicole Good and Alex Pretti, Rob and Patrick try to figure that out. Sort of, anyway.</em></p><hr><p><strong>Rob, Jan. 15:</strong> The other day I was driving down to Boston for a doctor's appointment when the semi next to me let out a series of loud blasts from its horn. I briefly panicked, wondering if they were about to merge into my lane or if they'd spotted something up ahead that I couldn't see. Then I caught a bit of movement from the overpass we were approaching. There were people waving from behind a large sign made of pasteboard letters: GET ICE OUT FOREVER.</p><p>A few hours later I was at a grocery store in Lexington and overheard a customer talking to one of the stockers. He was describing being confronted by federal agents sometime recently. Finding himself suddenly surrounded by a bunch of guys getting out of government SUVs yelling at him and the people he was with. "I've heard that's what they do," the well-meaning older white lady said. "They travel in these packs and just swarm people." She then continued on, helpfully explaining the tactics of immigration agents to someone who had literally just gone through the experience. In its way it was a testament to the indomitable spirit of the northeast, where empathy is often expressed in the form of a book report on recent news stories that have upset your liberal interlocutor.</p><p>It's hard not to drive down Massachusetts Route 2, running from Boston through Lexington and Concord and not think about how 250 years ago the road was littered with British dead and swarming with Minutemen in response to provocations that are relatively tame compared to what we see daily on the news. The redcoats on Lexington Common were at least confronting an armed militia force when they opened fire. Jonathon Ross couldn't speak to a mom in a car full of children's toys for ten seconds before he decided to fire half a pistol clip into her at point-blank range. Somehow I don't think John Adams would have taken his case the way he did for the British sentries who carried out the Boston Massacre. Would loyalists have started a GoFundMe for them? "After seeing the woodcuts of the incident I think they were 1000 percent justified in using deadly force."</p><p>There are increasing stories that DHS is going to have another campaign in Boston in the coming weeks, not that its agents ever really left. They were here last year but their tactics have only gotten more aggressive. I feel like you can chart a path of escalation from what they were doing in Boston to what they did in Chicago to what they're doing in Minnesota. To live in an American city or a "blue" state right now is to know that the government sees your home as a stage for state violence and statements of moral and legal impunity. Life goes on, but I can't overstate the degree to which every conversation you have around here is in some way circling around the ongoing crisis. Hell, my doctor couldn't even give me my blood pressure check without caveating, "You know, when you consider the… everything… I think we can feel especially good about this result."</p><figure><figcaption><span>Photo by </span><a href="https://unsplash.com/@shootnmatch?ref=remapradio.com"><span>weston m</span></a><span> / </span><a href="https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=ghost&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=api-credit"><span>Unsplash</span></a></figcaption></figure><p><strong>Patrick, Jan. 16: </strong>I was at a PTA meeting for my kids’ school last week where the principal explained a recent decision by the Trump administration to gut a series of educational grants. Practically, it means the school’s Boys and Girls Club program, which primarily serves the 60% of low-income families whose kids attend our school, was going to run out of money soon. The grant subsidizes the program and means it’s “free” for families who need to take advantage of it. It’s not only a form of after care—they get a free meal.</p><p>The principal told us there were plans for a rainy day fund, plans for exploring other grants, longshot hopes a lawsuit against the administration would mean everything would turn out okay…but they were also staring at a situation where the program would have to start charging families to continue operating.&nbsp;</p><p>Is this a cut targeted at a blue state like Illinois, or part of a broader attack on education? I have no idea, man, and I’m not really interested in reading news articles to find out. I raised my hand to find out if there’s a way to personally contribute money to the so-called rainy day fund, and I was put in touch with someone who would tell me what steps to take next. My hope is to livestream a fundraiser in the next few weeks.</p><p>That, at least, feels like a tiny ray of hope. A way I can contribute. But…</p>
		<div>
	<h2><svg role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" height="1em" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><!--! Font Awesome Free 6.4.2 by @fontawesome - https://fontawesome.com License - https://fontawesome.com/license (Commercial License) Copyright 2023 Fonticons, Inc. --><path d="M144 144v48H304V144c0-44.2-35.8-80-80-80s-80 35.8-80 80zM80 192V144C80 64.5 144.5 0 224 0s144 64.5 144 144v48h16c35.3 0 64 28.7 64 64V448c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64H64c-35.3 0-64-28.7-64-64V256c0-35.3 28.7-64 64-64H80z"></path></svg>  Library, Zeal or Foundation tier</h2>
	<p>Subscribe at  Library, Zeal or Foundation tier(s) or above to access "Bad Vibes". You'll also get access to the full back catalog of that tier's content.</p>
	<p><a href="https://remapradio.com/signup/">Sign up now</a>
	<small>Already have an account? <a href="https://remapradio.com/#/portal/signin/">Sign in</a></small>
</p></div>
	</div>
</article>

				</div>
			<div id="notifications">
	<p>You’ve successfully subscribed to Remap</p>
	<p>Welcome back! You’ve successfully signed in.</p>
	<p>Great! You’ve successfully signed up.</p>
	<p>Success! Your email is updated.</p>
	<p>Your link has expired</p>
	<p>Success! Check your email for magic link to sign-in.</p>
</div>
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://remapradio.com/articles/bad-vibes/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Moves Odyssey Curved Gaming Monitor Into Clearance, 49″ G93SC Series Hits an All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-moves-odyssey-curved-gaming-monitor-into-clearance-49-g93sc-series-hits-an-all-time-low-2000664187</link>
            <guid>1420828</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Calling the Samsung Odyssey OLED G9 “ultra-wide” barely scratches the surface. This thing is enormous. At 49 inches across, it can dominate an entire desk. It’s the kind of monitor that makes dual-screen setups look quaint, delivering a single, seamless canvas that stretches far into your peripheral vision. Right now, it’s also far more affordable than usual. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/">The Odyssey OLED G9 normally sells for $1,249, but Amazon has dropped the price to $900, knocking a hefty $349 off the total for a limited time.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Lose Yourself in Super Wide Worlds</h2>
<p>That massive panel isn’t just about size for the sake of spectacle. The display runs at a resolution of 5120 by 1440, effectively matching two 27-inch QHD monitors fused together. Games and apps have room to breathe, and multitasking feels natural instead of cramped. The 1800R curve gently wraps around your field of view, making long gaming sessions feel immersive rather than overwhelming. It mirrors the way our eyes naturally take in our surroundings, pulling you deeper into sprawling open worlds or competitive arenas.</p>
<p>Speed is another major highlight. With a 240Hz refresh rate, the Odyssey OLED G9 is built for fluid motion and fast reactions. Paired with an ultra-low 0.03ms response time, on-screen action stays immediate and razor sharp even during frantic firefights or high-speed racing. NVIDIA G-Sync and AMD FreeSync Premium Pro support keep frames smooth and synchronized with your GPU, minimizing screen tearing and stutter so gameplay stays consistent and responsive.</p>



<p>The OLED panel itself elevates everything you put on screen. Blacks are truly black, whites are strikingly bright, and colors have a depth that standard LCDs struggle to match. Contrast is intense and precise, with light and dark areas kept tightly controlled. There’s no distracting glow or bleed around bright objects, which helps scenes look cleaner and more realistic. Games, movies, and even everyday desktop use benefit from the added clarity and vibrancy.</p>
<p>Connectivity is refreshingly flexible. The monitor includes HDMI 2.1, DisplayPort, and a built-in USB hub, making it easy to juggle multiple devices. You can keep a gaming PC, work laptop, and another device connected at the same time and switch between them effortlessly. The Odyssey OLED G9 can even detect active sources and automatically jump to the right input. For power users, picture-in-picture and split-screen options allow two different systems to share the display side by side.</p>
<p>Deals like this don’t come around often for flagship OLED gaming monitors. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/">Dropping from $1,249 to $900, the Samsung Odyssey OLED G9 becomes far more compelling for anyone ready to go all-in on a truly immersive setup.</a> For players who want size, speed, and image quality in one unapologetically massive package, this is a rare chance to save big.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-moves-odyssey-curved-gaming-monitor-into-clearance-49-g93sc-series-hits-an-all-time-low-2000664187]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Has Reportedly Surpassed 20 Million Copies Sold]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-has-reportedly-surpassed-20-million-copies-sold/</link>
            <guid>1420825</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>According to a new report, Helldivers 2 has crossed 20 million copies sold and brought in $700 million in revenue. </p>



<p>Helldivers 2 has emerged as one of the most inspiring success stories in the gaming industry recently. Its success has influenced other games, such as ARC Raiders, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-ditched-free-to-play-because-of-helldivers-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to abandon a free-to-play model</a> in favor of a reasonably priced one. This approach has made a significant impact and has seemingly contributed to reaching a major milestone today.</p>







<h2 id="h-helldivers-2-crosses-20-million-copies-and-700-million-in-revenue">Helldivers 2 Crosses 20 Million Copies and $700 Million in Revenue</h2>



<p><a href="https://alineaanalytics.substack.com/p/helldivers-2-sells-20m-copies" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Alinea Analytics</a> has reported the latest sales figures for Helldivers 2. The game has surpassed the 20 million sales benchmark, with the Xbox release helping it cross the threshold, accounting for 1.6 million units sold since launch. In the past month, Helldivers 2 has attracted over 3.6 million players across Steam, PS5, and Xbox platforms. Additionally, estimates indicate that more than 250,000 players have logged over 500 hours in the game.</p>



<p>Sales figures for various platforms have been announced, with Steam continuing to dominate the market. Steam alone sold 13.1 million copies, while PlayStation accounted for an additional 5.6 million. Notably, the Xbox launch was faster-selling during the first eight days than the PlayStation launch. Additionally, China played a significant role in boosting Steam sales, with 10% of Steam players coming from the country.</p>







<p>In other news, <span>the developers of Helldivers 2 have spoken about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-devs-have-plans-to-extend-vehicle-gameplay/" target="_blank">extending the&nbsp;</a></span><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-devs-have-plans-to-extend-vehicle-gameplay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">vehicle gameplay</a>. Additionally, Arrowhead has talked about working on a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-devs-are-working-on-a-rogue-lite-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rogue-lite mode</a> for the title. What are your thoughts on Helldivers 2 surpassing 20 million copies? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/build-a-rocket-boy-io-interactive/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming’s exclusive report on Build a Rocket Boy deciding to part ways with their publisher, IO Interactive</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-has-reportedly-surpassed-20-million-copies-sold/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 76 goes free to celebrate TV show's season 2 conclusion, adds a $30 cosmetic cameo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-76-goes-free-to-celebrate-tv-shows-season-2-conclusion-adds-a-30-cosmetic-cameo</link>
            <guid>1420816</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-season-2-ncr-power-armor.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-season-2-ncr-power-armor.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-season-2-ncr-power-armor.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-season-2-ncr-power-armor.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-season-2-ncr-power-armor.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-season-2-ncr-power-armor.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-season-2-ncr-power-armor.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-season-2-ncr-power-armor.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-season-2-ncr-power-armor.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Amazon MGM Studios / Bethesda</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>To celebrate the conclusion of the Fallout show's second season, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-76">Fallout 76</a> has gone free-to-play for a limited time. It also gained a new $30 DLC pack featuring a camo from the series.</p>
<p>The free-to-play period, which has already started and will last until the 5th February for Xbox and PC players (and the 4th February on PlayStation). You'll have access to all the released updates for the game, giving a pretty substantial peek into what Fallout 76 has got going on.</p>
<p>For those jumping in that are super fans of the Amazon show, the NCR power armour is available too! You'll have to bust out the wallet for it though, as it's part of the new Mojave bundle. It contains the power armour, as well as the ranger power armour paint, NCR flag, New Vegas neon sign, Ad Victoriam super sledge, legion legate outfit, and player titles.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Watch Eurogamer's video on Fallout 76 Burning Springs.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BmgbbMFS5x0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>That bundle costs $30. Steam reviews for the bundle currently lie at Mostly Positive, but taking a look at the reviews themselves paint a mixed picture.<a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/CirillaFionaElenRiannon/recommended/4250650/"> Some have added a phrase from the show</a>: "Never underestimate the power of brand recognition", <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/moonlitfrappe/recommended/4250650/">while others</a> wish they could buy the NCR power armour on its lonesome: "Only bought it for the Ranger armor, should've been in the atomic shop/earned via quest. I'm tired of Fallout being the staple of microtransactions franchise for content."</p><p>Amazon recent went to great lengths to tempt stragglers in to watch the popular Fallout show recently <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/you-can-watch-the-first-season-of-amazons-excellent-fallout-adaptation-free-on-youtube-but-act-quickly-as-it-wont-be-there-for-long">by uploading season one to YouTube</a>, though only for a limited time. As for Fallout 76, it recently received its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-76s-new-update-features-walton-goggins-as-the-ghoul-from-amazons-tv-series">Fallout show themed Burning Springs update</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-76-goes-free-to-celebrate-tv-shows-season-2-conclusion-adds-a-30-cosmetic-cameo]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero Version 2.6 Brings Two New Agents and More in February]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-2-6-release-date</link>
            <guid>1420801</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The release date for <em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>Version 2.6 has been officially revealed, and you can look forward to new Agents, an exciting new rhythm-based adventure, and much more.</p><p>Following on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-25-release-date" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="744db640-1a04-4b35-93b7-05bfbb2fae4f" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">December's Version 2.5</a>, <em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>Version 2.6 will arrive on February 6th, and it'll revolve around the in-game Angels of Delusion musical group, which is preparing for its first live performance "under the guidance of an enigmatic vocal coach".</p><p>You'll be helping the Angels of Delusion with their "training schedules and social media activities", participating in a new rhythm-driven gameplay mode as you work through the events of the so-called "A Harmony of Delusions" centerpiece.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-2.6-release-date-angels-of-delusion.jpg?itok=HtpAB9zW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/zenless-zone-zero-version-2.6-release-date-angels-of-delusion.jpg?itok=IPBC-Cwg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption><em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>Version 2.6 will have you helping to manage the Angels of Delusion.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Two new Agents will make their debut in <em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>Version 2.6. The first, Sunna, is an S-Rank Physical Support Agent who can grant big buffs to party members and facilitate quicker switching of characters with her Ultimate.</p><p>She's joined by Aria, the lead vocalist of the Angels of Delusion, who's an Ether Anomaly Agent with two distinct forms. Unlike Sunna, Aria is all about dealing big damage, so if you like to tackle problems head-on, she's your fighter.</p><p>Reruns for Yixuan and Yuzuha will be appearing as part of this Version cycle's banners, and the Bangboo Biggest Fan will also be added to the game as part of this update, complete with an HP restoration ability and an attack boost around Angels of Delusion.</p><p>A number of other bonuses and activities, including a chance to earn Polychromes for logging in and completing daily challenges, will be introduced as part of Version 2.6 as well. Suffice it to say that it's all go in <em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>land.</p>
<p><em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>is available to <a href="https://zenless.hoyoverse.com/en-us/main" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">play right now for free</a> on PC, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and mobile devices. Version 2.6, "Encore for an Old Dream", arrives on all platforms on February 6th.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zenless-zone-zero-version-2-6-release-date]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Clears Out 45W Nintendo Switch Charger at Record Low, Compatible With Switch Lite and Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-clears-out-45w-nintendo-switch-charger-at-record-low-compatible-with-switch-lite-and-steam-deck-2000664238</link>
            <guid>1420798</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Powering your Switch doesn’t have to be complicated. While you technically can power your console with any third-party USB charger or a power bank, you’ll get the best performance with only a few. The 45W Nintendo charger by Marsdock is one of the most reliable options around.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6960/">It typically sits at an already affordable price of $17, but you can now grab it for only $14 at Amazon – thanks to a 15% discount.</a> This offer applies to the option that includes a 5-foot cable. If you’re looking for something that’s a bit longer, the 10-foot is available for $17, down from $19. Grabbing two of these will knock another 6% off your total. Prime members can enjoy free delivery with their purchase, which brings the overall cost down even further.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6960/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Speedy and Reliable</h2>
<p>For under $15, you’ll enjoy high-speed charging. It gets your consoles from 0 to 50% in just an hour, offering significantly greater charging stability and higher efficiency than the standard 39W options. The adapter supports input from 100-240V and output up to 15V/2.6A, which makes it great for everyday gaming and travel. Compatibility is just as impressive, as the charger plays nicely with most devices that can be charged under 45W via USB-C. These include Switch, Switch OLED, Switch Lite, Switch TV dock, Steam Deck, and Switch Pro Controller.</p>



<p>Marsdock takes durability seriously with this one, too. The premium cord is rated for over 2000 bends, which ensures longevity, while the solid, well-fitting plug maintains safety and offers efficient power transfer. Additionally, there are built-in multi-safeguards and a cooling system that intelligently monitors temperature, offering protection against overcharging, short circuiting, overheating, and sparking. Basically, you can use the charger anywhere, anytime, without worry.</p>
<p>Included in the box are the 45W AC power adapter, with a 5ft AC extension cord. On a regular day, you’d pay around $17 to enjoy the convenience and fast speeds this charger offers, which is already quite affordable. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6960/">The current 15% discount, however, drops it to just $14.</a> Amazon has listed the discount as a limited-time offer, so it’s best to grab it without wasting much time. Now is also a great time to stock up on other gaming accessories and essentials, as we’re spotting quite a lot going for less at the retailer. We’re covering the best offers that are worth your hard-earned money, so be sure to check back for the latest drops!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6960/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-clears-out-45w-nintendo-switch-charger-at-record-low-compatible-with-switch-lite-and-steam-deck-2000664238]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s The Last Chance To Buy The Nintendo Switch’s Best Deal]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-game-vouchers-last-day-save-money-2000664520</link>
            <guid>1420795</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Switch vouchers over a Mario Party background.</span> © Nintendo / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>The Nintendo Switch Game Voucher is <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-voucher-mario-kart-fire-emblem-discount-1850062170">one of those straight-up good deals</a>. If you’re a subscriber to Nintendo Switch Online, you can buy two coupons for $100, which can then be used to buy two full-price digital games more usually priced at $60 each. Boom, $20 saved, two new games to enjoy. And today, January 30, 2026, marks the very last day you can buy the vouchers. Boo.</p> <p>Back in July of last year, <a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-vouchers-pokemon-za-metroid-prime-4-preorder-1851785969">Nintendo announced its intention to kill off the voucher scheme</a> alongside the launch of the Switch 2. With newer game prices nudging up to $70 and $80, it was made immediately clear the vouchers would not be valid for Switch 2 games, but that it <em>would</em> still be possible to take advantage of the scheme for another six months, and that all vouchers bought would remain valid for a full year after the point of purchase. Well, that day has come, and if you want to be sure of a way to pick up a couple of full-price Switch games between now and 2027, this is your last chance. A huge thanks to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/reminder-todays-your-last-day-to-buy-switch-game-vouchers"><em>Nintendo Life</em></a> for reminding us of the deadline.</p>

 <p>It’s still a great offer! Nintendo very notably still hasn’t moved on to focusing its new titles on the Switch 2, and the vouchers will save you a chunk off the just-released <em>Metroid Prime 4</em>, and indeed on April 16’s&nbsp;<em>Tomodachi Life: Living the</em> Dream<a href="https://kotaku.com/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-direct-nintendo-2000664120">,</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-direct-nintendo-2000664120">which we learned new details about yesterday</a>. The vouchers are also valid on a really decent range of games including <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em>,&nbsp;<em>Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</em>,&nbsp;<em>Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</em>, and even the $70&nbsp;<em>Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em>. These are all first-party Nintendo titles which are&nbsp;very rarely put on sale.&nbsp;You can see the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/games/game-voucher-eligible/#sort=df&amp;p=0">lengthy full list of eligible titles here</a>.</p> <p>It’s a double-bummer that this isn’t being extended to the Switch 2, given Nintendo also killed off its <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendos-rewards-program-is-actually-pretty-good-1823654369">splendid gold coins</a>. These were accrued by buying new games, and every dollar spent got you 5c worth of coins. At its best, this meant spending the $100 needed to get two vouchers also got you another $5 off a purchase. Quite why Nintendo’s removed all these advantages and offered no new incentives on Switch 2 is unknown, and a massive disappointment.</p>

 <p>However, if you <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/nintendo-switch-game-vouchers/">buy a pair of vouchers today</a>, they will remain valid until Jan 30, 2027. That <em>Tomodachi Life</em> was added to the scheme so close to its demise is a sign that&nbsp;maybeNintendo might even put other new Switch 1 releases into the offer even after it can no longer be purchased. No guarantees, though.</p> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-game-vouchers-last-day-save-money-2000664520]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crimson Desert Promises the World, But How Much Will It Deliver?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-desert-promises-the-world-but-how-much-will-it-deliver</link>
            <guid>1420792</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Legend of Zelda. The Witcher. Dragon’s Dogma. Monster Hunter. Street Fighter. And now, GTA 5? Every time South Korean studio Pearl Abyss shows off a new slice of its upcoming open-world, action-adventure Crimson Desert, I feel like I see a new line of influence. Over the six years since its reveal, we’ve seen a fantasy land akin to one Geralt would explore, puzzle shrines in the sky that could easily hover above Hyrule, and a complex combat system rooted in Capcom classics. But in the developer’s latest lengthy video detailing the world of Pywel, a new surprise awaited us: the addition of two new playable characters to join Scottish Jon Snow-alike main protagonist, Kliff Macduff. With whole skillsets of their own for us to now anticipate getting our heads around, I can’t help but be excited, but also cautiously wary. By trying to do so much, does Crimson Desert risk achieving nothing?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I say this as someone who has had the benefit of seeing and playing Crimson Desert more than pretty much anyone outside of Pearl Abyss’ walls, having visited the studio a few months back for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/what-is-crimson-desert-hands-on-preview"><u>our IGN First</u></a>. Despite playing a good few hours of it, and having quite a lot of fun with its dynamic systems and satisfyingly flexible action, I still left feeling like I’d only scratched the surface of what Crimson Desert has in store. And I don’t mean that entirely positively – while it’s good to leave a preview knowing there’s plenty more to see, it’s not often you conclude a studio visit still unsure of a game’s big picture. If all those hours of hands-on haven’t successfully communicated what the game is, is something off?</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">We now know that Crimson Desert’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-deserts-open-world-is-at-least-twice-as-big-as-skyrims-and-larger-than-the-red-dead-redemption-2-map"><u>open world is twice the size of Skyrim’s and larger than Red Dead Redemption 2’s</u></a>. I’ve put over 200 hours into Rockstar’s Western masterpiece and feel like I still haven’t seen everything, so it’s anyone’s guess how much awaits in this world. Crimson Desert’s Pywel is a gorgeous piece of geography, too, with streets filled with life and rivers running with glistening water. That water is also systemically linked to the gameplay options, conducting lightning magic to electrocute those who stand in it, and is transformed into blocks of ice when struck by freezing spells. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s all very impressive on a technical level, but leaves me wondering if this is all part of a “we can put it in the game, so why shouldn’t we?” mentality. From what I played, and from talking to the team, the ability to manipulate the elements won’t necessarily have puzzles or challenges built around them to make it a system you’d legitimately find worthwhile. In Breath of the Wild or Tears of the Kingdom, for example, you know that if you’re taught how to make giant ice cubes, a puzzle shrine will likely follow asking you to put that lesson into action. Nintendo is a developer that has been making games like this for decades now, though, whereas Pearl Abyss is a studio in its relative infancy, having only released MMORPG Black Desert Online so far. By trying to fit everything it can think a player would like to do in a fantasy open world into Crimson Desert, I fear it may be shooting straight for the moon without learning how to get into orbit first.</p><p>The power trip is there; I just worry about the rest of the journey.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It all loops back to this latest revelation that not only will we be playing through Kliff’s story, but stepping into the shoes of two new protagonists along the way. The as-yet-unnamed characters with their own (presumably) complex fighting systems look very fun to play as, don’t get me wrong — I’m particularly drawn to the quick dodging, magic-shifting, pistol-wielding woman who appears at first glance to better fit my more rogue-ish tendencies — but it's yet another layer added on top of an already ambitious cake. I like cake, you can probably tell from a quick look at my face that that would be the case, but when it's stacked so high that even Bruce Bogtrotter would take a pass on it, I worry it's a sign that Crimson Desert should not be trying to have and eat it. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The other new playable hero is a hulking, giant axe-wielding brute with a machine gun attached to his wrist. If you’ve been keeping up with Crimson Desert, you’ll know that this isn’t your typical fantasy world, but one where <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-deserts-combat-explained"><u>dragons, steam trains, and mechs</u></a> also roam around. It’s all very exciting in isolation, and genuinely fun to play as your giant metal monsters come face-to-face with helpless medieval soldiers holding only a shield. The power trip is there; I just worry about the rest of the journey.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Story and questing are incredibly important to me when it comes to open-world games. The Witcher’s twisting tales and many memorable side stories are what make The Wild Hunt an all-timer in my eyes. The cast of characters in Red Dead Redemption 2 and the way they weave seamlessly in and out of its world are what make it my favourite game ever. Crimson Desert has a lot going for it — the combat is exciting, the world is diverse and beautiful, and its systems are impressively reactive — but I can’t help but feel wary. Most of the missions I’ve played so far, at several different events, have been castle sieges, often ending in admittedly impressive boss battles. But, they’ve all been relatively thin narrative-wise, aside from an interesting detour to a mad inventor’s lair where he’d built <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-desert-golden-star-quest-gameplay"><u>a golden mechanical dragon</u></a>, as you do. I’ve seen little of what’s going to be the thrust story-wise in Crimson Desert as a whole to get me hyped in that regard, nor met any characters that I feel will get close to my heart. And I can’t help but worry that there’s a reason we’ve seen so little of this world’s story. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, with the surprise addition of two extra playable protagonists to get to know on this adventure that is less than two months away, I worry that Kliff and his friends may well be fun to play as stylistically, but contain little substance within them. I’d be very happy to be wrong, though. I’ve been looking forward to Crimson Desert for a long time now, and have had a genuinely fun time whenever I’ve managed to get hands-on with it. I just wonder how all of these well-constructed building blocks will, in turn, create a greater whole. Will its gameplay systems overlap in interesting ways and be built into mission design? Will authorial intent come to the fore, or will I ultimately feel like a kid being dropped into a sandbox of possibilities with direction? I’m excited, just also a little afraid that by trying to be everything, it may end up achieving nothing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-desert-promises-the-world-but-how-much-will-it-deliver]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['We Remain Committed and Focused': Beyond Good & Evil 2 Creative Director Gives First Statement Since Ubisoft Reorganization]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/we-remain-committed-and-focused-beyond-good-evil-2-creative-director-gives-first-statement-since-ubisoft-reorganization</link>
            <guid>1420789</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/beyond-good-and-evil-2">Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2</a> creative director Fawzi Mesmar has responded to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-cancels-6-projects-including-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-closes-2-studios-and-confirms-further-layoffs-in-major-company-restructure">Ubisoft's sweeping company reshuffle</a> that resulted in the cancellation or delay of a swathe of game projects, as well as studio closures and layoffs — including a further <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-follows-last-weeks-game-cancelations-and-studio-closures-with-a-proposed-reduction-of-200-more-jobs-at-its-paris-headquarters">200 job losses proposed at the company's Paris headquarters this week</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Writing on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7421227406130335744/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a>, former DICE veteran Mesmar assured fans of Ubisoft's long-in-development Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 that the project had not been impacted in the restructure, as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/miraculous-beyond-good-evil-2-fans-cant-believe-the-game-has-survived-ubisofts-major-project-cull-that-killed-the-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake">had previously been expected</a>. Still, the developer said he was "saddened" by the reorganization's effects on his colleagues across the wider company.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With an on-again, off-again development stretching back almost two decades, Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 remains an ongoing project within Ubisoft, led by its French team based in Montpellier.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Thank you for everyone who has reached out to me over the past few days in regards to recent news at Ubisoft," Mesmar wrote. "Myself, my team and our project Beyond Good and Evil 2 are unaffected by the recent changes. I would direct you to the official press release for more information around the latest organisational structure."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This press release was the one which laid out Ubisoft leadership's vision for the company to be split into five "Creative Houses" that lump the publisher's many franchises into groups loosely based around their genre and audience.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last week, Beyond Good &amp; Evil was announced as being part of Creative House 4, a group dedicated to narrative driven and fantasy-orientated series that also includes Anno, Might &amp; Magic, Rayman and Prince of Persia (though not the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake">Prince of Persia: Sands of Time Remake</a>, which was canned).</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Beyond Good and Evil 2 Concept Art</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Needless to say, I am saddened by the cancellations that has affected my colleagues in other parts of Ubisoft and the industry," Mesmar continued. "I urge everyone — myself included — to offer support whenever and however they can during these times. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We remain committed and focused on delivering a remarkable game for our players to enjoy," he concluded.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 originally begun early development in 2007, with series creator and Rayman mastermind Michel Ancel on board alongside the majority of the Montpellier team behind the first Beyond Good &amp; Evil game. Development was put on the back burner while Ancel's team worked on other projects, but Ubisoft re-announced the game with fanfare in 2017 and showed off an in-engine concept featuring space flight and designs to feature multiple solar systems and planets.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Again, however, development struggled — and the project was further impacted by Ancel's departure from Ubisoft and the sad death of its subsequent creative lead Emil Morel. But the last couple of years have seen work coalesce once more, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/beyond-good-evil-20th-anniversary-edition-has-a-new-narrative-link-to-beyond-good-evil-2">the sequel's characters given intriguing cameos in the new Beyond Good &amp; Evil 20th Anniversary Edition</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/beyond-good-and-evil-2-gets-new-creative-director">the hiring of Mesmar as creative director</a> to steady the ship. That said, 20 years on from the original, there remains no word on when its follow-up will launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this week, an actress believed to have been working on the Prince of Persia: Sands of Time Remake said that she had lost three years' worth of work and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/after-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-cancelation-actress-says-shes-lost-3-years-of-work-and-found-out-via-the-internet">discovered her project had been canceled after her brother read about Ubisoft's shock decision online</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/we-remain-committed-and-focused-beyond-good-evil-2-creative-director-gives-first-statement-since-ubisoft-reorganization]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AirPods 4 With ANC Carry the Biggest Discount in Apple’s Earbuds Lineup, Now at Its Lowest Price of the Year]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/airpods-4-with-anc-carry-the-biggest-discount-in-apples-earbuds-lineup-now-at-an-all-time-low-2000664296</link>
            <guid>1420765</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Apple AirPods 4 are wireless earbuds with Active Noise Cancellation in a compact form that is convenient to carry and use throughout the day. To enhance comfort and stability, Apple redesigned the AirPods 4 earbuds with a more defined shape and a shorter stem with easy-to-use press controls for playing music and answering calls. For a quieter experience, the Active Noise Cancellation feature helps reduce external sounds as they reach your ears. If you prefer to stay aware of your surroundings, Transparency Mode lets you listen to what is happening around you while continuing to listen to your music.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6034/">You can purchase the Apple AirPods 4 at Amazon for $119. This is a savings of $60 and 34% off of their original price of $179.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6034/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Some of Apple’s best earbuds for calls, music, podcasts, and more</h2>
<p>AirPods 4 have an optical in-ear sensor that ensures they play audio only when the earbuds are worn and pause when they are removed. They feature a vent system designed for pressure-balanced sound, which can make extended listening feel much more comfortable. Plus, there are physical controls that let you perform common actions, such as controlling music playback and managing calls, without having to access your phone.</p>
<p>With Active Noise Cancellation, the Adaptive Audio feature combines noise cancellation with Transparency Mode to adapt to your surroundings. Conversation Awareness can automatically lower the volume of what you are listening to when you begin talking with someone nearby, and then raise it back up after you stop speaking. Voice Isolation uses computational audio to minimize ambient noise and improve clarity in noisy environments.</p>



<p>For music, TV programs, movies, and video games, Personalized Spatial Audio features dynamic head tracking to place sound around you. The high-excursion driver, high-dynamic-range amplifier, and Adaptive EQ work together to deliver a consistent, balanced sound that adapts to how well each AirPod fits your ears. The H2 headphone chip supports the processing required for spatial effects and noise reduction.</p>
<p>The USB-C charging case provides additional battery life, extending how long you can listen. With Active Noise Cancellation, you can expect up to 4 hours of listening time and up to 20 hours with the charging case. Five minutes of charging can provide approximately one hour of listening time.</p>
<p>Hands-free Siri can be activated with either “Siri” or “Hey Siri.” Also, with Siri Interactions, you can respond with a nod yes or a gentle shake no. Audio Sharing lets you share audio with two AirPods. Find My lets you locate your AirPods 4 and the charging case<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6034/">. The AirPods 4 and the charging case are both rated IP54 for dust, sweat, and water resistance. Now’s a great time to buy the AirPods 4, as they’re currently $119, down from $179.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6034/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/airpods-4-with-anc-carry-the-biggest-discount-in-apples-earbuds-lineup-now-at-an-all-time-low-2000664296]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PUBG: Blindspot Release Date Countdown & Exact Start Times]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pubg-blindspot-release-date-start-times/</link>
            <guid>1420762</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new PUBG experience is on the horizon with PUBG: Blindspot, with the release date for early access in the title rapidly approaching.</p>



<p>PUBG: Blindspot is the latest release from developers ARC Team and PUBG Corporation, moving away from the established Battle Royale approach to offer a 5v5 top-down tactical shooter.</p>



<p>For all the details on the release date of PUBG: Blindspot, and the exact time you can dive in and start playing, Insider Gaming has you covered with all the key information.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-the-pubg-blindspot-release-date">What is The PUBG: Blindspot Release Date?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Coming soon. Image via PUBG Corporation</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>PUBG: Blindspot releases into early access on February 5, 2026, though the precise date will vary depending on where you are located in the world.</strong></p>



<p>PUBG: Blindspot’s early access release is exclusively available on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PC</a>, with no news of a console release yet, but there is still some variation to the release date.</p>



<p>This is due to PUBG: Blindspot, like other <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a> releases, having a global release structure, and not a staggered release like players on consoles usually experience.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-time-does-pubg-blindspot-release">What Time Does PUBG: Blindspot Release?</h2>



<p><strong>PUBG: Blindspot will be released at 9 PM PT on February 4, with the majority of players in the United States able to jump in before the official release date the following day.</strong></p>



<p>Those in the Central US will be able to jump in on that date, with those on the East Coast having to wait until midnight. Meanwhile, those in Europe have a release in the early hours of the morning, and gamers in the Pacific and Australia face a mid-afternoon release.</p>



<p>All times for the release come through <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/3143710/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>, which is always a reliable source for this type of information, though, as this is an early access release, the times may be subject to change. If there are any adjustments, all the details in this article will be updated.</p>



<p>The table below has the exact release times for PUBG: Blindspot in major time zones across the world.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Release Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">9 PM – Feb. 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">11 PM – Feb. 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">12 AM – Feb. 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">5 AM – Feb. 5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (AET)</td><td data-align="center">4 PM – Feb. 5</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<hr>



<p>What are your expectations for the release of PUBG: Blindspot? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mewgenics-release-date-start-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date details for Mewgenics</a>, and find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-to-beat-cairn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how long it takes to beat Cairn</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pubg-blindspot-release-date-start-times/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>