<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:19:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD FSR 4 Will Be Used in PS5 Pro Games Next Year, Reveals Sony’s Mark Cerny]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-4-will-be-used-in-ps5-pro-games-next-year-reveals-sonys-mark-cerny/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amd-fsr-4-will-be-used-in-ps5-pro-games-next-year-reveals-sony%E2%80%99s-mark-cerny.1130244/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-4-will-be-used-in-ps5-pro-games-next-year-reveals-sonys-mark-cerny/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following the <a href="https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-4-confirmed-to-have-been-co-developed-with-sony/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmation</a> that AMD FSR 4 had been co-developed with Sony as part of the wider machine learning Project Amethyst collaboration, PlayStation 5 Pro System Architect Mark Cerny revealed today <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-mark-cerny-fsr-4-to-play-a-key-part-in-the-next-evolution-of-pssr-upscaling" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in an interview with Digital Foundry</a> that AMD's latest upscaling technology will be introduced to the most powerful console currently on the market in 2026.</p>
<p>This year, Sony plans to focus on helping developers implement the current version of PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution (PSSR), but they are already working on the future implementation of AMD FSR 4, or rather, its equivalent tailored for the PS5 Pro console:</p>
<p><em>Our target is to have something very similar to FSR 4's upscaler available on PS5 Pro for 2026 titles as the next evolution of PSSR; it should take the same inputs and produce essentially the same outputs. Doing that implementation is rather ambitious and time consuming, which is why you haven't already seen this new upscaler on PS5 Pro.</em></p>
<p><em>RDNA 4 and the hardware in PS5 Pro are completely separate designs, which is why I speak in terms of 'reimplementation' on PS5 Pro when I talk about the new upscaling network used in AMD FSR 4. I’m definitely looking forward to a future with co-developed hardware features for machine learning that will dramatically increase the interoperability.</em></p>
<p>When questioned about whether the console could handle the increased computational cost of AMD FSR 4, Cerny expressed confidence that the PS5 Pro's 300 8-bit TOPS would make it work. Later in the Q&amp;A, the programmer and game designer returned to discuss both short-term and long-term objectives that are part of Project Amethyst (<a href="https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-lead-architect-mark-cerny-unveils-codename-amethyst-ml-collaboration-with-amd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed a few months ago</a>):</p>
<p><em>The shorter-term goal is to co-develop neural network architectures and training strategies for game graphics. The longer-term goal is to work together to create a more ideal hardware architecture for machine learning, something capable of processing the neural networks needed for game graphics at high speed. PS5 Pro was a wonderful learning experience for us here at SIE, and of course, AMD has an incredible amount of knowledge from its multi-generation RDNA roadmap. Again, it just makes sense to combine those expertises. [...] AMD FSR 4 and this next evolution of PSSR are a paradigm for our future. Going forward, we expect to have our own implementations of each of the algorithms developed through the collaboration.</em></p>
<p>Closing up, he added there might be quite a few tweaks because technical targets for console and PC games are quite different. For example, 60FPS is still believed to be the golden standard for consoles, while PC games aim much higher nowadays.</p>
<p>With FSR 4, AMD definitely <a href="https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-4-better-fsr3-dlss-cnn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">closed the gap with NVIDIA</a>, although the latest DLSS 4 transformer model and the GeForce RTX 50's Multi Frame Generation keep the Green Team ahead. Still, NVIDIA will have to continue investing in advancements, something that users should be thankful for.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite is set to return to Brazilian iPhones]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/626935/epic-games-fortnite-store-brazil-apple-ios</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-set-to-return-to-brazilian-iphones.1130241/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/626935/epic-games-fortnite-store-brazil-apple-ios<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Epic Games plans to bring its mobile game store and <em>Fortnite</em> to iOS users in Brazil in July, the company says <a href="https://x.com/Fortnite/status/1899083361982808390">in a post on X</a>. The announcement follows a ruling in Brazil last week that gave Apple 90 days to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/625753/apple-ios-alternative-app-stores-sideloading-brazil">allow sideloading in the country</a>.</p><p>Last year, Epic brought back <em>Fortnite</em> and launched <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/16/24221361/fortnite-iphone-epic-games-app-store">the mobile Epic Games Store</a> on iOS in the EU in August after Apple was forced to allow third-party app stores in the EU to comply with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/25/24050200/apple-third-party-app-stores-allowed-iphone-ios-europe-digital-markets-act">the Digital Markets Act</a>.</p><p>The judge who issued the ruling in Brazil said that “Apple has already complied with similar obligations in other countries without demonstrating significant impact or irreparable harm to its economic model.” Apple plans to appeal the ruling.</p><p>The Epic Games Store launched on iPad in the EU <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/17/24247062/epic-games-store-ipad-eu-fortnite">in September</a>. Epic has also brought back <em>Fortnite</em> and launched the Epic Games Store on Android, but those are both available globally.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Super Mario Game Ranked From Worst To Best]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-super-mario-bros-best-ranked-odyssey-1850286446</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-super-mario-game-ranked-from-worst-to-best.1130232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-super-mario-bros-best-ranked-odyssey-1850286446<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="48843d1be25326a64b077f7c9c7f890b" data-recommend-id="image://48843d1be25326a64b077f7c9c7f890b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario, Peach, Yoshi, and Luigi float above dozens of Super Mario-series games." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario, Peach, Yoshi, and Luigi float above dozens of Super Mario-series games." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="shutterstock" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku / Telnov Oleksii<!-- --> (<!-- -->Shutterstock<!-- -->)</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="48843d1be25326a64b077f7c9c7f890b" data-recommend-id="image://48843d1be25326a64b077f7c9c7f890b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario, Peach, Yoshi, and Luigi float above dozens of Super Mario-series games." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>For a long time, the word “Nintendo” was synonymous with video games, and Nintendo has always been shorthand for Mario. The Japanese console mainstay has published dozens of platformers starring the overall-loving plumber since his original debut in 1981’s <em>Donkey Kong</em>, and we’re here to tell you which ones are the worst and best.<br></p><p><em> This ranking was originally published on March 31, 2023. We are re-publishing it today with the addition of </em>Super Mario Bros. Wonder<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-bundle-mario-day-sale-mk8-odyssey-wonder-1851768159&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-bundle-mario-day-sale-mk8-odyssey-wonder-1851768159"><em>for Mar10 Day 2025</em></a></span><em>.</em> </p><p>After connecting with his brother Luigi in 1983’s single-screen arcade hit <em>Mario Bros.</em>, Mario made the jump to consoles—and scrolling—in 1985’s NES adventure <em>Super Mario Bros.</em> Nearly 40 years and 25 games later, the <em>Super Mario</em> games comprise one of the longest running and most predictably spectacular series ever. From 2D to 3D, on good hardware and bad, Mario running, jumping, and collecting coins has been a constant not just for Nintendo, but in the fabric of the medium itself, driving it forward, inspiring it, reacting to what’s worked, and pushing back against what hasn’t. </p><p>Trying to rank the<em> Super Mario</em> games is like trying to rank flavors of ice cream. Some are clear favorites. Others are acquired tastes. Most are still better than whatever the alternative is. In putting together this list, which includes input from across <em>Kotaku</em>’s staff, as well as direct contributions from many of us, we tried to consider the games holistically: their historical context, their revolutionary or creative innovations, how well they hold up now, and the impressions they’ve left with us. </p><p>The ranking we arrived at is not beyond reproach and is far from scientific, but it is correct. Here we go!</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="2558199d590295fd743cef0c3f97855a" data-recommend-id="image://2558199d590295fd743cef0c3f97855a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2372" data-height="1334" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Screenshots show Mario jumping through levels in Super Mario Run. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Screenshots show Mario jumping through levels in Super Mario Run. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Mario Wiki / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2558199d590295fd743cef0c3f97855a" data-recommend-id="image://2558199d590295fd743cef0c3f97855a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2372" data-height="1334" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Screenshots show Mario jumping through levels in Super Mario Run. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Super Mario Run</em> is a brilliant attempt to make Nintendo’s mascot run and jump on a smartphone with just one input. It is also, without a doubt, the worst <em>Super Mario</em> game because making him run is half the fun. Do you want a peanut butter sandwich without jelly? Or chocolate cake without vanilla frosting? Here’s a gin and, uh, more gin.<br></p><p>The 2016 mobile game is a decent time waster and…that’s it. Perhaps that’s why Nintendo hasn’t made a sequel to it. Or maybe the Google Play and Apple App stores just remain completely hostile to premium experiences that don’t nickel and dime the user. In any event, Nintendo made <em>Super Mario Run </em>so we have to include it on this list and here it is. — Ethan Gach</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-run-is-really-good-1790147132&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-run-is-really-good-1790147132"><em>Super Mario Run</em>: The <em>Kotaku</em> Review</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="7fd2957687ce17b7d4295c1928968868" data-recommend-id="image://7fd2957687ce17b7d4295c1928968868" data-format="jpg" data-width="2123" data-height="1194" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario confronts a Thwomp blocking a coin. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario confronts a Thwomp blocking a coin. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7fd2957687ce17b7d4295c1928968868" data-recommend-id="image://7fd2957687ce17b7d4295c1928968868" data-format="jpg" data-width="2123" data-height="1194" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario confronts a Thwomp blocking a coin. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The <em>New</em> sub-series of<em> Super Mario Bros. </em>games had a penchant for over-promising and under-delivering.<em> </em>2012’s <em>New Super Mario Bros. 2 </em>was the worst offender in this regard. It’s comforting, but short, breezy, and at times insultingly easy and simplistic. The soundtrack is largely one song on repeat that will make you want to mute your 3DS sooner than later. The game is a coin collectathon above all else, and while the moment-to-moment gameplay can still be fun, there’s nothing really memorable, let alone new, about the third entry in the <em>New Super Mario Bros.</em> series. — Ethan Gach<br></p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/new-super-mario-bros-2-the-kotaku-review-5934327&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/new-super-mario-bros-2-the-kotaku-review-5934327"><em>New Super Mario Bros. 2</em>: The <em>Kotaku</em> Review</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="605814446ed3255596e563ac9ae3b944" data-recommend-id="image://605814446ed3255596e563ac9ae3b944" data-format="jpg" data-width="2123" data-height="1194" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario gets big and crashes through some blocks. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario gets big and crashes through some blocks. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="605814446ed3255596e563ac9ae3b944" data-recommend-id="image://605814446ed3255596e563ac9ae3b944" data-format="jpg" data-width="2123" data-height="1194" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario gets big and crashes through some blocks. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>It may sound strange now, but back in 2006, classic 2D-style video games still felt like a bit of an endangered species. Consider this: 11 whole years (!) had passed since the <em>Super Mario</em> series’ last original side-scroller, <em>Yoshi’s Island</em>. You can see why folks were twitchy. As such, Nintendo announcing <em>New Super Mario Bros.</em> for its DS handheld made for a welcome surprise.<br></p><p>The game’s title alone was intriguing: no numbers, no subtitles, just the word “New” attached to the name of the side-scroller that changed everything back in ‘85. Indeed, this “new” <em>Super Mario Bros.</em> attempted something of a return to baseline, jettisoning some of the series’ later complications in favor of more basic <em>Mario</em> action. I wondered if it’d rekindle the deep enjoyment I had derived from the original NES trilogy.</p><p>It did not. While GameCube’s slightly troubled <em>Super Mario Sunshine</em> had exposed some cracks in the edifice, <em>New Super Mario Bros.</em> ended up being the first mainline <em>Mario</em> that felt inessential. Its straightforward level designs and basic run-jump-bop action came off as bland, and its new ideas proved a mixed lot. </p><p>The wall-jumping maneuver was inoffensive, but the new power-ups ranged from “who cares?” to actively detrimental: The mega-mushroom rampages were just mindless spectacle, the mini mushroom was simultaneously too powerful and a frustrating prerequisite for important shortcuts, and the unwieldy blue shell suit actively tried to send you careening off cliffs. I grew bored, and stopped playing around the sixth or seventh world.</p><p><em>New Super Mario Bros.</em> was a solid platform game by most standards and the start of a welcome revival for side-scrolling <em>Mario</em>. But it didn’t measure up to the very high standard of its predecessors. — Alexandra Hall</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-chief-mario-is-part-of-gamers-dna-5935721&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-chief-mario-is-part-of-gamers-dna-5935721">Nintendo Chief: Mario Is Part Of Gamers’ DNA</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="131cbabf6f3c2595d8a247c4818a6a4a" data-recommend-id="image://131cbabf6f3c2595d8a247c4818a6a4a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Game Boy screen displays Mario jumping through a spider tunnel. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Game Boy screen displays Mario jumping through a spider tunnel. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="131cbabf6f3c2595d8a247c4818a6a4a" data-recommend-id="image://131cbabf6f3c2595d8a247c4818a6a4a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Game Boy screen displays Mario jumping through a spider tunnel. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>It was 1989 and Nintendo Entertainment System mania was in full swing. For Nintendo’s next trick it introduced the Game Boy, a category-defining new portable cartridge system. The NES had rocketed to success, in part, on the strength of <em>Super Mario Bros.</em>, so Game Boy naturally launched with <em>Super Mario Land</em>, a bite-sized take on the platforming plumber.<br></p><p>Luckily <em>Super Mario Land</em> was quite good—heck, it eventually became the fourth best-selling Game Boy game (18 million!). The physics were kinda wonky, but the tiny Mario ran about nimbly, tossing ricocheting “superballs” at a strange new cast of bomb-shelled turtles, oversized insects, hopping kyonshi zombies, and a literal alien. It even had two mild but pleasant shoot ‘em up stages, in which Mario piloted subs and airplanes in hopes of rescuing a new princess, Daisy.</p><p>It turns out the weirdness was not just from the new platform, but because development was handled by Nintendo producer Gunpei Yokoi’s R&amp;D1 group rather than Shigeru Miyamoto’s EAD. (R&amp;D1 later made <em>Super Mario Land 2</em> and branched off into the <em>Wario</em> series.) <em>Super Mario Land</em> is as off-brand as <em>Mario</em> would ever get, and I’d say the better for it. This was also the first <em>Super Mario</em> game with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-land-was-a-bit-heavy-on-the-stereo-1845044987&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-land-was-a-bit-heavy-on-the-stereo-1845044987">(very good) stereo music</a></span>, and the first time western players—who’d missed out on Japan’s <em>Super Mario Bros. 2</em>—got to revisit the original adventure’s bricks-and-mushrooms formula.</p><p><em>Super Mario Land</em> was a slight but enjoyable jaunt which, in hindsight, feels a little outshone by the brilliant games that followed. That doesn’t mean Mario’s charming visit to Sarasaland wasn’t a great way to burn through another set of four double-As, though. — Alexandra Hall</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/game-boy-color-advance-nintendo-switch-online-direct-1850090977?rev=1675895622264&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/game-boy-color-advance-nintendo-switch-online-direct-1850090977?rev=1675895622264">Game Boy Games Have Arrived On The Switch </a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="73c08af6abfce95da11a2c1b7a306426" data-recommend-id="image://73c08af6abfce95da11a2c1b7a306426" data-format="jpg" data-width="1621" data-height="912" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Toads scurry between Piranha plants to catch up with Mario" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Toads scurry between Piranha plants to catch up with Mario" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="73c08af6abfce95da11a2c1b7a306426" data-recommend-id="image://73c08af6abfce95da11a2c1b7a306426" data-format="jpg" data-width="1621" data-height="912" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Toads scurry between Piranha plants to catch up with Mario" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Wedged in-between the release of two of the best 3D Mario games ever, 2009’s <em>New Super Mario Bros. Wii</em> offered console players their first full-fledged return to 2D <em>Super Mario</em> action in well over a decade. This second entry in the <em>New Super Mario Bros.</em> series was beefy compared to its handheld predecessor.. The new jump-spin technique added more nuance to navigation and wild, four-player co-op (or was it?) offered a completely different way to enjoy the carefully paced, but sometimes rote levels. If <em>New Super Mario Bros. Wii</em> didn’t quite manage to shed the charges of blandness that dogged the DS game, its heavy helping of chaotic multiplayer mayhem made for a pleasant consolation prize. — Ethan Gach</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong>&nbsp;<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/new-super-mario-bros-wii-review-go-buy-a-wii-5403839&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/new-super-mario-bros-wii-review-go-buy-a-wii-5403839">New <em>Super Mario Bros. Wii</em> Review: Go Buy A Wii</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="ab17342f30778c0723d4f727e1051057" data-recommend-id="image://ab17342f30778c0723d4f727e1051057" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario jumps over water while floating in a bubble. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario jumps over water while floating in a bubble. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ab17342f30778c0723d4f727e1051057" data-recommend-id="image://ab17342f30778c0723d4f727e1051057" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario jumps over water while floating in a bubble. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Building on the success of the first <em>Super Mario Land</em>, <em>6 Golden Coins</em> carved out a cult-classic niche for itself by living halfway between all-time greats <em>Super Mario Bros. 3</em> and <em>Super Mario World</em> and introducing flatulent bad boy Wario to the world. A much more sophisticated affair than its predecessor, you can now roam a world map, scroll in all directions, and occasionally find secret exits that unlock hidden levels.<br></p><p><em>Mario Land 2</em> oozes personality from top to bottom, with memorable overworld maps and detailed sprites, including Wario’s own imposing and garish figure. Rather than just feel like a fun but inferior approximation of the console<em> </em>2D <em>Super Mario </em>experience, Nintendo R&amp;D1’s <em>6 Golden Coins</em> feels like the series reflected through <em>Alice in Wonderland</em>’s looking glass, complete with a unique musical soundtrack and rewardingly goofy boss fights. — Ethan Gach</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/wario-voice-charles-martinet-nintendo-tesco-ds-wariowar-1848877413&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/wario-voice-charles-martinet-nintendo-tesco-ds-wariowar-1848877413">Wario’s Big Speaking Role For...A British Supermarket</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8f2e12fda73e856f3a53f3701eba73bf" data-recommend-id="image://8f2e12fda73e856f3a53f3701eba73bf" data-format="jpg" data-width="2123" data-height="1194" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Goomba looks menacingly at Mario. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Goomba looks menacingly at Mario. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8f2e12fda73e856f3a53f3701eba73bf" data-recommend-id="image://8f2e12fda73e856f3a53f3701eba73bf" data-format="jpg" data-width="2123" data-height="1194" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Goomba looks menacingly at Mario. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Super Mario 3D Land </em>is now overshadowed by its bigger, better successor for the Wii U and Switch, and because it’s relegated to the 3DS, it may soon become one of the least-accessible mainline <em>Mario</em> games, doomed to relative obscurity. But when it arrived in 2011, <em>3D Land </em>was one of the best titles for Nintendo’s gimmicky dual-screen handheld.<br></p><p>A game of small but satisfying stages perfect for play on the go, it took a refreshingly different approach to 3D <em>Mario</em> platforming than games like <em>Sunshine </em>and <em>Galaxy </em>had, one rooted more in the design principles of early 2D <em>Mario</em> games. Today in some ways it feels like a strong proof of concept, establishing ideas that would be more fully realized in <em>3D World</em>. But if you ever find yourself with a hankering for some <em>Super Mario</em> action and only a 3DS at your disposal, you could do a lot worse than this charming and innovative pleaser. — Carolyn Petit</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-3d-land-the-kotaku-review-5860126&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-3d-land-the-kotaku-review-5860126"><em>Super Mario 3D Land</em>: The<em> Kotaku</em> Review</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="2672f0334a61dc03175537c3e75ff916" data-recommend-id="image://2672f0334a61dc03175537c3e75ff916" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Luigi sprints across a moonlit ice course. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Luigi sprints across a moonlit ice course. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2672f0334a61dc03175537c3e75ff916" data-recommend-id="image://2672f0334a61dc03175537c3e75ff916" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Luigi sprints across a moonlit ice course. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>By the time <em>New Super Mario Bros. U </em>came along, the whole <em>NSMB </em>series seemed pretty worthy of writing off. Their largely uninspired level design made the whole series feel like a soulless attempt to cash in on nostalgia for earlier <em>Super Mario</em> side-scrollers, with little understanding of what made people love those games in the first place.<br></p><p>That all went out the window with <em>New Super Mario Bros. U </em>(which, thankfully, is not relegated to the Wii U on which it was first released, having gotten a Switch incarnation in the form of <em>New Super Mario Bros. U Deluxe</em>). Here, at last, was new (and <em>New</em>) <em>Mario</em> platforming with lively, varied levels that also did one of the things Nintendo does best, presenting a fairly easy (but still fun and inventive) challenge that most players of different skill levels can complete to get the satisfaction of “beating Bowser,” while also providing an intensely challenging and rewarding quest for those who wanted to 100% the game and truly test their platforming skills. </p><p>If you overlooked this game because you thought the <em>New </em>series just wasn’t delivering on its promise, you may want to give it a chance. It’s a terrific 2D thrill ride that actually understands what makes the best <em>Mario </em>level design so good, and sometimes even offers up some exciting surprises of its own. — Carolyn Petit</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/new-super-mario-bros-u-deluxe-the-kotaku-review-1831680503&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/new-super-mario-bros-u-deluxe-the-kotaku-review-1831680503"><em>New Super Mario Bros. U Deluxe</em>: The <em>Kotaku</em> Review</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="9c644206702a7825df8c026d54b407de" data-recommend-id="image://9c644206702a7825df8c026d54b407de" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A grid shows where new Mario level elements can be placed. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A grid shows where new Mario level elements can be placed. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Mario Wiki</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9c644206702a7825df8c026d54b407de" data-recommend-id="image://9c644206702a7825df8c026d54b407de" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A grid shows where new Mario level elements can be placed. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Nintendo is notorious for keeping an iron grip on its properties, and if you play its 2015 platformer creation kit for a minute you might understand why: Left unchecked, most of us will create impossible troll rooms that double as torture chambers. Most people can’t make levels that capture, much less outdo, the simple brilliance of any single level from the first <em>Super Mario Bros</em>.<br></p><p>But the beauty is in that same madness. Nintendo has, for the most part, moved on from 2D <em>Mario</em> games. Why not let players run wild with their own designs? Every so often, someone will put together a world that rivals if not outdoes Nintendo’s own creations. If nothing else, it was a hoot to watch people spend months trying to beat diabolical levels made by Satan himself, along with tinkerers pushing the game engine to its very limits. — Patricia Hernandez</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-maker-is-forcing-me-to-leave-my-wii-u-on-al-1748342307&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-maker-is-forcing-me-to-leave-my-wii-u-on-al-1748342307"><em>Super Mario Maker</em> Is Forcing Me To Leave My Wii U On All Day</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="9e0410361bf4f4b809d82a0321b8422e" data-recommend-id="image://9e0410361bf4f4b809d82a0321b8422e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario dodges flying fish in Lost Levels. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario dodges flying fish in Lost Levels. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9e0410361bf4f4b809d82a0321b8422e" data-recommend-id="image://9e0410361bf4f4b809d82a0321b8422e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario dodges flying fish in Lost Levels. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The Japanese version of <em>Super Mario Bros. 2</em> is essentially <em>Super Mario Bros.</em>, but harder. Its cute little disk seems to taunt, “Oh, you think you’re hot stuff for rescuing the princess? Well, try these levels on for size.” Except here in the west we couldn’t, because the folks at Nintendo apparently deemed this sequel too difficult for foreign markets.<br></p><p>It’s easy to see why. Compared to the challenging but relatively chill original, the Japanese <em>Super Mario Bros. 2</em> is kind of mean. It sets the tone immediately by making the first “power-up” a poison mushroom which kills you. Or a few worlds in, you might find a beanstalk that leads to the sky. In the first game this was cause for celebration, but here your reward is a reverse “warp zone” that sends you all the way back to world 1-1. But don’t fret: In a hilarious example of the game’s twisted version of “mercy,” a small chasm next to the unwanted warp pipe offers the opportunity to dispose of your current Mario should you wish to avoid being sent back. Aw, those softies.</p><div><p>Sadism aside, <em>Super Mario Bros. 2</em> really is more a <em>Super Mario Bros.</em> expansion than a wholly original sequel. A lot of the tile graphics are redone to be uglier, there aren’t many new items or foes, and you need to beat worlds one through eight a whopping eight times to unlock the even harder worlds A through D. Oh, and now Luigi has his different physics.</p><p>Is it good? Sure, in that it’s more <em>Super Mario Bros.</em>, the landmark action game that changed everything. But the west never saw this sequel until it was part of the 1993 SNES remake package <em>Super Mario All-Stars</em>, by which point we’d also experienced the first two <em>Super Mario Land</em> games, <em>Super Mario Bros. 3</em>, and <em>Super Mario World</em>. So many folks, myself included, didn’t get a chance to experience this one fresh out of the oven, and I know I don’t quite appreciate it as much as a result. It’s also not a big leap to suggest that the first <em>Super Mario</em> outing is just plain more appealing to a wider audience. — Alexandra Hall</p></div><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-2-japan-super-mario-bros-2-usa-m-1846717790&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-2-japan-super-mario-bros-2-usa-m-1846717790"><em>Super Mario Bros. 2 </em>Japan + <em>Super Mario Bros. 2</em> USA = My Dream Game</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="ae183bb0262634b3662f599d4f967beb" data-recommend-id="image://ae183bb0262634b3662f599d4f967beb" data-format="jpg" data-width="1269" data-height="714" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Builder Mario hammers through some blocks. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Builder Mario hammers through some blocks. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Mario Wiki</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ae183bb0262634b3662f599d4f967beb" data-recommend-id="image://ae183bb0262634b3662f599d4f967beb" data-format="jpg" data-width="1269" data-height="714" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Builder Mario hammers through some blocks. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Bigger and better than the first in almost every way, <em>Super Mario Maker 2 </em>is a pretty obvious case of more is more. The content creator playground remains alive and vibrant, for one, which already puts it head and shoulders above the 3DS and Wii U originals. No, the UI experience isn’t quite as good as on the Wii U, whose tablet felt custom-made for crafting new <em>Mario</em> levels. And there are weird oversights and missing features, like no 100-man challenge mode and no ways to track stats or help players easily discover cool creations. The sheer number of new design elements helps make up for that, however. And the new story mode is a drastically better teaching tool that has neat levels of its own. — Ethan Gach<br></p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-maker-2-the-kotaku-review-1835857984&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-maker-2-the-kotaku-review-1835857984"><em>Super Mario Maker 2</em>: The <em>Kotaku</em> Review</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e90ac81a8c54228d88f888dc9e48b1c3" data-recommend-id="image://e90ac81a8c54228d88f888dc9e48b1c3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario smashes Koopa shells underground. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario smashes Koopa shells underground. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e90ac81a8c54228d88f888dc9e48b1c3" data-recommend-id="image://e90ac81a8c54228d88f888dc9e48b1c3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario smashes Koopa shells underground. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Super Mario Bros. </em>was hardly the first game with side-scrolling, character-based action. Taito’s <em>Jungle King /</em> <em>Jungle Hunt </em>had it as early as 1982, and gaming’s first true superstar, Pac-Man, got his own cartoonish side-scroller in 1984’s <em>Pac-Land</em>. But nonetheless, to play <em>Super Mario Bros</em>. in 1985 was to know that everything had changed.<br></p><p>It was an absolute revelation to see Mario, previously the star of <em>Donkey Kong </em>and <em>Mario Bros.</em>, bust free from the single-screen confines of the past and run toward the right. A whole world of adventure awaited him, packed with immediately iconic power-ups, unforgettable secrets, a real sense of vastness and depth thanks to subterranean stages, and bonus coin zones hidden in the clouds. </p><p>But of course, none of that would have mattered if <em>Super Mario Bros</em>. didn’t feel so damn good to play. The option to hold down a button to run, the way Mario soared through the air, the sheer bliss of getting an invincibility star and plowing right through rows of goombas and koopas, all of it elevated <em>Super Mario Bros. </em>far beyond any side-scroller that had come before. </p><p>It’s also, for my money, the first game in which Nintendo’s signature, subtly intuitive level design is on display. There’s a reason why world 1-1 remains iconic to this day: Shigeru Miyamoto knew exactly what he was doing, telling you everything you needed to know with just a goomba and one super mushroom. And yet, for all its fundamental simplicity, the game continues to surprise as you progress, introducing nefarious new challenges (those damn hammer bros.!) and capping off each world with a castle so treacherous that surviving leaves you feeling both triumphant and relieved. </p><p>Some might argue that although it kicked off an action-gaming dynasty, the original <em>Super Mario Bros. </em>isn’t worth going back to today. I disagree. I think its level design is timelessly great (unlike that of some games in the <em>New Super Mario Bros. </em>series), its music and visuals are enduringly charming, and its controls as pleasurable and intuitive today as ever. Games that change the landscape of gaming forever are rare, but this is one of them, no question about it. — Carolyn Petit</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/when-we-show-a-power-up-to-mr-miyamoto-we-get-a-bit-n-5861970&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/when-we-show-a-power-up-to-mr-miyamoto-we-get-a-bit-n-5861970">‘When We Show A Power-Up To Mr. Miyamoto, We Get A Bit Nervous.’</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="2e27914998a8564ee871971d8f7e8543" data-recommend-id="image://2e27914998a8564ee871971d8f7e8543" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Luigi prepares to jump too far in Super Mario Bros. 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Luigi prepares to jump too far in Super Mario Bros. 2. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2e27914998a8564ee871971d8f7e8543" data-recommend-id="image://2e27914998a8564ee871971d8f7e8543" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Luigi prepares to jump too far in Super Mario Bros. 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Super Mario Bros.</em> was a game about jumping on turtles, growing large, and smashing bricks. Then <em>Super Mario Bros. 2</em> came out and had us ripping up extradimensional grass to feed a gambling addiction, assailing trans elders with their own eggs, and force-feeding turnips to a despotic toad to liberate a subconscious dream land. Whiplash much?<br></p><p>Nope! I was a child, and did not think to question this massive change in gameplay, tone, or plot. (Wish I could be so mellow today!) I just knew that <em>Super Mario Bros. 2</em> was hard to find in stores, fun as heck, and had graphics so good that I sincerely believed it looked like a damn cartoon.</p><div><p>Of course, everyone now knows that Nintendo pulled a switcheroo, withholding the real <em>Super Mario Bros. 2</em>—a sort of high-difficulty level pack for the original<em> </em>adventure—and reskinning the Famicom Disk System game <em>Doki Doki Panic</em> with <em>Mario</em> characters for the west.</p><p>While a few folks will always kvetch about not getting <em>Super Mario Bros.</em>’ “true” sequel, truth is, the weird, trippy adventure we ended up with is a fantastic 2D platformer full of curious, colorful sights and pleasing discoveries. It’s got a good difficulty curve and is just an all around pleasant time. A lot of its innovations even persist in the series today, including Peach’s float ability, Birdetta, bob-ombs, and the lovably weird shy guys, so I think history is on its side.</p></div><p>I miss the days, before everything went big-budget triple-A and games got “too big to fail,” when major game companies felt free to develop “weird sequels.” — Alexandra Hall</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/america-got-the-better-super-mario-bros-2-1845330030&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/america-got-the-better-super-mario-bros-2-1845330030">America Got The Better<em> Super Mario Bros. 2</em></a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="08cfac105a8921dea5108f09eff85069" data-recommend-id="image://08cfac105a8921dea5108f09eff85069" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Giga Bowser stares down Mario. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Giga Bowser stares down Mario. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="08cfac105a8921dea5108f09eff85069" data-recommend-id="image://08cfac105a8921dea5108f09eff85069" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Giga Bowser stares down Mario. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Some might argue that <em>Bowser’s Fury</em>, which came packaged with the Switch re-release of <em>Super Mario 3D World</em>, isn’t even a <em>Super Mario Bros.</em> game. It’s more like an expansion, they might say, just an experiment in modernizing <em>Mario</em> gameplay using a Wii U game as a base. But whatever, it rules, so it’s on the list!<br></p><p>Throwing a lot of traditional <em>Mario</em> ideas out the window, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-3d-world-bowser-s-fury-the-kotaku-review-1846235344&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-3d-world-bowser-s-fury-the-kotaku-review-1846235344"><em>Bowser’s Fury</em></a></span> is an open-world game in which you spend most of your time doing standard platforming stuff but every so often the sky goes dark and you get to fight (or run/hide from) a Godzilla-sized incarnation of Mario’s arch-foe. It is a sight to behold, one of the coolest individual moments in series history, and while there’s not much variety or scope to <em>Bowser’s Fury</em>—the whole game is over in just a few hours—for as long as it lasts this is almost as good as <em>Super Mario</em> gets. — Luke Plunkett</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/i-hope-bowsers-fury-is-the-future-of-mario-1846137847&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/i-hope-bowsers-fury-is-the-future-of-mario-1846137847">I Hope <em>Bowser’s Fury</em> Is The Future Of Mario</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="302416cf74fd97a288f0aa0e0636b21b" data-recommend-id="image://302416cf74fd97a288f0aa0e0636b21b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A pink Yoshi leads its eggs through a watery cavern. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A pink Yoshi leads its eggs through a watery cavern. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="302416cf74fd97a288f0aa0e0636b21b" data-recommend-id="image://302416cf74fd97a288f0aa0e0636b21b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A pink Yoshi leads its eggs through a watery cavern. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Up until this point, <em>Super Mario</em> games starred Mario and were largely linear affairs. Find some secrets. Survive. Get to the end. <em>Yoshi’s Island</em> switched the emphasis from simply getting from point A to point B to grabbing every collectible and solving every puzzle in-between. It had a playful, twee art style that would become a mainstay for <em>Yoshi</em> games moving forward, but still featured the titular hero in an origin story in which the fail state wasn’t getting hit too many times, but having your baby Mario abducted.<br></p><p>Some might consider <em>Yoshi’s Island</em> firmly in the <em>Yoshi</em>-game camp, but that subtitle stands, and a number of play mechanics, like red coins, went on to become staples of later <em>Super Mario </em>games. Even Yoshi transforming into vehicles like a helicopter hinted at Mario’s own transformations decades later in <em>Super Mario Odyssey</em>. From its level design to its boss fights, <em>Yoshi’s Island</em> remains one of the most beautiful <em>Mario </em>games ever made, and an oddly subversive, playful mashup that trades challenging platforming for deep exploration. — Ethan Gach</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/yoshi-devolved-from-babysitter-to-baby-1845999049&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/yoshi-devolved-from-babysitter-to-baby-1845999049">Yoshi Devolved From Babysitter to Baby</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="9b6918850b79b069a6e8fdd31c4224e3" data-recommend-id="image://9b6918850b79b069a6e8fdd31c4224e3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1593" data-height="896" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario washes off the pavement. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario washes off the pavement. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Mario Wiki</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9b6918850b79b069a6e8fdd31c4224e3" data-recommend-id="image://9b6918850b79b069a6e8fdd31c4224e3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1593" data-height="896" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario washes off the pavement. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Like a lot of GameCube games, <em>Super Mario Sunshine</em> didn’t advance the series so much as take it sideways. The result isn’t always perfect, but it can still often manage to feel revelatory. Mario’s vacation to Isle Delfino Island sees him strap a robotic water pump to his back to clean up goop and rescue Princess Peach from the consequences of Bowser’s poor parenting. Between detailed, open-ended levels and Mario’s new water jetpack, <em>Sunshine</em> transforms where Mario can go and how he gets there. It’s not quite an open world, but it feels almost as liberating.<br></p><p>The story beats and sporadic voice acting don’t always land, and the Pianta and Noki islanders haven’t etched themselves into the series’ lore the way other, more beloved creatures have. In fact, <em>Super Mario Sunshine</em> has a lot of rough edges, not the least of which are the finicky camera controls. Halfway between a<em> Super Mario 64</em> sequel and a completely new type of 3D <em>Mario</em> game, <em>Sunshine</em> still managed to rise above its flaws thanks to some clever puzzle mechanics and imaginative map designs. It’s a <em>Super Mario</em> game based around a gimmick, but still a great one. — Ethan Gach</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lets-debate-the-merits-of-super-mario-sunshine-1845215692&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lets-debate-the-merits-of-super-mario-sunshine-1845215692">Let’s Debate The Merits Of <em>Super Mario Sunshine</em></a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="dfb28a8a9ad27a37e4ec6b7d83c94f2d" data-recommend-id="image://dfb28a8a9ad27a37e4ec6b7d83c94f2d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario rides a green pipe. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario rides a green pipe. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dfb28a8a9ad27a37e4ec6b7d83c94f2d" data-recommend-id="image://dfb28a8a9ad27a37e4ec6b7d83c94f2d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario rides a green pipe. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Super Mario Bros. Wonder </em>is the culmination of decades of evolving 2D Mario design ideas and platforming polish. It’s full of neat mechanics and new powerups as well as impressive visual set pieces each rapidly discarded one after another like veteran musicians riffing on their greatest hits who have nothing left to prove but keep throwing out new surprises anyway just for kicks. Fitting, then, that some of the game’s most memorable moments are elaborate musical numbers that bring out the platformer’s inner rhythms and make them sing.</p><p>It’s a crowd-pleasing victory lap that held back only by its occasional conservativism. Limiting the risks limits some of the payoff, and Super Mario Bros. Wonder never quite reaches the envelope-pushing heights of the best games in the series, but it’s excellent nevertheless. — Ethan Gach</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-wonder-review-switch-nintendo-kotaku-1850964104&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-wonder-review-switch-nintendo-kotaku-1850964104">Mario’s latest platforming adventure may not be his hardest, but it is certainly his weirdest</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="70834425b614507d98921ca62b63ecda" data-recommend-id="image://70834425b614507d98921ca62b63ecda" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="675" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario wears a baseball cap to the platforming course. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario wears a baseball cap to the platforming course. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / MobyGames</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="70834425b614507d98921ca62b63ecda" data-recommend-id="image://70834425b614507d98921ca62b63ecda" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="675" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario wears a baseball cap to the platforming course. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-odyssey-the-kotaku-review-1819856086&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-odyssey-the-kotaku-review-1819856086"><em>Super Mario Odyssey</em></a></span> is one of the best Switch games ever released. It boasts some of the best-looking and biggest worlds seen in a 3D <em>Super Mario</em> game and is just a joy to play. It’s one of those games that can easily suck away a whole day before you realize it.<br></p><p><em>Odyssey</em> is also endlessly creative, using Mario’s new hat friend for all sorts of interesting and silly shenanigans. How many <em>Mario</em> games let you become a tank, control a large T-Rex, or turn into literal electricity? Every hour in<em> Odyssey </em>is exciting as you explore new worlds filled with completely original ideas and moments.</p><p>And then there’s the music! <em>Super Mario Odyssey </em>features some of the best jams in the entire series and that’s without mentioning that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/ssVT38kWv78&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/ssVT38kWv78" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">incredible music-themed stage in New Donk City</a></span>. It’s just a pure joy machine and easily one of Nintendo’s best 3D <em>Super Mario</em> adventures. — Zack Zwiezen</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-odyssey-six-months-later-1825662055&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-odyssey-six-months-later-1825662055"><em>Super Mario Odyssey</em>, Six Months Later</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="fef24f5c2fff088c9024e485728aad0c" data-recommend-id="image://fef24f5c2fff088c9024e485728aad0c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario and friends scurry up a wall in cat costumes while a giant bullet fires out of the wall." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario and friends scurry up a wall in cat costumes while a giant bullet fires out of the wall." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="fef24f5c2fff088c9024e485728aad0c" data-recommend-id="image://fef24f5c2fff088c9024e485728aad0c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario and friends scurry up a wall in cat costumes while a giant bullet fires out of the wall." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Move aside, <em>New Super Mario Bros.</em>. Despite the <em>3D </em>in its title and the fact that, yes, the gameplay takes place in three dimensions, it’s actually here in <em>Super Mario 3D World</em> that the spirit of early <em>Super Mario</em>’s tightly designed obstacle courses is most apparent, and most thrillingly iterated upon. The new Cat Mario power-up belongs directly in the lineage of all of <em>Super Mario Bros. 3</em>’s classic animal costumes, and the flagpoles at each level’s end hearken back to the game that started it all.<br></p><p>But it’s much more than just a tribute to those classics. The 3D environments open up a slew of new possibilities that the level designers make the most of, four-player co-op makes for delightful chaos, and the game’s difficulty teeters brilliantly between accessible (for players who want a breezy but satisfying experience) and nail-biting (for those who want to test their skills and tackle every challenge the game has to offer). While other 3D Mario games like <em>Super Mario 64 </em>and <em>Super Mario Odyssey </em>have focused on more expansive environments for us to explore, <em>Super Mario 3D World</em>’s narrower, more propulsive stages<em> </em>chart a categorically different course, one that keeps the spirit of early <em>Super Mario</em> alive while also investing it with wonderful new ideas. — Carolyn Petit</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-3d-world-the-kotaku-review-1467128494&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-3d-world-the-kotaku-review-1467128494"><em>Super Mario 3D World</em>: The <em>Kotaku </em>Review</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8fb7250ce739ca5139310dfb166ac447" data-recommend-id="image://8fb7250ce739ca5139310dfb166ac447" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario faces down a giant penguin atop an icy road." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario faces down a giant penguin atop an icy road." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8fb7250ce739ca5139310dfb166ac447" data-recommend-id="image://8fb7250ce739ca5139310dfb166ac447" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario faces down a giant penguin atop an icy road." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Did you think this was gonna be number one? Well it’s not, but it’s still an all-time classic. Gross Nintendo 64 polygons, a busted camera, and tricky wall jumps aside, 1996’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-3d-all-stars-the-kotaku-review-1845070139&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-3d-all-stars-the-kotaku-review-1845070139"><em>Super Mario 64</em></a></span> isn’t just a historically significant relic—it’s still a modern-day revelation. Watching Mario break the 2D plane for the first time changed a generation of players, creating one of the defining “next-gen” epiphanies current leaps in technology struggle to live up to.<br></p><p>Just the movement and physics alone were breathtaking, harnessing the Nintendo 64’s new analog control stick to both set new standards in player-character expressiveness and instantly make the digital-only controls of competing games feel antiquated. So enthused were the designers that they went a little overboard, giving Mario the single largest and most complex moveset he’s ever enjoyed. It can be a little hard to fully get to grips with, but the high skill ceiling for mastery is a big part of the fun.</p><p><em>Super Mario 64</em> is also pound for pound one of the best 3D <em>Super Mario</em> games, bursting at the seams with mischievous platforming and satisfying puzzles. From Cool, Cool Mountain to Dire, Dire Docks and Rainbow Ride, the game features iconic maps and some of the most satisfying collectible challenges in the series. Tick Tock Clock haunts me to this day. </p><p>The game straddles a difficult inflection point for the series, showcasing top-tier course designs built around Mario’s multitude of new jumps, while also being hampered by compromises made to take advantage of then cutting-edge technology. Those weigh it down, keeping it from ranking higher, but in some ways it’s a testament to just how strong its fundamentals are that the overall package remains one of the best platform games ever. Maybe Nintendo will remake it one day, making it the number-one Mario game it has the DNA to be. — Ethan Gach</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-64-youtube-sm64-nintendo-secret-1up-hidden-1850214597&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-64-youtube-sm64-nintendo-secret-1up-hidden-1850214597"><em>Super Mario 64 </em>Fans Have Tried To Get This 1-Up Without Dying For Over 20 Years</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e4b4ad72f706f24c93859afbcf7d04ef" data-recommend-id="image://e4b4ad72f706f24c93859afbcf7d04ef" data-format="jpg" data-width="1621" data-height="912" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario takes a walk along a mini-planetoid. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario takes a walk along a mini-planetoid. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e4b4ad72f706f24c93859afbcf7d04ef" data-recommend-id="image://e4b4ad72f706f24c93859afbcf7d04ef" data-format="jpg" data-width="1621" data-height="912" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario takes a walk along a mini-planetoid. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>After <em>Super Mario 64</em>, it was tough in some ways to imagine Nintendo ever delivering another massive leap in terms of imagination and possibility for its flagship series. (<em>Super Mario Sunshine </em>has its place, but a paradigm shift it was not.) What new frontiers were there for Mario, and for 3D platforming, to conquer?<br></p><p>Oh, how wrong we were to doubt. <em>Super Mario Galaxy </em>was yet another massive imaginative leap forward for the series, playing with gravity, with the shape of environments, with a cosmic theme that took the series to bold new places and reinforced the feeling that Mario really has no limits. Buoyed by a gently melancholy story that introduced the character of Rosalina and by the most mind-bending and profound ending in the series, <em>Super Mario Galaxy </em>is all the things we want <em>Mario </em>to be: challenging, inventive, vibrant, intuitive, beautiful, and epic. — Carolyn Petit</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-galaxy-s-opening-is-still-terrifying-1845095341&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-galaxy-s-opening-is-still-terrifying-1845095341"><em>Super Mario Galaxy</em>’s Opening Is Still Terrifying</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="f52c80603cc251476db8eb4bd49a034b" data-recommend-id="image://f52c80603cc251476db8eb4bd49a034b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1624" data-height="912" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario flies to some ancient ruins. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario flies to some ancient ruins. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f52c80603cc251476db8eb4bd49a034b" data-recommend-id="image://f52c80603cc251476db8eb4bd49a034b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1624" data-height="912" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario flies to some ancient ruins. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Sequels aren’t always better than the original. And in Mario’s case, they often tend to feel like uneven leftovers doctored up into another night’s dinner; a collection of half-baked ideas, prototypes, and B-sides that didn’t make the first cut but are still ultimately good enough to see the light of day eventually.<br></p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-galaxy-2-review-in-praise-of-superfluous-m-5544249&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-galaxy-2-review-in-praise-of-superfluous-m-5544249"><em>Super Mario Galaxy 2</em></a></span> is not that. Yes it’s more, but it’s also better, in every way, than its already groundbreaking predecessor. The 2010 Wii game is the definitive 3D <em>Super Mario</em>, complete with gorgeous worlds to explore, ambitious puzzle designs, and one of the most satisfying versions of Mario to control in any game. It somehow has even more planets than the first game, with an even greater level of variation and experimentation. Perhaps buoyed by previous success and the Wii’s blockbuster sales, Nintendo’s designers seemed to take even more chances—and, I suspect, had more fun—making <em>Galaxy 2</em>. </p><p><em>Super Mario</em> has always fundamentally been a series about gravity. You can’t jump if you don’t eventually fall, and Nintendo spent decades exploring that in 2D and 3D. <em>Galaxy</em> explored it from the inside out, using Wii motion controls to help you tease it out and feel it deep in your bones, and <em>Galaxy 2</em> took that to another level. — Ethan Gach</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-just-threw-super-mario-galaxy-2-down-the-memor-1844947959&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-just-threw-super-mario-galaxy-2-down-the-memor-1844947959">Nintendo Just Threw <em>Super Mario Galaxy 2</em> Down The Memory Hole</a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1eb826fa6d22709018a4fd1d50842861" data-recommend-id="image://1eb826fa6d22709018a4fd1d50842861" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Tanooki Mario dodges Bullet Bills. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Tanooki Mario dodges Bullet Bills. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1eb826fa6d22709018a4fd1d50842861" data-recommend-id="image://1eb826fa6d22709018a4fd1d50842861" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Tanooki Mario dodges Bullet Bills. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The debate over whether <em>Super Mario Bros. 3 </em>or its SNES successor represents the pinnacle of 2D Mario platforming may never be settled, but one thing seems certain to me: The plumber’s final NES adventure delivered on the promise of a “world” for Mario to journey through two years before we got the game that’s actually called <em>Super Mario World</em>.<br></p><p>It wasn’t just the new map system that did it, though that’s certainly a big part of it. Getting to see King Koopa’s military might represented across the landscape by forts and castles as your quest took you from the bucolic Grass Land (world 1) all the way to the foreboding, Mordor-like Dark Land (world 8) conjured the sense of a true quest against a vast force of evil, while little touches like the ways the hammer bros. moved around between stages brought that map to life–a real, living world. </p><p>But the game also represented another massive leap for the series (and for platforming games in general) in its level design, with slopes you could slide down, autoscrolling airships lending a formidable new feel to Bowser’s forces, and gimmicks that still surprise and delight to this day, like Giant Land (world 4), in which enemies and environmental features alike are suddenly many times their normal size. </p><p>To top it all off, Mario’s momentum is newly refined—run interrupted for a bit and you attain P-speed, moving faster, leaping farther, and even able to take flight—and he’s got a slew of new power-ups to play with, from the oddball Kuribo’s shoe to the iconic tanooki suit. <em>Super Mario Bros. 3</em> is just bursting with ingenuity and generosity from top to bottom, and upon release utterly destroyed the existing standards for games of this type with all of its inventiveness and fun, seamlessly weaving dozens of great new ideas into one epic adventure. — Carolyn Petit</p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-making-and-legacy-of-super-mario-bros-3-1773499946&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-making-and-legacy-of-super-mario-bros-3-1773499946">The Making (And Legacy) Of<em> Super Mario Bros. 3</em></a></span></p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="90786d10d539fa373cd872917bf7dca1" data-recommend-id="image://90786d10d539fa373cd872917bf7dca1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario rides some dolphins. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario rides some dolphins. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="90786d10d539fa373cd872917bf7dca1" data-recommend-id="image://90786d10d539fa373cd872917bf7dca1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario rides some dolphins. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>This is it. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;http://Super Mario World: The Kotaku Review&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://Super Mario World: The Kotaku Review"><em>Super Mario World</em></a></span>. The best 2D <em>Mario</em> game Nintendo ever made is thus the best Mario game overall. Elegant and simple yet challenging and complex, the 1990 pack-in launch game for the SNES has aged like a fine Bordeaux: silky smooth and exquisitely harmonized. It controls like a dream. The pixel art still looks great. And each of its 73 levels offers something unique, with puzzles that evolve as new block types are unlocked and even a  visual overhaul once you reach a certain point.<br></p><p>It’s not as daring as <em>Super Mario Bros. 3</em> or as ambitious as <em>Super Mario Galaxy 2</em>, but it’s undoubtedly the most balanced and well-rounded package in the series. Feathers transform Mario into a gravity-defying superhero. Different-colored Yoshi harness various magical abilities from fire balls to mini-earthquakes. And ingenious hidden exists culminate in Star Road, an immaculate series of secret levels whose level of challenge is exceeded only by the amount of imagination on display. </p><p>Each zone on the map tells a story, and each one connects to the next, weaving an adventure that’s minimalistic but evocative, taking Mario over hills, underground, through foggy forests, and across prehistoric mountains. An underappreciated aspect of <em>Super Mario World</em> is how each new level, and new zone, slowly builds upon the last, not just mechanically but thematically as well. There’s no real backstory and hardly any dialogue, and yet each new step and every enemy jumped on carries you along a bit further through the most polished and quintessential <em>Mario </em>adventure ever made. </p><p>At least, for now. — Ethan Gach</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/unearthed-1990-interview-reveals-great-insights-about-s-1748732983&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/unearthed-1990-interview-reveals-great-insights-about-s-1748732983">Unearthed 1990 Interview Reveals Great Insights About <em>Super Mario World</em></a></span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle PS5 Release Date Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-leaked.1130229/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-leaked/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-94479">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle has seen its release date on PlayStation 5 (PS5) leaked thanks to a known data miner.</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/voici-les-dates-de-sortie-de-indiana-jones-et-le-cercle-ancien-sur-ps5-60055" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">billbil-kun</a>, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will release on PS5 on April 17, 2025. </p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-the-future-of-call-of-duty-insider-gaming-weekly">PODCAST: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-future-of-call-of-duty-insider-gaming-weekly/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Future Of Call of Duty—Insider Gaming Weekly</a></h6>



<p>In addition to the game’s main release date, it was also revealed that “at least two physical editions” of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will launch for the system. There will be the Standard Edition for $69.99 as well as a Premium Edition for $99.99. The Premium Edition of the game will get the game two days early on April 15. It will also include The Order of the Giants DLC, a digital articook, and the Temple of Doom outfit for Indy.</p>



<p>Pre-orders for the game on PS5 are expected to being around March 25, according to the report.</p>



<p>Bethesda, Microsoft, or Sony have officially announced the game’s release date. Until then, please take the exact dates with a grain of salt.</p>



<p>Are you going to pick up Indiana Jones and the Great Circle when it launches on PS5 in April? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official Insider Gaming Forums.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out what major <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-reaches-major-sales-milestone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sales milestone Split Fiction reached</a> after just 48 hours on the market. &nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-6-classes-every-battlefield-2025-class-what-we-know/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-6-classes-every-battlefield-2025-class-what-we-know/">All Battlefield 6 Classes—Every Battlefield 2025 Class &amp; What we Know</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Battlefield’s number of Classes has reduced in recent years. With 2025’s Battlefield 6 looming, we’ve seen a sneak peek of the new Classes.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-release-date-platforms-editions-price/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-release-date-platforms-editions-price/">Death Stranding 2 On The Beach Release Date—Platforms, Editions &amp; Price</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Kojima Productions’ Death Stranding 2 On The Beach is aiming to be just as mysterious and mind-blowing, and its release date is locked in.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-length-explained/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-length-explained/">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Length Explained</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The length of Assassin’s Creed Shadows is a great mystery when you consider how long recent AC titles have been, so let’s find out.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-factions/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-factions/">Battlefield 6 Factions—Everything we Know About Battlefield 2025 Factions</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Factions form the basis of Battlefield 6’s allegiance in 2025. Early gameplay has given us an indication about the direction EA is headed.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cozy simulation game Urban Jungle for PC launches March 21]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/cozy-simulation-game-urban-jungle-for-pc-launches-march-21</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cozy-simulation-game-urban-jungle-for-pc-launches-march-21.1130226/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/cozy-simulation-game-urban-jungle-for-pc-launches-march-21<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Transform small, ordinary apartments into lush, green havens.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Cozy <a title="Genres > Simulation [659 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Urban Jungle" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/urban-jungle">Urban Jungle</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,548 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2744010/Urban_Jungle/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 21, publisher <a title="Companies > Assemble Entertainment [25 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/assemble-entertainment">Assemble Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Kylyk Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kylyk-games">Kylyk Games</a> announced. <span id="more-949008"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2744010/Urban_Jungle/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Urban Jungle</em> is a charming and relaxing simulation game that invites you to transform small, ordinary apartments into lush, green havens by placing delightful plants with savvy. But no worries, you won’t have to deal with watering or pest control—the plants just need a good spot, and that’s enough to create the comfiest and coziest home of them all. Oh, and don’t forget to pet your cat!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Decorate with Plants</strong> – The core gameplay revolves around arranging a diverse selection of plants in your apartment. Each plant can be placed in different spots, challenging you to find the optimal placement to enhance the room’s coziness and aesthetics.</li><li><strong>Puzzle Elements</strong> – While the game is primarily about decoration, it includes puzzle-like aspects. You’ll need to think strategically about where to place each plant to maximize the comfort and visual appeal of your home, ultimately unlocking new plants.</li><li><strong>Relaxing Atmosphere</strong> – <em>Urban Jungle</em> is designed to be a stress-free experience. There are no time limits or high-pressure scenarios. You can move plants around freely and adjust your setup at your own pace.</li><li><strong>Environmental Storytelling</strong> – The game’s narrative is subtly woven into the environment. As you progress, you’ll uncover pieces of a heartwarming story that unfolds across the different stages of the protagonist’s life.</li><li><strong>Interactive Elements</strong> – In addition to plants, you can interact with other items like lamps and humidifiers to alter the ambiance of your apartment, further enhancing the cozy feeling.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Why You’ll Love <em>Urban Jungle</em></strong></p><p><em>Urban Jungle</em> is perfect for players seeking a wholesome and meditative gaming experience. The simple yet engaging gameplay, combined with the delightful visuals and calming music, creates an oasis of tranquility. Whether you’re an avid gardener in real life or someone who simply loves cozy spaces, <em>Urban Jungle</em> offers a beautiful blend of creativity, relaxation, and gentle storytelling.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Urban Jungle | Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j44G5_9sEWA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Super Mario Bros. Scenes Now Available On Nintendo Alarmo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-mario-bros-scenes-now-available-on-nintendo-alarmo/1100-6530008/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/super-mario-bros-scenes-now-available-on-nintendo-alarmo.1130220/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-mario-bros-scenes-now-available-on-nintendo-alarmo/1100-6530008/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530008">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>There's a hot new machine from Nintendo that everybody's talking about that just received a major update, and you know we don't mean the Switch 2. Yes, Nintendo's motion-activated alarm clock got a free update recently that adds scenes from the original NES Super Mario Bros. to the proceedings.</p><p dir="ltr">According to the social media post announcing the move, you can receive these new scenes by connecting <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-alarmo-now-available-at-major-retailers-mario-will-wake-you-up-for-100/1100-6529653/" data-ref-id="1100-6529653">your Alarmo</a> to the internet and linking it to your Nintendo Account. These scenes are the first from a retro Nintendo game, as the rest of those with scenes featured are all on the Switch. Those games include Super Mario Odyssey, The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild, Splatoon 3, Pikmin 4, and Ring Fit Adventure. Connecting your Nintendo account will also give you access to scenes from Mario Kart 8 Deluxe and Animal Crossing: New Horizons.</p><p dir="ltr">Retailing for $100, the Alarmo is a motion-activated alarm clock with sleep tracking features. It offers a variety of alarms, including "Gentle," which keeps the tone at one set volume, and "Steady," which makes the alarm increasingly louder. The Alarmo does not interact with other Nintendo devices and is not a limited-time or limited-edition product, unlike some other Nintendo devices from over the years.</p><p dir="ltr">In other Nintendo news, the company the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/">much-anticipated Switch 2</a> back in January. A Nintendo Direct that will presumably answer many questions about the new console, such as when it will be released, will be held on April 2.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Split Fiction passes major sales milestone in just 48 hours]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/split-fiction-passes-major-sales-milestone-in-just-48-hours</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/split-fiction-passes-major-sales-milestone-in-just-48-hours.1130217/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/split-fiction-passes-major-sales-milestone-in-just-48-hours<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>In just 48 hours, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/split-fiction">Split Fiction</a> has sold an impressive 1m units.</p>
<p>Developer Hazelight celebrated today's milestone on social media.</p>
<p>"The love you all show for our game is overwhelming," <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/hazelightgames.bsky.social/post/3ljztto3sws2v">it wrote on Bluesky</a>. "Everyone here at Hazelight are beyond happy - and we can't stop enjoying your amazing reactions!"</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Split Fiction PS5 Gameplay - Zoe &amp; Ian Play The First 90 Minutes!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6aHKxuDEDtg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Split Fiction PS5 Gameplay - Zoe &amp; Ian Play The First 90 Minutes!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6aHKxuDEDtg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6aHKxuDEDtg?autoplay=1" title="Split Fiction PS5 Gameplay - Zoe &amp; Ian Play The First 90 Minutes!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's Eurogamer's video team giving Split Fiction a whirl with the game's first 90 minutes. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6aHKxuDEDtg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Again, these are all sales. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/split-fiction-isnt-included-in-eas-play-subscription-at-launch">Split Fiction isn't currently included in the EA Play subscription</a>, nor is it on Game Pass or PS Plus. It's also worth noting that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/split-fictions-free-copy-offer-includes-crossplay-on-all-platforms-a-first-for-it-takes-two-developer">Split Fiction includes crossplay for the first time across all platforms</a> via the Friend's Pass function.</p>
<p>Needless to say, Split Fiction has had a great debut. Along with scores of praise across the industry, Hazellight's latest co-op caper currently boasts a peak concurrent player number of 259,003 on Steam.</p>
<p>To compare, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/it-takes-two">It Takes Two</a>'s all time concurrent player peak is 71,039, which it reached three months ago as anticipation for Split Fiction grew. In October last year, Hazelight announced <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/marital-platformer-it-takes-two-sales-pass-20m">It Takes Two had sold over 20m copies</a> since its own debut in 2021. That number will no doubt be even higher now. </p>
<p>A film adaptation of It Takes Two was also said to be in the works, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/even-josef-fares-doesnt-know-whats-happening-with-the-it-takes-two-film-adaptation">even Hazelight founder Josef Fares isn't sure what's happening with that right now</a>. </p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(573)_3D54dQn.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>SteamDB</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>But, I digress! Back to the here and now. We awarded Split Fiction five stars on its release last week.</p>
<p>"Fantastic from start to finish, Split Fiction is one of the most inventive and joyful co-op games to date, and a testament to the power of human imagination," our Katharine wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/split-fiction-review">Eurogamer's Split Fiction review</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego's New Mario Set Is The Best One Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lego-mario-kart-nintendo-new-set-price-may-mario-day-1851768825</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/legos-new-mario-set-is-the-best-one-yet.1130178/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/lego-mario-kart-nintendo-new-set-price-may-mario-day-1851768825<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="741e0baae88b254b719868f4285c0cb2" data-recommend-id="image://741e0baae88b254b719868f4285c0cb2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Lego / Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="741e0baae88b254b719868f4285c0cb2" data-recommend-id="image://741e0baae88b254b719868f4285c0cb2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Mamma mia, Mario, your new <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-8-lego-nintendo-switch-release-date-1851628089&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-8-lego-nintendo-switch-release-date-1851628089"><em>Mario Kart</em> Lego</a></span> set looks wonderful! And the large set, which was just officially revealed by Lego after a few leaks, might just be the best <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-best-games-zelda-mario-kart-pokemon-1851768535&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-best-games-zelda-mario-kart-pokemon-1851768535">Nintendo</a></span>-themed build yet! </p><p>On March 10, aka <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-bundle-mario-day-sale-mk8-odyssey-wonder-1851768159&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-bundle-mario-day-sale-mk8-odyssey-wonder-1851768159">Mario Day</a></span> (because Mar 10 looks like Mario, get it?), Nintendo and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/mario-kart-mario-standard-kart-72037&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/mario-kart-mario-standard-kart-72037" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lego revealed set #72037, Mario Kart</a></span>, the next big collaboration between the two companies. The large Lego kit is priced at $170 and is made up of over 1,900 pieces. The new build recreates Mario in a go kart and features posable arms. You can pre-order the set starting today and it will be available to buy on May 15.</p><p>The decorative set is intended for adults and older builders. And it’s pretty dang big, too. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/mario-kart-mario-standard-kart-72037&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/mario-kart-mario-standard-kart-72037" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">According to Lego’s website</a></span>, the <em>Mario Kart</em> set is 8.5 inches high, 12.5 inches long and 7.5 inches wide! You are going to need some space to display this bad boy and all his wonderful details, including what appears to be printed face features and a bulbous nose. </p><p>Seriously, I’m shocked at how perfectly Lego has captured Mario’s face, body, and proportions. Lego bricks can make many things, but human-like figures tend to be the trickiest and yet, Mario looks amazing in this new set. </p><p>In fact, because of how awesome Mario looks as a big brick-built Lego character, I’m just dreaming of a video game that looks like this. It makes me wish Nintendo and Lego would make the plunge and greenlight a Lego<em> Mario</em> video game. Even Bowser looks great as a brick-built character, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/bowser-lego-set-giant-2800-pieces-october-27-nintendo-1849152567&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/bowser-lego-set-giant-2800-pieces-october-27-nintendo-1849152567">as seen in his 2022 set</a></span>. So come on Nintendo. Come on Lego. Make a Lego <em>Mario</em> platformer. Do it you cowards! Do it!</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Battlefield 6 Classes—Every Battlefield 2025 Class & What we Know]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-6-classes-every-battlefield-2025-class-what-we-know/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-battlefield-6-classes%E2%80%94every-battlefield-2025-class-what-we-know.1130172/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-6-classes-every-battlefield-2025-class-what-we-know/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Battlefield 6 Classes dictate how you approach every match. The franchise has notoriously stuck by the same few Classes throughout the years. EA’s early work on Classes for the 2025 Battlefield sequel has been revealed, and each one favors a particular playstyle.</p>



<p>The Class system has always helped Battlefield stand out from its competition. Whereas Call of Duty allows users to create bespoke loadouts—usually factoring in the best meta gear and equipment—Battlefield is more restrictive. DICE gives the community a small handful of Classes to pick, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2025-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6</a> looks to be much the same in 2025.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-sign-up-for-battlefield-labs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield Labs test</a> is an early pre-Alpha designed to test the game’s foundations. But <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-leaks-reveal-battlefield-4-vibe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leaked gameplay footage</a> has already shed light on the direction the full Battlefield 6 release is heading.</p>



<h2 id="h-every-class-in-battlefield-6-revealed-so-far">Every Class in Battlefield 6 Revealed so far</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Is it the same Classes again? Credit to EA</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Leaked Battlefield 6 Labs footage reveals four familiar Classes: Assault, Engineer, Support, and Recon.</strong></p>



<p>Like the <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/battlefield" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Battlefield</a> 2042 image I’ve posted above shows, Battlefield 6 looks to be a continuation of the popular Classes. Apart from Battlefield 1—which had Assault, Medic, Support, Scout, Pilot &amp; Tanker, Cavalry, and Elite Classes—most Battlefield games use the same Classes.</p>



<p>As we’ve covered, the Battlefield Labs pre-Alpha has already leaked. In-match gameplay footage clearly shows you can choose from Assault, Engineer, Support, and Recon. This doesn’t mean these are the final Classes though: Everything is subject to change between a pre-Alpha and a full release.</p>



<h3 id="h-assault">Assault</h3>



<p>This is your typical Battlefield, on-foot infantry with automatic weapons designed to eliminate the opposition at close-to-medium distances. They get stuck in, offer limited healing properties, and are an all-round killer.</p>



<h3 id="h-engineer">Engineer</h3>



<p>An Engineer gets stuck into the technical and mechanical side of things. Repairing ally vehicles, sabotaging enemy vehicles, and using a full breadth of equipment to be as impactful as any other role.</p>



<h3 id="h-support">Support</h3>



<p>Your Support are your healers, the fastidious individuals scurrying around the Battlefield resupplying and restocking teammates. They can also hinder the enemy team with their unique equipment and are very important.</p>



<h3 id="h-recon">Recon</h3>



<p>If you prefer to engage at long distances, pick off enemies, and remain unseen, Recon is the way for you. The role is known for Sniper Rifles and players capable of highlighting and identifying threats for the rest of their team.</p>



<hr>



<p>There’s plenty of time between now and the full Battlefield 6 release. We know Battlefield Labs is a testing ground and nothing more. We’ll have to wait and see, but are you happy to see Battlefield 6 stick to the same four Classes? Or should the shooter be more ambitious?</p>



<p>For more Battlefield news, check out everything we know about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-factions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 Factions</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Light Your Room With These Retro Dragon Quest 3 Pixelights]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/light-your-room-with-these-retro-dragon-quest-3-pixelights/1100-6529998/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/light-your-room-with-these-retro-dragon-quest-3-pixelights.1130166/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/light-your-room-with-these-retro-dragon-quest-3-pixelights/1100-6529998/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529998">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Square Enix released <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DRAGON-QUEST-HD-2D-Remake-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B0D71HX7PY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dragon Quest 3 HD-2D Remake</a> last year, offering a modern way to relive the iconic RPG. The company is now gearing up to launch a series of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DTJF9V24,B0DTJFDVQV,B0DTJFNWCS,B0DTJFHXDL&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dragon Quest 3 Pixelights</a> on September 24, all four of which are now available for preorder. These official Square Enix products offer a unique way to illuminate your game room, each based on the likeness of various characters from the original NES version of the classic RPG.</p><p>Each Pixelight requires three AAA batteries, so consider picking up the affordable <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Basics-AAA-High-Performance-36/dp/B00LH3DMUO?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon Basics AAA Battery Pack (36-Count)</a> for just $13.82. They come with a 10-year shelf life and should be good for all your electronics beyond these Pixelights.</p><p>If you’ve yet to play <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DRAGON-QUEST-HD-2D-Remake-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B0D71HX7PY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dragon Quest 3 HD-2D Remake</a>, it's on sale at Amazon. The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DRAGON-QUEST-HD-2D-Remake-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B0D71HX7PY?tag=gamespot-promos-2" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Series X</a> version is the cheapest at $46.54 (was $60), though there are also nice discounts for <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DRAGON-QUEST-HD-2D-Remake-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B0D71SHR5B?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Switch</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DRAGON-QUEST-HD-2D-Remake-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B0D71JQXR4?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5</a>.</p><p>Beyond the Pixelights, there are a few other Dragon Quest items for fans to check out. The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dragon-Quest-Illustrations-30th-Anniversary/dp/1974703908?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dragon Quest Illustrations: 30th Anniversar</a>y hardcover book is on sale for $20 (was $35), and since it’s packed with 240 pages of illustrations and designs, it’s a cool way to go behind the scenes. There’s also a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B06XSGCHZP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dragon Quest X Tarot Card Pack</a> with 22 large Arcana cards, each featuring colorful artwork from the series. Typically sold for $26.65, the pack is discounted to $20.47.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/1972-piece-lego-mario-kart-display-model-revealed-on-mario-day/1100-6530000/">1,972-Piece Lego Mario Kart Display Model Revealed On Mario Day</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/suikoden-hd-remaster-collection-is-steeply-discounted-for-pc-on-launch-day/1100-6526150/">Suikoden HD Remaster Collection Is Steeply Discounted For PC On Launch Day</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/zelda-master-sword-replica-on-sale-for-big-discount-at-amazon/1100-6523376/">Zelda Master Sword Replica On Sale For Big Discount At Amazon</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/spider-man-x-magic-the-gathering-trading-card-set-is-available-to-preorder/1100-6529819/">Spider-Man X Magic: The Gathering Trading Card Set Is Available To Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-biggest-upcoming-games-that-you-can-preorder-now/2900-6285/">The Biggest Upcoming Games That You Can Preorder Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sandisk-1-5tb-microsd-card-is-steeply-discounted-at-amazon-expand-your-steam-deck-storage/1100-6527841/">SanDisk 1.5TB MicroSD Card Is Steeply Discounted At Amazon - Expand Your Steam Deck Storage</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-series-x-s-owners-can-save-big-on-western-digitals-1tb-expansion-card/1100-6527818/">Xbox Series X|S Owners Can Save Big On Western Digital's 1TB Expansion Card</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-exclusive-pokemon-tcg-premium-collection-gets-huge-limited-time-discount/1100-6528386/">Amazon-Exclusive Pokemon TCG Premium Collection Gets Huge Limited-Time Discount</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/105566936584242225941?rel=author">Jon Bitner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529981&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fortnite-is-being-sued-over-its-item-shop-again\/1100-6529981\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529965&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-long-is-split-fiction-campaign-length-and-chapters-list\/1100-6529965\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529980&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/wwe-2k25-locker-codes\/1100-6529980\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529932&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/all-split-fiction-side-stories-and-locations\/1100-6529932\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529970&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kingdom-come-2-goes-drm-free-soon-massive-1-2-patch-release-date-confirmed\/1100-6529970\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529971&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-release-date-trailer-songs-game-pass\/1100-6529971\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529987&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-launches-in-june\/1100-6529987\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529953&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/inzoi-release-date-trailer-story\/1100-6529953\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529962&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/wwe-2k25-how-to-change-your-characters-appearance-in-the-island\/1100-6529962\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529935&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-new-wireless-dreamcast-controller-is-available-now-also-works-on-switch-and-pc\/1100-6529935\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529954&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/it-may-be-a-bad-idea-to-update-your-xbox-controller-right-now\/1100-6529954\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529836&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/suikoden-star-leap-is-the-first-new-suikoden-in-over-a-decade-and-its-a-mobile-game\/1100-6529836\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529925&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-prime-members-get-these-20-free-games-in-march\/1100-6529925\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529729&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mattels-official-minecraft-movie-toys-are-available-at-amazon\/1100-6529729\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529984&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-switch-2-specs-confirm-wi-fi-6-suggest-amiibo-compatibilities\/1100-6529984\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529959&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dungeon-crawler-carl-hardcover-editions-save-on-the-best-selling-litrpg\/1100-6529959\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529986&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2s-new-trailer-shows-the-rift-between-joel-and-ellie\/1100-6529986\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529973&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-next-update-resolves-some-notable-issues\/1100-6529973\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Control Ultimate Edition free update adds Hideo Kojima mission for all players]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/control-ultimate-edition-free-update-adds-hideo-kojima-mission-for-all-players</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/control-ultimate-edition-free-update-adds-hideo-kojima-mission-for-all-players.1130163/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/control-ultimate-edition-free-update-adds-hideo-kojima-mission-for-all-players<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Coming to PC, PS5 and Xbox Series.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/screenshot-from-control-with-an-image-of-Hideo-Kojima-overlayed-on-top.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Remedy/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Remedy has released a free content update for its Control Ultimate Edition.</p>
<p>The update - which includes access to Dr Yoshimi Tokui's Guided Imagery Experience featuring a certain <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/hideo-kojima">Hideo Kojima</a> - is arriving first for those on PC (Steam and Epic Games Store, with GOG to follow later) today.</p>
<p>It will then be available to those who have Control Ultimate Edition on either PS5 or Xbox series X/S consoles. "We have a small team working on these updates so we want to space them out to give us time to fix potential issues that might come up," the <a href="https://controlgame.com/control-march-2025-update-notes-pc/">developer explained</a>, saying it will update with dates as and when. "We appreciate your patience!"</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="13 Ways Control Gameplay Connects To Alan Wake - CONTROL + ALAN WAKE EASTER EGGS!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XaXnKMmOR2w?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>13 Ways Control Gameplay Connects To Alan Wake - CONTROL + ALAN WAKE EASTER EGGS!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XaXnKMmOR2w?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XaXnKMmOR2w?autoplay=1" title="13 Ways Control Gameplay Connects To Alan Wake - CONTROL + ALAN WAKE EASTER EGGS!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>13 Ways Control Gameplay Connects To Alan Wake. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XaXnKMmOR2w" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Here's everything included in today's free content update for Control Ultimate Edition, as laid out by Remedy.</p>
<p><strong>OUTFITS</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong>The following outfits are now available to all players. The outfits can be accessed and equipped from the Control Point in the Central Executive Sector area.</p>
<ul>
<li>Astral Dive Suit (formerly a pre-order exclusive)</li>
<li>Tactical Response Gear (formerly a pre-order exclusive)</li>
<li>Urban Response Gear (formerly a pre-order exclusive)</li>
<li>Extradimensional Suit (formerly obtainable in the AWE DLC by finishing SHÜM)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>MISSIONS</strong></p>
<p>All players will receive the mission Dr. Yoshimi Tokui's Guided Imagery Experience, featuring voiceover by Hideo Kojima. The mission is playable when you pick up the Dr Tokui Tapes collectible in the Extrasensory Lab of the Research Sector. (This mission was previously exclusive to the PlayStation 4 Digital Deluxe version of Control.)</p>
<p><strong>GRAPHICS</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added HDR support</li>
<li>Added new Ultra ray tracing preset, which gets you more rays per pixel and higher temporal stability</li>
<li>Added ultrawide monitor support for up to 48:9 monitors</li>
<li>Added an FOV scaling setting for the gameplay camera</li>
<li>Updated SDR to 10bit (from 8bit), which reduces visible color banding</li>
<li>Improved graphics adapter detection at startup, with automatic selection between DX11 and DX12</li>
<li>Implemented screen aspect ratio fixes for ultrawide monitors</li>
<li>Your current monitor resolution can now reliably be selected from the screen resolution and rendering resolution menus</li>
<li>Added rendering resolution support beyond 4K</li>
<li>Implemented texture streaming fixes</li>
<li>Ray tracing bug fixes</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>DLSS SUPPORT</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added DLSS support for arbitrary resolutions</li>
<li>Added DLAA support</li>
<li>Updated DLSS to DLSS 3.7, with higher temporal stability</li>
<li>Film grain added back to DLSS SR</li>
<li>Fixed shadow resolution when DLSS is enabled</li>
<li>Added resolution dependent mip map bias for DLSS. This enhances texture quality, for example when applying the DLSS Performance setting.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>GENERAL</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Updated the audio on cinematics and end credits to remove unintended channel mixing. You will no longer hear anything that isn't intended to be heard. (It wasn't the Hiss, it was us. Sorry.)</li>
<li>Several bug and crash fixes</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GlrubOzWYAAfM6q.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Remedy</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for what's next for Remedy and its Control series, the world is set to expand this year with the developer's multiplayer release, FBC: Firebreak.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/alan-wake-control-developer-remedy-reveals-first-ever-multiplayer-game">FBC: Firebreak is scheduled to release later this year</a>, across PC via Steam and Epic Games Store, Xbox Series X S and PlayStation 5. It will also be available across PC Game Pass and Game Pass Ultimate, as well as day one onto the PlayStation Plus Game Catalogue, which is available for all Extra and Premium members.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the launch of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/control-2-tease-lies-in-alan-wake-2s-lake-house-dlc-fans-say">Alan Wake 2's Lake House expansion last year provided what looks to be an intriguing tease for where Control 2's story is headed</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Control March 2025 PC Update Introduces New Ultra Ray Tracing Preset, Support for Resolutions Higher Than 4K, Updates NVIDIA DLSS to Version 3.7 and M]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/control-arch-2025-update-ultra-ray-tracing-dlss-3-7/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/control-march-2025-pc-update-introduces-new-ultra-ray-tracing-preset-support-for-resolutions-higher-than-4k-updates-nvidia-dlss-to-version-3-7-and-m.1130136/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/control-arch-2025-update-ultra-ray-tracing-dlss-3-7/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Control update has gone live today on PC, introducing a new ray tracing preset, official HDR support, NVIDIA DLSS updates, and more.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://controlgame.com/control-march-2025-update-notes-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1.30 update</a> brings to all users content that was previously available only as a pre-order bonus, such as the Astral Dive Suit, the Tactical Response Gear, and the Urban Response Gear, as well as the Dr. Yoshimi Tokui's Guided Imagery Experience featuring voiceover by Hideo Kojima, which was only available as a PS4 Digital Deluxe Edition pre-order bonus.</p>
<p>Besides making pre-order exclusive content available to all, the new Control March 2025 PC update introduces plenty of technical improvements, such as a new ultra ray tracing preset which gets the user more rays per pixel and higher temporal stability, ultrawide resolution support up to 48:9 aspect ratio, updated SDR to 10 bits to reduce visible color banding, support for resolutions higher than 4K and more. Additionally, the new update also updates NVIDIA DLSS to version 3.7 with higher temporal stability and adds DLAA and arbitrary resolutions support, among other things.</p>
<p>The Control 1.30 update also finally brings official HDR support to the game, but <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-new-patch-for-remedys-control-just-dropped-adds-fake-hdr-despite-true-hdr-being-available-via-semi-official-mod.1129878/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">according to online reports</a>, it only caps the overall brightness value without adding additional highlight detail, so the<a href="https://wccftech.com/control-unofficial-hdr-ultrawide-patch-version-1-4-brings-hdr-and-dlss-improvements-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> unofficial implementation</a> still continues to be the way to go for those with HDR monitors.</p>
<p>Control is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, and Xbox One worldwide. <a href="https://wccftech.com/remedy-says-control-2-will-be-an-action-rpg-alan-wake-2-has-sold-1-8-million-units/">A sequel</a> is currently in the works, alongside a spin-off multiplayer game called FBC: Firebreak, which will launch<a href="https://wccftech.com/fbc-firebreak-multiplayer-game-set-in-the-control-world-revealed-with-new-trailer/"> later this year.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Split Fiction Sales Hit 1m in First 48 Hours]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-sales-1m-48-hours</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/split-fiction-sales-hit-1m-in-first-48-hours.1130133/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-sales-1m-48-hours<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>EA and Hazelight Studios' new co-op action-adventure platformer&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>has reached a major sales milestone, the two studios have announced, and it only took the game a measly two days to get there.</p>

<p>Per a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/hazelightgames.bsky.social/post/3ljztto3sws2v" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on Hazelight's Bluesky page,&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>managed to sell a million copies within its first 48 hours, which is a pretty impressive milestone. Hazelight says it's "beyond happy" with the result and that it "can't stop enjoying [fans'] amazing reactions".</p>

<p><em>Split Fiction</em>'s strong performance probably shouldn't come as a surprise given that it was EA's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-ea-second-most-played-game-steam" rel="nofollow">second most-played game of all time on Steam</a> just a day or so after its release, losing out only to battle royale shooter&nbsp;<em>Apex Legends&nbsp;</em>(and I can't exactly blame it on that score).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/split-fiction-sales-1m-sci-fi.jpg?itok=kYAo-5hT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/split-fiction-sales-1m-sci-fi.jpg?itok=EV7NyvLS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>has done pretty well for EA and Hazelight sales-wise.</figcaption></figure><p>For context, it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/it-takes-two-sales-hit-1-million-copies-in-month" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">took around a month</a> for&nbsp;<em>It Takes Two&nbsp;</em>to reach the same milestone. That game would go on to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hazelight-josef-fares-new-ip-it-takes-two-sales" rel="nofollow">sell more than 20 million copies</a> at last count, so it's entirely possible that&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>will do even better for itself.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction</em>, it's the latest game from&nbsp;<em>A Way Out&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>It Takes Two&nbsp;</em>developer Hazelight Studios.</p>

<p>Like the studio's previous games (with the exception of&nbsp;<em>Brothers: A Tale of Two Sons</em>),&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>can only be played as a co-op game; there's no single-player mode here, since the story and gameplay both revolve heavily around two individuals.</p>

<p>However, if you do happen to want to try out the game, the Friend's Pass <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-friends-pass-crossplay" rel="nofollow">means you can play it with anyone on any platform</a>, whether they own the game or not (as long as you do, of course).</p>




<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2001120/Split_Fiction/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/split-fiction/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/split-fiction/9N1WXXD1RL8D" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. Make sure to read our Erren's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/split-fiction-review-everything-everywhere" rel="nofollow">review of the game</a> to see how it holds up!</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Split Fiction Reaches Major Sales Milestone]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-reaches-major-sales-milestone/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/split-fiction-reaches-major-sales-milestone.1130121/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-reaches-major-sales-milestone/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-94458">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Split Fiction, the latest co-op game from Hazelight Studios, has hit a major sales milestone. The developers have announced that Split Fiction sold over one million copies in its first 48 hours of availability.</p>



<p>Hazelight Studios launched on March 6, meaning that the current number is likely higher than the one million mark set on March 8.</p>



<p>“The love you all show for our game is overwhelming!” the studio said via <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/hazelightgames.bsky.social/post/3ljztto3sws2v" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">social media</a>. “Everyone here at Hazelight are beyond happy – and we can’t stop enjoying your amazing reactions!”</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-the-future-of-call-of-duty-insider-gaming-weekly">PODCAST: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-future-of-call-of-duty-insider-gaming-weekly/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Future Of Call of Duty—Insider Gaming Weekly</a></h6>



<p>Split Fiction is available now for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. The game features cross-platform multiplayer, and those who want to play with a friend only need to own one copy of the game to enjoy online co-op. </p>



<p>Have you played Split Fiction yet or are you still waiting to check it out? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-release-date-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date for Death Stranding 2</a> and check out the first trailer for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/verdansk-officially-returning-to-call-of-duty-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the return of Verdansk</a> to Call of Duty: Warzone.  And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/verdansk-officially-returning-to-call-of-duty-warzone/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/verdansk-officially-returning-to-call-of-duty-warzone/">Verdansk Officially Returning To Call of Duty: Warzone</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Activision has officially  announced that Verdansk is returning to Call of Duty: Warzone alongside Season  3.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-receives-esrb-rating-for-ps5/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-receives-esrb-rating-for-ps5/">Indiana Jones and The Great Circle Receives ESRB Rating for PS5</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle has received an ESRB rating for the PS5, hinting that a release date announcement could arrive soon. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/motive-iron-man-game-demo-ready-gdc/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/motive-iron-man-game-demo-ready-gdc/">Motive’s Iron Man Game Might Be Demo Ready at GDC</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Motive’s Iron Man might be under a spotlight at GDC, if a scheduling post is anything to go by. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-xbox-not-a-console-at-all-insider/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-xbox-not-a-console-at-all-insider/">Next Xbox Might Not Be a Traditional Console, Insider Claims</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It has been claimed that the next Xbox won’t be a traditional home console but more of a gaming PC in a ‘TV-friendly shell’.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Players Discover Captured Monsters Will Eventually Just Exit Stage Left]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-players-discover-captured-monsters-will-eventually-just-exit-stage-left</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-players-discover-captured-monsters-will-eventually-just-exit-stage-left.1130118/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-players-discover-captured-monsters-will-eventually-just-exit-stage-left<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Most people associate Monster Hunter with actually hunting monsters, but capturing is an important piece of the pie, too. As <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> players have discovered, capturing a monster and hanging around long enough can result in a funny little interaction playing out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As shown by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1j7olr4/fun_fact_captured_monsters_just_get_up_and_leave/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit user RDGtheGreat over on the r/MonsterHunter subreddit</a>, hanging around a captured monster long enough will let you catch a little behind-the-scenes magic. Namely, the monster getting up and leaving.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After capturing a Nu Udra and waiting around, the giant cephalopod just kind of gets up and leaves. Jokes about it all feeling like a wrap on a film set <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1j7olr4/comment/mgylnqy/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">were made a few times over</a>, it's some good fun. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For actual in-universe theories as to why this is happening, well, it's not like the research team has giant cages or anything. Monster Hunter Wilds taking a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1j7olr4/comment/mgzf2rm/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more catch-and-release approach</a> to their studies certainly seems appropriate, and fits with the general attitude of Alma and the rest throughout the story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whatever the lore reasons are, it's a fun little moment. I find it neat that the developers at Capcom thought this scenario through and planned a little animation, rather than just a fade out. It looks a little silly with this monster, now lacking in several limbs and other appendages, scurrying off into the distance. But it's a neat touch that possibly adds some deeper insight as to how Alma and the crew are conducting their research.</p><div id="monster-hunter-wilds-weapons-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Monster Hunter Wilds Weapons Tier List</h3><h3>Monster Hunter Wilds Weapons Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-patch-10000500-fixes-quest-blockers-among-other-things-but-there-are-no-performance-improvements-yet">Patch 1.000.05.00 just went live for Monster Hunter Wilds</a>, fixing some quest progression blockers and addressing bugs. Performance tunings are still on the way, as the game still sits at a '<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mixed' overall rating on Steam</a> as of this writing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To help get your Monster Hunter Wilds adventure started, take a look at <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/monster-hunter-wilds/Things_Monster_Hunter_Wilds_Doesn%27t_Tell_You_-_Tips"><u>what Monster Hunter Wilds doesn’t tell you</u></a>, and a guide to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/monster-hunter-wilds/Weapons"><u>all 14 weapon types</u></a> in the game. We’ve also got a detailed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/monster-hunter-wilds/Walkthrough"><u>Monster Hunter Wilds walkthrough</u></a> in progress, a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/monster-hunter-wilds/Multiplayer_Guide_-_Crossplay,_Link_Parties_and_More"><u>Monster Hunter Wilds multiplayer</u></a> guide to explain how to play with friends, and if you’ve played one of the open betas, here’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/monster-hunter-wilds/How_to_Transfer_Beta_Character_Creator_Data"><u>how to transfer your Monster Hunter Wilds Beta character</u></a> over.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-review"><u>Monster Hunter Wilds review</u></a> returned an 8/10. We said: “Monster Hunter Wilds continues to smooth off the rougher corners of the series in smart ways, making for some extremely fun fights but also lacking any real challenge.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Reveals $170 Mario Kart Set Specifically Designed for Adult Builders]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-reveals-170-mario-kart-set-specifically-designed-for-adult-builders</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-reveals-170-mario-kart-set-specifically-designed-for-adult-builders.1130115/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-reveals-170-mario-kart-set-specifically-designed-for-adult-builders<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Don't break these bricks.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It's Mario's big day, and Nintendo's plumber is getting a new Lego set with quite a few pieces in the box. Lego has revealed a new Mario Kart Lego set today, March 10, with almost 2,000 pieces and an "18+" age recommendation, arriving on May 15, 2025. It's available to <a href="https://zdcs.link/9wXvkb?object_uuid=dd9b580c-ead5-4882-b0b5-bf79e0f3a7d8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">preorder now at the LEGO Store</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Originally spotted <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/a-new-lego-mario-kart-set-aimed-at-adults-has-appeared-online-ahead-of-an-official-announcement/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">popping up on some store listings</a>, Lego has officially unveiled the set, which includes both Mario and his Standard Kart from the Mario Kart series. It's a detailed model, meant for display and decor, with a special stand meant to showcase Mario and his kart at various angles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/mario-kart-mario-standard-kart-72037" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lego's site</a>, the company clocks the Mario Kart build at 1,972 pieces with a recommended "18+" Ages rating. This is due to the complexity of the build, it seems, and the intention of the product versus sets meant for play. "This building kit is part of a large assortment of LEGO Sets for Adults designed for people who enjoy hands-on creative activities to relax," Lego said in its description.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Here we go! 🏆 Launching May 15th 🏁 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LEGOSuperMario?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#LEGOSuperMario</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MarioKart?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#MarioKart</a> <a href="https://t.co/NZ13sCIFHo" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/NZ13sCIFHo</a></p>— Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) <a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1899083988142092785?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">March 10, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The tenor of this build certainly seems aimed at the older, "advanced" builder of Lego. It also works with the Lego Builder app, which offers in-app building instructions and tools that let builders zoom and rotate around a 3D image of the model as they build. The final result is a posable, Lego-made Mario in his Kart.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lego and Mario have built up a solid relationship over the years, with the collaboration resulting in numerous crossover sets. There's the Lego Super Mario line, which erred more on the side of interactive play and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-super-mario-is-great-once-it-clicks">incorporated some game elements into its set design</a>.</p><div catalogid="c504915f-8be6-46c4-874c-f7103df9f4c4" id="216537"><div id="216537" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Mario Kart – Mario &amp; Standard Kart</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, some other options were aimed more at the older crowd who might like to build for relaxation and display over interactivity, like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/my-first-adult-lego-purchase-was-this-mario-set-and-i-have-no-regrets">the Pirahna Plant</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-build-lego-super-mario-world-mario-yoshi">the Lego Super Mario World set featuring Mario and Yoshi</a>. Some offer activities for the kids, while others offer nostalgia and complex builds for the adults.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Lego Mario Kart build is up for pre-order now, at a price point of $169.99 / £139.99 / €169.99. The set will fully launch on May 15, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Mar 10, 2025 2:40 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forgotlings launches June 12 for PC, later for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, and Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/forgotlings-launches-june-12-for-pc-later-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forgotlings-launches-june-12-for-pc-later-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch.1130112/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/forgotlings-launches-june-12-for-pc-later-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>2D cinematic action adventure game from studio behind Forgotton Anne.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>2D cinematic <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [924 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,549 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Forgotlings [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/forgotlings">Forgotlings</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,548 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2059570/Forgotlings/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on Jue 12, followed by <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,012 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,850 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,790 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,836 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,765 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> at a later date, publisher <a title="Companies > Hitcents [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hitcents">Hitcents</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Throughline Games [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/throughline-games">Throughline Games</a> announced. <span id="more-949000"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2059570/Forgotlings/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Forgotlings</em> is a breathtaking cinematic action adventure set in an enchanted realm inhabited by lost things searching for a purpose. Journey to distant corners of our collective memories and unite warring tribes against a mysterious looming threat to their existence.</p><p>A wholly original storyworld filled with wonder and imagination awaits your discovery.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Travel the lands as Fig, a gifted posing doll, and captain of the sentient ship Volare.</li><li>Bandits and critters lurk in the wilderness – Be <a title="Genres > Stealth [76 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a>y or confront enemies head-on.</li><li>Connect with forgotlings from various tribes through conversation or challenge them to a game of INA—a popular pastime in the world of forgotlings!</li><li>Full voice-acting bring characters and moments to life together with a beautifully haunting score featuring the renowned ensemble Theatre of Voices.</li><li>Choose your destination in your quest to unite all things lost in this semi-open world <a title="Genres > Metroidvania [198 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/metroidvania">Metroidvania</a>.</li><li>Thousands of hand-drawn animation frames and beautifully realized environments makes you feel as if you’re playing an animated movie.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Forgotlings Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wfjXWA5QW78?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[God Of War's 20th Anniversary Event Will Have Donuts And Beach Towels, But No New Announcements]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/god-of-wars-20th-anniversary-event-will-have-donuts-and-beach-towels-but-no-new-announcements/1100-6530004/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/god-of-wars-20th-anniversary-event-will-have-donuts-and-beach-towels-but-no-new-announcements.1130106/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/god-of-wars-20th-anniversary-event-will-have-donuts-and-beach-towels-but-no-new-announcements/1100-6530004/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530004">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sony Santa Monica and Gallery Nucleus are collaborating on an exhibition to celebrate God of War's 20th anniversary later this month, but don't expect any new announcements.</p><p>"With such a stellar lineup and all the anticipation we’ve seen around the anniversary, we do want to be clear that there are no planned announcements for this event," Sony Santa Monica <a href="https://x.com/SonySantaMonica/status/1898101454038351995" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">clarified on Twitter</a>.</p><p>The <a href="https://gallerynucleus.com/events/1072?more_info=1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">exhibition</a> runs between March 15-23, with a panel cast and game dev taking place on March 15 and 22. While there won't be any new announcements, attendees will be able to check out and grab limited edition prints, Phantasy Arcade Cabinets, God of War-themed donuts from Moonbridge, and a Kratos beach towel.</p><p>Sony Santa Monica has been silent on what it's been working on since it launched God of War Ragnarok in 2022. However, the studio is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/god-of-war-developer-sony-santa-monica-is-reportedly-working-on-a-new-ip/1100-6525531/" data-ref-id="1100-6525531">reportedly working on its first new IP</a> since the debut of God of War back in 2005.</p><p>There are rumors that the games in the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rumored-god-of-war-remasters-for-ps5-could-be-revealed-in-march/1100-6529692/" data-ref-id="1100-6529692">original God of War trilogy</a> are being remastered and that the reveal would occur around the franchise's anniversary, but Sony has now confirmed that there won't be any planned announcements during the exhibition. However, it's possible that there could be announcements outside of the event.</p><p>Bluepoint Games, the studio behind the Demon's Souls remake, was also reportedly working on a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-cancels-two-games-including-a-live-service-god-of-war-report/1100-6528869/" data-ref-id="1100-6528869">God of War live-service game that was ultimately canceled</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The surprising origins and alien inspirations of Extreme Evolution: Drive to Divinity]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-surprising-origins-and-alien-ethos-of-extreme-evolution-drive-to-divinity</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-surprising-origins-and-alien-inspirations-of-extreme-evolution-drive-to-divinity.1130103/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-surprising-origins-and-alien-ethos-of-extreme-evolution-drive-to-divinity<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The&nbsp;</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://igf.com/">IGF</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>&nbsp;(Independent Games Festival) aims to encourage innovation in game development and to recognize independent game developers advancing the medium.&nbsp;</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/keyword/road-to-the-igf">This year, Game Developer sat down with the finalists for the IGF's Nuovo Award and the Seamas McNally Grand Prize</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>&nbsp;ahead of GDC to explore the themes, design decisions, and tools behind each entry. Game Developer and GDC are sibling organizations under Informa.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nuovo Award nominee </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Extreme Evolution: Drive to Divinity</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is an experience in movement and transformation across stunning,&nbsp;alien worlds that you're tasked with bouncing, flinging, and leaping through.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer caught up with Sam Atlas, the Nuovo Award-nominated game's creator, to talk about its surprising origins in body horror, the thought and design processes that go into shaping the game's colorful landscapes, and the challenges that come from creating visual accessibility features in a game that can sometimes border on visually-overwhelming with its shifting cosmos.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Who are you, and what was your role in developing </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Extreme Evolution: Drive to Divinity</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I'm Sam Atlas! I did everything except the music and some other sound effects for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Extreme Evolution</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which were composed and recorded by DL Salo.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What's your background in making games?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This is my 4th standalone game and the follow-up to the</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> Space Hole </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">trilogy. Before my own games, I made mods especially on the Source (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Half Life 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">) engine (I generally made level pack style single-player mods).&nbsp;I've got a background in general software, so I approach game development from a holistic/ synergistic approach (i.e. mix tech and design).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>How did you come up with the concept for </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Extreme Evolution: Drive to Divinity</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It started as a vague project called </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Flesh</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which was going to be more of a horror game about an organism seeking humanity through the mechanical accumulation of human parts.&nbsp;It was a brain in a void, and the game would have been in first person, with real-life footage of hands/organs as the tools you use. These tools would be used to, for example, paddle your hand to swim the psychic-brain around.&nbsp;Accumulation and the imitation of humanity were themes; but it was more body horror.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What development tools were used to build your game?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Unity, chatGPT, VSCode, Blender (lightly for certain 3d), Unity ProBuilder (the majority of custom 3d meshes), Paint.NET, Davinci Resolve, Audacity, and my camera phone! I take videos/photos of natural patterns, such as waves or light reflecting on water, or fire, and loop those in the video editor (by flipping and tessellating the videos).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Extreme Evolution: Drive to Divinity</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> explores many different forms of movement as you explore its dizzying visual landscapes. What thoughts went into creating the various ways players could evolve to move around? What made a form of movement feel interesting to you to include in the game?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One core design idea for the game was "a platformer where every pickup extends your range."&nbsp; The main design idea here was to begin stumbling—a speck of dust or a pebble rolling/shambling—and by the end to be a maximally-empowered platformer (i.e., fling yourself, drive up walls, hang in the air indefinitely etc). So, a lot of the form design derived from trying to find a middle ground between "can go anywhere" and "can only tumble along the ground."&nbsp; The name "Extreme Evolution" alludes to this: starting at the most basic (a clunky, oblong egg) and eventually the most obscene (Deity, a hovering orb that spits out projectiles that seek pickups and count as part of your body). "Drive to Divinity" is also a reference to this, and another literal description of the game.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Movement often comes with unique shapes that feel alien, but also convey some of their capabilities to the player through shape and form. What thoughts went into making movement feel somewhat clear while also keeping things mysterious?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For this, I think the key is to make the rules of the world consistent and to use visual cues to explain how objects interact. Furthermore, I have a short flavor text for each form, which, when combined with its name, was intended to convey some efficient expectation to the player. For example, "Cor" is "the oblong car," and it is both a corrupted motorcycle and a corruption of the word "Car."&nbsp; But as is the case in nature, the "Car" remains around in the world as well. I wanted the world to have a sense of logic and consistency to it, as well as a mix of earth-references and references that seem alien.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>You put a great deal of thought and work into the visuals of your games, crafting this sense of moving through higher realities of color and shape. What feelings were you looking to evoke in the player with the cosmic visual work in this game?&nbsp;</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">My goal is to create an environment that you haven't seen before. I think the fun of the game is a repeating cycle of "what's over there?" and following intuition. I want to encourage the player to feel in control of their experience. I make games essentially by playing through them extremely slowly, making the levels in front of me as I go. So, whichever game I make tends to represent my feelings during development, or the feeling that I wanted.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What thoughts went into birthing this whole new visual cosmic universe? How do you craft whole worlds to platform in that capture this sense of being otherworldly and alien through your use of color and shape?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Iteration, willingness to cut ideas/areas, and gradually narrowing the focus of my work as a level progresses. It takes many, many coats of paint (and sometimes major cuts) to make sure each zone has a good feeling.&nbsp; For this game, the whole overall thing was "playable" a year before release in an alpha form, but everything went through major revisions following that.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Basically, I become more focused/editorial as I get deeper into development, but every level starts with some kind of simple idea (for example, "Thyroid" was conceived as "Jump," a delta where you are given many exits to choose between; the name "Thyroid" was chosen due to the geographical notion of the thyroid as a gateway to the body from the head). Sometimes, the name of the level is a remnant of that original idea and separate from the actual level (which sometimes is funny, so I leave it in). Often, levels become most extreme at some middle point in development—the most visual elements, the most pickups, etc. Then, over time, like a sine wave, I cut/uncut stuff until it feels right.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What challenges do you face in creating visuals that can be so powerful they border on overwhelming? What is it like to pore over these visions as you weave them together while developing the game?&nbsp;</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I like to develop the game intuitively, so the border between "too much" and the right amount is always revealed only by the end of the project (but really, many years after).&nbsp;I also will sometimes revert to an earlier version but keep a single element from the newer (cut) revision, resulting in a hybrid that is mostly the old but with some specific improvement. I also have learnt to be sensitive (and un-offended) to the way people respond to visuals; people respond in a very specific way (they avoid playing) if it's making them nauseous, so I do mix my own feelings with the (sometimes visceral) player reactions. If you go too far everywhere, it also reduces the sense of change when entering spaces that are more or less intense.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>You have put in some systems to help players who may have difficulties or health issues that are affected by the game's visuals, but they cannot be turned all the way off. What ideas go into balancing the need to protect the player with preserving the vital visual style of </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Extreme Evolution: Drive to Divinity</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I think of accessibility as a natural tool to make games better. I think it's absolutely a balance; another element of this issue (ensuring people don't have a physically painful experience playing the game) is to represent the game as accurately as possible in marketing materials. And, while you can turn lots of the effects off, there is a limit because I wanted to make sure every version of the game at least emphasized the separation of foreground and background.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Using the Mod menu (unlocked about an hour into the game) you can go further into untested effects. However, because of the large amount of complex color correction, there are cases where turning an effect off might result in the ground and sky being too close in color. The major effect which produces nauseous feelings in my game is using uncleared buffers; this results in pixels which can change each frame as their behavior becomes so unpredictable. To balance this, I've tried blurring in the past, but now I use blur (and motion blur) as sparingly as possible because I find it tends not to be worth its nauseousness-to-budget, so to speak.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The representation of nothingness as infinitely-complex static feels too perfect and fitting for the game and the game's themes (nothingness/everythingness) to not be on by default in my mind, but I also have no qualms about the idea that some future playerbase might prefer it off. Ownership and setting your own goals is an intention of the game. I mostly focus on making sure the geometry of the level still reads and making sure the default modes reflect what I personally prefer when enabling accessible graphics options. I'm happier with how I've managed the accessibility features in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Extreme Evolution</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> over </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Space Hole 2020</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but it's something I spend a lot of time thinking about for future projects.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty's original Verdansk map return dated]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-dutys-original-verdansk-map-return-dated</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-dutys-original-verdansk-map-return-dated.1130100/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-dutys-original-verdansk-map-return-dated<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Celebrating fifth anniversary.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Unforgettable-Verdansk-Teaser-_-Call-of-Duty_-Warzone-0-38-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Activision</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Call of Duty's original Verdansk map is set to return on 3rd April.</p>
<p>Activision shared the news on social media, adding "it's time to revisit a place of unforgettable memories".</p>
<p>The map return will coincide with Season 3 of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-2024">Black Ops 6</a> and Warzone, as a celebration of Warzone's fifth anniversary.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Unforgettable Verdansk Teaser | Call of Duty: Warzone" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX2LeqDlkBg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Unforgettable Verdansk Teaser | Call of Duty: Warzone</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX2LeqDlkBg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OX2LeqDlkBg?autoplay=1" title="Unforgettable Verdansk Teaser | Call of Duty: Warzone">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Unforgettable Verdansk Teaser | Call of Duty: Warzone<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OX2LeqDlkBg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-warzones-classic-verdansk-map-returning-next-year">return of Verdansk was revealed last year</a> - it's the original map for the battle royale that's no longer available.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-season-delayed-verdansk-return-now-expected-next-month">Activision announced a delay to Season 3 last week</a>, which was widely expected to include the Verdansk map. Now it's officially confirmed.</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>As we celebrate Call of Duty: Warzone’s 5 Year Anniversary, it's time to revisit a place of unforgettable memories 🪂</p><p>Verdansk returns to Call of Duty: Warzone on April 3 💥 <a href="https://t.co/Ot7i77VOtd">pic.twitter.com/Ot7i77VOtd</a></p></div>— Call of Duty (@CallofDuty) <a href="https://twitter.com/CallofDuty/status/1899083215802904607?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 10, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Verdansk's return follows a similar move from Epic with the return of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a>'s classic OG map, which resulted in its highest-ever player count of 44.7 million participants in 24 hours. It's now a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-reviving-original-map-as-permanent-addition-featuring-multiple-classic-seasons">permanent addition to Fortnite</a>. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pubg-is-doing-a-fortnite-and-bringing-back-its-original-island-map">PUBG also brought back its original map</a>, Erangel.</p>
<p>It's hoped this new season can turn around the fortunes of Call of Duty so far this year.</p>
<p>Ahead of the second season's launch, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-bans-another-136000-cheaters">Activision stated it was dealing with rampant cheating</a>, acknowledging cheaters "are frustrating and severely impact the experience for our community".</p>
<p>Before that, the company was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-block-ops-6-players-accuse-activision-of-using-ai-slop">accused of using "AI slop"</a> following artwork of a six-fingered zombie Santa. Then in February, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-admits-call-of-duty-includes-generative-ai">Activision admitted to using AI</a> in an update to the Call of Duty Steam page.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>