<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 19:56:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Interactive Entertainment to Integrate Subsidiary SN Systems]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sony-interactive-entertainment-to-integrate-subsidiary-sn-systems/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-interactive-entertainment-to-integrate-subsidiary-sn-systems.1101219/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/sony-interactive-entertainment-to-integrate-subsidiary-sn-systems/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been announced that Sony Interactive Entertainment will integrate wholly owned subsidiary SN Systems, which is a developer company of programming tools for game creators on PlayStation consoles. They will then become one unified company on April 1.</p>
<p>To provide a bit of context about SN Systems and what they do, the company was first founded in 1990 and acquired by Sony Interactive Entertainment. Then, in 2005, Sony Computer Entertainment acquired SN Systems. Since then, the companies have been working closely together to help create software development kits and game creation tools for the Sony consoles. This includes PlayStation 3, PS Vita, <a href="http://wccftech.com/ps4-razor-gpucpu-profiler-pc-sampling-detailed-sn-systems-working-optimize-console/">PlayStation 4</a>, and PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>SN Systems originally began as a two-person operation and has since expanded across the globe, becoming an international company with more than 100 employees. The company's headquarters are based in Bristol in the UK, with other satellite offices in Dublin and California. Due to the nature of the company, they also work closely with the Sony Interactive Entertainment office in Japan and some of their other SIE offices in the US and Europe.</p>
<p>"The exceptionally talented team at SN Systems has been an integral part of Sony Interactive Entertainment by driving innovation in tools development, which has been central to our success across multiple PlayStation generations. This next step in our partnership will strengthen our shared sense of unity. together, we look forward to continuing to empower developers to create compelling gaming experiences for PlayStation players," said Sony Interactive Entertainment Platform Business Group CEO Hideaki Nishino.</p>
<p>SN Systems has developed technologies such as debuggers, toolchains, and performance analyzers to help aid the developers in their creative processes and to try and provide a more efficient way of working and creating the games for Sony consoles.</p>
<p>Considering how closely linked these companies are with each other, it makes total sense as a business move to finally integrate the two companies, and it's interesting that it hasn't happened sooner, especially since they've been working together since the PlayStation 1.</p>
<p>Not only did they provide tools for Sony, though, but they also helped provide tools for the Sega Genesis, Super NES, Nintendo 64, GameCube, and the Nintendo DS.</p>
<p>Sony Interactive Entertainment <a href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/press-releases/2025/sony-interactive-entertainment-announces-the-integration-of-wholly-owned-subsidiary-sn-systems/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">goes on to say</a> that the integration of SN Systems will "drive further innovation and creativity for PlayStation products and services." While the development process was already considered to be efficient thanks to the tools of SN Systems, by having the companies integrate wholly, it will reportedly enhance operational efficiencies.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man Puts A New Spin On Captain America: Civil War]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spiderman-civil-war-marvel-1851756150</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-puts-a-new-spin-on-captain-america-civil-war.1101216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spiderman-civil-war-marvel-1851756150<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>When it comes to Marvel Cinematic Universe lore, few things have been more impactful than <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/what-we-liked-and-loved-about-captain-america-civil-wa-1775100456?_gl=1*v7limb*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODc3NzcyNS4zOTEuMS4xNzM4Nzc4MTM1LjQ4LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/what-we-liked-and-loved-about-captain-america-civil-wa-1775100456?_gl=1*v7limb*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODc3NzcyNS4zOTEuMS4xNzM4Nzc4MTM1LjQ4LjAuMA.."><em>Captain America: Civil War</em></a></span>, which signaled a seismic shift in the MCU’s future by introducing characters and moments Marvel fans still gush about. The seminal film is largely remembered for the jaw-dropping introductions of Black Panther (Chadwick Boseman) and Spider-Man (Tom Holland) into the MCU. But, in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-disney-marvel-1851750993&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-disney-marvel-1851750993"><em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man</em></a></span>, that wouldn’t have happened.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196032" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku Unboxes The Spider-Man 2 Limited Edition PS5" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="270" data-playlist="196032,195896,195859" data-current="196032"><div><p>Kotaku Unboxes The Spider-Man 2 Limited Edition PS5</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196032/196032_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196032/196032_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196032/196032_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196032/196032_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21556.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><figure id="" data-id="f21e10ac63e9f4a566d32e835951aeda" data-recommend-id="image://f21e10ac63e9f4a566d32e835951aeda" data-format="jpg" data-width="1315" data-height="145" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Kotaku Spoiler Warning" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Kotaku Spoiler Warning" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="in-house-art" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Graphic<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f21e10ac63e9f4a566d32e835951aeda" data-recommend-id="image://f21e10ac63e9f4a566d32e835951aeda" data-format="jpg" data-width="1315" data-height="145" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Kotaku Spoiler Warning" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>In Episode 4, titled “Hitting the Big Time,” Peter Parker (Hudson Thames) is informed by Norman Osborn (Colman Domingo) of the ratification of The Sokovia Accords, the  governmental oversight measures that most notably required super-powered individuals to register with their respective governments. In <em>Civil War</em>, its passage divided superhero leaders Captain America (Chris Evans) and Iron Man (Robert Downey Jr) over whether superheroes should sign it or not, forcing others like Black Panther and Spider-Man to choose opposing sides. These differences come to a head during an intense all-out brawl among some of Marvel’s fiercest fighters at the Leipzig/Halle Airport in Germany.</p><p>In <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-marvel-venom-1851747418&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-marvel-venom-1851747418"><em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man</em></a></span>, Parker is not part of that fight, and instead finds out about it from a news report. Osborn tells Parker he’s his “own hero” when the young web slinger asks if the Avengers will patch it up, implying the fractured group’s reunion still hasn’t happened yet. In <em>Civil War</em>, Spider-Man’s involvement sets the foundation for this relationship with his mentor Tony Stark, who uncovers Parker’s identity as Spider-Man and gives him an upgraded Spider-Man suit in exchange for joining his team against Captain America. </p><p><em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man</em> acts as a sort of parallel universe in which Osborn takes the place of Stark, uncovering Parker’s identity in the series’ third episode and offering him a suit upgrade in the fourth. I doubt Marvel would ever make a series named <em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man </em>and turns its lovable character into a villain. But, Parker’s relationship with Stark in <em>Civil War </em>was a catalyst for him joining the Avengers and following in his mentor’s footsteps. Given Osborn’s storied history as a nefarious character known as the Green Goblin, his partnership with Parker will, at least, delay Spider-Man’s entry into the Avengers, and, at worst, make him their enemy. </p><p>Another wrinkle in <em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man</em> is that Parker’s fandom is reserved for Captain America, not Iron Man, which could be a foreshadowing of issues to come. In the series’ fourth episode, Osborn lays out his plan for Parker to represent the next generation of superheroes after the Avengers’ destructive involvement in the events of the first two <em>Avengers</em> films left parts of the world decimated without any superhero accountability. In this alternate reality, <em>Civil War</em> didn’t introduce Spider-Man to the MCU; instead, he’s being led on an uncharted path that potentially results in him being the leader of the world’s next era of protectors. Or, maybe it leads him to disappointing Osborn, driving him to madness, and eventually ending with the inventor dead. </p><p>Either way, we’ll be tuned in for the next few Wednesdays to find out. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Gets PC Benchmark and New System Requirements]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-pc-benchmark-and-new-system-requirements</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-pc-benchmark-and-new-system-requirements.1101213/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-pc-benchmark-and-new-system-requirements<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> is just a few weeks away, and Capcom has released a PC benchmark for players to see if their system is up to snuff. Alongside that, the PC system requirements have been officially lowered.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As announced during yesterday's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-spotlight-february-2025-and-monster-hunter-wilds-showcase-everything-announced">Capcom Spotlight</a>, the PC benchmark for Monster Hunter Wilds is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>live on Steam right now</u></a>. The tool will need to compile some shaders once it's loaded up, but otherwise it's fairly easy to run and see where your computer lands. It's a good idea to check, especially if you're curious about how the updated system requirements might affect your performance.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-system-requirements-revealed"><u>Previously</u></a>, the system requirements for hitting 1080p and 60 frames per second (with Frame Generation enabled) called for an Nvidia GeForce RTX 2070 Super, NVIDIA GeForce RTX 4060, or AMD Radeon RX 6700XT graphics card; an Intel Core i5-11600K, Intel Core i5-12400, AMD Ryzen 5 3600X, or AMD Ryzen 5 5500 CPU; and 16 GB of RAM.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-us/benchmark/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>an updated page alongside the benchmark</u></a>, Capcom appears to have lowered the requirements. For Recommended, or 1080p (FHD) with 60 frames per second and Frame Generation enabled, here are the new requirements:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>OS: </strong>Windows 10 (64-bit required) / Windows 11 (64-bit required)</li><li><strong>Processor: </strong>Intel Core i5-10400 / Intel Core i3-12100 / AMD Ryzen 5 3600</li><li><strong>Memory: </strong>16 GB</li><li><strong>Graphics Card (GPU): </strong>GeForce RTX 2060 Super / Radeon RX 6600 (8 GB VRAM)</li><li><strong>Storage: </strong>75 GB (SS required)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">This should, per Capcom's site, have Monster Hunter Wilds running at 1080p and 60 frames per second with Frame Generation enabled. As you might have noticed, it's a slight but still noticeable down-tick in requirements.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">All Monsters in Monster Hunter Wilds</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Users are <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1ihv19n/monster_hunter_wilds_requirements_officially/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>already reporting some noticeable benefits to performance</u></a> in the benchmark compared to the beta test, though that's with Frame Generation enabled. Steam Deck still doesn't seem likely; while the gaming rig I tested passed with flying colors, my personal attempt on the Deck didn't elicit promising results.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What's noticeable, alongside the processing changes, is the difference in storage size. Before, Monster Hunter Wilds called for 140 GB of available space on your SSD; now, it's 75 GB. As <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/whats-up-with-these-huge-video-game-install-sizes"><u>file sizes seem to constantly grow year-over-year</u></a>, it's surprising to see such a change.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more on what's in store for Monster Hunter Wilds, be sure to read up on our recent IGN First coverage, showcasing bouts with fearsome beasts <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/monster-hunter-wilds-oilwell-basin-apex-nu-udra-full-hunt-4k-ign-first"><u>like the apex monster Nu Udra</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-the-final-preview-ign-first"><u>our final hands-on impressions of Capcom's latest Monster Hunter</u></a> before it arrives later this month. Monster Hunter Wilds is out for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, and PC on February 28, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2K Reportedly Fires Boss At Live-Service Project Ethos Studio After Lukewarm Response]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2k-reportedly-fires-boss-at-live-service-project-ethos-studio-after-lukewarm-response/1100-6529271/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2k-reportedly-fires-boss-at-live-service-project-ethos-studio-after-lukewarm-response.1101210/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2k-reportedly-fires-boss-at-live-service-project-ethos-studio-after-lukewarm-response/1100-6529271/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529271">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2025-02-05T11:42:03-0800">February 5, 2025 at 11:42AM PST</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>2K Games has revealed a major change at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/project-ethos/" data-ref-id="5000-647673">Project Ethos</a> developer 31st Union, confirming that studio head Michael Condrey--known best for the Dead Space and Call of Duty franchises--is transitioning to an advisory role before an expected exit. Sources told <a href="https://kotaku.com/michael-condrey-projet-ethos-31st-union-2k-games-1851756173" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kotaku</a> that Condrey was fired, though 2K Games didn't use that terminology and maintains it is "very committed" to the game and the studio. </p><p>A 2K spokesperson told Kotaku that it is "grateful to Michael Condrey for the dedication, passion, and work ethic it took to build an incredible team and shape the vision of 31st Union." The statement went on to say that Condrey will be "transitioning his role in the short term" to become an advisor on Project Ethos. </p><p>"We remain very committed to the forward path for Project Ethos and the people and culture of the 31st Union studio," 2K said.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u5Y6b7nk0ZM" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/u5Y6b7nk0ZM" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>In November, 2K parent company Take-Two boss Strauss Zelnick said he <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-company-says-only-relying-on-sequels-could-spell-disaster/1100-6527627/" data-ref-id="1100-6527627">"couldn't be more proud"</a> of the team at 31st Union and Project Ethos. 31st Union held an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2k-games-unveils-new-hero-shooter-project-ethos-and-you-can-play-it-today/1100-6527220/" data-ref-id="1100-6527220">open test for the game at the end of 2024</a>, and Zelnick said the team has been "enthused" about the feedback. "So we're off to a great start, and there's more to come," he said.</p><p>GameSpot's hands-on preview of Project Ethos said 2K's first-ever live-service game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/project-ethos-is-delightfully-different-but-struggles-with-its-identity/1100-6527304/" data-ref-id="1100-6527304">had potential but suffers from an identity crisis.</a></p><p>This report came out just a day before Take-Two is due to report earnings on February 6. We will report back with new details on the situation surrounding Project Ethos if more information comes to light.</p><p>Condrey is best known for his work on the Dead Space and Call of Duty franchises. Condrey left Sledgehammer Games in 2018 to start the new 2K studio, while Sledgehammer's other co-founder, Glen Schofield, left in 2018 as well and eventually started Striking Distance Studios, but left the company following the disappointing launch of The Callisto Protocol. </p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2K’s 20th Birthday Brings Big Savings on Massive Titles Across Steam and Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/2ks-20th-birthday-brings-big-savings-on-massive-titles-across-steam-and-xbox/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2k%E2%80%99s-20th-birthday-brings-big-savings-on-massive-titles-across-steam-and-xbox.1101189/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/2ks-20th-birthday-brings-big-savings-on-massive-titles-across-steam-and-xbox/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>2K turns 20 this year, and as a way of celebrating 20 years of 2K, some of the most popular titles and franchises will be on sale on Xbox and Steam. If you've been wanting to pick up some of 2K's well-known franchises, now is the perfect time to do so. Additionally, if you want to get even more savings, there is a "20 for 20" bundle, which will have 20 of 2K's digital legacy titles, including Civilization IV, Mafia, Borderlands, and more. If you want to purchase the 20 for 20 bundle, you have until 10 AM PST / 1 PM ET / 6 PM GMT to purchase it. This bundle is only available on Steam, so you, unfortunately, will not be able to find it on Xbox.</p>
<p>Plus, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-2k-launcher-is-gone-forever-so-you-can-launch-everything-from-steam-and-epic-games-store/">2K Launcher is no more</a>, meaning you won't have to worry about opening another launcher if you are playing your games through Steam, making it a more seamless gaming experience.</p>
<p>For those on PC, the Steam sale starts on February 6 and will end on February 20. For those on Xbox, the sale starts on February 6 and ends on February 17.</p>
<p>The sales may differ slightly between the two, and below is a list of all the games on sale on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/publisher/2K" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and Xbox, respectively, along with their discount amount so you know how much of a bargain you're getting.</p>
<p>Below are the 2K titles on sale on Steam:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><em>Bioshock Collection&nbsp;</em></strong>(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Borderlands 3</em></strong>&nbsp;(90% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Borderlands Collection: Pandora's Box</em></strong>&nbsp;(75% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Civilization V Complete Edit</em></strong>&nbsp;(75% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>LEGO 2K Drive&nbsp;</em></strong>(60% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Mafia 1 Definitive Edition&nbsp;</em></strong>(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Mafia Trilogy</em></strong>&nbsp;(75% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Marvel's Midnight Suns</em></strong>&nbsp;(85% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Marvel's Midnight Suns Legendary Edition</em></strong>&nbsp;(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>NBA 2K25 All-Star Edition</em></strong>&nbsp;(65% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>NBA 2K25 Standard Edition</em></strong>&nbsp;(67% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Risk of Rain</em></strong>&nbsp;(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Risk of Rain 2</em></strong>&nbsp;(67% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>The Quarry</em></strong>&nbsp;(85% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>The Quarry Deluxe Edition</em></strong>&nbsp;(85% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Tiny Tina's Wonderlands</em></strong>&nbsp;(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Tiny Tina's Wonderlands: Chaotic Great Edition&nbsp;</em></strong>(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>TopSpin 2K25</em></strong>&nbsp;(67% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>TopSpin 2K25 Grand Slam Edition</em></strong>&nbsp;(67% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>WWE 2K24</em></strong>&nbsp;(67% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>XCOM 2</em></strong>&nbsp;(40% off)</li>
</ul>
<p>Then below are the titles that are on sale on Xbox:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><em>Bioshock Collection&nbsp;</em></strong>(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Borderlands 3&nbsp;</em></strong>(90% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Borderlands Collection: Pandora's Box</em></strong>&nbsp;(75% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>LEGO 2K Drive&nbsp;</em></strong>(60% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Mafia 1 Definitive Edition&nbsp;</em></strong>(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Mafia Trilogy</em></strong>&nbsp;(75% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Marvel's Midnight Suns</em></strong>&nbsp;(85% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Marvel's Midnight Suns Legendary Edition</em></strong>&nbsp;(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>NBA 2K25 All-Star Edition</em></strong>&nbsp;(65% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>NBA 2K25 Standard Edition</em></strong>&nbsp;(67% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Risk of Rain</em></strong>&nbsp;(75% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Risk of Rain 2</em></strong>&nbsp;(75% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>The Quarry&nbsp;</em></strong>(85% off on XB1) (86% off on XBS)</li>
<li><strong><em>Tiny Tina's Wonderlands&nbsp;</em></strong>(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>Tiny Tina's Wonderlands: Chaotic Great Edition&nbsp;</em></strong>(80% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>TopSpin 2K25</em></strong>&nbsp;(67% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>TopSpin 2K25 Grand Slam Edition</em></strong>&nbsp;(67% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>WWE 2K24</em></strong>&nbsp;(75% off)</li>
<li><strong><em>XCOM 2 Collection&nbsp;</em></strong>(90% off)</li>
</ul>
<p>Then, of course, there is the 20 for 20 bundle that you can get exclusively on Steam, which includes some of the most iconic titles by 2K.</p>
<p>What will you be picking up in the 2K 20th Birthday sale?</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 10 Vehicles and Mounts in MTG Aetherdrift]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/aetherdrift-top-10-vehicles-and-mounts</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/top-10-vehicles-and-mounts-in-mtg-aetherdrift.1101186/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/aetherdrift-top-10-vehicles-and-mounts<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Aetherdrift </em>is almost here, and it’s time to zoom across the race course with the best vehicles and mounts you can find. Over 50 new rides are making their premiere Aetherdrift, and in this article I’ll be sharing my picks for the top 10 Vehicles and Mounts in <em>Aetherdrift</em>, from the vehicles of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/aetherdrift-brings-wacky-races-and-new-name-for-old-plane-to-magic-gathering" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Avishkar">Avishkar</a> to the dinosaurs of Muraganda. Due to their similarity in mechanics, we’ve grouped these sweet rides together to be sorted out, and then list them in classic top 10 form.</p>



<p>#10) <strong><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/158/district-mascot" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="District Mascot">District Mascot</a></strong></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/district-mascot-duo.jpg?itok=J0LozQT3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/district-mascot-duo.jpg?itok=PLbpaC9f 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Kicking off our list is the cutest entry, as well as the cheapest as a 1 mana doggo, who jumps onto the field with a +1/+1 counter. This adorable little corgi gets an additional +1/+1 counter whenever it attacks when saddled. So if you drop this on turn 1, and then another creature on turn 2, you can saddle the good dog, and grow it to attack, and it becomes a 2/2. Beyond that, you also have bonus flexibility here, as <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/158/district-mascot" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="District Mascot">District Mascot</a> can remove two +1/+1 counters to destroy artifacts. And who could refuse that face?</p>

<p>9) <strong><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/168/lumbering-worldwagon" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Lumbering Worldwagon">Lumbering Worldwagon</a></strong></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/lumbering-worldwagon.jpg?itok=wZGSqZmb 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/lumbering-worldwagon.jpg?itok=agXAsoiG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>What happens when you strap a win condition onto a ramp spell at a reasonable rate? You make it onto this list, though to be fair the Worldwagon probably will need some help to close out the game. At 3 mana it does a <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dsc/193/rampant-growth" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Rampant Growth">Rampant Growth</a>, and whenever it attacks, it will do another one. After that early game ramp it can lurk in the background, until later on you can activate it’s Crew 4 ability, and send a creature with power equal to the number of lands you have running down at your opponent, while fetching another basic land.</p>

<p>8) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/295/salvation-engine" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Salvation Engine"><strong>Salvation Engine</strong></a></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/salvation-engine.jpg?itok=1Ur7J-jL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/salvation-engine.jpg?itok=6XtU1sbG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/2xm/34/tempered-steel" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Tempered Steel">Tempered Steel</a> got strapped onto an engine and given a giant crane running over players. While it’s unlikely to see much play in 60-card formats, it will become a common sight in white artifact creature heavy decks with a big pump for the creatures, and the capability of resurrecting any artifact to the battlefield.</p>

<p>7) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/183/thunderous-velocipede" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Thunderous Velocipede"><strong>Thunderous Velocipede</strong></a></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/thunderous-velocipede.jpg?itok=EaLwMHaT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/thunderous-velocipede.jpg?itok=paZg0x5q 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Sometimes, everyone just wants to let their inner Timmy out, and <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/183/thunderous-velocipede" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Thunderous Velocipede">Thunderous Velocipede </a>heartily approves. This 3 mana vehicle can become a 5/5 trample with Crew 3, but while that is impressive, it’s less important than its other ability. In short, whenever you play a creature that costs 4 or less it gets one +1/+1 counter, while anything bigger than that gets a big 3 +1/+1 counters.</p>

<p>6) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/298/valors-flagship" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Valor's Flagsip"><strong>Valor's Flagship</strong></a></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/valors-flagship.jpg?itok=0P4h88UK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/valors-flagship.jpg?itok=rQR5FOnZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/298/valors-flagship" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Valor's Flagship">Valor’s Flagship </a>calls back for me to a card that was important in competitive magic when I began playing: <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/mh3/263/decree-of-justice" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Decree of Justice">Decree of Justice</a>, which could be played as an expensive wincon or cycled for an army of creatures. It’s a strong capstone for Vehicle decks, and its ability to be highly adjustable makes it much more playable then it might seem. In Commander, it is going to be best buddies with <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/neo/220/greasefang-okiba-boss" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Greasefang, Okiba Boss">Greasefang</a> who will love its ability to drop to the grave on its own, along with its 7/7 flying, first strike, lifelink body</p>

<p>5) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/113/boommobile" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Boommobile"><strong>Boommobile</strong></a></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/boommobile.jpg?itok=zY7CtoNW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/boommobile.jpg?itok=S97smFCi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Kaboom, this vehicle is going to be a limited bomb, but it should see some constructed play either casually or competitively. A solid size to cost, it also refunds itself on playing, which invites it to be abused in combo decks that might reduce its cost or bounce it back and forth. On the fair side of things (well outside of limited), it can also do a single <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/j22/499/blaze" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Blaze">Blaze</a> type effect with X damage to anything, possibly burning out an opponent or one of their creatures. As a small bonus on top of that, it also gets a +1/+1 counter for doing it.</p>

<p>4) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/313/gastal-thrillroller" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Gastal Thrillroller"><strong>Gastal Thrillroller</strong></a></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gastal-thrillroller.jpg?itok=IetfQDTI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gastal-thrillroller.jpg?itok=BZGcXlbx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>We continue with another red entry, but this one is going to be likely seeing more constructed play, as a a take on your 3 mana hasty red threat (a tradition that dates back to <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/fdn/618/ball-lightning" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Ball Lightning">Ball Lightning</a>). <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/313/gastal-thrillroller" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Gastal Thrillroller">Gastal Thrillroller</a> is an impressive fast attacker, it comes in as a 4/2 trample haste vehicle, during its first turn it doesn’t even need to be crewed. Then, later in the game, you can pay 3 mana, and discard a land or something to resurrect it with a finality counter to run right over your opponent.</p>

<p>3) <strong><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/28/skyseers-chariot" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Skyseer's Chariot">Skyseer's Chariot</a></strong></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/skyseers-chariot.jpg?itok=Yn3UJdaD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/skyseers-chariot.jpg?itok=byku62GX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>A vehicular take on a hatebear (even if it's not a 2/2), as a 2 mana creature that interferes with the opponent. Making activated abilities from a particular card cost 2 more can really disrupt a game plan. It’s more likely to be playable in low to mid power casual, but it could make an appearance in the right Standard metagame.</p>

<p>2) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/7/bulwark-ox" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Bulwark Ox"><strong>Bulwark Ox</strong></a></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bulwark-ox.jpg?itok=Bpf-ZSvB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bulwark-ox.jpg?itok=g57XoIm3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Everyone loves protection, and <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/7/bulwark-ox" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Bulwark Ox">Bulwark Ox </a>provides plenty of it. This Ox is more than just a <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/10e/268/grizzly-bears" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Grizzly Bears">Bear </a>(a 2/2 for 2), as when saddled and attacking he gets to hand out a +1/+1 counter to a creature. This grows something, while also marking it under Ox Insurance Services. Those with counters are protected when he sacrifices to give them indestructible and hexproof for a turn. A solid protection piece for white weenie type decks to boost wrath resistance, and it fits right into counters matter decks.</p>

<p>1) <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dft/83/demonic-junker" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Demonic Junker"><strong>Demonic Junker</strong></a></p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/demonic-junker.jpg?itok=-ebJ5WAG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/demonic-junker.jpg?itok=k1e8jVWR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>My top pick is this black vehicle that promises to be a constant sight in black aligned artifact decks at multiplayer tables for the foreseeable future. Coming down as cheaply as one mana due to Affinity, it can destry a creature from each player, and if you picked one of your own, it gets bigger. Already a 4/3 with Crew 2, it has decent enough size, but as a 6/5 that triggers all your Aristocrats effects it gets crazy. It is essentially a black version of <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dmu/24/leyline-binding" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Leyline Bundle">Leyline Binding</a> + <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/cmm/823/grasp-of-fate" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Grasp of Fate">Grasp of Fate</a>, trading flexibility of permanent type for the ability to turn into a truck and run you over.</p>

<hr><p>Agree or disagree about my choices above? You can see all of the vehicles and mounts in <em>Aetherdrift</em> in this <a href="https://scryfall.com/search?q=%28set%3Adft+or+set%3Adfc%29+%28type%3Avehicle+or+type%3Amount%29&amp;unique=cards&amp;as=grid" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Rides Aetherdrift Scryfall Search">Scryfall search</a>. In the meantime, you can also look at our <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/aetherdrift-commander-living-energy-review-and-upgrades" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Aetherdrift Commander: Living Energy Review and Upgrades"><em>Aetherdrift </em>Precon Upgade and Review of <em>Living Energy</em></a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>A longtime lover of speculative fiction, in almost all its forms, Don joined TechRaptor in 2014 on a whim sending in an application as he was looking for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/don-parsons">More about Don</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Thinks Dragon Age: The Veilguard Would Have Done Better If It Were Live Service]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-mass-effect-5-bioware-live-service-1851756169</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-thinks-dragon-age-the-veilguard-would-have-done-better-if-it-were-live-service.1101180/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-mass-effect-5-bioware-live-service-1851756169<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Electronic Arts CEO Andrew Wilson recently spoke on an earnings call about the underperformance of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-4-review-dreadwolf-rook-action-rpg-1851681954&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-4-review-dreadwolf-rook-action-rpg-1851681954"><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em></a></span><em>, </em>which reportedly reached 1.5 million players. This was apparently around half of what EA was projecting, but given the game was in development hell for a decade and was a sequel to a game that came out before millions of potential players had fully developed frontal lobes, it wasn’t too surprising. Wilson, however, is convinced the reason the long-awaited RPG sold fewer copies than the company wanted is that it wasn’t live-servicey enough. That’s not the sentiment BioWare fans want to hear with the development of <em>Mass Effect 5</em> still on the horizon.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196742" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="254" data-playlist="196742,196452,195150" data-current="196742"><div><p>What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22297.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On the earnings call (thanks <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/it-sure-sounds-like-ea-thinks-cutting-dragon-age-the-veilguards-live-service-components-was-a-mistake/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/it-sure-sounds-like-ea-thinks-cutting-dragon-age-the-veilguards-live-service-components-was-a-mistake/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>PC Gamer</em></a></span>), Wilson’s answer as to “why” the game underperformed conveyed a deep lack of introspection on the effects that a long and difficult development had on <em>Dragon Age.</em> It also seemed altogether disconnected from the video game industry at large.</p><p>“In order to break beyond the core audience, games need to directly connect to the evolving demands of players who increasingly seek shared-world features and deeper engagement alongside high-quality narratives in this beloved category,” Wilson said. “<em>Dragon Age</em> had a high-quality launch and was well-reviewed by critics and those who played; however, it did not resonate with a broad enough audience in this highly competitive market.”</p><p>In summary, he thinks <em>Dragon Age </em>would have done better if it was a live-service game, rather than the story-driven single-player RPG BioWare excels in creating. Multiple shifts in direction weighed down <em>The Veilguard</em>’s 10-year-long development cycle. One iteration was an online multiplayer game with repeatable levels and all the live-service stuff nobody asked for in a BioWare game, but the studio made a complete pivot after the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/how-biowares-anthem-went-wrong-1833731964&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/how-biowares-anthem-went-wrong-1833731964">critical and commercial failure of <em>Anthem</em></a></span>, the RPG studio’s looter shooter detour that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/anthem-bioware-5-years-later-1851294156&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/anthem-bioware-5-years-later-1851294156">became a cautionary tale</a></span> for how forcing live-service features into studios not built to make those games will only ever have diminishing returns.</p><p>There’s an odd dissonance in Wilson saying <em>The Veilguard</em>’s problem is that it didn’t appeal to people looking for another forever game to add to the growing list of competing live-service titles on the market. If live service were in and of itself a universal selling point, we wouldn’t be seeing these games being <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/concord-sony-biggest-flop-failure-box-office-1851676475&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/concord-sony-biggest-flop-failure-box-office-1851676475">sent out to die on the regular</a></span>. <em>Baldur’s Gate 3,</em> a dense single-player RPG that builds upon the foundation of BioWare’s old style, became <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-too-many-awards-winning-larian-goty-1851593323&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-too-many-awards-winning-larian-goty-1851593323">one of the biggest games of the past decade</a></span>. Obviously, the children don’t simply yearn for the live-service mines.</p><p><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em>’s problems were that it was a continuation of a 10-year-old cliffhanger that was not newcomer-friendly, was met with good but <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-reviews-metacritic-score-bioware-1851683347&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-reviews-metacritic-score-bioware-1851683347">not universally glowing reviews</a></span>, and was only marketed in earnest <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-dreadwolf-teaser-trailer-xbox-1851528812&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-dreadwolf-teaser-trailer-xbox-1851528812">for four months</a></span>. It is a miracle that BioWare was able to right the ship after a decade of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-past-and-present-of-dragon-age-4-1833913351&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-past-and-present-of-dragon-age-4-1833913351">publisher-mandated</a></span> pivots, and the reward has been a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-5-bioware-dragon-age-veilguard-dlc-layoffs-1851750767&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-5-bioware-dragon-age-veilguard-dlc-layoffs-1851750767">complete restructuring of a studio</a></span>, excising people foundational to its legacy.</p><p>This kind of blinder-wearing isn’t new for EA, though. The company notoriously <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://gamerant.com/ea-single-player-focus-good-jedi-survivor-dead-space-immortals/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://gamerant.com/ea-single-player-focus-good-jedi-survivor-dead-space-immortals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">claimed single-player games were “finished,”</a></span> then <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://gamerant.com/ea-importance-single-player-games/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://gamerant.com/ea-importance-single-player-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">changed its tune</a></span> when one of its own studios had a recent success story in Respawn’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-jedi-survivor-review-fallen-order-respawn-ps5-1850377427&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-jedi-survivor-review-fallen-order-respawn-ps5-1850377427"><em>Star Wars Jedi</em> games</a></span>, despite its competitors releasing critically and commercially successful single-player games the entire time. So it’s not surprising that Wilson would attribute <em>The Veilguard</em>’s underperforming to something EA can only contextualize in its own catalog. <em>Baldur’s Gate 3 </em>might as well not have happened if EA didn’t make it.</p><p>All of this has me worried about what it could mean for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-4-5-bioware-teaser-release-date-2029-1851009417&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-4-5-bioware-teaser-release-date-2029-1851009417"><em>Mass Effect 5</em></a></span>. The writing is on the wall now that BioWare has one more chance to right the ship, and since moderate successes aren’t enough anymore, it has to be a cultural moment on the scale of the original sci-fi trilogy. Hearing that Wilson thinks the key to success is repeating proven mistakes should scare any <em>Mass Effect </em>fan. Because if BioWare is once again forced to capitulate to something it isn’t built for, the series and studio’s legacies will continue to be diminished until there’s nothing left.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Might Provide ‘Real Energy’ for FC and Madden, Says EA]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-might-provide-real-energy-for-fc-and-madden-says-ea/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-might-provide-%E2%80%98real-energy%E2%80%99-for-fc-and-madden-says-ea.1101177/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-might-provide-real-energy-for-fc-and-madden-says-ea/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>EA recently stated that franchises like Madden and FC might find ‘real energy’ on a platform like Nintendo Switch 2.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to a report by <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-says-madden-and-fc-might-find-real-energy-on-nintendo-switch-2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">IGN</a>, EA CEO Andrew Wilson was asked whether Nintendo Switch 2 is a platform they are focusing on during a recent earnings call. Wilson replied that a new console arriving in the marketplace is a “benefit” for them as it allows them to “acquire new players.” Wilson added that EA’s franchises have “typically” performed well on Nintendo’s platforms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The EA CEO then discussed some of their most popular franchises, EA FC and Madden, stating that products like those could “find real energy” on the Nintendo Switch 2, “as they have done in the past.” Wilson also provided an example with The Sims and My Sims cozy bundle, explaining how it performed better than expectations, with “50% of all players” new to EA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>EA revealed “nothing in our models at this juncture.” However, they expect that “anytime a great new console” hits the market, it will allow them to reach new players and communities, so they need an IP to benefit from that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>EA Sports FC 24 is already available for purchase on the Nintendo Switch, and the next instalments of the franchise should arrive on the Switch 2. The fascinating addition would be Madden, as no games from that franchise have made it to Nintendo’s prized console. Also, it will be interesting to see if the platform can breathe new life into these franchises, as EA FC is struggling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, EA is working on a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-working-major-apex-legends-update-after-battlefield/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">significant Apex Legends update</a> that will arrive after the upcoming Battlefield, which is scheduled to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-launch-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launch before April 2026</a>. What are your thoughts on EA stating that Madden and FC might find ‘real energy’ on the Switch 2?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-sells-1-million-copies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 selling 1 million copies.</a> Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo says it’s ‘taking risks’ to meet Switch 2 demand]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/606817/nintendo-switch-2-production-demand-q-a</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-says-it%E2%80%99s-%E2%80%98taking-risks%E2%80%99-to-meet-switch-2-demand.1101156/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/606817/nintendo-switch-2-production-demand-q-a<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Nintendo is gearing up for the Switch 2’s launch sometime in 2025, and president Shuntaro Furukawa says that the company is “taking risks and proceeding with production so that we can meet as much demand as possible,” according to a machine translation of an <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2025/250205.pdf">earnings Q&amp;A</a>.</p><p>The company had some trouble <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/28/15474262/nintendo-switch-2ds-xl-supply-issues-restock-reggie-fils-aime-interview">keeping the original Switch in stock</a> during its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/27/15447342/nintendo-switch-sales-forecast-earnings-2016">very successful 2017 launch</a>. Nintendo isn’t going to reveal its specific Switch 2 production plans until it releases the business plan for its next fiscal year (which begins in April), Furukawa says, but the company wants to gauge demand following the Switch 2-focused Nintendo Direct <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/606504/nintendo-switch-2-direct-new-time">on April 2nd</a>.</p><p>“As with the Nintendo Switch, we believe it will not be easy to rapidly increase production capacity, but based on our past experience, we will make preparations to respond as quickly as possible,” he says.</p><p>The Q&amp;A has a few other interesting tidbits:</p><div><ul><li><span>Furukawa says that “dedicated software” is important with the launch of a console, which could indicate that Nintendo won’t have many new games for both the original Switch and the Switch 2 (though Switch games will <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24343666/nintendo-switch-2-cartridge-backwards-compatibility">be backward compatible with the Switch 2</a>). The only known Switch 2 game is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24337198/switch-2-mario-kart-nintendo">what appears to be a new <em>Mario Kart</em></a>, but Nintendo hasn’t said if it will be on the first Switch, too.</span></li><li><span>Nintendo doesn’t plan to change the price of the original Switch “at this time,” but it isn’t ready to share the price of the Switch 2 yet. The price will presumably be announced at the Switch 2 Direct.</span></li><li><span>Despite generally <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/3/22/22990710/nintendo-dragalia-lost-ios-android-gacha-mobile-game-shut-down">pulling</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22597294/nintendo-dr-mario-world-shut-down-date-mobile-game">back</a> on mobile apps, Nintendo is still working on making new game apps and is considering ways to link smartphones to its games.</span></li></ul></div><p>But there are still a lot of unanswered questions <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24344718/nintendo-switch-2-specs-date-price-launch-games-mario-kart">about the Switch 2</a>, and it seems like Nintendo is going to keep a pretty tight lid on things ahead of the Switch 2 Direct. I’m just happy that the Switch 2 looks like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24345191/nintendo-switch-2-bigger-screen">a bigger, more refined Switch</a>.</p><p>As part of its earnings, Nintendo announced that the Nintendo Switch has sold more than 150 million units, meaning that it’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/605948/nintendo-switch-lifetime-sales-nintendo-ds">closing in</a> on surpassing the Nintendo DS.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CS2 Superstar ZywOo Says the Scene Misses His Rivalry with S1mple]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cs2-superstar-zywoo-says-the-scene-misses-his-rivalry-with-s1mple/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cs2-superstar-zywoo-says-the-scene-misses-his-rivalry-with-s1mple.1101147/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/cs2-superstar-zywoo-says-the-scene-misses-his-rivalry-with-s1mple/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The rivalry between Counter-Strike superstars Mathieu “ZywOo” Erbeau and Oleksandr “s1mple” Kostyljev is an era-defining one. As the game fully embraces a new CS2 era though, along with some new stars, the MVP of the final CS:GO Major says that his rivalry with s1mple is missed.</p>



<p>But not by him.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-zywoo-and-s1mple-dominated-counter-strike-together-for-four-years">ZywOo and s1mple dominated Counter-Strike together for four years</h2>



<p>In an interview with bo3.gg, <a href="https://bo3.gg/news/exclusive-zywoo-about-s1mple-absence-from-the-pro-scene-for-me-though-nothing-has-changed-donk-and-m0nesy-are-now-the-rivals" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ZywOo was asked</a> about his own rivalry with s1mple and how it compares with the rivalry between <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-counter-strike-players-of-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new stars Danil “donk” Kryshkovets and Ilya “m0NESY” Osipov</a>. ZywOo said that donk and m0NESY reminds him of great sports rivals like LeBron James and Michael Jordan, and Lionel Messi and Cristiano Ronaldo.</p>



<p>From 2019 to 2022, the rivalry between ZywOo and s1mple was on par with those sports greats. In all four of those years, the two owned the top two spots in HLTV’s Players of the Year list. ZywOo won in 2019 and 2020, and s1mple won in 2021 and 2022. S1mple won his Major first at PGL Stockholm 2021, but he slipped to number 7 in the 2023 players list. That year, ZywOo reclaimed the top spot and won his first Major at BLAST Paris.</p>



<p>“I wouldn’t say I miss it,” ZywOo said when asked about his rivalry with s1mple. “But I think the scene does. He brought so much to the game.”</p>



<p>Since the release of CS2, the player regarded as the GOAT of CS:GO has not managed to find the same level of success. After CS2 came out, he took some extended time off, as he was unhappy with the state of the game. While away from NAVI, the team won the first CS2 Major without him, which he says <a href="https://www.hltv.org/news/38871/s1mple-on-return-navi-won-the-major-so-some-plans-have-changed" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“changed plans”</a> for his return. He stood in for Team Falcons early in 2024, then re-joined the team on loan from NAVI to close out the 2024, but is now back on NAVI’s reserve roster.</p>



<p>Even if s1mple never returns to the top echelon again, the way ZywOo says his rival pushed him to be better as laid a foundation for new rivalries to blossom. But hopefully, the story of their rivalry doesn’t end here.</p>



<p>Do you miss seeing s1mple perform at the biggest Counter-Strike events of the year? Let us know what you think down below and on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/overactive-media-cdl-major-in-madrid-results/">the success of the most recent Call of Duty League Major</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox and Nintendo Spurred the Two Scariest Moments of Former PlayStation Exec Shuhei Yoshida's Career]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-and-nintendo-spurred-the-two-scariest-moments-of-former-playstation-exec-shuhei-yoshidas-career</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-and-nintendo-spurred-the-two-scariest-moments-of-former-playstation-exec-shuhei-yoshidas-career.1101144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-and-nintendo-spurred-the-two-scariest-moments-of-former-playstation-exec-shuhei-yoshidas-career<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Shuhei Yoshida, former president of Worldwide Studios for Sony Interactive Entertainment, has revealed that Nintendo and Xbox each orchestrated the two scariest moments of his long career at PlayStation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Yoshida told <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HtiJlzs0xRE" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MinnMax</a> that the release of the Xbox 360 one year before the PlayStation 3 was "very, very scary," as those who considered waiting for Sony's console would be well behind in tasting the next generation of video games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But Yoshida said "the biggest shock I had from an announcement from the competition" was when Nintendo announced that Monster Hunter 4 was going to be a 3DS exclusive. "That was the biggest shock," he said.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/05/91e9vcxn6fl-ac-sl1500-1738776824510.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Monster Hunter 4 launched exclusively on the Nintendo 3DS in 2013. Ultimate launched a year later.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter was a colossal hit on the PlayStation Portable, to the point where it had two exclusive games, but Yoshida had no idea Nintendo had secured this new game for its own console. To make matters worse, it then slashed the price of the 3DS by $100, putting it well below the PlayStation Vita.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"After launch, both Nintendo 3DS and Vita were $250 but they dropped $100," Yoshida said. "I was like, 'Oh my god'. And [then they] announced the biggest game... The biggest game on PSP was Monster Hunter. And that game is going to come out on Nintendo 3DS exclusively. I was like, 'Oh no.' That was the biggest shock."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-veteran-shuhei-yoshida-retiring-from-sony-in-january">Yoshida retired in January after more than three decades with Sony</a>, where he became a face of the PlayStation brand and was beloved by fans worldwide. His no longer being with the company has allowed Yoshida to share some previously unheard insight such as this, however.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-legend-shuhei-yoshida-wouldve-tried-to-resist-sonys-live-service-push">Yoshida has also said how he'd have tried to resist Sony's embattled live service push</a> and even given his two cents on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-hasnt-sony-done-anything-more-with-bloodborne-playstation-legend-shuhei-yoshida-has-a-personal-theory">why it won't make a remake or sequel to cult classic Bloodborne</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Stuart Wilson/BAFTA/Getty Images for BAFTA.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demon Tides demo launches February 24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/demon-tides-demo-launches-february-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demon-tides-demo-launches-february-24.1101141/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/demon-tides-demo-launches-february-24<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Save data can be carried over to the full game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Fabraz [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fabraz">Fabraz</a> will release a demo for <a title="Genres > Open-World [560 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> 3D platformer <em><a title="Games > Demon Tides [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/demon-tides">Demon Tides</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,262 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3477260/Demon_Tides_Demo/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on February 24 as part of Steam Next Fest: February 2025 Edition, the developer announced. <span id="more-942420"></span></p><p>The demo includes the beginning of the story, the tutorial, and a small part the open world for players to explore. This includes several levels, challenges, and gear to collect. The in-game leaderboard is also present, and save data from the demo will carry over to the full game when it launches in 2025.</p><p>Here is an overview of the demo, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3477260/Demon_Tides_Demo/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Welcome to the Demo</strong></p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the beginning of the game to get your appetite wet for the full game! Your save data will carry over into the main game. You can also directly compete with other players using the demo’s leaderboards.</p><p><strong>About the Game</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Follow Beebz and her crew on a journey of self-discovery as they travel the vast oceans of Ragnar’s Rock.</p><p>Navigate the open seas and explore each distant structure, uncovering every hidden nook and cranny with your diverse, expressive move-set. Beat challenges or find hidden chests to collect talismans along the way that modify and even expand your abilities or switch up your drip with a plethora of discoverable outfits!</p><p>And never forget, you’re not alone in this journey! Compete with other players for speedrunning times by challenging their ghosts or tag a wall and share your message in the form of graffiti with the entire world!</p><p>Are you ready to conquer this kingdom and expose all of its mysterious secrets? Or will Beebz be crushed by what awaits her… Only one way to find out!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>A deeply expressive platforming move-set that enables you to travel through the world in countless unique ways. Express yourself through your schmovement and get lost in the flow!</li><li>Travel the seamless, open ocean and reach any point of interest at blazing speeds! Explore each locale and figure out creative ways to beat challenges or reach certain areas!</li><li>Hang out on your mobile hub, the Floating Fashionista, to chill with your crew or buy new items of interest!</li><li>Discover hidden secrets and use context clues to unravel this world’s mysteries alongside the main story told through major, cinematic story events!</li><li>Place your own checkpoints wherever you want and return to them any time you meet your untimely demise.</li><li>Collect over 50 unique talismans that uniquely modify or add to your move-set! Get a paraglider to soar the skies, spawn a bubble to float in place indefinitely, change your spin form into a hookshot and so much more!</li><li><a title="Companies > ACQUIRE [341 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation/acquire">Acquire</a> a ton of unique head gear, outfits and hair dyes to change up your appearance! With over 50,000 possible combinations there’s no shortage of drip.</li><li>Compete for the best completion times of each locale by <a title="Genres > Racing [224 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> other player’s ghosts! Get notified if your ghost was beaten to challenge them right back, may the best runner win!</li><li>Create and share graffiti that will appear in other player’s worlds! Make something pretty, hint towards a secret nearby or troll the players with lies you little rascal!</li></ul><p><strong>Frequently Asked <a title="Companies > Question [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/question">Question</a>s</strong></p><ul><li><strong>How long is the demo?</strong><ul><li>The demo includes the beginning of the story, the tutorial as well as a small part of the open world for you to explore and platform in! This includes several levels, challenges and gear to collect! Additionally you can also compete for completion times with the in-game leaderboard and even race other people’s ghosts!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Is this a sequel to <em><a title="Games > Demon Turf [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/demon-turf">Demon Turf</a></em> and do you need to play it before playing <em>Demon Tides</em>?</strong><ul><li>You can definitely play <em>Demon Tides</em> without ever having played <em>Demon Turf</em> before! In fact, we encourage new players to jump right into <em>Demon Tides</em>! It takes place after <em>Demon Turf</em>‘s story but is designed for new players to jump right in with a brand new narrative and world to explore. Any backstory is carefully reintroduced while returning players will notice plenty of fun references harkening back to <em>Demon Turf</em>.</li></ul></li><li><strong>What does “Expressive” platforming mean, exactly?</strong><ul><li>A platformer with a lot of combinatorial depth, allowing you to express yourself through the game’s movement. Meaning a gap can be crossed in a multitude of creative ways!</li><li>We’re pushing the concept of this subgenre to new limits with an incredibly deep, combinatorial move-set that can even be heavily customized! The further you get into the game, and the more comfortable you get with the movement, the more unique your gameplay will end up looking to others!</li></ul></li><li><strong>What’s Fabraz done before <em>Demon Tides</em>?</strong><ul><li>We’re most well known for the 3D <a title="Genres > Platformer [607 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">Platformer</a> <em>Demon Turf</em> and 2D platformer <em>Slime-san</em>! But we’re also behind lesser known titles such as <em>Cannon Crasha</em>, <em>Planet Diver</em>, and even acted as publisher for friends on two games called <em>Skellboy</em> and <em>SpiritSphere DX</em>!</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Demo Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Demon Tides - Demo Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j46GGr-8nz0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Japan’s weak enconomy mean a cheaper Switch 2 in the US?]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/02/will-japans-weak-enconomy-mean-a-cheaper-switch-2-in-the-us/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/will-japan%E2%80%99s-weak-enconomy-mean-a-cheaper-switch-2-in-the-us.1101138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/02/will-japans-weak-enconomy-mean-a-cheaper-switch-2-in-the-us/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          <p>Since <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/01/its-official-take-a-first-look-at-the-switch-2/">our first glimpse of the Switch 2</a> last month, we've been <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/01/all-the-things-nintendo-didnt-tell-us-about-the-switch-2/">left guessing</a> on many crucial hardware details, including the all-important launch price. Now, Nintendo has hinted that the unsteady state of the international money market may play an outsize role in that pricing decision.</p>
<p>Addressing a question about Switch 2 hardware pricing during <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2025/250205.pdf">an investor Q&amp;A session</a> Wednesday, Nintendo president Shintaro Furukawa said (via machine translation):</p>
<blockquote><p>In addition to the current inflation, we are aware that the exchange rate environment has changed significantly since the launch of the Nintendo Switch in 2017. We also need to consider the affordable price that customers expect from Nintendo products. When considering the price of a product, we believe that it is necessary to consider these factors from multiple angles.</p>
<p>At this time, we cannot disclose the specific price of the Nintendo Switch 2, but we are considering it while taking various points into consideration. At this time, we do not plan to change the price of the Nintendo Switch hardware.</p></blockquote>
<p>Most of that is the usual polite executive-speak shorthand for "we're not ready to answer that yet." But the bit about exchange rates and inflation got us wondering just how vulnerable a Japanese company like Nintendo might be to <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2024/4/30/why-is-japans-yen-so-weak-against-the-us-dollar">the yen's historic weakness</a>, and what this might mean for the Switch 2.</p>
<h2>More yen for your buck</h2>
<p>When the Switch launched in early 2017, a single dollar could get you about 114 Japanese yen, a rate broadly in line with the norm over the previous two decades. Today, that same dollar can get you over 152 yen, matching rates the world hasn't seen since before 1990.</p>
<p>This means that, at launch, the 29,980 yen asking price for the Switch in Japan was worth about $262, in roughly the same ballpark as the $299 US launch price. Today, Nintendo still asks 29,980 yen for a Japanese Switch and $299 for an American Switch. But that yen-denominated Japanese price is now worth just $196 under today's exchange rates.</p>
<figure>
    <div id="caption-2074691"><p>
              A dollar goes a lot farther in Japan these days than it did in 2017.
                              </p>
                          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      A dollar goes a lot farther in Japan these days than it did in 2017.

              <span>
          Credit:

                      <a href="https://www.macrotrends.net/2550/dollar-yen-exchange-rate-historical-chart" target="_blank">
          
          MacroTrends

                      </a>
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>This means that, in real terms, customers currently pay a lot less for Nintendo hardware in Japan. Conversely, it also means Nintendo makes a lot more money selling hardware in the US than in Japan.</p>
<p>What does this mean for the Switch 2? Well, let's say Nintendo wanted to launch its new system at about the same price as the original Switch but adjusted for the last eight years of inflation. The $299 US launch price of the Switch in 2017 is worth about $387 in today's dollars, making a $399 Switch 2 price seem entirely reasonable in this scenario.</p>

          
                      
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Gets PC Benchmark Tool -- See How Your System Stacks Up]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-pc-benchmark-tool-see-how-your-system-stacks-up/1100-6529248/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-pc-benchmark-tool-see-how-your-system-stacks-up.1101135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-pc-benchmark-tool-see-how-your-system-stacks-up/1100-6529248/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529248">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Between the giant creatures, multiple on-screen characters, and a large map to explore, there's no question that Capcom's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/we-played-monster-hunter-wilds-and-so-far-it-rules/1100-6526070/" data-ref-id="1100-6526070">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> is going to demand a lot of power from PCs. Now, less than a month away from the game's release, Capcom has shared a PC benchmark tool to show players how their computer measures up to the system specs.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-us/benchmark/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Wilds benchmark</a> is on Steam's site, and it requires players to have Steam installed and room to download the benchmark itself. The benchmark can rate the performance of your machine and give it a score up to 20,000. Any computer that hits 10,250 and up on the benchmark will be able to play the game. Everything that comes in underneath may take some changes in order to properly enjoy the experience.</p><p>The game's minimum <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-us/benchmark/#systemrequirements" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">system requirements</a> have also been released and can be seen below:</p><ul><li><dl><dt>Resolution</dt><dd>1080p（FHD）</dd></dl></li><li><dl><dt>Frame Rate</dt><dd>60fps (with Frame Generation enabled)</dd></dl></li><li><dl><dt>OS</dt><dd>Windows®10(64-bit Required)/Windows®11(64-bit Required)</dd></dl></li><li><dl><dt>Processor</dt><dd>Intel Core i5-10400<br>Intel Core i3-12100<br>AMD Ryzen 5 3600</dd></dl></li><li><dl><dt>Memory</dt><dd>16GB</dd></dl></li><li><dl><dt>Graphics</dt><dd>GeForce RTX 2060 Super（VRAM 8GB）<br>Radeon RX 6600（VRAM 8GB）</dd></dl></li><li><dl><dt>VRAM</dt><dd>8GB or more required.</dd></dl></li><li><dl><dt>Storage</dt><dd>75GB　SSD</dd></dl></li><li><dl><dt>Note</dt><dd>SSD required. This game is expected to run at 1080p (Upscaled) / 60 fps (with Frame Generation enabled) under the "Medium" graphics setting. DirectStorage supported.</dd></dl></li></ul><p>Capcom also debuted <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/monster-hunter-wilds-6th-trailer-into-the-iceshard-cliffs/2300-6465662/" data-ref-id="2300-6465662">a new Monster Hunters Wilds trailer</a> that introduces the Iceshard Cliffs and the deadly monsters that dwell there. Once you see that, you'll understand why this game needs so much processing power.</p><p>Players who want to get an early taste of what's to come can join <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-is-getting-another-cross-platform-beta-next-month/1100-6528691/" data-ref-id="1100-6528691">the second open beta test for Monster Hunter Wilds</a>, which will take place on two consecutive weeks: February 6-9 and February 13-16. Most of the content in the second beta will be identical to the first one that was held last November, as players will be able to get their hands on the character-creation tools as well as a story trial, and a Doshagma hunt. In the second beta, the Doshagma hunt is now the jumping-off point for further adventures that can pit players against the Gypceros and Arkveld. Everyone who plays the second beta will be given a Felyne pendant or Seikret, as well as a bonus item pack that will carry over to the main game upon its release.</p><p>Monster Hunter Wilds will arrive on Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC on February 28. But if players want to get some bonus items ahead of time, all they have to do is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-bonus-monster-hunter-wilds-items-by-playing-monster-hunter-now/1100-6528784/" data-ref-id="1100-6528784">play the mobile game Monster Hunter Now</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Features Flagship Monster]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-features-flagship-monster/1100-6529269/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-features-flagship-monster.1101132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-features-flagship-monster/1100-6529269/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529269">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Capcom has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/02/04/new-monster-hunter-wilds-trailer-reveals-iceshard-cliffs-and-the-monsters-within/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">revealed</a> that its second open beta test for Monster Hunter Wilds will feature its flagship monster, the Arkveld.</p><p>The second open beta test will be split into two sessions. The first one will run from February 6 at 7 PM PT / 10 PM ET to February 9 at 6:59 PM PT / 9:59 PM ET. The second will be from February 13 at 7 PM PT / 10 PM ET to February 16 at 6:59PM PT / 9:59 PM ET. Players can start preloading for the second open beta test starting today, February 5, at 7PM PT.</p><p>Both sessions will have identical content, including the character creation, story trial, and Doshagma hunt from the first open beta test back in November. There are a few new features in this upcoming open beta test, though.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OFoueW07mxQ" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OFoueW07mxQ" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Players can take on the Gypceros, a poisonous bird wyvern, as well as the Arkveld, the game's flagship monster. Also known as the White Wraith, the Arkveld is a quadruped monster with grayish white scales, fur, and armor.</p><p>The training area will also be accessible, and players will be able to create a private lobby in order to hunt with specific people. The online single player mode will be available as well, which lets players go solo without joining a lobby. While the open beta test does not support PS5 Pro-enhanced features, there will be a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-console-details-revealed-ps5-pro-support-will-be-in-day-one-patch/1100-6528576/" data-ref-id="1100-6528576">dayone patch to implement PS5 Pro support</a>.</p><p>Characters created in the open beta tests will be carried over to the full version of the game once it comes out on February 28, 2025 for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. For more on the PC version, be sure to check out the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-pc-benchmark-tool-see-how-your-system-stacks-up/1100-6529248/" data-ref-id="1100-6529248">new system-benchmark test first</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance II sells 1 million copies in just one day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-launches-1-million-copies-sold</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-sells-1-million-copies-in-just-one-day.1101126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-launches-1-million-copies-sold<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Warhorse/Deep Silver.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Warhorse's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">sold </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/WarhorseStudios/status/1887155255130866099">1 million copies</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on launch day.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For comparison, the original </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Come: Deliverance </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">reached that milestone </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/rick5292/status/966579154362798081">two weeks</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> after its release in 2018. In its first two days, that game sold </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/02/15/kingdom-come-deliverance-has-sold-around-half-a-million-copies">500,000 copies</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and hit 2 million copies within its first year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Deliverance II </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">is also outpacing its predecessor in player numbers: at time of writing, SteamDB shows the sequel opened to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://steamdb.info/app/1771300/charts/">166,046 concurrent players</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The first game launched at </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://steamdb.info/app/379430/charts/">96,069 players</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We're beyond grateful for your support," wrote Warhorse. "Thank you for making [our game] a triumph!"</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Who wants to sell 1 million copies?">Who wants to sell 1 million copies?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The sales jump between the two Kingdom Come games is a notable achievement, and continues the trend of Embracer's major sequels opening strong. In 2023, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-i-dead-island-2-i-slays-its-way-to-1-million-copies-in-one-weekend">Dead Island 2</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">sold 1 million copies in its launch weekend, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/remnant-2-has-topped-1-million-sales-in-one-week">Remnant II</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">sold the same amount in a week.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Its 2024 slate was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-attributes-2024-2025-declines-to-a-lack-of-substantial-new-releases">not as strong</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but that was partially owed to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Deliverance II </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and other titles (namely, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hyper Light Breaker </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">) being pushed into 2025.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/WarhorseStudios/status/1853489512233480418">late 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the first </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Come </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">sold 8 million copies. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Deliverance II </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">currently holds the top spot on Steam's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/topselling/US">best-seller chart</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which means it may reach or surpass the first game before 2025 is over.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals’ Latest Patch Shows The Game Is On The Right Track]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-new-patch-notes-captain-america-luna-snow-1851756109</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals%E2%80%99-latest-patch-shows-the-game-is-on-the-right-track.1101081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-new-patch-notes-captain-america-luna-snow-1851756109<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="738a4b25414639c6b4393a52d949d967" data-recommend-id="image://738a4b25414639c6b4393a52d949d967" data-format="jpg" data-width="2304" data-height="1296" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Captain America in his Infinity War skin." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Captain America in his Infinity War skin." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="738a4b25414639c6b4393a52d949d967" data-recommend-id="image://738a4b25414639c6b4393a52d949d967" data-format="jpg" data-width="2304" data-height="1296" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Captain America in his Infinity War skin." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Half the appeal of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975"><em>Marvel Rivals</em></a></span> is that it’s not a polished, competition-ready esports shooter. NetEase’s <em>Overwatch </em>clone is full of chaotic, unbalanced abilities that lend themselves to experimentation and viral shenanigans. The hero shooter just got its next patch, and it looks like the team is continuing a slow, methodical approach to balancing, rather than upending the meta with each update.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195670" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="184" data-playlist="195670,195150,196055" data-current="195670"><div><p>This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21167.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.marvelrivals.com/gameupdate/20250204/41548_1210144.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.marvelrivals.com/gameupdate/20250204/41548_1210144.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">full patch notes</a></span> lay out a series of bug fixes that target a handful of hero-specific bugs players have been experiencing, but there are no balance changes to be seen here. Compare this to other shooters like <em>Overwatch 2</em>, which typically incorporate at least a few balance changes into almost every update. <em>Marvel Rivals </em>could still use some tuning (nerf Hela’s health when she casts her ultimate, dammit), but NetEase letting players have some chaotic fun is a big reason it’s overshadowing the hero shooter competition right now.</p><figure id="" data-id="f4a07c04dcd251358db1f0b3ab66eed5" data-recommend-id="image://f4a07c04dcd251358db1f0b3ab66eed5" data-format="jpg" data-width="2304" data-height="1296" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Luna Snow in her new skin." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Luna Snow in her new skin." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f4a07c04dcd251358db1f0b3ab66eed5" data-recommend-id="image://f4a07c04dcd251358db1f0b3ab66eed5" data-format="jpg" data-width="2304" data-height="1296" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Luna Snow in her new skin." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The update will go live tomorrow, February 6, at 1 a.m. Pacific / 4 a.m. Eastern, and will include a new skin for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-how-to-play-captain-america-tank-1851754920&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-how-to-play-captain-america-tank-1851754920">Captain America</a></span> based on his appearance in <em>Avengers: Infinity War</em>, and another for Luna Snow called Mirae 2099. The patch notes read as follows:</p><p><strong>General</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>1. Adjusted age rating labels.</li><li>2. Fixed an issue with the Epic Launcher restarting after 5 minutes of inactivity, which caused random anti-cheat notifications.  </li></ul><p><strong>Maps and Gameplay</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>1. Resolved multiple instances where players could get stuck in unique terrain.</li><li>2. Fixed an occasional synchronization issue with some doors in Hydra Charteris Base: Frozen Airfield</li></ul><p><strong>Hero Bug Fixes</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>1. Venom’s Wild Swing: Fixed an issue where Venom Swing could occasionally fail to end properly. Now, he’ll always land with style.  </li><li>2. Venom’s Ultimate Devour: Resolved a problem where pressing Devour as soon he lands after unleashing Feast of the Abyss would sometimes deal no damage or knockback. Venom’s hunger will now be fully satisfied!  </li><li>3. Mister Fantastic’s Bulletproof Rubber: Addressed a bug where his Reflexive Rubber ability could sometimes fail to end correctly. He’s back to being as fantastic as ever!  </li><li>4. Storm’s Tempestuous Control: Fixed an issue where Storm’s Ultimate Ability could lead to unintended positions if she unleashes it just as she passes through Doctor Strange’s portal. She’ll now control the storm without getting lost!  </li><li>5. Storm’s Recovery Rumble: Resolved a bug where Storm’s Ultimate Ability could end abnormally if trapped by recovering destructible structures. She’s ready to unleash her powers—no more interruptions in the eye of the storm!  </li><li>6. Moon Knight’s Handy Prompt: Corrected the issue where the ground visual cue for Moon Knight’s Ultimate Ability would prematurely disappear—no more being caught unaware about incoming talons.  </li><li>7. Wolverine’s Fastball Bewilderment: Fixed occasional synchronization issues in the Fastball Special Team-Up Ability where on Wolverine’s side, he would appear as being held by the Hulk, but others would see Wolverine still in his original place. Now, everyone’s in sync to play ball.  </li><li>8. Magneto’s Ironic Iron Issue: Resolved an occasional problem where Iron Man’s Ultimate Ability would still take effect even after being absorbed by Magneto’s Ultimate Ability. Magneto’s magnetic prowess now has it fully contained!  </li><li>9. Jeff the Land Shark’s Spitting Shenanigans: Fixed an issue where if Jeff the Land Shark spit out others just as his Ultimate Ability was about to end, it would be interrupted and automatically spit them out when the ultimate ended, causing it to look like the animation played twice. He’ll now eject everyone in one smooth motion!  </li><li>10. Banner’s Revival Wardrobe: Addressed a costume issue that occasionally occurred with Banner after being revived by Rocket Raccoon’s beacon. He’s looking sharp and ready to hulk out!  </li><li>11. Loki’s Reload: Fixed a rare issue where Loki’s Mystical Missiles would not refill after reloading during unstable network conditions. He’s back to being the trickster with a full arsenal!  </li></ul><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>12. Loki’s Transformation Trouble: Resolved a rare occurrence where Loki’s Ultimate Ability transformation would end immediately after activation in unstable network conditions. His mischief will now last as intended! </li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Dino We Spotted In The Jurassic World Rebirth Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/jurassic-world-rebirth-trailer-every-dinosaur-mutant-1851755947</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-dino-we-spotted-in-the-jurassic-world-rebirth-trailer.1101078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/jurassic-world-rebirth-trailer-every-dinosaur-mutant-1851755947<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="41eca006b53dbc256aa1968cf633a5f2" data-recommend-id="image://41eca006b53dbc256aa1968cf633a5f2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="41eca006b53dbc256aa1968cf633a5f2" data-recommend-id="image://41eca006b53dbc256aa1968cf633a5f2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/jurassic-park-world-4-rebirth-trailer-screenshots-2025-1851636033&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/jurassic-park-world-4-rebirth-trailer-screenshots-2025-1851636033">After months of teasing</a></span>, Universal Studios <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/jurassic-world-rebirth-trailer-scarlett-johansson-1851755629&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/jurassic-world-rebirth-trailer-scarlett-johansson-1851755629">finally released a trailer</a></span> for <em>Jurassic World Rebirth</em>, the upcoming seventh film in the long-running dinosaur franchise. And yes, it includes plenty of dinosaurs.</p><p>This entry in the series is a bit of reboot, though it doesn’t ignore the events of the last few films. Instead, all the characters from the last three <em>Jurassic World </em>movies are gone and replaced by new ones played by Scarlett Johansson, Mahershala Ali, and Jonathan Bailey. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.jurassicworld.com/synopsis/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.jurassicworld.com/synopsis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">These three are searching for special dino DNA that could hold secrets to helping humanity</a></span>. But first, before anyone can use that DNA, our team of new characters has to go to an island which was used as a research facility for the first Jurassic Park to poke some creatures (and eggs) with needles to get that ever-so-useful dino DNA.</p><p>And as you might expect with a <em>Jurassic World </em>trailer, there were a lot of dinosaurs in this first look at <em>Rebirth</em>! Here’s all the ones we spotted. </p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1441b9a5a1329207c1d0215c15627bb7" data-recommend-id="image://1441b9a5a1329207c1d0215c15627bb7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1441b9a5a1329207c1d0215c15627bb7" data-recommend-id="image://1441b9a5a1329207c1d0215c15627bb7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This behemoth is the first dino we see in the trailer and is one of three “giant” creatures that have the special DNA our team of heroes must extract.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="ced44d8303025adf42e58ce372e9bd98" data-recommend-id="image://ced44d8303025adf42e58ce372e9bd98" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ced44d8303025adf42e58ce372e9bd98" data-recommend-id="image://ced44d8303025adf42e58ce372e9bd98" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Just to be clear: This Tyrannosaurs Rex isn’t the same one seen in the past movies, known by fans as “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://jurassicpark.fandom.com/wiki/Rexy#Jurassic_World:_Dominion&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://jurassicpark.fandom.com/wiki/Rexy#Jurassic_World:_Dominion" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rexy.</a></span>” She is presumably still in the Biosyn refuge as seen in the last movie. And also she didn’t have tiger stripes. So this is a new king of the dinosaurs.  </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="7248598c7e2f75976e5329cab5bc4343" data-recommend-id="image://7248598c7e2f75976e5329cab5bc4343" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7248598c7e2f75976e5329cab5bc4343" data-recommend-id="image://7248598c7e2f75976e5329cab5bc4343" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Yeah, yeah, the whole spitting venom and fleshy-frill thing was made up for the movies, but whatever, I’m just happy to see this fan favorite predator back. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a0bf0fc4b858daff178eb0ff934d8b37" data-recommend-id="image://a0bf0fc4b858daff178eb0ff934d8b37" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a0bf0fc4b858daff178eb0ff934d8b37" data-recommend-id="image://a0bf0fc4b858daff178eb0ff934d8b37" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This is another one of the three giants that the team need to extract some DNA from to save humanity. In the trailer they go after its eggs to avoid the creatures themselves. That goes poorly for them. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="de1f00b3952d079a262351ca5a45c6d2" data-recommend-id="image://de1f00b3952d079a262351ca5a45c6d2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="de1f00b3952d079a262351ca5a45c6d2" data-recommend-id="image://de1f00b3952d079a262351ca5a45c6d2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Jurassic Park 3</em> fans rise up. Spino is back, but looking very different. They still have big fins on their backs, as seen in this overhead shot. And what dinosaur is that at the bottom of the frame...?</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="26c1e95c25824c3e82818f315d946777" data-recommend-id="image://26c1e95c25824c3e82818f315d946777" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="26c1e95c25824c3e82818f315d946777" data-recommend-id="image://26c1e95c25824c3e82818f315d946777" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Hey, it’s a Mosasaurus! While these big aquatic beasts have been a part of the franchise since the original <em>Jurassic World</em>, it’s still always cool to see them blast out of the ocean and chomp on some humans or other dinos. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="f791593a6371074f33301e027b12ef36" data-recommend-id="image://f791593a6371074f33301e027b12ef36" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f791593a6371074f33301e027b12ef36" data-recommend-id="image://f791593a6371074f33301e027b12ef36" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Yes, <em>Jurassic Park 3</em> fans, this is what a Spinosaurus looks like in the new movie. While I think the design is still scary (and is more accurate), I do hope that somewhere in this movie the original Spino design from the third film appears once more. I mean, maybe that thing was a failed clone. That might seem far-fetched but keep scrolling.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="50f1c7cbe86298a6c39a10d154f9e182" data-recommend-id="image://50f1c7cbe86298a6c39a10d154f9e182" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="50f1c7cbe86298a6c39a10d154f9e182" data-recommend-id="image://50f1c7cbe86298a6c39a10d154f9e182" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>At one point in the trailer we see what looks like a classic <em>Jurassic Park</em>-era Velociraptor hanging out in a tank. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="5ee76bb50db7075395eaf4f29cc829b6" data-recommend-id="image://5ee76bb50db7075395eaf4f29cc829b6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="5ee76bb50db7075395eaf4f29cc829b6" data-recommend-id="image://5ee76bb50db7075395eaf4f29cc829b6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Now, I believe the movie wants us to <em>think </em>this is a Velociraptor. It already showed you one in a tank, as seen a moment ago, and so it wants you to assume this is one of those. But I’m not convinced. Something about those feet, the color, and the way the trailer hides everything above the claws behind a shadow has me wondering if this is a Velociraptor or some other kind of raptor.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="7544f3272e30e861715782b0d46320ba" data-recommend-id="image://7544f3272e30e861715782b0d46320ba" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7544f3272e30e861715782b0d46320ba" data-recommend-id="image://7544f3272e30e861715782b0d46320ba" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Finally, let’s talk about the scariest and oddest “dinosaur” in the trailer. This thing looks like an alien monster and is likely the rumored “failed mutant clone” that has been referenced in various leaks over the last year or so.</p><p> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/JurassicPark/comments/1iadbq3/compiling_all_the_information_on_the_drex/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/JurassicPark/comments/1iadbq3/compiling_all_the_information_on_the_drex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">There’s speculation out there</a></span> that this is going to be called a D-Rex and might have four arms and some other weird mutations. Either way, its scary and might help make this <em>Jurassic</em> movie the first one in a long time that actually makes me shake a bit in my seat when it arrives in theaters July 2. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eggs Are The New PS5s As Mystery Thief Steals 100,000 In Overnight Heist]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/egg-prices-inflation-bird-flu-steal-cheap-ps5-1851756027</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eggs-are-the-new-ps5s-as-mystery-thief-steals-100-000-in-overnight-heist.1101075/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/egg-prices-inflation-bird-flu-steal-cheap-ps5-1851756027<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="b54bd19c5283084525c5224660642016" data-recommend-id="image://b54bd19c5283084525c5224660642016" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Link holds up a chicken in front of a shelf of eggs. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Link holds up a chicken in front of a shelf of eggs. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="getty" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Brandon Bell / Nintendo / Kotaku<!-- --> (<!-- -->Getty Images<!-- -->)</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b54bd19c5283084525c5224660642016" data-recommend-id="image://b54bd19c5283084525c5224660642016" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Link holds up a chicken in front of a shelf of eggs. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>This is not what I eggspected. According to Pennsylvania state police, someone recently made off with a partial truckload of premium, top-shelf, organic eggs. The thief absconded with their protein-rich haul in the night, and now appears to be dust in the wind.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195618" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Unboxing The Baldur’s Gate 3 Collector’s Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="376" data-playlist="195618,196230,197298" data-current="195618"><div><p>Unboxing The Baldur’s Gate 3 Collector’s Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195618/195618_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195618/195618_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195618/195618_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195618/195618_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21110.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The fowl play took place on February 1 around 8:40 p.m. at a distribution trailer for Pete &amp; Gerry’s Organics in Antrim Township, according to the State Police. No further leads as to who stoles the eggs or why have been shared so far. Law enforcement estimated the value of the 100,000 eggs at $40,000, which if you’ve ever gazed longingly at  Pete &amp; Gerry’s free range extra large brown eggs on the shelf at the grocery store sounds like low-balling it. </p><p> “We take this matter seriously and are committed to resolving it as quickly as possible,” Pete &amp; Gerry’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/2025/02/05/eggs-stolden-pennsylvania/78244593007/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/2025/02/05/eggs-stolden-pennsylvania/78244593007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told <em>USA Today</em></a></span> in a statement. </p><p>The unusual heist recalls the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/postal-worker-caught-stealing-playstation-and-nintendo-1846054192&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/postal-worker-caught-stealing-playstation-and-nintendo-1846054192">PlayStation 5 snatchings</a></span> that occasionally happened back in 2020, when the launch console was super-rare and hard to find. The internet lit up with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/uk-gangs-stealing-ps5s-from-delivery-trucks-while-theyre-driving&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/uk-gangs-stealing-ps5s-from-delivery-trucks-while-theyre-driving" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tales of roving UK gangs</a></span> raiding trucks full of PS5s and drivers absconding with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/amazon-cuts-ties-with-driver-allegedly-caught-failing-to-deliver-ps5/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/amazon-cuts-ties-with-driver-allegedly-caught-failing-to-deliver-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">undelivered consoles</a></span>. </p><p>Now, with prices spiking because of the bird flu outbreak, eggs are the luxury items on everyone’s mind. Sure, they’re still super-cheap compared to gaming consoles, but the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/egg-price-explainer-bird-flu-1851748448&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/egg-price-explainer-bird-flu-1851748448" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">roughly 20 percent spike</a></span> in prices in recent months hits doubly hard. The pain isn’t only felt in our wallets but in our stomachs as well. </p><p>Luxury purchases feel different than a few unexpected extra bucks on carefully scrutinized grocery bills. I used to eat a dozen eggs at week at least. Eggs on toast. Eggs on noodles. Hard boiled. Soft boiled. Omelets. I was a fiend for these golden delights. No longer. I’m not quite ready to pawn my PS5 for a month’s supply of eggs, but I no longer instantly perish the thought. </p><p>I doubt this mystery thief is a Robin Hood, preparing to doll out free eggs in the woods of Western PA. But I do wonder what you actually <em>do</em> with 100,000 stolen eggs. Make a giant cake? Sell them on eBay? I will be watching the development of this story with great interest, and many pangs of hunger. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rendering Ranger: R² [Rewind] launches March 20]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/rendering-ranger-r2-rewind-launches-march-20</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rendering-ranger-r%C2%B2-rewind-launches-march-20.1101072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/rendering-ranger-r2-rewind-launches-march-20<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em><a title="Games > Rendering Ranger: R² [Rewind] [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rendering-ranger-r2-rewind">Rendering Ranger: R² [Rewind]</a> will launch digitally for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,767 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,656 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,598 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,262 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2167260/Rendering_Ranger_R2_Rewind/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/rendering_ranger_r_rewind" target="_blank">GOG</a> on March 20, publisher <a title="Companies > Ziggurat Interactive [32 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ziggurat-interactive">Ziggurat Interactive</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Limited Run Games [199 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/limited-run-games">Limited Run Games</a> and Rainbow Arts announced. Physical standard and “Armageddon” editions will also be available for pre-order via <a href="https://limitedrungames.com/collections/rendering-ranger-r2-rewind" target="_blank">Limited Run Games</a> from February 14 to March 16. <span id="more-942416"></span></em></p><p><em>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2167260/Rendering_Ranger_R2_Rewind/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</em></p><blockquote><p><em><strong>About</strong></em></p><p><em>The legendary <a title="Platforms > SNES" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/snes">Super Famicom</a> cult classic is back.</em></p><p><em>Developed by Manfred Trenz (creator of the <em>Turrican</em> series) and published by German software powerhouse Rainbow Arts, this game was originally released in 1995. Originally slated to come to the West as Targa, the game ultimately ended up as a Japan-only title, with only 10,000 copies printed, making it one of the most sought-after collectibles in retro gaming.</em></p><p><em>You are the Rendering Ranger known as Double R, a special forces soldier who must defend the Earth from a devastating alien invasion. Through nine levels of <a title="Genres > Action [2,463 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> platforming as well as blisteringly fast horizontal <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,992 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> stages, Rendering Ranger: R² is one of the greatest technological showcases ever seen on the Super <a title="Platforms > Nintendo [21,418 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a>!</em></p><!-- AD: content --><em>
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Faithful emulation of <em>Rendering Ranger: R²</em> and its unreleased PAL version Targa with rewind and save features.</li><li>Gut-wrenching <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [891 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> action with sprawling stage design and cinematic presentation.</li><li>Mind-blowingly fast horizontal shooting stages unlike any seen before on Super Nintendo.</li><li>Upgradable weapons, tons of enemies, dynamic on-scene mayhem at nearly every turn.</li><li>Gigantic bosses in <a title="Companies > sprite [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sprite">sprite</a>s converted from pre-rendered 3D models.</li><li>Timeless 16-bit action at its best from legendary game creator Manfred Trenz.</li></ul></em></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends Season 24 is getting big and buff]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/05/apex-legends-season-24-is-getting-big-and-buff/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-season-24-is-getting-big-and-buff.1101039/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/05/apex-legends-season-24-is-getting-big-and-buff/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Apex Legends Season 24 marks the sixth anniversary of the breakout battle royale hit, taking the genre by storm in early 2019. Six years is a long, long time to keep a game running and to keep a large audience of players engaged, but you know what people love? Buffs. Lots of buffs. That’s what Season 24 is bringing to the table when it launches next week on 11th February.</p>
<p><iframe title="Apex Legends: Takeover Dev Update" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HRAKqGo_wBE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As the rumblings coming out of EA higher-ups seem to vacillate between Apex Legends needing a full sequel and needing to keep a hold of what it’s got, and the work for Season 24 has certainly looked to refine and hone the game further. There’s no new Legend characters this time around, with Respawn recognising that, when you’ve got more than two dozen characters, it’s difficult to create something that’s tangibly different and exciting. So the team is pushing toward making more systemic changes with quality of life changes and improvements prioritised alongside new content through the year ahead.</p>


<p>So let’s start with those QOL changes. Matchmaking is getting another overhaul to prioritise fairness, now making use of ranked placements to impact unranked play – so less ability to go and smurf some lower players –&nbsp;and will display the skill width to give you an idea of where you stand in relation to the rest of the lobby.</p>
<p>Speaking of Ranked, anti-cheat will be a continuing priority, but Respawn has also come up with an intriguing way to help disincentivise cheaters with a new Road to Ranked system. This system of in-game challenges will replace the simple account level check, making it so you need to prove skill and teamwork to play Ranked, getting new players up to speed, and adding a hurdle that bot accounts cannot bypass simply through time. Existing ranked players will keep access, though.</p>

<p>And then more broadly points of interest will be highlighted when you drop, letting you easily scope out loot tier and zones, you’ll get even more granular detail through the end of match summaries, and weapon mastery trials are removing sillier objectives in favour of consistent performance.</p>

<p>There’s also new Arsenal crates, visible while diving, that guarantee a weapon and a quick upgrade, removing some of the guessing game from the first few seconds of a match and making things more deterministic.</p>
<p>All good changes, but the thing that Respawn really hope will get players hooked again is a general boost to how fast-paced, snappy and rewarding the combat is. Every single weapon has been buffed in one way or another, increasing damage and with changed headshot multipliers. Some weapons are getting a bigger boost than others, but the general goal is to uplift all ships to the same level, instead of neutering an effective and popular build.</p>
<p>At the same time, armour has been simplified, effectively removing helmet armour from the game –&nbsp;a mythic helmet armour upgrade is actually just upgrading the main armour to red tier – and with headshots no longer affected by armour. Sniping is just about to get much, much more effective – the Kraber will be able to one-shot players with anything up to purple armour. The counter to this is that you can carry more syringes, and crawl speed when downed is increased, so you can hopefully get to cover or nearby buddies.</p>

<p>With no new characters, Respawn has looked to rebalance the meta in two ways. Support characters will no longer have the Heal Expert perk, aiming to push them back to actually being a support class, while the Assault characters Ash and Ballistic have been buffed to make them more explosive in combat.</p>
<p>Both have a new Stowed Reload perk that will reload any weapon after 2 seconds –&nbsp;the Gold Mag weapon upgrade is also boosted to this level – their Combat Reserve perk will add two additional slots specifically for grenades, beyond whatever your backpack can hold, and the Battle Surge ability triggers whenever cracking an enemy shield to increase move speed and reloads, as well as highlight that enemy for your team.</p>
<p>More specifically, Ash can snare more effectively, her ultimate will travel further and move faster, and Tether will snare enemies from your location instead of theirs to really hamper their movement. Her data knife is also making way for a new omnidirectional dash for added mobility. Ballistic’s upgrade can now double his Whistler tactical charge, and his Sling can carry Havoc ammo, to boot.</p>

<p>Again, this is all about the meta shift, to try and put Apex Legends in a better, happier place going forward. But what’s the ‘Takeover’ thing about? Well, that’s referring to community curated game and mode modifier, leaning on the game’s most popular streamers and creators to cook up challenges, rewards, modes and events. Each one will run for two weeks, with a community challenge in week 1 determining the reward for the solo challenge in week 2.</p>
<p>And the beloved R-301 is getting even more love with three Mythic variants dropping into Pubs with Rampart-themed supply drops. They’ll have three distinct Hop-Ups –&nbsp;Red for aggression, Yellow for speed, and Green for support – and give you a big boost to any match your playing. This ties in with a Wraith-inspired Mythic R-301 look that can be purchased.</p>

<p>As there’s questions over the future of Apex Legends, Season 24 feels like a slow and steady kind of update. There’s less of the glitz and glamour of a new map or hero, there’s no grand throwback event to call back to the “good old days”. Instead, it actually seems to be doing the one thing that players tend to want the most: buff the heck out of everything. Will that be enough?</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE 2K25 Hands-On Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/wwe-2k25-hands-on-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wwe-2k25-hands-on-preview.1101030/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/wwe-2k25-hands-on-preview<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Ever since its successful 2022 reinvention, 2K’s popular WWE  series has continually made a host of iterative improvements in an attempt to not only build upon its winning formula but also justify its annual releases. WWE 2K25 certainly promises a new batch of iterations, including a brand new, online interactive world called The Island, a revamp of its story, general manager and Universe mode,  a new hardcore match type called Bloodline Rules, and several more. However, I can’t say if all these new additions will elevate 2K25 above its predecessor because, unfortunately, I didn’t get to sample any of them at a recent preview event. </p>Instead of sampling this year’s most significant alterations, my time with 2K25 was largely focused on the (mostly) unchanged core gameplay and this year’s adjusted Showcase Mode, which focuses on The Bloodline stable of wrestlers. But while I was locked out of most of this year’s new ideas, I did appreciate some small but significant alterations. They’re enough that I’m confident WWE 2K25 will be another successful evolution of the series and most likely worth any wrestling fan’s time.<output data-cy="article-video"></output><div data-cy="paragraph"><p>WWE 2K25’s Showcase Mode focuses on the history of the Anoa’i family, headlined by its most recent stars Roman Reigns and The Bloodline, but also celebrates previous generations like The Wild Samoans, Yokozuna and, most famously, The Rock. The mode now includes three types of matches: Ones where you <em>recreate</em> history, others where you <em>create</em> history, and most interestingly for me, matches where you <em>alter </em>history. I got to experience all three types in the shape of recreating Nia Jax’s Queen of the Ring victory from 2024, creating a dream Wild Samoans versus The Dudley Boyz match, and altering the history of the iconic Roman Reigns against Seth Rollins bout from the Royal Rumble in 2022. All three offered their own style of fun and unique perspective for any hardcore WWE fan and an improvement on last year’s showcase mode. But that’s not to say there aren’t still some small issues.</p><p>The Showcase Mode in last year’s WWE 2K24, much like the one in WWE 2K23 before it,  was hampered by an over-reliance on switching to real-life footage that ran for multiple minutes – a system developer Visual Concepts dubs “Slingshot”.  As I pointed out in my preview for WWE 2K23,<em> “I found myself wanting to be back in the action and create these moments myself, not just watching clips of footage that are already burned into my brain.” </em>Two years later, I’m happy to confirm that although the issue is not completely solved, progress has been made.</p><p>The cut to real-life footage is now gone, as is the over-reliance on taking you away from the action (at least as far as I experienced in the hands-on session). Key moments are recreated in-engine through animation, providing a less jarring experience and a level of satisfaction from seeing iconic moments realised in the game’s (mostly) gorgeous graphics. These sequences also seem significantly shorter, meaning less time away from controlling the action. </p></div><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">WWE 2K25 Screenshots</h3></div></output><div data-cy="paragraph"><p>That’s not to say that all my prior gripes with staying in control have been addressed, though. During the conclusion of my Nia Jax match, complete control was taken away from me. Rather than stay in the ring, I was forced to embody a bystander during the 1,2,3. Ideally, I’d like more control during these important moments. I want to relive them with my own gameplay decisions, not merely observe as a passive bystander. </p><p>Elsewhere, 2K25 makes minor improvements to other rough edges. Previous showcase modes relied heavily on a checklist system, requiring you to complete often rudimentary manoeuvres to trigger the match’s live-action sequences. A common complaint is that this approach makes a match feel less like dynamic gameplay and more like a to-do list. This system<em> is</em> back, which no doubt will prove contentious once again, but it has been slightly refined for WWE 2K25, with added optional objectives on a timer. You’re rewarded for completing these actions with cosmetics, but most importantly you’re not punished for failing them as you were in previous entries. It’s a vital (baby) step in the right direction.</p><p>The standout addition to Showcase Mode is without a doubt the aforementioned ability to change the conclusion of certain historic matches. Where Roman Reigns once lost by disqualification to Seth Rollins, you can now experience how things could have played out should Roman have altered his temperament in the final moments. It’s a fresh experience for hardcore fans of WWE and I’m very excited to see what happens in the other unannounced change matches.</p></div><output data-cy="article-video"></output><div data-cy="paragraph"><p>While there are notable changes in modes and match types, the core gameplay essence of WWE 2K25 is basically the same as before with some minor tweaks. That’s not necessarily a bad thing. I was already happy with the grappling action in WWE 2K24, so I largely believe it’s a smart decision to stick with the proven, successful formula. There are though a few interesting additions and returns, however.</p><p>WWE 2K25 sees the long-requested revival of chain wrestling, a gameplay sequence that was sacrificed with WWE 2K22’s huge engine revamp. During the opening moments of a bout, instigating a grapple will now force players into a mini-game that allows you to gain the upper hand. After locking up you can choose to drive, wrench, attack and ultimately reposition your opponent into a spot that is advantageous to you. Like the trading blows mechanic introduced last year, chain wrestling adds another staple of WWE action, taking another vital step towards accurately recreating what fans see on TV every week.</p><p>Also making a return is the submission system, a mini-game in which you must either avoid or match your opponent's colour block on a wheel. While it has an overwhelming U.I. presentation,  it quickly becomes second nature, and I’m glad to see it return. If you’re less excited by its reappearance, it can fortunately be disabled in the options. The same goes for chain wrestling and other quick-time event moments – they’re all optional. </p></div><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Wrapping a bottle of Logan Paul’s luminous juice around your opponent's head certainly feels like the best use of the egregious electrolytes.</p></div><div data-cy="paragraph"><p>Without a doubt, my favourite gameplay feature from WWE 2K24 also makes its triumphant return: weapon throwing. Not only has the roster of weapons been improved, but the backstage brawls have now expanded into new environments that are perfect for weapon tossing. The best location I experienced in the demo was the WWE archives, which not only allows you to toss apples, footballs and megaphones, but also drops you into a WWE fan’s dream environment, littered with history and easter eggs galore. Oh, and you can also fight on top of a giant Wrestlemania sign and everyone’s favourite giant fist from the Smackdown days of yore.</p><p>As to be expected, much like in real life, the ring area is covered in Prime sponsorships. Say what you will about that, but it does allow you to use the Prime Hydration Station’s giant bottle as a weapon. For my money, wrapping a bottle of Logan Paul’s luminous juice around your opponent's head certainly feels like the best use of the egregious electrolytes.</p><p>Perhaps the most notable gameplay alteration this year, though, is the long-overdue intergender gameplay. For the first time in a 2K WWE game, you’re able to pit the men against the woman in a match of your choosing. This, along with the largest roster ever (with 300+ wrestlers to choose from) finally opens the doors to a whole host of matchups that previously weren’t available. </p></div><div data-cy="paragraph"><p>Lastly, although the demo build featured a limited amount of new updates to explore, I did get some hands-on time with the brand-new match type called Underground. It’s a rope-less variation of an exhibition match that puts you in a Fight Club-like setting with lumberjacks around the ring. This is something completely brand new for the series and something I can share more about later this month as part of our exclusive IGN First content. Be sure to check IGN later this week to get a look at a full match,  as well as a full, detailed explanation of the new match type from Visual Concepts developer, Derek Donahue.</p><p>WWE 2K25 continues the recent tradition of the series, layering new features on top of existing and robust fundamentals. Nothing right now feels particularly revolutionary as the formula feels largely consistent with last year's offering just with some small-but-smart tweaks. Time will tell if the advertised big sweeping changes and new modes I didn’t get to see will truly make this edition stand out from its peers, but from my brief experience, it’s hard to say this is anything but a very incremental step for an already well-realised series.
</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Dale Driver is an Executive Producer of Video Programming at IGN and a lifelong WWE fan/apologist who acknowledges his Tribal Chief. Be thoroughly bored by following him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/daledriver.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@daledriver.bsky.social</em></a><em></em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>