<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 14:59:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Lords of the Fallen 2.0 Is a Massive Improvement Over the Launch Version]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-is-a-massive-improvement-over-the-launch-version/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-is-a-massive-improvement-over-the-launch-version.1171371/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-is-a-massive-improvement-over-the-launch-version/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>If you have been following us for some time, you are well aware of how much I like FromSoftware's Souls series. Despite having quite a few problems getting into the original Demon's Souls before it officially made its way to the West back in the PS3 days, once the game clicked, I came to appreciate the formula so much that I even enjoyed Dark Souls 2 with all of its well-known issues.</p>
<p>Having something of a fondness for clunky experiences that still manage to get some of their features right, I expected to enjoy <a href="https://lordsofthefallen.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lords of the Fallen</a> by Hexworks far more than <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/lords-of-the-fallen-frustration-your-side/">I actually did</a>. While the game wasn't bad by any means, there were too many issues in the launch version to make it anything more than a decent experience, though far too frustrating for my taste. I felt the developer completely misunderstood the idea of challenge that FromSoftware implements in its titles, going for unbalanced enemy configurations that, coupled with the frankly bad movesets of most weapons, made going through any area past the tutorial a pointless exercise in patience. For this reason, after clearing Lords of the Fallen, I never returned to it, as I felt that the bad definitely outweighed the good the game had.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lords-of-the-Fallen-1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Following the launch of the game, however, Hexworks showed some exemplary dedication to their game and has often updated Lords of the Fallen with new features and balance changes, culminating with the release of the 2.0 update <a href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-out-now-with-enhanced-combatmovement-and-free-friends-pass/">last week</a>, which massively improves the game in pretty much every way. For starters, the game is much more forgiving and better eases the player into the experience after completing the tutorial, which I felt, in the launch version, wasn't really representative of what awaited players in the real game. Some may find the game too easy now, but the presence of some modifiers allows players to ramp up the challenge level, providing an unprecedented level of flexibility for a Soulslike. I haven't played through the entire game yet, but the fact that I was not swarmed by three enemies or more while getting sniped by long-range fighters as soon as the proper journey begins has made me more willing to play through it again to experience its solid world design once again. The addition of Lamp Guidance, a new mechanic that guides players from one Vestige save point to another, is a very welcome touch that makes experiencing the game's world even more enjoyable and stress-free.</p>
<p>The 2.0 update also brought significant improvements to movement and combat, which ultimately make Lords of the Fallen a much better game. For starters, the Crusader is much more responsive, which, by itself, already makes combat more enjoyable against single enemies and even groups. Movesets have also been massively improved, with similar weapons also getting some differentiation between them that gives them a more distinct identity and provides more reasons for players to use them besides stats. The movesets overhaul also makes any combat maneuver considerably less floaty, so the massive positioning issues I experienced at launch are no longer present, though combat still feels a little unsatisfying, as movesets still lack weight, animations are stiff, and sound effects continue to sound a little too thin for my tastes.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lords-of-the-Fallen-2-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The new Lords of the Fallen update also goes a long way in improving the co-op experience with some very welcome tweaks. Shared co-op progression is a game changer, allowing players to seamlessly enjoy the entire game together, something that FromSoftware titles do not offer, and is only available on PC via mods. The Free Friend's Pass is also an incredibly generous offering that allows players to experience the game without owning it, which is, again, something that is rarely offered. In this regard, Hexworks really hit it out of the park, not only listening to players' feedback but going the extra mile to make the experience as enjoyable and accessible as possible in terms of multiplayer.</p>
<p>While the 2.0 update doesn't address all the issues found in Lords of the Fallen, as the clunky inventory management hasn't been improved, and some of its additions aren't exactly great, like the new UI which I feel doesn't really fit the game's aesthetics too much, there's no denying that Hexworks' dedication to their game has paid off big time. It's rare that we see such a level of post-launch support for a single-player-focused experience, and as such, the developer has to be commended for it. Hopefully, the lessons learned during the long development of Lords of the Fallen will benefit its sequel, which is currently in <a href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-will-continue-to-receive-meaningful-updates-up-to-version-2-0-sequels-playtesting-to-take-place-this-year/">development</a> for PC and consoles.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows Tops US Charts for March 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-circana-march-2025-sales</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-tops-us-charts-for-march-2025.1171368/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-circana-march-2025-sales<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>US analysis firm Circana has released its gaming sales data for March, and it probably won't come as a surprise that Ubisoft's latest major release&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>is leading the pack for the month.</p>

<p>According to Circana's Mat Piscatella over on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lniaufpggs26" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Bluesky</a>,&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>topped the all-format sales chart for March, with new sports release&nbsp;<em>MLB: The Show 25&nbsp;</em>coming in second. Capcom's&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>is in third, which isn't surprising given its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-sales-10m" rel="nofollow">incredibly strong sales performance</a>.</p>

<p><em>Shadows&nbsp;</em>is also Xbox's top-selling game for the month, although it's pipped to the post on PlayStation by the aforementioned&nbsp;<em>MLB: The Show 25</em>. Since neither game launched on Switch, the honor for Nintendo's console goes instead to&nbsp;<em>Xenoblade Chronicles X</em>'s <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-announced" rel="nofollow">recent remaster</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/xenoblade-chronicles-x-circana-sales-data-march-2025.jpg?itok=CajVuSfV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/xenoblade-chronicles-x-circana-sales-data-march-2025.jpg?itok=qOFJBYOP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Xenoblade Chronicles X&nbsp;</em>was the best-selling Switch game in March.</figcaption></figure><p>In terms of play time,&nbsp;<em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em>topped the charts for both PlayStation and Xbox, although the honor on Steam goes to wacky co-op horror game&nbsp;<em>R.E.P.O.</em>, probably because&nbsp;<em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em>isn't available on Steam.</p>

<p>Just in case you're wondering,&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows</em>' March performance wasn't enough to give it the top spot in the year-to-date sales chart; that still belongs to&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, although&nbsp;<em>Shadows&nbsp;</em>is in a very respectable second place.</p>

<p>Hardware spending fell by 25% over last March, representing the lowest March total since 2019. Sony's PS5 was once again the market leader for both dollar and unit sales, with Xbox Series X|S coming in second on both measures.</p>

<p>Switch sales dropped by 37% when compared to last March, although that's almost certainly due in large part to consumers waiting for the Switch 2, which is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-release-date" rel="nofollow">launching in June this year</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/nintendo-switch-2-circana-sales-data-march-2025.jpg?itok=quiYN9ZJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/nintendo-switch-2-circana-sales-data-march-2025.jpg?itok=h_sClzgN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Switch sales are down, but the Switch 2 is coming later this year.</figcaption></figure><p>Overall, gaming spending dropped by 6% in March when compared to March last year, with only non-mobile subscriptions and console premium digital purchases growing.</p>

<p>As ever, I'd recommend checking out Piscatella's <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lniauceqes26" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">full Bluesky thread</a> if you want to delve deep into the numbers. Join us again in a few weeks for April's figures!</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo's Already Apologizing For Not Having Enough Switch 2s]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-preorders-my-nintendo-japan-sold-out-1851777449</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendos-already-apologizing-for-not-having-enough-switch-2s.1171359/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/switch-2-preorders-my-nintendo-japan-sold-out-1851777449<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Switch 2 preorders don’t begin in the U.S. until late tonight (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-preorder-amazon-walmart-best-buy-gamestop-1851777336&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-preorder-amazon-walmart-best-buy-gamestop-1851777336">12:01 a.m. ET on April 24</a></span>), but they’ve already been underway in other parts of the world and even Nintendo has been shocked by the level of demand so far. The company said that, with over 2.2 million fans seeking to preorder a Switch 2 directly from My Nintendo in Japan alone, the demand already “far exceeds” its ability to fulfill shipments to that country at launch.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194644" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Return To Hyrule" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="165" data-playlist="194644,194907,194842" data-current="194644"><div><p>The Week In Games: Return To Hyrule</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20101.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>“We received an extremely large number of applications, approximately 2.2 million people in Japan alone,” Nintendo president Shuntaro Furukawa <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Nintendo/status/1914982671522083155&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Nintendo/status/1914982671522083155" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted directly on X today</a></span>. “However, this number far exceeds our expectations, and far exceeds the number of Nintendo Switch 2 consoles that can be delivered from the My Nintendo Store on June 5th. Therefore, unfortunately, we expect that a significant number of customers will not be selected when the winners are announced tomorrow, April 24th.”</p><p>He added that while the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-requirements-store-online-1851774277&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-requirements-store-online-1851774277">My Nintendo preorder lottery selection process</a></span> will be ongoing, and retailers in Japan will begin taking preorders soon as well, it’s unlikely that everyone who wants to preorder a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502">Switch 2</a></span> will be able to do so. “We deeply apologize for not being able to meet your expectations despite our prior preparations,” he added. Woof. Fans in the U.S. won’t know how My Nintendo preorders shake out here until May 8. <br></p><p>While that preorder situation is particular to Japan at the moment, it could soon become a recurring story across other countries as well. It’s certainly a rude wake-up call for anyone who thought the Switch 2 wouldn’t be hard to get at launch. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www-videogameschronicle-com.webpkgcache.com/doc/-/s/www.videogameschronicle.com/news/switch-2-is-targeting-march-2025-and-was-delayed-to-avoid-shortages-new-report-claims/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www-videogameschronicle-com.webpkgcache.com/doc/-/s/www.videogameschronicle.com/news/switch-2-is-targeting-march-2025-and-was-delayed-to-avoid-shortages-new-report-claims/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Despite reports</a></span> that the console was delayed precisely in order to provide more time for manufacturing extra units and stacking the Switch 2's year-one launch lineup, it seems like early hype might still outstrip supply. </p><p>Some analysts are already predicting that Nintendo will sell 14.7 million Switch 2 units in its first 12 months, which would eclipse even the original hardware’s popular rollout in 2017. How that stock gets divided up between various markets remains to be seen. The <em>Mario</em> maker <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-stock-tariffs-price-loss-nintendo-sell-out-1851775602&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-stock-tariffs-price-loss-nintendo-sell-out-1851775602">was reportedly shifting more of its inventory</a></span> to the U.S. in recent months to avoid getting caught up in President Trump’s ongoing tariff war. </p><p>“With the cooperation of retailers, we will continue to ship the console and make efforts to get as many Nintendo Switch 2 consoles as possible into your hands,” Furukawa wrote. “We plan to continue producing and shipping a considerable number of Nintendo Switch 2 units in the future. We apologize for the delay in our ability to meet your expectations, and we appreciate your understanding.”</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yes, The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered Still Has All the Bugs, Glitches, and Memes Fans Know and Love From 20 Years Ago]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/yes-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-still-has-all-the-bugs-glitches-and-memes-fans-know-and-love-from-20-years-ago</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yes-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-still-has-all-the-bugs-glitches-and-memes-fans-know-and-love-from-20-years-ago.1171350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/yes-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-still-has-all-the-bugs-glitches-and-memes-fans-know-and-love-from-20-years-ago<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a> has only been out for 24 hours, but already players are enjoying its nostalgia-fueled gameplay — bugs and all.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Every veteran Bethesda fan knows the studio’s games come with a generous dollop of jank. Oblivion, which first launched in 2006, was one of the chief culprits, with objects flying all over the place, characters making poorly-timed (but often hilarious) on-screen interjections, and <em>things </em>happening in the background that, in the context of what was going on in the foreground, were perfect meme material.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nearly 20 years later, and Bethesda’s remaster (not a remake, it’s insisted), has all the “charm,” of the original, as Todd Howard put it. And that’s not an issue. In fact, it’s quite the opposite.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Oblivion is back,” is what players of the remaster are saying in response to clips of the game going wrong in some way, or doing that Bethesda game thing of having a random NPC's face steal the scene.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even glitches players exploited in the original Oblivion have been found to work in the remaster.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">The permanent bound weapons and armour glitch still works in Oblivion Remastered LMAO <a href="https://t.co/Nzp8gCAucK" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/Nzp8gCAucK</a></p>— Nerbit (@Nerbit_13098) <a href="https://twitter.com/Nerbit_13098/status/1914780386648809874?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 22, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">And players are recreating Oblivion memes, trying to recapture the hilarity of the game’s NPC behavior as it was all those years ago.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Original for comparison <a href="https://t.co/egYXGxe438" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/egYXGxe438</a></p>— crobb 🌹 (@corombb) <a href="https://twitter.com/corombb/status/1914864882232475829?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 23, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">None of Oblivion Remastered’s jank is seriously affecting player enjoyment of the game. For some it offers a warm familiarity. Can you imagine if the game had stripped all this out? It would feel… soulless, somehow, and nothing like the original fans fondly remember. Perhaps such attention on polish is best reserved for The Elder Scrolls VI.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bugs, glitches, and memes are just one aspect of Oblivion Remastered’s success, which has seen players use the character creator <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/oblivion-remastereds-funny-character-faces-are-going-viral-for-being-total-nightmare-fuel-and-for-looking-like-the-original-fallout-talking-heads">to come up with some hilarious and nightmarish faces</a>. There are also already loads of mods available, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-mods-have-already-been-published-online">despite Oblivion Remastered not officially supporting them</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And it really does look like Oblivion Remastered is a hit. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-launches-big-on-steam-and-its-only-going-to-get-bigger">On Steam it enjoyed an impressive peak concurrent player count of over 180,000 on release day</a> — a figure that’s set to increase as the game heads into its first weekend on sale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We've got a comprehensive guide to everything you'll find in Oblivion Remastered, including an expansive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/maps/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/cyrodiil"><u>Interactive Map</u></a>, complete Walkthroughs for the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Main_Quest_Walkthrough"><u>Main Questline</u></a> and every <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Guilds"><u>Guild Quest</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Character_Building_Guide"><u>How to Build the Perfect Character</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Things_to_Do_First_in_Oblivion"><u>Things to Do First</u></a>, and much more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Starter Pokemon From Each Generation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-starter-pokemon-from-each-generation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-starter-pokemon-from-each-generation.1171344/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-starter-pokemon-from-each-generation<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The most pivotal moment in any Pokemon game comes right at the start – choosing your partner Pokemon. The first moment you lock eyes with the creature you’ll spend tens of hours raising, bonding with and sending into battle is a special experience. That decision is usually based on vibes and taste to the point where many fans see it as a personality test. However, in those moments, you have no knowledge of how that decision will affect your journey to becoming a Pokemon master, with the gyms, rivals and secrets of the region yet to reveal themselves to you.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Well, we’ve done the research, looked into the base stats, found every strength and weakness of every starter Pokemon and all their evolutions and pitted them against their native regions to determine who is the best starter pick, not just to get you past the first couple gyms, but to take on the Elite Four and beyond. This is the first step to becoming a Pokemon master across all iterations.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gen 1: Bulbasaur</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/22/best-pokemon-starters-bulbasaurpng-1745318747449.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">While being the obvious pick to tackle the first gym in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-red-version">Pokemon Red</a> and Blue (Grass beats Rock, as any Pokemon fan knows), Bulbasaur outshines both Charmander and Squirtle as  the best starter pick in any bid to dominate the Kanto region. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Initial analysis might understandably lean towards Charmander. Fire types are a minority in Gen 1, many random encounters pitt you against Flying types (which are strong against Bulbasaur’s Grass) and the final gym is heavy on Ground types – something Charizard is immune to. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, those who are Bulbasaur-inclined will find themselves flying through the majority of the game, with the Grass type being super effective against Brock’s Rock Pokemon, Misty’s Water collection, and the Giovanni’s final gym line-up, as well as being the best choice to take out the first two members of the Elite Four. The biggest challenge Bulbasaur will face are Erika’s Grass type gym, where strategy will be vital to overcoming the barrage of “not very effective” attacks, and Blaine’s Fire type gym, which can be defeated thanks to the abundance of water types present in Kanto. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are some issues a Bulbasaur trainer will have to contend with, not least the many Pidgeys and Spearows you’ll come across in tall grass, whose Flying typing will provide a problem for anyone looking to grind their way to a high level. Thankfully, the amount of Ground and Rock types in caves will provide ample opportunity for Bulbasaur to wipe out entire bloodlines of Pokemon to gain a few XP. Also problematic are the frequent encounters with Blue, whose Pidgeot and Charmander will be a consistent issue, the latter of which can be helped by a Water type on your team. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But Bulbasaur, along with having well-balanced base stats, has the added bonus of evolving into Venasaur who also is a poison-type, giving him a solid advantage over the other two offerings from Professor Oak.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gen 2: Cyndaquil</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/22/best-pokemon-starters-cyndaquil-1745320920819.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-gold-version">Pokemon Gold</a> and Silver introduced just eight new Fire types to the series, in comparison to 10 Grass and 18 Water types. That minority means snapping up a powerful Fire Pokemon like Cyndaquil from the start adds a great deal of diversity to your team. More importantly, Cyndaquil proves to be the best matchup for the majority of gyms and Elite Four members that populate Johto. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bugsy’s (you guessed it) Bug type gym and Jasmine’s Steel type gym will easily fall before a few Embers and Flame Wheels from Cyndaquil and his subsequent evolutions. The same cannot be said for the cutest of the starters, Water type Totodile, with there being no Fire, Ground or Rock gyms for him to dismantle. Grass type Chikorita (or more likely her third form, Meganium) would have a field day in Pryce’s Water gym but would struggle with the early Bug and Flying type gyms as well as Morty’s Poison type gym. Pryce will pose a problem for Cyndaquil, and so you’ll want to put together a well-balanced team to get you through that penultimate gym, but you’ll have many hours to assemble the perfect group before that hurdle. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Also working in Cyndaquil’s favour are the Grass and Bug types dotted throughout the Elite Four’s roster. Though all four of these teams are well-balanced enough to give you trouble no matter who you pick as a starter, the many Poison types and Lance’s team of Dragon/Flying types makes this a no-go zone for Meganium. Meanwhile Totodile’s final evolution, Ferligator, would certainly hold its own against many of these Pokemon, but won’t blaze through a few like Typhlosion will. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Picking Cyndaquil does come with its issues. There will be many Rock and Ground Pokemon bothering you with random encounters in caves and Lance’s team containing a Charizard and a Gyrados will require some solid strategy to overcome, but the effects of these are much lesser compared to what ails Chikorita and Totodile. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gen 3: Mudkip</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/22/best-pokemon-starters-mudkip-1745320946409.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">You might pick Mudkip because you just think he’s neat, but the reasons to go Water type for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-ruby-version">Pokemon Ruby</a> and Sapphire run a bit deeper. In terms of gyms, Water type Mudkip has a bit of competition from the Grass type Treecko as both of them are super effective against three of the eight. They both have an advantage in Roxanne’s and Tate &amp; Liza’s Rock/Ground gyms, while Mudkip will be best suited to take on Flannery’s Fire gym and Treeko for Wallace’s Water gym. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">By the time you get to Wallace, Treeko would have almost definitely evolved into Sceptile, as Sootopolis City houses the final gym. The significance of that can’t be understated, but Treeko’s Grass typing sees it at a disadvantage in battles with Flannery and with Winona’s Flying type lineup. Mudkip, on the other hand, will struggle with just the one gym – Wattson’s (you guessed it) Electric type gym early on in Mauville City. Your third option, Torchic, doesn’t really enter the conversation here, with Fire types being super effective against none of the gyms and Fighting (a type gained by Torchic’s third form, Blazicken), only super effective against one, not to mention being at a massive disadvantage for Wallace’s battle. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The makeup of the Elite Four can lend a slight advantage towards Treeko’s final form, Sceptile, as you come across Glacia’s Ice/Water Pokemon and a few Grass Pokemon along the way which will cause Swampert (Mudkip’s third evolution) some issues. However, as Mudkip evolves into its final form, it gains Ground typing and very nicely balanced stats which see it gain a huge defensive boost, becoming immune to Electric and its only weakness being Grass. This makes Swampert able to power through battles where it usually might be the underdog. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another consideration may be the amount of water present in the Hoenn region, meaning random encounters can be a bit of a grind, but Mudkip shows enough advantages in other areas to overcome that obstacle. Bonus points for being the cutest of the bunch.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gen 4: Chimchar</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/22/best-pokemon-starters-chimchar-1745320985367.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Continuing the trend from the very first game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-diamond-version">Pokemon Diamond</a> and Pearl adds far fewer Fire type Pokemon to the series; just five in comparison to the14 introduced for Water and Grass. Though this isn’t a deciding factor in which starter to pick, it adds to the list of attributes going in Fire type Chimchar’s favour over Grass type Turtwig and Water type Piplup. Three is the magic number in terms of how many gyms a Pokemon needs to be super effective against to come out on top over its peers, and Chimchar’s Fire typing helps it overcome Gardenia’s Grass type gym, as well as the sixth and seventh gyms ran by Byron’s Steel types and Candice’s Ice types. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Chimchar faces tough competition from Turtwig, who can eliminate Roark’s Rock type and Crasher Wake’s Water type gyms with ease. After evolving into Torterra, it also gains Ground typing, making it immune to Electric attacks which will see it waltz through the final gym owned by Volkner. Though they may seem perfectly matched, a lot of Turtwig’s strengths are most exemplified in the early stages of the game, while Chimchar’s abilities sees him primed for late game success.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Coming through the gyms with minimal fuss is important due to the Sinnoh region’s very well-balanced Elite Four. Chimchar’s final evolution, Infernape, is perfect to take on Aaron’s Bug Pokemon, which would be super effective against Torterra, but the Grass type would admittedly be best to dismantle Bertha’s Water and Ground types. Piplup, despite evolving into the very resilient Empoleon, doesn’t have a significant advantage over many of the gym leaders or the Elite Four to make a dent here. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a close matchup between Chimchar and Torterra, but due to the frequent battles with Team Galactic’s Bug types, the advantage falls with Chimchar, who has the gym battle credentials to back it up. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gen 5: Tepig</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/22/best-pokemon-starters-tepig-1745321009249.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Gen 5 makes for a more clean cut decision, with the Fire type Tepig making the biggest claim for being the smartest pick. Grass type Snivy doesn’t quite make the cut as it only has an advantage over just the one gym, nor any significant advantages over any Elite Four member, as well as being plagued by the various Bug and Flying types across the Unova region’s tall grass and boss battles. Water type Oshawott isn’t as embattled as Snivy, being the best choice to take on Clay’s Ground type gym and being resistant to Brycen’s Ice Pokemon, which are super effective against Snivy. But like the Grass type, there are no Elite Four members who lean into a type specifically tailored to Oshawott or its evolutions. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, Tepig’s Fire abilities, and its final form, Emboar, also being a Fighting type, allows it to have a smoother ride through Unova. Firstly, Burgh’s Bug gym and Brycen’s gym are light work for a Fire type, the latter being the penultimate gym in the game. Alternative solutions will need to be found to make it through Clay’s Ground-based gym, but the same can be said for Oshawott as it arrives in Elesa’s Electric gym. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Elite Four battles are where Emboar’s Fighting type comes in handy, being super effective against Grimsley’s Dark type Pokemon. Emboar is admittedly vulnerable to Caitlin’s Psychic types, but if you have a strong enough bench, this battle can easily be overcome. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Also working in Emboar’s favour are his strong attacking stats and the presence of Team Plasma, who have an abundance of Steel types. Having to fight the Elite Four twice makes <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-black-version">Pokemon Black</a> and White a tough challenge no matter who you choose, but Tepig can put your mind at ease more often than the others. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gen 6: Fennekin</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/22/best-pokemon-starters-fennekin-1745321043423.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-x-version">Pokemon X</a> and Y continue the dominance of Fire types in this list. The sixth generation has a quirk where you can choose from two sets of starters, first between the new bunch of Chespin, Fennekin and Froakie, and later between the Kanto starters from the original games. For this list, we’ll focus on the starters unique to this game, of which Fennekin is the standout. The Fire Pokemon can almost stroll through the gyms, being super effective against three and resistant to two more. Though two of those gyms are in the early stages of the game, the final three being Fairy, Psychic and Ice based means that Fennekin’s third evolution, Delphox, now imbued with Psychic typing, can head off to the Pokemon League relatively unscathed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Froakie evolves into Greninja, a Water/Dark type Pokemon, making it super effective against Olympia’s Psychic team but weak against Valerie’s Fairy types. Being a Water type mostly gets it into trouble, matching up poorly against Ramos’ Grass types and Clemont’s Electric types, something Grant’s early Rock gym doesn’t make up for. Chespin’s story makes for similar reading, struggling off the bat with Viola’s Bug gym and going on to gain a Fighting typing after evolving into Chesnaught which leaves it at a disadvantage against Olmpia and Valerie. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As the games progress, the Elite Fours get a bit more balanced. Pokemon X and Y is another example of a series of battles suited to a different type each time. You’ll want Water to overcome Malva, Fire to overcome Wikstrom and Grass to overcome Siebold. Delphox just about has the edge, able to resist whatever Diantha’s Gardevoir throws at it. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gen 7: Litten</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/22/best-pokemon-starters-litten-1745321072999.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Rounding out this Fire type four-peat is Litten from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-sun-version">Pokemon Sun</a> and Moon. Despite having to struggle through the first couple trials (the Alola region’s version of gyms, of which there are only seven), Litten is the obvious choice for the rest of the battles. Mallow’s Grass trial is the only lineup where each Pokemon is weak to Fire, but Sophocles’ Electric gym contains two Steel types and a Bug type. And by the time you arrive at Acerola’s Ghost trial you could have evolved Litten into the Fire/Dark type Incineroar whose attacks will be super effective against the whole lineup, especially the Grass and Ice Pokemon in Acerola’s team. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The final trial, in which you must face Mina with her Fairy Pokemon, is a little more complicated because of Incineroar’s Dark typing. A regular Fire type would be able to resist Fairy attacks, but Incineroar is damaged normally by them. Helpfully, Mina has a Steel, Grass and Bug type in her team.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Litten’s starter counterparts, Rowlet and Popplio, will find success with one of the first three trials, but will cease to have an advantage over any of the late game battles. Rowlet’s evolution, Decidueye, gains Ghost typing, which is a blessing and a curse for Acerola’s trial, but doesn’t garner much of an advantage elsewhere. Popplio evolves into the Water/Fairy type Primarina, but that doesn’t affect its fortunes with the trials at all. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sun and Moon’s Elite Four are just a small fraction of what awaits you in the Pokemon League. After becoming champion yourself, you face challenges from 10 more trainers looking to take your place. These battles, on top of the Elite Four themselves, are too diverse for any starter to have any advantage over the other, meaning Litten’s ability to clear the trials is even more vital. The Alola region also introduces just eight Fire Pokemon in comparison to Grass and Water’s 13 (after the series had become more balanced in that regard) so snapping Litten up early is a great aid.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gen 8: Sobble</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/22/best-pokemon-starters-sobble-1745321095167.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Sobble’s victory over Grookey and Scorbunny might be the closest of the lot. All three Pokemon are the best picks against three gyms, with Gordie and Raihan’s Rock and Ground gyms being perfect for Sobble and Grookey, and Melony’s Ice gym and Opal’s Fairy gym being tailor made for Scorbunny. Additionally, the first three gyms are Grass, Water and Fire typed, in that order, lending no advantage to any of the three starters. Raihan’s gym being the final one gives it a bit more importance, so the gym battles give a hair’s breadth of a lead to Grookey and Sobble. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Galar region’s version of the Elite Four, The Champion Cup, allows Sobble to just inch past Grookey in the standings. None of these Pokemon’s final evolutions gain any new types, making them work with what they’re given from the start. The semi-final opponents don’t lean any particular way, but Bede's Fairy Pokemon, followed by Nessa’s Water types and Raihan’s Fire and Ground heavy Dragon team, favour Fire, Grass and Water respectively. If success against the toughest opponents is most valued, then Sobble just about edges victory here. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other considerations like the rivals, Team Yell, and random encounters are even less impactful than normal in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-sword">Pokemon Sword</a> and Shield. Team Yell uses mostly Dark types, which attack and defend normally against Fire, Water and Grass types, and the introduction of overworld Pokemon means random encounters happen less. If there’s any other factor that tips the scales towards Sobble, it would be that its final evolution, Inteleon, has a nicely balanced set of stats. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gen 9: Fuecoco</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/22/best-pokemon-starters-fuecoco-1745321116725.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The sixth Fire type to be chosen on this list is one of the clearest winners. You might think that the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-scarlet">Pokemon Scarlet</a> and Violet’s focus on player freedom might allow for little separation between Sprigatito, Fuecoco and Quaxly – You can do the gyms and raid Team Star bases in any order you like and you can avoid encounters with wild Pokemon almost entirely. But even with all of that, the Paldea region feels designed to be dominated by Fuecoco. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The gyms in Scarlet and Violet don’t level scale, so if you have a bad matchup, you can just return once you’re able to power through a disadvantage. Still, the highest level gyms being Psychic/Fairy and Ice types, courtesy of Tulip and Grusha, and the two lowest level gyms being Katy and Brassius’ Bug and Grass types, means there’s a good reason to go with Fuecoco (and its Ghost type final evolution, Skeledirge) regardless of your strategy. Being a water type, Quaxly isn’t strong against any gym until it reaches its third form, Quaquaval, where it becomes a Fighting type, helping it in Larry’s Normal type gym. Sprigatito fares a bit better, evolving into Grass/Dark type Meowscarada, enabling it to best Tulip’s gym and Ryme’s Ghost gym. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Team Star base raids place even more importance on what starter you pick, being vital to the story progression of the game. The crews based around Dark and Poison Pokemon have an abundance of Bug Pokemon who have to be cleared before you can face the boss, while crews based around Fairy and Fighting types are perfect for Skeledirge, who is immune to attacks from the latter. Quaquaval and Meowscarada are worthy opponents for the first member of the Elite Four, Rika and her Ground Pokemon, but from Poppy’s Steel team onwards, Skeledirge finds itself miles ahead of the competition. </p><div id="the-best-starter-pokemon" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">The Best Starter Pokemon</h3><h3>The Best Starter Pokemon</h3></p></div></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered’s Funny Character Faces Are Going Viral for Being Total Nightmare Fuel — and for Looking Like the Original Fallout Talking Heads]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/oblivion-remastereds-funny-character-faces-are-going-viral-for-being-total-nightmare-fuel-and-for-looking-like-the-original-fallout-talking-heads</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered%E2%80%99s-funny-character-faces-are-going-viral-for-being-total-nightmare-fuel-%E2%80%94-and-for-looking-like-the-original-fallout-talking-heads.1171338/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/oblivion-remastereds-funny-character-faces-are-going-viral-for-being-total-nightmare-fuel-and-for-looking-like-the-original-fallout-talking-heads<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The nose have it.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">As thousands flock to the launch of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a>, the character creator is being used to generate terrifying (and often hilarious) abominations. Yes, Oblivion is back, and so are those funny faces.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Oblivion Remastered, developed by remake specialist Virtuos using Unreal Engine 5, has a long list of visual and feature improvements. It runs at 4K resolution and 60 frames per second, as you'd expect, but other changes are more meaningful. Everything from the leveling systems to character creation, and combat animations to in-game menus have been improved. Meanwhile, there's lots of new dialogue, a proper third-person view, and new lip sync technology. The changes are going down well with fans, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-fans-react-to-all-the-biggest-changes-say-its-good-enough-to-be-called-a-remake"><u>some of whom believe Oblivion Remastered would be more accurately described as a remake</u></a>. Bethesda, however, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-comments-on-the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-changes-we-never-wanted-to-remake-it"><u>has explained why it went down the remaster route</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Bethesda’s remaster gives Oblivion a new lick of paint, and while everything in the game looks a lot better than it did 20 years ago, there’s no getting away from that trademark Bethesda face jank.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And, as is typically the case with Bethesda games, Oblivion Remastered’s character creator lets you create some outlandish faces. Some of these have already gone viral across social media, despite the remaster being less than 24 hours old. Here’s a snippet of our favorites:</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">This is my magnum opus in Oblivion Remaster. Sir Vancealot <a href="https://t.co/q3hsDd3Uys" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/q3hsDd3Uys</a></p>— CAMELCAST OFFICIAL (@CAMELCASTOff) <a href="https://twitter.com/CAMELCASTOff/status/1914797155300110786?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 22, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Trying the Oblivion remake, character creation is going well, elves are gorgeous now <a href="https://t.co/fjw4oqoPBl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/fjw4oqoPBl</a></p>— Julia (@Julia_CaSsian) <a href="https://twitter.com/Julia_CaSsian/status/1914751449554411742?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 22, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">As old-school Fallout fans may have noticed, there’s something worryingly familiar about these Oblivion Remastered faces. That’s probably because they rekindle memories of the original Fallout talking heads, which, at the time (late ‘90s) looked impressive, but now look, well… a bit like some of these Oblivion Remastered faces.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">oblivion so funny to me. we finally have the technology to recreate the og fallout talking head renders in real time <a href="https://t.co/SSG5iVLlKq" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/SSG5iVLlKq</a></p>— 🦇🩸𝕸𝖔𝖓𝖌𝖗𝖊𝖑🩸🦇 (@FearMongrel) <a href="https://twitter.com/FearMongrel/status/1914804183661994018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 22, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">one thing that's pretty neat is that the way some faces are done in oblivion remastered is similar to faces in fallout 2 which means a fallout 3 remaster could look closer to fallout 2 and have WAY COOLER LOOKING GHOULS <a href="https://t.co/dHVawmh9cl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/dHVawmh9cl</a></p>— shley died from lavender town syndrome (sad!!) ˂/3 (@gloomygvrl666) <a href="https://twitter.com/gloomygvrl666/status/1914881853628223964?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 23, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It’s all in good fun, of course, and evidence, really, that Oblivion is back in a big way. What would be a big Bethesda game launch without some reliably old face jank? Veteran fans wouldn’t want it any other way.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And it really does look like Oblivion Remastered is a hit. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-launches-big-on-steam-and-its-only-going-to-get-bigger">On Steam it enjoyed an impressive peak concurrent player count of over 180,000 on release day</a> — a figure that’s set to increase as the game heads into its first weekend on sale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We've got a comprehensive guide to everything you'll find in Oblivion Remastered, including an expansive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/maps/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/cyrodiil"><u>Interactive Map</u></a>, complete Walkthroughs for the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Main_Quest_Walkthrough"><u>Main Questline</u></a> and every <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Guilds"><u>Guild Quest</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Character_Building_Guide"><u>How to Build the Perfect Character</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Things_to_Do_First_in_Oblivion"><u>Things to Do First</u></a>, and much more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: </em><a href="https://x.com/CAMELCASTOff/status/1914797155300110786" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@CAMELCASTOff</em></a><em>.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 My Nintendo Store lottery applications surpass 2.2 million in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/switch-2-my-nintendo-store-lottery-applications-surpass-2-2-million-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-my-nintendo-store-lottery-applications-surpass-2-2-million-in-japan.1171335/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/switch-2-my-nintendo-store-lottery-applications-surpass-2-2-million-in-japan<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>"This number significantly exceeded our expectations," Nintendo president Furukawa says.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Over 2.2 million people in Japan alone have submitted applications for the My <a title="Platforms > Nintendo [21,885 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a> Store <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [110 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> pre-order lottery, Nintendo president Shuntaro Furukawa said in a <a href="https://twitter.com/Nintendo/status/1914982671522083155" target="_blank">tweet</a>. <span id="more-960514"></span></p><p>“This number significantly exceeded our expectations, and even further exceeds the amount of <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,987 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> 2 units we will be able to deliver via My Nintendo Store on June 5,” Furukawa said. “That being said, we unfortunately anticipate a considerable number of customers will not be chosen when the lottery winners are announced tomorrow, April 24.”</p><p>Those who are not selected in the first lottery draw will automatically be entered into the second lottery draw, but that even with a second draw, Nintendo will not be able to accommodate every application.</p><p>Furukawa added that Nintendo plans to strengthen its production system in order to meet this unexpected demand.</p><p>It should be noted that My Nintendo Store is just one retailer. On April 24, pre-orders and lottery sales for Switch 2 will also open nationwide at other Japanese retailers.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Just Made It Easier For Devs To Promote Their Games' Accessibility Features]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/steam-just-made-it-easier-for-devs-to-promote-their-games-accessibility-features/1100-6531047/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-just-made-it-easier-for-devs-to-promote-their-games-accessibility-features.1171332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/steam-just-made-it-easier-for-devs-to-promote-their-games-accessibility-features/1100-6531047/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531047">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Steam is rolling out a new questionnaire for developers that makes it easier for them to highlight <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-xbox-playstation-are-teaming-up-for-accessible-games-initiative/1100-6530272/" data-ref-id="1100-6530272">accessibility features</a> in their games. Later in 2025, it will also become easier for players to search for games with specific accessibility features.</p><p>These updates were outlined in a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/groups/steamworks/announcements/detail/536595840131663919" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog post</a> on April 22. In the "Edit Store" section for a game on Steamworks, developers can now complete an accessibility support questionnaire to confirm that their game has various gameplay, audio, visual, and input accessibility options. From there, developers can self-identify their game's level of accessibility.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1849/18498836/4481080-dad4d0852ce47f116b63cba4469478ba2b678aa4.png" data-ref-id="1300-4481080" data-ratio="0.41045454545455" data-width="2200" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1849/18498836/4481080-dad4d0852ce47f116b63cba4469478ba2b678aa4.png" data-ref-id="1300-4481080"></a><figcaption>This is what the accessibility support questionnaire game developers can now fill out on Steamworks looks like.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1849/18498836/4481080-dad4d0852ce47f116b63cba4469478ba2b678aa4.png"></figure><p>For now, this will only be visible within Steamworks, but later this year, it will have more public-facing uses. Developers will eventually be able to share information from this questionnaire on the Steam Store and App pages. Steam users will also gain the option to search for specific accessibility features. The following accessibility filters for search have been confirmed by Valve:</p><ul><li>Adjustable Difficulty</li><li>Save Anytime</li><li>Adjustable Text Size</li><li>Subtitle Options</li><li>Color Alternatives</li><li>Camera Comfort</li><li>Custom Volume Controls</li><li>Stereo Sound</li><li>Surround SOund</li><li>Narrated Game Menus</li><li>Playable without Timed Input</li><li>Keyboard Only Option</li><li>Mouse Only Option</li><li>Touch Only Option</li><li>Chat Speech-to-text</li><li>Chat Text-to-speech</li></ul><p>Valve explains that it is implementing these features to bring "a more positive experience on Steam for everyone by making it easier to find games that support Accessibility features." It's not required that devs fill out the questionnaire, but Valve says it is "highly recommended" because it will make it easier for players with accessibility needs to find these games.</p><p>If you're a Steam user, expect to see these game accessibility-focused improvements on Steam sometime this year.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ready Or Not Surpasses 9 Million Copies Sold Ahead Of Its Console Launch This Summer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ready-or-not-surpasses-9-million-copies-sold-ahead-of-its-console-launch-this-summer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ready-or-not-surpasses-9-million-copies-sold-ahead-of-its-console-launch-this-summer.1171314/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ready-or-not-surpasses-9-million-copies-sold-ahead-of-its-console-launch-this-summer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Just under a week after VOID Interactive <a href="https://wccftech.com/void-interactives-ready-or-not-coming-to-consoles-in-summer-2025/">announced</a> that Ready or Not would be coming to PS5 and Xbox Series X/S consoles, the tactical FPS hit another milestone by surpassing <strong>9 million copies sold</strong> on PC.</p>
<p>"<em>Our flagship tactical shooter Ready or Not is hitting a huge new milestone: We're officially coming to PlayStation and Xbox this summer</em>," VOID Interactive's chief executive officer, Julio Rodriguez, said in a press release.</p>
<p>"<em>As we approach 10 million units sold on Steam, we're beyond excited to bring the experience to console players worldwide.</em>"</p>
<p>There's still no specific release date for Ready or Not on consoles, but we know it will be sometime during summer 2025.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ready or Not – Console Reveal Trailer (PS5/Xbox Series X | S)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jW3zr1Jn5bM?start=15&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Ready or Not is a tactical FPS that puts you in the boots of a SWAT team where, unlike plenty of other shooters, you're trying to not pull the trigger as much as possible, instead of going in guns blazing for every situation.</p>
<p>The realistic scenarios Ready or Not emphasize to players that they need to strategize as much as possible. It's not your average war-shooter or Call of Duty, where the aim is to kill everyone in sight. A successful mission in Ready or Not means you've apprehended all hostile combatants and ensured everyone in harm's way gets out safely and alive.</p>
<p>Ready or Not originally launched in early access in <a href="https://wccftech.com/tactical-fps-ready-or-not-swat/">2017</a> before reaching its full 1.0 release in <a href="https://wccftech.com/ready-or-not-launches-out-of-early-access-adding-lots-of-missions-and-content/">2023</a>. This release came after a few delays, with the full release being first scheduled for 2020. Now that it's due to arrive on consoles two years after its full PC release, VOID Interactive's long journey with Ready or Not will enter its next chapter.</p>
<p>The console version of Ready or Not will arrive with 20 missions that can be tackled solo or in co-op with up to five players. Two brand-new missions will also be available in the console version, which PC players will receive the same day as the console launch in a free update.</p>
<p>It'll also include two DLC expansions, which add another six missions to the pile. Those who pre-order the console version will have access to the M32A1 Grenade launcher, MK-V Pistol, and 590M Shotgun. Once again, PC players who already own the game will get these weapons in a free update.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Is Up to Its Old Web3 Tricks Again With Might & Magic Fates]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/might-and-magic-fates-blockchain-mobile</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-is-up-to-its-old-web3-tricks-again-with-might-magic-fates.1171311/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/might-and-magic-fates-blockchain-mobile<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ubisoft has announced&nbsp;<em>Might &amp; Magic Fates</em>, a new free-to-play trading card game created in conjunction with blockchain studio Immutable, and yes, that does mean the game will have Web3 elements.</p>

<p>In an announcement <a href="https://x.com/MightMagicFates/status/1915033605266456909" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X, Ubisoft says&nbsp;<em>Might &amp; Magic Fates&nbsp;</em>will give you the opportunity to "collect and trade iconic cards", and that the game will offer the chance to "play for free [and] dominate with skill".</p>

<p>According to an <a href="https://www.mightandmagicfates.com/faqs" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">FAQ</a> on&nbsp;<em>Fates</em>' official website, the game is a "strategic card game where every decision matters", and it'll involve building "powerful decks by combining creatures, spells, artifacts, buildings, and heroes" from across the&nbsp;<em>Might &amp; Magic&nbsp;</em>world.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/might-magic-fates-free-to-play-blockchain-art.jpg?itok=rpyoZYSk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/might-magic-fates-free-to-play-blockchain-art.jpg?itok=B-fKlTqA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Might &amp; Magic Fates&nbsp;</em>is another Web3-infused offering from Ubisoft.</figcaption></figure><p>Naturally, you'll be able to play&nbsp;<em>Might &amp; Magic Fates&nbsp;</em>online against other players, and Ubisoft promises the chance to build your collection either through earning rewards by playing the game or through "opening booster packs filled with cards of varying rarities".</p>

<p>If you're wondering where the Web3 elements come in, Ubisoft says the blockchain stuff in&nbsp;<em>Might &amp; Magic Fates&nbsp;</em>will be "optional" and will "unlock digital ownership for players who want it".</p>

<p>According to Ubisoft, that means you can "enjoy the full experience, grow your collection, and compete at the highest level" without ever having to touch&nbsp;<em>Fates</em>' Web3 elements, but if you want to, you can "freely trade your cards using the Immutable blockchain".</p>

<p>This is, of course, far from Ubisoft's first dalliance with Web3 gaming. In October last year, the company <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-nft-game" rel="nofollow">released the rather generically-named</a>&nbsp;<em>Champions Tactics: Grimoria Chronicles</em>, an NFT game that features figurines you can buy with your real-life hard-earned cash.</p>




<p>I'm not entirely sure that&nbsp;<em>Might &amp; Magic Fates&nbsp;</em>is going to be the thing to turn Ubisoft's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-financials-cost-cutting-q3" rel="nofollow">flagging fortunes</a> around, but then again, given that it's a blockchain game, I don't think Ubisoft is banking on it doing so either.</p>

<p><em>Might &amp; Magic Fates&nbsp;</em>has no release date yet, but when it launches, it'll arrive for mobile devices "with potential expansion to PC". Watch this space for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia’s AI assistant on Windows now has plugins for Spotify, Twitch, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/654221/nvidia-g-assist-plugins-spotify-twitch-apps</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia%E2%80%99s-ai-assistant-on-windows-now-has-plugins-for-spotify-twitch-and-more.1171308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/654221/nvidia-g-assist-plugins-spotify-twitch-apps<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/tom-warren">Tom Warren</a> <span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Nvidia is updating its G-Assist AI assistant on Windows to take it beyond optimizing game and system settings. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/635155/nvidia-g-assist-ai-assistant-available-download">G-Assist originally launched last month</a> as a chatbot primarily focused on improving PC gaming, but it’s now getting plugin support so you can extend the AI assistant to control Spotify, check if a streamer is live on Twitch, and look at stock or weather updates.</p><p>The new ChatGPT-based <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/rtx-ai-garage-g-assist-plugin-builder/">G-Assist plugin builder</a> lets developers and enthusiasts create custom functionality for Nvidia’s AI assistant. G-Assist will be able to connect to external tools and use APIs to expand the capabilities of what Nvidia offers right now.</p><div><p>Nvidia has published <a href="https://github.com/NVIDIA/g-assist">sample plugins on GitHub</a> that can be compiled and used by G-Assist:</p></div><div><ul><li><span><strong>Spotify</strong> — hands-free music and volume control</span></li><li><span><strong>Google Gemini </strong>— allows G-Assist to invoke Gemini for cloud-based complex conversations</span></li><li><span><strong>Twitch</strong> — you can use this plugin to checks if a streamer is live with voice commands like, “Hey, Twitch, is [streamer] live?” </span></li><li><span><strong>Peripheral Controls</strong> — change RGB lighting or fan speed on <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fsoftware%2Fnvidia-app%2Fg-assist%2F" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored" target="_blank">Logitech G, Corsair, MSI and Nanoleaf devices</a></span></li><li><span><strong>Stock Checker</strong> — provides real-time stock prices</span></li><li><span><strong>Weather Updates</strong> — provides current weather conditions in any city</span></li></ul></div><p>These plugins all run locally using a small language model on Nvidia’s RTX GPUs, and developers will also be able to share their own custom plugins through GitHub. G-Assist uses a local small language model that requires nearly 10GB of space for the assistant functions and voice capabilities. The AI assistant works on a variety of RTX 30-, 40-, and 50-series desktop GPUs, but you’ll need a card with at least 12GB of VRAM.</p><p>If you’re interested in trying out G-Assist or building a plugin, the app is available as an optional part of <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fsoftware%2Fnvidia-app%2F" rel="sponsored">Nvidia’s main app for Windows</a>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Fall Release Calendar Takes Shape As Ghost of Yotei Rushes Out Ahead Of Grand Theft Auto 6]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ghost-yotei-release-date-gta-6-collector-edition-1851777437</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-fall-release-calendar-takes-shape-as-ghost-of-yotei-rushes-out-ahead-of-grand-theft-auto-6.1171299/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ghost-yotei-release-date-gta-6-collector-edition-1851777437<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Open-world samurai adventure <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ghost-of-yotei-tsushima-protagonist-atsu-wolf-ps5-1851657667&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ghost-of-yotei-tsushima-protagonist-atsu-wolf-ps5-1851657667"><em>Ghost of Yotei</em></a></span> is the latest blockbuster to stake out a release date in a fall calendar overshadowed by the impending arrival of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gta-6-second-trailer-2-release-date-ceo-october-launch-1851773636&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-second-trailer-2-release-date-ceo-october-launch-1851773636"><em>Grand Theft Auto VI</em></a></span>. The sequel to <em>Ghost of Tsushima</em> will come to PlayStation 5 in October as we get more release dates for the second half of 2025. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196299" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="You Should Play Grand Theft Auto III Before GTA VI | Total Recall" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="385" data-playlist="196299,195922,195371" data-current="196299"><div><p>You Should Play Grand Theft Auto III Before GTA VI | Total Recall</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21849.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>  <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> will come out October 2 with pre-orders going live in May, Sucker Punch Studios announced <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.playstation.com/2025/04/23/ghost-of-yotei-comes-to-playstation-5-on-october-2/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/04/23/ghost-of-yotei-comes-to-playstation-5-on-october-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over on the PlayStation Blog</a></span> on Wednesday. The studio also revealed a collector’s edition complete with a Ghost Mask, pouch of gold coins, papercraft ginkgo tree, and other physical artifacts related to the game’s story of betrayal and revenge (no physical disc though). </p><p>We also got a new trailer that gives us a better look at new protagonist Atsu, the gang of outlaws she’s trying to kill, and her fierce but adorable companion wolf:<br></p><p>With <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> now on the board we have a much clearer sense of how the second half of the year is shaping up. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-gameplay-new-trailer-gearbox-game-awards-1851720346?_gl=1*wrb8x*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NTQxMzQ2MC4xMjMuMS4xNzQ1NDE1NjI2LjI5LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-gameplay-new-trailer-gearbox-game-awards-1851720346?_gl=1*wrb8x*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NTQxMzQ2MC4xMjMuMS4xNzQ1NDE1NjI2LjI5LjAuMA.."><em>Borderlands 4</em> is out September 23</a></span>, as is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marathon-bungie-runner-extraction-hardcore-1851775956&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-bungie-runner-extraction-hardcore-1851775956">Bungie’s sci-fi extraction shooter <em>Marathon</em></a></span>. Supernatural semi-open world adventure <em>Hell Is Us</em> is also due out that month, while <em>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2</em> is currently TBD for sometime in October after years of delays. <br></p><p>Of course, there’s still a <em>GTA VI</em>-sized blackhole threatening to swallow anything inside its event horizon. Slated only for “fall 2025,” we don’t know exactly when the most anticipated game launch possibly ever is coming out, but it’s safe to assume it won’t be too close to <em>Borderlands 4 </em>which is published by the same parent company. Maybe it will hit <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gta-6-release-october-borderlands-4-take-two-rockstar-1851764006&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-release-october-borderlands-4-take-two-rockstar-1851764006">in late October or early November</a></span>. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gta-6-publishers-delays-avoid-fall-2025-release-ps5-1851772198&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-publishers-delays-avoid-fall-2025-release-ps5-1851772198">Companies have clearly been playing a game of chicken</a></span> to wait and see who blinks first with picking fall release dates, or more optimistically waiting for Rockstar Games to just reveal <em>GTA VI</em>’s actual release date so everyone else can get out of the way. One potential consequence of that strategy, however, is that release dates start piling up on either side of the it. </p><p><em>Ghost of Yotei</em> coming less than two weeks after <em>Marathon </em>already feels like a bit of a pile-up despite them being completely different genres. The former seems likely to be fine whenever it lands, but a paid PVP-only extraction shooter like Bungie’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marathon-price-free-bungie-shooter-pvp-sony-concord-1851775949&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-price-free-bungie-shooter-pvp-sony-concord-1851775949">will need all the help it can get</a></span> in the current hyper-competitive live-service hellscape. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zombie Police: Midsummer Unhappy New Year announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/zombie-police-midsummer-unhappy-new-year-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zombie-police-midsummer-unhappy-new-year-announced-for-pc.1171293/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/zombie-police-midsummer-unhappy-new-year-announced-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A follow-up to Zombie Police: Christmas Dancing with Police Zombies.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Lobstudio [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/lobstudio">Lobstudio</a> has announced detective <a title="Genres > Visual Novel [556 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel">visual novel</a> <em><a title="Games > Zombie Police: Midsummer Unhappy New Year" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/zombie-police-midsummer-unhappy-new-year">Zombie Police: Midsummer Unhappy New Year</a></em>, a follow-up to the 2024-released <em><a title="Games > Zombie Police: Christmas Dancing with Police Zombies [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/zombie-police-christmas-dancing-with-police-zombies">Zombie Police: Christmas Dancing with Police Zombies</a></em>. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,966 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3649840/Zombie_Police_Midsummer_Unhappy_New_Year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> in 2026. <span id="more-960422"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3649840/Zombie_Police_Midsummer_Unhappy_New_Year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>“Old Tradition VS Zombie = ???”</p><p>“Detective Zomby” tackles a mysterious case in the freezing midsummer!</p><p>Akemi Kabane, who solves cases with her extraordinary thinking and <a title="Genres > Action [2,683 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s, and Yasu Tamura, the common-sense guy (?) obsessed with detective dramas who gets swept up in her pace.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>This mismatched duo’s new adventure takes place in Tamura’s hometown, Sanjusanda City, featuring the mysterious “Shimofuri Village” that’s frozen like eternal winter despite being midsummer.</p><p>The darkness hidden in the village, and the truth lurking behind the case. What’s the real story behind the tragedy that unfolded during a VTuber’s live stream?</p><p>Are you ready to challenge the freezing midsummer mystery with the detectives?</p><p>A character-driven detective <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a>, <em>Zombie Police: Midsummer Unhappy New Year</em>.</p><p><strong>How to Play</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Unique Interrogation Through the Special Ability “Zombie Dive”!</strong><ul><li>Dive into witnesses’ minds to investigate cases as a Detective Zomby.</li><li>Jump into people, objects, and even museum exhibits!</li><li>Beetles? Woolly mammoths? Is that really okay?</li></ul></li><li><strong>Complete the “Journal” to Advance Your Investigation!</strong><ul><li>Work with Tamura, a <a title="Companies > crim [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">crim</a>e drama enthusiast, to organize information from collected testimonies.</li><li>Build up his case notes called the “Journal” and piece together your deductions to uncover the full picture of the case!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Gather Evidence, Deduce, and Corner the Culprit!</strong><ul><li><a title="Companies > Experience [211 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the satisfaction of analyzing evidence and testimonies to uncover the truth behind each case.</li><li>Your choices change the story’s ending – aim to discover all possible conclusions!</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>The Immortal “Detective Zomby”</strong> – Because I’m… a zombie, after all! Reckless investigation with an undying body!? Removing her head, sleeping in freezers, drinking poison in one go (!?) to test theories… Solving cases with unconventional methods!</li><li><strong>Comedy Meets Serious!</strong> – While this odd-couple duo engages in amusing banter, a gruesome case unfolds behind the scenes. Your emotions will swing with this perfectly unique atmosphere! Enjoy the comedy-mystery that only “Zombie Police” can deliver.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 GameCube Controller Works Outside Of Switch Online, But Could Run Into "Issues"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-gamecube-controller-works-outside-of-switch-online-but-could-run-into-issues/1100-6531045/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-gamecube-controller-works-outside-of-switch-online-but-could-run-into-issues.1171287/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-gamecube-controller-works-outside-of-switch-online-but-could-run-into-issues/1100-6531045/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531045">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nintendo confirmed that the GameCube Controller designed for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Nintendo Switch 2</a> will be compatible with games outside of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-gamecube-game-coming-to-switch-2s-switch-online-library/2900-6400/" data-ref-id="2900-6400">Switch Online GameCube Classics library</a>, but some issues may arise when using it in that way.</p><p>In a statement to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/04/switch-2-gamecube-controller-compatible-with-other-games-but-there-may-be-some-issues" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo Life</a>, Nintendo explained that the controller is designed for use with classic games, so issues may arise when using it with other games. This confirms its compatibility with other Switch 2 software, although Nintendo is getting ahead of any problems that arise with that by pointing out that there could be issues. Hopefully, it at least works with games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/super-smash-bros-ultimate/" data-ref-id="5000-480957">Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</a> on Switch 2.</p><p>"The Nintendo GameCube controller is designed for use with the Nintendo GameCube – Nintendo Classics collection of games and is an optional way to play those games," Nintendo's full statement explains. "Since it doesn’t have all the buttons and features found in other controllers that can be used with the Nintendo Switch 2 system, there may be some issues when playing other games. The Nintendo GameCube controller can only be used on Nintendo Switch 2 and is not compatible with Nintendo Switch."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0MvkSVs8f_w" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0MvkSVs8f_w" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The Switch 2's GameCube controller was revealed alongside the addition of GameCube games to Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack during the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/switch-2-nintendo-direct-april-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6391/" data-ref-id="2900-6391">April 2 Switch 2 Direct</a>. It features a very similar layout to the original GameCube controller, but works wirelessly and has the Home, Capture, C, and ZL buttons present on the Joy-Con 2 controllers. A disclaimer in one of Nintendo's trailers suggested that the Switch 2's GameCube Controller wouldn't work with other games, which is why Nintendo had to clarify this in the first place.</p><p>This new GameCube controller will become available for preorder on the My Nintendo Store the same day as Nintendo Switch 2. Currently, that date appears to be May 8. You should also check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">GameSpot's Switch 2 preorder guide</a> if you plan on picking up Nintendo's new system.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devolver Digital lays off almost half of Reigns studio Nerial]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/devolver-digital-lays-off-almost-half-of-reigns-studio-nerial</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/devolver-digital-lays-off-almost-half-of-reigns-studio-nerial.1171284/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/devolver-digital-lays-off-almost-half-of-reigns-studio-nerial<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>To "address issues around recent releases".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/reigns-2-doe.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nerial</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Indie publisher <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/devolver-digital">Devolver Digital</a> has cut staff at Reigns developer Nerial by 40 percent.</p>
<p>In Devolver Digital's <a href="https://investors.devolverdigital.com/files/downloads-and-publications/DEVO-FY24-Investor-Presentation.pdf">FY24 investor presentation</a>, the publisher explained Nerial had "undergone a team restructure" which aimed to "address issues around recent releases and to better shape the team for future releases".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="8 Wholesome 2025 Cosy Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cnh2QCkzw90?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>8 Wholesome 2025 Cosy Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cnh2QCkzw90?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cnh2QCkzw90?autoplay=1" title="8 Wholesome 2025 Cosy Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eight wholesome 2025 cosy games. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cnh2QCkzw90" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In the same presentation, Devolver Digital said it had downsized its Polish studio Artificer by 50 percent early last year.</p>
<p>"Good Shepherd / Big Fan also reduced its headcount by 50 percent + over the course of 2024," it wrote. "Overall group headcount has reduced from a peak of 303 at end 2023 to c. 270 now, including the above reductions."</p>
<p>Nerial is one of Devolver Digital's internal studios, which it acquired in 2021. As reported by <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/devolver-cuts-40-percent-of-workforce-at-reigns-developer-nerial">Game Developer</a>, Nerial's Reigns franchises is one the publisher's most successful, earning over $20m in lifetime revenue across five titles.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/REIGNS-DEER-in-a-crown.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nerial</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Along with its Reigns games, Nerial is also known for its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-crush-house-is-a-thirst-person-shooter-that-holds-a-mirror-to-reality-tv-production">"thirst-person shooter" The Crush House</a> (pictured below), which was released last year, as well as Card Shark.</p>
<p>"Even though some parts might momentarily break the illusion, The Crush House maintains its shiny sheen of plastic perfection (one that hides a dark, sickly goo inside). It touches upon multiple facets of reality TV with sharp satire and wit, including the nature of the relationships we have with contestants on these shows, the industrial churn of people and their lives for our entertainment, and the truth of what's captured on screen impacting what's happening when the cameras are off," reads <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-crush-house-review">Eurogamer's four star The Crush House review</a>.</p>
<p>"You'll definitely want to tune in for this one."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CrushHouse-Keyart_Horizontal.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Devolver Digital</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for Card Shark, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/card-shark-review-scoundrels-and-intrigue-delivered-with-a-flourish">here is what Christian Donlan had to say about it</a>: "Card Shark is brilliant. It's a game about card games, but it isn't a card game itself - not really. It's a game about tricks, but you're in a world of con artists rather than magicians."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Slapped with €500m Fine in Ongoing Battle with Epic Games]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-apple-500-million-euro-fine</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apple-slapped-with-%E2%82%AC500m-fine-in-ongoing-battle-with-epic-games.1171257/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-apple-500-million-euro-fine<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Apple has been ordered to pay a fine of&nbsp;€500 million and make changes to the way its iOS store works as part of its ongoing legal battle with&nbsp;<em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em>studio Epic Games.</p>

<p>In a news <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/site/en-US/news/apple-is-breaking-the-law-by-charging-fees-for-steering-imposing-restrictions-on-third-party-stores" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on its website, Epic reveals that the European Commission has <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_25_1085" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">found</a>&nbsp;Apple to be in breach of the Digital Markets Act (DMA), which requires the iPhone maker to "inform customers, free of charge, of alternative offers outside the App Store".</p>

<p>As part of the DMA, Apple must also "steer [customers] to those offers and allow them to make purchases", an obligation with which the European Commission believes Apple "fails to comply". The Commission says Apple "prevents app developers" from informing customers about alternative offers and distribution channels.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/apple-epic-european-commission-fortnite.jpg?itok=nL_9tJEl 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/apple-epic-european-commission-fortnite.jpg?itok=qPrGULfx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Apple's battle with Epic has resulted in another blow to the Cupertino tech giant.</figcaption></figure><p>Today's ruling means that Apple must "remove the technical and commercial restrictions on steering" (i.e. allowing developers to recommend other offers and non-iOS alternatives to customers) and "refrain from perpetuating the non-compliant conduct in the future".</p>

<p>According to Epic, changes Apple must make include the removal of fees imposed on purchases made outside of an iOS app, as well as the elimination of "restrictions on the language, style and flow that developers can use to link to their website or to access an alternative payment system".</p>

<p>If you need a reminder of where all this started, it's been running since 2020, when Epic <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fortnite-slashes-up-to-20-off-purchases-on-all-platforms" rel="nofollow">decided to offer a discount</a> on in-game&nbsp;<em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em>purchases across all platforms, but only if using a new direct payment system introduced by the company at the time.</p>

<p>Apple took umbrage at this decision and removed&nbsp;<em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em>from the iOS App Store, prompting Epic to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fortnite-apple-store-version-removed-for-violating-app-store-guidelines" rel="nofollow">file a lawsuit in response</a>. Google, the owner of the Android operating system, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-sues-google-over-fortnites-removal-from-play-store" rel="nofollow">took similar measures</a> and was also sued by Epic.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/fortnite-mobile-epic-apple-european-commission.jpg?itok=pYA66nQy 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/fortnite-mobile-epic-apple-european-commission.jpg?itok=nia3XVmp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>All of this started as part of a row over alternative payment systems within&nbsp;<em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em>on mobile.</figcaption></figure><p>The saga has essentially been running since then, but Epic <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-google-victory-play-store" rel="nofollow">won another pretty significant victory</a> back in October, this time against Google. As part of the ongoing case, a judge ruled that Google must open up its Play Store to third-party apps and give "rival third-party app stores access to the full catalog of Google Play apps".</p>

<p>That ruling referred specifically to the Epic Games Store's availability on Android rather than alternative payment systems, but since Epic would rather funnel players through its own store and payment systems than Google or Apple's, it's all connected.</p>

<p>We'll have to wait and see what today's ruling means for Epic and Apple in the future. In the meantime, you can still play <i>Fortnite&nbsp;</i>on mobile devices, although you'll need to download the Epic Games Store app to do so.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yōtei hits the PS5 in October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/654227/ghost-of-yotei-ps5-release-date-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-y%C5%8Dtei-hits-the-ps5-in-october.1171254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/654227/ghost-of-yotei-ps5-release-date-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-webster">Andrew Webster</a> <span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>One of the year’s biggest PlayStation 5 games is launching this fall: <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/04/23/ghost-of-yotei-comes-to-playstation-5-on-october-2/">Sony just announced</a> that <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/24/24253576/ghost-of-tsushima-2-yotei-ps5-pro-2025">Ghost of Yōtei</a></em> will hit the PS5 on October 2nd. The news was accompanied by a fresh trailer that’s mostly dramatic samurai cinematics, but also some brief glimpses of its bloody combat and traversing the beautiful landscape on horseback.</p><p>The follow up to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/21323144/ghost-of-tsushima-review-ps4-game-developer-samurai">2020’s <em>Ghost of Tsushima</em></a> from developer Sucker Punch, <em>Yōtei</em> features a new samurai protagonist called Atsu, who is, naturally, on a quest for revenge. The trailer introduces a gang of outlaws, and her ultimate goal is to find and eliminate all six. “One by one, she’s hunting them down to avenge her family,” the official description reads. “But while Atsu’s story begins with vengeance, she’ll find there’s more to her journey than just revenge. As she explores Ezo, Atsu will meet unlikely allies and forge connections that help give her a new sense of purpose.”</p><p>The game’s structure sounds fairly open, as Sony says “you’ll choose which leads to follow as you pick which Yōtei Six member you want to hunt down first.”</p><p><em>Ghost of Yōtei</em> is one of s small number of major exclusives planned for the PS5 this year. It will follow the launch of <em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</em>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/610946/death-stranding-2-trailer-ps5-state-of-play-on-the-beach">which comes out on June 26th</a>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Colony simulation reverse RPG Gold Gold Adventure Gold limited-time demo now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/colony-simulation-reverse-rpg-gold-gold-adventure-gold-limited-time-demo-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/colony-simulation-reverse-rpg-gold-gold-adventure-gold-limited-time-demo-now-available.1171245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/colony-simulation-reverse-rpg-gold-gold-adventure-gold-limited-time-demo-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A demo for colony <a title="Genres > Simulation [717 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation</a> / reverse <a title="Genres > RPG [17,185 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Gold Gold Adventure Gold" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gold-gold-adventure-gold">Gold Gold Adventure Gold</a></em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,966 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3133650/Gold_Gold_Adventure_Gold/" target="_blank">Steam</a> until May 19, developer <a title="Companies > Can Can Can a Man" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/can-can-can-a-man">Can Can Can a Man</a> announced. <span id="more-960027"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Can Can Can a Man:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In this chaotic colony sim / reverse RPG, you’re sent to the wilderness to build a settlement around a monster-filled dungeon. Choose your path—build an economy based on farming or profit from monster-slaying (either way, don’t forget to collect taxes). Recruit adventurers and send them on quests to kill, defend, explore, and more. After all, everyone knows the only thing adventurers love more than glory… is gold.</p><p>With no army and no budget, you’ll have to throw gold at every problem and hope your hired heroes survive long enough to gear up, grow stronger, and maybe evolve into something more. If they don’t? Feed them to the pet god-beast you found snacking on your supplies. It’s growing faster than expected—so raise it, teach it spells or tricks, pet it, brush it, and if necessary, discipline it. Treat it well, and it just might become a trusted companion on your journey. Run the town, fund the chaos, and hope your gold lasts longer than your heroes.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Give <a title="Platforms > Quest [138 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a>s</strong> – Everyone knows that adventurers do not work for free. Their loyalty lies with GOLD! You’ll have to recruit them with promises of gold or glory, and give them quests! Kill, defend, explore, and more!</li><li><strong>Recruit Unique <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a>rs</strong> – Gold-thirsty adventurers will come from all corners of the world. Humans, beastmen, mothmen, undead, and more may join your cause. Pick them all, or only your favorites!</li><li><strong>Build a City</strong> – Build a thriving city around a monster-filled dungeon. Create an economy based on either farming or monster-slaying, and watch as it evolves based on your <a title="Genres > Action [2,683 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s. Whatever you choose, remember to collect your share of the taxes!</li><li><strong>Raise a Pet God-Beast</strong> – The pet you found snacking on your supplies seems to be growing more than expected. Far more. It might be wise to teach it what is right and wrong, before it grows too big to care about your opinions. Raise it, teach it spells or tricks, pet it, brush it, and if necessary discipline it. You might find that it becomes a trusted companion on your journey!</li><li><strong>Fight Monsters</strong> – As your adventurers clear the world of monsters, you can watch their pathetic struggle against the world. Be merciful and help them survive, get better items, and learn new skills… or feed them to your god-beast. Each level brings them one step closer towards a forbidden evolution.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>