<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 20:54:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country announced at the end of Opening Night Live]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/mafia-the-old-country-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-announced-at-the-end-of-opening-night-live.958830/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/mafia-the-old-country-trailer/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Rumours of a new Mafia game have been floating around for a while and they have now been confirmed with the reveal of Mafia: The Old Country. This time you will be heading to the 1900s Sicily underworld and the game will be out on PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC via Steam.</p>
<p><iframe title="Mafia: The Old Country - Official Teaser Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>“Uncover the origins of organized crime with a gritty mob story set in the brutal underworld of 1900s Sicily. Fight to survive in this dangerous and unforgiving era, with action brought to life by the authentic realism and rich storytelling that the critically acclaimed&nbsp;<em>Mafia</em> series is known for.”</p>
<p>“Across the first three entries in the&nbsp;<em>Mafia</em>&nbsp;franchise, we introduced players to the world of the Mafia through brutal stories set in different eras,” said Nick Baynes, President of Hangar 13. “In&nbsp;<em>Mafia: The Old Country</em>, we’re going back to the roots of what fans love about the franchise, crafting a deep, linear narrative with that classic mob movie feeling, visiting a stunning new setting, and delivering it all in a tight, focused package perfect for fans of immersive experiences.”</p>
<p>A full reveal of the game will occur in December, so I would guess that would be at The Game Awards 2024.</p>


<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=crDUx5suLm4">YouTube</a> / <a href="https://newsroom.2k.com/news/uncover-the-origins-of-organized-crime-in-mafia-the-old-country-coming-in-2025">2K</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones is coming to PS5, but only after Xbox and PC December release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/indiana-jones-is-coming-to-ps5-but-only-after-xbox-and-pc-december-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-is-coming-to-ps5-but-only-after-xbox-and-pc-december-release.958824/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/indiana-jones-is-coming-to-ps5-but-only-after-xbox-and-pc-december-release/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Well, there we go. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> <em>is</em> coming to PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>After months and months of only talking about the game in terms of Xbox Series X|S and PC, MachineGames had Geoff Keighley do the dirty work and confirm that the Indy adventure will also come to PlayStation 5, as part of Microsoft’s broadening push for cross-platform gaming.</p>


<p>However, there will still be a period of exclusivity. Indiana Jones and the Great Circle comes to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X|S</a> and PC on 9th &nbsp;December 2025 – and on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Xbox Game Pass Utlimate</a> of course, while you can play three days early by pre-ordering the Premium Edition, Premium Edition Upgrade, or Collector’s Edition. The PlayStation 5 port will traipse along a few months later in Spring 2025.</p>
<p>Here’s a new trailer with Troy Baker exploring the world in which he will take on the role of Indiana Jones:</p>
<p><iframe title="Gamescom Date Reveal Trailer - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/STrKl828Aeg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>This will only further the rumours that Microsoft will bring practically everything to PlayStation 5 in the fullness of time – rumours earlier this year already suggested that <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/02/05/rumours-grow-of-starfield-indiana-jones-more-xbox-games-coming-to-ps5/">Indiana Jones was on the way over, alongside Starfield</a>, and potentially even Halo.</p>

<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is a mixed first and third person action adventure set between Raiders of the Lost Arc and The Last Crusade in 1937, and includes characters from the original film returning including Doctor Marcus Brody, originally played by Denholm Elliott. Doctor Jones is working late at Marshall College but is woken up late to find a rather imposing thief stealing a sacred relic. He then heads to Vatican to figure out why that one particular relic was stolen. From there the story will take players to Sukhothai, the Pyramids, the Himalayas and beyond.</p>
<p>The iconic whip naturally makes an appearance and can be used for attacking enemies to stun them, pull their legs and more, as a distraction in stealth, or for swinging around the environments, and there will be plenty of puzzles for Indy to solve. While it’s mainly a first person game, it will swap to third person when certain actions are performed, such as climbing, and for cutscenes.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FuzzyBot Unveils New Title ‘Lynked: Banner of the Spark’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fuzzybot-unveils-new-title-lynked-banner-of-the-spark/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fuzzybot-unveils-new-title-%E2%80%98lynked-banner-of-the-spark%E2%80%99.958818/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fuzzybot-unveils-new-title-lynked-banner-of-the-spark/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ma0FpzjPmBs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gamescom Opening Night Live</a>, FuzzyBot unveiled their debut title, Lynked: Banner of the Spark. This game is an arcade-inspired co-op action where playing together can both be a help and a hindrance. You get to brawl with a friend and build and befriend other characters in the game when a town-builder meets hack-and-slash with roguelite elements sprinkled in.</p>
<p>Gamescom 2024 is shaping up to be one of the biggest events<span>. Xbox will have its "biggest booth yet," as will some other huge names such as Larian Studios, AMD,</span>&nbsp;and more.</p>
<p>For those wanting to get their hands on this game, Lynked: Banner of the Spark will be in Early Access as of October 22, 2024. The game will be available for purchase for $24.99. For those who want to get a bit more of an insight into what the game has to offer, check out the official announcement trailer below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lynked: Banner of the Spark | Official Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C9f4uzx7i74?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The game takes place in the year 30XX, with humanity verging on extinction. You play as one of the last remaining survivors, where you must form alliances with the robot resistance to try and defend the world against Combots. To be able to fight off against the Combots, you must rescue Robot allies, explore their stories, and work towards uncovering the fate of the legendary group of robots known as the Banner of the Spark.</p>
<p>In an announcement statement, Max Spielberg, the Co-Founder and Game Director of FuzzyBot, said, "We got tired of building dark, gory games, so we formed FuzzyBot to make fun, vibrant worlds with a ton of action. We're super proud to share the world of Lynked: Banner of the Spark with everyone! And honestly, we're just excited we finally got to make a fishing minigame..."</p>
<p>Lynked: Banner of the Spark features high-paced action with plenty of hack-and-slash combat, where roguelites inspire the missions. You'll be able to power up your character with mid-run upgrades, making your fight against the Combots easier as you go along. The more you progress, the more weapons you unlock, giving you the perfect playstyle to aid your journey.</p>
<p>If you manage to complete a run, you can use your gathered tools and resources to help build up your town while enlisting the help of your fellow robot allies. The in-town system features a slew of mini-games, including gathering, fishing, and farming, which will benefit you and your town's citizens.</p>
<p>You can either decide to play the game solo, or you can play it and complete missions with up to two other friends, where you can choose your specialized fighting roles that can enhance your team's synergy while completing challenges and boss battles.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 Early Access on November 15]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-early-access-on-november-15/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-early-access-on-november-15.958815/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-early-access-on-november-15/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In a new trailer shown at Gamescom 2024, Grinding Gear Games gave players a glimpse into some of the high-intensity bosses that populate the world of Wraeclast in Path of Exile 2. In addition to showing off the game's content, Grinding Gear has also announced that it is coming to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2694490/Path_of_Exile_2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Early Access</a> on November 15.</p>
<p><iframe title="Path of Exile 2 - Early Access Date Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eYaSU9UCe0w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Path of Exile 2 was initially announced in 2019 and has been developing since then. It was initially announced as a large update for the original game but has since become its own game, and it will be available for players to get stuck into this year.</p>
<p>It's been a long time coming, with the original game continuing to get patches that balance out the game and certain abilities or traits that players will access throughout their time in the game.</p>
<p>While Path of Exile 2 is shaping into a huge game, the plan is still free-to-play, likely with microtransactions available. These will probably be in the form of bag space and cosmetics, similar to the microtransactions currently available for Path of Exile.</p>
<p>Path of Exile 2 will feature 12 character classes, with two for every combination of Strength, Dexterity, and intelligence. With each of the twelve character classes, there are also three Ascendancy specializations, which gives players a grand total of 36 Ascendancy Classes to pick between.</p>
<p>Path of Exile is notoriously known for its extensive skill tree, and it will return in Path of Exile 2. There will be 1,500 skills to choose from, allowing you to customize your gameplay experience. However, the skill tree now includes Dual Specialization, which will enable you to allocate passive skill points to two sets of skills. For example, this allows you to have points assigned to both ice and lightning.</p>
<p>This new game will also be home to 700 equipment base types, each with its unique item that you can obtain. You can now use new weapons such as Spears, Crossbows, Flails, and the usual supplementary items like Focuses, Traps, and Sceptres.</p>
<p>Path of Exile 2 is shaping up to be a huge overhaul of the first game, adding bigger and better bosses throughout the Campaign for you to fight, whether you play the<a href="https://wccftech.com/path-of-exile-2-launches-this-year-in-early-access-on-pc-and-consoles-with-couch-co-op-cross-play-progression/"> game solo</a> or engage in tactile combat alongside your friends.</p>
<p>Players will get to engage in a six-act campaign, where you'll then be able to access the endgame, with more than 100 endgame maps to work your way through. Grinding Gear Games has promised to showcase more of the endgame maps closer to the full release date of Path of Exile 2.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones And The Great Circle releases December 9th, will hopefully contain gameplay by that point]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-december-9th-will-hopefully-contain-gameplay-by-that-point</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-december-9th-will-hopefully-contain-gameplay-by-that-point.958812/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-december-9th-will-hopefully-contain-gameplay-by-that-point<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Just in time for December 10th</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Archive_s3riFFc.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microsoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Oh, and new <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones And The Great Circle</a> trailer! Great. I’ve been looking forward to a nice, juicy chunk of extended gameplay. You know, something to really convey the flow of the game, rather than the admittedly impressive but nonetheless very fragmented snippets we’ve gotten so far. Now to sit back and…oh, wait. Hang on. It’s just actor Troy Baker telling me about all the great acting he’ll be doing. It is great, by the way. He’s doing a fantastic job. Maybe just, you know, a crumb of acknowledgement or elucidation over the whole ‘interactivity’ part?</p>
<p>Anyway, don’t mind me. I’m just an old fool who likes to press buttons. And, to be fair, it's not like Machinegames don't have a great track record. Anyway, here’s some good news: The game releases December 9th this year. Have a release date trailer.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Gamescom Date Reveal Trailer - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/STrKl828Aeg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Gamescom Date Reveal Trailer - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/STrKl828Aeg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/STrKl828Aeg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=STrKl828Aeg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Hang on, turns out I’m talking shit. This has literally never happened before! Said longed-for elucidation does actually exist, and on this very website, no less! Edwin had a chinwag with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-both-a-more-relaxed-wolfenstein-and-riddick-plus-nazis">game director Jerk Gustafsson</a>, and reckons the game will be both “a more ‘relaxed’ Wolfenstein and Riddick plus Nazis”. Not too shabby!</p>
<p>“Larger setups give you the option of being sneaky or violent, boffing guards in a particular order and hiding the bodies, or making use of the fittings. You can lob spears to create surfaces to swing from, for example,” wrote Edwin “You also have the option of donning a disguise - there are story episodes that require it, and you'll build up a wardrobe of outfits you can change to suit the situation. One particular scenario might have you playing the servant and bringing wine to a rancorous fascist. I don't get the impression this is an Agent 47-grade exercise in social camouflage, though the idea of a Hitman level set in one of Indy's tombs with a cast of stymied stormtroopers has a certain appeal.”</p>
<hr>
<p><em>For more of the latest news and previews from Gamescom 2024, head to our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2024">Gamescom 2024 hub</a>.</em></p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Batman: Arkham Shadow Looks Like The Batman Games You Love In First-Person]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/batman-arkham-vr-looks-good-1851627260</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/batman-arkham-shadow-looks-like-the-batman-games-you-love-in-first-person.958800/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/batman-arkham-vr-looks-good-1851627260<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hey, so I know that a bunch of us actually <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;opi=89978449&amp;url=https://kotaku.com/facebook-meta-1-billion-every-month-loss-vr-metaverse-1851438748&amp;ved=2ahUKEwi95MX9rYSIAxVRE1kFHd66LjAQFnoECBQQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw20bYqksy4T0Izju1f9b1G5&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;opi=89978449&amp;url=https://kotaku.com/facebook-meta-1-billion-every-month-loss-vr-metaverse-1851438748&amp;ved=2ahUKEwi95MX9rYSIAxVRE1kFHd66LjAQFnoECBQQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw20bYqksy4T0Izju1f9b1G5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">don’t have VR or are all that interested</a></span> in getting into it, but that new <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;opi=89978449&amp;url=https://kotaku.com/batman-arkham-shadow-meta-quest-3-vr-release-date-1851448597&amp;ved=2ahUKEwi95MX9rYSIAxVRE1kFHd66LjAQFnoECDkQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw26ljOGDZh7qIhHPKVoeRLB&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;opi=89978449&amp;url=https://kotaku.com/batman-arkham-shadow-meta-quest-3-vr-release-date-1851448597&amp;ved=2ahUKEwi95MX9rYSIAxVRE1kFHd66LjAQFnoECDkQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw26ljOGDZh7qIhHPKVoeRLB" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VR Arkham <em>Batman </em>game</a></span> looks pretty good, right? Shown off at Gamescom Opening Night Live 2024,<em> Batman: Arkham Shadow </em>seems like a pretty decent follow-up to the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/batman-arkham-gotham-knights-suicide-squad-assassins-cr-1848911270&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/batman-arkham-gotham-knights-suicide-squad-assassins-cr-1848911270">Arkhamverse</a></span>, and one done in an entirely new way.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195859" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: What’s Coming Out Beyond Marvel's Spider-Man 2" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="123" data-playlist="195859,195896,196394" data-current="195859"><div><p>The Week In Games: What’s Coming Out Beyond Marvel's Spider-Man 2</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195859/195859_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195859/195859_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195859/195859_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195859/195859_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21379.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The thing that was always working against this game was going to be the constraints of VR. In the past, VR experiences have been pretty limited, but what everyone loved about the <em>Arkham </em>games was how much players felt like they could inhabit the Batsuit. You were able to move, talk, and fight like Batman, fulfilling the childhood dreams of millions. To trnslate that into VR, players would have to be able to feel like they<em>&nbsp;</em>were in the iconic hero’s boots.<br></p><p>At first glance, <em>Arkham Shadow </em>appears to get things right. It  follows the pursuit of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kU-0N1b-6ns&amp;ab_channel=messody&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kU-0N1b-6ns&amp;ab_channel=messody" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the Rat King</a></span> in a direct sequel to the Warner Bros. developed prequel, <em>Batman: Arkham Origins</em>, and passes on vibes alone. However, the game also looks pretty great in motion. Movement doesn’t seem to be limited, and it even features an adapted version of the <em>Arkham</em> series’ signature freeflow combat. From the moment that the trailer begins, we’re treated to first-person scenes of Batman grappling an enemy close to him and then uppercutting them into the air. A few seconds later, Batman is on a perch (as he often is in these games) and punching a goon’s lights out before letting them dangle for their friends to see.</p><p>Additional scenes show off other familiar sights, such as the ability to glide through the city streets, fly into enemies and greet them with a divekick, and even get a glimpse at how detective vision will work. In first-person combat, you appear to be able to use all of Batman’s same old tricks, including Batarangs and his explosive gel. When an enemy goes to attack him, the HUD shows the blue counter icon found across the <em>Arkham </em>series as well as indicator as to where the attack is coming from, just in case the foe isn’t onscreen. A lock-on function looks to help close gaps and be more accurate with your strikes in virtual reality. <br></p><p>The <em>Arkham Shadows</em> trailer also<em> </em>provides a small glimpses at how puzzles and movement work. In one scene, Batman toggles his detective vision to be able to look over a crime scene and find a hidden compartment. <em>This </em>is the good shit that’ll have people champing at the bit to dive into a new Batman game, and might even sell people on VR. <br></p><p>I’m not one of those folks who are antsy to jump into VR. In fact, I’ve often balked against the whole medium for its inaccessibility, but even I’ve got to admit that <em>Arkham Shadow </em>looks quite good. Maybe not enough to make me buy a headset entirely to play it, but if experiences of this depth are becoming more widely available in VR, I don’t see why I shouldn’t splurge on it sometime down the line.<br></p><p><em>Batman: Arkham Shadow </em>is coming to Meta Quest 3 later this year in October. <br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Mafia Game Announced, Launching Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-the-old-country-trailer-gamescom-hangar-13-2k-1851627259</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-mafia-game-announced-launching-next-year.958797/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-the-old-country-trailer-gamescom-hangar-13-2k-1851627259<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="a6a29b8811d233677fe5c676377237d0" data-recommend-id="image://a6a29b8811d233677fe5c676377237d0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / 2K Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a6a29b8811d233677fe5c676377237d0" data-recommend-id="image://a6a29b8811d233677fe5c676377237d0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Today, during Gamescom Opening Night Live, 2K Games and Hangar 13 announced <em>Mafia: The Old Country</em>, the next main entry in the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mafia-iii-the-kotaku-review-1787722761&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mafia-iii-the-kotaku-review-1787722761">long-running open-world series</a></span> about gangsters.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196394" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="97" data-playlist="196394,196470,196299" data-current="196394"><div><p>The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21942.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>This new game in the franchise is set in Sicily during the early 1900s and appears to be taking the <em>Mafia </em>series back to its roots, showing the very early days of the mob and how it was formed. “Uncover the origins of organized crime in <em>Mafia: The Old Country</em>, a gritty mob story set in the brutal underworld of 1900s Sicily,” is how 2K and Hangar 13 describe the newly announced game.</p><p> Here’s the first trailer for the new <em>Mafia </em>sequel: </p><p><em>Mafia: The Old Country</em> is set to arrive sometime in 2025 on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC. There wasn’t much more revealed during the short teaser that premiered at Gamescom, but 2K is promising more information will be revealed in December 2024. I’d expect <em>Mafia: The Old Country—</em>and a new trailer<em>—</em>to make an appearance at this year’s big Game Awards event. But we’ll have to wait and see. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-release-date-hangar-13-haden-blackman-lucasarts-1848883555&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-release-date-hangar-13-haden-blackman-lucasarts-1848883555">As we previously reported in 2022</a></span>, the new <em>Mafia </em>game is a prequel of sorts and has been in the works at Hangar 13 for some time now. The game is reportedly ditching the engine that Hangar 13 created and used on <em>Mafia 3 </em>and the <em>Mafia: Definitive Edition</em> and the studio is moving to Unreal Engine. While in development the game was codenamed “Nero.” </p><p>It has been a rough few years for Hangar 13. After shipping <em>Mafia III </em>in 2016<em>,</em> it suffered two rounds of layoffs. The studio worked on several new IPs during this time. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/how-the-makers-of-mafia-iii-lost-their-way-1825242177&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/how-the-makers-of-mafia-iii-lost-their-way-1825242177">As previously reported by <em>Kotaku</em></a></span><em>, </em>one was a spy game revolving around music cues called <em>Rhapsody</em>. Another was a class-based co-op action game <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/take-two-cancels-unannounced-53-million-dollar-game-by-1847992907&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/take-two-cancels-unannounced-53-million-dollar-game-by-1847992907">code-named “Volt</a></span>.” That project was quietly killed by parent company Take-Two last year after more than $50 million had already been spent on it. A third new IP, a looter-shooter code-named “Mosaic” was also reportedly abandoned before it was ever officially revealed.</p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country Announced At Opening Night Live]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-the-old-country-announced-at-opening-night-live/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-announced-at-opening-night-live.958791/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-the-old-country-announced-at-opening-night-live/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-53701">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>At the end of Gamescom Opening Night Live on Tuesday, 2K closed out the show with the announcement of Mafia: The Old Country.</p>



<p>Developed in Unreal Engine 5, the game is set to launch in 2025 with a deeper reveal coming this December.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Mafia: The Old Country - Official Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>“Uncover the origins of organized crime in Mafia: The Old Country, a gritty mob story set in the brutal underworld of 1900s Sicily,” the trailer’s description reads. </p>



<p>“Fight to survive in this dangerous and unforgiving era, with action brought to life by the authentic realism and rich storytelling that the critically acclaimed Mafia series is known for.”</p>



<h6 id="h-related-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-release-date-revealed-at-gamescom-onl">RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-release-date-revealed-at-gamescom-onl/">Indiana Jones And the Great Circle Release Date Revealed at Gamescom ONL</a></h6>



<p>The development of Mafia: The Old Country <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-4-prequel/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has been known</a> for some time now. However, it had never been announced in any sort of official capacity by Take-Two Interactive and 2K.</p>



<p>When it releases, the game will be available for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of Mafia: The Old Country coming from 2K? For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/civilization-7-release-date-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date for Civilization 7</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-release-date-revealed-at-gamescom-onl/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-release-date-revealed-at-gamescom-onl/">Indiana Jones And the Great Circle Release Date Revealed at Gamescom ONL</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The release date for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle was announced at Gamescom 2024’s opening night live. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mercenaries-diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-gamescom-trailer/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mercenaries-diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-gamescom-trailer/">A Fresh Look at Mercenaries in the Diablo 4: Vessel of Hatred Gamescom Trailer</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>After checking out the latest Gamescom trailer for Diablo 4, which mercenary will you hire first?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squid-game-unleashed-unveiled-at-gamescom-2024/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squid-game-unleashed-unveiled-at-gamescom-2024/">Squid Game: Unleashed Unveiled at Gamescom 2024</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Netlfix Games has officially unveiled its upcoming multiplayer title, Squid Game: Unleashed, at Gamescom 2024. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/peter-molyneux-masters-of-albion-opening-night-live/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/peter-molyneux-masters-of-albion-opening-night-live/">Peter Molyneux Reveals Masters of Albion at Opening Night Live</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Peter Molyneux returns with a self-funded project set in a fantasy world!</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/mafia-the-old-country-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.958788/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/mafia-the-old-country-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A gritty mob story set in the underworld of 1900s Sicily.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > 2K [642 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/take-two-interactive-software/2k">2K</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Hangar 13 [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/take-two-interactive-software/2k/hangar-13">Hangar 13</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Mafia: The Old Country" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mafia-the-old-country">Mafia: The Old Country</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,716 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,881 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,962 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1941540/Mafia_The_Old_Country/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch in 2025. <span id="more-907727"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via 2K:</p><blockquote><p>Uncover the origins of organized <a title="Companies > crim [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">crim</a>e in <em>Mafia: The Old Country</em>, a gritty mob story set in the brutal underworld of 1900s Sicily.</p><p>Fight to survive in this dangerous and unforgiving era, with action brought to life by the authentic realism and rich storytelling that the critically acclaimed Mafia series is known for.</p></blockquote><p>More information about <em>Mafia: The Old Country</em> will be announced in December.</p><p>Watch the announcement teaser trailer below.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Announce Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Mafia: The Old Country - Official Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unknown 9: Awakening launches October 18]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/unknown-9-awakening-launches-october-18</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/unknown-9-awakening-launches-october-18.958782/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/unknown-9-awakening-launches-october-18<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Available in standard, Deluxe Digital, and Collector's editions.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Action [2,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,675 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Unknown 9: Awakening [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/unknown-9-awakening">Unknown 9: Awakening</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,716 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,881 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,072 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,404 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,962 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1477940/Unknown_9_Awakening/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on October 18, publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,548 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Reflector Entertainment [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment/reflector-entertainment">Reflector Entertainment</a> announced. <span id="more-907722"></span></p><p>The game is available for pre-order now in the following editions:</p><ul><li>Standard Edition (base game, pre-order bonus cosmetic downloadable content) – $49.99 / £44.99 / €49.99</li><li>Deluxe Digital Edition (base game, pre-order bonus cosmetic downloadable content, all other downloadable content) – $59.99 / £49.99 / €59.99</li><li>Collector’s Edition (base game, pre-order bonus cosmetic downloadable content, all other downloadable content, Quaestor’s journal, Haroona’s amulet replica, Collector’s coin, and metal case)</li></ul><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Bandai Namco:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Delve into the mysterious world of the <em>Unknown 9</em>, and uncover mysteries hidden in plain sight.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>You are Haroona, a Quaestor born with the ability to venture into a mysterious dimension that overlaps our own, known only as the Fold. On her quest for powerful hidden knowledge, Haroona will learn to master her unique connection to the Fold, which allows her to channel its powers into our world… But such power does not go unnoticed and Haroona quickly becomes the target of a splinter faction calling themselves the Ascendants, who want to use the Fold to alter the course of human history.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Become Haroona</strong> – Play as a young and courageous woman who has the ability to dive into and channel powers from a parallel dimension known as the Fold.</li><li><strong>Master the Fold</strong> – Leverage your mastery of the Fold and choose your own playstyle. Step into your enemies to control them, dodge bullets, vanish in plain sight, hurl Umbric energy at your opponents, and more.</li><li><strong>Journey Across the world</strong> – From the sands of Mauritania and perilous Indian jungles to the gothic landscapes of 19th century Portugal, discover some of the most mysterious locations the world has to offer.</li><li><strong>Discover the <em>Unknown 9</em> Universe</strong> – <em>Unknown 9: Awakening</em> lies at the heart of intertwining stories, unfolding through a multitude of <em>Unknown 9</em> products whose events and characters make up a much larger Storyworld.</li></ul></blockquote><h2><span>Live-Action Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Unknown 9: Awakening – Live Action Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0QgaV3cZwVI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Great Circle is Indiana Jones for a post-Uncharted world]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2044166</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-great-circle-is-indiana-jones-for-a-post-uncharted-world.958779/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/?p=2044166<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
                                    
<figure>
  
      <figcaption><p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Archive-scaled.jpg" data-height="1440" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> <span>/</span> A time traveler with a flashlight would blow Indiana Jones' mind.</p></figcaption>  </figure>

  




<!-- cache hit 30:single/related:5671a0e455457b31f0b816bd42b3fd9b --><!-- empty -->
<p>At first glance, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2014/05/wolfenstein-the-new-order-review-satisfying-straightforward-nazi-hunting/"><em>Wolfenstein: The New Order</em></a> developer MachineGames might seem like an awkward fit for the first (non-Lego) Indiana Jones video game <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2009/06/this-week-in-game-releases-june-8-14-2009/">since the Wii era</a>. While there's some overlap in the over-the-top Nazi villain department, the "shoot your way through every obstacle" nature of the new <em>Wolfenstein</em> games doesn't seem to lend itself well to Indy's more free-wheeling, adventurous exploration style.</p>
<p>For <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/01/first-look-at-indiana-jones-game-suggests-a-wolfenstein-like-romp/">the upcoming <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em></a>, director Jerk Gustafsson said that going from first-person shooter to a "MachineGames adventure" style change has been a difficult tightrope walk for the developers. While the team never wanted to prevent the player from using their revolver during action scenes, there was the potential that giving a player that freedom would allow them to "just shoot their way through" in a way that's antithetical to Jones' character.
</p><figure><p><iframe type="text/html" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/STrKl828Aeg?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure>
<p>To help avoid this problem, Creative Director Alex Torvenius said most of the game has been balanced so that "it's dangerous to shoot your gun and it's dangerous to be shot at." Guns-blazing action will be a winning strategy in some in-game situations, but "[there are] many scenarios where you can go through the environment without using guns at all," he continued.</p>
<p>The design is focused on "trying to make sure you should foremost try to use your wits and your whip... navigating around an enemy rather than through them," Torvenius added. "The only solution in this game is absolutely not to shoot your way through."</p>
<figure><figcaption><p>The hand-to-hand combat of the <em>Chronicles of Riddick</em> games was a big inspiration for MachineGames.</p></figcaption></figure>
<p>Gustafsson said this design was heavily inspired by <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2009/03/chronicles-of-riddick-dark-athena-remains-violent-fun/">the early 2000s <em>Chronicles of Riddick</em> games</a>, which many of the MachineGames team worked on directly. As in those games, the combat focus in <em>Great Circle</em> is more on hand-to-hand fights or using improvised weapons gleaned from the immediate environment.</p>
<p>Gustafsson said he "likes to see the whip as the entry point to combat," and during a short gameplay session viewed by Ars Technica, we saw that whip being used to disarm unaware enemies, trip them up from a sentry position, or simply to swing in from above to get the jump on them. We also saw Indy doing the tried-and-true "throw a bottle to make the guards think I'm over there" trick and using nearby hammers and even rolling pins as handy melee or throwing weapons. The revolver only came out occasionally during the demo, such as to take out a sentry on a far-off scaffolding.</p>                                                                        
                                                                                
<p>The change in style from the guns-first Wolfenstein games has been a fun one for the studio, Gustafsson said. "You can see on the team the step from going from what we are so used to doing—the guns blazing, crazy shooting experience that we have done—to something that is much more lighthearted... It has taken some time to shepherd that transition for sure, but it has been refreshing for the team, for the studio."</p>
<h2>“Ignore the shooting part”</h2>
<p>To help shepherd that transition, Gustafsson said the team decided to just "ignore the shooting part" early in the game's development, in part because "we know that we can do it well, we know that we can get that right." Instead, the early focus was on a scene that incorporated the many types of non-shooting tasks that would be integrated into the game, such as exploration, stealth, and traversing around trap-filled environments, as well as the aforementioned hand-to-hand combat.</p>
<figure><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Voss-Treasure-Room.png" data-height="2160" data-width="3840" alt="Scenery-chewing Nazi villain? Check!"></a><figcaption><p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Voss-Treasure-Room.png" data-height="2160" data-width="3840">Enlarge</a> <span>/</span> Scenery-chewing Nazi villain? Check!</p></figcaption></figure>
<p>Set in 1937 during the gap between <em>Raiders of the Lost Ark</em> and <em>The Last Crusade</em>, <em>The Great Circle</em> starts with a break-in that focuses on a priceless relic in Jones' home. Pursuing that break-in leads Jones and a team of unlikely allies to a set of mystical stones arranged in the titular "great circle" of locations that map a full arc around the globe. In pursuing those stones, the team is trying to outrun Dr. Emmerich Voss, a Nazi scientist who sees the artifacts as an otherworldly force that's key to a grand global conspiracy.</p>
<p>The scenery-chewing villain and McGuffin-filled plot are all in service to gameplay focused heavily on exploration. Using a period-appropriate camera, Indy can take photos of various clues and detritus around the environment, providing the player with important spoken and written background information as he does (it's like an old-fashioned version of <em>Metroid Prime</em>'s scan visor). All those photos and clues go into a continually updated scrapbook that the player can consult at any time to solve minor mysteries and figure out what to do next.</p>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones And The Great Circle Release Date Set, PS5 Version Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-release-date-set-ps5-version-confirmed/1100-6525933/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-release-date-set-ps5-version-confirmed.958773/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-release-date-set-ps5-version-confirmed/1100-6525933/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525933">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is a big departure for MachineGames, as despite taking place in first-person like the Wolfenstein series, it places a franchise-appropriate emphasis on investigation and exploration over brutal, violent murder sprees. In a new gameplay presentation at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-5715/" data-ref-id="2900-5715">Gamescom Opening Night Live</a>, we learned just where Indy will be exploring, as well as a few of the tools he has at his disposal. We also got a release date of December 9, 2024 for the Xbox Series X|S, PC, and Game Pass versions, along with confirmation of a PS5 release coming in Spring 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">Rather than stick to one location for Dr. Jones' mission to put everything in a museum, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will send you to a variety of destinations. These include the Vatican, the Himalayas, and Sukhothai temples, but Indy won't just waltz into these places in his signature fedora and hope no one notices him. Instead, he'll make use of a number of disguises--for instance, he can dress as a priest to explore the Vatican, which makes sense, and MachineGames is putting an emphasis on slower, stealthy gameplay.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=STrKl828Aeg" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/STrKl828Aeg" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr"><span>For those who have played the studio's Wolfenstein games, this shouldn't come as a huge surprise, but your options will be a little less lethal when dealing with unsuspecting enemies here. You can throw objects like a hammer or shovel to distract baddies in classic video-game fashion, but you can also use Indy's whip for some more-inspired takedowns--see a metal barrel and want to yank a Nazi directly into it? Go for it.</span></p><p dir="ltr">Alongside his trusty whip, Indiana Jones also has a camera that can be used both for getting historical information about the environments and discovering clues on what to do. Utilizing clues at your disposal will be key to solving puzzles, and these can be found both by traversing the environment and examining Indy's journal. The pen might not actually be mightier than the sword, but it can still be more helpful.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia Prequel Announced, More Info Coming In December]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mafia-prequel-announced-more-info-coming-in-december/1100-6525996/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-prequel-announced-more-info-coming-in-december.958767/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mafia-prequel-announced-more-info-coming-in-december/1100-6525996/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525996">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The rumors were right--Hangar 13 is making a new Mafia game. As <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-mafia-prequel-game-currently-in-development-report/1100-6503153/" data-ref-id="1100-6503153">rumored</a>, it's a prequel called Mafia: The Old Country, taking place in 1900s Sicily when the Italian mob was forming. The game was announced at the end of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-5715/" data-ref-id="2900-5715">Gamescom Opening Night Live.</a></p><p>All we got was a very brief teaser trailer for Mafia: The Old Country. It's a tantalizing tease, and Hangar 13 said it will share more information the game this December. That could line up with The Game Awards, but nothing is confirmed at this stage.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=crDUx5suLm4" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/crDUx5suLm4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The Old Country is also the <a href="https://mafiagame.fandom.com/wiki/The_Old_Country" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">name of a Mafia II mission</a> that takes place during World War II in Italy.</p><p>Hangar 13 also developed Mafia: The Definitive Edition, which is now available on Xbox Game Pass, as well as Mafia III. More recently, Hangar 13 made the very un-Mafia game TopSpin 2K25.</p><p>In addition to Mafia: The Old Country, 2K announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-vii-releasing-february-11-or-a-week-earlier-with-more-expensive-editions/1100-6525960/" data-ref-id="1100-6525960">more details on Civilization VII</a> during Gamescom Opening Night Live. The publisher also revealed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/borderlands-4/" data-ref-id="5000-640429">Borderlands 4. </a>For more on the show, check out GameSpot's rundown of all the biggest news in the gallery below.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life is Strange creators' Lost Records launches in two parts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/life-is-strange-creators-lost-records-launches-in-two-parts</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/life-is-strange-creators-lost-records-launches-in-two-parts.958758/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/life-is-strange-creators-lost-records-launches-in-two-parts<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Landing February and March 2025.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/UNI_SCREENSHOT_REVEAL_1_1080p-1024x576.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Don't Nod</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/life-is-strange-devs-lost-records-brings-hazy-summer-vibes-and-90s-nostalgia-in-new-trailer">the long-awaited next game from the team behind the original Life is Strange</a>, will arrive in two parts. 
</p>
<p>
The first installment launches for PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S on 18th February 2025, with its concluding slice then a month later on 18th March.
</p>
<p>
Tonight also brings an initial look at gameplay from Don't Nod's latest teen adventure, which has a dual timeline split between 1995 and 2022, when its young protagonists are now adults - and dealing with the consequences of their/your actions. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage | Lo-fi Summer Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2aNUtMUvIM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage | Lo-fi Summer Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2aNUtMUvIM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/A2aNUtMUvIM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A2aNUtMUvIM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage marks a long-awaited return for the team which developed both <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/life-is-strange">Life is Strange</a> and its sequel. 
</p>
<p>
In the years since, the Life is Strange series has continued, though developed by Life is Strange: Before the Storm studio Deck Nine. It's this outfit that created 2021's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/life-is-strange-true-colors">Life is Strange: True Colors</a>, and the upcoming <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/life-is-strange-double-exposure">Life is Strange: Double Exposure</a>, which is set to launch in October. 
</p>
<p>
Life is Strange began as an episodic series, though this was ditched for True Colors, which launched as a single release. 
</p>
<p>
Splitting Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage in two seems something of a middle-ground, then - with only a month's wait for part two.
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/original-life-is-strange-team-delays-new-game-to-avoid-new-lis-launch-date">Don't Nod's game was once set to launch this year, before its arrival was pushed into 2025</a> to avoid clashing with Life is Strange: Double Exposure this autumn.
</p>
<p>
Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/life-is-strange-creators-discuss-leaving-their-hit-narrative-adventure-series-behind-building-on-it-with-lost-records">I spoke with Don't Nod about creating Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage - and why the team had wanted to move on from Life is Strange</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle confirmed for PlayStation 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-confirmed-for-playstation-5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-confirmed-for-playstation-5.958755/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-confirmed-for-playstation-5<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Indy-resurfaces-in-Indiana-Jones-and-the-Great-Circle.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>MachineGames</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-everything-we-know-9408">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> - the Microsoft-owned-Bethesda-release set to arrive on Xbox and PC this year - is also coming to PlayStation 5. 
</p>
<p>
At this evening's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-time-where-to-watch">Gamescom</a> Opening Night Live event, host <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/geoff-keighley">Geoff Keighley</a> revealed that everyone's favourite fedora sporting professor will be cracking his whip on Sony's platform as well.
</p>
<p>
In addition to this news, Bethesda announced a release date for the game. Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will release across Xbox Series X/S and PC on 9th December. Its PS5 release will then follow a few months later, during the spring of 2025.  
</p>
<p>
We also got a look at a new trailer for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, showing us some of Troy Baker behind the scenes on set. You can check it out for yourself below.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Gamescom Date Reveal Trailer - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/STrKl828Aeg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Gamescom Date Reveal Trailer - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/STrKl828Aeg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/STrKl828Aeg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Gamescom Date Reveal Trailer - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=STrKl828Aeg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Get a new look at Indy's global adventure and the tools at his disposal as he faces off against sinister forces," reads the blurb. "From the whip and colt to his trusty journal and camera, you'll need everything he's got to unravel the mystery of the Great Circle."</p>
<p>
On its release, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-reveal-shows-globe-trotting-escapades-spiders-and-a-game-pass-promise">available for Xbox Game Pass members</a>. 
</p>
<p>
Those interested can <a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/75UbsSjcgLIkfwqjJIgRfu/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-launch-december-9">pre-order Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> now on Xbox Series X/S consoles and PC. Wishlisting is also available on PlayStation. The team revealed those who purchase the Premium Edition, Premium Upgrade or Collector's Edition of the game will also receive three days of early access, beginning on 6th December December.</p>
<p>"Players can also look forward to more content with the launch of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: The Order of the Giants DLC," MachineGames and Bethesda furthered. "This story-focused DLC will be available with purchases of the Premium, Premium Upgrade and Collector's Edition post-launch with more details coming at a later date."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-order_Bonus_Vanity_16x9_RD6-ENUS.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>MachineGames</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>You can find details for all Indiana Jones and the Great Circle editions below:</p>
<p><strong>Standard Edition</strong></p>
<p>Includes: Indiana Jones and the Great Circle base game (Digital or Physical)</p>
<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Standard Edition is included with Xbox Game Pass. Game disc included with physical purchases of Xbox Standard Edition. Game code included with physical purchases on PC Standard edition.</p>
<p><strong>Premium Edition</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Base Game (Digital or Physical)</li>
<li>Up to 3 days early access</li>
<li>The Order of Giants Story DLC (upon release)</li>
<li>Digital Art Book</li>
<li>Temple of Doom Outfit</li>
<li>The Last Crusade Pack with Travelling Suit Outfit, Lion Tamer Whip</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Premium_Edition_Vanity_16x9_RD6-ENUS.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>MachineGames</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p><strong>Premium Edition Upgrade</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Up to 3 days early access</li>
<li>The Order of Giants Story DLC (upon release)</li>
<li>Digital Art Book</li>
<li>Temple of Doom Outfit</li>
<li>The Last Crusade Pack with Travelling Suit Outfit, Lion Tamer Whip</li>
</ul>
<p>The base game is sold separately.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Premium_Edition_Upgrade_Vanity_16x9_RD6-ENUS.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>MachineGames</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p><strong>Collector's Edition</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Base Game</li>
<li>The Great Circle 11" Globe with Hidden Storage</li>
<li>Up to 3 days early access</li>
<li>Allmaker Relic Replica with Game Code (Base Game)</li>
<li>Jumbo SteelBook Case</li>
<li>New Adventure Journal</li>
<li>The Order of Giants Story DLC (upon release)</li>
<li>Digital Art Book</li>
<li>Temple of Doom Outfit</li>
<li>The Last Crusade Pack with Travelling Suit Outfit, Lion Tamer Whip</li>
</ul>
<p>Explore the world of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle with the 11" Great Circle tabletop globe. Use your wits to unlock the puzzle of the globe and reveal hidden storage.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collectors_Edition_Vanity_16x9_RD6-ENUS.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>MachineGames</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>News that Indy is making the jump to PlayStation follows Microsoft's earlier announcement that it would be making more of its games available to a wider audience. Earlier this year, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-review">Sea of Thieves</a>, Grounded, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hi-fi-rush">Hi-Fi Rush</a> and Pentiment all also made the move across to additional platforms. On its PS5 debut, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-xbox-console-exclusive-just-topped-europes-ps5-download-charts">Sea of Thieves went onto top the console's download charts</a>.
</p>
<p>
Elsewhere during Gamescom Opening Night Live, we also got a tease for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/borderlands-4-coming-2025-taking-players-to-an-all-new-planet">Bordlerlands 4</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dune-awakening-out-next-year-on-pc-heres-a-first-look-at-gameplay">Dune: Awakening</a>. 

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delta Force: Hawk Ops looks like a Battlefield & Ghost Recon fan’s dream game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/delta-force-hawk-ops-early-access-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/delta-force-hawk-ops-looks-like-a-battlefield-ghost-recon-fan%E2%80%99s-dream-game.958710/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/delta-force-hawk-ops-early-access-release-date/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>TiMi Studios’s Team Jade has shared a fresh look at Delta Force: Hawk Ops, announcing that the game will be playable during the next Steam Next Fest in October, before kicking off PC Early Access in Q4 of this year. The game is coming to PS5, PS4, PC and mobile.</p>
<p><iframe title="Delta Force - Gamescom 2024 Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DNcXW26gtPk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Delta Force: Hawk Ops is set to be a free-to-play online FPS, reviving the classic game franchise for a modern audience. The Delta Force will return with a lot of high tech and upgraded weapons within a dynamic world. Large scale multiplayer battles look like they will have the kind of vehicular combat and building destruction that will appeal to Battlefield fans, while there’s also the kinds of high tech gadgetry that has come to define Ghost Recon games of late.</p>
<p>There will be multiple game modes, including Havoc Warfare, which will include battles across land, sea and air, while Hazard Operations shifts gears for an extraction shooter form. There’s also a Black Hawk Down campaign that is inspired by the Ridley Scott film.</p>
<p>The game has been in development for a while, first at NovaLogic, before the rights were acquired by Tencent and development duties handed over to TiMi Studios, who are best known for having developed Call of Duty: Mobile.<sup id="cite_ref-4"></sup></p>



<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 is coming in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/borderlands-4-is-coming-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-is-coming-in-2025.958704/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/borderlands-4-is-coming-in-2025/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Hot on the heels of the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/08/the-first-borderlands-movie-reviews-are-in-and-they-dont-hold-back/">Borderlands film release</a>, Gearbox has announced that Borderlands 4 is coming… and it’s coming next year in 2025!</p>
<p><iframe title="Borderlands 4 - Official Teaser Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1Q8WImF649E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>All that we have is this teaser trailer at this time, depicting a vast crystalline attack on a moon and planet, before the now iconic Psycho bandit mask is revealed to confim that yes, this is Borderlands 4. “The next Borderlands” was confirmed to be in development earlier this year, but this states clearly that it’s the next numbered entry in the series.</p>
<p>This announcement is sure to go down well amongst series fans. While the film did… not meet expectations, there’s still a huge amount of love for the Borderlands series and its spin-offs – <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/03/30/tiny-tinas-wonderlands-review/">Tiny Tina’s Wonderlands.</a> We defniitely preferred Wonderlands to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/09/18/borderlands-3-review/">Borderlands 3,</a> in large part for the tone and style of humour, and hope Gearbox strikes a fresh balance between the two.</p>
<p>We said of Borderlands 3, “I’ve got very mixed feelings about Borderlands 3. Overall I like it and it’s fun to play, but it could have been so much more and the writing feels like time traveling back to your high school days and being surprised and a little disappointed at how immature everyone is. Few things in life are as embarrassing as the person you were five years ago. If you’re not embarrassed, then I’m sorry to say that you may well be the Borderlands 3 of your friend group; stuck in the past unable to grow or change in any meaningful way, relying on fart jokes as a stand-in for your personality.”</p>

<p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/03/28/embracer-sells-off-gearbox-to-take-two-for-460-million/">Take-Two acquired Gearbox from Embracer for $460 million</a> – paid for in newly created stocks that Embracer is expected to cash out as soon as possible to help ease their cashflow problems. Borderlands 4 would have been deep into development at the time, pushing Take-Two to make the acquisition of one of their key money-makers. They also acquired the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/homeworld-3/">Homeworld</a>, Risk of Rain, Brothers in Arms and Duke Nukem IP at the same time.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>