<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 15:56:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GDQ Flame Fatales Marathon Raises $118k for Malala Fund]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gdq-flame-fatales-118k-malala</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gdq-flame-fatales-marathon-raises-118k-for-malala-fund.963786/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gdq-flame-fatales-118k-malala<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>GDQ's women-focused Flame Fatales event has concluded, and it's raised a pretty impressive amount of money for a charity that benefits women and girls around the world.</p>
<p>Flame Fatales ran between August 18th and yesterday, concluding with over $118,000 raised for the <a href="https://malala.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Malala Fund charity</a>. As you've probably guessed, the charity was founded by Malala Yousafzai and advocates for girls' education globally.</p>
<p>As a press release points out, Flame Fatales saw speedrunning attempts being made across a number of games this year, including classics like&nbsp;<em>Super Mario 64 DS&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Chrono Trigger</em>, as well as newer games like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-kingdom">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a>&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/bayonetta-3"><em>Bayonetta 3</em></a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bayonetta-3-gdq-flame-fatales.jpg?itok=tdZHRCrG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bayonetta-3-gdq-flame-fatales.jpg?itok=CDphiYBi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Flame Fatales saw speedrunning efforts being made in games like&nbsp;<em>Bayonetta 3&nbsp;</em>this year.</figcaption></figure><p>In fact, it was during a&nbsp;<em>Bayonetta 3&nbsp;</em>speedrun that Flame Fatales reached a new lifetime milestone of $1 million donations. That's a heck of a lot of money given to charity over the years.</p>
<p>Other speedruns during Flame Fatales this year included Jerikandra's "intense"&nbsp;<em>Chrono Trigger&nbsp;</em>Vortex Save Any% final boss attempt, as well as SnowballSMB achieving a new world record in New Game+ for&nbsp;<em>Sonic &amp; Knuckles</em>.</p>
<p>If you're still jonesing for your speedrunning fix, then you'll be pleased to know that AGDQ (that's Awesome Games Done Quick) is just around the corner; next year's AGDQ event runs between January 5th and 12th.</p>
<p>Games Done Quick has generally been a force to be reckoned with when it comes to raising money for charity; this year's Summer Games Done Quick event <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/summer-games-done-quick-2024">racked up $2.5 million</a> for Doctors Without Borders, and last year's AGDQ <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/awesome-games-done-quick-raises-26-million-for-prevent-cancer-foundation">raised $2.6 million for the Prevent Cancer Foundation</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/chrono-trigger-flame-fatales-2024.jpg?itok=lXDx2LIZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/chrono-trigger-flame-fatales-2024.jpg?itok=yvM_ZKBI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This year's Flame Fatales played host to a rather tense&nbsp;<em>Chrono Trigger&nbsp;</em>speedrun.</figcaption></figure><p>At a time when women, non-binary folks, and those presenting female are struggling to make their voices heard in the gaming industry, it's great to see Flame Fatales raising some serious cash for the Malala Fund.</p>
<p>The jury's out on how much progress the industry is making when it comes to women in gaming, especially when the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-37m-user-milestone-wukong">phenomenally popular&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-37m-user-milestone-wukong">Black Myth: Wukong</a>&nbsp;</em>can tell players streaming the game <a href="https://videogames.si.com/news/black-myth-wukong-streamers-feminist-propaganda" rel="noopener" target="_blank">not to include "feminist propaganda"</a> in their streams, whatever that means.</p>
<p>At any rate, stay tuned for more on this, as well as all other things GDQ-related. Here's hoping for a real stunner for January's AGDQ.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15 Years Ago, Batman: Arkham Asylum Changed Superhero Games Forever]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/batman-arkham-asylum-city-knight-anniversary-15-sale-1851631469</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/15-years-ago-batman-arkham-asylum-changed-superhero-games-forever.963783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/batman-arkham-asylum-city-knight-anniversary-15-sale-1851631469<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Now and then you see something that reminds you that the passage of time marches on so quickly that it’s nearly imperceptible. Yesterday, August 25, was <em>Batman: Arkham Asylum</em>’s 15th anniversary. That’s right. What is arguably the most well-regarded game starring Bruce Wayne ever made is old enough for a learner’s permit. The <em>Arkham </em>series has seen better days, as the most recent entry in Rocksteady’s DC universe, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/suicide-squad-justice-league-review-is-it-good-batman-1851222047&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/suicide-squad-justice-league-review-is-it-good-batman-1851222047"><em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</em></a></span>, is rightfully divisive. But looking back at where it all began, <em>Arkham Asylum </em>was a truly remarkable experience that set a new bar for what we expect out of a superhero game. If you’ve never played it, the original game and its sequels are bundled on sale on both <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/batman-return-to-arkham/brw49cbs558d/0001&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/batman-return-to-arkham/brw49cbs558d/0001" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xbox</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1018-CUSA00133_00-ARKHAMBUNDLE0000&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1018-CUSA00133_00-ARKHAMBUNDLE0000" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation</a></span> for less than $10.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196394" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="97" data-playlist="196394,195719,196191" data-current="196394"><div><p>The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21942.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><em>Arkham Asylum </em>opens with a grimy intro sequence during a rainy Gotham City night, and that vibe doesn’t let up. The caped crusader is delivering his archnemesis, the Joker, to the titular facility. As he and the guards bring in the clown, Batman sees a few of the people he’s put away over the years, such as Killer Croc, and they’re not thrilled to see the hero. It quickly becomes clear that a whole pantheon of <em>Batman </em>villains is being kept here. It’s not surprising that the Joker springs a trap and takes over the facility, and you’re quickly hit with the realization that Bruce, in addition to tackling a number of colorful characters in his rogue’s gallery, is also going to have to face a few of his demons in Arkham before he can go home to Alfred.</p><p>The rest of the <em>Arkham</em> games were good in their own right, but none of them quite captured the same feeling of entrapment and dread you feel in <em>Asylum</em>. This was before the series made a pivot to open-world, so its Metroidvania structure feels more focused, with Bruce gaining new tools that let him explore new areas of the asylum and face new foes. There was a real sense of discovery and progression to <em>Asylum </em>that you lose in the larger scale of the later games. One of his most memorable tools is explosive gel, which he uses to blow up weak walls and access new areas and which, despite his grim, Kevin Conroy-voiced seriousness, he sprays in the shape of a bat, suggesting a bit of playful whimsy lurks under the cowl. Flying around Gotham is one way to feel like Batman, but having to make the most of a situation with tools and tech is the heart of who Bruce Wayne is.</p><p>But the utility belt is only one part of being Batman. The world’s greatest detective also gets to investigate crime scenes with the Detective Vision mechanic. The tools Rocksteady gave you to track down evidence and recreate visualizations of crimes captured this part of Batman’s character better than probably any other video game adaptation at the time. It’s something that games like <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> are still emulating to this day, and it was a welcome bit of thoughtful character-building and attentiveness to environmental detail between traversing the asylum and beating up baddies.</p><p>And god, the <em>Arkham </em>games have such a snappy, fluid combat system, one that makes you feel both acrobatic and powerful, a force to be reckoned with. The hand-to-hand combat is so slick people joke it’s a rhythm game, allowing you to bounce between goons with a fluidity that practically had Bruce dancing on the battlefield. But it wouldn’t be Batman if he just came in fists swinging as a rule. <em>Arkham Asylum</em>’s stealth mechanics were pretty forgiving, but let you perch above unsuspecting baddies and pick them off one by one. <em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</em> even <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/suicide-squad-batman-arkham-museum-scene-hunting-1851216708&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/suicide-squad-batman-arkham-museum-scene-hunting-1851216708">has a whole level that’s an homage</a></span> to the terrifying feeling bad guys must have felt knowing Batman was waiting to descend upon them like prey.</p><p>And then there are the boss battles, each spotlighting an iconic Batman villain with a sequence that is unlike anything else you play in the game. Scarecrow’s hallucinogenics put you through a nightmare that only a utility belt can wake you up from. Poison Ivy uses her thorny plant friends to trap Batman in her tangled vines. The Joker fight is notoriously derided for feeling silly and anticlimactic, but overall, the boss fights are some of the most memorable and rewarding parts of making your way through <em>Arkham Asylum</em>.</p><p>The future of the <em>Arkham </em>series feels uncertain these days, as <em>Suicide Squad </em>has failed to meet Warner Bros. expectations. Does Rocksteady get to go back to basics with its next game? I’d hope so, but I also wouldn’t be mad if the studio got to make something new. <em>Arkham Asylum</em> still stands out as one of the most well-designed superhero games of the era, and in pursuit of an open world, it feels like we lost some of the clever restrictions Batman had in that first outing. I’d love to see that team get a chance to work within those constraints again, even if it’s not returning to the caped crusader.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Direct August 2024: Start Time, How To Watch, And What To Expect]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-direct-august-2024-start-time-how-to-watch-and-what-to-expect/1100-6526111/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-direct-august-2024-start-time-how-to-watch-and-what-to-expect.963774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-direct-august-2024-start-time-how-to-watch-and-what-to-expect/1100-6526111/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526111">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">A new Nintendo Direct is just around the corner, and the showcase will be a 2-for-1 special. That's because Nintendo has revealed the livestream for tomorrow, August 27, will start with an Indie World presentation and then transition into a Partner Showcase. So here's when the Nintendo Direct for August 2024 will start, how to watch the livestream, and what to expect. Nintendo has also made it clear what shouldn't be expected: any news regarding <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Switch 2</a>.</p><h3 dir="ltr">When is the Nintendo Direct?</h3><p dir="ltr">The Nintendo Direct for August 2024 will start at 7 AM PT / 10 AM ET on Tuesday, August 27.</p><ul><li dir="ltr">7 AM PT</li><li dir="ltr">10 AM ET</li><li dir="ltr">3 PM BST</li><li dir="ltr">12 AM AET (August 28)</li></ul><h3 dir="ltr">How to watch the Nintendo Direct</h3><p dir="ltr">As usual, Nintendo will stream the Nintendo Direct on the company's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NintendoAmerica" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YouTube</a> and <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/nintendo" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitch</a> channels. There is also an embed for the presentation below.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bh7o96_yIWw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Bh7o96_yIWw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">What to expect</p><p dir="ltr">For starters, Nintendo has made it perfectly clear there will be nothing about Switch 2. The company even shared a follow-up post <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1828070150127456613" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on X</a> to confirm this point and keep people's expectations in check.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1828070150127456613" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Please note, there will be no mention of the Nintendo Switch successor during either of these presentations.</p>  — Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) <a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1828070150127456613?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 26, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">With that out of the way, the Indie Showcase portion will of course have people hoping for an update on Hollow Knight: Silksong. At one point, Silksong was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-has-been-delayed/1100-6513963/" data-ref-id="1100-6513963">planned to launch in the first half of 2023 before Team Cherry delayed the game</a>. Earlier this month, Geoff Keighley revealed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-will-not-be-shown-at-gamescom-opening-night-live/1100-6525900/" data-ref-id="1100-6525900">Silksong wouldn't be shown at Gamescom Opening Night Live</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">As for the Partner Showcase portion of the presentation, there are a handful of games releasing on Switch before the end of the year that would make sense to appear. For example, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/epic-mickey-rebrushed-paints-the-town-red-blue-and-every-other-color-in-new-trailer/1100-6525493/" data-ref-id="1100-6525493">Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed</a> might get spotlighted, since it's a remake of a Wii exclusive and comes out September 23. It also wouldn't be surprising for Level 5 to make its presence known with upcoming titles like Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/professor-layton-and-the-new-world-of-steam-gets-2025-release-window-and-new-trailer/1100-6519543/" data-ref-id="1100-6519543">Professor Layton and the New World of Steam, which is arriving in 2025</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">The Nintendo Direct will have an overall runtime of around 40 minutes.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Street Fighter 6 Terry Gamescom Hands-On – Ready for Domination]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/street-fighter-6-terry-gamescom-hands-on-ready-for-domination/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/street-fighter-6-terry-gamescom-hands-on-%E2%80%93-ready-for-domination.963732/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/street-fighter-6-terry-gamescom-hands-on-ready-for-domination/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The release of Terry Bogard in Street Fighter 6 next month is going to be an important event not only for the game but for the franchise as well since the character who starred in the Fatal Fury and The King of Fighters franchises will be the first guest character to appear in any entry in the series by CAPCOM. As such, it was not surprising to learn last week that he is likely going to make a big splash, having the potential of being among the best characters in the game.</p>
<p>During Gamescom, I had the chance to try out Terry before release, using him in a few matches against CPU-controlled opponents and fighting against him using other characters (mainly my mains Blanka and M.Bison). While the testing environment wasn't the best, as I really felt the input delay on the PlayStation 5 version as opposed to the PC version I have played since the game was released, and the available time wasn't long (around 30 minutes), I feel Terry won't take long to shoot high on the tier list of most players due to a few reasons.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Street-Fighter-6-Terry-Gamescom-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Even without being able to explore the nuances of the character due to the lack of training mode and its ever-useful frame data meter, it's clear how Terry is a very strong character. He has every tool that a Street Fighter 6 character needs to be top tier: cancelable crouching medium kick, overhead, invincible OD reversal, some long-reaching normals, including some that make the character advance forward, and explosive damage, although not on par with that of M.Bison, the first <a href="https://wccftech.com/street-fighter-6-year-2-dlc-characters-include-some-unexpected-guests/">Season 2 character</a>. Like a few other characters already in the game, some of Terry's special moves change depending on the strength of the button, which makes the character a little more complex than others but potentially more deadly. One of these special moves, Crack Shoot, reminiscent of G's wheel kick special move, felt plus on block, something that could grant the character the oppressive pressure most of the game's top tiers can dish out without spending meter. Even some of his supers are pretty unique, as his Level 2, Power Geyser, has multiple follow ups, including one that uses Drive to increase its power.</p>
<p>What truly stood out, besides his potential, is how great of a recreation of the original character Terry in Street Fighter 6 is. One of his target combos, Passing Sway, allows him to jump into the background ala Fatal Fury and then return to the front with two different attacks. I couldn't test how much mix-up potential this has, but I'm sure it will be a pretty disorienting technique in the first few days of the character's availability.</p>
<p>Without more time with the character, it is difficult to say if Terry will be able to hold his own against the likes of Ken, Cammy, and Akuma, but there's no doubt that the potential is definitely there. While he's definitely another shoto type of character, his unique fighting style and mechanics will make his addition to Street Fighter 6 a worthy one on September 24th. The Pao Pao Cafè stage will also be released on the same day.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Newzoo July 2024 Report Reveals EA Sports College Football 25 Is An Instant Hit]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/newzoo-july-2024-report-reveals-ea-sports-college-football-25-is-an-instant-hit/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/newzoo-july-2024-report-reveals-ea-sports-college-football-25-is-an-instant-hit.963729/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/newzoo-july-2024-report-reveals-ea-sports-college-football-25-is-an-instant-hit/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
							<p data-nosnippet="">
					This is not investment advice. The author has no position in any of the stocks mentioned. Wccftech.com has a <a href="https://wccftech.com/legal-disclaimer/#11">disclosure and ethics policy.</a>
				</p>
			
			
			<p><a href="https://newzoo.com/games-market-reports-forecasts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Newzoo</a> has released its latest report on the games industry, this time focusing on PC and console MAU (Monthly Active Users) and Revenue Rankings. Some results come as a bit of a surprise, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/video-game-sales-in-july-are-up-in-europe-despite-no-major-releases/">multiplayer games</a> outperforming most single-player games across the board. One of the most prominent games to be released this year was EA Sports College Football 25.</p>
<p>While sports games tend to get overlooked in the mix of other releases, EA Sports College Football 25 immediately jumped to #1. Specifically, it was #1 on both PlayStation and Xbox when the game was released in July and became the best-selling sports game in July.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, realistic sports games were the ones that dominated some of the top slots in gaming revenue across the board, regardless of platform. We've already established that EA Sports Football 25 jumped to #1, but EA Sports FC 24 came in at #3, and NBA 2K24 came in at #9, dropping three positions since the month prior.</p>
<p>Despite receiving mixed reviews, The First Descendant also did surprisingly well in July. It was #5 overall and on Xbox, #6 on PC, and #7 on PlayStation, respectively. It received a whopping 10 million player count across the board in the first week of its release, which is pretty significant for a free-to-play game.</p>
<p>Although miHoYo typically has taken the gacha world by storm, Zenless Zone Zero didn't mainly hold up on other consoles than the PlayStation. The game was released on PlayStation 5, Android, iOS, and PC but only managed to enter the PlayStation rankings at #11.</p>
<p>Once looking at the report in detail, it makes a lot of sense that multiplayer games have gone on to outperform singleplayer games, especially since this year hasn't particularly seen a huge influx of AAA games, with most of the potential big-hitters being slated to release much later in Q4 of 2024. It's possible that when games such as Silent Hill 2, Dragon Age: The Veilguard, and The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom are all released respectively, the charts will shift in favor of single-player games, with them bringing in more revenue and active players.</p>
<p>One of the most surprising results is that the single Nintendo Switch game will make it into the top 20 revenue ranking overall. That game is Nintendo World Champions: NES Edition. While it immediately jumped up the charts and made it to #1 on Nintendo Switch, it didn't experience such luck in the general charts. Instead, it sat at #17 as the only Nintendo-developed title out of the hard hitters.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gamescom ONL 2024 Doubled Last Year's View Count to 40m]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gamescom-onl-2024-view-count</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamescom-onl-2024-doubled-last-years-view-count-to-40m.963726/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gamescom-onl-2024-view-count<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Gamescom Opening Night Live host Geoff Keighley has revealed how many views this year's presentation racked up, and if his count is to be believed, then this year's show was much more popular than last year's.</p>
<p>Per <a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/1827724818416087329" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a post on Keighley's X (formerly Twitter) account</a>, Gamescom ONL 2024 managed to amass "more than 40 million video views", which amounts to "double that of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gamescom-opening-night-live-here-are-all-trailers-news-reveals">2023</a>". That's not bad at all.</p>
<p>Naturally, Keighley's numbers must be coming from multiple platforms, because the Gamescom Opening Night Live 2024 show only has 1.2 million views on YouTube. Keighley doesn't break down viewership by platform, though, so we're left guessing on that one.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-warcraft.jpg?itok=DSn5-t2i 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-warcraft.jpg?itok=bH9MWfkF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Gamescom Opening Night Live 2024 featured around two and a half hours of announcements and reveals.</figcaption></figure><p>Keighley also says in his post that the in-person Gamescom event welcomed around 335,000 visitors this year, which is an increase on 2023's total of 320,000.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In short, it sounds like Gamescom 2024 was a much more popular event all around than last year's, so we can reasonably expect next year's showcase to increase its viewership and attendance even further, right?</p>
<p>If you missed out on Gamescom Opening Night Live 2024, it aired last Tuesday and featured around two and a half hours of reveals and announcements for both new and existing games.</p>
<p>We got to see reveals for the likes of&nbsp;<em>Borderlands 4</em>, a new&nbsp;<em>Dying Light&nbsp;</em>game, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/tarsier-studios-reanimal-introduces-tense-and-terrifying-journey">Tarsier Studios' spooky&nbsp;<em>Reanimal</em></a>, which looks strongly reminiscent of&nbsp;<em>Little Nightmares&nbsp;</em>(which makes sense given that Tarsier worked on the first two installments of that series).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tarsier-studios-reanimal-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024.jpg?itok=nl-tj9e7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tarsier-studios-reanimal-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024.jpg?itok=xKrcElId 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Tarsier Studios'&nbsp;<em>Reanimal&nbsp;</em>was just one of the many games shown during Gamescom ONL 2024.</figcaption></figure><p>Remarkably, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gamescom-onl-2024-switch">just six</a> of the announcements made during Gamescom ONL 2024 are confirmed to be coming to Nintendo Switch right now, so it looks like that Switch 2 announcement <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-confirmation">Nintendo promised us</a> can't come soon enough.</p>
<p>If you missed Gamescom ONL 2024 and you want to catch up with the show, you can do so right here. Be warned, though: it's long. Grab yourself a cup of coffee or something.</p>

</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Obsidian’s Blockbuster Avowed Feels Like The Perfect Combination Of First-Person And Classic RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/avowed-preview-obsidian-rpg-pillars-eternity-1851631371</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/obsidian%E2%80%99s-blockbuster-avowed-feels-like-the-perfect-combination-of-first-person-and-classic-rpg.963723/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/avowed-preview-obsidian-rpg-pillars-eternity-1851631371<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The thing is, <em>Avowed</em> just feels <em>right</em>.<br></p><p>Usually, sitting down with a new role-playing game, there’s a period of adjustment, of getting used to the foibles and learning its particulars. But with <em>Avowed</em>, I just started playing. I had picked a rogue-ish character, armed with twin pistols and a bow for longer range, and immediately set about exploring some caves beneath Dawnshore like I’d lived there my whole life.</p><p>A lot of what’s been shown of <em>Avowed</em> up until now has been very much focused on action and exploration, either the game’s combat systems (especially dual-wielded wands for some reason) or the un-RPG-like jumping and climbing around its first-person world. The demo I played at GamesCom was much more focused on an aspect I imagine long-time Obsidian fans might have been missing until now: the roleplay. While I took part in multiple battles and did my fair share of exploration, the emphasis here was on conversation, deliberation, and branching decision-making.</p><p>Being first-person certainly helps with that feeling of familiarity—it removes a lot of what can feel alienating about more traditional, remotely-viewed RPGs, and means you’re not learning a new UI of 800 buttons. Instead all your actions here are dealt with via wheels that pop up when holding down the left bumper (I started out playing mouse/keyboard, because that’s my natural inclination, but then found it more comfortably played on a controller), the action pausing when you select a health potion, or ask your companion Kai (voiced by Garrus himself, Brandon Keener) to help out with something in particular.</p><p>It also helped that so much of the conversation in this 45-minute section of the game felt familiar for someone who’s already spent a fair few dozen hours in Eora, the world in which <em>Pillars of Eternity</em> was set. Here, I was tasked with finding a missing expedition team, who themselves had been hunting down a holy relic, related to the god Eothas. I know Eothas! Or indeed, don’t, given the events of the 2015 RPG, and its 2018 sequel, <em>Deadfire</em>, and entirely understood why the godlike I then meet, Sargamis, notes that Eothas’ light has recently been fading.</p><figure id="" data-id="e3445a18f68059cf8b28e9eb031696bf" data-recommend-id="image://e3445a18f68059cf8b28e9eb031696bf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The rather proud Sargamis stands in front of his home-made statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The rather proud Sargamis stands in front of his home-made statue." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e3445a18f68059cf8b28e9eb031696bf" data-recommend-id="image://e3445a18f68059cf8b28e9eb031696bf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The rather proud Sargamis stands in front of his home-made statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Of course, developers Obsidian aren’t daft, and all of this is color for those who’ve been along for the ride, while an aside for those who are new. And to maintain a balance between the two, <em>Avowed</em> continues the RPG series’ tradition of including footnotes for absolutely everything of note, including the option to pull up a paragraph on Eothas (the god of rebirth, and the deity of the earlier games’ antagonist, Waidwen). (I leaned over from my PC and asked an Obsidian developer, “Why doesn’t he know what happened to the gods?” and was told, “Eora is a <em>big</em> place, and news takes time to travel—these people don’t even have the printing press.”) The Living Lands, where <em>Avowed</em> is set, is deliberately an entirely new location, meaning it’s fresh for first-time players, but flavored enough to be familiar to longer-term followers.<br></p><p>Right, so Sargamis is a godlike, like your own character (a unique race, beings thought to be blessed by the gods, with special skills), and he’s clearly up to no good. He’s got some ridiculous plan to revive Eothas via a statue, and he’s stringing us along with some nonsense about never having seen the exploration party. Sargamis is clearly too chicken to go get the relic he needs, given it’s beyond a collapsed and flooded section of caverns and guarded by various beasties, so inevitably suggests that we go get it ourselves.</p><p>So begins the quest of leaping between platforms over a massive chasm, climbing and exploring to find chests, and discovering the route to reach this magical MacGuffin. As I played, I couldn’t help but collect every item, harvest every plant, and seek out every chest, even though I knew I wasn’t going to be using any of it given the brevity of my time with the game. But that it was there, that it was compelling, I think is crucial. This meant I was finding strange electric devices that were triggered by throwing seeds of a plant I’d plucked which opened doors to special areas, or smashing my way through suspicious-looking wooden boards to find bonus chests.</p><figure id="" data-id="2b5007eec7666adc33fd66b71e561a37" data-recommend-id="image://2b5007eec7666adc33fd66b71e561a37" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The enormous caverns of Avowed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The enormous caverns of Avowed." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2b5007eec7666adc33fd66b71e561a37" data-recommend-id="image://2b5007eec7666adc33fd66b71e561a37" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The enormous caverns of Avowed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>What took me aback, aside from how natural this all felt, was the scale. This section is all set in caves, and could easily have been tunnels and small rocky rooms. Instead, it was a series of vast, beautiful caverns, extraordinarily detailed across vast areas I couldn’t hope to reach, pretty enough to want to just stay still and stare for a while. This is bolstered by some stunning lighting. (You’ll see what I mean if you jump to 13:30 in the video below and see the candle-lit library, then the turn toward the spider-filled sunlit section of cave just beyond.)<br></p><p>The one thing I didn’t have time to get to grips with properly was combat. I managed fine, although I felt slight shame at how many health potions I was glugging, but clearly performing as the rogue when things get close-up is going to take some practice. (It would also have helped if I’d had the sense to spend more time improving my skills and putting on some of the armor I’d collected.) But at range, I felt like a fucking master. The bow and arrow is fantastic to use, and rather generous with its aiming (this is an RPG after all, not a first-person shooter), meaning I was more often clearing an area of the goblin-like Xurips before I’d even arrived. Thankfully, Kai was also helping out, his own AI taking care of his fighting.</p><figure id="" data-id="7cc9f7c39c878f001697d5a0aecfa8ed" data-recommend-id="image://7cc9f7c39c878f001697d5a0aecfa8ed" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The candle-lit library, leading to a sunlit cave of spiders." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The candle-lit library, leading to a sunlit cave of spiders." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7cc9f7c39c878f001697d5a0aecfa8ed" data-recommend-id="image://7cc9f7c39c878f001697d5a0aecfa8ed" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The candle-lit library, leading to a sunlit cave of spiders." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The same sequence from the game was being used for hands-off demos elsewhere in the German conference, so you can see an alternative playthrough of what I saw, albeit with a wizard instead of a rogue, and making different conversation choices. Also notable is there’s a whole section of opening a gate here that I never encountered, because I’m fairly sure I found a completely different route through.<br></p><p>I’ve seen a lot of gaming sites comparing <em>Avowed</em> to <em>Skyrim</em>, which I find the most peculiar idea. The games are both RPGs and both first-person, but after that I struggle to find a connection, no matter how much I love Bethesda’s game. <em>Avowed</em> feels much <em>much</em> more coherent, more focused, like the natural evolution of games like Arkane’s wonderful 2006 RPG, <em>Dark Messiah of Might and Magic</em>. It felt emboldened by the storytelling chops Obsidian has gained through its wonderful third-person RPGs, and distinct from its Bethesda-adjacent <em>Fallout</em> and <em>The Outer Worlds</em> titles.</p><p>In the mad frenzy of a week of nonstop appointments, I entirely forgot the release date for <em>Avowed</em>, and got it into my head it was arriving before this Christmas. With the demo completed, Sargamis dealt with, and a ridiculous hankering to carry on playing, I turned back to the Obsidian guy and said, “What’s the release date for this again?” “February 2025,” he replied, and in a moment of complete unprofessionalism I respond, “WHAT?! NO!”</p><p>I think that’s likely the most useful bit of information to take away from all this: I exclaimed like an affronted nine-year-old when I realized how long I have to wait to be able to play any more.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gamescom Is Expensive, So Devs Are Highlighting Their Great-Looking Games In Another Way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gamescom-is-expensive-so-devs-are-highlighting-their-great-looking-games-in-another-way/1100-6526107/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamescom-is-expensive-so-devs-are-highlighting-their-great-looking-games-in-another-way.963720/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gamescom-is-expensive-so-devs-are-highlighting-their-great-looking-games-in-another-way/1100-6526107/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526107">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>For developers, showing your game's trailer at Gamescom Opening Night Live costs upwards of $125,000. That can be an untenable proposition, so many of them are taking to Twitter/X to show them off instead.</p><p>Many developers felt left out of Gamescom Opening Night Live due to the high costs of showcasing or even attending the live show. This did not discourage many of these developers, instead fuelling their passion and desire to show them off to as wide of an audience as possible.</p><p>These great-looking games have yet to be released. Developers started this trend by tweeting/quoting the phrase, "Gamescom trailer is more than 100k dollars, so here's..." before posting GIFs, trailers, and gameplay of their games still in the developing stages.</p><p>Below, we round up some games that you should definitely check out.</p><h2>Squeakross: Home Squeak Home</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2871440/Squeakross_Home_Squeak_Home/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Tiny Tires</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2433790/Tiny_Tires/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Constance</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2313700/Constance/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Genokids</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1239360/Genokids/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>MIGHTREYA</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3077640/MIGHTREYA/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Katsl</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2631780/Katsl/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Keylocker</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1325040/Keylocker__Turn_Based_Cyberpunk_Action/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Bits &amp; Bops</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1929290/Bits__Bops/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Catto's Post Office</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2908050/Cattos_Post_Office/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Paper Perjury</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1919600/Paper_Perjury/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>BioCrisis : Return 2 the Lab</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1835570/BioCrisis__Return_2_the_Lab/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Identifile</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3054210/Identifile/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>AIKODE</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2406140/AIKODE/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Motorslice</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2830030/MOTORSLICE/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>Hollowbody</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2123640/Hollowbody/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><h2>One S'More</h2><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2452930/One_SMore/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wishlist on Steam</a>.</p><p>Be sure to check out all the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-gamescom-awards-2024-categories-and-nominees/2900-5710/#1" data-ref-id="2900-5710">Gamescom 2024 award winners</a>, as well.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526098&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arcade1up-machines-drop-to-prime-day-prices-mortal-kombat-arcade-table-ms-pac-man-countercade-and-more\/1100-6526098\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525389&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/best-wireless-gaming-headset\/1100-6525389\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526096&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sony-inzone-gaming-earbuds-pc-and-ps5-headset-amazon-deals\/1100-6526096\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525928&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/buy-two-get-one-free-nintendo-switch-games-and-preorders-my-best-buy-members\/1100-6525928\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525907&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nier-automata-anime-blu-ray-preorder\/1100-6525907\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525903&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/attack-on-titan-final-season-final-chapters-blu-ray-preorder-amazon\/1100-6525903\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526083&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/yu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time\/1100-6526083\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525784&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-all-dapper-delights-star-path-duties-and-how-to-complete-them\/1100-6525784\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526005&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/baldurs-gate-3s-new-dark-urge-evil-ending-gets-a-teaser\/1100-6526005\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526065&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvel-studios-reveals-first-looks-at-red-hulk-and-daredevil-in-now-deleted-video\/1100-6526065\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526062&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/heres-why-borderlands-4-is-launching-on-steam-after-borderlands-3-didnt\/1100-6526062\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6522523&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/star-wars-outlaws-preorder-guide\/1100-6522523\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6516719&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/baldurs-gate-3-dribbles-the-clown-guide\/1100-6516719\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526097&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/best-deals-on-mmo-gaming-mice-for-world-of-warcraft-the-war-within\/1100-6526097\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526087&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/star-wars-outlaws-is-being-livestreamed-a-week-before-official-release\/1100-6526087\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526026&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-is-getting-a-huge-first-of-its-kind-dungeon-filled-with-exclusive-rewards\/1100-6526026\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526094&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sega-wants-yakuza-fans-opinions-on-putting-stars-like-keanu-reeves-and-the-rock-in-future-games\/1100-6526094\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Direct Double Bill Announced for Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-double-bill-august-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-direct-double-bill-announced-for-tomorrow.963705/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-double-bill-august-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo has announced two brand new Nintendo Direct presentations for tomorrow, so prepare to see some games from prominent Nintendo partners, as well as some smaller indie projects worth checking out.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1828070146117644476" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a post on Nintendo's official X (formerly Twitter) account</a>, the company will air an Indie World showcase tomorrow at 10am Eastern, followed by a Partner Showcase straight afterwards.</p>
<p>As a quick recap, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-partner-showcase-january-2023-recap-find-all-news-and-announcements">Partner Showcases</a> tend to show off bigger releases from larger companies like Atlus or THQ Nordic (although they can feature indies too), while <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-indie-world-showcase-april-2024">Indie World shows</a> are usually built around smaller studios.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pentiment-nintendo-direct-partner-showcase.jpg?itok=ppT4_C_t 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pentiment-nintendo-direct-partner-showcase.jpg?itok=KegfTLrG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>We first learned&nbsp;<em>Pentiment&nbsp;</em>would come to Nintendo Switch during a Partner Direct.</figcaption></figure><p>Games announced during previous Partner Direct showcases include&nbsp;the Switch releases of Xbox games&nbsp;<em>Pentiment&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Grounded</em>, as well as games like&nbsp;<em>Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope</em>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/everything-announced-during-todays-nintendo-direct-mini">Switch releases for&nbsp;<em>Persona</em></a>, and more.</p>
<p>Indie World shows, meanwhile, have given us reveals for the likes of&nbsp;<em>SteamWorld Heist 2</em>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/everything-announced-at-todays-nintendo-indie-world-showcase">sporting RPG&nbsp;<em>Sports Story</em></a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/everything-announced-at-nintendo-indie-world-showcase">cartoony Soulslike&nbsp;<em>Another Crab's Treasure</em></a>, among many others.</p>
<p>It's somewhat unusual for Nintendo to air both presentations one after the other, especially when partner showcases sometimes feature indie games as well. Will tomorrow's showcases be strictly split along the lines of bigger third-party games and smaller indie projects? We'll have to wait and see.</p>
<p>Of course, both shows have a rather large, insect-shaped shadow hanging over them. Will tomorrow finally be the day when we get to hear more about&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/hollow-knight-silksong"><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em></a>? Almost certainly not, but hey, we can dream (yet again), right?</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-direct-august-2024-indie-world.jpg?itok=ECUz9e_x 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-direct-august-2024-indie-world.jpg?itok=znQ4ck4c 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Yep, we're dancing this pavane again.</figcaption></figure><p>In any case, Nintendo says that both presentations, when taken together, will last roughly 40 minutes. Whether that means an even 20-20 split or something different, we're not yet sure.</p>
<p>If you want to find out, you'll be able to tune into Nintendo's twin Directs <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/Bh7o96_yIWw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">via the company's YouTube channel</a> tomorrow. Once again, Nintendo has confirmed we <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1828070150127456613" rel="noopener" target="_blank">won't be hearing anything about the Switch 2</a>, either, so put down those bingo cards.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo is closing out the summer with a 40-minute showcase]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/24228697/nintendo-direct-indie-showcase-partner-direct-august</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-is-closing-out-the-summer-with-a-40-minute-showcase.963702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/24228697/nintendo-direct-indie-showcase-partner-direct-august<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article id="content"><div><div><div><h2>Nintendo is closing out the summer with a 40-minute showcase</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>‘Please note, there will be no mention of the Nintendo Switch successor during either of these presentations.’</h2></span></p></div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a></span><span>, <span>a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and writing about the intersection of video games and sex.</span></span></span></p><p><time datetime="2024-08-26T14:41:24.265Z"> <!-- -->Aug 26, 2024, 2:41 PM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div></div></div><div><figure><span><span></span></span><p><cite>Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge</cite></p></figure></div></div><div><p>Nintendo has added one final event to the summer game-a-palooza calendar with not one but two game showcases. Tomorrow at 7AM PT / 10AM ET, Nintendo will host an indie world showcase, and then a partner direct will immediately follow. Altogether, Nintendo says the two back-to-back events will be 40 minutes long.</p><div><p>Nintendo’s already had its big bang summer showcase this year. Back in June, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/18/24180183/nintendo-direct-june-2024-news-trailers">Nintendo announced several new first-party games</a>. Among them was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24180608/mario-and-luigi-brothership-release-date-nintendo-direct">a new <em>Mario &amp; Luigi</em> title</a>, a new game in the<em> Legend of Zelda</em> series <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24180615/legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-trailer-nintendo-direct">that actually stars Zelda</a>, and the company finally announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23768041/metroid-prime-4-nintendo-direct-trailer"><em>Metroid Prime 4</em> would finally exit its development purgatory</a> of nigh on 10 years sometime in 2025.</p></div><p>These two showcases will likely not have announcements as big as those in June, but hey, <em>Hollow Knight:</em> <em>Silksong</em> by Team Cherry hasn’t been seen in years, and it <em>is</em> technically an indie game, so... y’know hope springs eternal.</p><p>Of note, the company has once again trotted out what’s become its catchphrase of late, warning viewers that, “there will be no mention of the Nintendo Switch successor during either of these presentations.” The new console is rumored for launch in Q1 2025, with promises it’ll be revealed before April 2025. </p></div></article></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Quietly Announces Super-Secret Hero Shooter Deadlock Months After People Started Playing It]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/deadlock-valve-steam-hero-shooter-moba-release-date-1851631341</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-quietly-announces-super-secret-hero-shooter-deadlock-months-after-people-started-playing-it.963696/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/deadlock-valve-steam-hero-shooter-moba-release-date-1851631341<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="6a50e4d04d51c66ab83b8a354081023f" data-recommend-id="image://6a50e4d04d51c66ab83b8a354081023f" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A bearded man holds a gun. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A bearded man holds a gun. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6a50e4d04d51c66ab83b8a354081023f" data-recommend-id="image://6a50e4d04d51c66ab83b8a354081023f" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A bearded man holds a gun. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Deadlock </em>is official. The multiplayer shooter that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/valve-next-game-deadlock-early-access-beta-steamdb-pc-1851620354&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/valve-next-game-deadlock-early-access-beta-steamdb-pc-1851620354">thousands of players have been testing on Steam</a></span> but not been allowed to talk about now has its own store page that’s mostly full of information about how the game could drastically change at any moment. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195805" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: September 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="338" data-playlist="195805,196013,196131" data-current="195805"><div><p>The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: September 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195805/195805_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195805/195805_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195805/195805_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195805/195805_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21320.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>“<em>Deadlock</em> is a multiplayer game in early development,” reads Valve’s official description. “<em>Deadlock</em> is in early development with lots of temporary art and experimental gameplay,” reads another disclaimer. “Access is currently limited to friend invite via our playtesters.” The competitive game’s user-generated tags include MOBA, third-person shooter, team-based, and cute.</p><p>The Steam page went up late on Friday, over a week after the floodgates opened on players invited to test the game talking about it online. People are excited about<em> Deadlock </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/valve-next-game-new-shooter-deadlock-neon-prime-moba-pc-1851493739&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/valve-next-game-new-shooter-deadlock-neon-prime-moba-pc-1851493739">in part because of the bizarre fig-leaf of secrecy that’s surrounded it</a></span>, with thousands of people playing it prior to any official announcement, but also because it has the potential to really shake up a genre of online shooter dominated by existing franchises like<em> Overwatch 2</em>, <em>Apex Legends</em>, and <em>Valorant</em>. </p><p>Each of those offers a slightly different flavor of the hero-based shooter experience, but <em>Deadlock</em>’s MOBA elements <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/12/24219016/valve-deadlock-hands-on-secret-new-game&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/12/24219016/valve-deadlock-hands-on-secret-new-game" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sound like a drastic departure</a></span> from the familiar formula, with heroes leveling up stats over the course of a match and leading small armies of AI-controlled grunts against the opposing team until their giant death-ray-wielding robot is destroyed. For fans of <em>Team Fortress 2</em>, <em>Dota 2</em>, and even <em>Artifact</em>, Valve’s defunct attempt to reinvent <em>Magic: The Gathering</em> with MOBA elements, it sounds like <em>Deadlock </em>places an exciting layer of RPG and strategy elements  on top of your standard <em>Call of Duty </em>deathmatch. </p><p>Unfortunately, the new store page doesn’t give any further indication of when most fans will actually get to play <em>Deadlock</em>. The current test sessions are still invite only, so you need a friend who’s already playing to get you in the door. Hopefully Valve actually revealing the game for real means access will expand in the coming months. Though knowing Valve, it’s just as possible <em>Deadlock</em>’s barebones Steam page stays that way for another year as its developers continue tinkering under the hood before its ready for prime time. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Of Warcraft Is Adding An Arachnophobia Mode To Keep Spiders At Bay]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/world-of-warcraft-the-war-within-arachnophobia-mode-1851631262</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-warcraft-is-adding-an-arachnophobia-mode-to-keep-spiders-at-bay.963693/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/world-of-warcraft-the-war-within-arachnophobia-mode-1851631262<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If creepy-crawlies such as spiders give you the major heebie-jeebies, the latest quality-of-life feature in <em>World of Warcraft: The War Within </em>will come as something of a relief. The newly added Arachnophobia Mode allows those of us who would rather keep the spiders at bay a shot at enjoying the game without making our skin crawl.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195326" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="326" data-playlist="195326,195150,194907" data-current="195326"><div><p>Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20784.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Since the entirety of the new expansion takes us deep underground into the realm of the Nerubians, there will be a ton of spiders. Here is a quick rundown of how to toggle on the new mode in <em>World of Warcraft: The War Within </em>and what types of content it can change.</p><h2 id="h715"><a id=""></a><strong>How To Toggle Arachnophobia Mode</strong></h2><p>Once you have logged into your character of choice, hit “Escape” and select the “Options” menu. Select “General” within the Accessibility tab, and scroll to the bottom of this menu. You will see the new option to put a checkbox into “Arachnophobia mode” here, as well as toggle it off the same way whenever you’d like. Maybe some days you <em>do</em> like spiders? Toggling the mode will not affect difficulty, nor anything else other than the look of certain enemies, bosses, or NPCs.</p><figure id="" data-id="682f2dd3bb4e7243a7d8fd21877ec3a8" data-recommend-id="image://682f2dd3bb4e7243a7d8fd21877ec3a8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The options screen with an arrow marking the new Arachnophobia Mode." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The options screen with an arrow marking the new Arachnophobia Mode." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="682f2dd3bb4e7243a7d8fd21877ec3a8" data-recommend-id="image://682f2dd3bb4e7243a7d8fd21877ec3a8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The options screen with an arrow marking the new Arachnophobia Mode." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h716"><a id=""></a><strong>What Arachnophobia Mode Can Do</strong></h2><p>The new mode will turn specified creatures and bosses—whether in the outside world, raids, or dungeons—into other creatures like crabs that are less intimidating (for some) than our eight-legged friends. This mode won’t only apply to spiders, as some spider-like creatures will also be changed, based on which creatures Blizzard believes will trigger discomfort by those affected by the phobia.</p><p>The developers do recommend toggling the mode to on as soon as you launch the game, to ensure that all the spooky spiders are managed prior to you running into one along the way. Certain creatures, such as those in pre-rendered cinematics, journal boss entries, loading screen art, item or icon art, and 3D or 2D cobwebs or webbings in-game, will not be changed.</p><p>It’s only taken 20 years for Blizzard to think this might be an idea to make life more pleasant for its arachnophobic players! There’s a good chance the developer might have been inspired by other games recently making similar changes, for instance <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/if-youre-scared-of-spiders-obsidians-upcoming-game-wil-1842778660&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/if-youre-scared-of-spiders-obsidians-upcoming-game-wil-1842778660">Obsidian’s <em>Grounded</em></a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hogwarts-legacy-arachnophobia-ps4-xbox-one-switch-1850409010&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hogwarts-legacy-arachnophobia-ps4-xbox-one-switch-1850409010"><em>Hogwarts Legacy</em></a></span>. For those not fussed by spiders it can seem a peculiar demand, but for those who are affected it can be the difference between not being able to play, and having another mighty game to enjoy.</p><p>  Kabourphobics still have longer to wait.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Announces Indie World & Direct Partner Showcase Coming This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-announces-indie-world-direct-partner-showcase-coming-this-week/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-announces-indie-world-direct-partner-showcase-coming-this-week.963684/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-announces-indie-world-direct-partner-showcase-coming-this-week/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a new <a href="https://x.com/NintendoEurope/status/1828070412883800414" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post on X</a> today, Nintendo announced that an Indie World Showcase and a Nintendo Direct Partner Showcase are coming this week on August 27, 2024.</p>



<p>Nintendo will host a livestream of both presentations back-to-back, starting at 16:00 CEST / 10 am EST / 7 am PST. Today’s post also mentions that the combined runtime of these presentations will add up to about “40 minutes in total.”</p>



<p>It also links to the YouTube channel, where a description again warns fans that “there is no mention of the Nintendo Switch successor during either of these presentations.” Nintendo reiterated this in a follow-up tweet too, as buzz around the Switch successor continues to build.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Nintendo held an Indie World Showcase <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-indie-world-showcase-april-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in April 2024</a>, which did last 22 minutes. It featured a variety of games, with some of the highlights including SteamWorld Heist II and Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles Splintered Fate. </p>



<p>The latter was a welcome surprise for many fans, since it was originally an Apple Arcade title. The anticipated roguelike eventually launched on the Nintendo Switch <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tmnt-splintered-fate-is-coming-to-nintendo-switch-in-july-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in July 2024</a>.</p>



<p>Most recently, Nintendo also held a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-june-2024-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">40-minute Direct showcase</a> in mid-June 2024. That kicked off with Mario &amp; Luigi Brothership, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mario-luigi-brothership-announced-for-november-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced for November 2024</a>. It also featured Nintendo World Championships, Donkey Kong Country Returns HD, Funko Fusion and more.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about 11 bit studios apparently <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/frostpunk-2-developers-tease-mods-with-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">teasing mods and crossovers</a> coming to Frostpunk 2 with a new trailer, and sign up for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blowing A Door Open Never, EVER Gets Old]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/tactical-breach-wizards-pc-impressions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blowing-a-door-open-never-ever-gets-old.963678/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/tactical-breach-wizards-pc-impressions<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After six years in development, <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em>--the latest game from <em>Gunpoint's</em> Tom Francis and friends--is now out. You would be excused for missing it, because <a href="https://aftermath.site/black-myth-wukong-feminist-propaganda-politics-twitch-steam" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Monkey Game</a> has been sucking all the oxygen out of the room, but I'm here to remind you <em>not </em>to miss it, because it rules.</p><p><em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> is tactical brilliance distilled. Remember<em> Into The Breach</em>, and how it took games like <em>Final Fantasy Tactics </em>and stripped them back to the studs? This is like that, but for <a href="https://aftermath.site/tactical-breach-wizards-steam-demo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>XCOM</em>,</a> putting you in control of a team of magicians who are simultaneously <em>Call of Duty </em>characters, in a world where the modern military and magic co-exist.</p><p>When I say this game strips the genre back to the studs, what I mean is that it throws away as much bloat as it can, preferring small rooms to sprawling stages and emphasising economy over all else; you're rewarded for completing missions in as few turns and with as few actions as possible. But you don't <em>need </em>to do this, because the game is also completely fine with you doing whatever you want to get the job done. There's a rewind button that lets you undo moves for free--one of your guys is a time-shifting seer, so why not--and the variety of weapons and spells at your disposal makes every stage less of a tactical slugfest and more of a puzzle you can solve in one of dozens of different ways.</p><p>Though many of those end up in the same place: blasting a guy out a window.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Tactical Breach Wizards is OUT! Here's a launch trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FXMSBXnJlWM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>I could spend all day talking about the ways <em>TBW </em>absolutely nails this brief, about how good it is, how funny it is, how effortlessly it delivers on the absurdity of its setting. I might never shut up about how even the most mundane powers at your disposal, like its take on the tactics staple of overwatch, are now immensely satisfying magic tricks. It's all so perfect, and smart, and cool.</p><p>But there are lots of reviews saying that stuff already, so I instead just want to focus on one thing: breaching. It's one of the three words in the title, and it's the one thing the whole rest of the game is built around. Like I've said, <em>TBW</em> isn't a "big map" kind of tactical experience; instead it breaks down each engagement into small, bite-sized rooms that you tackle sequentially by quite literally smashing the door down each time you move through them.</p><p>Breaching is fun, no matter the scenario, the genre or the game you're doing it in. It's a constant highlight in <em>Call of Duty</em> games, for example, but as fun as that is, it's even <em>better </em>here. The combination of painting a magic rune on the door, blasting it, hearing a satisfying sound effect then getting some visual flair--a bit of flashbang then some zoom while the camera perspective shifts--makes it a blast every time. The opening seconds of the trailer below show what I'm talking about:</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Tactical Breach Wizards: Release Date Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ILThlN_-uGg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>You will see this same animation plentyof times before you're done with this game, multiple times per stage, and it never gets old. It's both funny and deeply satisfying the very first time you encounter it, and it's no different the last.</p><p>Beyond the sensory satisfaction, it got me wondering why breaching is so cool. Maybe because, regardless of whether it's <em>TBW </em>or <em>CoD</em>, it's a fulcrum point, the moment the rubber hits the road, where plans become action, where calm meets chaos. It's <em>important</em>, and what comes after is generally a whirlwind of tactics quickly followed by satisfying execution.</p><p>I wanted to give it a particular shoutout here because I can't think of many other singular moments in video games like it! For me, every time a door blows inwards in <em>TBW</em> feels as special as a <em>Tony Hawk's Pro Skater</em> grind, a <em>Burnout </em>boost or a chainsaw kill in <em>Doom</em>. A perfect moment, no matter how frequently we're exposed to it.</p><p>We've opened doors in countless other games before, but after doing it so many times with explosive runes here it'll be tough going back to doing it the old-fashioned way.&nbsp;</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Toronto Managing Director Says Splinter Cell Remake “Remains in Stealth Mode”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-toronto-managing-director-says-splinter-cell-remake-remains-in-stealth-mode/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-toronto-managing-director-says-splinter-cell-remake-%E2%80%9Cremains-in-stealth-mode%E2%80%9D.963660/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-toronto-managing-director-says-splinter-cell-remake-remains-in-stealth-mode/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At the moment, Ubisoft Toronto is highly ambitious with the number of ongoing projects it has. This isn't limited to just the eagerly awaited Splinter Cell remake. It also includes the upcoming controversial game Star Wars: Outlaws, which is released on August 30. They are also working on the Prince of Persia: Sands of Time remake and, of course, the Splinter Cell remake.</p>
<p><iframe title="Splinter Cell Remake: Stepping Out of the Shadows | Ubisoft [NA]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HH1_ZCSf_HY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><a href="https://www.psu.com/news/ubisoft-toronto-managing-director-says-splinter-cell-remake-ps5-still-in-stealth-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PSU took a trip to Ubisoft Toronto</a> predominantly to discuss behind-the-scenes looks at Star Wars: Outlaws, but also took a moment to ask them about the Splinter Cell remake. The original Splinter Cell was made in 2002 and made way for plenty of other games in the Splinter Cell franchise, with the most recent iteration being in 2013. There is no official planned release date for the Splinter Cell remake, and truthfully, no one knows how long it has left in development. Ubisoft Toronto is remaining relatively hush-hush on the matter.</p>
<p>The Splinter Cell remake was announced in 2021, and very minimal news has appeared since then. In 2022, David Grivel, the person who was supposed to be directing the Splinter Cell Remake, left Ubisoft after 11 years of working there. At the moment, it remains unknown who is leading the project and what sort of development stage the game is in.</p>
<p>When PSU visited for a hands-on of Star Wars: Outlaws, they also asked Managing Director Darryl Long about how the Splinter Cell Remake was shaping up. Much to many excited fans' dismay, he didn't really give much of an answer. Instead, he replied that it would "remain in stealth mode, for now."</p>
<p>Ubisoft recently had their own showcase of sorts named the Ubisoft Forward in June where many were expecting to get some answers to their long-awaited questions regarding the remake. However, those questions still remain unanswered, as there has been no information given in Forward, nor anywhere else.</p>
<p>The only hint that production is still going forward is the number of jobs that popped up during December 2023. There were 12 jobs listed for Ubisoft Toronto, the main studio taking on the massive project of remaking Splinter Cell.</p>
<p>For now, excited fans will have to continue to wait and see for any <a href="https://wccftech.com/splinter-cell-remake-news/">sort of breadcrumbs</a> that Ubisoft Toronto may drop regarding the remake of the iconic 2002 game, but for now, fans will just have to accept that it is in development.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong Helps Steam Reach 37m User Milestone]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-37m-user-milestone-wukong</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-helps-steam-reach-37m-user-milestone.963657/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-37m-user-milestone-wukong<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Steam has broken yet another user count record, thanks in large part to the astonishing (and, perhaps most importantly, continuing) success of single-player action RPG&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>.</p>
<p>As noted by Steam <a href="https://x.com/SteamDB/status/1827757119224857007" rel="noopener" target="_blank">tracking site SteamDB</a>, Valve's gaming platform broke 37 million users this weekend, reaching an impressive total of 37,266,324 users within the last few days.</p>
<p>To remind you, the last time Steam broke its user record was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-player-count-record-sale">around the time of July's summer sale</a>, when the platform managed to reach 36,928,521 users online at the same time. This weekend's record therefore represents a jump of around 300,000 users, which is not too shabby.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/black-myth-wukong-steam-user-count-dragon.jpg?itok=tN2VuZbj 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/black-myth-wukong-steam-user-count-dragon.jpg?itok=qEOs5AuI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Black Myth: Wukong&nbsp;</em>has helped Steam reach a new user count high.</figcaption></figure><p>According <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2358720/charts/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">to SteamDB's data</a>,&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong </em>has managed to reach a concurrent player count of 2,130,243 over the last 24 hours, easily shattering its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/black-myth-wukong-24-hour-player-count">record-breaking launch day player count</a>&nbsp;record.</p>
<p>Of course, players were enjoying other games over the weekend as well; perennially popular games like&nbsp;<em>Counter-Strike 2</em>,&nbsp;<em>Dota 2</em>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/playerunknowns-battlegrounds"><em>PUBG: Battlegrounds</em></a>&nbsp;(as well as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/banana-steam-popular">definitely-not-a-cynical-moneymaking-exercise&nbsp;<em>Banana</em></a>) scored big user numbers this weekend too.</p>
<p>Still, the fact that a single-player game has managed to amass these kinds of numbers is very impressive indeed, especially considering that&nbsp;<em>Wukong&nbsp;</em>is leagues ahead of the <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1086940/charts/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">highest player count</a> achieved by hugely popular RPG&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/baldurs-gate-3">Baldur's Gate 3</a>&nbsp;</em>(which, yes, does technically feature multiplayer).</p>
<p>It also demonstrates that the <a href="https://videogames.si.com/news/black-myth-wukong-streamers-feminist-propaganda" rel="noopener" target="_blank">controversy surrounding the document</a> sent to streamers by&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>'s publisher hasn't really dented the game's sales. It's worth noting, though, that the vast majority of&nbsp;<em>Wukong</em>'s player base is in China, where the story may not have been quite as controversial.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pubg-battlegrounds-steam-user-count.jpg?itok=Y0RKfCqx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pubg-battlegrounds-steam-user-count.jpg?itok=oKqjeeJc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Games like&nbsp;<em>PUBG: Battlegrounds&nbsp;</em>have remained hugely popular as well.</figcaption></figure><p>It remains to be seen whether Steam will break the 38 million user count at some point in the next few months, although if the platform keeps going at its current pace, that seems inevitable. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things Steam.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Visual Concepts South Hit With Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/visual-concepts-south-hit-with-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/visual-concepts-south-hit-with-layoffs.963639/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/visual-concepts-south-hit-with-layoffs/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Visual Concepts South, a division of 2K’s Visual Concepts studio, has been hit with a wave of layoffs. The layoffs broke late last week while many were focused on the events surrounding Gamescom.</p>



<p>“My heart is aching,” 3D artist Katlynn Woodward posted on <a href="https://x.com/Katlynn3D/status/1826692837049860483" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Twitter</a>. “The majority of my team that I worked on Lego 2K Drive with were laid off this week. Less than a year after I was laid off along with countless others.”</p>



<p>Visual Concepts South, as you may have guessed from the above post, was known for being the main studio behind 2023’s Lego 2K Drive. The developers also contributed in development of the NBA 2K series.</p>



<p>“Unfortunately, like many of my colleagues, I was affected by the recent layoffs,” VFX artist Arnold Song wrote on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7232122321510014976/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">LinkedIn</a>.</p>



<p>It’s unknown currently how many people were impacted by these layoffs at Visual Concepts South. Insider Gaming has reached out multiple times to 2K for comment, but no response has been received.</p>



<p>In 2024, <a href="https://gaminglayoffs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over 11,700 people</a> have been impacted by layoffs in the gaming industry across at least 130 companies.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/concords-launch-is-worse-than-expected/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">struggles of PlayStation’s new hero shooter Concord at launch</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming Wrap Up</a>, a once-a-week newsletter with exclusive columns, interviews, and more.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bleach: Rebirth of Souls character trailer – Kisuke Urahara]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-kisuke-urahara</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-%E2%80%93-kisuke-urahara.963636/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-kisuke-urahara<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>A balanced fighter who can manage a variety of situations.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,552 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Tamsoft [288 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tamsoft">Tamsoft</a> have released a new character trailer for fighting <a title="Genres > Action [2,118 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Bleach: Rebirth of Souls [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bleach-rebirth-of-souls">Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</a></em> highlighting playable fighter Kisuke Urahara. <span id="more-909750"></span></p><p>“Who stands freely at close quarters offensively and defensively,” reads Kisuke’s character description. “Kisuke is a balanced fighter with a kit that can manage a variety of situations.”</p><p><em>Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</em> will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,786 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,972 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,104 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,062 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1689620/BLEACH_Rebirth_of_Souls/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date has yet to be announced.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Character Trailer: Kisuke Urahara</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="BLEACH Rebirth of Souls — Kisuke Urahara Character Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pglr-98uFBY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="「BLEACH Rebirth of Souls」キャラクタームービー #07｜浦原喜助" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GaS4ybi0xwA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Indie World Showcase / Nintendo Direct Partner Showcase set for August 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/nintendo-indie-world-showcase-nintendo-direct-partner-showcase-set-for-august-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-indie-world-showcase-nintendo-direct-partner-showcase-set-for-august-27.963633/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/nintendo-indie-world-showcase-nintendo-direct-partner-showcase-set-for-august-27<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A 40-minute combined presentation.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Platforms > Nintendo [20,651 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a> will host a Nintendo Indie World Showcase followed directly by a Nintendo Direct Partner Showcase on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20240827T1400" rel="noopener" target="_blank">August 27 at 7:00 a.m PT / 10:00 a.m. ET</a>, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1828070146117644476" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. Both presentations combined will be roughly 40 minutes in length. You will be able to watch it on YouTube (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bh7o96_yIWw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">America</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tmcgU1_f0Zc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Europe</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R46BMMdYPKU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Japan</a>) and Nintendo.com (<a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/nintendo-direct/08-27-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">America</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.uk/News/Nintendo-Direct/Latest-Nintendo-Direct/Nintendo-Direct-698557.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Europe</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/jp/nintendo_direct/20240827/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Japan</a>). <span id="more-909743"></span></p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1828070150127456613" rel="noopener" target="_blank">According to Nintendo</a>, there will be no mention of the <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,838 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> successor during either of these presentations.</p><p>Stay tuned.</p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Multiplayer Trailer Shows Off What's New In This Year's Call Of Duty]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-multiplayer-trailer-shows-off-whats-new-in-this-years-call-of-duty/1100-6526103/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-multiplayer-trailer-shows-off-whats-new-in-this-years-call-of-duty.963630/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-multiplayer-trailer-shows-off-whats-new-in-this-years-call-of-duty/1100-6526103/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526103">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Activision has released the reveal trailer for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a>'s multiplayer mode, showing off what fans can expect in the multiplayer department from this year's game. In particular, the video provides a better look at Black Ops 6's new "Omnimovement" system that Activision says is a "holistic approach to redefine what Black Ops 6<i> </i>movement really means."</p><p>The trailer also spotlights some of the 16 all-new maps coming to Black Ops 6 at launch. Additionally, it teases the return of Gunsmith and Classic Prestige, among other things. Take a look for yourself in the video below.</p><p>It's a big week for Call of Duty, as the Call of Duty Next event takes place on August 28, with lots of reveals and announcements expected for the multiplayer game. Then on August 30, Black Ops 6's multiplayer beta begins, first for people who <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-preorder-guide/1100-6524005/" data-ref-id="1100-6524005">preorder</a> (or have Game Pass) and then opening to everyone. For more, check out GameSpot's full breakdown of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-beta-dates-how-to-get-in/1100-6524124/" data-ref-id="1100-6524124">how to get into the Black Ops 6 beta.</a></p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1444330414" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464977,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Call%20of%20Duty%3A%20Black%20Ops%206%20-%20Official%20Multiplayer%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:135,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-official-multiplayer-reveal-trailer\/2300-6464977\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464977\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464977\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464977\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464977&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464977,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526103&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty-black-ops-6&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,playstation-5,pc,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;activision,microsoft-game-studios&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464977},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464977\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4356931-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/DouYl71e.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724681520,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="DouYl71e" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6464977" data-src="/videos/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-official-multiplayer-reveal-trailer/2300-6464977/" data-width="854" data-height="480" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 - Official Multiplayer Reveal Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>Black Ops 6 launches on October 25, and even though Microsoft owns Call of Duty and Activision, the game will launch on PlayStation platforms right away. Game Pass subscribers can play Black Ops 6 as part of their membership, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-price-games-tiers/1100-6524825/" data-ref-id="1100-6524825">Game Pass Core and Game Pass Standard subscribers are locked out.</a></p><p>In addition to multiplayer, Black Ops 6's campaign is set in the '90s and features a story involving conspiracy theories and an alternate look at history, as the Black Ops series is known to do. Then there's the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-zombies-gameplay-reveal-and-everything-we-know/1100-6525644/" data-ref-id="1100-6525644">Zombies mode</a>, made by Treyarch, which brings back the popular round-based format.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>