<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 17:28:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disco Elysium-inspired RPG Hollow Home is a memory of Mariupol from before Russia's invasion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-inspired-rpg-hollow-home-is-a-memory-of-mariupol-from-before-russias-invasion</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disco-elysium-inspired-rpg-hollow-home-is-a-memory-of-mariupol-from-before-russias-invasion.921711/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-inspired-rpg-hollow-home-is-a-memory-of-mariupol-from-before-russias-invasion<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>"We want to tell the story of the people, and how the city has changed."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_IxkEVAZ.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Galaktus / Twigames Inc</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>The Ukrainian city of Mariupol came under heavy bombardment during the opening months of Russia's invasion in 2022, a programme of artillery and air strikes that damaged or destroyed the majority of residential buildings and has killed or dispossessed thousands of people. It has now been occupied by Russia for almost two years, during which, as reported by the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-war-erasing-mariupol-499dceae43ed77f2ebfe750ea99b9ad9">Associated Press</a>, Russia has demolished, rebuilt and renamed much of the city, overwriting its Ukrainian heritage.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a>-inspired <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> Hollow Home is a memory of Mariupol from just before the war - not a 1:1 recreation, but a collection of details, colours, personalities and some familiar buildings, painstakingly amassed and offered up in the face of erasure. Speaking to me during a very brief demo at Digital Dragons in Poland this year, artist Anastasia Hlyniana called my attention to the plants jutting from old car tyres around the game's isometric map, which she says are a common sight in Mariupol.</p><!--more-->
<p>Hollow Home began development in 2022, just after Mariupol's occupation, and is partly based on journalistic coverage of the invasion, though its characters and story are fictional. It unfolds over 30 in-game days, beginning shortly before Russia's vicious attack, and casts you as 14-year-old Maksym, who must survive and help others to survive. There's no combat in Hollow Home, and apparently, no direct or "graphic" representation of violence. Instead, the game explores the impact of the war on civilians, and the decline of individual neighbourhoods as residents are killed or flee the city.</p>
<p>Hollow Home's pen-and-paper-style role-playing and splashy, graphic novel colours are immediately reminiscent of ZA/UM's game, but the English writing is relatively straight-laced and reverential, as you might expect given that the devastation of Mariupol is both a lived reality and still unfolding. "It's our perspective on what happened, and also we want to tell the story of the people, and how the city has changed," Hlyniana summarised.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_JXlbJ4g.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Galaktus / Twigames Inc</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Maksym gets a limited supply of action points each day, which you'll use to perform skills such as cooking and first aid, based on character traits such as Sociability and Handiness. During the opening, pre-war section of the game, however, these points are reserved for more innocent activities: clambering onto a roof to fix a satellite dish, telling fibs about why you're ditching school, beating your friend's high score at the arcade, and trying to chase away a bullying older boy. In the course of these teenage antics, you'll meet and map out a community of shopkeepers, car mechanics, nosy neighbours and local layabouts, all speculating about reports of troops massing on the border.</p>
<p>"Some places will be destroyed, some new places will arrive, like shelters, volunteer centres," Hlyniana explained. "Some people will die, some new people will come, and the game has several endings. We aim to have about 24 hours of gameplay, and it will contain about three districts of the city, so it will be one big, typical Ukrainian city."</p>
<p>At the risk of centring my own responses as somebody whose country is not currently under assault, it felt strange to hear the situation in Mariupol outlined in terms of video game reviewer preoccupations like playlength and choice of endings. Sadly, my language skills were not up to the task of asking Hlyniana how the developers feel about positioning this memorial work as a commercial product <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2362070/Hollow_Home/">on Steam</a>, where it must frame itself for consumption alongside RPGs for whom an apocalyptic setting is an escapist fantasy. Hollow Home is due for release in 2025.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Heroes As Transformers Look Pretty Sick, Actually]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-transformers-event-ramattra-reinhardt-skins-1851581064</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-heroes-as-transformers-look-pretty-sick-actually.921702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-transformers-event-ramattra-reinhardt-skins-1851581064<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="961e0c063b1ee788778562fdd3f60c63" data-recommend-id="image://961e0c063b1ee788778562fdd3f60c63" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ramattra and Reinhardt clash in their Transformers skins." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Ramattra and Reinhardt clash in their Transformers skins." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="961e0c063b1ee788778562fdd3f60c63" data-recommend-id="image://961e0c063b1ee788778562fdd3f60c63" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ramattra and Reinhardt clash in their Transformers skins." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Overwatch 2</em>’s latest collaboration gives four of its heroes skins based on <em>Transformers</em>. It <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/media/stories/transmission/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/media/stories/transmission/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">started with a comic</a></span> that seems to actually canonize the robots in disguise within Blizzard’s universe, rather than simply letting its characters “cosplay” something from a different property as it did with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/one-punch-man-doomfist-skin-season-3-event-saitama-1850078252&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/one-punch-man-doomfist-skin-season-3-event-saitama-1850078252"><em>One Punch Man</em></a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-cowboy-bebop-skin-cassidy-sombra-ashe-mauga-1851317241&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-cowboy-bebop-skin-cassidy-sombra-ashe-mauga-1851317241"><em>Cowboy Bebop</em></a></span>. And while I’m growing weary of Blizzard seemingly investing more time and energy in these collaborations than it is in expanding upon <em>Overwatch 2</em>’s own lore, the studio has also released an animated teaser trailer for the crossover that is so slick, I couldn’t help but be won over.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195460" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="195460,196880,192616" data-current="195460"><div><p>Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20938.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The trailer shows Bastion, Ramattra, Reinhardt, and Illari all dressed up like different <em>Transformers</em> characters. Bastion is shown sporting Bumblebee’s signature yellow, Reinhardt swings his hammer as Optimus Prime, Illari takes flight as Arcee, and Ramattra puts his own transformative capabilities to work as Megatron. The animated trailer doesn’t really have any plot to it, but it’s action-packed and beautifully animated. It also has a nifty new arrangement of the <em>Transformers</em> theme. Kinda just makes me wish once again that Blizzard would dump all that money and talent into <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-mauga-a-good-day-animated-short-series-1851065584&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-mauga-a-good-day-animated-short-series-1851065584">an <em>Overwatch </em>animated series</a></span>. Come on, y’all. If you’re <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-story-missions-campaign-canceled-blizzard-1851345720&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-story-missions-campaign-canceled-blizzard-1851345720">reportedly canceling the story missions</a></span> in <em>Overwatch 2</em>, telling that story in an animated series would be the next best thing. Yeah, you’ve done <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anime-genesis-story-missions-youtube-1850659770&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anime-genesis-story-missions-youtube-1850659770">your online shorts</a></span>, but think bigger.</p><p>Check out the full teaser below:</p><p>Unfortunately, the video doesn’t show these skins in-game. But at the very least, <em>Overwatch 2 </em>players know who is getting something new when the <em>Transformers</em> collaboration launches tomorrow on July 9.</p><p><em>Overwatch 2 </em>is in the midst of its eleventh season, and the whole theme seems to be poking at millennial nostalgia, featuring not only the <em>Transformers </em>collaboration but also an homage to <em>Power Rangers </em>via the seasonal event and mythic skin. While that’s all well and good, the game still has some lingering issues with balance that players are having trouble with. Tanks are having trouble across the role, but Blizzard says it <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-tank-heroes-reinhardt-buffs-rework-nerf-1851567261&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-tank-heroes-reinhardt-buffs-rework-nerf-1851567261">will be making adjustments to those heroes in a future update</a></span>.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Pixel RPG Pre-Registrations Are Now Live in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/disney-pixel-rpg-pre-registrations-are-now-live-in-japan/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-pixel-rpg-pre-registrations-are-now-live-in-japan.921699/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/disney-pixel-rpg-pre-registrations-are-now-live-in-japan/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Disney and GungHo Online Entertainment have announced a new mobile gaming title, Disney Pixel RPG. The latest game is set to arrive later this year, and the pre-registrations are live on the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/disney-pixel-rpg/id6502584695" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">iOS App Store </a>and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jp.gungho.tri" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Google Play Store</a>. However, players should note that pre-registrations are only available in Japan, and the developers have yet to confirm the game’s availability in other regions. Learn more about Disney Pixel RPG below.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9J34RDSUVC/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14"></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<h2 id="h-disney-pixel-rpg-s-narrative-nbsp">Disney Pixel RPG’s Narrative &nbsp;</h2>



<p>Disney Pixel RPG is a playground for Disney fans, offering a diverse cast of characters to play as. The story unfolds in a chaotic realm, where diverse game worlds are interconnected, and a series of characters have assembled to save their respective game world. You’ll get to play Maleficent from an RPG, Mickey from a board game, Ariel from a rhythm game, Baymax, Genie, Pooh, Aurora, Stitch and more, each with their own unique abilities and captivating stories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The game worlds are under a mysterious attack and are being broken down by the second. Once, they were all isolated, but they have suddenly come together. All of the characters are confused about what to do, and it is your role as a player to embark on this epic quest with them, save these game worlds from being destroyed, and restore order to this chaotic universe.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-gameplay-elements">Gameplay Elements</h2>



<p>Disney Pixel RPG offers a thrilling gameplay experience with its fast-paced battles. The controls are designed to be simple, ensuring that even newcomers to the genre can dive into the action. The addition of an auto-play feature further enhances the ease of play. You can also send groups of different Disney characters on expeditions to find resources while you’re away. To add a personal touch, you can create your own customizable avatar, complete with a range of Disney-themed clothing items.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, THQ Nordic recently revealed that Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed will arrive<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-is-coming-september-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> this September</a>. Also, Disney Dreamlight Valley devs recently announced a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/disney-dreamlight-valley-devs-announce-dungeons-dragons-project/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dungeons and Dragons project</a>. What are your views on Disney Pixel RPG? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/blumhouse-games-reveals-plans-for-future-titles-adaptations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Blumhouse Games revealing plans</a>&nbsp;for its slate of future titles in a new interview and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2K Is Reportedly Remaking A Game, And Fans Are Filling In The Blanks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2k-is-reportedly-remaking-a-game-and-fans-are-filling-in-the-blanks/1100-6524755/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2k-is-reportedly-remaking-a-game-and-fans-are-filling-in-the-blanks.921696/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2k-is-reportedly-remaking-a-game-and-fans-are-filling-in-the-blanks/1100-6524755/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524755">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It looks like 2K is remaking one of its games, but we don't know any more details about what the game could possibly be. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PS5/comments/1dxep09/report_2k_working_on_unannounced_remake/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fans are taking guesses</a> at what they want to see, with names like BioShock, The Darkness, and Spec Ops: The Line popping up.</p><p>According to the LinkedIn page of a 2K 3D artist (found by <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/report-2k-working-on-unannounced-remake" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">MP1st</a>), 2K is working on an upcoming unannounced remake. However, the mention of the remake has since been removed, as well as any mention of a canceled project by Supermassive Games, called "Erebus." Some other projects that are listed in the profile are upcoming Mafia and BioShock games.</p><p>One possible remake candidate is the first BioShock, as that could drive future interest in the upcoming BioShock game. The first two BioShock games did get remasters for PS4 and Xbox One, but BioShock Infinite didn't. Fortunately, it's backward compatible on Xbox One and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p>Spec Ops: The Line is a cult-classic shooter that was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/spec-ops-the-line-delisting-reason-revealed-director-comments-on-removal/1100-6520743/" data-ref-id="1100-6520743">delisted earlier</a> back in January due to licensing issues, which to some fans could make it a candidate for a remake. The Darkness is a first-person shooter that was released in 2007 and got a sequel in 2012. While that series has remained dormant since, the two games are also backward compatible on Xbox as well.</p><p>We've already known about the new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-new-mafia-game-is-in-development/1100-6506973/" data-ref-id="1100-6506973">Mafia</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-bioshock-game-is-now-in-development/1100-6472016/" data-ref-id="1100-6472016">BioShock</a> games, as 2K announced them back in 2022 and 2019, respectively. However, very few updates about them, if any, have appeared since. Until Dawn developer Supermassive Games <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/until-dawn-dev-supermassive-games-is-cutting-jobs/1100-6521363/" data-ref-id="1100-6521363">laid off employees earlier this year</a>, so it's possible that these cuts may have impacted Erebus.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Huge Spike in Player Count for Bloodborne before Elden Ring DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/huge-spike-in-player-count-for-bloodborne-before-elden-ring-dlc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/huge-spike-in-player-count-for-bloodborne-before-elden-ring-dlc.921678/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/huge-spike-in-player-count-for-bloodborne-before-elden-ring-dlc/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>With the release of the brand new DLC for Elden Ring, players returned to an older FromSoftware classic. While players were waiting to get lost in the <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-patch-1-12-3-brings-more-balance-tweaks-and-bug-fixes/">Shadow of the Erdtree</a>, they returned to Bloodborne.</p>
<p>Bloodborne has always had a huge cult following and has surged back in popularity even ten years later. While players are still waiting and hoping for the day that the game comes to PC, players who have access to the game via a PlayStation 4 or 5 have been jumping back into the game as they waited for the DLC to drop.</p>
<p>A report <a href="https://www.truetrophies.com/news/bloodborne-player-count-july-2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener">from TrueTrophies</a> found that Bloodborne's player count had spiked by a whopping 57% and even spiked by 11% once the DLC had officially dropped. This put Bloodborne back on the leaderboard and was that week's 65th most-played PlayStation game.</p>
<p>If players weren't sinking time into Bloodborne, there was also a rise in popularity for Dark Souls III during the wait for the Elden Ring DLC. However, the number of players who sunk time into Dark Souls III was significantly smaller, at a measly 5.6%.</p>
<p>It's fascinating to see that even ten years later, Bloodborne is still incredibly popular, with many people replaying it multiple times or even people playing it for the first time ever. The fan base has been asking for a 60 FPS patch or even a PC port for many years, but it seems that Sony is still ignoring their call in favor of other PlayStation games, such as Ghost of Tsushima and The Last of Us.</p>
<p>Whether Sony will ever release the rights of Bloodborne back to FromSoftware remains unanswered, and fans can only continue to hope and pray that a Bloodborne PC port will be announced at some point in their lifetime. FromSoftware <a href="https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-pc-port-miyazaki-not-opposed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">certainly isn't opposed</a>, but it's all in Sony's hands.</p>
<p>With Elden Ring being one of the biggest game releases in recent years and having some of the biggest hype for the DLC, it would be the perfect opportunity for Sony to drop an announcement like that and bring further buzz and excitement to those in the community, as well as making Bloodborne a more accessible game.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Piranha Bytes Senior Devs Form New Studio, Pithead Studio]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/piranha-bytes-senior-devs-form-new-studio-pithead-studio/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/piranha-bytes-senior-devs-form-new-studio-pithead-studio.921669/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/piranha-bytes-senior-devs-form-new-studio-pithead-studio/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Not even hours after news broke that Gothic developer <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gothic-developer-piranha-bytes-reportedly-shut-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Piranha Bytes has shut down</a>, news of a new studio formed by former senior developers has emerged. Jennifer and Bjorn Pankratz&nbsp;have announced the launching of Pithead Studio.</p>



<p>The announcement came via a <a href="https://x.com/PitheadStudio/status/1810222288484389201" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">post on social media</a> and a nearly six-minute video on YouTube. The video, with English subtitles, explains the decision from both Jennifer and Bjorn to start Pithead Studio as well as their plans for the company.</p>



<p>“In the future, we will focus on developing Indie Games,” Jennifer Pankratz said. </p>



<p>“Yes, we wanted to keep doing what we love. This seemed like the best way to do it,” Bjorn Pankratz added.</p>



<p>As far as the types of games the pair will be developing, that wasn’t revealed in the video. However, the pair said that every Monday they will be releasing a new video answering questions from the community about Pithead Studio’s future.</p>



<p>“We love to make video games that we personally enjoy playing, and this is exactly what we will do in the future,” Jennifer Pankratz said. “We hope you are looking forward to this as well.”</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="WE ARE BACK ⚒️🦉🦇 Pithead Studio TV" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lCOIsrbctNM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the latest update on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/eve-vanguard-gets-update-from-ccp-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the development of EVE Vanguard</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gran Turismo 7 July Update Includes New Cars, A Track and More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-july-update-includes-new-cars-a-track-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gran-turismo-7-july-update-includes-new-cars-a-track-and-more.921666/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-july-update-includes-new-cars-a-track-and-more/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Gran Turismo World Series 2024 is live in Montreal, featuring adrenaline-fuelled races between some of the best drivers in the world. During the event, a July Update trailer for Gran Turismo 7 was featured, detailing new tracks, cars and more arriving for the game. Learn more about the Gran Turismo July 7 update below.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Next update coming Thursday, 25 July!</p><p>The <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GT7?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GT7</a> July Update trailer was revealed during 'Gran Turismo World Series' 2024 Rd.1, currently taking place in Montréal, Canada 🇨🇦!</p><p>This update will include a variety of content such as new cars and a much-anticipated new track💪<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GTWS?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GTWS</a>… <a href="https://t.co/AE8l1dWtjs">pic.twitter.com/AE8l1dWtjs</a></p></div>— Gran Turismo (@thegranturismo) <a href="https://twitter.com/thegranturismo/status/1809703139421143374?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Gran Turismo 7’s July update is completely free, and it takes players to a breathtaking new region, Eiger Nordwand. It features lush greens and snow-covered peaks as you burn rubber across the scenic tracks. The update will be adding new physics, changing the way the car absorbs shocks and reacts to different types of tracks. Additionally, there are new Michelin tyres and fresh wheels to outfit your vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Get ready for an adrenaline-pumping experience as you challenge Gran Turismo 7’s superhuman racing AI agent, GT Sophy, across Nurburgring 24-hour Autodrome Lago Maggiore. You can take part in this race and other races in some new whips, too; check out the complete list of new cars added to Gran Turismo 7 below:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Ferrari 430 Scuderia 2007</li>



<li>BMW M3 1997</li>



<li>Lamborghini Gallardo LP 560-4 2008</li>



<li>Genesis X Gran Racer Vision Gran Turismo Concept</li>



<li>Subaru Impreza Rally Car 1998</li>



<li>RUF RGT 4.2 2016</li>
</ul>



<p>Players can look forward to exploring all the new content in Gran Turismo 7’s July Update on July 25. In addition, you can check out what cars and world circuits were added in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-april-update-includes-new-cars-and-world-circuits/">previous update</a> and even get a glimpse of the special edition Gran Turismo <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-special-edition-bulgari-watch-unveiling-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bulgari Watch </a>released last year. Let us know how you feel about the upcoming update in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about a new report claiming Gothic developer&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gothic-developer-piranha-bytes-reportedly-shut-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Piranha Bytes shut down</a>&nbsp;last June and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends Will Now Have Two Battle Passes Per Season, Says Respawn]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-will-now-have-two-battle-passes-per-season-says-respawn/1100-6524756/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-will-now-have-two-battle-passes-per-season-says-respawn.921663/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-will-now-have-two-battle-passes-per-season-says-respawn/1100-6524756/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524756">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/apex-legends/">Apex Legends</a>' seasonal battle pass is undergoing a major rework prior to Season 22's launch. In fact, it's not fully accurate to call it one single battle pass, as Respawn has just announced that starting next season, every season will include two battle passes: one that becomes available upon the season's launch, and one that becomes available during the middle of the season, at the same time as the seasonal Ranked Mode split.</p><p dir="ltr">The announcement was made via a post on the official Apex Legends Twitter account, and was accompanied by an infographic explaining the multitude of changes to the game's long-standing battle pass system.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/PlayApex/status/1810330029265420515" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Starting with Season 22, we’re evolving the Apex Legends Battle Pass to improve your experience and progression goals.<br>Read on to learn everything to know about the upcoming changes or check out the infographic below to learn more. <br>📃: <a href="https://t.co/kg5NhlFfVq" rel="nofollow ">https://t.co/kg5NhlFfVq</a> <a href="https://t.co/i516ktP9ma" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/i516ktP9ma</a></p>  — Apex Legends (@PlayApex) <a href="https://twitter.com/PlayApex/status/1810330029265420515?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">Previously, each season included a singular, 110-level battle pass that players had an entire three-month season to complete. The battle pass had a free tier, a premium tier available for 950 Apex Coins ($9.50 USD), and a "premium plus" tier that gave those willing to pay 2,800 AC ($28 USD) a helpful boost, unlocking the first 25 levels of the battle pass instantly.</p><p dir="ltr">Starting with the launch of Season 22, players will no longer need to purchase AC, and can instead purchase the first of the season's two battle passes directly. Each of Season 22's battle passes will cost $9.99 USD for the standard premium tier, and will feature 60 levels of unlockable goodies.</p><p dir="ltr">The free version of the battle pass will still be available, as will the "premium plus" version, the latter of which will cost $19.99 and give players an instant 10-level boost.</p><p dir="ltr">"If you opt to purchase Premium+ for $10 USD more than the Premium Track, you’ll receive an additional 6100+ AC value including: 10 Levels, 2 Premium+ Legendary skin variants per Battle Pass that will be exclusive for one year, 10 Exotic Shards (additional to the 10 in the Premium Track), and ALL Legends playable for the duration of the Battle Pass you purchase this for," explained a <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/news/battle-pass-update" rel="nofollow ">blog post</a> accompanying the Twitter announcement.</p><p dir="ltr">The free rewards track has also been given a boost.</p><p dir="ltr">"AC has doubled across the season: Each split will have 200 AC up for grabs, which brings your total potential currency to 400 AC per season as part of the Free Track," Respawn said of the free battle pass. "We’ve also doubled the Apex Packs, making it 14 Apex Packs per season (7 for each split’s Battle Pass)."</p><p dir="ltr">The free version of the battle pass will also include upgraded cosmetics: Instead of Rare-tier cosmetics, Apex's free battle passes will include a set of Epic-tier cosmetics that include a Legend skin, weapon skin, emote, and four additional Epic-tier items per battle pass.</p><p dir="ltr">But one staple of Apex's previous battle passes will be absent starting next season: Stat trackers have been removed from the game's battle passes, at least for now.</p><p dir="ltr">"Some of y’all are really passionate about these (especially the designed ones), but there were a lot of under utilized Trackers bloating the BP rewards," the blog post reads. "It’s one of the first things we noticed. And while they’re great for gloating, we want you to have bigger and better rewards for your time in-game regardless of how much time you have to spend in the Outlands. We’ll be removing the base level Trackers from the Battle Pass while we work on some quality of life upgrades on the side."</p><p dir="ltr">But Respawn did make sure to reassure players that non-standard trackers featuring unique designs aren't going anywhere. In fact, they'll become much more flexible as a part of the battle pass revamp.</p><p dir="ltr">"Fully designed Trackers featuring art will still be available in the Battle Pass," the blog post explained. "And with our upcoming revamp, Tracker art will become agnostic--meaning you can take any art and put it on any Legend’s banner card. Bloodhound art on Fuse’s card? We ship it."</p><p dir="ltr">The blog post also noted that Season 22's first 60-level battle pass will be available to unlock for free by completing a special set of challenges during the first two weeks of the season.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Colossal Order delays Cities: Skylines II's console launch due to 'unresolved issues']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/colossal-order-delays-cities-skylines-ii-s-console-launch-due-to-unresolved-issues-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/colossal-order-delays-cities-skylines-iis-console-launch-due-to-unresolved-issues.921660/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/colossal-order-delays-cities-skylines-ii-s-console-launch-due-to-unresolved-issues-<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via Colossal Order/Paradox Interactive.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cities: Skylines II </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">was set to come to PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S in October, but Colossal Order has now said it'll be delayed out of that date. This is the second setback for that version, which was originally meant to launch this past spring.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/console-development-status.1694383/">forums</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the developer explained that it hasn't met the desired stability and performance targets. What's more, it claims there are "unresolved issues" that would severely hamper the player experience.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We understand this is disappointing, and it’s not what we had hoped for either," wrote Colossal Order. "However, we are committed to keeping you informed throughout this development process, even if the updates aren’t always what we’d like."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Cities: Skylines II"><span>Cities: Skylines II</span> has fought performance issues since launch</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Things have been </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/the-rushed-attempt-to-rehabilitate-cities-skylines-ii-is-becoming-a-cautionary-tale">rocky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cities: Skylines II </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">since its PC launch in October 2023. While it sold 1 million copies in a matter of months, performance issues have haunted the city-building sim, to the point publisher Paradox admitted it was unhappy with its late 2023 launches and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/paradox-sets-new-revenue-record-says-it-needs-to-address-quality-issues">publicly apologized</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio is making "slow but steady progress" on the console version, and is hoping to lock down a new Release Candidate after a review in August. From there, it can "determine whether we can begin the submission process and provide a solid release date, or if further issues need to be addressed."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Both Colossal Order and Paradox have spoken about working to regain player trust. With </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cities: Skylines II </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">needing both general improvements and proper work on its console version, it may be some time before it's fully regained.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero launches with 50 million worldwide downloads]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/zenless-zone-zero-launches-with-50-million-worldwide-downloads</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-launches-with-50-million-worldwide-downloads.921657/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/zenless-zone-zero-launches-with-50-million-worldwide-downloads<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">MiHoYo's newest action-RPG </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/ZZZ_EN/status/1809527720768074217">Zenless Zone Zero</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">has garnered 50 million downloads worldwide since its launch on July 4.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The game released on PlayStation 5, Windows, and mobile, and builds on the developer's ongoing success in recent years. Last year's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/hoyoverse-s-i-honkai-star-rail-i-had-20-million-downloads-in-one-day">Honkai Star Rail</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">opened with 20 million players at launch, which itself built on the 17 million players for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Genshin Impact.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"A city that once only existed in the hopes and dreams of the dev team has never been as buzzing with life as it is now," wrote MiHoYo.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="MiHoYo's reputation as a hit maker stays intact">MiHoYo's reputation as a hit maker stays intact</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The developer's clout helped </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Zenless, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">as did going viral over the weekend and being free-to-play. The latter market can make almost </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/xdefiant-reportedly-netted-1-million-players-within-2-5-hours-of-launch">any game</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> explode into popularity at launch, particularly if there's been strong marketing behind it.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Genshin </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Honkai, Zenless </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">has received fairly solid reviews, with the studio's gacha mechanics being the main point of contention. MiHoYo noted that the game has "lots of improvements to be made," but was overall pleased with its reception.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the years since their respective launches, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Genshin Impact </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Honkai Star Rail </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">were nominated (and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/honkai-star-rail-leads-google-play-s-best-of-2023-awards">won</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) several awards, and the former has an anime in the works. Time will tell if </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Zenless Zone Zero </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">can reach similar heights.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Japan has avoided the gaming industry’s persistent layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/24191650/nintendo-sega-from-software-japan-video-game-layoffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-japan-has-avoided-the-gaming-industry%E2%80%99s-persistent-layoffs.921627/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/24191650/nintendo-sega-from-software-japan-video-game-layoffs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><p>Typically, layoff season arrives around Christmas: a flurry of pink slips, empty desks, the anxieties of the newly unemployed, all so companies can cut costs and fatten up bottom lines just before the calendar year ends. But for those plying their trade in video games, it has been layoff season for the entirety of the last three years. The approximate number of workers let go globally in 2022 was <a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/vg-layoffs/Archive/2022">8,500</a>; last year, in 2023, that number was <a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/vg-layoffs/Archive/2023">10,500</a>. According to the latest data, the total for the first six months alone of 2024 is <a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/vg-layoffs/Archive/2024">10,800</a>. In the US, some <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/us-video-game-industry-unemployment">experts</a> believe the unemployment rate in the video game industry is as high as 9 percent, over double the <a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/pdf/empsit.pdf">national average</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Amid the video game industry’s cruel fire sale of highly skilled workers, one region remains notably untouched: Japan. (Excluding <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24151047/xbox-shuts-down-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-microsoft">Tango Gameworks</a>, which was shuttered at the direction of its US owner, Microsoft.) On the contrary, recent years have seen many of the country’s firms commit to workers rather than cut them: Sega raised salaries by <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/sega-to-increase-japan-based-employee-salaries-by-30">33 percent</a>, Koei Tecmo upped wages by <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/koei-tecmo-worker-salaries/">23 percent</a>, employees at <em>Persona</em>-maker Atlus saw their incomes jump by <a href="https://kotaku.com/atlus-annual-salary-increase-15-percent-persona-1851025919">15 percent</a>, and Nintendo gave its employees a <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-sticks-with-employee-pay-raises-despite-declining-sales">10 percent</a> raise. Most recently, Capcom increased graduate salaries by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/capcom-announces-salary-increase-for-all-employees-this-year#:~:text=Graduate%20salaries%20will%20rise%20from,to%20attract%20and%20retain%20staff.">27.7 percent</a>, describing it as an “investment in the people who support the future of the company.”&nbsp;</p><p>The recent words of FromSoftware president Hidetaka Miyazaki back up these ostensible labor wins for Japanese workers. Of the mass layoffs that are happening in the US and elsewhere, Miyazaki <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/fromsoftware-boss-addresses-gaming-industry-layoffs-as-long-as-this-companys-my-responsibility-i-would-not-let-that-happen/">said</a>, “as long as this company is my responsibility, that’s something I would not let happen.” But more so than the personal benevolence of leaders like Miyazaki, it is the country’s robust labor regulations that most protect workers. </p><p>“Japanese employment law is, for certain, what protects employees in terms of stability and contract continuity,” says Peter Matanle, an expert on Japanese employment at the University of Sheffield in Britain.</p><div><figcaption><em>Hi-Fi Rush.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Tango Gameworks</cite></p></div><p>Matanle outlines a historic picture not of innate employment rights but one in which Japanese courts, at key moments, such as 1975’s Nihon Shokuen Seizō case, ruled in favor of workers and unions. As a result, one of the key provisions of the country’s employment law, specifically on the “<a href="https://www.shakaiho.com/single-post/2015/10/15/legal-doctrine-of-abusive-dismissal">doctrine of abusive dismissal</a>,” is that “employers can’t just shed employees.” They can only do so, says Matanle, “when the employer can prove that the organization would go bust.”&nbsp;</p><p>Should a Japanese company be found to break the law by, say, reducing its workforce to cynically juice the numbers of a quarterly report, dismissed employees are liable to be reinstated. “You can imagine the relationship problems,” says Matanle, “of staff who have won a court case against the organization for aggressive dismissal.”</p><div><p>“Japanese employment law is, for certain, what protects employees in terms of stability and contract continuity.”</p></div><p>If the lack of Japanese layoffs can be explained in terms of law, then the proliferation of US layoffs can be explained in precisely the same way (alongside conventional wisdom that companies overexpanded during the covid-19 pandemic and the contention of analyst Matthew Ball that <a href="https://www.matthewball.co/all/gaming2024#:~:text=video%20game%20revenues%20are%20falling">gaming revenues are shrinking</a>). The US operates what is commonly known as “at-will” employment, a legal doctrine that some <a href="https://heinonline.org/HOL/LandingPage?handle=hein.journals/amhist60&amp;div=30&amp;id=&amp;page=">scholars</a> date back to the Reconstruction era. Back then, it was argued that if workers had a “right to quit” without restrictions, employers should have a “right to fire.” The doctrine made its way to the Supreme Court in the early 1900s, thereby enshrining in law a boss’s power to fire an employee for no reason at all.</p><p>Beyond the labor law they must adhere to, Matanle notes a divergence between Japanese bosses and their Western peers in terms of “ethical accountability.” Japanese organizations, he suggests, tend to be run with longer-term horizons and are less fixated on pleasing shareholders than their actual employees. Executives are often recruited under “long-term employment systems,” arriving as fresh-faced graduates in their early 20s before rising through the corporate ranks. Compare this to the US, where executives are often outsiders to their respective industries, the product of a culture where it is commonplace — and even advantageous — to switch jobs every few years.&nbsp;</p><div><figcaption><em>Late Nintendo president Satoru Iwata at the Game Developers Conference in 2011.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Photo by Kim White / Nintendo of America via Getty Images</cite></p></div><p>In the light of Japanese labor law, the much-mythologized personal pay cuts of former Nintendo president Satoru Iwata in <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/iwata-takes-50-percent-pay-as-he-takes-responsibility-for-3ds">2011</a> and <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-25941070">2014</a> appear a touch less selfless. (Although there certainly were other options on the table in terms of savings, like voluntary redundancies, which Japanese studio <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/japanese-studio-gumi-wants-80-people-to-accept-voluntary-redundancy">Gumi</a> recently asked around 80 employees to accept.) It’s worth stressing that when Japanese companies are able to make cuts, particularly those operating internationally, they tend to do so. Case in point: Nintendo, which laid off <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-of-europe-will-lay-off-320-people-this-month-1627924242">320 employees</a> at Nintendo of Europe just a few months after Iwata and other executives took pay cuts in 2014. More recently, Square Enix <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/square-enix-confirms-us-eu-layoffs-as-part-of-restructuring/">laid off</a> an unspecified number of workers across its US and European offices. These examples speak to Matanle’s key point: it is Japanese labor law that protects the country’s workers.&nbsp;</p><p>But even if there is no danger of the layoff season arriving in Japan, the country is hardly a proletariat utopia. When Liam Edwards, co-founder of Kyoto-based studio Denkiworks, started working at Q-Games, the studio founded by <em>Star Fox</em> lead developer Dylan Cuthbert, he encountered a tough working environment. It was one he was acutely well prepared for, having often worked “12 hour days, 6 days a week” at Rockstar Lincoln. “I heard a lot of staff [at Q-Games] complain about overtime, the hours, and expectation [of work],” he says, “never really from Japanese staff, because they were used to it, but certainly from other foreign staff.”</p><div><p>“My only real complaint with those years was that I was just working all the time. That’s just the normal state of things at Japanese studios.”&nbsp;</p></div><p>Historically, the country’s game makers have produced some of the most innovative, playful video games under such grueling conditions. Jake Kazdal, co-founder of the 15-person Kyoto studio 17-Bit, worked at Sega in the late ’90s and early 2000s under the stewardship of <em>Rez </em>creator Tetsuya Mizuguchi. “My only real complaint with those years was that I was just working all the time,” he says. “That’s just the normal state of things at Japanese studios.”&nbsp;</p><p>Japanese studios also rely on contract and temporary labor, which has the effect of creating a kind of two-tier labor system similar to that which exists in the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/sep/24/google-temps-fighting-two-tier-labor-system">US</a>. Job security is reserved for those who are permanently employed, i.e., seishain. Those employed on temporary contracts are called keiyakushain, and if cuts are to be made, it tends to come in the form of their contracts not getting renewed. Finally, there are haken, dispatch workers or “hired guns,” says Colin Williamson, lead tech artist at 17-Bit who has worked in Japan for 15 years including a stint at Square Enix in the aughts. In his experience, haken tend to be brought in for short periods of time to do “low-level graphics engineering” and other “hardcore stuff.”&nbsp;</p><p>Haken aren’t employed by studios themselves but by outsourcing firms such as <a href="https://www.cri.co.jp/">Creek &amp; River</a> (which has contributed landscape modeling, character modeling, and texture to the likes of <a href="https://www.cri.co.jp/case_studies/produce/000542.html"><em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em></a> and <a href="https://www.cri.co.jp/case_studies/produce/000517.html"><em>Pokémon Scarlet </em>and<em> Violet</em></a>). For the time they spend at the studio, Williamson says haken are “honorary team members… in the trenches with everybody else.” But ultimately, their tenure is short-lived. “The stability isn’t there,” continues Edwards. “Imagine going to work somewhere for six months, making a life for yourself with new colleagues, all to go away as soon as you leave. That must be tough.”</p><div><figcaption><em>Hidetaka Miyazaki (center) at the Game Awards in 2019.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Photo by JC Olivera / Getty Images</cite></p></div><p>Still, if video game workers anywhere in the world are safe from the interminable layoffs, then it is those who are permanently employed in Japan. Serkan Toto, a veteran analyst of the Japanese games industry based in Tokyo, points to the country’s long-term shrinking population (down <a href="https://www.nippon.com/en/japan-data/h01967/#:~:text=The%20population%20of%20Japanese%20citizens,women%20and%20423%2C000%20for%20men.">837,000</a> in 2024) as an additional factor that could theoretically benefit workers by pushing up demand for their services. The Japanese language, spoken by relatively few people outside of the country (compared to the world’s de facto lingua franca, English) might also prove itself a boon to workers, making their roles less susceptible to outsourcing in a country with lower wages. These are idiosyncratic quirks of a country that, stresses Toto, “has its own game culture, its own business culture, its own insular ecosystem of game companies.” It’s one that is able to, and often does, march to the beat of its own drum.&nbsp;</p><p>Yet Kazdal and Edwards, expats in Japan with deep connections to Europe and the US, find themselves at the mercy of a currently merciless global video game economy. “Most of our contacts are with western publishers,” says Kazdal. “We’re in the same boat [as Western studios], having to get our next deal signed, competing with everybody else in a funding landscape that is more challenging than ever.” The mantra Kazdal says he and his colleagues who run independent studios are chanting is “survive ‘till 2025.”&nbsp;</p><div><p>Japan “has its own game culture, its own business culture, its own insular ecosystem of game companies”</p></div><p>For all the current stresses, 17-Bit is in better shape than it perhaps would have been following an acquisition deal with Embracer, the former conglomerate that, in June 2023, began a cost-saving exercise that resulted in some 4,532 workers <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-the-human-cost-of-embracers-restructuring-programme">losing</a> their jobs. Multiple meetings were held and numbers were being pushed around, reveals Kazdal, but in the end, negotiations stalled. “Thank God we didn’t go through with it,” he says. “They’re just trashing stuff, throwing people out left and right. It’s a disaster.”&nbsp;</p><p>The actions of Embracer’s C-suite and those at video game companies couldn’t stand in sharper relief to the famous <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2013/7/5/4496512/why-nintendos-satoru-iwata-refuses-to-lay-off-staff">words</a> of Nintendo’s Iwata who, just over a decade ago, said, “I sincerely doubt employees who fear that they may be laid off will be able to develop software titles that could impress people around the world.” These are the words Miyazaki was referencing when he spoke about avoiding layoffs at FromSoftware: it is not just the angst, nervousness, and worries of an endemic layoff culture that affects work but also the practicalities of securing alternative employment, drawing focus away from the task at hand.</p><p>For the employees of Nintendo, this is simply not a concern, nor will it be barring changes in legislation. One can speculate whether it was personal conviction or Japanese labor law that ultimately dissuaded Iwata from enacting layoffs (maybe it was both!), but that doesn’t mean his words ring any less true.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cities: Skylines 2 console launch delayed again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-console-launch-delayed-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cities-skylines-2-console-launch-delayed-again.921621/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-console-launch-delayed-again<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"There are still unresolved issues."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Cities-Skylines-2-cropped.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Paradox/Colossal Order</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Publisher Paradox Interactive has delayed Cities: Skylines 2's console release once again.</p>
<p>The game was initially slated to arrive on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-gets-first-gameplay-trailer-october-release-date">Xbox Series X/S and PS5 alongside PC in October last year</a>. However, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-console-release-gets-delayed">this date got moved to spring</a>, before getting <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-publisher-refunds-dlc-and-admits-we-let-you-down">bumped back again to October of this year</a>. At this time, the team said it had been "struggling to get Cities: Skylines 2 to the necessary level of optimisation for a console release".</p>
<p>Now, the game's console launch isn't going to be in October either, as the team has "not yet met the stability and performance targets" it had set for Xbox and PlayStation.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Cities: Skylines 2 official gameplay trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ATX4tryenDM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In a new post, <a href="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/console-development-status.1694383/">Paradox</a> said the team is making "slow [and] steady progress", but there are still "unresolved issues" it needs to address before Cities Skylines 2 is ready to make its console debut.</p>
<p>"We expect to receive a new [Release Candidate], which will undergo a thorough review in August," the company said today. "This evaluation will determine whether we can begin the submission process and provide a solid release date, or if further issues need to be addressed."</p>
<p>Paradox said it understood this news was likely disappointing for those eager to see Cities: Skylines 2 on consoles, adding it remains "committed to keeping you informed throughout this development process, even if the updates aren't always what we'd like".</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_8201697e698f66e89d73147d744c9c7918acd83d.1920x1080.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Paradox</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Cities: Skylines 2 has had a rough time of it over the past several months.</p>
<p>Ahead of its release, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-performance-has-not-achieved-the-benchmark-we-targeted-paradox-admits-ahead-of-launch">Paradox confessed the city building sequel had "not achieved the [performance] benchmark we targeted"</a>, but it still decided not to delay the PC launch. Then, back in April, the company along with developer Colossal Order issued a stark apology for the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-fans-complain-of-performance-woes-after-developer-admits-it-missed-target">state of Cities: Skylines 2</a> and the release of its recent DLC, admitting to fans: "We let you down". </p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EVE Vanguard Gets Update From CCP Games]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/eve-vanguard-gets-update-from-ccp-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eve-vanguard-gets-update-from-ccp-games.921612/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/eve-vanguard-gets-update-from-ccp-games/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>CCP Games, the studio behind <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/inspiring-journey-eve-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the ever-popular EVE Online</a>, has released its latest update on the development of EVE Vanguard.</p>



<p>The studio is transitioning from the “First Strike” era of development in 2024 to the “Solstice era” for the second half of the year for members of the<a href="https://vanguard.eveonline.com/#founders-access" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"> game’s Founders Program</a>. </p>



<p>As far as what’s currently being developed, CCP Games is working on improving player progression and rewards, adding new gameplay elements, “expanding the frontlines” with more depth to corruption and suppression, and enhancing the player agency of the game, among other improvements. </p>



<p>In addition to the roadmap release, the studio provided fans with an update video looking into the future of EVE Vanguard. You can watch that video below.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>CCP Games is planning to launch EVE Vanguard into Steam Early Access following a major update coming in November 2024. This update will “introduce new features such as stronger economic links to&nbsp;<em>EVE Online</em>, a strategic deployment map featuring diverse planetary environments, engagement with multiple factions, weapon chipset crafting, and more emergent activities.” </p>



<p>No specific date on when Early Access would launch was provided.</p>



<p>Set in the EVE Universe, EVE Vanguard is an online sandbox FPS. The game takes place 21,000 years into the future “on far-flung worlds across the star cluster of New Eden”.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Vanguard in Focus | A Future Vision" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I1wrjMwUrwk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the latest update for EVE Vanguard? For more Insider Gaming, check out the first <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-sports-college-football-25-gets-first-full-look-at-gameplay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full look at gameplay for College Football 25</a>, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Okami's Creators Explain How It Could Have Been Even Better, How It Could Have Saved Clover Studio, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hideki-kamiya-and-ikumi-nakamura-discuss-okamis-development-brilliance-and-its-many-challenges</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/okamis-creators-explain-how-it-could-have-been-even-better-how-it-could-have-saved-clover-studio-and-more.921609/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/hideki-kamiya-and-ikumi-nakamura-discuss-okamis-development-brilliance-and-its-many-challenges<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Capcom and Tango Gameworks veteran Ikumi Nakamura hasn't been shy about her love and nostalgia for the project that initiated her into AAA development: Ōkami. And now in a new video conversation with Hideki Kamiya, the pair have opened up about Ōkami's development, including Kamiya's belief that its development team as a whole...could have been better.</p><p>This comes from a new entry in a video series presented by Nakamura's new studio, Unseen, called Ask Ikumi. In it, she's been sharing all sorts of behind the scenes game development insights both on Unseen's project, Kemuri, and her own development experience. In this latest video, she sits down to chat with longtime colleague Hideki Kamiya, with whom she worked on Ōkami, Bayonetta, and briefly on Scalebound. Their conversation largely focuses on Ōkami's development, and the pair has a lot to say!</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The video opens with Kamiya explaining his notorious philosophy of blocking anyone who annoys him on Twitter by asking questions he's answered before, or not addressing him in Japanese. They then launch into a discussion of Ōkami's development. First, they discuss its original conception in a photo-realistic style. Ōkami was apparently first conceived while Kamiya was working on Viewtiful Joe, and saw work on the Resident Evil remake for GameCube being done next to him. He was impressed by the realism, and wanted to use that style for something more "light-hearted" than the horror genre. So Ōkami was conceived as a game about "healing."</p><p>But, he says, the photorealistic style they were aiming for was a struggle to get working on PS2. With Ōkami in trouble, the team was looking for new ideas, when character designer Kenichiro Yoshimura drew main character Amaterasu with a brush. This design sparked a new visual style for the entire game. Not long after, the studio leads convened a three-day summit over a weekend to revamp the game, during which time the Celestial Brush was pitched, and Ōkami changed directions for the better.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Ōkami was supposed to be Clover Studio's signature title...It was supposed to be a dream team with all the best staff in each section. That was the plan, but in the end, not everyone, but as the whole team, I frankly think it was weak.</p></div><p>But even so, Kamiya is candid that Ōkami could have been even better. For one, Ōkami was supposed to have a bigger story, but the team ran out of time and ended midway through what Kamiya wanted to do. What's more, Kamiya has apparently been notoriously critical of the team that worked on Ōkami, as Nakamura brings up. She reminds him that at a party near the end of development, Kamiya apparently said to the whole room, "This team was the worst!" Kamiya admits it, and while he backs off his comments at the time a bit, he goes on to say he was "half right."</p><p>"Ōkami was supposed to be Clover Studio's signature title," he says. "That's why we wanted to create a dream team. It was supposed to be a dream team with all the best staff in each section. That was the plan, but in the end, not everyone, but as the whole team, I frankly think it was weak.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Kemuri Exclusive Concept Art - Fan Fest 2024</h3></div></output><p>"It wasn't a dream team. There was a very drastic contrast within. There were certainly people without whom there would be no Ōkami. Those members shone brightly. Some of them really shone stronger even more than ones I had worked with previously. I'm not saying this as flattery, but you [Nakamura] certainly did. Naoki Katakai and Keniichirou Yoshimura, Sawaki Takeyasu, Mari Shimazaki, Hiroshi Yamaguchi. I'm really grateful, but when viewed as a whole, it wasn't a dream team."</p><p>Kamiya elaborates a little further in banter with Nakamura here and later in the interview, suggesting  that the issue was that the level of passion and enthusiasm for Ōkami wasn't high throughout the entire team, but instead was rather uneven. Nakamura acknowledges she noticed this, too.</p><p>"If I think about the Viewtiful Joe and DMC teams, the passion was uniformly high," Kamiya says. "But in Ōkami's team there was a huge contrast."</p><p>"Because all the users who played and enjoyed Ōkami, I'm sure they all think it was made by a great team, but actually, that wasn't the case," Kamiya concludes. "This is my honest opinion."</p><p>The full conversation between Kamiya and Nakamura is fascinating and worth watching in its entirety. In it, Kamiya refers to Ōkami as a "failure" (though he seems to be referring to commercial success) and notes that Clover Studio could have continued existing if it had been successful. Nakamura also states that Ōkami has had the greatest influence on the work she's doing now at Unseen with Kemuri. You can watch the whole video right here, and then <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/exclusive-ikumi-nakamura-kemuri-interview-fan-fest-2024">catch up on our own interview with Nakamura</a> from IGN FanFest earlier this year.</p><p><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Multiplayer Mod Gains Traction Following Successful Playtest]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-multiplayer-mod-gains-traction-following-successful-playtest</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-multiplayer-mod-gains-traction-following-successful-playtest.921603/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-multiplayer-mod-gains-traction-following-successful-playtest<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> multiplayer mod CyberMP has gained traction following a successful playtest in which 20 players ran around in the same Night City.</p><p>The one-person developer behind <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCPnq_U4kBrcVbyZNTphPbUg/videos" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CyberpMP</a> recently invited YouTuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7oKJTufdwzU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JuiceHead</a> and others to test its multiplayer version of Cyberpunk 2077, and it actually worked. Though lacking proper animations, never mind quests, the mod lets players roam the open world together, engage in firefights, and race across Night City.</p><p>This bare bones version of a full Cyberpunk 2077 multiplayer mode is therefore a far cry from official contemporaries like Grand Theft Auto Online but may lay the groundwork for one. JuiceHead noted "no issues with lag or players teleporting around", and, even in a 15-player death match, "the sync was almost perfect."</p><p>The mod currently lacks proper player animations because, as Cyberpunk 2077 only exists as a single-player, first-person game, developer CD Projekt had no reason to make the player look good in third-person.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Cyberpunk 2077: Phantom Liberty Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>The mod is still in active development, of course, so there's a chance this will be added before it's released fully. The developer has already made clear it won't receive quest support, however, so the mod won't be as involved as a full GTA Online-style mode. That being said, it does have mod support itself, so there's always a chance other community members will work on additional features after it's released. It has no launch date yet, but as even this basic version seems to work quite well, a full release is perhaps not too far off.</p><p>Cyberpunk 2077 players have longed for a multiplayer mode ever since CD Projekt itself announced it, but <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077s-multiplayer-mode-was-cancelled-following-its-turbulent-launch">the game's infamous launch saw it canceled</a> as work was instead focused on fixing the base game.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cd-projekt-considering-adding-multiplayer-to-cyberpunk-2">It's not ruled out for the Cyberpunk 2077 sequel</a> currently in development at CD Projekt, however, so players may have some hope for some official multiplayer shenanigans in the future.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Retro Revengers coming to PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, and Xbox One on July 23]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/retro-revengers-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-july-23</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/retro-revengers-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-july-23.921600/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/retro-revengers-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-july-23<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Retro-style adventure platformer game inspired by hits of the past.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Ratalaika Games [30 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ratalaika-games">Ratalaika Games</a> will release ALEX-developed retro-style <a title="Genres > Action [1,995 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,604 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [481 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Retro Revengers [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/retro-revengers">Retro Revengers</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,421 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,662 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,910 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,309 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> on July 23, the publisher announced. Wishlisting is available now via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10011613" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a>. <span id="more-897444"></span></p><p><em>Retro Revengers</em> first launched for Switch on July 28, 2023 in Japan under the publishing of <a title="Companies > Happymeal [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/happymeal">Happymeal</a>, and was released worldwide by <a title="Companies > Shinyuden [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/shinyuden">Shinyuden</a> for Switch and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2445640/Retro_Revengers/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on August 24, 2023.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Ratalaika Games:</p><blockquote><p>Far out in the uncharted backwaters of the unfashionable end of Central Japan lies Ludens Castle, where five friends, the Retro Revengers, get isekai’d into a strange land that threatens the existence of not just their games, but their world too.</p><p>Embark on a journey with Ossan, Mao, Taicho, Matchan and Notchi as you harness their newfound abilities bestowed upon them by the Retro Goddess. Meet companions from the past, defend yourself from enemies, and overcome the bosses blocking your way to the Demon Overlord of Triple-A.</p><p>Explore diverse stage environments and different powers with each companion, all in beautiful 16-bit pixel art and accompanied by retro music. Master the characters’ different powers as you traverse diverse environments full of unforgiving enemies in this retro-style platformer.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>With the stages and their mechanics changing as you progress through the game, switch between the characters to find the fastest way through each level. The upbeat music and a narrative bursting with references and easter eggs will keep you on the edge of your seat until the very end!</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eve Vanguard roadmap outlined for the ‘Solstice Era’ of the MMO shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/08/eve-vanguard-roadmap-outlined-for-the-solstice-era-of-the-mmo-shooter/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eve-vanguard-roadmap-outlined-for-the-%E2%80%98solstice-era%E2%80%99-of-the-mmo-shooter.921552/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/08/eve-vanguard-roadmap-outlined-for-the-solstice-era-of-the-mmo-shooter/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>CCP Games has shared a big update on the future roadmap for their online FPS EVE Vanguard, their latest attempt at creating a counterpart to the long-running MMO EVE Online, as the in-development game shifts from the ‘First Strike era’ to the ‘Solstice era’.</p>
<p><iframe title="Vanguard in Focus | A Future Vision" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I1wrjMwUrwk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>EVE Vanguard boils down to being CCP’s take on the PvPvE extraction shooter, with players dropping into the world of New Eden, scrounging for loot drops, and then trying to get out before other players steal their stuff – or trying to grab the loot that others have collected. That’s then wrapped into an overarching meta game to determine control of New Eden for factions, and with teams able to take on jobs put out there by other players.</p>
<p>The game was opened up to with private Founders’ Playtests through the First Strike era, with plenty fans of CCP’s last FPS attempt, Dust 514, getting to sample the action. The transition to the Solistice Era was marked with the introduction of a new map, the adaptive weaponry system, new tools and gadgets, new objectives and activities, and more. Through the second half of the year,&nbsp;there will be regular dev diaries and AMAs, as well as a more focused testing and development approach through the second half of this year. These efforts will culminate in a major feature update in November.</p>

<p>The aim is to gradually deepen and grow the gameplay loop within the ethos of EVE Online, to which Vanguard is an additive experience as opposed to a standalone shooter as Dust 514 was. To that end, they’re trying to deepen that link between Online and Vanguard.</p>

<p>In the fullness of time, EVE Vangard will launch into Steam Early Access, though the timing of this will be announced at a later date, and likely won’t come this year.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.eveonline.com/news/view/directors-letter">EVE Online</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elex and Gothic Developer Piranha Bytes Reportedly Shut Down]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/piranha-bytes-shut-down-report</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elex-and-gothic-developer-piranha-bytes-reportedly-shut-down.921549/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/piranha-bytes-shut-down-report<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Gothic&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Risen&nbsp;</em>developer Piranha Bytes appears to have been shut down by parent company THQ Nordic (itself owned by Embracer Group), if a new report is to be believed.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.cdaction.pl/newsy/piranha-bytes-closed-the-end-of-the-studio-behind-gothic-risen-and-elex" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a report by Polish gaming news platform CD-Action</a>, the developer, which is known for mechanically clunky but ambitious RPGs like&nbsp;<em>Risen</em>,&nbsp;<em>Gothic</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Elex</em>, was shut down towards the end of last month.</p>
<p>The report claims that Piranha Bytes was expecting funding to arrive from an investor for its latest project, which CD-Action says would have been a&nbsp;<em>Gothic</em>-style dark fantasy RPG created in Unreal Engine 5.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/piranha-bytes-shut-down-rumor-elex-2.jpg?itok=DrhWH6Hr 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/piranha-bytes-shut-down-rumor-elex-2.jpg?itok=usRf3ByS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Don't expect any more&nbsp;<em>Elex&nbsp;</em>games any time soon.</figcaption></figure><p>It's worth noting that CD-Action simply cites an anonymous "source" who is supposedly a Piranha Bytes employee, but since that employee isn't named, make sure to take this report with a pinch of salt.</p>
<p>It does, however, line up with what we already know about Piranha Bytes' situation. Back in January, the studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/piranha-bytes-rumors-difficult-situation">described its situation as "difficult"</a>, imploring fans not to "write us off yet" with regards to an unannounced project.</p>
<p>Piranha Bytes said at the time that it would "do whatever it takes" to find a publishing and funding partner for the project, but it seems that if CD-Action's report is correct, those efforts sadly haven't borne fruit.</p>
<p>Additionally, Piranha Bytes creative director and longtime staffer&nbsp;Björn Pankratz <a href="https://x.com/PitheadStudio/status/1810222288484389201" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced earlier today</a> that he has founded a new indie studio, Pithead, along with his wife Jennifer, although <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bj%C3%B6rn-pankratz-4b926a5/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">his LinkedIn page</a> still lists him as a current employee of Piranha Bytes.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/thq-nordic-gothic-remake-piranha-bytes.jpg?itok=tAhUiG5h 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/thq-nordic-gothic-remake-piranha-bytes.jpg?itok=1_KzQ68m 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A&nbsp;<em>Gothic&nbsp;</em>remake is in the works, but it's nothing to do with Piranha Bytes.</figcaption></figure><p>If Piranha Bytes has indeed been closed, then that means the studio's final project was 2022's&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/elex-2-review"><em>Elex 2</em></a>, an action RPG very much in the Piranha Bytes tradition. There are worse ways to go out, eh?</p>
<p>Of course, this won't impact the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Gothic&nbsp;</em>remake. Although Piranha Bytes was the developer for the original&nbsp;<em>Gothic</em>, the new project is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-thq-nordic-studio-alkimia-interactive-to-develop-gothic-remake">being worked on by an internal THQ Nordic studio</a> and doesn't involve Piranha Bytes.</p>
<p>We contacted THQ Nordic for further information on this story, but they refused to comment on the situation. Watch this space for more info.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dr Disrespect Skins Removed From Abandoned Online Shooter, Players Refunded With Fake Money]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/rogue-company-dr-disrespect-skin-refund-hirez-sexting-1851580867</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dr-disrespect-skins-removed-from-abandoned-online-shooter-players-refunded-with-fake-money.921546/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/rogue-company-dr-disrespect-skin-refund-hirez-sexting-1851580867<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Free-to-play tactical shooter <em>Rogue Company</em> has disabled all cosmetics themed around Guy “Dr Disrespect” Beahm in the game following the streamer’s admission that he was banned from Twitch back in 2020 for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-twitch-ban-sexting-minor-response-1851559888&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-twitch-ban-sexting-minor-response-1851559888">having “inappropriate” conversations with a minor</a></span>. Players will get refunds but only in the form of Rogue Bucks, the premium in-game currency for the shooter that hasn’t been updated in years.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196626" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Who Is The Best Hang In Unicorn Overlord? A Scientific Ranking" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="271" data-playlist="196626,195386,196251" data-current="196626"><div><p>Who Is The Best Hang In Unicorn Overlord? A Scientific Ranking</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22184.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/rogue-company-is-fine-just-fine-nothing-more-its-fin-1844447518&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/rogue-company-is-fine-just-fine-nothing-more-its-fin-1844447518">Remaining players</a></span> began to notice last week that the controversial streamer’s skins had been disabled in-game. “hey, @RogueCompany appreciate yall taking away the ability to use my @DrDisrespect skin that was $40 that I paid for,” one <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/CABOOSE27xx/status/1809627847222276499&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/CABOOSE27xx/status/1809627847222276499" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote</a></span> on Twitter. “no excuses or reasons to revoke access to something I paid for.” The set was added back in October 2020, shortly after Beahm’s now infamous Twitch ban, and included a skin for <em>Rogue Company</em>’s Dallas character for $20 and a bundle of accessories for another $20. </p><p>Publisher Hi-Rez didn’t respond until July 7 when it issued a statement confirming players would get refunds in the coming days, though only in in-game currency. “Hey Rogue Company, we have disabled Dr. Disrespect content previously available on game,” the company <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/roguecompany/status/1810028535882342577?s=46&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/roguecompany/status/1810028535882342577?s=46" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted</a></span>. “We will provide full Rogue Buck refunds to any impacted account this week.”</p><p>The Rogue Company skins were one of several Dr Disrespect collaborations that companies have formally distanced themselves from in recent weeks after <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-sexting-twitch-ban-youtube-elden-ring-1851556854&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-sexting-twitch-ban-youtube-elden-ring-1851556854">Beahm’s “sexting” allegations spread online</a></span>. The streamer’s in-game appearance in <em>NBA2K24 </em>was also pulled, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-turtle-beach-twitch-ban-sext-minor-1851559715&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-turtle-beach-twitch-ban-sext-minor-1851559715">former sponsor Turtle Beach</a></span> erased Beahm and its Dr Disrespect-themed gaming headset from its website. </p><p>While Beahm used to stream <em>Rogue Company</em>, he hasn’t touched it in years, nor have many others. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://famiboards.com/threads/hi-rez-ending-support-for-paladins-and-rogue-company-on-nintendo-switch.6103/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://famiboards.com/threads/hi-rez-ending-support-for-paladins-and-rogue-company-on-nintendo-switch.6103/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hi-Rez announced last year</a></span> it was pulling everyone off the game, as well as its hero shooter <em>Paladins</em>, to focus almost exclusively on its popular MOBA<em> Smite </em>and its sequel, expected later this year. <em>Rogue Company</em> hasn’t received new content since 2022, and its concurrent player count on Steam has dwindled into the low hundreds in recent months. </p><p>That will make the new refunds all but meaningless to any players who had previously purchased the Dr Disrespect pack. “Lol you guys are wild,” reads one recent negative Steam review trashing the move, though it’s clear some players are just as angry that the skins were disabled for them in the first place. “This sucks I only played the game for the doc skin,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/CABOOSE27xx/status/1809637385300267045&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/CABOOSE27xx/status/1809637385300267045" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted</a></span> one fan. </p><p>Beahm is currently on hiatus from streaming after putting out a statement in which he said messaging a minor was “stupid” but that he’s “no fucking predator or pedophile.” Even if he returns, it’s unclear where he’ll go now that YouTube has demonetized his entire 4 million subscriber channel. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>