<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:30:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pure Rock Crawling looks like a knockabout MudRunner without the mud]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pure-rock-crawling-looks-like-a-knockabout-mudrunner-without-the-mud</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pure-rock-crawling-looks-like-a-knockabout-mudrunner-without-the-mud.1080081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pure-rock-crawling-looks-like-a-knockabout-mudrunner-without-the-mud<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>It received a new map today</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/pure-rock-crawling-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Maciej Kuzianik</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Pure Rock Crawling is about steering off road vehicles across rocky terrain. It's about pumping the gas pedal and wrenching the steering wheel just so, such that you lurch forward and over the obstacles, rather than tumbling backwards. It's MudRunner without the mud, with a knockabout simplicity presumably as a result of its apparently one-man development team. It launched last October but I hadn't heard of it until today, when a new map was added, and now I want to play it.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/824720/Pure_Rock_Crawling/">Steam page</a> boasts of the features you'd want: it's got soft body physics on the tires, suspension that you can tweak as if you know what you're doing, and a range of different kinds of terrain to free roam around. The latest hunk of terrain is a map called Ghost Mine, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/824720/view/518576368664969762">based on photogrammetry assets created by the game's maker after a trip to Death Valley</a>.
</p>
<p>It seems like Pure Rock Crawling was released in Early Access in April 2018 and hit 1.0 in October 2024. I really don't know how I've never heard of it before, but it looks like its 1.0 release hasn't stopped there being a trickle of new updates in the months since. 
</p>
<p>I liked <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/spintires">Spintires</a> back when it came out some ten years ago, then lost track of it when it became mired in the mud of controversy and was succeeded by MudRunners. There's something supremely satisfying about getting up and over an obstacle, whether you're driving a big rig or even a dirt bike in a game like Trials. I have no interest in high scores or improving my times, but I will absolutely have a go at hauling myself up a mountain.
</p>
<p>Pure Rock Crawling is 50% off to coincide with the release of the new map, making it £6.39/$7.49/€7.39 at the time of writing.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft's beta versions now offer adorable hot and cold pig variants]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecrafts-beta-versions-now-offer-adorable-hot-and-cold-pig-variants</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecrafts-beta-versions-now-offer-adorable-hot-and-cold-pig-variants.1080066/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecrafts-beta-versions-now-offer-adorable-hot-and-cold-pig-variants<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Plus a crafting recipe update</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/minecraft-pig-variants.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Mojang</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-minecraft-seeds-java-survival-seeds">Minecraft</a> is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rps-100-2024">the best PC game</a>, according to me and the RPS staff who dare not cross me. I played it for three hours today and, among the many build challenges and adventures, a small story formed around a baby pig. We named him Porky, we caged him as our pet, and in an unfortunate accident, we watched as he fell to his death from the sky island that was our home. RPS in peace, Porky.
</p>
<p>How many befriended pigs like Porky have there been across the last several hundred hours of play? I'm not sure - dozens, hundreds - but soon such pigs might have a new form. After 15 years, Mojang are adding new types of pig to Minecraft.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Specifically, it's getting two new pig variants. The cold pig is coated with fur and will be found in cold and frozen biomes; the warm pig will found in the sandy biomes and is rust-brown. Mojang are calling it the "warm pig" because they know that, fundamentally, all pigs are hot.
</p>
<p>These cute porkchops are part of a handful of minor updates coming to Minecraft, which are all currently available to test in the Java Edition (and only some available to test in Bedrock).
</p>
<p>Forest biomes are also now getting falling leaves, which will flitter from the tree canopy and leave leaf litter on the ground. Leaf litter can be used to decorate blocks and rustles when you walk through it. In meadows and birch forests, you'll also find wildflowers, which have multiple stages of growth and can be gathered to craft into dye. Only the falling leaves are present in Bedrock preview and beta currently.
</p><p>Lastly, the Lodestone crafting recipe is being amended. This block, which compasses point towards to help players find their way home, previously required eight chiseled stone bricks and a netherite ingot to make. Netherite isn't easy to come by in Minecraft, requiring a long and lucky visit to the Nether to obtain Ancient Debris. Given that the Lodestone is meant to help players with the simple task of not getting lost near their home, that seems a bit daft, so a Lodestone can now be crafted with a simple iron ingot in place of the netherite instead. This turns a late-game item into something early or mid, which makes more sense.
</p>
<p>All of these changes are small, but god, I play so much of this game now. I am pumped for there to be leaves on the ground. My hobbit homes are going to look so quaint with leaves on the ground outside.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals' latest update disabled mods, meaning you can no longer play as Skibidi Toilet or Vegeta]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvel-rivals-latest-update-disabled-mods-meaning-you-can-no-longer-play-as-skibidi-toilet-or-vegeta</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-latest-update-disabled-mods-meaning-you-can-no-longer-play-as-skibidi-toilet-or-vegeta.1080057/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvel-rivals-latest-update-disabled-mods-meaning-you-can-no-longer-play-as-skibidi-toilet-or-vegeta<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Yet more cowardice from Big Tech</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marvel-rivals-skibidi-toilet-mod.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nexus Mods user Smelliots Mods</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marvel-rivals">Marvel Rivals</a> received a patch earlier this week <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvel-rivals-patch-makes-hulk-less-hulky-hawkeye-less-shooty-and-the-goddess-of-death-deader-just-in-time-for-season-1">which made Hulk less hulky</a> and paved the way for the launch of its first season. It also did something else: disabled the mods players had been using to add custom skins to the game.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-season-1-update-appears-to-have-disabled-mods-much-to-the-dismay-of-fans-of-custom-skins">IGN</a>, players are reporting that the latest update adds asset hash checking, effectively blocking the use of edited files inside the game.
</p>
<p>The move maybe comes as no surprise. Marvel Rivals is a free-to-play hero shooter that makes money by selling premium skins to players. Allowing mods enables players to make versions of those skins themselves for free. A number of such skins have proven <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/marvelrivals/mods/">popular on Nexus Mods</a> since Rivals' launch last year, including replacing Iron Man with Vegeta and the Winter Soldier with CJ from GTA: San Andreas.
</p>
<p>I can think of no live service game (of this type) that allows this kind of modding, and the game's terms of use have forbidden mods since the off. Publishers NetEase have also stated publicly that players risk being banned for modifying any game files.
</p><p>Inevitable or not, I am forced to write my little spiel once more: that games are better with mod support, and first-person games thrived once upon a time in part due to mods, and all of this used to be fields. I honestly doubt the existence of some daft, free, user-made skins is going to eat into Marvel Rivals' bottomline, and I'm sure there are technical workarounds that would allow the practice without threatening the integrity of online matches. <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/counter-strike-two">Counter-Strike 2</a> has thousands of mods, for example.
</p>
<p>One supposes that there's another issue here: that license holder Disney wouldn't be too pleased if the Marvel characters they've leant NetEase end up covered in visible nipples. Cowards.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hellblade 2 and Gears of War Are Also Reportedly Coming to PlayStation This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hellblade-2-and-gears-of-war-are-also-reportedly-coming-to-playstation-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hellblade-2-and-gears-of-war-are-also-reportedly-coming-to-playstation-this-year.1079991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/hellblade-2-and-gears-of-war-are-also-reportedly-coming-to-playstation-this-year/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>New reports suggest that Hellblade 2 and Gears of War will be making their way to the PlayStation 5 later this year.</p>



<p>That’s according to a new report from <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/the-game-im-most-excited-for-in-2025-is-already-discounted-before-launch" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">WindowsCentral</a>‘s Jez Corden, who corroborated yesterday’s rumors that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/at-least-two-xbox-exclusives-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Halo: The Master Chief Collection and Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024</a> would be making their way to other platforms.</p>



<p>In the new report, Corden states that Hellblade 2, Age of Mythology, and potentially Gears of War 1 Ultimate Edition are all also slated for PlayStation 5 later this year.</p>



<p>Corden also points out that most of Xbox’s upcoming games slate will primarily be timed exclusive games for Xbox and PC, which is a direction I think most of us in the industry expected Microsoft to go eventually.</p>



<p>As for when all of these games will be announced to be coming to other platforms, it remains to be seen, but seeing those slated for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-acknowledges-recent-nintendo-switch-2-leaks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2</a> would be welcomed announcements whenever Nintendo decides to hold its next Nintendo Direct. The games going to PlayStation may be announced during some “third-party” conference, possibly around the time of Summer Games Fest in June, if those releases are in the latter half of the year.</p>



<p>From the original rumors, NateTheHate also suggested that Final Fantasy 7 Remake and Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth, both PlayStation 5 console exclusives, will come to the Xbox platform soon.</p>



<p>What do you think of Microsoft changing its gaming strategy to release its exclusive games on other platforms? Do you think Microsoft runs the risk of alienating its hardware? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-appoints-advisors-to-explore-all-company-options/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest developments at Ubisoft</a>&nbsp;and a possible sale and our official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">preview of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2.</a>&nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals already has a higher Steam concurrent player count than GTA 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-rivals-already-has-a-higher-steam-concurrent-player-count-than-gta-5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-already-has-a-higher-steam-concurrent-player-count-than-gta-5.1079973/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-rivals-already-has-a-higher-steam-concurrent-player-count-than-gta-5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>That's also more than Apex Legends, Fallout 4,​​ and Helldivers 2.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Fantastic-Four-in-Marvel-Rivals.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>NetEase</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>We already knew that Marvel Rivals has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-rivals-opening-weekend-sees-10m-players-join-in">proven incredibly popular</a> since its launch last month - 10 million players joined online at launch - but now it's smashed another milestone, topping 600K concurrent players this weekend on Steam.</p>
<p>As recorded by <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2767030/charts/">SteamDB</a>, the number of players jumping into NetEase's hero shooter has hit 644,269 on Valve's digital platform, making it one of the biggest games not just of the  weekend, but also one of the biggest games by concurrent numbers of all-time, too.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Season 1: Eternal Night Falls Official Trailer | Marvel Rivals" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zATLJ6Cqt0c?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Season 1: Eternal Night Falls Official Trailer | Marvel Rivals</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zATLJ6Cqt0c?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zATLJ6Cqt0c?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Season 1: Eternal Night Falls Official Trailer | Marvel Rivals.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zATLJ6Cqt0c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>With just <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/counter-strike-two">Counter-Strike 2</a>, PUBG, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dota-2">Dota 2</a> sporting more concurrent players in the last 24 hours, Marvels Rivals' 644,269 concurrent players cements it in the annals of Steam history as the 14th biggest game by simultaneous player-count alone.</p>
<p>That's bigger than <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a>' all-time Steam concurrent peak (578,569), <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-4-walkthrough-and-guide-4019">Fallout 4</a> (472,962), <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> (458,709), and Grand Theft Auto 5 (364,548).</p>
<p>"NetEase's spin on the hero battler is complex and moreish, but rarely much actual fun," our Chris wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-rivals-review">Eurogamer's Marvel Rivals review</a>. "Its biggest impact is a renewed appreciation for the rivals that do it better." He awarded it two out of five stars.</p>
<p>Yesterday's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-rivals-update-kills-mods-removing-cheats-skins-and-19-inches-of-venom">Marvel Rivals update has seemingly wiped the ability to use mods on PC</a>.</p>
<p>Marvel Rivals has been in Season 0 since its release last month, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-rivals-season-1-will-nerf-some-of-the-most-dominant-characters">yesterday the online hero shooter's first season launched</a>, bringing significant balance changes and the heroic Fantastic Four team: Mister Fantastic, the Invisible Woman, the Human Torch, and the Thing.</p>
<p>Since the update rolled out, however, players are reporting that asset hash checking has stripped the ability to use mods, such as custom skins or FPS boost mods.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wicked Star Cynthia Erivo Really Wants To Play This X-Men Character]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/wicked-star-cynthia-erivo-really-wants-to-play-this-x-m-1851737682</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wicked-star-cynthia-erivo-really-wants-to-play-this-x-men-character.1079943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/wicked-star-cynthia-erivo-really-wants-to-play-this-x-m-1851737682<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>“Wicked” actress<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theroot.com/cynthia-erivo-and-ariana-grande-finally-discuss-that-we-1851731834&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theroot.com/cynthia-erivo-and-ariana-grande-finally-discuss-that-we-1851731834"> Cynthia Erivo </a></span>clearly has a thing for playing characters who fly. In an interview at the National Board of Review Awards Gala, Erivo was asked what “dream role” she’s manifesting for her future. And now, she said she’s ready to tackle one of the most iconic superheroes in history.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>In quite the change of pace from Erivo’s most recent portrayal of Elphaba, the Wicked Witch of the West in “Wicked,” she announced her dream role is Storm, the character from Marvel’s “X-Men.”</p><p>“I really want to play Storm,” Erivo told the interviewer. “I know it sounds frivolous, but I think we haven’t uncovered how grand she is, and all of that inner turmoil she has,” the 38-year-old continued. “So I think there’s a world in which we could do something with that.”</p><p>Storm, the weather-controlling superhero mutant, was made famous in the Marvel comics in the 1970s. The character has been portrayed on the big screen by Alexandra Shipp and, most famously, Halle Berry.</p><p>Since Erivo expressed interest in playing the silver-haired character, many online have shared their excitement while others don’t seem to think she’s the right fit for the role. But on X, user @daimaobutterfly said they don’t get the debate over the matter. They wrote “idk why everyone’s pretending cynthia erivo wouldn’t body storm.”<br></p><p>Another user, @taystytee, said Erivo did so well in “Wicked,” they should cast her as Storm and then “make it a musical…”</p><p>Even one former X-Men showrunner, Beau DeMayo, said Erivo as Storm is “an absolute no brainer.” DeMayo was fired from the animated X-Men reboot after accusations of “egregious” misconduct came to light, according to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/beau-demayo-accuses-marvel-disney-misconfuct-x-men-97-blade-1236130803/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/beau-demayo-accuses-marvel-disney-misconfuct-x-men-97-blade-1236130803/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Variety</a></span>.</p><p>Now could be a perfect time for Erivo to snag her dream role as Marvel has started to slowly integrate the original X Men characters into its current universe, according to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://movieweb.com/mcu-x-men-movie-writer-cast-plot/#:~:text=Avengers:%20Secret%20Wars&amp;text=The%20MCU's%20X%2DMen%20is,of%20the%20X%2DMen.%22&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://movieweb.com/mcu-x-men-movie-writer-cast-plot/#:~:text=Avengers:%20Secret%20Wars&amp;text=The%20MCU's%20X%2DMen%20is,of%20the%20X%2DMen.%22" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">movieweb.com.</a></span> But, Erivo isn’t the only actress gunning for the role.</p><p>Previously, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.imdb.com/news/ni64577261/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.imdb.com/news/ni64577261/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Janelle Monae has expressed interest</a></span> in playing Storm. We’ll just have to let the Marvel executives decide on the best star for the role.</p><p><em>This story originally appeared on The Root, our sister site, on January 10.</em></p><p><em>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney And Starbucks Have A $50 Collab That May Not Suck]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/starbucks-disney-minnie-mouse-cups-stanley-quenchers-1851737678</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-and-starbucks-have-a-50-collab-that-may-not-suck.1079940/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/starbucks-disney-minnie-mouse-cups-stanley-quenchers-1851737678<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Starbucks is looking to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-new-items-value-wars-mcdonalds-2025-1851733465&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-new-items-value-wars-mcdonalds-2025-1851733465" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reignite consumer interest</a></span> by teaming up with Disney for a limited-edition Minnie Mouse-themed collection. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194664" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Disney's New Post-Apocalyptic Anime Proves The Mouse Has Good Taste" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="162" data-playlist="194664,193897,196115" data-current="194664"><div><p>Disney's New Post-Apocalyptic Anime Proves The Mouse Has Good Taste</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20130.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The 24-ounce stainless steel cold cup, priced at <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.disneystore.com/minnie-mouse-stainless-steel-starbucks-tumbler-with-straw-walt-disney-world-433133581380.html?cjdata=MXxOfDB8WXww&amp;LSID=100103763|15734611|126006X1587338X0a8cc9ddc9a2417fb33a1dcab6a91a65&amp;CMP=AFL-AffLSGen_Content_5370367_15734611&amp;att=LSGenAffl&amp;EFC=224510&amp;cjevent=cd68e550cd2411ef808b76c70a82b832&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.disneystore.com/minnie-mouse-stainless-steel-starbucks-tumbler-with-straw-walt-disney-world-433133581380.html?cjdata=MXxOfDB8WXww&amp;LSID=100103763|15734611|126006X1587338X0a8cc9ddc9a2417fb33a1dcab6a91a65&amp;CMP=AFL-AffLSGen_Content_5370367_15734611&amp;att=LSGenAffl&amp;EFC=224510&amp;cjevent=cd68e550cd2411ef808b76c70a82b832" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$45</a></span>, features a satin red metallic base, white polka dots, and Minnie’s face. Alongside the cold cup, Starbucks is also offering a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.disneystore.com/minnie-mouse-icon-stainless-steel-travel-tumbler-with-straw-plus-zip-case-433113582451.html?cjdata=MXxOfDB8WXww&amp;isProductSearch=1&amp;searchType=regular&amp;LSID=100103763|15734611|126006X1587338X040a0b91a6f928de7e9606889e1be943&amp;CMP=AFL-AffLSGen_Content_5370367_15734611&amp;att=LSGenAffl&amp;EFC=224510&amp;cjevent=0fff0486cd2511ef808a11160a82b839&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.disneystore.com/minnie-mouse-icon-stainless-steel-travel-tumbler-with-straw-plus-zip-case-433113582451.html?cjdata=MXxOfDB8WXww&amp;isProductSearch=1&amp;searchType=regular&amp;LSID=100103763|15734611|126006X1587338X040a0b91a6f928de7e9606889e1be943&amp;CMP=AFL-AffLSGen_Content_5370367_15734611&amp;att=LSGenAffl&amp;EFC=224510&amp;cjevent=0fff0486cd2511ef808a11160a82b839" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$50</a></span> Minnie Mouse Steel Travel Tumbler, which bears a striking resemblance to Stanley’s popular Quenchers.</p><p>This move comes as Starbucks grapples with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-q3-2024-us-china-demand-weakens-1851609406?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-q3-2024-us-china-demand-weakens-1851609406?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">slowing sales growth</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-refreshers-coffee-brian-niccol-coffee-1851675411?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-refreshers-coffee-brian-niccol-coffee-1851675411?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">rising competition</a></span>. While the nostalgic tie-up with Disney might generate some buzz, it’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-strike-christmas-pay-raise-labor-amazon-1851726088?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-strike-christmas-pay-raise-labor-amazon-1851726088?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">unlikely to address</a></span> the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-in-office-mandate-or-quit-amazon-dell-walmart-1851683336?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-in-office-mandate-or-quit-amazon-dell-walmart-1851683336?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">underlying challenges</a></span> the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-strike-locations-christmas-1851727460?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-strike-locations-christmas-1851727460?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">brand is facing</a></span>. </p><p>Starbucks’ new CEO, Brian Niccol, has <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-menu-items-drinks-cut-brian-niccol-oleato-1851687207?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-menu-items-drinks-cut-brian-niccol-oleato-1851687207?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">vowed</a></span> to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-ceo-brian-niccol-retail-consumer-q4-2024-1851679223?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-ceo-brian-niccol-retail-consumer-q4-2024-1851679223?_gl=1*p3561z*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">return the company</a></span> to its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-changes-ceo-brian-niccol-analysts-1851696533?_gl=1*1wan155*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-changes-ceo-brian-niccol-analysts-1851696533?_gl=1*1wan155*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">roots</a></span> by focusing on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-turnaround-plan-ceo-brian-niccol-1851686795?_gl=1*1wan155*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-turnaround-plan-ceo-brian-niccol-1851686795?_gl=1*1wan155*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5MTMuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">speed and simplicity</a></span>. Niccol has <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-q4-2024-linear-tv-ads-agronomists-baristas-1851686255&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-q4-2024-linear-tv-ads-agronomists-baristas-1851686255" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">committed</a></span> to making <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-ceo-brian-niccol-coffee-menu-pare-down-retail-1851690763?_gl=1*1diu0*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5OTAuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-ceo-brian-niccol-coffee-menu-pare-down-retail-1851690763?_gl=1*1diu0*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzc5OTAuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">coffee in under four minutes</a></span>,  <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-cuts-olive-oil-oleato-beverage-brian-niccol-1851684549&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-cuts-olive-oil-oleato-beverage-brian-niccol-1851684549" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">paring down the menu</a></span> to make ordering more efficient, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-q4-2024-non-dairy-charges-condiment-bar-chang-1851685647?_gl=1*46vv1a*_ga*NjQwMDk3NjE0LjE3MTMxODc3NjE.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI3NjcxNy4xMDIuMS4xNzM2Mjc5Mjk1LjU1LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-q4-2024-non-dairy-charges-condiment-bar-chang-1851685647?_gl=1*46vv1a*_ga*NjQwMDk3NjE0LjE3MTMxODc3NjE.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI3NjcxNy4xMDIuMS4xNzM2Mjc5Mjk1LjU1LjAuMA.." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">removing the upcharge</a></span> for non-dairy milk alternatives. However, whether these steps can spur growth and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-money-hiring-new-workers-brian-niccol-retail-1851676553?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-money-hiring-new-workers-brian-niccol-retail-1851676553?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">weather</a></span> the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/21-states-raise-minimum-wage-inflation-1851731661?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/21-states-raise-minimum-wage-inflation-1851731661?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">broader economic pressures</a></span> – such as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/cpi-consumer-price-index-inflation-federal-reserve-1851716425?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/cpi-consumer-price-index-inflation-federal-reserve-1851716425?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">inflation</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/glp-1-drugs-grocery-bill-spending-retail-food-2025-1851731159?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/glp-1-drugs-grocery-bill-spending-retail-food-2025-1851731159?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">rising food prices</a></span> — remains uncertain.</p><p>Starbucks’ Red Cup Day in November, during which the company handed out <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.placer.ai/blog/starbucks-red-cup-day-makes-a-comeback&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.placer.ai/blog/starbucks-red-cup-day-makes-a-comeback" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reusable red cups</a></span>, saw a 42.4% increase in foot traffic compared to the previous months, according to analytics firm Placeri.ai. This success, along with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-new-items-value-wars-mcdonalds-2025-1851733465?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-new-items-value-wars-mcdonalds-2025-1851733465?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recent menu additions</a></span> like new espresso options and vegan-friendly falafel wraps, could help it compete in the ongoing “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/mcdonalds-chilis-taco-bell-winners-losers-casual-dining-1851728895?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/mcdonalds-chilis-taco-bell-winners-losers-casual-dining-1851728895?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">value wars</a></span>.” </p><p>But in 2024, the Starbucks fell short of attracting consumers both in the U.S. and in China, its second-largest market. In December, the company announced it would <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-paid-parental-leave-18-weeks-retail-workers-1851721988?_gl=1*klf80n*_ga*NjQwMDk3NjE0LjE3MTMxODc3NjE.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI3NjcxNy4xMDIuMS4xNzM2Mjc5Mjk1LjU1LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-paid-parental-leave-18-weeks-retail-workers-1851721988?_gl=1*klf80n*_ga*NjQwMDk3NjE0LjE3MTMxODc3NjE.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI3NjcxNy4xMDIuMS4xNzM2Mjc5Mjk1LjU1LjAuMA.." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">triple its parental leave</a></span> for baristas who work a least 20 hours per week. Meanwhile, in China, Starbucks hired its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/starbucks-china-business-appoints-chief-growth-officer-1851721861?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/starbucks-china-business-appoints-chief-growth-officer-1851721861?_gl=1*kobuln*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">first-ever chief growth officer</a></span> as it looks to collaborate with entertainment brands to attract customers that have flocked to chains like Luckin’ Coffee. </p><p>The Minnie Mouse collaboration could attract some traffic, but like McDonald’s “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/mcdonalds-collectors-meal-promo-big-arch-5-meal-deal-1851615552?_gl=1*g780ji*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/mcdonalds-collectors-meal-promo-big-arch-5-meal-deal-1851615552?_gl=1*g780ji*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Collector’s Cup</a></span>” promotion, which saw customers <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://qz.com/mconalds-happy-meal-cups-resale-ebay-mercari-1851624021?_gl=1*g780ji*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://qz.com/mconalds-happy-meal-cups-resale-ebay-mercari-1851624021?_gl=1*g780ji*_ga*MTkzNTUxMDgwMy4xNzI0MjQ2NjI3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MjEyMS42Mi4xLjE3MzYyNzgwMDYuNDQuMC4w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reselling the cups for up $100</a></span> on third-party websites like eBay, Starbucks’ boost might be short-lived. The company will need more than novelty items to truly address its current challenges.</p><p><em>This story originally appeared on Quartz, our sister site, on January 7.</em></p><p><em>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lords of the Fallen publisher CI Games publicly shuns "DEI", says it won't "embed social or political agendas"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/lords-of-the-fallen-publisher-ci-games-publicly-shuns-dei-says-it-wont-embed-social-or-political-agendas</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lords-of-the-fallen-publisher-ci-games-publicly-shuns-dei-says-it-wont-embed-social-or-political-agendas.1079937/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/lords-of-the-fallen-publisher-ci-games-publicly-shuns-dei-says-it-wont-embed-social-or-political-agendas<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Our games are developed to maximise player enjoyment and commercial success."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lords-of-the-fallen-screenshot.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hexworks</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/lords-of-the-fallen">Lords of the Fallen</a> publisher CI Games confirmed it would not "embed social or political agendas" in its games due to the "high risk it can present".</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://strefainwestorow.pl/czaty-inwestorskie/20250108/ci-games-marek-tyminski">Strefa Inwestorów</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/lords-of-the-fallen-studio-embraces-the-dei-bugbear-says-it-will-not-include-any-social-or-political-agendas-in-its-games/">PC Gamer</a>), global marketing director Ryan Hill told investors the studio would focus on "excellent user experience with compelling thematics and characters created specifically for core and adjacent audiences" following perceptions "a number of high profile releases underperform[ed] commercially during the last year" due to what he believed to be "social or political agendas."</p>
<p>"We remain committed to producing player-first video games that prioritise an excellent user experience with compelling themes and characters created specifically for core and adjacent audiences," Hill said when asked for the studio's position on "DEI [diversity, equity, and inclusion - more commonly known as EDI in the UK] in gaming".</p>
<p>"While some video games have recently taken the opportunity to embed social or political agendas within their experiences, it is clear that many players do not appreciate this, and as a result, we have seen a number of high profile releases underperforming commercially during the last year alone.</p>
<p>"Our games will always be developed to maximise player enjoyment and commercial success, and as such, we will not be integrating any social or political agencies into these experiences going forward having observed the high risk this can present."</p>
<p>Hill did not expand on his definition of "social or political agencies", nor defined what "high risk" meant to him and studio leadership. He also didn't exemplify what games he considered had "underperformed commercially" or, indeed, clarify what commercial success looked like to him.</p>
<p>CI Games declined to comment further on Hill's statement to investors.</p>
<p>The action-RPG is currently sitting on a "mixed" Steam user score, and received just two stars in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lords-of-the-fallen-2023-review">Eurogamer's Lords of the Fallen review</a>. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lords-of-the-fallen-sequel-now-in-full-development">A sequel is currently in development</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything we know (and think we know) about the Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/11/24341043/nintendo-switch-2-rumors-details-leaks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-we-know-and-think-we-know-about-the-nintendo-switch-2.1079922/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/11/24341043/nintendo-switch-2-rumors-details-leaks<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><p>Nintendo’s announcement of the Switch successor is imminent. Just how imminent is anyone’s guess with the company stating that it would <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/7/24150891/nintendo-switch-2-console-announcement-earnings-q4-2024">reveal info on the console</a> before the end of its fiscal year in March. Rumors regarding the new Switch have been circulating for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24051677/nintendo-switch-2-pro-rumors-news">more than a year</a>, but with less than two months to go until the promised deadline, and in the absence of any real information from Nintendo itself, speculation about the console, its specs, physical profile, and more have reached a fever pitch. So before the official reveal, here’s everything we think we know about Nintendo’s next console.</p><p>The only concrete, Nintendo-confirmed piece of information we know about the new console is that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/5/24284745/switch-2-backward-compatibility-nintendo-online-preservation">it’ll be backwards compatible with the Switch</a>. Everything else has come by way of leaks and info supplied by third-party manufacturers. Late last year, one such manufacturer, Dbrand, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24320659/nintendo-switch-2-dbrand-killswitch">debuted its Killswitch carrying case meant for the Switch 2</a>. According to Dbrand CEO Adam Ijaz, the Killswitch is based on the “actual dimensions” of the new console obtained from a “3D scan of the real hardware.” But in an interview with <em>The Verge</em>, he declined to say exactly how or where Dbrand obtained such information.</p><div><figcaption>Dbrand’s render of its Killswitch 2 case.</figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Dbrand</cite></p></div><p>If the Killswitch’s design is indeed derived from the real thing, the new console will be larger than the Switch OLED with an 8-inch screen, and feature a kickstand that will span the length of the console similar to the OLED model. That the new Switch will be larger than previous iterations is supported by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/18/24324483/nintendo-switch-2-leak-reddit-next-handheld">leaks</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/9/24339979/nintendo-switch-2-leaks-renders-onleaks">info from other accessory manufacturers</a> as well as the idea that the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/26/24141744/is-nintendo-going-off-the-rails">Joy-Con controllers will attach via magnet</a> instead of sliding and snapping into place. The new controller design will also incorporate magnets in the joysticks to combat against the dreaded “Joy-Con drift” that plagues the Switch even now.</p><p>CES 2025 provided even more fodder for the rumor mill, with accessory manufacturer Genki <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/8/24339396/nintendo-switch-2-genki-ces-2025">showing off a 3D printed mock-up of the console</a> on the show floor. In an interview with <em>The Verge</em>, Genki CEO Eddie Tsai went into detail about what he knows about the new Switch reaffirming rumors regarding its larger size, magnetic Joy-Con, and more.</p><p>While there’s a lot of speculation and potential evidence about what the new console will look like, there’s less circulating about what it can actually do. Beyond <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/1/24333491/new-year-new-alleged-switch-2-leak">an alleged photo of the console’s motherboard</a>, there hasn’t been much out there about the console’s hardware specifications. Because Nintendo has never made consoles at the bleeding edge (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/23420732/bayonetta-3-review-nintendo-switch">or, honestly, even the cutting one</a>) of graphics or processing power, it’s hard to guess how well the console will perform or what additional features, like a microphone, it’ll have.</p><p>Though the console’s internals remain a mystery, we do know that it’ll be backwards compatible with Switch games. We can also reasonably guess at least one game that’ll be a launch title: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/13/15782806/metroid-prime-4-nintendo-switch-announced-e3-2017"><em>Metroid Prime 4</em></a>. Announced in 2017, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/25/18197164/metroid-prime-4-nintendo-switch-delay-release-date">undergoing a change of studio and a development reboot</a> two years later, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23768041/metroid-prime-4-nintendo-direct-trailer">Nintendo debuted gameplay footage</a> for the first time last year and shared a soft launch window of 2025. When <em>Twilight Princess</em> launched in 2006, it debuted on both the GameCube and served as a launch title for the Wii. <em>Breath of the Wild</em> was also cross-gen, debuting on the Wii U while launching with the Switch in 2017.</p><div><figcaption>At CES 2025, The Verge saw a 3D printed mockup of the Nintendo Switch 2, here it is next to the Steam Deck.</figcaption> <p><cite>Photo by Antonio G. Di Benedetto / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>Knowing that the new Switch and <em>Metroid Prime 4</em> both launch in 2025 and with <em>Twilight Princess </em>and <em>BotW</em> as examples, it’s speculated that the reason for <em>Metroid 4</em>’s long stint in development hell was, at least in part, because the game <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24050473/metroid-prime-4-nintendo-switch-2">was being tooled for both the Switch and its successor.</a> Also, you just can’t have a new Nintendo console without a <em>Mario</em> game. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/26/16552118/super-mario-odyssey-review-nintendo-switch"><em>Super Mario Odyssey</em> was a Switch launch title</a>, and though there’s been other new releases like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23920647/super-mario-bros-wonder-review-nintendo-switch"><em>Super Mario Wonder</em></a>, there hasn’t been a new, <em>standalone</em> (put down your pitchforks <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22274990/super-mario-3d-world-bowsers-fury-review-nintendo-switch"><em>Bowser’s Fury</em></a> fans) 3D <em>Mario</em> game since then. It’s all but assured one will be announced with the new Switch. The recently announced <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em> is also a good launch title candidate as Nintendo curiously worded the game’s debut trailer with “releasing simultaneously worldwide on Nintendo Switch in 2025.”</p><p>For all the rumors and reasonable guesses supported by increasingly convincing evidence, it’s helpful to remember that at the end of the day, we’re still talking about Nintendo. The company has always tread <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/22/24276650/nintendo-switch-2-predictions-playtest-alarmo">a separate and unpredictable path</a> from the other two major console manufacturers and that oddball strategy has mostly worked very well. Though the company is <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-nintendo-of-america-laying-off-contractors-ahead-of-switch-2-launch">not immune to the same layoffs</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/16/24075174/switch-2-launch-date-rumor-q1-2025">delays</a> (the Switch 2 was originally pegged for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/7/31/23814298/nintendo-switch-sequel-2024-rumor">a 2024 release</a>) plaguing its peers and indeed has its own <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/10/13/23402344/nintendo-nlrb-complaint-settlement-aston-carter">manifold</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/30/11335284/nintendo-alison-rapp-fired-harassment-denial">issues</a> with how it treats and pays its employees <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/24/23039777/workers-nintendo-third-party-repair-facility-were-reportedly-overwhelmed-with-joy-con-repairs">and contractors</a>, of the major publishers, it seems to be the one that is best navigating the current crisis ravaging the industry.</p><p>It is folly trying to predict what Nintendo will do, and that applies to its new console. All we can count on is that it’s coming soon, and when it arrives, it’ll be big.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some Fans Are Calling For Rebel Ridge’s Aaron Pierre To Be The Next James Bond]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/some-fans-are-calling-for-rebel-ridge-s-aaron-pierre-to-1851737676</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/some-fans-are-calling-for-rebel-ridge%E2%80%99s-aaron-pierre-to-be-the-next-james-bond.1079916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/some-fans-are-calling-for-rebel-ridge-s-aaron-pierre-to-1851737676<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>When Daniel Craig stepped down as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theroot.com/james-bond-novels-rewritten-to-remove-racist-language-1850162680&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theroot.com/james-bond-novels-rewritten-to-remove-racist-language-1850162680">James Bond</a></span> after the release of the 2021 film, “No Time to Die,” fans everywhere have been searching for the next actor worthy to be 007. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theroot.com/black-actors-who-would-be-perfect-as-the-next-james-bon-1851348203&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theroot.com/black-actors-who-would-be-perfect-as-the-next-james-bon-1851348203"><em>The Root </em>even suggested several actors</a></span> who would fit the role, including Damson Idris, Regé-Jean Page, Daniel Kaluuya, John Boyega, and  Kingsely Ben-Adir.</p><p>But after sitting back and taking note of the actors who have separated themselves from the pack, we are seeing a pattern among one particular actor. Is it a coincidence that Aaron Pierre, the British actor, is everywhere right now and particularly in movies that show his specific talents?  In other words, is Pierre being groomed to be the next secret agent for the British Secret Service (MI6)?</p><p>It’s our theory but please hear us out. In his role as Terry Richmond in the 2024 film “Rebel Ridge,” Pierre proved he has the physical chops to cut it as Bond. </p><p>Just watch this fight scene from the movie and imagine Pierre in a tux instead of casual clothing. He can squabble with the best of them. </p><p>Furthermore, he’s shown that he has the acting chops through his variety of roles. He’s played a badass former marine (“Rebel Ridge”), an enslaved Black man in the 1800s (“<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theroot.com/exclusive-ibram-x-kendi-presents-the-underground-rail-1849040705&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theroot.com/exclusive-ibram-x-kendi-presents-the-underground-rail-1849040705">The Underground Railroad</a></span>”), Malcolm X (“<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theroot.com/heres-why-kelvin-harrison-jr-was-nervous-to-play-mlk-j-1851321412&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theroot.com/heres-why-kelvin-harrison-jr-was-nervous-to-play-mlk-j-1851321412">Genius: MLK/X</a></span>”), and even a lion cub (“Mufasa: The Lion King”).</p><p>The fact that none of these roles are like the other exemplifies his skill set as a movie star. </p><p>Lastly, (and maybe most importantly), he’s got the looks. While it may not be the most important part of being 007, Bond is an infamous lady killer who can have almost any woman he wants. It’s what makes him a flawed and interesting character because oftentimes the women he falls for get him into loads of trouble. If you go on any social media platform, there are thousands of women always fawning over the young man. Just check TikTok daily and several edits highlight his looks.</p><p>Not that he needed our help, since he’s already doing pretty well for himself. But we’ve cast our vote. Pierre is the future of 007.</p><p><em>This story originally appeared on The Root, our sister site, on January 10.</em></p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wccftech’s Most Anticipated Action Games of 2025 – Excellence Ahead]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-action-games-of-2025-excellence-ahead/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wccftech%E2%80%99s-most-anticipated-action-games-of-2025-%E2%80%93-excellence-ahead.1079895/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-action-games-of-2025-excellence-ahead/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>After the awesome output <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-action-games-of-2024-no-enemy-left-standing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seen in 2024</a>, 2025 is setting out to be yet another great year for action games. While the next 12 months may not see the release of action games of the more straightforward variety, the highly anticipated return of some of video gaming's most celebrated franchises will be sure to provide fans of the genre with plenty of fun.</p>
<p><em>Previously on Wccftech's Most Anticipated Games of 2025: <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-fighting-games-of-2025-off-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fighting</a></em></p>
<h2>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater (2025 - PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S)</h2>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Metal-Gear-Solid-Delta-Snake-Eater.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Following Hideo Kojima's departure from Konami, it felt like the Metal Gear Solid series was done, as the Japanese publisher has since only released the multiplayer game <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metal-gear-survive-more-than-expected/">Metal Gear Survive</a>. With the launch of the first series collection last year, however, Konami made it clear that it was time to bring back Big Boss.</p>
<p>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater is setting out not only to be an extremely faithful remake, but also a prime example of what a proper remake should be. Leaving the original story untouched, the remake of the third entry in the series, which reveals Big Boss' backstory after having been the series' main villain since its inception, will only feature, besides enhanced visuals powered by Unreal Engine 5, quality-of-life improvements that promise to elevate the original stealth gameplay to new heights. If taking down enemies without being seen using everything around you to your advantage is your thing, there will be no better game in 2025 to get than Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater.</p>
<h2>Ghost of Yotei (2025 - PlayStation 5)</h2>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/ghost-of-yotei-HD-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ghost-of-tsushima-duty-heavier-than-a-mountain-death-lighter-than-a-feather/">Ghost of Tsushima</a> has been so successful that it was only a matter of time until Sucker Punch Productions brought players back to their beautiful rendition of Feudal Japan. And that time is almost upon us, as Ghost of Yotei will make its debut later this year on PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>Very little is known about the second entry in the series, but from the game's reveal trailer, it's clear how Sucker Punch will double down on everything that made the original such a great game: amazing atmosphere, tense duels, stealth gameplay, and a guiding wind that will help Yotei reach her next destination. If her final destination will truly be vengeance remains to be seen, but there's no doubt that the journey through Hokkaido will be well worth it and count among the top action games released in 2025.</p>
<h2>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond (2025 - Nintendo Switch)</h2>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The silence surrounding Metroid Prime 4: Beyond since its announcement has been so deafening that it almost felt like the game would never see the light of day. Thankfully, that was not the case, and the wait for the next first-person adventure of famed bounty hunter Samus Aran is almost over.</p>
<p>Following a development reboot that brought the game back into the hands of series' creator Retro Studios, the fourth entry in the series was finally properly revealed to the world last year with a <a href="https://wccftech.com/metroid-prime-4-first-trailer-release-date/">short gameplay trailer</a> that showed just enough of what fans of the series expected to see. With an oppressive atmosphere, navigational puzzles, and a combat system that will force players to use every tool at their disposal to survive, Metroid Prime 4: Beyond looks like the perfect game to bring Samus back into the spotlight following the release of the excellent Metroid Dread.</p>
<h2>Crimson Desert (Fall 2025 - PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S)</h2>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Crimson-Desert_Key-Art_2-HD-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Unlike every other game on this list, <a href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-to-launch-in-fall-2025-pc-requirements-revealed/">Crimson Desert</a> is a bit of an unknown. While developer Pearl Abyss has proven itself in the MMO space with Black Desert: Online, developing an open-world action-adventure game of this scope is a whole different matter, but from what has been shown so far, it looks like the Korean developer is more than up to the challenge.</p>
<p>Controlling Macduff as he traverses the continent of Pywel, which is going through political turmoil following the death of the Unifier of Lands, players will get to explore tons of different locations, ranging from the plains of Akapen to the cold lands of Kweiden, raid castles, enter dungeons to solve puzzles, befriend allies and fight foes and mythical beasts using a variety of weapons and martial arts techniques, including weapons that usually don't see much representation in games with a fantasy setting such as pistols and hand-mounted cannons, weapons that hint at how the world where Macduff will leave his mark is a lot more complex than what it seems at a glance.</p>
<h2>Grand Theft Auto VI (Fall 2025 - PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S)</h2>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/GTA-VI-HD-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>While 2025 will see the release of some hotly anticipated titles, the excitement surrounding them pales in comparison to the anticipation for Grand Theft Auto VI. This should be hardly surprising for anyone, as it is predicted to be the <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-is-expected-to-be-the-biggest-entertainment-launch-of-all-time-but-a-performance-below-expectations-could-impact-the-entire-industry/">biggest entertainment launch of all time</a>.</p>
<p>If it were any other game, however, the anticipation for the next entry in the series by Rockstar Games would be completely unjustified, as we have seen very little of the game so far. Still, the return to Vice City together with the criminal duo headed by Lucia promises to be one to remember, as does the parody of contemporary American culture with the dominance of social media and influencer culture, considering what Rockstar Games achieved with its latest open-world game, Red Dead Redemption 2, and how much technology has moved forward since the release of Grand Theft Auto V back in 2013.</p>
<h2>Community Poll</h2>
<p>What's your most anticipated action game of 2025? Let us know by voting in the poll below!</p>
<div id="democracy-1392" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1392,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Most Anticipated Action Game of 2025</strong></p></div>
<h2>Honorable Mentions</h2>
<p>The five games listed above are only some of those that should be on the radar of any proper action games fans. The games below are in no way less deserving of attention than the ones above, as they promise to be just as good.</p>
<ul>
<li>Mafia: The Old Country</li>
<li>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</li>
<li>Eternal Strands</li>
<li>Dying Light: The Beast</li>
<li><a href="https://www.marvel.com/games/marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marvel 1943: Rise of Hydra</a></li>
</ul>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devil May Cry crossover is coming to Fortnite "soon", leakers tease]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/devil-may-cry-crossover-is-coming-to-fortnite-soon-leakers-tease</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/devil-may-cry-crossover-is-coming-to-fortnite-soon-leakers-tease.1079892/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/devil-may-cry-crossover-is-coming-to-fortnite-soon-leakers-tease<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Devil May Cry is coming to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a>.</p>
<p>That's according to Fortnite leakers Loolo_Wrld and Wensoing, both of whom say the long-running rumours of a Dante-flavoured crossover - which first bubbled up in 2023 - are indeed correct, and there is one in the works.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Whilst both are fairly established leakers in their own rights, their news was picked up and shared by noted Fortnite leaker ShiinaBR, adding credence - if not quite a cast-iron guarantee - to the claims.</p>
<p>When pressed for more information - such as well the collaboration may arrive - Loolo was coy, saying, "I can’t specify anything about that for now", appending the statement with a zipped-mouth emoji.</p>
<p>Wensoing similarly will only commit to "coming soon", but acknowledges that both leakers "have heard about [the Devil May Cry crossover] several times via [their] insiders".</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>As for the details? Well, that's all still very much up for speculation. There's no doubting that Devil May Cry boasts several iconic outfits and weapons, though, so there's plenty to pick from.</p>
<p>ICYMI, Fortnite Festival, the concert-themed rhythm-action portion of Epic Games' free-to-play jack-of-all-trades juggernaut, is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-festival-is-getting-local-co-op-support-rekindling-memories-of-rock-band">getting local co-op support next month</a> - conjuring nostalgic memories of countless evenings spent twanging away in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/rock-band">Rock Band</a> with pals.</p>
<p>As Matt reminded us yesterday, Fortnite Festival is the work of Rock Band developer Harmonix - which Epic Games <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-games-acquires-rock-band-developer-harmonix">acquired back in 2021</a> - and is extremely reminiscent of the studio's beloved earlier titles, right down to its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rock-band-developer-harmonixs-new-fortnite-music-mode-will-support-instrument-controllers">support for guitar-shaped plastic peripherals</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our Most Anticipated Games Of The Year, Another Assassin's Creed Shadows Delay, And More Of The Week's Top Stories]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-leaks-assassins-creed-shadows-delay-1851737102</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/our-most-anticipated-games-of-the-year-another-assassins-creed-shadows-delay-and-more-of-the-weeks-top-stories.1079847/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/switch-2-leaks-assassins-creed-shadows-delay-1851737102<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="c73d5e0018940f5fd553263f63ba282f" data-recommend-id="image://c73d5e0018940f5fd553263f63ba282f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="in-house-art" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Nintendo / Lego / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Sony / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Rockstar Games / Kojima Productions / Dot Emu / Ubisoft / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Ubisoft<!-- -->, <!-- -->Acer / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Sony / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Remedy / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo<!-- -->, <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c73d5e0018940f5fd553263f63ba282f" data-recommend-id="image://c73d5e0018940f5fd553263f63ba282f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This week, we took the opportunity to look ahead to what 2025 has in store, and reminded ourselves (and you!) of the many, many exciting games coming our way in the next 12 months. Also, the steady drumbeat of Switch 2 leaks seems to be speeding up, <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows </em>has been hit with another delay, and at CES, Acer revealed a very large gaming “handheld.” All this and more awaits in the pages ahead.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="4fffca9298740f84c1347148b2e7f59a" data-recommend-id="image://4fffca9298740f84c1347148b2e7f59a" data-format="png" data-width="1600" data-height="899" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Astro Bot and friends turn off their PS5. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Astro Bot and friends turn off their PS5. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="4fffca9298740f84c1347148b2e7f59a" data-recommend-id="image://4fffca9298740f84c1347148b2e7f59a" data-format="png" data-width="1600" data-height="899" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Astro Bot and friends turn off their PS5. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/psa-turn-off-your-ps5-faster-by-scrolling-left-not-ri-1845669127&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/psa-turn-off-your-ps5-faster-by-scrolling-left-not-ri-1845669127">I only ever turn my PlayStation 5 off a few times a year</a></span>, and it’s usually when there’s an unexpected power outage or I accidentally hit the red switch on the power strip it’s plugged into. My PS5 yells at me when I turn it back on and I vow never to do it again. Apparently only about 50 percent of players live this way, however. - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ps5-unplug-turn-off-welcome-hub-sony-design-resume-1851733029&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-unplug-turn-off-welcome-hub-sony-design-resume-1851733029">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="3738ed7730edddefa962011195beb639" data-recommend-id="image://3738ed7730edddefa962011195beb639" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Art shows the biggest games coming in 2025. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Art shows the biggest games coming in 2025. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Rockstar Games / Kojima Productions / Dot Emu / Ubisoft / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3738ed7730edddefa962011195beb639" data-recommend-id="image://3738ed7730edddefa962011195beb639" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Art shows the biggest games coming in 2025. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>After a quieter year for bigger releases in 2024 (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/best-video-games-2024-pc-ps5-xbox-switch-1851291118?_gl=1*1s6bmsv*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MDk0MS4yNDcuMS4xNzM2MjcwNjE0LjYwLjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/best-video-games-2024-pc-ps5-xbox-switch-1851291118?_gl=1*1s6bmsv*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjI2MDk0MS4yNDcuMS4xNzM2MjcwNjE0LjYwLjAuMA..">though there was still plenty of great stuff overall</a></span>), 2025 has the potential to blow the lid off things with a ton of blockbusters ranging from the unexpectedly delayed <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> to the long-awaited <em>Grand Theft Auto VI </em>(<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gta-6-development-2026-delay-rockstar-office-release-1851359831&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-development-2026-delay-rockstar-office-release-1851359831">which could also still get delayed—boo, hiss</a></span>). A ton of major games still don’t have specific release dates, and some of the biggest potential releases—a new 3D <em>Mario </em>from Nintendo, for example— haven’t even been officially announced yet. For now though, and working with the ever-shifting video game release calendar as it’s currently constituted, here are <em>Kotaku</em>’s most anticipated upcoming games of 2025.   - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/big-games-coming-out-2025-gta-6-borderlands-4-1851730256&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/big-games-coming-out-2025-gta-6-borderlands-4-1851730256">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="0758f7e3d376d1a62f1578a1039361e5" data-recommend-id="image://0758f7e3d376d1a62f1578a1039361e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Switch OLED being put into its dock." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Switch OLED being put into its dock." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0758f7e3d376d1a62f1578a1039361e5" data-recommend-id="image://0758f7e3d376d1a62f1578a1039361e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Switch OLED being put into its dock." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Nintendo’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-ai-4k-motherboard-leak-1851731108&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-ai-4k-motherboard-leak-1851731108">ongoing refusal to announce the Switch 2</a></span> has reached the point of being downright absurd. As <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-leaks-reveal-release-date-reddit-1851725408&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-leaks-reveal-release-date-reddit-1851725408">leaks continue apace</a></span>, we’re piecing together the unacknowledged console like a jigsaw puzzle, rapidly leaving Nintendo with nothing else to say but, “Yup, that.” The latest pieces come from third-party manufacturers; some via a GameStop employee leaking new SKUs listed on the store’s systems, and others from third-party peripheral company Genki. - John Walker <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-dock-joy-cons-rumors-leaks-ces-2025-1851735925&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-dock-joy-cons-rumors-leaks-ces-2025-1851735925">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="d338ef732fb8a6dff33b895698e593d5" data-recommend-id="image://d338ef732fb8a6dff33b895698e593d5" data-format="png" data-width="986" data-height="554" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Lego and Game Boy logos appear next to each other. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Lego and Game Boy logos appear next to each other. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Lego / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d338ef732fb8a6dff33b895698e593d5" data-recommend-id="image://d338ef732fb8a6dff33b895698e593d5" data-format="png" data-width="986" data-height="554" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Lego and Game Boy logos appear next to each other. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Nintendo just announced a new console and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-dock-joy-cons-rumors-leaks-ces-2025-1851735925?_gl=1*1hyabow*_ga*ODE3ODM5ODIyLjE3MjA0NjY0NTg.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjQ0ODEwNC43MS4xLjE3MzY0NDk2OTAuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-dock-joy-cons-rumors-leaks-ces-2025-1851735925?_gl=1*1hyabow*_ga*ODE3ODM5ODIyLjE3MjA0NjY0NTg.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNjQ0ODEwNC43MS4xLjE3MzY0NDk2OTAuNjAuMC4w">it’s still not the Switch 2</a></span>. The console maker is teaming up with Lego to release a Game Boy made of plastic bricks. It follows after a previous collaboration in which the two companies released a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=xzXATABADTI&amp;mid=13923&amp;u1=KT-&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fnintendo-entertainment-system-71374&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=xzXATABADTI&amp;mid=13923&amp;u1=KT-&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fnintendo-entertainment-system-71374" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody">Lego NES</a></span> together, complete with retro TV that displayed the first level of the original <em>Super Mario Bros</em>.  - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lego-game-boy-price-release-date-tetris-nintendo-1851736436&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lego-game-boy-price-release-date-tetris-nintendo-1851736436">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="347b5d8eb012de4630eed3bfd51444c1" data-recommend-id="image://347b5d8eb012de4630eed3bfd51444c1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A blonde lady appears to be delighted by her Switch OLED model." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A blonde lady appears to be delighted by her Switch OLED model." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="347b5d8eb012de4630eed3bfd51444c1" data-recommend-id="image://347b5d8eb012de4630eed3bfd51444c1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A blonde lady appears to be delighted by her Switch OLED model." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Articles <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-dock-joy-cons-rumors-leaks-ces-2025-1851735925&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-dock-joy-cons-rumors-leaks-ces-2025-1851735925">saying Switch 2 leaks and rumors are appearing like a torrent</a></span> are appearing like a torrent, as CES 2025 produced a new round of speculation, hope, confusion and possible visions of the unrevealed device. All the while, Nintendo has sat silently, presumably watching our frenetic rushing about with arch amusement, perhaps taking some sort of pleasure in not actually announcing the console. But last night, the Japanese company finally spoke up, only to tell us all to sit back down. - John Walker <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-rumors-genki-ces-2025-official-1851736830&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-rumors-genki-ces-2025-official-1851736830">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="3218488f8ef37002a81163ae498adeb8" data-recommend-id="image://3218488f8ef37002a81163ae498adeb8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Two images show grown adults holding the massive Acer Nitro 11. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Two images show grown adults holding the massive Acer Nitro 11. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Acer / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3218488f8ef37002a81163ae498adeb8" data-recommend-id="image://3218488f8ef37002a81163ae498adeb8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Two images show grown adults holding the massive Acer Nitro 11. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Computer maker Acer is one of the few PC tech companies that hasn’t released a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/valve-steam-deck-pc-console-switch-horizon-zero-dawn-re-1848628507&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/valve-steam-deck-pc-console-switch-horizon-zero-dawn-re-1848628507">Steam Deck-like handheld gaming device</a></span>. That changes later this year when it releases not one but three different portable PC devices, one of which is so big that it almost looks like a joke and really begs the question if it’s even a handheld device anymore. - Zack Zwiezen <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/astro-nitro-blaze-11-steam-deck-ces-2025-size-handheld-1851734392&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/astro-nitro-blaze-11-steam-deck-ces-2025-size-handheld-1851734392">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="b659cf1597d15ff0e2049816710d7e13" data-recommend-id="image://b659cf1597d15ff0e2049816710d7e13" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b659cf1597d15ff0e2049816710d7e13" data-recommend-id="image://b659cf1597d15ff0e2049816710d7e13" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Sony has debuted some wild-looking, <em>Star-Trek</em>-holodeck-like technology that, if it works as advertised, will let people step into the world of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-2-tlou-remastered-review-1851167660&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-2-tlou-remastered-review-1851167660"><em>The Last of Us</em></a></span><em> </em>and get up close and personal with the franchise’s grotesque spore zombies. This new tech will even let you uh...smell them.  - Zack Zwiezen <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/new-sony-tech-holodeck-last-of-us-ces-2025-smell-vr-ps5-1851734687&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/new-sony-tech-holodeck-last-of-us-ces-2025-smell-vr-ps5-1851734687">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="c00c0f69c36bb3d58146a55288c98310" data-recommend-id="image://c00c0f69c36bb3d58146a55288c98310" data-format="png" data-width="1015" data-height="565" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A PlayStation logo appears on a black DualSense controller. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A PlayStation logo appears on a black DualSense controller. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c00c0f69c36bb3d58146a55288c98310" data-recommend-id="image://c00c0f69c36bb3d58146a55288c98310" data-format="png" data-width="1015" data-height="565" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A PlayStation logo appears on a black DualSense controller. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The PlayStation 5 lineup of consoles and accessories continues to expand. Just a couple of months after the 30th Anniversary set was released, Sony has revealed another lineup of color variants, this time in all-black. The new PlayStation Portal looks especially slick.  - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ps5-black-portal-cover-plates-dualsense-edge-pulse-1851733979&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-black-portal-cover-plates-dualsense-edge-pulse-1851733979">Read More</a></span></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>