<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 15:07:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Police Department Woefully Misunderstands Terminator Movies By Using Theme Music To Introduce New Cybertruck]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/police-department-terminator-theme-music-cybertruck-1851671511</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/police-department-woefully-misunderstands-terminator-movies-by-using-theme-music-to-introduce-new-cybertruck.1008159/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/police-department-terminator-theme-music-cybertruck-1851671511<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="0b531403f4f9405eb0a88ee8ec7dc12d" data-recommend-id="image://0b531403f4f9405eb0a88ee8ec7dc12d" data-format="jpg" data-width="2043" data-height="1147" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Irvine Police Department</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0b531403f4f9405eb0a88ee8ec7dc12d" data-recommend-id="image://0b531403f4f9405eb0a88ee8ec7dc12d" data-format="jpg" data-width="2043" data-height="1147" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The city of Irvine, California’s police department officially <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://jalopnik.com/police-department-in-southern-california-wants-to-be-th-1851599096&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://jalopnik.com/police-department-in-southern-california-wants-to-be-th-1851599096">introduced its cringy new Tesla Cybertruck</a></span> on Tuesday to the public in the most cringe way possible: a dorky video featuring theme music from “The Terminator,” a franchise that famously portrays cops in a poor light. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197284" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Iconic Director And Proud Nerd Kevin Smith On Sneaking Into Movies, Mallrats, And More" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="643" data-playlist="197284,197260,197209" data-current="197284"><div><p>Iconic Director And Proud Nerd Kevin Smith On Sneaking Into Movies, Mallrats, And More</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22826.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>First spotted by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://gizmodo.com/california-cops-show-off-absurd-new-cybertruck-with-music-from-terminator-movies-2000509382&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://gizmodo.com/california-cops-show-off-absurd-new-cybertruck-with-music-from-terminator-movies-2000509382">Gizmodo</a></span>, Irvine Police posted videos to Twitter and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://fb.watch/v6tX0KL90B/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://fb.watch/v6tX0KL90B/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></span> showcasing the truck. The minute-long video is just as sphincter clenching as you’d expect. It shows the Cybertruck rolling out to the Terminator theme music. For some reason there’s smoke for the Cybertruck to drive through  before the truck stops and is joined by Irvine Police officers who awkwardly pose with the truck, complete with cyborg-like smiles. The video ends with custom thunder and lightning graphics created for the truck that reads “Irvine Police Cybertruck.” I guess we’re all supposed to go “hell yeah!” at that point.<br></p><p>Irvine Police are doubling down on the department’s reasoning for spending well over six figures on this electric pickup. In the video description, the department says the truck is for community engagement, specifically for officer support with the DARE (Drug Abuse Resistance Education) program.<br></p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>The truck will support our Drug Abuse Resistance Education (DARE) program and community outreach efforts. While the fully equipped vehicle won’t be used as a patrol car, it can respond to emergencies and assist the community when needed. For over three decades, our DARE officers have driven attention-grabbing and one-of-a-kind vehicles that never fail to turn heads and excite students.</p></blockquote><p>Despite the department saying that this will be for community engagement, the truck has been divisive. Back in September, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://jalopnik.com/southern-california-police-departments-expensive-cybert-1851656133&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://jalopnik.com/southern-california-police-departments-expensive-cybert-1851656133">public records</a></span> showed the department dropped over $150,000 on the electric truck. Things didn’t look much better when it was also revealed that the department attempted to keep the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://irvinewatchdog.org/city-hall/public-records-reveal-irvine-police-spent-153175-on-tesla-cybertruck-sparking-community-concerns-over-transparency-and-financial-accountability-in-the-irvine-police-department/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://irvinewatchdog.org/city-hall/public-records-reveal-irvine-police-spent-153175-on-tesla-cybertruck-sparking-community-concerns-over-transparency-and-financial-accountability-in-the-irvine-police-department/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">exact purchase amount secret</a></span>. And not everyone is buying the department’s reasoning that the truck is for community engagement. Some experts believe the money spent on the Cybertruck and its law enforcement modifications should have been actually spent on, you know, the community. </p><p>The truck being a part of the DARE program doesn’t help things either. As Gizmodo pointed out, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1999-03346-017&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1999-03346-017" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">studies have shown</a></span> the program does not work. It also doesn’t look as if Irvine PD actually got proper licensing to use “The Terminator” music in the video; the department mentioned in a statement to Gizmodo that “The video was used on our socials and music credit was given to the artist.” Between the public backlash, this cringe video and a possible copyright violation, it looks like this Cybertruck is already turning out to be less of a plus for the department and more of a headache. <br></p><p><em>This story originally appeared on Jalopnik, our sister site, on Wednesday, October 9.</em></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halloween 2024 storyscream: the best spooky things to watch and play]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/12/24264357/halloween-2024-game-film-tv-reviews</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halloween-2024-storyscream-the-best-spooky-things-to-watch-and-play.1008150/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/12/24264357/halloween-2024-game-film-tv-reviews<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="region" aria-labelledby="stream-lede"><p>It’s been a pretty good year for horror fans. When it comes to movies, the summer was packed with the likes of <em>Cuckoo</em>, <em>MaXXXine</em>, and <em>Alien: Romulus</em>, while gaming has seen releases such as a <em>Silent Hill 2</em> remake and the retro <em>Crow Country</em>. So, if you’re looking for something new to play or watch in the lead-up to Halloween, we’ve gathered all of our spookiest coverage here in one place to make things a little easier. (And if you missed it, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23911556/halloween-2023-games-movies-tv-streaming-recommendations">we did the same thing last year</a>.) So, grab some snacks, turn down the lights, and get ready for a few scares.</p></div><section id="updates-section"><ul><li role="article" id="stream-entry-342a0577-688e-4c95-957b-657e953287f4"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/10/24240464/the-substance-review">The Substance is a grotesque takedown of our obsession with youth</a></h2><p>As much as studios love hyping up their latest scary movies as being so terrifying that they traumatize audiences, it is rare for features to live up to that kind of buzz. But <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/8/24238342/the-substance"><em>The Substance</em></a><em> </em>writer / director Coralie Fargeat’s new body horror is infinitely more disturbing (a feature, not a bug) than any of its early trailers have let on.&nbsp;</p><p>Films about the agony of living up to female beauty standards aren’t new, but <em>The Substance </em>weaves them into an incisive feminist parable that feels jacked directly into the moment that has given us <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/20/24160884/hims-hers-ozempic-weight-loss-wegovy-pharmacy">on-demand Ozempic</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/23/24203547/kamala-harris-presidential-campaign-charli-xcx-brat-summer-meme"><em>Brat</em></a><em>. </em>And what the film lacks in subtlety, it makes up for with an inspired — if stomach-turning — story that’s meant to get all the way under your skin, no matter how secure in your body you might feel.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/10/24240464/the-substance-review">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-c4f4a714-3616-42c7-8041-2f3ecd3c8ec7"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/14/24219417/alien-romulus-review">Alien: Romulus is a solid franchise tribute plagued by weird optics</a></h2><div><figure><span><span></span></span><p><cite>Image: 20th Century Studios</cite></p></figure></div><p>It’s mind-boggling that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24170776/alien-romulus-trailer-release-date"><em>Alien: Romulus</em></a> almost wound up <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/alien-movie-fede-alvarez-20th-century-studios-1235037155/">debuting on Hulu</a> instead of theaters. The film’s intricate set design alone makes it one of the series’ most visually impressive chapters, and its practical effects are a welcome change of pace in a summer blockbuster season that has been <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/11/24218046/deadpool-wolverine-is-in-the-billion-dollar-club">dominated</a> by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24161853/furiosa-mad-max-review">uninspired CGI spectacle</a>.</p><p>Director Fede Álvarez’s new standalone entry in the long-running sci-fi / horror franchise feels especially primed to speak to a new generation of fans. But as fun as <em>Romulus </em>is to look at, its story plays more like a compilation of the <em>Alien </em>series’ greatest hits than a movie that’s trying to sing its own tune. And the few new ideas <em>Romulus </em>does bring to the table are undercut by its insistence on leaning into some very questionable optics.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/14/24219417/alien-romulus-review">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-1bd3d180-1112-40d7-b610-ef4c41881805"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24216922/horror-movies-maxxxine-longlegs-cuckoo-nothing-to-say">Horror movies need to be more than a big mood</a></h2><p>The release of <em>Get Out </em>in 2017 disturbed Hollywood — not just the box office but, briefly, the entire horror genre, which had long been the most consistent moneymaker in the industry. The film made a multiple of 56 times on its $4.5 million budget and was less a breakthrough and more of a victory lap for Blumhouse, the studio that had for nearly two decades championed scary movies at a low cost with hopes of a high return.</p><p>Partly, <em>Get Out</em> was exceptional — not the first movie where the true horror is racism, but one that balanced the terror with humor and absurdity. Eager to repeat that success, Hollywood greenlit a swath of horror movies about racism. Many of them were underwhelming and, in some cases, <a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/09/antebellum-movie-review-i-am-tired-of-films-like-this.html">appalling</a>. Mostly, it was exhausting to see so much repetition in a genre that thrives on novelty. But at least these movies were <em>about</em> something. Now we’re onto the next wave of horror films, which have trended toward being about nothing.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24216922/horror-movies-maxxxine-longlegs-cuckoo-nothing-to-say">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-94413712-7afd-4b0a-b402-4fa052e067bc"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/9/24215555/neon-cuckoo-review">Cuckoo is a picturesque nightmare that struggles to get its point across</a></h2><p>Coming on the heels of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24199318/longlegs-ending-explained-questions-oz-perkinsk"><em>Longlegs</em></a> and <em>Immaculate</em>, director Tilman Singer’s <em>Cuckoo </em>feels like the next phase of Neon’s plan to dominate this summer of horror. The movie’s haunting atmosphere and gorgeous cinematography make it seem primed to tap into Hollywood’s current obsession with unsettling features running on spooky vibes alone. But for all of its hype and a solid performance from its leads, <em>Cuckoo</em> suffers from a lack of thematic coherence. It’s definitely the strongest of Neon’s recent scary movies, but that isn’t exactly a high bar to clear.</p><p>Set in a corner of the German Alps where few foreigners tend to wander, <em>Cuckoo</em> follows as sullen, American teenager Gretchen (Hunter Schafer) is forced to move in with her estranged father, Luis (Marton Csokas), and his new family. With all of Gretchen’s beloved bandmates and treasured possessions back in the States, she can’t help but feel alone living with her stepmother Beth (Jessica Henwick) and mute half-sister Alma (Mila Lieu). And while Gretchen doesn’t try to hide her distaste at being uprooted for Luis’ job expanding a secluded resort owned by Herr König (Dan Stevens), she only feels comfortable expressing the depths of her sadness in voicemails to her unseen mother.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/9/24215555/neon-cuckoo-review">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-96f4fc9e-9ce6-4d4e-b35a-b4edbd82d836"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24187551/maxxxine-review-ti-west">A24’s MaXXXine flips the script to give you something fresh to scream about</a></h2><p>With <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22979890/x-review-ti-west-horror-movie"><em>X</em></a><em> </em>and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23352979/pearl-review-tiff-2022"><em>Pearl</em></a>, it was hard to miss that Ti West was using pornography and horror as lenses through which to tell a story about the evolution of film. Both were explorations of how naked bodies have always been a subject of cinematic fascination, and while the movies were tonally different, they similarly spotlighted how sex has always been one of the driving forces behind the advancement of movie-making technology. </p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24124163/maxxxine-trailer-release-date-a24-mia-goth"><em>MaXXXine </em>enters the <em>X </em>franchise</a> knowing full well how easily it could fall victim to the threequel curse if it simply dropped its star into a new decade to fight for her life on yet another farm. And while it features plenty of callbacks to its predecessors, it switches the formula up just enough to make it feel like West has pulled off a blood-soaked hat trick.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24187551/maxxxine-review-ti-west">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-d54d29f0-bef4-44bf-a23d-58b285f03ec8"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24190083/ti-west-interview-maxxxine-a24">‘MaXXXine is very different from both of them’: Ti West on closing out his X horror trilogy</a></h2><p>For the last few years, Ti West hasn’t stopped thinking about the horror villains Pearl and Maxine. Since 2020, the writer and director has been fully immersed in the genre-spanning franchise that started with the ’70s slasher flick <em>X</em> and continued with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23352979/pearl-review-tiff-2022">the technicolor prequel <em>Pearl</em></a>, which were filmed back-to-back in New Zealand during the pandemic and released in 2022. Now things culminate with the premiere of the series’ third act, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24124163/maxxxine-trailer-release-date-a24-mia-goth">the very ’80s thriller <em>MaXXXine</em></a>. It’s been an intense process that has meant West hasn’t had much time for anything else. “It’s all such a blur at this point,” he tells <em>The Verge</em>. “It’s been seven days a week, 12 hours a day, for four and a half years.”</p><p>The franchise was born, in part, out of practicality. West had initially only pitched <em>X</em> to the powers that be at A24 but had ideas for a bigger trilogy in the back of his mind. And after getting a cast and crew to New Zealand and building the sets, he realized he could film a lot of that work again for a prequel. “We had already spent all of this time and money building a Texas farm in New Zealand. How do we reuse it for free?” he remembers thinking. “How do we amortize all of those costs and make the movie less of a risk for A24? That’s where the idea came from from a practical standpoint.” He ended up writing the script for <em>Pearl</em> in a two-week-long flurry while in quarantine so that they could start shooting right away.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24190083/ti-west-interview-maxxxine-a24">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-3cd8d11b-4330-4052-a2a9-483085c52be9"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24159054/i-saw-the-tv-glow-jane-schoenbrun-interview">For the director of I Saw the TV Glow, Buffy the Vampire Slayer was just the start</a></h2><div><figure><span><span></span></span><p><cite>Photo by Monica Schipper / Getty Images for IMDb</cite></p></figure></div><p>There is an honesty to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24141747/i-saw-the-tv-glow-review-a24"><em>I Saw the TV Glow</em>’</a>s depiction of growing up as a lonely, fantasy-obsessed kid in the ’90s that makes it resonate. And that’s true regardless of whether you, like writer / director Jane Schoenbrun, were a fan of <em>Buffy the Vampire Slayer</em>.</p><p>The film’s mind-bending story centers on Owen (Justice Smith) and Maddy (Brigette Lundy-Paine). The two outsiders spark an unlikely friendship over their shared love of <em>The Pink Opaque</em>, a fictional fantasy / horror series that feels like a twisted mashup of <em>The Adventures of Pete &amp; Pete </em>and <em>Are You Afraid of the Dark? </em>Between its angsty, lo-fi atmosphere and pivots into explicit B-movie horror, almost every frame speaks to how large an impact <em>Buffy</em> had on Schoenbrun’s young imagination. But you can also hear Schoenbrun <a href="https://www.queergeektheory.org/2009/04/eve-kosofsky-sedgwick-1950-2009/">channeling the ideas</a> of queer theorists like <a href="https://queertheoryvisualculture.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sedgwick_queerperformativity.pdf">Eve Kosofsky Sedgwick</a> as the film explores what it really means to see one’s self in fiction.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24159054/i-saw-the-tv-glow-jane-schoenbrun-interview">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-02b82cbb-6a99-4dc5-9a47-27fdc5ff2b31"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24161514/hellblade-2-review-xbox-pc">Hellblade II’s stunning world is alive with horror</a></h2><p>Traversing the nightmare realms of the human mind has always been central to horror. The stories we tell ourselves about what’s moving in the darkness, the creation of monsters out of unknown sounds — from this emerges our fascination with terror. In <em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II</em>, players navigate a cold, dark ninth-century Iceland in the often wet shoes of the Pictish warrior Senua on her second adventure in the third-person action-horror franchise. I was very fond of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/9/16117978/hellblade-senuas-sacrifice-review-ps4-pc">the first <em>Hellblade</em></a>, which saw Senua journey into Hel to save the soul of her lover. But the sequel pulled me in even further, with some of the most unforgettable and unsettling psychological horror I’ve ever experienced.</p><p>Senua, who lives with psychosis that causes her to hear constant voices, is a fierce warrior who has “killed” gods before in her personal quests at redemption. Cast out by her people in the Orkney Islands for being different, or a “witch,” she has taken her battles across the sea to rescue her people from slavers.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24161514/hellblade-2-review-xbox-pc">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-6bbb6b61-13b0-46e0-936e-5bfa71151366"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24153478/crow-country-review-steam-ps5-xbox">Crow Country is a gloriously grimy revival of ’90s survival horror</a></h2><p>Even as modern horror games become <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/23/14353714/resident-evil-7-biohazard-review-ps4-xbox-one-pc">unnervingly immersive</a>, there’s still a place for the particular mood of old-school survival horror. Through a combo of grimy visuals, cryptic puzzles, slow pacing, and clunky controls, PlayStation-era games like <em>Resident Evil</em> and <em>Silent Hill</em> were able to create a distinct kind of tension and terror. <em>Crow Country</em> is what would happen if that kind of game never went out of style. It has the look and feel of the classics but with just the right amount of modern flourish. It’s a perfect bite of classic horror.</p><p><em>Crow Country</em> comes from indie studio SFB Games — led by brothers Tom and Adam Vian — which has so far managed to create quite the eclectic library of releases. There was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/10/16633946/snipperclips-plus-nintendo-switch-interview">the playful Switch launch title <em>Snipperclips</em></a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/16/20917268/apple-arcade-tangle-tower-localization-translation">the point-and-click murder mystery <em>Tangle Tower</em></a>, and now a dark survival horror game. <em>Crow Country</em> doesn’t just evoke the <strong>’</strong>90s&nbsp;— it’s set during the period as well. The entire game takes place in an abandoned Atlanta amusement park in 1990, as a woman named Mara sets out in search of the park’s elusive owner who mysteriously disappeared. Of course, the place is teeming with monsters and mystery.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24153478/crow-country-review-steam-ps5-xbox">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-a61f2bbf-e1b8-49ed-941b-676f935ec39b"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24141747/i-saw-the-tv-glow-review-a24">I Saw the TV Glow is a tribute to the transformative power of fandom</a></h2><p>Discovering and latching on to pieces of art that touch you in profound, formative ways is a beautiful part of growing up in a world that’s so thoroughly saturated with mass media. In their first film, <em>We’re All Going to the World’s Fair</em>, writer / director Jane Schoenbrun turned that facet of childhood into an intimate coming-of-age horror about creating one’s identity on the internet. </p><p>But with their second feature, A24’s <em>I Saw the TV Glow</em>, Schoenbrun cultivates that idea into an even more unsettling, moving narrative by framing obsessive fandom as both a blessing and a curse. Whereas <em>We’re All Going to the World’s Fair </em>was a snapshot of life in the age of modern social media, <em>I Saw the TV Glow </em>is an exploration of what it felt like to be an outcast teenager in the ’90s — a time when young fans of sci-fi and fantasy often had to find each other by chance.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24141747/i-saw-the-tv-glow-review-a24">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-92f9809c-0bd9-40a4-a952-2d1b99dd0165"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/20/24135658/late-night-with-the-devil-horror-movie-shudder">The self-possessed horrors of Late Night with the Devil</a></h2><div><figure><span><span></span></span><p><cite>Courtesy of IFC Films and Shudder</cite></p></figure></div><p>Horror films live and die by their conceits. And sometimes, the best way to make a movie scary is to place it in an environment that’s not scary at all.</p><p>Is there anything further from spooky than a brightly lit TV studio? The <a href="https://variety.com/2024/film/box-office/ghostbusters-frozen-empire-box-office-opening-weekend-1235950537/amp/">surprise box office darling</a> <em>Late Night with the Devil</em>, which hit horror streamer Shudder this weekend (and might be more suited to home viewing), tries to make one of the most innocuous American broadcast traditions into a terror. David Dastmalchian, a character actor who you’ll recognize from the margins of half a dozen Christopher Nolan and Denis Villeneuve movies, gets a rare star turn as Jack Delroy, the host of late-night talk show <em>Night Owls</em>. But in an era where Johnny Carson rules after-hours broadcast, Delroy’s second-place program is on the verge of getting canceled. The only way to save it, Delroy believes, is to air an extraordinary Halloween episode about the occult in the middle of sweeps season.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/20/24135658/late-night-with-the-devil-horror-movie-shudder">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li></ul></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Are People Still Bidding On Back To The Future DeLorean Replicas In 2024?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/back-to-the-future-delorean-replica-bidding-1851671507</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-are-people-still-bidding-on-back-to-the-future-delorean-replicas-in-2024.1008147/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/back-to-the-future-delorean-replica-bidding-1851671507<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Were you obsessed with “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://jalopnik.com/these-are-the-absurdly-great-cars-of-the-back-to-the-fu-450778851?_gl=1*7fa16j*_ga*MTI0MTc0NDE1Ni4xNzIxODQ4NTkw*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODY3NzIyMy45OC4wLjE3Mjg2NzcyMjMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://jalopnik.com/these-are-the-absurdly-great-cars-of-the-back-to-the-fu-450778851?_gl=1*7fa16j*_ga*MTI0MTc0NDE1Ni4xNzIxODQ4NTkw*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODY3NzIyMy45OC4wLjE3Mjg2NzcyMjMuNjAuMC4w">Back to the Future</a></span>” growing up? Did you never grow out of that obsession? Do you quote ‘80s movies so frequently your wife finally left you for some guy willing to watch newer movies and eat his vegetables without being told? Well, then boy have I got the car for you — this Back to the Future–themed 1982 <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://jalopnik.com/watching-vintage-dmc-delorean-crash-tests-will-make-you-1851622707?_gl=1*7fa16j*_ga*MTI0MTc0NDE1Ni4xNzIxODQ4NTkw*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODY3NzIyMy45OC4wLjE3Mjg2NzcyMjMuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://jalopnik.com/watching-vintage-dmc-delorean-crash-tests-will-make-you-1851622707?_gl=1*7fa16j*_ga*MTI0MTc0NDE1Ni4xNzIxODQ4NTkw*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODY3NzIyMy45OC4wLjE3Mjg2NzcyMjMuNjAuMC4w">DeLorean DMC-12</a></span> that’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://carsandbids.com/auctions/3gd5mN58/1982-delorean-dmc-12-time-machine-replica&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://carsandbids.com/auctions/3gd5mN58/1982-delorean-dmc-12-time-machine-replica" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">currently listed on Cars &amp; Bids</a></span>. Why bidding is already up to $35,000 at the time of writing, I can’t explain, but then again, I also have no idea who these replicas are for.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197284" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Iconic Director And Proud Nerd Kevin Smith On Sneaking Into Movies, Mallrats, And More" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="643" data-playlist="197284,197260,197209" data-current="197284"><div><p>Iconic Director And Proud Nerd Kevin Smith On Sneaking Into Movies, Mallrats, And More</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22826.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Now, I’ll readily admit, I’m too young to truly get “Back to the Future.” I may have been alive in the late 1900s and experienced the movie for the first time on VHS, but I was an ‘89 baby. By the time I was old enough to appreciate “Back to the Future,” its cultural impact had dissipated. Had I been born 20 years earlier, I would have been 16 when it came out, and I’d probably understand the attachment people have to a prop made out of a shitty car, but whether it’s age or something else, I just don’t get it. </p><p>The thing is, though, I don’t think it’s specifically a “Back to the Future” thing. I just don’t see any point in owning something that’s so obviously a movie prop. Want to build a replica of the black Toyota SR5 from the same series? Go for it. In fact, I even understand paying a little extra for a truck with the right BTTF<em> </em>look. It’s a subtle nod to those who know, but to everyone else, you’re just driving around in a cool, old pickup truck. </p><p>A DMC-12 that’s been given the time machine treatment, on the other hand, is only cool to people who are big fans of a move that’s nearly 40 years old. If you took it to a convention or something, I could see the appeal there, but for use outside of that? You’re just driving around in an obvious movie prop, and it comes off like you desperately want people to talk to you about your car. For less than $10,000, I could maybe understand, but these things go for real money! There are five days left on the auction, and as previously mentioned, it’s already been bid up to $35,000. I honestly wouldn’t be surprised if this thing ends up going for more than I make in a year.</p><p>The real questions here are “To whom?” and “Why?” And while it probably sounds like I’m being snarky here, I promise I genuinely want to understand. What is the appeal of these cars? Are Gen X-ers realizing 65 is creeping up on them quickly and desperately trying to relive their youth? Please tell me what I’m missing because, clearly, I’m missing something here.</p><p><em>This story originally appeared on Jalopnik, our sister site, on Friday, October 11.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forgotten Memories: Remastered Edition launches October 28 for Switch, iOS, and Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/forgotten-memories-remastered-edition-launches-october-28-for-switch-ios-and-android</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forgotten-memories-remastered-edition-launches-october-28-for-switch-ios-and-android.1008144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/forgotten-memories-remastered-edition-launches-october-28-for-switch-ios-and-android<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The 2015-released survival horror game remastered.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Survival [332 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> horror game <em><a title="Games > Forgotten Memories: Remastered Edition" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/forgotten-memories-remastered-edition">Forgotten Memories: Remastered Edition</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,167 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, iOS, and Android on October 28, developer <a title="Companies > Psychose Interactive" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/psychose-interactive">Psychose Interactive</a> announced. Pre-orders will open on October 25. <span id="more-921013"></span></p><p><em>Forgotten Memories: Remastered Edition</em> is a remastered version of the <em>Forgotten Memories</em>, originally released for iOS and Android on April 23, 2015, with “tons of new stuff and improvements.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Psychose Interactive:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A new <em>Forgotten Memories: Remastered Edition</em> is coming! Tons of new stuff and improvements!</p><p>Take a deep breath and get ready for the horror of <em>Forgotten Memories</em>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In <em>Forgotten Memories</em>, you take on the role of Rose Hawkins, a determined police detective who finds herself caught in a web of enigmatic events while investigating a strange case. As Rose wakes up in an eerie unfamiliar place, she encounters Noah, a mysterious and striking woman who offers her a deal. This precarious alliance promises to aid Rose in her investigation but at what cost?</p><p><strong>Old School Survival Horror With a Modern Touch</strong></p><p><em>Forgotten Memories</em> is a third-person survival horror game combining exploration, reflection, puzzles, action and survival where gameplay is centered around fear mechanics.</p><p>A spiritual successor to the greatest <a title="Genres > Horror [504 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror games</a> of the ’90s, <em>Forgotten Memories</em> is a true classic survival horror game redefined for modern audiences.</p><p><strong>A Great Gameplay <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong></p><p><em>Forgotten Memories</em> combines deep psychological narratives, beautifully rendered environments, and smooth gameplay action into a fantastic horror experience you will never forget.</p><p>Enjoy incredible voice acting with Guy Cihi and David Schaufele (as James Sunderland and Eddie Dombrowski in <em><a title="Games > Silent Hill 2 (2024) [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/silent-hill-2-2024">Silent Hill 2</a></em>) among others.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Climatic horror experience with a deep narrative.</li><li>Talented voice acting from diverse mediums.</li><li>High-resolution and smooth graphics (HDR, dynamic lighting and shadows, multiple shading models, and post-processing).</li><li>Classic survival horror mechanics.</li><li>Challenging but adaptable gameplay with multiple levels of gameplay difficulty.</li><li>Highly replayable gameplay with unlockables, achievements, and rankings.</li><li>Smooth, accurate touch and gamepad controls.</li><li>Full premium game without in-game mechanical purchases. We don’t sell any weapons, ammunition, or anything that will impact the game experience. You will be on your own!</li></ul><p><strong>Remastered Edition Features</strong></p><ul><li>New optimized renderer with latest BRDF and BSDF lighting models.</li><li>New graphic options, improved game resolution, new lighting effects, new post-processes and new particles FXs.</li><li>Improved textures and character models.</li><li>Audio, music, and videos remastered.</li><li>New voices and audio recorded.</li><li>New save system with checkpoints.</li><li>Improved gameplay systems.</li><li>New combats, interactions, and spawns.</li><li>Improved behavior, navigation and animation controllers for player and enemies.</li><li>Improved overall difficulty.</li><li>New Insane mode, new achievements.</li><li>Improved localization and user interface.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Genres > Action [2,239 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Forgotten Memories Remastered - Action Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/351KrPtoDb0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Streamer Finds Tarkov Player With 1.3 Million Raids and Kills]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/streamer-tarkov-player-million-raids/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/streamer-finds-tarkov-player-with-1-3-million-raids-and-kills.1008084/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/streamer-tarkov-player-million-raids/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Recently, a popular Escape from Tarkov streamer stumbled across a player with a staggering (and implausible) <strong>1.3 million raids and kills</strong>. This particular player has almost 9,000 hours of playtime, has survived 1,341,434 raids in a row, and has assembled a KD of just 1.0. None of the numbers make sense, so it’s either a mathematical marvel or a serious issue that has occurred in the back end.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-rookie-numbers">Rookie Numbers</h2>



<p>On Twitter, <a href="https://x.com/RealTigz/status/1844853227772416066" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">‘Tigz’ posted an image</a> of a player with some stunning stats.</p>



<ul>
<li>1,342,602 raids</li>



<li>567 survived</li>



<li>541 KIA</li>



<li>53 AWOL</li>



<li>1,341,764 kills</li>
</ul>



<p>Other users started commenting on this post, sharing images of the same player. One managed to capture a shot of this user just one match later, showing him kitted up (per the profile) and ready for battle, which suggests it’s a real player sitting behind a screen somewhere.</p>



<p>The most likely explanation is a bug in the data because it’s mathematically impossible for a user to have played that many matches since the game was wiped in August. It’s no big secret that Escape from Tarkov’s cheaters are capable of some pretty wild stuff, but they can’t bend the laws of time and space to their will.</p>



<p>It gets better, though.</p>



<p>A little digging <a href="https://x.com/Abbas2002_/status/1844955796024516638" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">turned up another user</a> with 64 hours played and <strong>41 million </strong>raids and kills. Again, this user has a KD of just 1 but they also had an average lifespan of 00:00, suggesting that their raids aren’t even loading before they’re dying again. </p>



<p>If nothing else, it’s an indication of how fragile Escape from Tarkov’s data infrastructure must be. This revelation comes mere weeks after <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-malfunction-profile-wipe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a data issue wiped thousands</a> of Escape from Tarkov accounts, leaving Battlestate Games to offer immense in-game compensation to users.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-now-shows-that-you-dont-actually-own-the-game-youre-buying/">the Steam licensing controversy</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Faker Has Just Won His 100th Match at League Worlds]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/faker-100-matches-league-worlds/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/faker-has-just-won-his-100th-match-at-league-worlds.1008081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/faker-100-matches-league-worlds/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Lee ‘Faker’ Sang-hyeok is arguably the most recognisable competitor in the world of esports. He’s the GOAT of League of Legends and is considered a rockstar in South Korea, and he <strong>just </strong>ticked over 100 match wins at League of Legends Worlds. He’s the first player in history to achieve that milestone, and it comes after ten years of competing at the tournament.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-massive-milestone">Massive Milestone</h2>



<p>In 2013, Faker attended – and won – his first League Worlds, scoring a 3 – 0 victory over Royal Club with T1 to net a $1,000,000 grand prize. Since then, he has claimed the top spot at the 2015, 2016, and 2023 League World Championships, becoming the winningest player not just in League, but perhaps in the entire esports industry.</p>



<p>Those major victories have been bolstered by number-one finishes at the likes of MSI, the LCK, and IEM. As a whole, Faker has claimed almost $2 million individually since entering the League of Legends pro scene.</p>



<p>Recently, he became the first player to secure a major milestone, notching up his one-hundredth win at LoL Worlds. It arrived during a Swiss Stage fixture against G2 Esports, with T1 effortlessly grabbing a 2 – 0 victory over the European side. </p>



<p>Thus far in the tournament, T1 has lost just one match out of four, and it’s looking good for yet another victory for Faker – but let’s not speak too soon. There’s still quite a long road ahead, and the grand final of this year’s League Worlds event won’t arrive until November 2, when players will descend upon London, England to fight for the $445,000 grand prize.</p>



<p>Are you predicting another win for T1? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nrg-hosts-valorant-event-with-intel-featuring-gaming-pros/">NRG is hosting an exclusive VALORANT event with Intel</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Something for the Weekend – 12/10/24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/12/something-for-the-weekend-12-10-24/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/something-for-the-weekend-%E2%80%93-12-10-24.1008054/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/12/something-for-the-weekend-12-10-24/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>There’s some sneezy sniffles in store for my weekend (thankfully without a C-word involved, at least), so I’m looking forward to hunkering down with games today and as much NFL as I can fit in my eyeholes tomorrow. Though I suppose I should try to finish some DIY projects as well…</p>
<p>Let’s get to the week’s gaming news and reviews, though, with a big huge JRPG that should be high on everyone’s wish lists.</p>
<h2>In the News This Week</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/11/tomb-raider-iv-vi-remastered-announced-for-another-valentines-day-release/">Tomb Raider IV-VI Remastered announced for another Valentine’s Day release</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/alien-isolation-2-sequel-announced/">Alien: Isolation sequel announced by Creative Assembly</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/343-industries-is-now-halo-studios-announces-switch-to-unreal-engine-5/">343 Industries is now Halo Studios – Announces switch to Unreal Engine 5</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/09/nintendo-alarmo-is-an-alarm-clock-and-not-switch-2/">Nintendo’s latest hardware reveal is quite alarming</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/08/red-dead-redemption-is-finally-coming-to-pc-this-month/">Red Dead Redemption is finally coming to PC this month</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/10/stampede-racing-royale-launches-for-free-with-a-dave-the-diver-collab/">Stampede Racing Royale launches for free with a Dave the Diver collab</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/10/football-manager-25-has-now-been-delayed-to-march-2025/">Football Manager 25 has now been delayed to March 2025</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/08/littlebigplanet-3-and-all-dlc-are-being-delisted-on-31st-october/">LittleBigPlanet 3 and all DLC are being delisted on 31st October</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/11/xbox-cloud-gaming-could-soon-let-you-stream-your-own-games-game-pass/">Xbox Cloud Gaming could soon let you stream your own games</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>Games in Review &amp; Featured Articles</h2>
<p>JRPG fans should be over the moon with Metaphor: ReFantazio, a new game that branches off the Persona style of role playing in a new direction.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/metaphor-refantazio-review/"><strong>Metaphor: ReFantazio</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PS4, PC – 9/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/10/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-review-incredible-anime-action-and-beautiful-visuals/"><strong>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</strong></a> – PS5, XSX|S, PC – 8/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/10/until-dawn-2024-review/"><strong>Until Dawn</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, PC – 8/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/09/ravenswatch-review-a-grimms-fairy-tale-delight/"><strong>Ravenswatch</strong></a> – PS5, XSX|S, PS4, XBO, <strong>PC</strong> – 8/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/parcel-corps-review/"><strong>Parcel Corps</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PC – 7/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/08/enotria-the-last-song-review/"><strong>Enotria</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PC – 7/10</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/undisputed-review/">Undisputed</a>&nbsp;</strong>– <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PC – 6/10</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond the reviews, Miguel delved into the big <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/mortal-kombat-1-khaos-reigns-review-kompletely-underwhelming/">Khaos Reigns DLC for Mortal Kombat 1</a></strong>, but came away a bit disappointed. Aran then previewed cute looking llama ’em up <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/08/llamalandia-preview-live-llama-love/">Llamalandia</a></strong>, and I got some hands on time with <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/10/mario-luigi-brothership-preview/">Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</a></strong>.</p>
<p><iframe title="Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership Preview – A big &amp; boatiful return?" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bbteDtZAuCM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Rounding things out as always, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/11/what-we-played-metaphor-refantazio-until-dawn-cyberpunk-2077/"><strong>What We Played</strong></a> featured Metaphor: ReFantazio, Until Dawn and Cyberpunk 2077.</p>
<h2>Trailer Park</h2>
<p><strong>Masahiro Sakurai ends his YouTube channel with a heartfelt ode to Satoru Iwata</strong></p>
<p><iframe title="Mr. Iwata [Grab Bag]" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o2wYKkqhkG0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/pathologic-3-revealed-for-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs/">Pathologic 3 revealed for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Pathologic 3 Announce Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zb0C2WYUjkI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>Your Achievements</h2>
<p>Let’s see what you’ve been up to:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>TSBonyman</strong> completed the point &amp; click adventure Truberbrook, continued on with Astro Bot and grabbed High on Life and the Sherlock Holmes bundle on sale, where he’s already liking the first case and detecting mechanics.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s the round up for this week. Hope you have a great weekend ahead!</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Must-Have Stormcast Eternals: Our Favorites]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/must-have-stormcast-eternals-our-favorites</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/must-have-stormcast-eternals-our-favorites.1008036/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/must-have-stormcast-eternals-our-favorites<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Serving as the golden children of the world of&nbsp;<em>Warhammer Age of Sigmar</em>, the Stormcast Eternals are once again riding down to the mortal realms on a crack of lightning! Including a huge new range of reinforcements (some brand new, some previously only available via boxed sets), there's a lot to choose from for your army. But I'm here to help! Games Workshop sent me a big batch of these new units to check out, so read on for my picks for Must-Have Stormcast Eternals.</p>
<p>For more of our&nbsp;<em>Age of Sigmar</em>&nbsp;coverage, check out our <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/new-skaven-warhammer-miniatures-review-rats-off-to-ya">coverage of new Skaven miniatures</a>, and our r<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-age-of-sigmar-skaventide-review-perfect-starter-set">eview of the new <em>Warhammer Age of Sigmar</em>&nbsp;Starter Set</a>. And to see all of the upcoming Stormcast Eternals releases coming up for pre-order, check out the <a href="https://www.warhammer-community.com/en-us/articles/yrpl1os9/sunday-preview-unleash-the-ruination-chamber/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">official Warhammer Community Sunday Previews article</a> breaking it all down.</p>
<h2>Must-Have Stormcast Eternals: Iridan The Witness</h2>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/iridan-the-witness.jpeg?itok=RxlPAZaH 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/iridan-the-witness.jpeg?itok=DwMCsdIa 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>First up, we have to talk about the largest, perhaps flashiest model in this batch of incoming Stormcast units. And even though I don't have access to the&nbsp;<em>Stormcast Eternals</em>&nbsp;battletome just yet (I do have the Faction Pack, which Iridan isn't in), what I can see from the article leading up to his release makes me&nbsp;<em>very</em>&nbsp;excited.</p>
<p>Take, for instance, his "Prayer of the Witness" ability, which states: <em>"For the rest of the turn, each time a friendly&nbsp;Ruination Chamber&nbsp;unit uses a&nbsp;Fight&nbsp;ability while it is wholly within 18" of this unit, after that ability has been resolved: Heal (D3)&nbsp;that unit. If the chanting roll was 8+,&nbsp;Heal (3)&nbsp;that unit instead. That unit has&nbsp;Ward (6+)&nbsp;rest of the turn."</em> In other words, if you plan on crowding other fighting units in around him, they'll be auto-healing every time they fight!</p>
<p>He also has an ability called "Dark Flight," which lets him roll to slay an enemy unit near him and then retreat for free. Because he's riding on a giant flying monstrosity, I love the flavor of this ability which is basically: he just blasts off out of danger, absolutely splattering one hapless foe in his way.</p>
<p>We can also see from his construction booklet that he has solid health and defense, with 12 HP and a 3+ save. We can also tell from these bare-bones rules that his main weapon has 4 attacks, hits and damages on 3+, with Rend 2, dealing d3 damage. So while we teasingly don't have the full details yet, I really like what I see - and the model is absolutely gorgeous.</p>
<h2>Must-Have Stormcast Eternals: Lord-Celestant</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/must-have-stormcast-eternals-lord-celestant.jpg?itok=0mrHg0lS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/must-have-stormcast-eternals-lord-celestant.jpg?itok=HS-mJ7jm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Lord-Celestant now comes in multiple builds, allowing you to customize the look of your army (MUCH needed in a Stormcast Eternals list)</figcaption></figure><p>The Lord-Celestant has always been a good option for players who prefer a more aggressive playstyle, as their key ability is to allow another friendly non-Hero Warrior Chamber unit within their combat range (3") to fight right after they fight (and adds 1 to wound rolls). This means you can really surround an enemy unit, and get in a lot of hits before they can reasonably respond with much force.</p>
<p>This new release of the model includes a big variety of potential builds for this unit, which I think does a really nice job of helping us get away from a samey-looking army of Stormcast Eternals, which is why I think this unit's definitely worth having!</p>
<h2>Must-Have Stormcast Eternals: Lord-Terminos</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/must-have-stormcast-eternals-lord-terminos.jpg?itok=LNVTrS_k 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/must-have-stormcast-eternals-lord-terminos.jpg?itok=k1A_TVEU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Lord-Terminos and his little friend here (the Memorian) simply shrug off your special abilities.</figcaption></figure><p>While I understand that the Lord-Terminos is effectively a beefed up version of the Lord-Celestant, the&nbsp;<em>way&nbsp;</em>in which he's beefed up is absolutely worth highlighting. First off, he has the same ability to let another unit fight as mentioned above, except that instead of adding 1 to wound rolls for that other unit, he's adding 1 to hit rolls. That's... big.</p>
<p>Also, when he's picked as the target of a non-Core ability (aka a special ability), once per turn you can roll a resistance die, and on a 4+, that ability has no effect on him. The thought of simply ignoring some fell spell makes this unit feel so hardy (and his 3+ save doesn't hurt either).</p>
<h2>Must-Have Stormcast Eternals: Stormstrike Palladors</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/must-have-stormcast-eternals-stormstrike-palladors.jpg?itok=TwDqKAZZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/must-have-stormcast-eternals-stormstrike-palladors.jpg?itok=R8drD3Lr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I love the look of these Griff-riding Palladors!</figcaption></figure><p>This is another unit that I don't have a ton of info on yet, except to say that the models themselves are absolutely top-rate and have an extremely dynamic, mid-action move to them that I've come to expect from modern cavalry units in&nbsp;<em>Age of Sigmar</em>. Giving some visual movement to the collection here is really nice, and shows the fury of their attack.</p>
<p>As for the abilities we do know about at the time of this writing, the most interesting (aside from them have the usual Anti-Infantry rule that makes sense for mounted units) is their "Ride For Vengeance" special ability, which states that: <em>"if any friendly Warrior Chamber units have been destroyed this battle: You can re-roll charge rolls for this unit. This unit has&nbsp;Strike-First&nbsp;if it charged in the same turn."</em></p>
<h2>Bonus! Stormreach Portal</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/must-have-stormcast-eternals-stormreach-portal.jpg?itok=tojQi5Ru 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/must-have-stormcast-eternals-stormreach-portal.jpg?itok=xeRRYVyi 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I love the mausoleum look of this portal - very fitting for our constantly dying Eternals!</figcaption></figure><p>Finally, and more as a bonus, because I don't honestly think this unit is a "Must-Have" necessarily, is the Stormreach Portal. Aside from it being just absolutely gorgeous, and looking very nifty on the battlefield, it also has an incredible ability built into it.</p>
<p>Basically, when on your movement phase, you can choose a friendly non-Monster Stormcast Eternals&nbsp;unit, and as long as it's not currently in combat and is close to the Portal (i.e. wholly within 6"), you can: <em>"Remove the target from the battlefield and set it up again on the battlefield more than 9" from all enemy units."</em></p>
<p>The amount of mobility that this will add to your army, getting them basically&nbsp;<em>wherever</em>&nbsp;they want to be, is hard to ignore. But I wouldn't call it officially "Must-Have" since not every army's going to need that extra mobility.</p>
<p>What do you think of the new models coming out for Stormcast Eternals? Is this a solid upgrade to the army (both tactically and, in the case of new sculpts, cosmetically), or were you hoping for a different approach? Let us know in the comments below!</p>
<hr><p><em>The models used in the creation of this feature article were provided by Games Workshop. All images courtesy of Games Workshop.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Giaco Furino joined the TechRaptor team as a Staff Writer in 2019 after searching for a dedicated place to write and talk about Tabletop Games. In 2020, he… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/giaco-furino">More about Giaco</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Until Dawn 2 Seemingly Teased by Actor Peter Stormare]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/until-dawn-2-seemingly-teased-by-actor-peter-stormare/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/until-dawn-2-seemingly-teased-by-actor-peter-stormare.1008033/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/until-dawn-2-seemingly-teased-by-actor-peter-stormare/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Renowned actor Peter Stormare (Fargo, Armageddon, Constantine) has seemingly teased the existence of Until Dawn 2 <a href="https://www.instagram.com/therealstormare/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on his Instagram profile</a>. The latest story is a repost of the fan page Until Dawn News, which suggested a sequel was kinda confirmed by one of the remake's new endings.</p>
<p>Peter Stormare played the key character Dr. Hill in the game, and he's set to reprise his role in the upcoming movie adaptation <a href="https://wccftech.com/until-dawn-is-being-adapted-into-a-movie-annabelle-2-creation-director-and-writer-attached/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> earlier this year to be in development by Annabelle 2: Creation and Shazam! Director David F. Sandberg. As such, he would likely be kept in the know for a follow-up game, too.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Sony does appear to be investing quite a lot in the IP, between the adaptation and the Unreal Engine 5 remake that was just released for PlayStation 5 and PC by Ballistic Moon. Granted, the remake didn't exactly have the best reception, with its <a href="https://wccftech.com/until-dawn-ps5-remake-is-expected-to-retail-at-60-consumers-will-have-to-pay-the-sony-tax/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">high price&nbsp;tag</a> and several <a href="https://wccftech.com/until-dawn-pc-remake-has-a-broken-ray-tracing-experience-amd-fsr-3-doesnt-work-at-all/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">broken tech features on the PC version</a>. However, personally, I would really love to see Until Dawn 2. The big question would be who would handle it: original developer Supermassive Games or Ballistic Moon itself. Sadly, the latter option appears unlikely as the studio just had to 'significantly scale down' and lay off some of its employees in order to stay afloat.</p>
<p>In case you're still on the fence about whether to get the remake, here's what I <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/until-dawn-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">thought</a> about the original when it first launched on PlayStation 4:</p>
<p><em>I'll be honest, I'm not the biggest fan of the horror genre. In fact, chances to see me in line for the next horror flick are basically none. Despite this, Until Dawn kept me engaged and interested all the way (and a bit scared - yes, I jumped a few times) thanks to its intriguing plot. Nothing is as it seems up on this mountain, and the writers definitely did a fine job in weaving the story, which is guaranteed to grab your attention.</em></p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hogwarts Legacy Definitive Edition Reportedly Coming Next Year With 10-15 Hours of New Content]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-definitive-edition-reportedly-coming-next-year-with-10-15-hours-of-new-content/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hogwarts-legacy-definitive-edition-reportedly-coming-next-year-with-10-15-hours-of-new-content.1008030/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-definitive-edition-reportedly-coming-next-year-with-10-15-hours-of-new-content/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Insider Tom Henderson has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-hogwarts-legacy-definitive-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published</a> a new report on Hogwarts Legacy Definitive Edition. We first got wind that Warner Bros. Games was doing something of the sort last June when Jason Schreier <a href="https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-directors-cut/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a> that some members of Rocksteady were working on a Director's Cut for the game.</p>
<p>Now, Henderson says this new version of the game will include between 10 and 15 hours of new content, including a story quest, more side quests and activities, and, of course, new outfits. According to the report, Hogwarts Legacy Definitive Edition should be launched next year. Owners of the base game will be able to upgrade to it for $20 or $30.</p>
<p>Avalanche Software's game was incredibly successful despite the boycott attempts against J.K. Rowling (who had nothing to do with the development). Hogwarts Legacy <a href="https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-sold-22-million-units-is-the-best-selling-game-of-2023-says-wb-more-hp-things-on-the-way/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">came out on top</a> in 2023's best-selling charts despite incredibly fierce competition. Last we heard, the game had <a href="https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-has-sold-24-million-units-new-features-and-ex-playstation-exclusive-content-coming-in-q3-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sold</a> 24 million units as of this January, and that number has certainly gone up since.</p>
<p>On Wccftech, the game <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/hogwarts-legacy-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">got</a> an 8.5 out of 10 score. Here's what reviewer Chris Wray had to say about it:</p>
<p><em>Hogwarts Legacy is, for better or worse, an entertaining and engaging game. By far the best digital version of the wizarding world, it offers a vast swathe of things to do. Even the more mundane elements (bandit camps!) are improved by a robust combat system that genuinely makes you feel like you're a part of the Harry Potter universe.</em></p>
<p>After all this success, it's no wonder Warner Bros. wants more of it. Just last month, WB Discovery CFO Gunnar Wiedenfels <a href="https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-2-is-wb-games-biggest-priority-but-itll-take-a-couple-of-years/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> the sequel is a priority, although it will take a few years before it can be released. WB Discovery also <a href="https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-2-is-probably-going-to-be-live-service-wb-says-aaa-console-market-isnt-enough/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hinted</a> via JB Perrette (CEO and President of Global Streaming and Games) that Hogwarts Legacy 2 could very well incorporate live service elements, although it's way too early to figure out in what capacity.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When Is Escape from Tarkov 1.0 Being Released?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/when-tarkov-1-0-being-released/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-escape-from-tarkov-1-0-being-released.1008024/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/when-tarkov-1-0-being-released/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Escape from Tarkov is the most ambitious and popular extraction shooter ever made. It can be argued it has driven the genre’s growth since dropping into an alpha state almost a decade ago. The game has been in beta since 2016, which is a fact that often prompts users to ask: ‘When <strong>is </strong>Escape from Tarkov 1.0 being released?’</p>



<p>Technically, Escape from Tarkov hasn’t <strong>been released </strong>because it has been in a testing phase for almost ten years. It’ll be officially released when it’s a 1.0 product, which will only happen when the developer, Battlestate Games, feels like it’s ready to be classed as a full, finished game.</p>



<p><strong>So</strong>, when is Escape from Tarkov being released? Let’s find out.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-what-is-tarkov-1-0">What is Tarkov 1.0?</h2>



<p>Escape from Tarkov 1.0 will be the game’s version number when it becomes a fully released product. Until now, it has been numbered ‘0.15’, for example. That means there have been 15 major updates to the game since it entered a beta phase, but it is yet to be considered a full game.</p>



<p>When Tarkov 1.0 is released, the first major update will be ‘1.1’, and so on. </p>



<p>Sometimes, a game will have such a monumental overhaul that it’s considered a 2.0 product. For instance, in 2023, Cyberpunk 2077 underwent a phenomenal list of changes that made it feel like a whole new game – but it wasn’t. To describe that scenario, it was dubbed Cyberpunk 2077 2.0.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-will-be-in-tarkov-1-0">What Will Be in Tarkov 1.0?</h2>



<p>Battlestate Games has fleshed out the Escape from Tarkov platform so much over the years, but there are still plenty of changes lined up for the 1.0 release. For instance, the team endeavours to put in place a dedicated storyline that’ll see players <strong>actually escape from Tarkov</strong>. By doing this, they’ll wipe the game, reset their character, and start afresh.</p>



<p>If they repeatedly complete the game, they’ll go through a ‘Prestige’ system.</p>



<p>Elsewhere, Battlestate wants to add clans, alliances, and more factions to the game. Factions are rarely added to Escape from Tarkov, and for the most part, we’ve had the same units running around the game for almost ten years. The team also wants to introduce more DLC, further hideout expansions, a third-party API release, and more new maps.</p>



<p>That’s alongside all the usual changes that are added to the game: new weapons, new equipment, tweaked mechanics, and so on.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-tarkov-1-0-being-released">When is Tarkov 1.0 Being Released?</h2>



<p>Presently, Tarkov 1.0 doesn’t have a release date, but in 2024, it dominated discussions related to the game. It’s expected that Tarkov 1.0 will arrive in 2026, as current roadmaps covering the game run until at least 2025. Like any new game, Battlestate will pour a huge amount of focus and money into marketing the release of Tarkov 1.0.</p>



<p>And that kind of thing takes <strong>a lot </strong>of time.</p>



<p>I’m predicting that Tarkov 1.0 will be released in 2026, and then the team will move on to focus on something else for the first time in more than a decade.</p>



<hr>



<p>Need more Tarkov content? Find out when the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-escape-from-tarkov-wipe/">next wipe is in Tarkov</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite's 2024 Halloween Event Arrives Today, Features Outfits from Saw, Texas Chainsaw Massacre]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnites-2024-halloween-event-arrives-today-features-outfits-from-saw-texas-chainsaw-massacre</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnites-2024-halloween-event-arrives-today-features-outfits-from-saw-texas-chainsaw-massacre.1008021/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnites-2024-halloween-event-arrives-today-features-outfits-from-saw-texas-chainsaw-massacre<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">There's a cannibal joke here, but it'd be in bad taste.</h2></div><section><p>Fortnitemares 2024, Fortnite's annual Halloween event, goes live today and will feature the return of Horde Rush, a pile of fresh quests and rewards, and a host of recognisable, horror-themed outfits hitting the Shop.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Horde Rush will be available for the duration of this year's event, and players will be able to complete Horde Rush quests and Rocket Racing Nitemares quests for XP that will grant a variety of rewards.</p><p>Fornitemares 2024 also arrives with a new chainsaw weapon dubbed the Boom Billy, which can be used to carve through enemies (or thrust into the ground and revved to drag your character forward at "frightening speeds"). In addition to this, the Wood Stake Shotgun, Pumpkin Launcher, and Witch Broom are all returning for this year's event.</p><p>New outfits include Billy the Puppet from Saw, Leatherface from The Texas Chainsaw Massacre, Pumpkin King and Sally from The Nightmare Before Christmas, Marvel's Mephisto, She-Venom, and Agony, plus Cruella de Vil, Maleficent, Captain Hook, Ravemello, and Edward Scissorhands. There will be an opportunity to unlock the She-Venom and Agony outfits before they arrive in the Shop for players who take part in the Symbiote Cup.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/10/11/the-symbiote-cup-en-1728622136422.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>The Symbiote Cup is a Battle Royale Duos tournament slated for October 22.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Fortnitemares 2024, which will run until the end of Chapter 5, Season 4, is just the latest salvo of content in Fornite's quest to absorb and homogenize all pop culture on the planet. Fortnite announcements in the past... fortnight alone include <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/fortnite-x-fast-furious-official-nissan-skyline-trailer">a new Fast &amp; Furious vehicle</a> and the arrival of... <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/fortnite-x-shaquille-oneal-official-trailer">Shaquille O'Neal.</a></p><p>For what it's worth, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-will-now-let-parents-set-time-limits-complete-with-in-game-pop-ups-warning-its-time-to-logoff">Fornite has also just introduced new time limit controls</a> which will reportedly allow parents to cap the amount of time their kids play the game each day.</p><p><em>Luke is a Senior Editor on the IGN reviews team. You can chat to him on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/MrLukeReilly" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em><strong>@MrLukeReilly</strong></em></a><em>, but not about Fortnite.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2 Vantage Point God Roll - Best Perks And How To Get It]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-vantage-point-god-roll-best-perks-and-how-to-get-it/1100-6527139/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2-vantage-point-god-roll-best-perks-and-how-to-get-it.1007937/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-vantage-point-god-roll-best-perks-and-how-to-get-it/1100-6527139/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527139">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">While a few other guns in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/destiny-2/" data-ref-id="5000-463450">Destiny 2</a>'s <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/destiny-2-the-final-shape-episode-revenant-season-pass-gear-and-exotics/2900-5847/" data-ref-id="2900-5847">Episode: Revenant</a> stand out a bit more, like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-exuviae-god-roll-guide-best-perks-and-how-to-get/1100-6527132/" data-ref-id="1100-6527132">Exuviae</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-liturgy-god-roll-guide-best-perks-and-how-to-get-it/1100-6527136/" data-ref-id="1100-6527136">Liturgy</a>, the adaptive frame Arc pulse rifle Vantage Point you can get from the episode is pretty good, too. Its god roll makes it a well-rounded weapon in PvE in particular, and can work well with Arc builds focused on delivering Jolt to enemies to keep them electrified while keeping yourself Amplified.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#How_To_Get_Vantage_Point">How To Get Vantage Point</a></li><li><a href="#Vantage_Point_God_Rolls">Vantage Point God Rolls</a><ul><li><a href="#Vantage_Point_PvE_God_Roll">Vantage Point PvE God Roll</a></li><li><a href="#Vantage_Point_PvP_God_Roll">Vantage Point PvP God Roll</a></li></ul></li></ul></div><h2 dir="ltr" id="How_To_Get_Vantage_Point">How To Get Vantage Point</h2><p dir="ltr">Right now, Revenant weapons can be earned by playing the episode's main attraction, the wave-based <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/destiny-2-onslaught-salvation-guide-potions-banes-and-new-defenses/2900-5849/" data-ref-id="2900-5849">Onslaught: Salvation mode</a>. Revenant guns, including Vantage Point, are random drops you can get after completing certain waves and earning reward chests.</p><p dir="ltr">However, the gear that comes out of those chests is random, so while you might get Vantage Point, you might pull other weapons or armor, as well. The best way to get the guns you want is to "attune" your rewards using Revenant's Tonics system. You can craft and use Enrichment tonics that will increase the chance of getting certain drops when playing Onslaught: Salvation, making it a little easier to get the guns and rolls you want. <a href="https://www.bing.com/ck/a?!&amp;&amp;p=2043cba717880dbaJmltdHM9MTcyODYwNDgwMCZpZ3VpZD0wNWQ0MGViMC00MWEwLTY1ZGEtMGM0Yi0xZDE2NDA0ZTY0ZDImaW5zaWQ9NTE4NQ&amp;ptn=3&amp;ver=2&amp;hsh=3&amp;fclid=05d40eb0-41a0-65da-0c4b-1d16404e64d2&amp;psq=destiny+2+tonics+gamespot.com&amp;u=a1aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ2FtZXNwb3QuY29tL2dhbGxlcnkvZGVzdGlueS0yLXJldmVuYW50LXRvbmljcy1ndWlkZS1ob3ctdG8tZ2V0LW1vcmUtdG9uaWMtcmVjaXBlcy1hbmQtZmllbGR3b3JrLzI5MDAtNTg1My8&amp;ntb=1">Check out our Tonics guide for more</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">You can also get a roll of Vantage Point as a reward for completing the Revenant Act 1 story quests.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4383477-20241011110640_1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4383477" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4383477-20241011110640_1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4383477"></a><figcaption>Vantage Point</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4383477-20241011110640_1.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Vantage_Point_God_Rolls">Vantage Point God Rolls</h2><h3 dir="ltr" id="Vantage_Point_PvE_God_Roll">Vantage Point PvE God Roll</h3><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Barrel</strong>: Arrowhead Break  <ul><li dir="ltr">Recoil +30, Handling +10</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Magazine</strong>: Tactical Mag  <ul><li dir="ltr">Reload Speed +10, Stability +5, Magazine +3</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>First Perk</strong>: Keep Away  <ul><li dir="ltr">Increases reload, range, and accuracy when no enemies are in close proximity.</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Second Perk</strong>: Jolting Feedback  <ul><li dir="ltr">Dealing repeated damage with this weapon inflicts Jolt.</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Masterwork</strong>: Reload Speed</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Vantage Point is a good addition to Arc builds thanks to Jolting Feedback, which is likely to be the main perk you go for in the weapon. It allows you to easily inflict Jolt on just about any enemy you shoot, which also means that Vantage Point is great for keeping the Amplified buff going if you're using an Arc or Prismatic subclass.</p><p dir="ltr">Keep Away is good also, since you're almost always using a pulse rifle from pretty far away, so you'll get those benefits almost constantly. For a version that's less focused on Arc synergy, Stats for All and One For All are good alternatives, but the best use of Vantage Point is to take advantage of laying down Jolt all the time.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Vantage_Point_PvP_God_Roll">Vantage Point PvP God Roll</h3><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Barrel</strong>: Smallbore  <ul><li dir="ltr">Stability +7, Range +7</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Magazine</strong>: Accurized Rounds  <ul><li dir="ltr">Range +10</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>First Perk</strong>: Keep Away  <ul><li dir="ltr">Increases reload, range, and accuracy when no enemies are in close proximity.</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Second Perk</strong>: Headseeker / Desperado  <ul><li dir="ltr">Headseeker: Body shots landed with this weapon increase precision damage and aim assist for a short time. Body shots landed while the perk is active refresh the time.</li><li dir="ltr">Desperado: Reloading after a precision final blow increases your rate of fire.</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Masterwork</strong>: Stability</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Vantage Point is only so-so in PvE, but it's reliable here, still. Range and stability are important stats for pulse rifles in the Crucible, making sure your bullets hit their targets more reliably at longer ranges. Keep Away is still a good choice here since you'll get the buffs in a lot of situations, while Headseeker amps your precision damage. Desperado is also a useful choice, though it requires getting a kill where Headseeker doesn't.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guide: Vegeta Buu Saga]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-vegeta-buu-saga/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-vegeta-buu-saga.1007925/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-vegeta-buu-saga/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s Episode Battle is the talk of the town, thanks to all the new scenarios players are exploring with the branching storylines. If you are wondering how the mode works, check out this Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles to learn about all the branching paths for Vegeta in the Buu Saga.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before getting into Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s alternative endings, players must know that these are achieved by completing specific battle tasks. Some Alternative Paths also have Sparking! Episodes, which are original cutscenes created for the new moments. Additionally, players who complete the entire path are rewarded 100,000 Zeni, a bunch of XP and more items. This guide will take you through Vegeta’s alternate endings in the Buu saga and show you how to unlock them.</p>



<p><strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-vegeta-android-cell-saga/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guide: Vegeta Android/Cell Saga</a>&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-canon-story">Canon Story</h2>



<p>If you want to follow the canon Buu Saga story for Vegeta in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battle, then make the same decision as the characters did in the anime. In this scenario, the choice comes in the second battle, when Babidi decides to corrupt Vegeta. You are confronted with a unique option: Shake Off Brainwashing or Succumb to Brainwashing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you choose Succumb to Brainwashing, the canon storyline is triggered, and Vegeta will turn into Majin Vegeta, looking to battle Goku. The events will follow as they did in the anime.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-goku-buu-saga/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guide: Goku Buu Saga</a></p>



<h2 id="h-number-one-spot-nbsp">Number One Spot&nbsp;</h2>



<p>If you decide to shake it off, there is a new Sparking! Episode that plays as the Buu Saga branching path for Vegeta begins. Vegeta shakes off Babidi’s brainwashing with his Pride but still challenges Goku to a fight. However, Babidi quickly interferes, sending Dabura to battle Vegeta.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dabura is defeated, and now Babidi doesn’t have anyone to siphon energy from; hence, he can’t revive Majin Buu. Vegeta and the Z warriors take advantage of the situation and defeat Babidi to end his reign of terror.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the end, Buu’s container is destroyed, and Dabura is defeated, so whoever was turned to stone has returned to their normal state. And the Universe was saved by Vegeta’s sheer will.</p>



<p>But that’s not what Vegeta wants as he challenges Goku to battle. They end up duking it out at the World Tournament Stage and decide not to transform or use any ki blast as a live audience surrounds them. Vegeta wins by a ring out, but his win is short-lived as Goku showcases his Super Saiyan 3 transformation before leaving Earth, which meant Vegeta couldn’t defeat Goku at his best.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-goku-saiyan-saga/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guide: Goku Saiyan Saga</a></p>



<h2 id="h-a-strong-dad">A Strong Dad</h2>



<p>This is more of a new ending than an alternative path. To unlock the A Strong Dad path for Vegeta Dragon Ball Sparking Zero, players must beat Majin Buu when Majin Vegeta confronts the character after battling Goku. The match will be time-based, and you must quickly defeat Buu before Vegeta sacrifices himself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you manage to do so, the ‘A Strong Dad’ ending is triggered, and Vegeta gets powered up by the thought of his loved ones and defeats Majin Buu and Babidi. He also embraces Trunks and promises to take him to the Amusement Park.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-goku-android-cell-saga/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guide: Goku Android/Cell Saga</a></p>



<h2 id="h-saiyans-the-warrior-race-nbsp">Saiyans: The Warrior Race&nbsp;</h2>



<p>To unlock the Saiyans: The Warrior race ending, players must defeat Kid Buu when Goku and Vegeta are battling him in the Land of the Kais. You have to finish him before Goku intervenes, and a new cutscene will be unlocked.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the new scenario, Vegeta practically kills Kid Buu while Goku is on the sidelines. However, Kid Buu is still resilient, so Goku and Vegeta finish him with a dual beam attack. The balance on Earth is restored through the Namekian Dragon Balls; however, there’s something yet to be resolved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vegeta demands a last battle with Goku. Players now have to fight Goku at his best, Super Saiyan 3. Once you defeat him, Vegeta finally wins his victory over Goku and beats him at his best, becoming the strongest ever Saiyan Warrior.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-find-dragon-balls-in-dragon-ball-sparking-zero/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to Find Dragon Balls in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero</a></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="DRAGON BALL: Sparking! ZERO - Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Dfbu3CJS0uY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>If you are new to the game, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-attack-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Attack</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-movement-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Movement</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-defense-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Defense</a>&nbsp;guides. These are all the branching paths for the Buu Saga in Vegeta’s Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles. Which one was your favourite?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/888/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/guides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Guides Hub</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guide: Goku Buu Saga]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-goku-buu-saga/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-goku-buu-saga.1007916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-goku-buu-saga/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s Episode Battles is the latest game mode added by Bandai Namco to the iconic Budokai Tenkaichi series. Through this game mode, players can experience new storylines vastly different from what happens in the canon events. This Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles guide will explain all the branching storylines for Goku in the Buu Saga.</p>



<p>Players need to complete specific objectives during battle to unlock the branching paths. These alternative paths can sometimes be whole Episodes, and completing them will reward you with 100,000 Zeni, a bunch of XP and other items. This Sparking Zero guide will explore the alternative ending for Goku in the Buu Saga and how to unlock it.</p>



<p><strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-goku-saiyan-saga/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guide: Goku Saiyan Saga</a></p>



<h2 id="h-we-ll-meet-again-one-day">We’ll Meet Again One Day</h2>



<p>There is only one alternate ending for Goku in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s Buu Saga Episode Battles, We’ll Meet Again One Day.</p>



<p>After Vegeta sacrifices himself, Goku goes to confront Majin Buu. This is an iconic scene that many fans would remember, the first time Goku showcases his Super Saiyan 3 transformation. Defeat Buu quickly in this Battle to unlock the “We’ll Meet Again One Day” path. To unlock the ending, you must defeat Buu before the match ends.</p>



<p><strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-vegeta-android-cell-saga/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guide: Vegeta Android/Cell Saga</a></p>



<p>Once you complete this challenge, a new dialogue will play where Majin Buu turns against Babidi after the fun yet intense battle with Goku and kills him. Goku then proceeds to bring Buu to the good side, and he happily agrees in exchange for an endless supply of candies. Buu also becomes great playmates with Goten and Trunks. However, he never builds a relationship with Mr. Satan.</p>



<p>There’s also a conversation between Goku and King Kai, where Goku talks about how Buu can be a great warrior for the next generation. Goku also says that he hopes to fight Buu again someday.</p>



<p><strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guide-goku-android-cell-saga/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guide: Goku Android/Cell Saga</a></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="DRAGON BALL: Sparking! ZERO - Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Dfbu3CJS0uY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p><strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-find-dragon-balls-in-dragon-ball-sparking-zero/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to Find Dragon Balls in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero</a></p>



<p>If you are new to the game, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-attack-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Attack</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-movement-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Movement</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-defense-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Defense</a>&nbsp;guides. What are your thoughts on this alternate ending for Goku in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s Buu Saga Episode Battles? Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/888/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/guides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Guides Hub</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Will Soon Let Players Stream All Their Games, Not Just Those On Game Pass - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-will-soon-let-players-stream-all-their-games-not-just-those-on-game-pass-report/1100-6527140/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-will-soon-let-players-stream-all-their-games-not-just-those-on-game-pass-report.1007913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-will-soon-let-players-stream-all-their-games-not-just-those-on-game-pass-report/1100-6527140/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527140">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In 2020, Microsoft launched <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-cloud-gaming-is-coming-to-amazon-tvs/1100-6524554/" data-ref-id="1100-6524554">Xbox Cloud Gaming</a> and allowed players to stream titles from the Xbox Game Pass library. But not every game was available on Game Pass, which put limits on which titles could be accessed. Now, Microsoft is reportedly planning to expand its streaming offerings to include games that aren't a part of Xbox Game Pass, as long as they're owned by the players themselves.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/11/24268038/xbox-cloud-gaming-project-lapland-game-library" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Verge</a>, Microsoft is planning to begin testing this new option on the Xbox Cloud Gaming servers with Xbox Insiders as soon as next month. The report notes that Microsoft has been building towards this moment for some time by upgrading the capabilities of Xbox Cloud Gaming to handle thousands of games. But the company has to be sure that those expanded capabilities will hold up under pressure before rolling them out to Game Pass subscribers.</p><p>Earlier this week, Xbox confirmed that as of November, players will be able buy or play Xbox games on Android via the Xbox app. And once the new streaming option becomes available, purchases on Android will immediately be available to stream no matter which devices players are using. As part of Epic Games' lawsuit win over Google, Microsoft will be able to sidestep Google Play and avoid giving the company a cut of its sales.</p><p>Additionally, Microsoft is still planning to build its own Xbox mobile store app. That will initially focus on deals and in-game items before eventually including Microsoft's first-party games.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Join Us In Appreciating Metaphor: ReFantazio’s Menu Screens]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/metaphor-refantazio-menu-screen-art</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/join-us-in-appreciating-metaphor-refantazio%E2%80%99s-menu-screens.1007904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/metaphor-refantazio-menu-screen-art<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The fact <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> has some of video gaming's most beautiful menu screens shouldn't be a <em>huge </em>surprise; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VqJnmphV9R8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">these are the <em>Persona</em> guys</a>, after all. But still...I don't think even I was quite prepared for just <em>how </em>beautiful the game's menu screens are.</p><p>Just look at this! These are <em>menus</em>.</p><figure></figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><figure></figure><p>Or, if you'd like to see them in motion--and they move just as nice as they look in screenshots--here you go:</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Metaphor ReFantazio Main Menu" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zmBr8ghQei4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Thank you for joining me on this episode of <em>Beautiful Menu Screens</em>, I hope to see you all again soon. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>