<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:28:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2: Renegades Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/05/destiny-renegades-review/</link>
            <guid>1374595</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Bungie have taken a step in to unknown for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/destiny-2">Destiny 2</a>: Renegades, their first expansion that’s based on an existing IP, and it’s a pretty big one. You might have had a bad feeling about this, but whether you knew the odds or not, you will be pleasantly surprised to hear that this Destiny 2 <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/star-wars">Star Wars</a> crossover is a gamble that has mostly paid off.</p>
<p><iframe title="Destiny 2: Renegades | Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PqicEwg2qEc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The idea with Destiny 2: Renegades is to take elements and themes from Star Wars and feed them into the Destiny universe. You won’t be running into Luke Skywalker, but you will hear music cues and imagery that refers to, rather than directly lifts from, Star Wars. This sounds like a bit of a mess until you step back and think just how much of Destiny, and indeed many other sci-fi shows, have been influenced by the George Lucas tale. The most obvious comparison is Spider,&nbsp; the gruff underworld criminal with a huge bulbous body sat on a throne, who is clearly inspired by Jabba the Hutt and takes that exact role in Renegades.</p>


<p>Then there’s Drifter, who has always been a wisecracking rebel working with but slightly outside the Vanguard – basically Han Solo – and Destiny as a whole has already explored the Light and Dark sides and given everyone Jedi-like powers. All this means that any additional Star Wars themes can slot in with ease rather than be honkingly obvious.&nbsp; It also helps that Destiny already has three worlds that are shoe-ins for those found in Star Wars. Mars stands in for the desert planet Tatooine, Io is the swampy Dagobah, and the frozen wastes of Europa are perfect for Hoth.</p>


<p>There are two new characters, the rather bland Aunor from the Praxic order – aka Jedis – and Bael, who couldn’t be more Kylo Ren if he tried, I honestly thought Adam Driver had been booked to do the voice work.</p>
<p>Renegades has two intertwined stories, the first of which finds you working for three splinter factions from existing Destiny races who have all set up home in a Cantina on Mars. This is genuinely fun and gives the game plenty of opportunity for some much-needed humour; The Vex have split from the Hive mind and gained individuality, which has manifested in them becoming obsessed with fashion, and capes in particular.</p>

<p>Each of the factions will give you bounty hunts, which take you to one of the three locations, where you have to perform a series of tasks whilst being hammered from all sides by an impressive number of enemies. It is mostly shooting, but that’s what Destiny is particularly good at, and as each location is large and features a good range of tasks, it never feels boring. Bungie have clearly been playing Hellidvers, as prep for each mission by going to your hangar and loading up with Strategems… I mean <em>abilities</em>. These are bonus powers that you can use while out in the field and include air strikes, vehicles, and healing drones, and they are very useful at giving you a few seconds of breathing space when cornered. The core Destiny gameplay remains the same and is as good as ever, and it’s really nice to have new expansive areas to explore.</p>
<p>The campaign lasts around eight hours on normal, longer on Legend difficulty and is bookended with two spectacular missions that are a joy to play and really channel the Star Wars vibe. After that you can start running bounty hunts for the various factions, but it remains to be seen if this going to become repetitive or Bungie are going to continue to mix things up.</p>

<p>I think the decision to allow players to complete the expansion in one sitting, rather than spreading out the missions over eight weeks has been detrimental to the game. When the Heresy expansion was live, Tuesday night was Destiny night. Everyone used to log in, do the mission, uncover some new areas or lord, and because your friends were online at the same time you could then team up for a Nightfall or a Raid. These days everyone does the campaign with a day or two of release and there’s quickly little need for everyone to check in the following weeks. The social aspect of the game have completely died off for me. Playing it all in one go also rushes the story beats, characters motives flip in moments, there’s no time to for things to settle and for the player to consider the most recent developments.</p>
<p>There are some new Star Wars inspired weapons, a set based on Han Solo’s blaster and Praxis blades – the Destiny take on Lightsabers. The blades are a lot of fun and you can perform all the classic Jedi moves with them, accompanied the by unmistakable vwooom sound effects. You can also dress up as Boba Fett, but that will cost you extra money.</p>

<p>Aside from the Star Wars campaign, the other plot continues the story of The Nine that began in The Edge of Fate, an expansion I did not play. Even though I had just missed one DLC, I had absolutely no idea what was going on. There’s talk of numbers and innies and outies and it all went over my head – they could have been chatting about Severance or belly buttons for all I know. There is a catch up movie at the start of the expansion, but it doesn’t explain half of what you would need to actually catch up and follow the plot.</p>
<p>Complaining that the story in a game over ten years old is incomprehensible does seem imprudent and with any other Destiny DLC I would agree, but The Edge of Fate was intended to kick off a new story arc, which should have been a bit of a reset, and Renegades has clearly marketed at Star Wars fans who may have not played Destiny before. If they had opened the game with a classic Star Wars text crawl explaining previous events that would have been perfect, but this is going to be as impenetrable to newcomers as usual for Destiny.</p>
<p>Taking of The Edge of Fate, while I didn’t play this at its launch, buying Renegades seems to have handed me access to The Edge of Fate as well.&nbsp;Whether intentional or a bug, I gave it a go. This has actually been my first time back in Destiny 2 since it was revamped and restructured around the Portal – the&nbsp;new way of delivering content used to grind for power and weapons.</p>
<p>I hate it. I absolutely hate it.</p>
<p>Destiny is a shooter RPG, and what used to happen is that to get to mission you got in your ship, flew to planet, pottered about on the surface and met some random Guardians. Maybe you’d join in a local event, find a secret area, and only then would you continue on to your mission marker to get to what you wanted to do. That has all gone, there’s no world building, there’s no random encounters, it’s just a list of tasks picked from a screen and it feels like work. It’s like someone has made a Kanban board of Destiny 2 stuff and then assigned it to you. I want to play video games to forget about my day job, not be reminded by it.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/05/destiny-renegades-review/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Necromunda Spire of Primus Review - The Divine Prince Arrives]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/necromunda-spire-of-primus-review-divine-prince-arrives</link>
            <guid>1374592</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Necromunda</em> is at war. The lines have been drawn, and everyone has to pick a side, or it will be picked for you. The next narrative campaign book for <em>Necromunda</em> has landed, and along with it, the golden-armoured Ozostium Aranthus himself. In this article, we take a look at <em>Necromunda</em>: The Aranthian Succession - Spire of Primus, Ozostium Aranthus, and the Palatine Jusicars.</p><p>We've covered <em>Necromunda</em> for a while on the site, and you can read our review of the most recent boxed set release, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/necromunda-hive-secundus-review" rel="nofollow">Hive Secundus</a>.</p><p><em>Necromunda</em> is a skirmish game set in Games Workshop's <em>Warhammer 40,000</em> universe. But rather than being about massive armies of capable warriors battling throughout the galaxy, <em>Necromunda</em> focuses on the inhabitants of the planet of Necromunda, most of whom are low-level gangers who inhabit the sprawling hive world.&nbsp;<em>Necromunda</em>&nbsp;is a campaign game, where each player creates a gang that gathers equipment and develops in skill as the campaign progresses.&nbsp;</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/necromunda-spire-of-primus-2.jpg?itok=v6SOVSct 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/necromunda-spire-of-primus-2.jpg?itok=Cl-_NXCn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><h2>The Aranthian Succession: Spire of Primus</h2><p>While the lower hives of Necromunda are filled with gangs and low-lifes, as you ascend the spires, a higher quality of inhabitant emerges, and with it, the conflict that always follows when there can only be one ruler.</p><p>One of the many fallen houses of Necromunda, defeated by House Helmawr, who have ruled Necromunda for centuries, was&nbsp;House Aranthus, thought all killed by a plague centuries ago. But now, emerging from an imprisonment in a casket,&nbsp;Ozostium Aranthus has risen, clad in a suit of golden armor and gathering supporters across Necromunda, throwing the planet into war.</p><p>Spire of Primus is the 4th book in the&nbsp;Aranthian Succession series of campaign books for <em>Necromunda</em>. It includes new background and lore for the ongoing narrative, and Part 4 of the Succession Campaign, which can be played with new gangs or continued from those in Part 3 of the&nbsp;Ruins of Jardlan book. Gangs in this campaign must choose between the Imperial House or House Aranthus, gaining benefits depending on which house they choose, and the chance for a major supporting character to fight for their gang in each battle.</p><p>Spire of Primus includes the rules and details for running the campaign, along with scenarios, which can be played normally or tweaked with directed force compositions to match the narrative in the book. The scenarios progress to a final multiplayer game, featuring all the gangs in the campaign, and includes all the major characters vying for power in a final standoff to decide the fate of Necromunda's ruling family. The book also contains rules for&nbsp;Ozostium Aranthus and the Palatine Justicars, which we discuss below, and the powerful Sthenian Spyre Hunter, Indentured Psykers, Hive Watchers, and Rogue Docs.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/necromunda-spire-of-primus-3.jpg?itok=VSuKrz7n 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="791">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/necromunda-spire-of-primus-3.jpg?itok=1-7TRBiE 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="494">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Ozostium Aranthus in his golden splendour that covers the rot beneath.</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>Ozostium Aranthus</h2><p>Ozostium Aranthus, the Divine Prince. This golden-armed figure stands above those who would oppose him. Ozostium won't just work for any gang, and only Aranthian-aligned gangs can roll on the petition table. His hire fee increases for those whose rep is too high, to the point where he thinks that you don't even need his help.</p><p>If Ozostium decides to help your gang, he arrives in all his splendor, with his Aranthian Beauty Plating that gives him a 4+ field armor save, and reflex enhancers to give him 2 actions per turn. He also has an Archaic Displacer, which can move him either 6, 12, or anywhere on the battlefield at the start of the turn on a random roll. His Bifurcated Blade is the length of a normal ganger, so long that it has a 2-inch range, along with -2 AP and damage 2. Ozostium is also an unsanctioned psyker and has the Divine Scorth Wyrd Power with a strength 2 template attack to keep the unwashed masses at bay.</p><p>Ozostium is always accompanied by a Caryatid-Servitor, a cherub mokery of a reanimated corpse that brings misfortune to those who target its master. Whenever Ozostium or the Caryatid are targeted by an attack, there's a chance the attacker's weapon will run out of ammo after the attack, and enemy fighters ending a move within 3 inches of have to take a nerve test.</p><p>Ozostium's miniature has a couple of build options, and you can leave off his mask and/or body plate to show the decaying corpse underneath.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/necromunda-spire-of-primus-4.jpg?itok=puijqwSU 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/necromunda-spire-of-primus-4.jpg?itok=KOxsx7F_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Palanite Justicars, literal Judge, Jury and an Executioner.</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>Palanite Justicars</h2><p>The Palanite Justicar Delegation is a mobile judge, jury, and executioner team that hunts down renegade nobles. Loyal to the Imperial House, their use is directed by the campaign scenarios in the Spire of Primus book when using the force selection rules to match the narrative campaign or the alliance rules and choosing the Justicar Court.</p><p>The delegation is made up of a Magistrate, armed with a bolt pistol and Pronouncement gavel hammer, an Executioner, armed with an executioner's axe and stub gun, and 3 bailiffs, who can be armed with a shock pistol and heavy club, shotgun, or man-catcher. The box has 2 man-catchers, 2 shotguns, and 2 heavy clubs/shock pistols, so you can't arm all 3 the same, but you can double up on a weapon that suits your needs.</p><p>The Magistrate and Executioner have group activation 2 and 1, respectively. So you can activate the entire delegation with 2 actions. You can't chain these activations, using the Magistrate to activate the Executioner to then group activate a bailiff wouldn't work, but it's still super handy for overwhelming your opponent's force.</p><h2>Necromunda Spire of Primus Final Thoughts?</h2><p><em>Necromunda</em> Spire of Primus is a great narrative and works fantastically for the setup of the linked campaign, and a conclusion to this story arc that has been building up for a few years. The final multiplayer face-off between Ozostium and Lady Haera is the perfect way to end it. Ozostium is a fantastic miniature, and a beast on the tabletop, and the new Palanite Justicars ooze with incredible thematic details.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>The copies of</em> <strong>Necromunda Spire of Primus,&nbsp;Ozostium Aranthus, and the Palanite Justicars&nbsp;</strong><em>used to produce this review were provided by Games Workshop.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/necromunda-spire-of-primus-review-divine-prince-arrives]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bushido Bai Qian Themed Warband Review - For The Emperor!]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/bushido-bai-qian-themed-warband-review-for-emperor</link>
            <guid>1374586</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Golden Empire from across the sea has always had envoys and diplomats in the Jwar Isles, but now the Empire has arrived in force, and the synchronized steps of their stone warriors herald their arrival. In this article, we take a look at the new Bai Qian themed warband box and the new Imperial Court faction for <em>Bushido</em>.</p><p>We've been covering <em>Bushido&nbsp;</em>for years, so if you'd like to learn more about the game, check out <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/guides/bushido-risen-sun-guide" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">our guide to <em>Bushido Risen Sun</em></a>, our <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/bushido-two-player-starter-set-review" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">review of the <em>Bushido Risen Sun</em>&nbsp;2-player starter set</a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/start-collecting-bushido-risen-sun-part-1-introduction-and-developer-interview" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">our "Start Collecting" guide to <em>Bushido</em></a>, which includes an interview with the game's developer.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/Inari%27s%20Judgement%20%281%29.jpg?itok=y3R3ZXoC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="800" height="315">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/Inari%27s%20Judgement%20%281%29.jpg?itok=jJ7Ps-DX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="800" height="315">
                  

  </picture><h2>Thematically Themed</h2><p>When selecting a warband in <em>Bushido</em>, you must first choose a faction from the now 14 available to select your fighters from. Each faction also has access to theme cards, which offer special abilities but restrict the units that can be included in the warband. The Imperial Court is a new faction for <em>Bushido</em>, and The Eternal Legion is a theme card that restricts you to Imperial and Ronin Imperial, and must include 1 Warden model for 1 or 2 Fangshi models, and 2 Wardens for 3 or more Fangshi models (we discuss why below), but gives them some incredible benefits that play into their theme.</p><p>Using the theme, Bai Qian, the stone warriors, gain Fear (5) and don't suffer the -1 in melee for taking the run action. Fangshi models who power the Bai Qian can focus to gain additional Ki for 1 activation counter rather than 2. In the first turn of the game, because of the Darkness special rule, models may only draw line of sight up to 4 inches (unless they're bakemono, soulless, or have sixth sense).</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bushido-bai-qian-4.jpg?itok=a_040Kaj 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bushido-bai-qian-4.jpg?itok=sxvhmjMR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>The Eternal Legion theme for the Imperial Court faction adds some much needed speed to your Bai Qian models.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>There have been a few Imperial Ronin models and the Ronin Imperial March theme in <em>Bushido</em> for a while, but this is the first time they've had their own dedicated faction.</p><p>The Eternal Legion is an exciting theme, with the bulk of the force made up of Bai Qian stone warriors (based on the Terracotta Army), and the Fangshi handlers who have the power to animate them. Watching over them all are the Wardens, who are empowered to stop the Fangshi from falling into enemy hands and revealing their secrets, usually through permanent means.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bushido-bai-qian-2.jpg?itok=nmoreo4s 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="967">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bushido-bai-qian-2.jpg?itok=X7oDPxEh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="604">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>The Bai Qian warband are made up of 6 Bai Qian stone warriors, 2 Fangshi handlers, and 1 Warden, to handle the handlers.</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>Stoic Resilience</h2><p>The Bai Qian themed warband box, under the Eternal Legion theme, contains 9 models. These are:</p><ul><li>Chen Lu - The box's&nbsp;Warden, in charge of protecting the Fangshi. Lu is a great fighter and can switch the target to herself with her Intercept ki feat, preventing&nbsp;the enemy from charging her wards. She has to be within 3 inches of a friendly Fanghsi to generate ki. If she's within 6 inches of a friendly Fangshi model, who is in base-to-base contact with an enemy model during the end phase, she removes the Fangshi model, and you gain a scenario point, as she stops them from falling into enemy hands.</li><li>Zuo Ci - Ci is 1 of the 2 Fangshi models in the warband. Ci can&nbsp;channel ki into the Bai Qian, and is also quite adept at smashing enemies with his ruined earth sword, which is +3 damage and adds 3 to the final attack score when allocating dice to attack. Ci can also, once per game, return a removed Shibing or Rui Jin to the battlefield.&nbsp;If Ci channels into a Bai Qian, they allow that model to also use the ki feats on their own card.</li><li>Zi Xu - Xu is the second Fangshi in the warband, and where Ci smashes opponents, Xu instead&nbsp;has a +3 damage weapon, but with Dodge 3, which allows them to make their opponent reroll up to 3&nbsp;attack dice. Their Mirage ki feat also lets them move after being targeted by an attack, wasting your opponent's action. As with Ci, if Xu&nbsp;channels into a Bai Qian, they allow that model to also use the ki feats on their own card.</li><li>Bai Qian - both types of Bai Qian below have similar rules. They gain&nbsp;one activation each round and turn into a destructible terrain element when exhausted (destructible elements can't be attacked directly, but can be removed by a model in base-to-base contact and not in an enemy zone of control, by taking a wait action). All 3 models on each profile can also operate as a group, all moving or attacking in the same activation.<ul><li>3x Shibing - The Shibing are melee-based, and all armed with +2&nbsp;damage yari's with reach. Their group activation means that if you can get them into combat, they can easily overwhelm an enemy.</li><li>3x Rui Jin - The Rui Jin are the long-distance version of the Bai Qian, armed with a range 12, +1 damage repeating crossbow. Their group activation means they can level 3 shots on a single target, or spread their fire.</li></ul></li></ul><p>The Eternal Legion theme requires a lot of strategy to use. The positioning of your forces is key. Chen Lu only generates ki if she's nearby Fangshi models, but if a Fangshi model ends a turn in base-to-base contact with an enemy, Lu will remove the from play.</p><p>The Fangshi also need to be close to the Bai Qian. The Bai Qian don't generate ki themselves, and after taking their activation, are in a dangerous position that a wait action could remove them. They do have an instant ki feat that you can use as the active player at a 1 ki cost to give them an activation counter and stop them from being terrain. They can use that ki to generate an activation on their turn, but you have to manage it to make sure they have enough to protect them from being taken out by a wait action.</p><figure role="group">
<picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bushido-bai-qian-3.jpg?itok=ySaDnYCf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1104">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bushido-bai-qian-3.jpg?itok=HVSpeBHJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="690">
                  

  </picture>
<figcaption>Like your Bai Qain thicc? Then upgrade to the&nbsp;Bu Dong.</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>Expanding The Empire</h2><p>While several Imperial Court Ronin models have been available for a while, the best addition to the Eternal Legion theme is currently the Bu Dong. These Bai Quin come in a pair, rather than a trio, have a lot more wounds, and come armed with a +2 strength Polearm with Pierce to help get through enemy armor.</p><p>They operate the same as the other Bai Qian, but have the option to gain the group trait during the starting phase. So if you want to smash into an opponent, you can choose to give them group, but if you want the additional separate activation, which is helpful sometimes to make sure you still get active player turns to stop your opponent taking out your Bai Qian terrain with a wait action, you can choose to activate them separately.</p><p>Their combined points are the same as the other 2 groups of Bai Qian, so they're a clean swap into a 100-rice warband out of the Bai Qian themed warband.</p><h2>What Are Our Final Thoughts On The Bai Qian Themed Warband?</h2><p>The Bai Qian themed warband continues the recent trend of incredible design from GCT Studios. The recent wave of faction starter sets and themed warbands has been inspired, and this is no different. Perfectly capturing thematically and mechanically the nature of how you'd imagine a group of stone statue warriors go to war, this set offers a great challenge (for you and your opponent) and adds an entirely new element to an already great wargame filled with interesting factions and warband themes.</p><hr><p>The copy of&nbsp;<strong>Bushido Bai Qian</strong>&nbsp;<em>used to produce this review was provided by GCT Studios.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/bushido-bai-qian-themed-warband-review-for-emperor]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout co-creator Tim Cain's rejoined Obsidian full-time to work on a mystery game, but plans to keep his YouTube chats going]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-co-creator-tim-cains-rejoined-obsidian-full-time-to-work-on-a-mystery-game-but-plans-to-keep-his-youtube-chats-going</link>
            <guid>1374583</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Also, here's a clip of him feeding a squirrel a walnut</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-creator-tim-cain-back-full-time-obsidian-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-creator-tim-cain-back-full-time-obsidian-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-creator-tim-cain-back-full-time-obsidian-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-creator-tim-cain-back-full-time-obsidian-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-creator-tim-cain-back-full-time-obsidian-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-creator-tim-cain-back-full-time-obsidian-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-creator-tim-cain-back-full-time-obsidian-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-creator-tim-cain-back-full-time-obsidian-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-creator-tim-cain-back-full-time-obsidian-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Tim Cain</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>He's back. Tim Cain, co-creator of the original Interplay <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout">Fallouts</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines">Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines</a> programmer has emerged from semi-retirement, returning to Obsidian to work on a game he can't talk about yet because legal documents. For the past few years, the veteran developer's been contracting on a number of games, including Obsidian's own <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-outer-worlds-2">The Outer Worlds 2</a>, having previously co-directed the first <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-outer-worlds">Outer Worlds</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kCVWRZqyroA">
</a>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kCVWRZqyroA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>

<p>"I’m back at Obsidian," Cain announced in the latest video posted to his YouTube channel where he talks about many things. "I’m there as a full-time employee and in-person, so not remote. I’m not a contractor anymore. So, this means that I’m not working at other places, although there’s at least one game that I worked on [in that capacity for another studio] that I know is going to ship."</p>
<p>Sensing the speculation swarm buzzing at his door, Cain swiftly said: "I can’t talk about the project that I’m working on at Obsidian, just because that’s covered by NDA. Don’t bother guessing, you’re not going to guess right. I would say that I’m probably a lot less retired now." Damn you, No Don't Ask paperwork.</p>
<p>Despite having a new gig, the veteran developer doesn't currently have any plans to stop posting to his YouTube channel, which he started to discuss stories from his career after being told a written memoir he penned was a bit boring.</p><p>"No one in Obsidian has even remotely suggested that I have to stop it," Cain explained. "In fact, many of my co-workers have said that they watch this channel. And I know they did because they started telling me which videos were their favorite or what stories I said that they thought were funny. So, people are saying that they like it. I'm going to keep doing it as long as I have stories to tell. As long as you have questions that are really good and that I think need a video to answer and that I can answer."</p>
<p>Good news, especially given a section of this particular video includes a clip of Cain feeding a squirrel a walnut, which he says is basically a tax he now has to pay whenever he leaves the place he's recently moved into.</p>
<p>Now, we just have to wait and see what this mystery game the studio who put out both The Outer Worlds 2 and its quirky mushroom sibling <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/avowed">Avowed</a> this year have brought the original Falloutman back for.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-co-creator-tim-cains-rejoined-obsidian-full-time-to-work-on-a-mystery-game-but-plans-to-keep-his-youtube-chats-going]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dyson’s No-Profit Play on Its Heater and Fan Combo Is Still Active to Offload Stock Even After Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dysons-no-profit-play-on-its-heater-and-fan-combo-is-still-active-to-offload-stock-even-after-black-friday-2000650900</link>
            <guid>1374574</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I love winter, but I am definitely the complaining type. Anything below 15 degrees is a bit too cold for me, and the same is the case during summer; above 30°C is basically the boiling point. If you can relate and are looking for a year-round solution that offers both focused and diffused modes, the Dyson Hot plus Cool AM09 Jet Focus heater and fan is an excellent option to consider, especially at its current price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4614/">Right now, you can pick it up for just $350 at Amazon, after the retailer took a whopping $150 off its usual price</a>. It’s a post Black Friday deal that made it through the main event, but it won’t be around forever. It won’t be long before the price shoots back up, so it’s best to get your orders in quickly.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4614/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Uninterrupted Airflow</h2>
<p>It’s Dyson, so as you’d expect, the overall design is quite minimal. The solid base makes it easy to place it just about anywhere, from the middle of the lounge to a corner of your room. Year-round comfort is made possible with its dual capabilities; cools you in summer and warms you up when things start to get chilly.</p>
<p>The fan uses an Air Multiplier technology that amplifies the surrounding air to give you a smooth, uninterrupted airflow. There are two operating modes to choose from. The Focused mode delivers fast, personal heating or cooling, while the Diffused mode gently adjusts the temperature of your entire room. Speaking of temperature, you can adjust it anywhere from 32 to 98.6°F. For instance, in winters, if you’ve just come home after spending time with friends on a chilly evening, go for the focused mode to relax your body a bit, and then switch to the Diffused mode to warm the entire room up. The ceramic plates heat up fast, so you won’t have to wait too long for the thing to work, either. When using the diffused mode, the fan oscillates at a 70° angle to direct airflow around the room evenly.</p>



<p>It also works fairly quietly, which is great if you want to take a nap with it running. What’s more, you can create sleep timers to program the fan to turn off after pre-set intervals. These can range anywhere from 15 minutes to 9 hours​. The included remote makes it easy to do this and more. You can adjust the temperature, switch modes, create schedules, etc. It’s also magnetized, so you can store it neatly on the fan itself and never lose track of it.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4614/">This deal brings the price of this smart, multifunctional fan to just $350, saving you $150 on your purchase.</a> It can be used in both summer and winter, doesn’t make an annoying sound while working, and even lets you set timers for added convenience. The Silver finish gives off a premium look, so it can blend into any setup with ease. And since the fan isn’t cordless, you don’t have to worry about running out of power when you need it the most. Just plug it into an outlet, and enjoy an uninterrupted stream of airflow for hours. Again, the retailer has listed it as a limited-time discount, so we don’t expect it to last long. In fact, it might not even make it through the weekend. If you’ve been after a unit that works as both a heater and a fan, now is the time to make the move.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4614/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dysons-no-profit-play-on-its-heater-and-fan-combo-is-still-active-to-offload-stock-even-after-black-friday-2000650900]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 5’s Michael is Coming Back After 12 Years, And He Has Aged]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-michael-coming-back-aged/</link>
            <guid>1374571</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Grand Theft Auto 5 dropped twelve years ago, and it’s still one of the best-selling games around. That’s because of GTA Online, the multiplayer component to GTA 5 that has proven to be a live-service cash cow for more than a decade. It’s what keeps the beating heart of GTA still pumping today.</p>



<p>Recently, it was revealed by Rockstar Games that Michael de Santa, played by Ned Luke, is <strong>finally coming back </strong>to GTA via a new update – GTA Online: A Safehouse in the Hills. The timeline has moved forward, though, and he has noticeably aged.</p>



<h2 id="h-michael-is-back-in-gta-online">Michael is Back in GTA Online</h2>



<p>In a post on social media, Rockstar Games revealed that Michael de Santa is headed back to GTA Online in the next major update, which gives players the opportunity to purchase a staggering mansion in the hills of Los Santos:</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Prime luxury real estate for those who've reached the highest rungs of the criminal ladder arrives on Dec 10 in GTA Online: A Safehouse in the Hills.</p><p>The monumental update also features a new action-packed adventure, new vehicles to collect and much more: <a href="https://t.co/xGottYirhm">https://t.co/xGottYirhm</a> <a href="https://t.co/cCsNpe25AW">pic.twitter.com/cCsNpe25AW</a></p></div>— Rockstar Games (@RockstarGames) <a href="https://twitter.com/RockstarGames/status/1996956990141075837?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 5, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>







<p>While other expansions have been backed by other characters, such as Lemar, Lester, or Martin Madrazo, this is the first time that a Michael de Santa has fronted an update. When GTA Online came out, characters like Trevor Philips (Steven Ogg) had smaller roles, and Franklin (with Chop) resurfaced a while ago, but Ned Luke is back in the booth for Michael de Santa for the first time in almost 15 years.</p>



<p>Ned Luke responded to the post with an excited sentiment:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Fans of Grand Theft Auto were constantly shocked by Rockstar Games’ apparent reluctance to expand GTA 5 with any kind of expansions, even though we know they were in the works, but later cancelled. This is how we get to revisit those characters after all these years, it seems.</p>



<p>Are you going to jump back into GTA Online to see Michael de Santa again? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-ending-shocking-realizatio/">Tarkov’s ending has a shocking twist</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-michael-coming-back-aged/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov Player Makes Shocking Realization About Game’s Ending]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-ending-shocking-realizatio/</link>
            <guid>1374568</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Escape from Tarkov now has an <strong>ending</strong>. You read that right; there’s now a way to finally escape from Tarkov and deliver on everything promised in the game over the last ten years of development. This is a new element in the game as of November 15, and with the arrival of 1.0, there’s a new campaign that players can ultimately complete to get the hell out of dodge.</p>



<p>It was only earlier this week that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/someone-finally-escaped-from-tarkov/">first person in the world</a> managed to complete Escape from Tarkov, and since then, others have popped up. In a shocking social realization, some players have found out that Battlestate Games has played a sick and twisted game that has, until now, been kept a complete secret.</p>



<h2 id="h-don-t-go-with-a-full-team">Don’t Go With a Full Team</h2>



<p>On social media, Axel, a popular Escape from Tarkov creator, posted an image showing what happens when you push through Escape from Tarkov’s final mission with <strong>a full squad</strong>. After you’ve all valiantly fought your way through Terminal, you’re presented with a drastic, horrifying message:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The Zubr boat cannot take everyone. The evacuation will begin only when there are 3 people left on the pier.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This means that, if you have four or five players, <strong>someone has to die</strong>. Given that this is Escape from Tarkov, it costs absolutely nothing to turn around and drop the man standing next to you, but who decides who lives and who succumbs right at the very end of the game?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s truly representative of how sadistic Battlestate Games can be with this spearhead extraction shooter title that has often been dubbed the most challenging game ever made.</p>



<p>Fans of Escape from Tarkov commented on Axel’s post, and many of them immediately understood the drill. It’s a kill-or-be-killed world out there, and if you want to get that ultimate achievement for escaping from Tarkov, you’ll need to eliminate one of your buddies, potentially fracturing a friendship.</p>



<p>Have you managed to get to the end of Escape from Tarkov yet? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> what ending you managed to get.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tim-cain-returns-to-obsidian-for-new-project/">Tim Cain is back at Obsidian</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-ending-shocking-realizatio/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Online Update Reveals First Look at Michael in the Grand Theft Auto Universe Since GTA 5 Launched Back in 2013 — and Settles Any Lingering Canon E]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-online-update-reveals-first-look-at-michael-in-the-grand-theft-auto-universe-since-gta-5-launched-back-in-2013-and-settles-any-lingering-canon-ending-questions</link>
            <guid>1374565</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">GTA fans finally have their first look at Grand Theft Auto 5 character Michael in the Grand Theft Auto universe since the game launched back in 2013.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We can see Michael in the trailer for GTA Online DLC A Safehouse in the Hills, below. In the teaser for the upcoming expansion, which adds a luxurious new home for the most successful of online criminals to the online mode, a noticeably older, greying, Michael De Santa and his wife Amanda can be seen greeting a player at the front door of their fancy new Hollywood Hills crib. This is the first time that Michael, played by Ned Luke, has been seen in the Grand Theft Auto universe since GTA 5 launched back in 2013.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The update also settles any lingering questions around the canon ending for GTA 5, confirming once and for all that Option C, otherwise known as “Deathwish”, is how the story <em>should </em>end. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It now means that all three playable protagonists, with Franklin and Trevor being the other two, have appeared in GTA Online. Naturally, this means the “Deathwish” ending is now canon in Online’s version of Los Santos, as this is the only way that all three characters remain alive at the end of GTA 5’s final mission “The Third Way” — one of three possible last levels available depending on the player’s choice. For reference, “Something Sensible” is Option A, which leaves both Franklin and Michael alive, but kills Trevor, and “The Time’s Come” is Option B, resulting in Franklin and Trevor’s survival, but Michael’s death.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In all three possible endings, Franklin lives to walk the streets of Los Santos, so it always felt natural that he’d be a part of GTA Online, which takes place after the events of Grand Theft Auto 5. Trevor has also been present since 2013, giving the online protagonist missions and calling to berate them over the phone in his own peculiar manner, but this is the first time we’ve seen Michael’s face since.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eagle-eared online players would’ve heard a small reference to the professional bank robber back in 2021, though, which, although it definitely alludes to Michael, didn’t 100% confirm he was still around. This occurs when Franklin is chasing two golfers through the Richards Majestic Studios film lot in the centre of the city. This is one of the places Michael works in order to achieve his Hollywood movie-producing dreams in the main game’s campaign. Franklin remarks, “I know one of the producers around here. I hope his ass ain’t work today…”, suggesting De Santa is still employed there after all this time.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every Celebrity in GTA 5 and GTA Online</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It is curious that Rockstar has chosen to put Michael back into the world of GTA so many years after we saw him last, and it does beg the question of how long this was planned for, seeing as this update has dropped so close to GTA 6’s previous release date of November 19, 2025. Is this the Grand Theft Auto and Red Dead Redemption developer saying their final goodbye to these characters before gearing up to unleash Lucia and Jason into the world in 2026?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">How do you feel about the “Deathwish” ending being chosen by Rockstar as the canonical one for GTA 5? Let us know in the comments below. And, of course, for everything GTA 6, stick with IGN.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-online-update-reveals-first-look-at-michael-in-the-grand-theft-auto-universe-since-gta-5-launched-back-in-2013-and-settles-any-lingering-canon-ending-questions]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Don't Bother Guessing. You're Not Going to Guess Right' — Tim Cain, One of the Creators of the Original Fallout, Has Rejoined Xbox Studio Obsidian to]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dont-bother-guessing-youre-not-going-to-guess-right-tim-cain-one-of-the-creators-of-the-original-fallout-has-rejoined-xbox-studio-obsidian-to-work-on-a-mystery-project</link>
            <guid>1374559</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Tim Cain, one of the creators of the original Fallout video game, has rejoined Xbox studio Obsidian Entertainment to work on a mystery project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In <a href="https://youtu.be/kCVWRZqyroA?si=8o176t6ChiiXY_eM" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a video published on his YouTube channel</a> (which he's used to tell <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-creator-reveals-lore-the-original-team-decided-was-true-but-never-explained-bethesda-is-free-to-invent-different-reasons-that-the-things-in-the-game-exist">a lot of fun stories about the making of the first Fallout game</a>), Cain said he was now a full-time member of staff at Obsidian, last seen releasing The Outer Worlds 2, Grounded 2, and Avowed. This means he’s not a contractor anymore, and so is not working at other studios, although there is a game set to come out at some point in the future that will have his name on it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Cain wouldn’t say anything about the project he’s joined Obsidian to work on, and told fans not to even bother guessing what it is.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN Fallout Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“I also can’t talk about the project I’m working on at Obsidian, just because that’s covered under NDA,” he said. “Don’t bother guessing. You’re not going to guess right. I would say that I’m probably a lot less retired now than I was before, so that whole video I have on being semi-retired, I guess I’m not.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Cain last worked at Obsidian as a full-time employee on Pillars of Eternity and The Outer Worlds. He then moved to being a contractor, contributing to The Outer Worlds 2. Obsidian has yet to announce its next project. Last month, Obsidian developers said they were well aware that whenever the studio announces a new game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/obsidian-knows-whenever-it-announces-a-new-game-everyone-asks-about-fallout-new-vegas-2-but-it-loves-making-original-ip-and-sequels-to-them">people ask where Fallout: New Vegas 2 is</a>, but they also love how they’ve been able to create new IP and even release sequels to them.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fallout Season 2 is set to hit Prime Video this December, and while Bethesda has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-announced-on-fallout-day-here-are-the-contents"><u>a new Fallout: New Vegas bundle</u></a> up its sleeve, there’s no word yet on a Fallout remaster or a Fallout: New Vegas 2 to capitalize on the surge of interest in the franchise. Obsidian is of course the developer of the much-loved 2010 RPG Fallout: New Vegas, so fans often wonder whether it will return to the setting for a sequel, especially given it’s now owned by Bethesda parent company Microsoft.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Obsidian, though, has focused on making brand new games, and it is prolific in doing so. It’s released Grounded (Grounded 2 came out this year), fantasy RPG Avowed (which came out this year), and sci-fi RPG The Outer Worlds (The Outer Worlds 2 came out this year). Pentiment, which came out last year, was another brand new game, although I wouldn’t expect a sequel to that any time soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last month, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-3-remaster"><u>Fallout 3 remaster</u></a> that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/oblivion-remaster-fallout-3-remaster-and-more-leaked-from-microsoft-document"><u>leaked back in 2023</u></a> was said to be still in the works. In response to Bethesda development chief Todd Howard’s recent interview with <a href="https://www.gq-magazine.co.uk/article/fallout-4-anniversary-todd-howard-interview" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>GQ</u></a>, in which he talked about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/im-preaching-patience-the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-todd-howard-warns-fans-teases-potential-shadowdrop"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6 still being some way off and “some other things we're doing” in the Fallout franchise</u></a>, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/7-years-after-it-was-announced-the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-todd-howard-says/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>VGC</u></a> reported that a remaster of Fallout 3 along the same lines as this year’s The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered is among them.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are all sorts of rumors floating around about potential Fallout remakes, and certainly a growing expectation among fans that Bethesda will turn to its older Fallout video games to keep fans on-side while they wait for The Elder Scrolls 6.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/dont-bother-guessing-youre-not-going-to-guess-right-tim-cain-one-of-the-creators-of-the-original-fallout-has-rejoined-xbox-studio-obsidian-to-work-on-a-mystery-project]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don’t Expect Rainbow Six Siege 2--Creative Director Explains Why It's Not Happening Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dont-expect-rainbow-six-siege-2-creative-director-explains-why-its-not-happening-yet/1100-6536724/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1374556</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536724">

            
            
        


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Rainbow Six Siege celebrated its 10th anniversary this month, a milestone that many live-service games haven't come close to matching. The tactical shooter launched in 2015, and it has evolved into a major attraction at esports tournaments across the globe, reaching 85 million players to date. To keep things fresh, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rainbow-six-siege-gets-most-transformative-update-ever-today-with-siege-x-launch/1100-6532322/">Rainbow Six Siege's "most transformative" update yet</a> went live earlier this year, prompting a surge of new and veteran players to hop into the game.</p><p>But will we ever see Rainbow Six Siege 2? Speaking to GameSpot, creative director Alexander Karpazis doesn't expect a sequel anytime soon, as Ubisoft aims to respect players' investment and keep the current game going for the foreseeable future.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="420702094" data-promo-id="52120" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466566,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;How%20Rainbow%20Six%20Siege%20Defied%20An%20Industry&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:1572,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/how-rainbow-six-siege-defied-an-industry\/2300-6466566\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466566\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466566\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466566\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466566&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466566,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536724&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;tom-clancys-rainbow-six-siege&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-one,playstation-4,pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x,stadia&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;ubisoft&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;tom-clancys-rainbow-six&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;tom-clancy&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466566},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466566\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1862\/18620770\/4616471-gamespot-insider-rs6_v2.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/ojl4abjv.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1764954000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="ojl4abjv" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> How Rainbow Six Siege Defied An Industry</p>
      </div>
<p>"Honestly, I think there are tons of reasons against it, just like there are reasons for it," Karpazis said. "But for us, it's about maintaining something that has been successful and competitive and fun for such a long time. We see it where players kind of get the rug pulled out from under them, and everything they've worked towards kind of changes in an instant when they jump over to a sequel. And that's something we don't want to do to our players. So there's an element of respecting players' investment. There's also an element of, this is an amazing legacy we're building--why would we want to throw that away?"</p><p>If you haven't checked it out yet, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-details-what-players-can-expect-from-rainbow-six-siege-x-launch-and-beyond/1100-6531636/" data-ref-id="1100-6531636">Siege X update</a> to Rainbow Six Siege added new features and functionality for all players. In addition to a new onboarding experience for players, modernized maps, and graphical upgrades, a new 6v6 game mode called Dual Front was also added to the game.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        <div>
	<p>
		Latest in
		Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six Siege
	</p>

	
</div>
  
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536671&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-preorder-guide\/1100-6536671\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536705&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-prime-members-get-these-14-free-games-in-december\/1100-6536705\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536701&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/you-probably-wont-guess-what-just-outsold-every-ps5-and-xbox-console-model-in-the-us\/1100-6536701\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536669&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/call-of-duty-is-underperforming-in-2025-analyst-says-citing-burnout-creative-decisions-and-ai-slop\/1100-6536669\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536675&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fallout-season-2-episode-release-date-schedule\/1100-6536675\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534941&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2026-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6534941\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536635&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/after-120-hours-in-arc-raiders-i-finally-killed-another-player\/1100-6536635\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536594&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/this-scary-the-game-awards-teaser-could-be-for-the-next-diablo-4-expansion\/1100-6536594\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535971&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-echoes-of-victory-ridge-quest-guide\/1100-6535971\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536599&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-switch-2-mario-kart-console-bundle-is-discounted-for-cyber-monday\/1100-6536599\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6532794&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/criterion-collection-50-off-movie-deals-restocked-at-amazon-sale-ends-december-7\/1100-6532794\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/all-arc-raiders-quests-full-mission-list\/1100-6535922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536690&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-6s-winter-offensive-update-is-all-about-combat-consistency-and-responsiveness\/1100-6536690\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536018&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-celestes-journals-quest-guide\/1100-6536018\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535962&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-the-majors-footlocker-quest-guide\/1100-6535962\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536650&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-start-elden-ring-nightreign-dlc-the-forsaken-hollows\/1100-6536650\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536069&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-flickering-threat-quest-guide\/1100-6536069\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536708&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024s-new-crossover-is-one-youll-never-expect\/1100-6536708\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536056&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-digging-up-dirt-quest-guide\/1100-6536056\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dont-expect-rainbow-six-siege-2-creative-director-explains-why-its-not-happening-yet/1100-6536724/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gone Home studio is taking a soothing dip with lost souls in its newly unveiled lo-fi narrative adventure Springs, Eternal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/gone-home-studio-is-taking-a-soothing-dip-with-lost-souls-in-newly-unveiled-lo-fi-narrative-adventure-springs-eternal</link>
            <guid>1374550</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spring-eternal-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spring-eternal-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spring-eternal-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spring-eternal-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spring-eternal-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spring-eternal-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spring-eternal-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spring-eternal-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spring-eternal-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Fullbright</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/gone-home">Gone Home</a> studio Fullbright has unveiled Springs, Eternal - a lo-fi narrative adventure where lost souls congregate in a "half-remembered otherworld" that's coming to PC sometime next year.
</p>
<p>
The Fullbright of 2025 is, of course, markedly different to the one that released Gone Home. Back in 2023, co-founder Steve Gaynor confirmed the studio was now <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gone-home-studio-fullbright-now-solo-outfit-as-controversial-co-founder-goes-it-alone">effectively a solo outfit</a> after his problematic workplace behaviour - which he acknowledged as "hurtful" - resulted in a split with the rest of the team.
</p>
<p>
Since then, Gaynor has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gone-home-developer-surprise-drops-toilet-spiders-in-early-access">released Toilet Spiders</a> as part of an "ongoing series of small, strange, lo-fi games", and the newly revealed Springs, Eternal is equally lo-fi, sporting a visual style evoking the "dithered and pixelated graphics of late '90s-era PC and home console games". But it's not just the 90s vibe and moody purple colour palette links it back to Gone Home; it shares a narrative-driven, first-person exploratory focus too.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Springs, Eternal: Official Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dIUoQBAzgSw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Springs, Eternal: Official Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dIUoQBAzgSw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dIUoQBAzgSw?autoplay=1" title="Springs, Eternal: Official Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Springs, Eternal reveal trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dIUoQBAzgSw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Springs, Eternal unfolds in the isolated mountain retreat of Stillwater, a forest sprawl - and a "half-remembered otherworld" full of "dark, winding paths" - where lost souls converge to enjoy its soothing waters. As for you, it's the memory of a relationship that's led you here, and you'll recall more of that in flashbacks over its two-to-three hour runtime.
</p><p>
And as you explore the "open-structure" world's pools, saunas, caverns, grand lodge, and other points of interest, you'll encounter over a dozen other characters - from "philosophers engaging in a debate that could last a lifetime" to a "tattooist waiting to inscribe you with your future" - whose stories you'll discover through branching dialogue. "The dark paths you walk are ominous", the announcement adds, "but you can’t die... can you?"
</p>
<p>
Springs, Eternal doesn't have a release date yet, but it's coming to PC - <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3677850/Springs_Eternal/">via Steam</a> at the very least - sometime next year.
</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  <div>
      <p>
        <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/gone-home">Gone Home</a>
      </p>

      <p>
            <span>PS4</span>, 
            <span>Xbox One</span>, 
            <span>Nintendo Wii U</span>, 
            <span>PC</span>, 
            <span>Mac</span>, 
            <span>Nintendo Switch</span>
      </p>





</div>

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/gone-home-studio-is-taking-a-soothing-dip-with-lost-souls-in-newly-unveiled-lo-fi-narrative-adventure-springs-eternal]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Developers of The God Slayer ‘Do Not Want to Use AI Too Much’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-god-slayer-developers-do-not-want-to-use-ai-too-much/</link>
            <guid>1374523</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-god-slayer-is-an-open-world-steampunk-action-rpg-from-the-makers-of-my-time-series/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The God Slayer</a> is the next big project in development at Chinese developer Pathea Games, known for My Time at Portia, My Time at Sandrock, and the upcoming third installment in that series, My Time at Evershine. </p>



<p>With The God Slayer, the studio is challenging itself with a more mature open world steampunk action RPG, not to mention switching engines from Unity to Epic's Unreal Engine 5. I recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-god-slayer-qa-from-our-point-of-view-weve-always-been-making-open-world-rpgs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">interviewed</a> Zifei Wu, founder and creative director at Pathea Games, to learn more about the game. During that conversation, I also inquired about the studio's stance on using generative AI tools during game development. You can find his answer below.</p>



<p><em>I think the only AI we use is when we're iterating. Like, for example, we say okay, we want this character to be a female salesperson, and then we'll try to use AI to go online to search for different models and stuff like that, and then after that, we just do it ourselves. I think overall, our developers don't want to use AI too much. First of all, you don't see a lot of Asian steampunk examples out there, so the examples that AI gives us are weird if I can put it that way. So, a lot of the stuff we actually have to think about ourselves and start from scratch. Overall, that's helped us keep the world setting as well as the characters of The God Slayer grounded. So I think, as far as like for us, I think we're not using too much AI. It's at least for now, the correct way to go.</em></p>



<p>The usage of generative AI tools is currently one of the most controversial topics within most industries, and that certainly includes the gaming industry. We recently reported that Masahiro Sakurai, the creator of Super Smash Bros., <a href="https://wccftech.com/super-smash-bros-creator-development-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">believes</a> that generative AI could make large-scale development more manageable. Hideo Kojima, the creator of the Metal Gear and Death Stranding franchises, <a href="https://wccftech.com/hideo-kojima-sees-creating-together-with-ai-way-stay-one-step-ahead/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">aims</a> to utilize the technology to automate basic tasks, allowing him to focus on the creative aspects of game development.</p>



<p>In an interview with Wccftech, Richard Pillosu, co-founder of Spanish indie developer Epictellers Entertainment, <a href="https://wccftech.com/theres-no-point-using-ai-for-any-creative-endeavor-says-game-developer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shared</a> a similar, albeit more unequivocal, opinion, stating that there is no point in using AI in any creative endeavour. In another Wccftech exclusive, Dean Hall, known for DayZ and ICARUS, <a href="https://wccftech.com/dayz-creator-says-ai-fears-remind-him-people-worrying-about-google-wikipedia-ai-is-here/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that AI is here and what really matters is how to deal with its impact. Lastly, Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick <a href="https://wccftech.com/take-two-ceo-says-game-characters-should-be-ai-trained-human-scripts-more-natural-conversations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">noted</a> that game characters could feel more realistic if AI-trained on scripts created by humans.</p>



<p>The God Slayer will be released for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, and potentially for next-gen platforms if available at the game's launch.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-god-slayer-developers-do-not-want-to-use-ai-too-much/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fans Can’t Believe How Much Microsoft Is Selling Used Xbox Consoles For]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fans-cant-believe-how-much-microsoft-is-selling-used-xbox-consoles-for-2000650923</link>
            <guid>1374514</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Good morning. I’ve got some great news for you. Today, yes today, is Friday. Tell everyone you know. Spread the word. Friday is back, baby. And on this wonderful Friday, I welcome you to the latest edition of Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku’s</em> daily round-up of video game news and other stuff you might care about. Today, we wonder what happened to a good <i>Black Ops 7 </i>map, learn more about why <em>Hytale</em> is skipping Steam, and ponder high console prices.</p> <h2>Used Xbox consoles are going for some wild prices</h2> <p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/xbox/comments/1pefqsl/dang_these_prices_are_getting_absurd/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">Over on Reddit,</a> people are shaking their heads in disbelief at the state of used game console prices. In 2025, <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/collections/certifiedrefurbishedxbox">Microsoft is selling refurbished Xbox Series X consoles for $550</a>. In 2020, I bought an Xbox Series X at launch for $500. Microsoft is also selling used Xbox Series S consoles for $330. At launch, the smaller machine was just $300, and you could often get it for less if you found a deal. These are absurd prices, but also not surprising when you consider how expensive consoles are in 2025, thanks to various factors like tariffs, inflation, AI squeezing demand, and every company trying to grow profits.</p>

 <p>Regardless of why prices are so high, it sucks that this is the first console generation where PlayStation and Xbox machines are <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/xbox/comments/1kdmdw4/a_history_of_xbox_console_prices_at_launch_vs_4/">more expensive five years after launch</a>. And <a href="https://kotaku.com/black-ops-7-helldivers-2-lava-skyblivion-delay-2000650525#:~:text=SSD%20and%20RAM%20maker%20Micron%20announced%20it%E2%80%99s%20getting%20out%20of%20the%20consumer%20business%20to%20focus%20on%20manufacturing%20for%20companies%E2%80%99%20AI%20computing%20needs.%20%E2%80%9CThe">prices are likely to keep going up for new and used consoles</a>. I can’t wait to take out a small bank loan to buy a PlayStation 6.</p>

 <h2><strong>A popular <em>CoD: Black Ops 7</em> map has been mysteriously removed</strong></h2> <p><em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7′</em>s first season is now live, and while it has added a lot of new content to the online FPS, it has also removed something: the fan-favorite map Blackheart. This was one of the original maps to launch with<em> Black Ops 7</em> and quickly became one of its most popular. But it’s gone now. Activision says it was removed “temporarily” from both private and public map pools as it investigates an undisclosed “issue.” The map will return in a future, but-not-yet-specified update.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">📢 Call of Duty: <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackOps7?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BlackOps7</a> </p> <p>Blackheart has been temporarily removed from both Public and Private map pools while we investigate an issue. It will return in an upcoming update.</p> <p>Details: <a href="https://t.co/rmpoklhguD">https://t.co/rmpoklhguD</a></p> <p>— Call of Duty Updates (@CODUpdates) <a href="https://twitter.com/CODUpdates/status/1996651809017045428?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2025</a></p></blockquote>    <h2><strong>Newly discovered fish species gets <em>Dragon Ball-</em>inspired name</strong></h2> <p>As spotted by <em>Dexerto</em>, a new small fish was discovered deep in the ocean near an island off the coast of Japan. And, likely due to its bright yellow markings across its body, the fish has been given the scientific name of Vanderhorstia Supersaiyan. Yup, this is a <em>Dragon Ball Z</em> fish. <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10228-025-01047-6">You can read more about the fish here</a>.</p>

 <h2><strong>Newly resurrected <em>Hytale</em> won’t be on Steam at launch</strong></h2> <p>Earlier this year, <em>Minecraft</em>-inspired survival game <em>Hytale</em> was canceled by Riot Games. <a href="https://kotaku.com/hytale-riot-minecraft-hypixel-revived-cancel-shutdown-2000645248">Then, in November</a>, the original creator behind the project was able to negotiate the rights back for the game, and now Hytale is back in development with some of the team that was working on it before it was canned. But when it launches in early access, you won’t find it on Steam.</p> <p><a href="https://hytale.com/news/2025/12/hytale-s-1st-faq">As explained in a new FAQ</a> on the game’s website, the devs are going to avoid Steam for a bit to focus on its existing community and improving the game instead of chasing “a flood of cold first impressions that could overcorrect the game’s direction.”&nbsp; The post clarifies that the team isn’t looking to avoid “bad reviews,” but I have to imagine that’s part of the reason the team is staying away from Steam until the game is in a good state. A game on Steam with negative or mixed reviews can be hard to overcome. I’ll be curious to see if more teams follow this move.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-carter-wu-homer-simpson-nipples-skins-shirtless-2000650650">Nipples are now allowed in <em>Fortnite</em></a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/outer-worlds-2-rpg-inventory-weight-encumbered-2000650641">Oh no, <em>Outer Worlds 2</em> gave me what I wanted, and I hate it</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/it-took-19-years-but-were-finally-getting-total-war-medieval-3-2000650612">Wow, 20 years later, <em>Medieval Total War 3</em> is happening&nbsp;</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/new-banjo-kazooie-sequel-remake-game-built-in-dreams-impressive-2000650541">Wow, this fan-made <em>Banjo-Kazooie</em> game is rad</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch This:</h2>    
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fans-cant-believe-how-much-microsoft-is-selling-used-xbox-consoles-for-2000650923]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Keeps Its MS Office Pro 2021 at 84% Off Black Friday Low to Extend Cyber Week Deal]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-keeps-its-ms-office-pro-2021-at-84-off-black-friday-low-to-extend-cyber-week-deal-2000650924</link>
            <guid>1374511</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Cyber Monday and Black Friday are a thing of the past at this point, but if you didn’t get a chance to grab all that you wanted during the biggest sale of the year, all is not lost. We’re still spotting quite a few lingering deals across retailers, so whether you’re after a new laptop, the latest smartphone, a kitchen appliance, or a subscription, there’s still time to save.</p>
<p>Stacksocial, in particular, is being the most generous with its post-Cyber Week drops. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/">We just spotted it offering a lifetime license of the 2021 Microsoft Office Professional for Windows at a whopping 84% discount.</a> This brings the price down to just $35, from $220. It’s selling out fast, though. We recommend grabbing your sooner rather than later, as the offer could wrap up any moment now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at StackSocial</a></p>

<h2>Ideal for Students and Work Professionals</h2>
<p>Note that this licensing type will be connected with your actual device, and not your Microsoft account. You will receive the redemption code with all the instructions immediately via email after your purchase, and you’ll have a week to set everything up. There are some system requirements you should know about before proceeding, as well. First, you should have Windows 10 or 11 installed, as the license is not supported on older versions. You’ll also need at least 1GB RAM, 4GB space available for hard disk formatting such as HFS+ (aka Windows OS Extended or HFS Plus), and a monitor with 1280×800 resolution or higher. Most latest systems already have all of this, but we still recommend double-checking before you proceed.</p>
<p>Office Professional 2021 includes Microsoft Office Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Teams (Free version only), OneNote, Publisher, and Access; everything you need for work, creative, and personal use. Word makes it easy to create and edit documents with a whole bunch of useful tools built right in, while Excel offers an easy way to handle data on a regular basis. You’ll be able to create stunning, jaw-dropping presentations with PowerPoint, take quick meetings using Teams, and manage calendars or emails using Outlook like a pro. OneNote is a personal favorite because of how fun it makes creating notes and organizing them in a single place. You can create different notebooks for different projects, incorporate media content within those, and a lot more.</p>



<p>Students can use these helpful programs to create assignments and collaborate on projects. Work professionals will be able to track their deadlines, create presentations, and manage emails; the possibilities are endless. On a regular day, you’d pay around $220 to enjoy all these features, but thanks to this Cyber Week deal, you can do it for just $35 today. It takes $185 off the price of an all-in-one solution. Don’t confuse it with Microsoft 365, though, which is a subscription service that offers the latest Office apps and lets you use them on multiple devices. This one is more of a one-and-done purchase with the core applications. You also won’t be able to use the programs on multiple devices with this license.</p>
<p>Make sure you redeem the activation code within 7 days of your purchase, as it won’t be valid after that. This is also a great time to grab some other subscriptions for less. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/">For instance, Stacksocial is also offering Windows 11 Home and Pro at a massive discount, as well. But get your orders in quickly, because the deals are selling out fast</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at StackSocial</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-keeps-its-ms-office-pro-2021-at-84-off-black-friday-low-to-extend-cyber-week-deal-2000650924]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Studio Affected By Warner Bros. & Netflix Merger—What Deal Means, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/every-studio-affected-by-warner-bros-netflix-merger/</link>
            <guid>1374505</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s been officially announced that Netflix is set to buy Warner Bros. in 2026 as part of a whopping $82.7 billion deal. Not only will Netflix acquire the rights to numerous Warner Bros. IPs, such as Harry Potter, Game of Thrones, and DC Comics, but it’ll also acquire all of Warner Bros. Games studios.</p>



<p>Warner Bros. has been no slacker in the gaming industry, either. Some major studios will be shifting to Netflix’s ownership, though whether the acquisition will affect their development remains to be seen.</p>







<p>This acquisition is certain to send shockwaves across every corner of the entertainment world, and the gaming sector is no exception. Warner Bros. Games oversees eight major studios, all of which are now set to feel the effects of Netflix’s takeover in one way or another.</p>



<h2 id="h-every-studio-owned-by-warner-bros-games">Every Studio Owned By Warner Bros. Games</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p><strong>In total, Warner Bros. Games oversees eight major studios—all of which will now come under Netflix’s ownership.</strong></p>



<p>These teams span a wide range of scale and specialties. From blockbuster franchises like Mortal Kombat to the critically acclaimed Batman: Arkham series, each studio has played a role in shaping some of gaming’s biggest hits. With such a diverse line-up moving to a new parent company, the industry will be watching closely to see how Netflix steers their future.</p>



<p>Here’s a breakdown of every studio currently operating under the Warner Bros. Games banner:</p>



<h3 id="h-avalanche-software">Avalanche Software</h3>



<figure><figcaption>The magical world of Harry Potter. Credit to Avalanche Software.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Avalanche Software have been around since 1995, and they’ve produced a variety of games over the years. Their most recent release was the incredibly popular <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hogwarts-legacy-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hogwarts Legacy</a>, though they’d had some success developing some Disney titles throughout the 2010s, such as Disney Infinity and Toy Story 3. </p>



<p>In regard to their upcoming projects, all eyes are on a sequel. There’s long been speculation that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hogwarts-legacy-2-a-priority-for-warner-bros-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hogwarts Legacy 2 is in development</a>, with the studio admitting that it’s a priority going forward.</p>







<h3 id="h-netherrealm-studios">NetherRealm Studios</h3>



<p>There’s one major franchise that people think of when NetherRealm Studios is mentioned: Mortal Kombat. The team is widely regarded as royalty in the fighting-game genre, and their other flagship series, Injustice, delivers the same high-impact combat through a DC Comics lens.</p>



<p>While a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mortal-kombat-3-film-confirmed-warner-bros/">Morta</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mortal-kombat-3-film-confirmed-warner-bros/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">l K</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mortal-kombat-3-film-confirmed-warner-bros/">ombat 3 movie</a> is officially in development, the future of the games themselves remains uncertain due to Warner Bros. Games’ acquisition. Speculation has been swirling for years about NetherRealm’s next project, with fans divided between two possibilities—a follow-up to Mortal Kombat 1 or a long-awaited Injustice 3. Whatever their future holds, fans will be hoping the Netflix merger doesn’t impact development.</p>



<h3 id="h-rocksteady-studios">Rocksteady Studios</h3>



<p>The Batman: Arkham series reshaped the landscape of modern superhero games, and Rocksteady Studios is the team that made it happen. Prior to Arkham Asylum, the studio’s only release was Urban Chaos: Riot Response on the PS2 and Xbox—but their work with Batman propelled them into industry stardom.</p>



<p>Their most recent project, Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League, landed with a mixed reception, yet Rocksteady remains a major force with the potential for a significant comeback. As for what comes next, nothing has been confirmed. Rumours continue to circulate about a return to Gotham with a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rocksteady-working-on-new-batman-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new Batman title supposedly in development</a>, but until an official announcement arrives, the studio’s next move remains firmly under wraps.</p>



<h3 id="h-tt-games">TT Games</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Fire up the Bat Signal. Image via TT Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>TT Games, or Traveller’s Tales, encompasses four major subsidiaries, though they all work together under the same umbrella. These are:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Traveller’s Tales</strong>. Primary Division of TT Games.</li>



<li><strong>TT Fusion</strong>. Division focused on porting games to handheld platforms.</li>



<li><strong>TT Games Publishing</strong>. Division focused on handling publishing duties.</li>



<li><strong>TT Odyssey</strong>. Mobile games developer.</li>
</ul>



<p>If you’re somehow not aware, these guys are responsible for the hugely successful and childhood-defining LEGO games. Its upcoming title, LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight, is slated for a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2026 release</a> and will probably be the first Warner Bros. game published following the Netflix acquisition announcement.</p>



<h3 id="h-wb-games-montreal">WB Games Montreal</h3>



<p>It’s no secret that Warner Bros. Games Montréal has had a mixed run in recent years. The studio supported Rocksteady on Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League, and before that developed Gotham Knights, another Arkham-adjacent project that met with a fairly lukewarm reception.</p>



<p>Despite this, it appears the team isn’t finished with the DC universe just yet. Reports suggest they’re now working on a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wb-games-montreal-is-working-on-a-aaa-live-service-title-based-on-dc-comics/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new AAA live-service title set within the DC Comics world</a>. Exactly what form that will take is still unclear, but fans will be hoping it avoids the pitfalls of previous superhero live-service attempts—particularly the comparisons to Marvel’s Avengers.</p>



<h3 id="h-wb-games-boston">WB Games Boston</h3>



<p>Warner Bros. Games Boston is best known for its work on MMO-RPGs, such as Dungeons &amp; Dragons Online and The Lord of the Rings Online.</p>



<h3 id="h-wb-games-new-york">WB Games New York</h3>



<p>WB Games New York works with developers to build online features and communities for video games. It’s not directly involved with developing a standalone video game. </p>



<h3 id="h-wb-games-san-francisco">WB Games San Francisco</h3>



<p>A Division of Warner Bros. Games that specifically works on mobile releases and titles, utilising IPs such as Harry Potter and the DC Universe.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-the-warner-bros-games-amp-netflix-merger">What Is The Warner Bros. Games &amp; Netflix Merger?</h2>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netflix-set-to-buy-warner-bros-in-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Netflix has officially acquired Warner Bros.</a> and all of its subsidiaries in a blockbuster deal reportedly valued at $82.7 billion—one of the largest entertainment acquisitions in history. The move marks a seismic shift in the media landscape, placing an enormous collection of globally renowned properties under the Netflix banner and signalling the company’s most aggressive expansion into traditional film, TV, and gaming yet.</p>



<p>The deal grants Netflix ownership of an expansive catalogue of IPs, ranging from Harry Potter to the full DC Comics universe. This also encompasses Warner Bros.’ prestigious film and television library, animation houses, HBO programming, and various production entities across the globe.</p>



<p>Crucially, the purchase includes Warner Bros. Games, bringing all eight of its studios—and their respective franchises—into Netflix’s growing gaming portfolio. That means Netflix now owns teams behind major titles such as Mortal Kombat, Batman: Arkham, LEGO games, Middle-earth, and more.</p>



<hr>



<p>How do you feel about the Netflix and Warner Bros. Merger? Do you think the gaming studios will be affected? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Insider Gaming content, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-arena-reloaded/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Splitgate 2’s relaunch as Splitgate: Arena Reloaded</a>, as well as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-showcase-announced-for-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest regarding the upcoming Monster Hunter Showcase</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/every-studio-affected-by-warner-bros-netflix-merger/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[20 Years Ago, Animal Crossing Finally Showed What It Could Be]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/20-years-ago-animal-crossing-finally-showed-what-it-could-be/1100-6536728/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1374499</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536728">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><em>Animal Crossing: Wild World is celebrating its 20-year anniversary today, December 5, 2025. Below, we look at how its modest pathing system laid the groundwork, so to speak, for what the series has become.</em></p><p dir="ltr">Animal Crossing has always balanced two fantasies: the joy of customizing a cozy little town and the simple pleasures of living among a cast of charming, slightly strange animal neighbors. Those two elements worked in tandem. Your creative expression shaped your village, but the daily routines of chatting with neighbors, fishing by the riverbank, and uncovering little surprises gave the world its soul.</p><p dir="ltr">Somewhere along the way, however, customization did not just complement village life--it began to overshadow it. And if you trace that shift back through the franchises' history, the turning point can be found within 2005's Animal Crossing: Wild World.</p><p dir="ltr">When Wild World released on the Nintendo DS, players expected a portable follow-up to the GameCube classic. What they did not expect was that the community would stumble onto a feature that would change how players approached the series forever. It was not a new tool, a new building, or a new villager type. It was something almost laughably simple. It was a path.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2ZB73-XpxR0" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2ZB73-XpxR0" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Custom designs already existed, but Wild World allowed players to place those designs freely outdoors. The intended purpose was small decorations and personal flair. What players actually did with the feature was far more ambitious. Once someone placed a tile in front of their house, they realized they could place another, then another, then a line of them stretching down the hillside toward the river. Suddenly, a mere decorative option transformed into a way to redesign the entire town.</p><p dir="ltr">Players began laying designs across their villages to create dirt trails, stone walkways, mossy forest routes, and pixel-art mosaics that zigzagged across the map. Wild World towns became sprawling canvases filled with hand-made road systems, seasonal pathways, and intricate layout experiments. A village was no longer just a place you inhabited. It was something you curated down to the color of a leaf laying on the ground under your feet.</p><p dir="ltr">This discovery fundamentally shifted how players thought about Animal Crossing. For the first time, one town could look drastically different from another. In the GameCube original, towns varied based on layout and villager mix, but they all followed the same structure. Wild World gave players the means to break from that structure entirely.</p><p dir="ltr">Nintendo only formally embraced paths years later, but Wild World’s influence appeared in every entry that followed. City Folk still let players carve out basic routes using designs, even if the system was more limited. New Leaf opened the floodgates. The introduction of custom design QR codes sparked a golden age of path sharing on Tumblr, GameFAQs, and early Twitter. Players traded wooden planks for rustic forests, geometric tiles for urban hubs, stone borders for garden pathways, and soft floral stepping stones for cottages long before cottage-core became a cultural phenomenon.</p><p dir="ltr">Then came the real shift in how Animal Crossing functioned.</p><p dir="ltr">When Animal Crossing: New Horizons launched in 2020, Nintendo finally acknowledged that paths had become central to the series. The Island Designer app made path placement a built-in system rather than an improvised one. Terraforming lets players reshape cliffs, rivers, and coastlines to match the layouts they envisioned. For many players, building an island felt less like moving into a place and more like designing it from scratch.</p><p dir="ltr">New Horizons was a global phenomenon, but it also solidified the series' new identity. Players became architects first, residents second. The core loop encouraged planning and layout experimentation. Some created zen gardens and tranquil forest towns. Others built dense shopping districts, amusement piers, horror-themed mazes, or entire cities with street grids and elevated walkways. The island's shape and flow became the primary creative outlet.</p><p dir="ltr">This evolution traces directly back to Wild World. Once players discovered they could cover entire towns with handmade designs, the series gradually shifted from a life sim about daily rituals to a platform for personal expression. The small social rhythms of talking to villagers and discovering tiny events still mattered, but they increasingly played a supporting role. The atmosphere began to matter more than routine. Layout mattered more than tradition.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MaxHm2zu0AE" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/MaxHm2zu0AE" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">The shift did not diminish the original charm of Animal Crossing. Instead, it showed how flexible the series could be. What began as a relaxed slice-of-life sim with quirky animals became, little by little, a playground for digital landscaping, environmental storytelling, and light urban planning. Animal Crossing grew up alongside its players, reflecting changing tastes and expanding creative ambition.</p><p dir="ltr">Nearly twenty years after Wild World, paths still sit at the heart of how players shape their towns. Entire YouTube channels and TikTok creators dedicate themselves to showcasing island layouts. Fan-made path sets circulate like seasonal fashion lines, complete with new color palettes and patterns each month.</p><p dir="ltr">Paths determine whether a town feels like a rustic forest hideout, a bright beachside boardwalk, a modern city block, a mystical grove, or a retro village pulled from a Super Nintendo RPG. They guide how you move through your town and how you experience it day to day. They influence everything from your morning routine to your choice of furniture themes.</p><p dir="ltr">As Wild World celebrates another anniversary this December, it is fitting to recognize the small, player-driven innovation that changed everything. Wild World may not be the flashiest entry in the series, but it laid down something more important than a set of tiles. It laid down the path for what the franchise would become.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/20-years-ago-animal-crossing-finally-showed-what-it-could-be/1100-6536728/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New GTA 5 DLC Adds Michael -- "Daddy's Back B***hes," Actor Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-gta-5-dlc-adds-michael-daddys-back-bhes-actor-says/1100-6536727/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1374496</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536727">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Rockstar Games has announced more details on the next big update for GTA 5's multiplayer mode, including the long-awaited return of Michael De Santa.</p><p>Michael is one of GTA 5's three main playable characters, and fans have been waiting for a long time to interact with him again after the events of the main story. A GTA Online expansion from 2021 <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-onlines-new-dlc-confirms-michael-is-still-alive-after-gta-5-story/1100-6499135/" data-ref-id="1100-6499135">confirmed that Michael was still alive</a>. In the soon-to-release A Safehouse in the Hills expansion, he's back--and he looks older. Take a look for yourself in the trailer below.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=APJ-lT0sBhg" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/APJ-lT0sBhg" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gtav-story-dlc-coming-in-2014/1100-6416619/" data-ref-id="1100-6416619">All the way back in 2013</a>, Rockstar Games said it would release more story content that extended the stories of Michael, Franklin, and Trevor. A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-online-is-adding-story-dlc-featuring-gta-5s-franklin-and-dr-dre/1100-6498737/" data-ref-id="1100-6498737">previous DLC for GTA Online focused on Franklin</a>, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-is-why-gta-5-trevor-dlc-was-reportedly-scrapped/1100-6524713/" data-ref-id="1100-6524713">plans for a Trevor-focused expansion were apparently canceled.</a></p><p>Actor Ned Luke, who plays Michael, responded to Rockstar's announcement by saying, <a href="https://x.com/ned_luke/status/1996971077998637459" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">"Daddy's back bitches."</a></p><p>Michael returns to Los Santos in the update on December 10, and the major focus of the expansion are new mansions in expensive neighborhoods that players can buy and live in. Players can spend their ill-gotten gains on mansions from Prix Luxury Real Estate. The homes are massive and contain things that rich people like, including trophy cabinets, salons, and huge garages. There are also animal kennels, and this means the new GTA Online update is adding personal pets as well.</p><p>There is also a new AI Assistant in the game, and given Rockstar's propensity for parody, it's possible the AI will have some lines that skewer the modern trend of AI assistants in the real world. You can hear some of the AI's voice lines in the trailer.</p><p>What's more, players should remember that they have until December 7 to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-online-is-free-right-now-lets-you-get-a-big-discount-on-new-mansions/1100-6536179/" data-ref-id="1100-6536179">complete special missions</a> to earn major discounts on buying the new mansions that are coming to the game on December 10.</p><p>In addition to ongoing support for GTA Online, Rockstar is developing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">GTA 6</a> and will launch the game in November 2026, following multiple delays.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-gta-5-dlc-adds-michael-daddys-back-bhes-actor-says/1100-6536727/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix Is Acquiring Warner Bros. And Its Games Division, Including Netherrealm, Rocksteady, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/05/netflix-is-acquiring-warner-bros-and-its-games-division-including-netherrealm-rocksteady</link>
            <guid>1374493</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Warner Bros. Discovery has been shopping around for a new owner the past few months, and this morning, they entered negotiations with a new winner; <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/netflix-to-acquire-warner-bros">Netflix won over Paramount and Comcast</a>. The deal, which combines cash and stock, will see the <em>Stranger Things</em> streaming service acquire Warner Bros. for $82.7 billion, while Discovery Global will spin off into a separate, independent company before the acquisition. Warner Bros. owns many major media brands, such as HBO and DC, &nbsp;as well as Warner Bros. Games, a publisher that owns several major game developers. While this part of the deal was previously unclear, <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/yes-netflix-is-acquiring-warner-bros-games"><em>Game Developer</em> has confirmed</a> that this division will be acquired by Netflix as well.</p><p>The inclusion of Warner Bros. Games is ignored in the initial press release (the only games mentioned are <em>Squid Game </em>and <em>Game of Thrones</em>), and <em>Game Developer</em> reports that a conference call held this morning only briefly suggested the game publisher would be a part of the deal. <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/yes-netflix-is-acquiring-warner-bros-games"><em>Game Developer's</em> Chris Kerr writes</a>, "Warner Bros. Games was briefly referenced during a conference call held this morning, when the Mortal Kombat logo was shown on a 'Business Overview' slide to highlight Warner Bros.' wider game and consumer product exploits—but that blink-and-you'll-miss-it-moment was largely it." In a later call with a representative of Warner Bros. Discovery, however, <em>Game Developer </em>confirmed that the Warner Bros. Games division would be a part of Netflix's deal.</p><p><em>Hogwarts Legacy, Mortal Kombat, and the Batman: Arkham series are just a few of the game series Netflix will own.</em></p><hr><p>Warner Bros. Games owns several major gaming studios. There's Netherrealm Studios (known for <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/mortal-kombat-legacy-kollection/chronicled-kombat">Mortal Kombat</a>), Avalanche (developers of <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/hogwarts-legacy/a-potion-well-brewed">Hogwarts Legacy</a>), Rocksteady (known for the Arkham series and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/06/a-new-report-details-how-a-troubled-development-led-to-suicide-squad-kill-the" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="05c73582-6d92-444a-ab3e-0821b01ab35e" data-entity-substitution="canonical">the recent Suicide Squad game</a>), and TT Games (known for the licensed Lego games, like Lego Star Wars and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/gamescom-2025/2025/08/27/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-is-the-next-arkham-game-youve-been" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="6ddac429-cbe0-4568-ba2d-fe81182bcbb7" data-entity-substitution="canonical">Lego Batman</a>). There are also several WB Games studios, most notably WB Montréal, which developed Batman: Arkham Origins and Gotham Knights.</p><p>Netflix has attempted to break into the gaming scene in recent years, offering a wide range of mobile games as a part of a Netflix subscription, including apps like Cut the Rope, indie hits like Dead Cells, and even Rockstar ports like Red Dead Redemption and GTA: San Andreas. Netflix has also acquired several game studios, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2021/09/28/netflix-acquires-oxenfree-developer-night-school-studio" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="dc5bdf17-9d59-46dd-adfb-21cbbf2eafb8" data-entity-substitution="canonical">like Oxenfree developer Night School Studios</a>. Netflix is currently <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/10/28/life-is-strange-developer-dont-nod-partners-with-netflix-for-game-adaptation-of-a-major">collaborating with Life is Strange creators Don't Nod</a> on a mysterious game adaptation of a "major IP". Still, it's unclear how far these efforts have gotten them, and adding major console developers to its portfolio could make a huge difference.</p><p>It will likely be a while before we see the results of this merger; the transaction process is lengthy and is estimated to last 12-18 months. This also assumes antitrust regulatory bodies don't get involved to slow the process, and with a deal of this size, it would not be surprising. The last deal we covered on this scale was Microsoft's acquisition of Activision Blizzard, which fought a major legal battle but ultimately succeeded. The jury is still out, however, on whether that merger was good for consumers or employees, as Microsoft has since <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/02/microsoft-lays-off-thousands-of-employees-cancels-perfect-dark-everwild-and-more-xbox" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="5d624b4b-915a-4605-840e-eca886d645df" data-entity-substitution="canonical">laid off thousands of employees</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/news/2024/05/07/xbox-is-shutting-down-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-more" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ee67f007-444c-47ee-ba02-5c106da54e43" data-entity-substitution="canonical">closed several major studios</a>, and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/19/xbox-console-prices-will-increase-again-next-month">raised the prices of its consoles</a> and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/10/01/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-is-getting-an-overhaul-and-a-50-percent-price-increase" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="38410bb2-8067-4828-aaaa-1faa408a2a69" data-entity-substitution="canonical">subscription service</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/05/netflix-is-acquiring-warner-bros-and-its-games-division-including-netherrealm-rocksteady]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bethesda boss and RPG lover Todd Howard names his 2025 Game of the Year, and it shouldn't come as a big surprise]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesda-boss-and-rpg-lover-todd-howard-names-his-2025-game-of-the-year-and-it-shouldnt-come-as-a-big-surprise</link>
            <guid>1374490</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/todd-ex33_xUoRTrj.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/todd-ex33_xUoRTrj.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/todd-ex33_xUoRTrj.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/todd-ex33_xUoRTrj.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/todd-ex33_xUoRTrj.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/todd-ex33_xUoRTrj.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/todd-ex33_xUoRTrj.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/todd-ex33_xUoRTrj.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/todd-ex33_xUoRTrj.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Bethesda's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/todd-howard">Todd Howard</a>, boss of the Elder Scrolls and Fallout series, has named his game of the year - it's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>.</p>
<p>"Expedition 33 is really unique and amazing," Howard told Eurogamer's social producer Mat Jones when asked for his game of the year choice, before name-checking <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/death-stranding-2">Death Stranding 2</a> and Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 as well.</p>
<p>"I think Expedition 33 is a really unique piece of art in so many ways," he added, doubling down on his choice.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Review: Outstanding Artwork And Glorious Combat" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hPbW6NcJ0P4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Review: Outstanding Artwork And Glorious Combat</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hPbW6NcJ0P4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/hPbW6NcJ0P4?autoplay=1" title="Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Review: Outstanding Artwork And Glorious Combat">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Review: Outstanding Artwork And Glorious Combat<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hPbW6NcJ0P4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>It's certainly a great choice, but also rounds off a rivalry from earlier this year. Bethesda shadow-dropped <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remake">The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion Remastered</a> two days before Clair Obscur: Expedition 33, with both also available on Xbox Game Pass.</p>
<p>But that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elder-scrolls-oblivion-surprise-release-didnt-seem-to-harm-clair-obscur-expedition-33-success-publisher-says">didn't scupper the release of Expedition 33</a>, as publisher Kepler's senior portfolio director Matt Handrahan said "proximity to Oblivion didn't seem to harm us at all". After all, both games represent opposing Western and Japanese ends of the RPG spectrum.</p>
<p>Expedition 33 has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/clair-obscur-expedition-33-will-receive-new-update-with-a-bit-of-whee-and-a-bit-of-whoo-as-studio-celebrates-new-sales-milestone">sold over 5m copies worldwide</a> across all formats and is the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/clair-obscur-expedition-33-makes-game-awards-history-as-most-nominated-game-ever">frontrunner at next week's The Game Awards with a record-breaking 12 nominations</a>. So it's not just Howard's favour the game has won.</p>
<p>The game has also been a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/clair-obscur-expedition-33-xbox-game-passs-biggest-third-party-success-2025">success for Xbox Game Pass as the subscription service's biggest third-party release of the year</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-says-todd-howard-but-development-is-his-everyday-thing">Howard currently has The Elder Scrolls 6 as his "everyday thing"</a>, but noted recently it's "still a long way off". In the same interview with Eurogamer, he <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-and-elder-scrolls-boss-todd-howard-defends-ai-in-game-development-but-aims-to-protect-artistry-and-human-intention-in-his-games">defended the use of AI but aims to "protect artistry" in his games</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesda-boss-and-rpg-lover-todd-howard-names-his-2025-game-of-the-year-and-it-shouldnt-come-as-a-big-surprise]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Mario Kart World Getting Donkey Kong Bananza DLC? Datamines Have Fans Speculating]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/is-mario-kart-world-getting-donkey-kong-bananza-dlc-datamines-have-fans-speculating</link>
            <guid>1374475</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="3449ea41b04fe"><a title="Donkey Kong in Mario Kart World DK Spaceport" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/3449ea41b04fe/donkey-kong-in-mario-kart-world-dk-spaceport.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>While <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> may have just received <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/mario-kart-world-has-been-updated-to-version-1-4-0-here-are-the-full-patch-notes">a rather hefty update</a>, fans of the Switch 2 launch game have been eagerly anticipating any potential DLC that will come to the racer. And a recent datamine of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/nintendo_today">Nintendo Today!</a> has brought all of those hopes and dreams to the surface (thanks, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-set-to-finally-acknowledge-donkey-kong-bananzas-secret-character-and-fans-are-now-convinced-the-timing-points-to-mario-kart-world-dlc">IGN</a>!).</p>
<p>So, some context: earlier this week, Nintendo updated its news app with a suite of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/nintendo-today-mobile-app-update-adds-a-new-donkey-kong-theme">Donkey Kong themes</a>, with many of them seemingly inspired by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>.</p>
<p>Fans decided to datamine the themes and see which Kong characters would be appearing in the future and over on Famiboards, user <a href="https://famiboards.com/threads/donkey-kong-community-st2-ohhh-bananza.14427/page-64#post-2086247">MondoMega shared the results</a>, and there were a few surprises.</p>
<p>Now, beyond this point, we'll be going into <strong>big Donkey Kong Bananza</strong> <strong>spoilers</strong>, so if you haven't beaten the game yet and want to be surprised, then stop reading right now; the spoilers will be after the image.</p>
<figure data-uuid="1c3b2a8231e02"><a title="Donkey Kong Bananza" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1c3b2a8231e02/donkey-kong-bananza.large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Watch out, spoilers below! — <em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>It turns out, none other than King K. Rool will be featuring on the app on 15th December. Nintendo has rarely acknowledged the villainous croc in recent years, besides his appearance in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_smash_bros_ultimate">Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</a>, and Donkey Kong Bananza's endgame — and his role as the final boss — was a huge surprise to many. Kritters will also be appearing a few days prior, on 9th.</p>
<p>Now, why would Nintendo have K. Rool pop up on the calendar on 15th December? Honestly, it may well be a harmless bit of promotion. Nintendo features multiple characters unrelated to game releases on the app.</p>
<p>But the timing of this update, and all of the assets coming from Bananza (you can see all of the <a href="https://www.mariowiki.com/Nintendo_Today!#Donkey_Kong">datamined animations on Mario Wiki</a> - beware of spoilers, obviously) has people fervently speculating; will King K. Rool be added to Mario Kart World?</p>
<p>It's not just baseless speculation, either; shortly after Bananza launched, eagle-eyed players noticed that both King K. Rool <em>and</em> Void Kong's voices <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Mario/comments/1m336wn/dk_bananza_spoiler_is_dk_bananzas_credits/">were listed in Mario Kart World's credits</a>, but neither character was in the game.</p>
<p>So will we be getting some DLC news soon? The Game Awards are next week, but Nintendo rarely makes an appearance at the ceremony, with its biggest announcements there being Bayonetta Origins and a variety of Smash Bros. DLC. Could the Big N buck the trend in 2025? We'll have to wait and see.</p>
<p>For now, take this with a pinch of salt. We'd <em>love</em> to see K. Rool in a kart, but we won't get our hopes up just yet.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>What do you think of the datamines? Do you think we'll see some Mario Kart World DLC soon? Drive down to the comments and let us know.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194643 @ 1764953332 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://famiboards.com/threads/donkey-kong-community-st2-ohhh-bananza.14427/page-64#post-2086247" rel="noopener" href="https://famiboards.com/threads/donkey-kong-community-st2-ohhh-bananza.14427/page-64#post-2086247">famiboards.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.mariowiki.com/Nintendo_Today!#Donkey_Kong" rel="noopener" href="https://www.mariowiki.com/Nintendo_Today!#Donkey_Kong">mariowiki.com</a>, <a title="External Link: https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-set-to-finally-acknowledge-donkey-kong-bananzas-secret-character-and-fans-are-now-convinced-the-timing-points-to-mario-kart-world-dlc" rel="noopener" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-set-to-finally-acknowledge-donkey-kong-bananzas-secret-character-and-fans-are-now-convinced-the-timing-points-to-mario-kart-world-dlc">ign.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/8eb82d945c875930ec9bcd857f046cb2 @ 1764955335 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/is-mario-kart-world-getting-donkey-kong-bananza-dlc-datamines-have-fans-speculating]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Prime 4 – Great Mines Omega Boss Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/05/metroid-prime-4-great-mines-omega-griever-boss-guide/</link>
            <guid>1374472</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It’s taken a lot to get here, but deep at the bottom of the Great Mines in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/Metroid-Prime-4">Metroid Prime 4</a>, Samus faces the greatest challenge yet on the planet Viewros. You know it’s going to be a rough time when you’re fighting something Omega in a Metroid game…</p>
<p>Now, obviously, <strong>this guide contains spoilers </strong>for Metroid Prime 4, so <strong>stop reading at this point if you are not currently at the final battle of the Great Mines</strong> in the game.</p>
<p>OK… so everyone that’s still here would like some helpful hints? Let’s go.</p>


<h2>Great Mines Omega Boss – First Phase</h2>
<h3>Wall Crawler</h3>
<p>The Omega boss in the Great Mines is a pretty challenging one to tackle, and it fights you in two modes, moves quickly and has long periods of invulnerability.</p>
<p>To start, the Omega Griever scurries around from side to side, high up on the walls of the battle arena. From there, t regularly stops and fires a series of green globs of gloop that slow you and deal damage over time if they hit. Look out for it winding up to start spitting and try to dodge and jump to the sides to evade.</p>


<p>While in this mode, the Omega Griever is hiding its weak spot on the chest and won’t take any damage, but it can be staggered. You need to aim to hit the fleshy coloured parts of its body, as opposed to the black armoured or green glowing sections –&nbsp;you’ll know you’re hitting when it glows gold. Just rapid fire the beam cannon during this and try to lead the target as it moves. The difficulty is that the Omega Griever can dash and break your lock-on, so be ready to quickly release and retarget.</p>
<p>Once enough hits have landed, the Omega Griever will be fatigued and drop to reveal the red weak spot on its chest. Hit this with as much damage as possible –&nbsp;a Super Missile does the trick! –&nbsp;and it will drop to the floor.</p>

<h3>Floor Battle</h3>
<p>Now that the Griever is on the floor, it gets more inventive with its attacks. Here’s what you need to be aware of:</p>
<p><strong>Sticky Green Gloop</strong> –&nbsp;The Omega Griever projectile vomits green gloop in a cone to its front. This will slow and damage Samus, and you need to mash A to free yourself.<br>
<strong>Claw Attack</strong> –&nbsp;The Omega Griever gets close and swipes with its big arms in turn. Try to keep your distance and jump or dodge away.<br>
<strong>Ground Pound</strong> –&nbsp;The Omega Griever slams on the floor, creating a shockwave that you can avoid by jumping over the top.<br>
<strong>Tongue Grab</strong> –&nbsp;Whipping out its long tentacle-like tongue, the Griever tries to grab Samus and draw her in. Deal as much damage to the tongue as possible while grabbed to get free.</p>

<p>During this phase you need to keep blasting, aiming for exposed fleshy limbs to stun the Omega Griever. Once stunned it slumps to the ground, but its weak spot is still covered. Change to the morph ball, roll under and lay some bombs quickly. This now puts the Omega Griever into a proper damage phase, leaning back to expose its chest.</p>

<p>Unload everything you have with super missiles and charged beam shots, but beware that it can unleash a gloop attack and escape once the stunlock is up.</p>

<h2>Omega Griever – Second Phase</h2>
<p>After taking around one third damage, the Omega Griever will try to escape and crash through a part of the wall, creating some ammo and health that you can absorb with while charging up a beam shot. It also causes some basic and explosive Grievers to spawn. Take them out quickly and it will start to crawl around the walls once more.</p>

<p>It moves a bit quicker now, and has more crusted black armour that is truly invulnerable, but it’s the same process of hitting the fleshy bits to stun, and then the weak spot to drop the Omega Griever to the floor.</p>
<p>Once on the floor, prepare yourself for variants of the same attacks and one new one:</p>
<p><strong>Big Green Ball</strong> –&nbsp;The Omega Griever rolls up and throws a big green ball at Samus. Keep moving to avoid.<br>
Leaping Claw Attack –&nbsp;Now there are up to three swipes and the Griever will leap forward to try and hit Samus.<br>
<strong>Double Ground Pound</strong> –&nbsp;It now hits the ground in quick succession. Just time a late double jump<br>
Sticky Green Gloop &amp; Tongue Grab are the same.</p>

<p>Again, keep hitting exposed flesh, morph ball and bomb its chest when stunned, and Super Missile the chest when you can.</p>
<h2>Omega Griever Third Phase</h2>
<p>Once down to its final third of health, the Omega Griever again escapes and smashes into the wall, summons lesser Grievers and grows more armour. It might be faster now, but follow the same methods as before to get it down to the ground.</p>
<p>Once on the ground be aware of new and modified attacks:</p>
<p><strong>Laser Beam</strong> –&nbsp;The Omega Griever does a full 360º&nbsp;laser beam attack that you need to jump over to avoid. This does also leave a temporary gas cloud at the edge of the arena, so don’t get too far away.<br>
<strong>Quad Ground Pound</strong> –&nbsp;Two double ground pounds from its lower and upper arms. Time your double jumps to avoid.<br>
Quad Claw Attack –&nbsp;It’s just four back-to-back claw attacks. Keep your distance.</p>

<p>Keep hitting exposed flesh, and get to that weak point!</p>
<h2><strong>Omega Griever Trick Phase!</strong></h2>
<p>Eventually the Omega Griever falls, flopping to the ground and dropping a power up… but wait! It’s a trap!</p>

<p>The Omega Griever grabs you when you get close and starts sapping your life. Shoot it a ton in the face to be released and go for one last ground fight phase. You know what to do and everything it can do by now. Finish the fight!</p>
<hr>
<p>Congratulations, you’ve just earned the final major upgrade in the game, and are into the final stretch. You now need to head back out, but there’s one last thing you should do in the Great Mines before leaving: <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/04/metroid-prime-4-where-to-find-scout-bot-guide/">look for the Scout Bot</a>.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/05/metroid-prime-4-great-mines-omega-griever-boss-guide/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Awards 2025: Where to Watch, All Nominations, What to Expect]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-where-to-watch-all-nominations-what-to-expect/</link>
            <guid>1374469</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The Game Awards is set to return for yet another year, celebrating the best video games, developers, and creators of 2025 while offering a showcase of world premieres for the future of gaming. Hosted once again by the event’s creator, Geoff Keighley, TGA 2025 is the definitive close to the gaming calendar year, bringing together the entire industry for one explosive night.</p>



<p>If you are planning to tune in, this is your definitive guide to the show, including when and where to watch, a breakdown of all the key categories, and what massive game reveals you can expect to see.</p>



<div><h2>Table of contents</h2><ul><li><a href="#h-when-and-where-to-watch-the-game-awards-2025" data-level="2">When and Where to Watch The Game Awards 2025</a><ul><li><a href="#h-date-amp-time" data-level="3">Date &amp; Time</a></li><li><a href="#h-where-to-watch" data-level="3">Where to Watch</a></li><li><a href="#h-how-long-will-the-game-awards-2025-be" data-level="3">How long will The Game Awards 2025 be?</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#h-the-game-awards-2025-official-nominations-list" data-level="2">The Game Awards 2025 Official Nominations List</a></li><li><a href="#h-special-performances" data-level="2">Special Performances</a></li><li><a href="#h-likely-announcements-and-new-looks-confirmed-or-strong-rumor" data-level="2">Likely Announcements and New Looks (Confirmed or Strong Rumor)</a></li></ul></div>



<h2 id="h-when-and-where-to-watch-the-game-awards-2025">When and Where to Watch The Game Awards 2025</h2>



<h3 id="h-date-amp-time">Date &amp; Time</h3>



<p>The <strong>official date and time</strong> are confirmed for:</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th>Detail</th><th>Schedule</th></tr><tr><td><strong>Date</strong></td><td><strong>Thursday, December 11, 2025</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong>Show Start Time</strong></td><td><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(232, 230, 227, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(232, 230, 227, 0.2)">4:30 PM PT / 7:30 PM ET / 12:30 AM GMT (UK) / 1:30 AM CET (Central Europe) (Dec 12)</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong>Pre-Show</strong></td><td>Starts one hour prior to the main show</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h3 id="h-where-to-watch">Where to Watch</h3>



<p>The Game Awards is broadcast <strong>free</strong> on every major platform globally.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Official Channels:</strong> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d-BDeU3R5ic" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">YouTube (4K)</a>, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/thegameawards" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Twitch</a> </li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Social Platforms:</strong> <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.facebook.com/thegameawards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Facebook</a>, <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://x.com/thegameawards" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">X</a>, <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@thegameawards?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TikTok</a>, <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://store.steampowered.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a></li>



<li><strong>Streaming Services</strong>: <a href="https://www.primevideo.com/offers/nonprimehomepage/ref=dv_web_force_root">Amazon Prime Video</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-how-long-will-the-game-awards-2025-be">How long will The Game Awards 2025 be?</h3>



<p>Official runtime has yet to be confirmed. Based on previous years, <strong>the show is expected to last between 3 and 4 hours.</strong></p>



<h2 id="h-the-game-awards-2025-official-nominations-list">The Game Awards 2025 Official Nominations List</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Clair-Obscur-Expedition-33.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is among the most nominated The Game Awards 2025 games</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-nominees-full-list/">full list of every The Game Awards 2025 nomination</a> highlights how Sandfall Interactive is expected to bring home quite a few awards, even against strong contenders like Hades II, Hollow Knight: Silksong and Death Stranding 2: On The Beach. </p>







<p><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://thegameawards.com/brackets/players-voice"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Player's Choice Award voting</strong></a> is still ongoing as well, so make sure to cast your votes for your favorite games ahead of the show on December 11.</p>



<h2 id="h-special-performances">Special Performances</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Evanescence-The-Game-Awards.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The Game Awards 2025 will host a special performance from Evanescence</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Goth Rock/Metal band <strong>Evanescence</strong> will perform the song <a href="https://x.com/thegameawards/status/1996265085380206695" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Afterlife from the Devil May Cry Netflix anime</strong></a> during this year's show. No other musical performance has been confirmed.</p>



<h2 id="h-likely-announcements-and-new-looks-confirmed-or-strong-rumor">Likely Announcements and New Looks (Confirmed or Strong Rumor)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Resident-Evil-Requiem-Gamescom-1.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>A new look at Resident Evil Requiem is coming during The Game Awards 2025</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The titles below have either been confirmed to be shown during The Game Awards 2025 or are heavily rumored to make an appearance.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag-remake-targeting-march-2026-launch/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Assassin's Creed: Black Flag Re</strong><strong>make</strong></a> (A rumored remake of the fourth entry in the Ubisoft series)</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/control-2-title-control-resonant-new-trademark-remedy-the-game-awards/">Control: Resonant</a></strong> (Rumored new entry in the series)</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-pc-version-rated-esrb-published-by-sony/">Death Stranding 2: On The Beach</a></strong> (Rumored PC port announcement)</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a href="https://x.com/EXODUSGame/status/1993365313962889525">EXODUS</a></strong> (New trailer)</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://x.com/NeonGiantGames/status/1995417593407050185">Neon Giant's Project Impact</a></strong></li>



<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-gamescom-hands-on-preview-two-heavens-as-one/">Onimusha: Way of the Sword</a></strong> (Expected to receive a final release date)</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a href="https://wccftech.com/pragmata-gamescom-hands-on-preview-an-unexpected-surprise/">P</a></strong><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/pragmata-gamescom-hands-on-preview-an-unexpected-surprise/">RAGMATA</a></strong> (Expected to receive a final release date)</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/1996732500614238540" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resident Evil Requiem</a></strong> (New look with the <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-finally-gets-first-combat-footage-but-leon-is-nowhere-to-be-seen/">possible reveal of Leon S. Kennedy</a>)</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a href="https://wccftech.com/titanfall-3-isnt-dead-and-will-be-revealed-at-the-game-awards-2025-rumor/">Titanfall 3</a></strong> (long-rumored new entry in the series)</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/total-war-medieval-iii-is-in-early-development-warcore-engine-announced/">Total War</a></strong> (Creative Assembly has confirmed a world premiere trailer)</li>
</ul>



<p>Though heavily rumored in the past few weeks, other games won't make an appearance this year:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-is-rumored-to-release-in-january-2026/">Prince of Persia: Sands of Time Remake</a></strong> (<a href="https://x.com/princeofpersia/status/1996323369080250412">Confirmed not to be present</a>)</li>



<li><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-new-trailer-ps5-60-fps-ray-tracing/">The Witcher IV</a></strong> (<a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-4-will-not-appear-at-the-game-awards-2025/">confirmed not to be present</a>)</li>
</ul>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-where-to-watch-all-nominations-what-to-expect/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix to Buy Warner Bros, Including Gaming Wing, for $82.7b]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netflix-warner-bros-acquisition</link>
            <guid>1374463</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Netflix has announced that it will buy Warner Bros following the separation of the company's Discovery wing, and the gaming arm will be part of the deal.</p><p>In an <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/netflix-to-acquire-warner-bros" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">announcement</a> on the Netflix website, the company says it's entered into an agreement to purchase Warner Bros for an eye-watering $82.7 billion, which puts this deal squarely above Microsoft's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/microsoft-buys-activision-blizzard-bobby-kotick-staying-as-ceo" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ca03cb11-0e22-42e4-bb57-2d2f082d977b" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">Activision Blizzard acquisition</a> (although this isn't just a gaming company, so it's perhaps an unfair comparison).</p><p>The deal will include not only Warner Bros' movie and TV divisions (as well as streaming service HBO Max and the HBO channel in general), but also the gaming wing of the company, which owns major IPs like <em>Harry Potter</em>, <em>Mortal Kombat</em>, and the DC Comics universe.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Hey, <em>Mortal Kombat</em>! Netflix owns you now.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Warner Bros president David Zaslav says the deal combines "two of the greatest storytelling companies in the world", while Netflix co-CEO Ted Sarandos said the acquisition will help to "define the next century of storytelling". Lofty words.</p><p>Although Netflix's acquisition does include Warner Bros' gaming division, the streaming giant's approach to the world of gaming hasn't exactly been consistent recently.</p><p>Earlier this week, the company <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/spry-fox-netflix-cozy-grove" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="09f8e073-0fa3-4438-aa2d-4597fbdc1182" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">sold <em>Cozy Grove </em>developer Spry Fox</a> back to its original co-founders, and it also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/boss-fight-entertainment-netflix-shutdown" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="9711bede-314c-4ee1-8135-fe8d85504170" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">shut down <em>Squid Game: Unleashed </em>developer Boss Fight Entertainment</a> back in October.</p><p>That's after the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netflix-team-blue-shut-down-report" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c5effee2-78cf-4130-87e2-24dccd22c939" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">reported dissolution of the mooted "Team Blue"</a> all-star development studio at Netflix, which boasted alumni from franchises like <em>Overwatch </em>and <em>Halo</em>, among others.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Netflix's approach to gaming has been a little inconsistent recently.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Of course, Warner Bros itself hasn't had the best time in the gaming space recently; the company <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warner-bros-financials-2024-revenue-falls" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a1302fcc-0d84-48b6-aa21-411321f7b968" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">reported a "disappointing" 2024</a> back in February, following the failure of high-profile releases <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/suicide-squad-seasons-ending-in-january-offline-mode" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="387228fe-0515-4876-bcca-8168a7d98e52" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</em></a><em> </em>and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/multiversus-flop-warner-bros-100m" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="83496c9d-eadc-44fc-bcd2-1ae280734dcc" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>MultiVersus</em></a>.</p><p>Indeed, in January, then-gaming head David Haddad said he would <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warner-bros-games-david-haddad-stepping-down" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="62548f64-1034-4f8c-aa51-9f8c9d131494" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">step down from the company</a> after 12 years, although it hasn't all been bad for Warner Bros; wizarding RPG <em>Hogwarts Legacy </em>represents a major hit for the studio, having <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hogwarts-legacy-sales-30m" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c84f603f-f074-4e42-8fa2-7ec0db96c201" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">sold 30 million copies at last count</a>.</p><p>We'll have to wait and see whether Netflix's acquisition of Warner Bros represents any sort of major policy shift for either company. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netflix-warner-bros-acquisition]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Pushes PlayStation 5 Pro at Its Black Friday Low While Xbox Series Consoles Stay Full Price]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sony-pushes-playstation-5-pro-at-its-black-friday-low-while-xbox-series-consoles-stay-full-price-2000650666</link>
            <guid>1374445</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>We’re now a full week out from Black Friday, but it looks like someone forgot to tell Sony. Amazon has the PlayStation 5 Pro on sale for $101 off. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6100/">This latest model of the console has recently been priced as high as $750, but for the holiday season, you can grab the system of just $649.</a></p>
<h2>The PS5 Has No Games</h2>
<p data-start="136" data-end="775">Alrighty, we all love to go online and make jokes. The recurring meme around the PS5 is that the system “has no games.” It’s become a tired bit at this point. When you step back from the jokes and actually look at what the console has to offer several years into its lifespan, the idea that the PS5 is starving for content just doesn’t hold up. While it would have been nice to have a more exclusives, the current library is anything but empty.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6100/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The PS5 Has Tons of Games</h2>
<p data-start="777" data-end="1567">A standout title of this generation is Ghost of Yōtei. This visually striking and mechanically tight action game that showcases the PS5’s graphical and performance capabilities better than anything in its wake. Then there’s Returnal, a fast-paced third-person shooter with roguelike elements that blends frenetic combat with an eerie atmosphere reminiscent of classic Metroid titles. It’s challenging, stylish, and moody. Gotta love it. And of course, Astro Bot marks a triumphant return to the 3D mascot platformer, a genre we’ve been missing for far too long. This game is a charming, heartfelt celebration of PlayStation’s history, packed with creativity from start to finish. The game’s quality and infectious fun earned it the title of 2024’s <em data-start="1508" data-end="1526">Game of the Year</em> at The Game Awards—well-deserved.</p>


<p data-start="1569" data-end="2375">If you happened to skip the PlayStation 4 generation entirely, the PS5 becomes an even more enticing system. You’ll find a treasure trove of beloved titles waiting to be experienced for the first time, with some receiving enhancements specifically for Sony’s latest console. Games like The Last of Us Part I and The Last of Us Part II continue to dominate discussions about storytelling in video games. The first entry is widely regarded as one of the strongest narratives the medium has ever produced, while the second remains divisive—but passionately defended by many fans who appreciate its bold thematic choices. Regardless of where you ultimately land, both games offer emotionally charged journeys through a post-apocalyptic world that became iconic enough to inspire a major HBO adaptation. Worth checking out at the very least.</p>
<p data-start="2377" data-end="2801">For players who want access to a large back catalog without purchasing every title individually, PlayStation Plus Premium is an excellent gateway. The subscription grants access to hundreds of games spanning multiple PlayStation generations. You can dive into acclaimed modern titles like Control, Kingdom Hearts III, and Final Fantasy VII Remake, as well as older classics that shaped the platform’s legacy.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6100/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sony-pushes-playstation-5-pro-at-its-black-friday-low-while-xbox-series-consoles-stay-full-price-2000650666]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>