<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 15:08:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Man's Sky Relics Update Lets You Assemble Your Very Own Fossils]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/no-mans-sky-relics-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-mans-sky-relics-update-lets-you-assemble-your-very-own-fossils.1145340/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/no-mans-sky-relics-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hello Games has released another new&nbsp;<em>No Man's Sky&nbsp;</em>update, and this one's all about the past; you'll be unearthing bones, assembling fossils, and doing battle with giant stone guardians.</p>

<p>The Relics update follows on from previous updates like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/no-mans-sky-worlds-part-2-update" rel="nofollow">Worlds</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/no-mans-sky-orbital-update" rel="nofollow">Orbital</a>, and like those updates, this one's pretty substantial. Its main addition is the ability to "design and assemble complete skeletons from your collection of ancient bones".</p>

<p>According to Hello Games, you'll be able to "imagine how ancient alien creatures might have looked, and re-assemble their bodies from their fossilized remains". There will also be "millions of possibilities for unique species" that you can assemble.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/no-mans-sky-relics-update-bones.jpg?itok=WZDhNdgK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/no-mans-sky-relics-update-bones.jpg?itok=TEu05Kcn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>No Man's Sky</em>'s Relics update is all about fossils.</figcaption></figure><p>While you're looking for the bones you'll use to reassemble these fossils, however, you'll need to contend with new stone guardian enemies, which "slumber by planetary fossil beds" and defend them from enterprising players.</p>

<p>A new Expedition will also see you signing up with the Galactic Paleology Society to "recreate ancient lifeforms and uncover secrets". If you've been waiting for a chance to discover the kind of creatures that inhabited&nbsp;<em>No Man's Sky</em>'s countless planets in the past, this update is for you.</p>

<p>Once you've assembled fossil exhibits, you can then visit Fossil Collectors aboard Space Stations in order to sell your creations or trade bones for other fossils.</p>

<p>Of course, this being a&nbsp;<em>No Man's Sky&nbsp;</em>update, you will also find tons of other new features and things to look forward to. You can read the update's full patch notes, as well as a rundown of its more significant features, <a href="https://www.nomanssky.com/relics-update/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right here</a>.</p>




<p>The Relics update continues Hello Games' quest to turn&nbsp;<em>No Man's Sky&nbsp;</em>into the most comprehensive space survival sim ever, and it's admirable just how focused on the game's ongoing development the studio still is all these years later.</p>

<p><em>No Man's Sky&nbsp;</em>is available right now for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/275850/No_Mans_Sky/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/no-mans-sky/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/no-mans-sky/BQVQTL3PCH05" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/no-mans-sky-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>. The Relics update is out now.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo’s next Direct is about Switch 1 games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/636324/nintendo-switch-direct-march-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo%E2%80%99s-next-direct-is-about-switch-1-games.1145334/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/636324/nintendo-switch-direct-march-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news">News</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>“There will be no updates about Nintendo Switch 2 during this presentation,” the company says.</p></div></div><div><div><p>“There will be no updates about Nintendo Switch 2 during this presentation,” the company says.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-03-26T14:15:20+00:00">Mar 26, 2025, 2:15 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-webster">Andrew Webster</a> <span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>While the games industry patiently waits for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/606504/nintendo-switch-2-direct-new-time">the proper reveal of the Switch 2 on April 2nd</a>, Nintendo isn’t quite done with its current console. The company <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1904896350853960065">announced</a> that it will be holding a Nintendo Direct on March 27th at 10AM ET, which will feature “around 30 minutes” of news about upcoming Switch games. Notably, Nintendo says that “there will be no updates about Nintendo Switch 2 during this presentation.”</p><p>With the launch of <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/629964/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-review-nintendo-switch">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition</a></em> last week, there aren’t a lot of first-party games currently on the Switch calendar. But there are still some notable titles in the works including the long-in-development <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/23768041/metroid-prime-4-nintendo-direct-trailer">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a></em> and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/618705/pokemon-legends-z-a-chikorita-tepig-totodile-battles">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a></em>. It’s also possible we’ll see a few more remasters for the Switch, like the much-rumored Switch version of <em>The Legend of Zelda: The Wind Waker</em>.</p><div><p>Given that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24343666/nintendo-switch-2-cartridge-backwards-compatibility">backwards compatibility has been confirmed for the Switch 2</a>, whatever Nintendo does announce tomorrow will also be good news for its upcoming platform.</p></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Installer</h2><p><span>A weekly newsletter by David Pierce designed to tell you everything you need to download, watch, read, listen to, and explore that fits in The Verge’s universe.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Leaker Confirms Mortal Kombat Content is Finally Koming to Fortnite]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leaker-confirms-mortal-kombat-content-is-finally-koming-to-fortnite/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-leaker-confirms-mortal-kombat-content-is-finally-koming-to-fortnite.1145319/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leaker-confirms-mortal-kombat-content-is-finally-koming-to-fortnite/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-97384">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>We’ve heard about Mortal Kombat content heading to Fortnite already. However, a new leak has pulled back the bloody curtain to reveal that March 28 potentially brings emotes, pickaxes, and skins to finish us (or anyone).</p>



<p>There was a time when I used to be shocked by Fortnite’s collaborations. It went out the window quickly once the likes of Kratos and Halo started dropping into Tilted Towers. Now, anyone who’s anyone can make an appearance—check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sabrina-carpenter-might-be-the-next-playable-fortnite-character/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sabrina Carpenter</a> dialog if you don’t believe me. </p>



<p>But there’s something surreal about the brutal nature of Mortal Kombat entering a new realm. Alas, after initial talk of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-mortal-kombat-mythics/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mortal Kombat content turning up for a fight in Fortnite</a>, it’s reportedly the case.</p>



<h2 id="h-fortnite-amp-mortal-kombat-crossover-content-reportedly-releases-march-28">Fortnite &amp; Mortal Kombat Crossover Content Reportedly Releases March 28</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Get over here, Fortnite. Credit to NetherRealm</figcaption></figure>



<p>Renowned leaker <a href="https://x.com/SpushFNBR" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SpushFNBR</a> has dropped a finishing blow on the MK and Fortnite conversation. They posted to their official X channel about the nature of the content coming to the battle royale shooter.</p>



<p>They provided a bullet-point list outlining some of the key inclusions:</p>



<ul>
<li>Scorpion (MK3) Skin: 1.500 vbucks</li>



<li>Kitana (MK3) Skin: 1500 vbucks</li>



<li>Raiden (MK3) Skin: 1500 vbucks</li>



<li>Scorpion’s Flame Skull backbling: 800 bucks</li>



<li>Raiden’s Amulet backbling: 400 vbucks#</li>



<li>Raiden’s Staff pickaxe: 800 bucks </li>



<li>Scorpion’s Katana Duo pickaxe: included with the backbling</li>



<li>Kitana’s Steel Fan pickaxe: 800 bucks</li>



<li>Kitana’s Fan Bear: included with the pickaxe</li>



<li>Kitana’s Fan Fado emote: 300 bucks</li>



<li>FLAWLESS VICTORY emote: 300 bucks</li>



<li>Toasty! emote: 300 bucks</li>



<li>Test your strength emote: 300 bucks</li>



<li>Guiding Staff Mark emote: 300 bucks</li>



<li>Raiden’s Victory emote: 300 bucks</li>
</ul>



<p>They finish by saying to expect the items on <strong>March 28</strong>. You can check out the full message here.</p>



<div><article><p><span>FORTNITE X CLASSIC KOMBAT (LOT OF COSMETICS!)

Scorpion (MK3) Skin: 1.500 vbucks

Kitana (MK3) Skin: 1500 vbucks

Raiden (MK3) Skin: 1500 vbucks

Scorpion’s Flame Skull backbling: 800 vbucks

Raiden’s Amulet backbling: 400 vbucks

Raiden’s Staff pickaxe: 800 vbucks

Scorpion’s</span></p></article></div>



<p>This may be the beginning of a fun and fatal partnership. Take the leaks with the usual punch of salt, but there’s every chance you can start preparing your best kombos to drop onto unsuspecting Fortnite players.</p>



<p>The Mortal Kombat collab isn’t the only rumored to be in the works: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-dragon-ball-daima-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Ball Daima</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-getting-a-kendrick-lamar-emote-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kendrick Lamar</a> might be boarding the bus soon enough.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-store-spring-sale-features-over-4000-games-on-sale/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-store-spring-sale-features-over-4000-games-on-sale/">
                                PlayStation Store Spring Sale Features Over 4,000 Games On Sale                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sony has launched the PlayStation Store Spring Sale featuring thousands of games up to 75% off. Check out some of the best deals, now.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-launches-new-community-digest-initiative-to-encourage-player-feedback/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-launches-new-community-digest-initiative-to-encourage-player-feedback/">
                                Escape From Tarkov Launches New Community Digest Initiative to Encourage Player Feedback                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Battlestate Games is looking to step up player feedback for Escape From Tarkov through its new monthly Community Digest feature.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-dragon-ball-daima-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-dragon-ball-daima-its-claimed/">
                                Fortnite is Collaborating with Dragon Ball Daima, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim states that Fortnite is collaborating with Dragon Ball again, but this time with the Daima series. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-confirmed-for-march-27/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-confirmed-for-march-27/">
                                Nintendo Direct Confirmed For March 27                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Nintendo has confirmed its next Nintendo Direct event will take place on March 27, and feature 30 minutes of updates.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RailGods of Hysterra launches in Early Access for PC on April 23]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/railgods-of-hysterra-launches-in-early-access-for-pc-on-april-23</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/railgods-of-hysterra-launches-in-early-access-for-pc-on-april-23.1145316/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/railgods-of-hysterra-launches-in-early-access-for-pc-on-april-23<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Full release to follow on PlayStation 5 and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Cooperative base-building survival <a title="Genres > Action [2,598 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > RailGods of Hysterra [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/railgods-of-hysterra">RailGods of Hysterra</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,717 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3201910/RailGods_of_Hysterra/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on April 23, publisher <a title="Companies > Digital Vortex" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/digital-vortex">Digital Vortex</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Troglobytes Games [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/troglobytes-games">Troglobytes Games</a> announced. A full release will follow for PlayStation 5 and PC. It will support English, French, Italian, German, Spanish (Spain), Portuguese (Brazil), Polish, Turkish, Russian, Japanese, Korean, and Simplified Chinese language options. <span id="more-952436"></span></p><p>“To fans of cosmic <a title="Genres > Horror [584 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a>, <a title="Genres > Survival [396 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival games</a>, and those who just love trains, we’re happy to shout ‘ALL ABOARD!,'” said Digital Vortex CEO and co-founder Alex Izotov in a press release. “This is an <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,149 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> we’ve been working on for a long time, and your feedback will be instrumental in shaping <em>RailGods of Hysterra</em> into its final form.”</p><p>Troglobytes Games CEO and lead designer Saverio Caporusso added, “We at Troglobytes are thrilled to invite all players to get on board the RailGod and wander through the Lovecraftian world we crafted with so much love and passion! See you all in Hysterra, and remember: Ph’nglui mglw’nafh Cthulhu R’lyeh wgah’nagl fhtagn!”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Digital Vortex:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Venture forth alone or with up to four friends into a world of waking nightmares, where the Old Gods of H.P. Lovecraft’s Cthulhu Mythos emerged victorious, twisting the earth and its inhabitants into unspeakable horrors. Defy their might by forging a bond with a powerful RailGod, an ancient abomination from beyond the stars fused with a mighty locomotive.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Board the train and expand it with custom cars for storage, loot, and workbenches. Navigate shifting hellscapes armed with axes, firearms, and spells, battling eldritch horrors and fanatical cultists—or capture them to feed the wheeled monstrosity. Seek the RailGod’s pounding heart to purge the creeping madness and unlock devastating GodKeeper abilities.</p><p>Resist mental torment while foraging for new materials and clues, then return to the RailGod to purge the mind of unearthly visions, develop new skills, and gear up for the next adventure. While the journey is long, this rolling base of operations is never far away – but remember, it always needs to feed… and it has a taste for flesh.</p><p><strong>What’s New in Early Access</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Improved Ranged Combat</strong> – <a title="Companies > Enhance [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>d targeting, projectile mechanics, and responsiveness.</li><li><strong>Inventory Filters and Optimization</strong> – Streamlined item <a title="Genres > Management [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> for a better user experience.</li><li><strong>Polished Combat Feedback</strong> – More impactful hit reactions, animations, and combat feel.</li><li><strong>Madness Level Gameplay</strong> – Expanded mechanics tied to the Madness system, adding new strategic elements.</li><li><strong>Connected Chests</strong> – Improved resource management by linking storage across carriages.</li><li><strong>Corrupted RailGod Gameplay</strong> – New mechanics and interactions with a corrupted version of the RailGod.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="RailGods of Hysterra - Early Access Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EU0wo0LRGTk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moroi launches April 30]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/moroi-launches-april-30</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/moroi-launches-april-30.1145310/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/moroi-launches-april-30<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Dark fantasy hack-and-slash action adventure game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Dark fantasy hack-and-slash <a title="Genres > Action [2,598 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,149 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Moroi [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/moroi">Moroi</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,717 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2518410/Moroi/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on April 30 for $19.99, publisher <a title="Companies > Good Shepherd Entertainment [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/devolver-digital/good-shepherd-entertainment">Good Shepherd Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Violet Saint [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/violet-saint">Violet Saint</a> announced. <span id="more-952626"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2518410/Moroi/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Moroi</em> is set within the Cosmic Engine, a personalized hellscape designed to distort any semblance of normalcy. Truth is an illusion, paranoia is constant, and your humanity is an oddity.</p><p>You awake to find yourself a prisoner within a living nightmare. Your name, your past: gone, but not the record of your misdeeds. Your <a title="Companies > crim [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">crim</a>es: beyond comprehension. Your conviction: incontestable. Your sentence: eternal. The need to escape and set things right: undeniable.</p><p>Fight your way out of a living, twisting labyrinth. Hone your skills as you take on dynamic combat encounters and absurd puzzles. Meet the Cosmic Engine’s most disturbing and grotesque inhabitants, all with unique and nonsensical personalities, who are just as likely to aid in your quest as they are to deceive you.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Escape means freedom, and in freedom, the truth.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Dark Fantasy Adventure</strong> – Descend through the surreal, twisting Spire as you recover from amnesia and slowly discover the morbid truth about your past and your hostile surroundings. Cling to your sanity as the very fabric of reality is unraveled before your eyes.</li><li><strong>Swiss Army <a title="Genres > Hack-and-Slash [53 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/hack-and-slash">Hack-and-Slash</a></strong> – Take on the army of undead with an arsenal of unorthodox weapons and accessories. You may prefer the quick slices of the Chainsword for large hordes of enemies while reserving the devastating blows of the Power Hammer for boss fights. Or go all-out and replace your entire arm with a fully functioning cannon. Mix and match to find the build that best suits your playstyle.</li><li><strong>Puzzling Paranoia</strong> – Test your resolve with a myriad of environmental and logic puzzles. In a world devoid of sense and reason, you’ll have to stoop to your lowest if it means moving forward. Solve puzzles by drinking blood, forcing regurgitation, and digging through viscera. Fun.</li><li><strong>Will the Madness Ever End?</strong> – Designed especially to torment you, the Cosmic Engine will stop at nothing to keep you contained. Several playthroughs of <em>Moroi</em> will be required to experience all the game has to offer, from subtle changes within the story to the multiple fate-changing endings.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Moroi - Official Release Date Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jSsL82tpsTM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Season 3 Release Date Moved Up, Warzone Going Offline, And Everyone Gets Free Gun]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-season-3-release-date-moved-up-warzone-going-offline-and-everyone-gets-free-gun/1100-6530375/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-season-3-release-date-moved-up-warzone-going-offline-and-everyone-gets-free-gun.1145301/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-season-3-release-date-moved-up-warzone-going-offline-and-everyone-gets-free-gun/1100-6530375/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530375">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Activision has announced that Call of Duty's big Season 3 update has brought forward its release date, while the studio has confirmed that Warzone will go offline for 24 hours prior to the return of Verdansk.</p><p>Season 3 was previously announced to kick off on April 3, but now it's starting on April 2, Activision revealed in a video podcast today (below). There will be a free 24-hour Black Ops 6 trial available at this time.</p><p>Additionally, Activision confirmed that Warzone will go offline for a period of 24 hours leading to the highly anticipated release of Warzone's OG map, Verdansk, on April 3. As a special bonus, everyone who simply opens the Warzone menu during the 24 hours that Warzone is offline will receive the Kilo weapon for free.</p><p>More specifically, Activision said players who have Warzone currently downloaded can click on the Warzone tile while the game is offline to receive the weapon. Anyone who doesn't have Warzone downloaded should do that now or soon if they want the free Kilo weapon when Verdansk launches.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rKCg90ZlZJs" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rKCg90ZlZJs" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Call of Duty seems to be banking on nostalgia to revive Warzone's player count. A recent insider report said if the arrival of Verdansk fails to retain existing players and/or bring back lapsed players, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2026-could-drop-last-gen-systems-and-make-other-big-changes-report/1100-6529841/" data-ref-id="1100-6529841">there will be no "Warzone 3."</a> It's not clear what this means, though.</p><p>Beyond Warzone, a new Call of Duty game is expected to release in 2025, and it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/" data-ref-id="1100-6529073">could be a Black Ops 2 sequel</a>. It'll face stiff competition in the market, as Rockstar's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> is coming this fall.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch-Focused Nintendo Direct Show Revealed for Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-march-2025-switch-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-focused-nintendo-direct-show-revealed-for-tomorrow.1145265/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-march-2025-switch-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo has announced a brand new Nintendo Direct presentation that's set to bring some more information about upcoming Switch titles tomorrow, but you should temper your expectations.</p>

<p>Per a <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1904896350853960065" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">new post</a> on social media platform X, tomorrow's Nintendo Direct will take place at 7am Pacific (that's 10am Eastern and 2pm GMT), and will feature "around 30 minutes" of info about "upcoming games for Nintendo Switch".</p>

<p>However, Nintendo swiftly clarifies that there won't be any information about the Switch 2 during tomorrow's Direct. If you want that, you'll have to tune in to the Direct <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-officially-announced" rel="nofollow">that will air next Wednesday</a>&nbsp;at 6am Pacific (and thanks to time zone shenanigans, that will also be around 2pm GMT).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-direct-march-2025-announcement.jpg?itok=cLYZaWsX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-direct-march-2025-announcement.jpg?itok=AtGCiPhN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Will we get more&nbsp;<em>Metroid Prime 4&nbsp;</em>info during tomorrow's Direct?</figcaption></figure><p>As for what games we're likely to see during tomorrow's Nintendo Direct, there's a decent chance we'll be learning more about&nbsp;<em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</em>, which was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/metroid-prime-4-beyond-2025" rel="nofollow">unveiled in full</a> during Nintendo's summer gaming show last year.</p>

<p>We still don't have a specific release date beyond (no pun intended) 2025 for&nbsp;<em>Metroid Prime 4</em>, so hopefully, we'll get to learn exactly when we can play Samus' latest adventure. Of course, there's also a chance we'll learn it's coming to Switch 2 as well during next week's show.</p>

<p>A release date for&nbsp;<em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A&nbsp;</em>doesn't seem especially likely given <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-presents-february-2025-all-reveals-and-announcements" rel="nofollow">how recent its first gameplay reveal was</a>, but hey, I can't deny it's on my wishlist, so let's hope we get some more info about that one too.</p>

<p>Obviously, no gaming show, whether it's a Nintendo Direct, a State of Play, or an Xbox Developer Direct, is complete without a mention of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/hollow-knight-silksong" rel="nofollow"><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em></a>. Will we get a release date for that tomorrow? It's highly unlikely, but a man can dream.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-direct-march-2025-announcement.jpg?itok=8E1GLPRL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-direct-march-2025-announcement.jpg?itok=cxJUgspm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A&nbsp;</em>is another of Nintendo's upcoming Switch games.</figcaption></figure><p>Whatever we're going to see during tomorrow's Nintendo Direct show, you'll be able to watch it via Nintendo's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/9OqoRxXUjGA" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">YouTube channel</a> at 7am Pacific/10am Eastern/2pm GMT.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Man’s Sky gets prehistoric with Relics expansion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/635890/no-mans-sky-relics-update-archaeology</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-man%E2%80%99s-sky-gets-prehistoric-with-relics-expansion.1145262/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/635890/no-mans-sky-relics-update-archaeology<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-webster">Andrew Webster</a> <span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The latest update for <em>No Man’s Sky</em> is going back in time. Called <a href="https://www.nomanssky.com/relics-update/">Relics</a>, the expansion launches today and introduces paleontology and archaeology elements to the sci-fi exploration game; players can now unearth the bones of alien creatures, piece them together, and even erect museums.</p><p>Perhaps most interesting is that players will be able to assemble the ancient creatures however they’d like. Here’s how developer Hello Games explains it:</p><div><blockquote><p>There is a truly huge variety of procedural prehistoric bones, in all shapes and sizes, to excavate and collect. It’s up to you how you reassemble them and there’s a lot of fun to be had building ever-more outrageous skeletons to put on display in your bases-turned-museums or share with your fellow Travellers.</p><p>Fossils out there to be discovered vary hugely in rarity, so you never quite know what you’re going to unearth. There’s a real buzz when you find something truly rare. The most uncommon finds hold huge value. For those trying desperately to finish their collection, we introduced a specialist who can be bartered with at the Space Station.</p></blockquote></div><p>Naturally, since this is <em>No Man’s Sky</em>, there’s also an element of danger. Certain bones and underground treasures will be guarded by golem-like creatures and a giant new type of worm.</p><div><p>As with all of the game’s major updates, Relics is free to download, and it joins an increasingly massive list of new content for the game since its launch in 2016. Most recently, that has included <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/17/24200072/no-mans-sky-next-update-worlds-part-1">big changes to the game’s graphics</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/599537/no-mans-sky-worlds-2-update">the addition of trillions of new planets</a>, and just as important: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/4/24234948/no-mans-fly-fishing">fishing</a>.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Store Spring Sale Features Over 4,000 Games On Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-store-spring-sale-features-over-4000-games-on-sale/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-store-spring-sale-features-over-4-000-games-on-sale.1145250/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-store-spring-sale-features-over-4000-games-on-sale/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-97355">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Sony has announced the start of its PlayStation Store spring sale, and with it comes over 4,000 games PlayStation owners can save on. Players who have been waiting on buying a specific game can save up to 75% on select titles and various add-ons. </p>



<p>Some of the games on sale include Hogwarts Legacy at 75% off, Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 at 35% off, Silent Hill 2: Deluxe Edition at 35%, and more. </p>



<p>You can check out the full list of games on sale for yourself via the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/pages/SpringSale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlayStation Store</a>. If you are looking for a specific game, check out some of the biggest sales below to see if there’s any that stand out to you.</p>



<p>The PlayStation Store Spring Sale runs through April 9.</p>



<h2 id="h-playstation-store-spring-sale-games">PlayStation Store Spring Sale Games</h2>



<p>With thousands of games to choose from, it could be hard to find the best deals. To help, we’ve put together a list of just some of the biggest discounts and latest games to get a sale price. The games are in no particular order.</p>



<ul>
<li>Hogwarts Legacy – 35% off – $17.49 (PS5), $14.99 (PS4)</li>



<li>Silent Hill 2 Deluxe Edition – 35% off – $51.99</li>



<li>Sniper Elite – Resistance: 20% off – $47.99</li>



<li>Helldivers 2 – 20% off – $31.99</li>



<li>Undisputed – 25% off – $44.99</li>



<li>The Crew Motorfest – 70% off – $17.99</li>



<li>Star Wars Outlaws – 50% off – $34.99</li>



<li>Mortal Kombat 1 – 67% off – $16.49</li>



<li>Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora – 67% off – $23.09</li>



<li>Hell Let Loose – 50% off – $24.99</li>



<li>Grand Theft Auto Trilogy – 60% off – $23.99</li>



<li>Dead by Daylight – 60% off  – $11.99</li>
</ul>



<p>Do any of the listed games stand out to you? Are there any not listed that you picked up? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our exclusive on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-launch-plans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">current plans for games on the Nintendo Switch 2</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-launches-new-community-digest-initiative-to-encourage-player-feedback/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-launches-new-community-digest-initiative-to-encourage-player-feedback/">
                                Escape From Tarkov Launches New Community Digest Initiative to Encourage Player Feedback                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Battlestate Games is looking to step up player feedback for Escape From Tarkov through its new monthly Community Digest feature.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-dragon-ball-daima-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-dragon-ball-daima-its-claimed/">
                                Fortnite is Collaborating with Dragon Ball Daima, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim states that Fortnite is collaborating with Dragon Ball again, but this time with the Daima series. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-confirmed-for-march-27/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-confirmed-for-march-27/">
                                Nintendo Direct Confirmed For March 27                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Nintendo has confirmed its next Nintendo Direct event will take place on March 27, and feature 30 minutes of updates.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-update-1-57-adds-three-new-cars-world-circuits/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-update-1-57-adds-three-new-cars-world-circuits/">
                                Gran Turismo 7 Update 1.57 Adds Three New Cars, World Circuits                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Polyphony Digital have announced Grand Turismo 7’s Update 1.57 is available for all players, including new cars, circuits, and more.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite is Collaborating with Dragon Ball Daima, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-dragon-ball-daima-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-dragon-ball-daima-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1145244/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-dragon-ball-daima-its-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Fortnite might have another Dragon Ball collaboration in the works, and this time, it’s with the latest Daima series.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As revealed by <a href="https://x.com/Loolo_WRLD/status/1904609271561805956" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Loolo_WRLD</a> on X (via <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/fortnite-reportedly-getting-dragon-ball-daima-skins-collaboration-crossover-item-shop-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TheGamer</a>), “an ID related to a new Dragon Ball wave” has been spotted in the Fortnite files, and it seems it could hint at new Daima skins. Reliable leaker Spheshal_Nick has added more information, stating that he has also recently heard about this collaboration. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Dragon Ball Daima is the latest addition to the popular anime franchise, and players would love to see characters from the series come to Fortnite Island. Daima features some of the most hyped characters of the series, such as Vegeta Super Saiyan 3 and Goku Super Saiyan 4. It also has new fan-favourite characters like Glorio, the Tamagamis, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fortnite has already collaborated with Dragon Ball in the past, with skins for Goku, Vegeta, Gohan, Beerus, Goku Black, Piccolo, Cell, Bulma, Trunks, Android 17, Android 18 and Frieza present in the game. These characters also come with their own set of accessories and emotes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Along with the cosmetics, Fortnite also had notable additions to gameplay for the Dragon Ball collaborations, including the Kamehameha and Nimbus Cloud (Kintoun) items in Battle Royale. They had also introduced a Dragon Ball Adventure Island where players could explore iconic locations from the series. It will be interesting to see if Fortnite receives additional themed gameplay for the alleged Daima collab.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sabrina-carpenter-might-be-the-next-playable-fortnite-character/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sabrina Carpenter</a> could be the next Fortnite Festival Icon. Also, their Ballistic Game Mode has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-ballistic-is-finally-getting-a-new-map-hammer-fall/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">finally received a new map</a>. What are your thoughts on Fortnite collaborating with Dragon Ball Daima?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-4-will-not-release-earlier-than-2027/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Witcher 4 not releasing before 2027</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naughty Dog’s Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet Reportedly Won’t Make 2026, Neil Druckmann Tells IGN ‘We Are Playing It at the Office and It's Incred]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/naughty-dogs-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-reportedly-wont-make-2026-neil-druckmann-tells-ign-we-are-playing-it-at-the-office-and-its-incredible</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/naughty-dog%E2%80%99s-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-reportedly-won%E2%80%99t-make-2026-neil-druckmann-tells-ign-%E2%80%98we-are-playing-it-at-the-office-and-its-incred.1145238/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/naughty-dogs-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-reportedly-wont-make-2026-neil-druckmann-tells-ign-we-are-playing-it-at-the-office-and-its-incredible<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">With <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/could-the-witcher-4-be-targeting-the-ps6-and-next-gen-xbox-given-it-wont-be-out-until-2027-at-the-earliest">the wait for The Witcher 4 set to head into 2027</a>, it’s a similar story for Naughty Dog’s recently announced <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bloomberg reporter Jason Schreier took to <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-studios-ot45-game-of-the-year-edition.1093518/page-284#post-137487981" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ResetEra</a> to say neither The Witcher 4 nor Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet will be out next year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That means like The Witcher 4, Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet will be released in 2027 at the earliest. And, like The Witcher 4, Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet will face questions around whether or not it’s targeting the PlayStation 5 or the inevitable PlayStation 6, or, perhaps most likely, is a cross-gen game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If Intergalactic heads straight to PS6, Naughty Dog faces the prospect of having skipped the PS5 generation in terms of brand new games. So far, the studio has released ports, remasters, and remakes on Sony’s current-gen console, including The Last of Us Part II, Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection, The Last of Us Part I, and The Last of Us Part II Remastered.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Naughty Dog revealed Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet at The Game Awards 2024. It features a star-studded cast that includes Tati Gabrielle from the Uncharted movie as protagonist Jordan A. Mun, and Kumail Nanjiani of Marvel's Eternals as a man called Colin Graves.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But fans have analysed the trailer, below, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/naughty-dog-fans-already-think-theyve-worked-out-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophets-cast">to piece together the rest of the cast</a>, and though it focuses on just a couple of characters, a photo of what appears to be a crew revealed even more.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this month, The Last of Us director Neil Druckmann <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-director-neil-druckmann-wants-naughty-dogs-new-game-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-to-make-you-feel-really-lost-and-confused">shared more details about <u>Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iJUab499PVA" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>interview</u></a> with Alex Garland, the writer of zombie movie 28 Days Later, Druckmann talked candidly about the development process, confirming Intergalactic had been in the works for four years already.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I joke about this with the team. We made a game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-last-of-us-2"><u>The Last of Us 2</u></a>, we made certain creative decisions that got us a lot of hate. A lot of people love it, but a lot of people hate that game," Druckmann said, to which Garland joked: "Who gives a shit?"</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Exactly," Druckmann added. "But the joke is like, you know what, let's do something that people won't care as much about — let's make a game about faith and religion."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet takes place in an alternate historical timeline and features a "pretty prominent religion," too, which has "changed and bastardized and evolved" over the years.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"This whole religion takes place on this one planet, and then at one point, all communication stops," Druckmann teased. "And you're playing a bounty hunter that's chasing her bounty, and she crash lands on this planet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"So many of the previous games we've done, there's always, like, an ally with you," he said. "I really want you to be lost in a place that you're really confused about what happened here, who are the people here, what was their history. And in order to get off this planet — again, no one has been heard from this planet for 600 years or so — if you ever have hoped to have a chance to get off, you have to figure out what happened here."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Assuming Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet releases in 2027, and taking into account Druckmann’s comment about it being in development for four years so far, by the time the game comes out it will have been in the works for six years.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a pretty long wait, but speaking to IGN on the red carpet ahead of The Last of Us Season 2 premiere, Druckmann said that Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet is not only playable right now, but “really good.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I will say we are playing it at the office and it's incredible,” Druckmann teased. “It's really good. I'm so excited to finally put gameplay out into the world and show people about it, because we just showed you the very, very, very tip on the iceberg. The game goes pretty deep beyond that.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Man’s Sky ‘Relics’ update now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/no-mans-sky-relics-update-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-man%E2%80%99s-sky-%E2%80%98relics%E2%80%99-update-now-available.1145235/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/no-mans-sky-relics-update-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Turn your hand to palaeontology.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Hello Games [82 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hello-games">Hello Games</a> has released the “Relics” (version 5.6) update for <em><a title="Games > No Man's Sky [75 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/no-mans-sky">No Man’s Sky</a></em>. <span id="more-952610"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the update, via its <a href="https://www.nomanssky.com/relics-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official website</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Relics: Introducing Update 5.6</strong></p><p>Turn your hand to palaeontology in update 5.6, Relics! Unearth hundreds of unique bones, assemble skeletons to design fossil exhibits, join the community on an expedition to recreate lost creatures, battle against gargantuan stone guardians, and more!</p><ul><li><strong>Design <a title="Companies > Creature [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/creature">Creature</a> Skeletons</strong> – Design and assemble complete skeletons from your collection of ancient bones. Imagine how ancient alien creatures might have looked, and re-assemble their bodies from their fossilized remains—with millions of possibilities for unique species.</li><li><strong>Reanimated Guardians</strong> – Hulking stone lifeforms slumber by planetary fossil beds, defending these ancient burial grounds from Travellers who would seek to disturb them…</li><li><strong>Collect a Huge Variety of Bones</strong> – Exhume a vast array of ancient bones, from ribcages plated to spiked, limbs dangling and grasping, skulls from warhounds, bogsnappers and titan worms, and an assortment of tails and tailbones—there are hundreds of unique fossilized parts to unearth.</li><li><strong>Relics Expedition</strong> – Sign up with the Galactic Palaeology Society and join the community on a journey to recreate ancient lifeforms and uncover secrets left undisturbed for millennia.</li><li><strong>Fossil Trading</strong> – Visit Fossil Collectors aboard Space Stations to sell your created fossil exhibits—or trade some of your bones for any of their broad selection of fossils. Haggle and experiment to find the best deal!</li><li><strong>Improved Abandoned Mode</strong> – Playing in an abandoned universe has been streamlined and enhanced. Derelict space stations now contain functional upgrade stations for the Exosuit, starship, and Multi-Tool, as well as salvage boxes containing valuable upgrades. Travellers can scavenge further technologies from planetary buried caches, and purple systems are automatically visible on the Galaxy map.</li><li><strong>Otherwordly Bone Creatures</strong> – On planets where ancient bones can be found, or within purple star systems, skeletal fauna have risen from their fossil beds to roam their planetary homes once more.</li><li><strong>Share Fossil Creations</strong> – Package assembled fossils into fused exhibits, conveniently stored in the Inventory. Reorganize your museum layout with ease, or gift your displays to other Travellers.</li><li><strong>Living Stone Hardpack</strong> – Participants in the Relics expedition can earn this unusual flight device, sculpted from the remains of sentient rock.</li><li><strong>Bone Cuisine</strong> – Prepare new bone-based recipes in the Nutrient Processor, to ingest for health and protective benefits, or to present to Iteration: Cronus for critique, judgement, and potential remuneration.</li><li><strong>Planetary Digsites</strong> – Visit roaming fossil collectors and harvest large bone caches at Palaeontological Digs, established upon many worlds across the galaxies.</li><li><strong>Living Stone Customization</strong> – Complete the Relics expedition to unlock a complete living stone appearance override. A powerful magnetic field runs through this ancient stone, turning lumpen rock into something almost alive.</li><li><strong>Skeletal Companion</strong> – The Relics expedition unlocks the exclusive living fossil companion: a loyal, fleshless creature of animated bone.</li><li><strong>Living Stone Sentries</strong> – Floating stone guardians protect fossil sites, hurling masses of rock and crystal at any who would seek to exhume their beds of ancient bones. Crafty and challenging opponents, these guardians will sometimes even resort to self-destruction to defend their territory.</li><li><strong>Colossal Stone Effigies</strong> – The crumbling ruins of relic worlds are watched over by monumental stone figures, vestiges of long-dead alien civilizations. These mysterious effigies appear dormant, their purpose lost to time.</li><li><strong>Titanic Boneworms</strong> – <a title="Companies > Rare [102 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/xbox-game-studios/rare">Rare</a> skeletal sandworms thunder through the dunes and darken the skies of some worlds, bringing even stranger variety to these titanic lifeforms.</li><li><strong>Precious Stone Relics</strong> – Bold explorers can steal the vigilant stones left by slumbering guardians. These rare relics are highly lucrative – but may provoke vengeance from the eye’s original owner…</li><li><strong>Decorate Freely with Bones</strong> – Enjoy complete decorative freedom with precision placement of individual bones. Design even more outlandish, biology-defying skeletons, or simply furnish habitable bases with skeletal decor.</li><li><strong>Basilisk Crown Staff</strong> – Travellers completing the Relics expedition will be rewarded with the exclusive Basilisk Crown staff, a fused pillar of bone and circuitry. Beware its gaze…</li><li><strong>Interplanetary Navigation</strong> – Pin celestial bodies to your starship’s navigational systems from the Discoveries screen, to help locate undiscovered planets within the solar system, or narrow down your search for rare planetary features such as ancient bones or dissonant worlds.</li></ul></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>And here are the full patch notes:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Collect and Display Skeletons</strong></p><ul><li>Planetary fossil beds now contain a vast array of specific bone formations.</li><li>Each of these bones can be placed as a decorative base part, either individually or mounted on a display plinth.</li><li>Larger display plinths allow a collection of bones to be reassembled into a complete skeleton, allowing the design and reassembly of ancient and extinct beings.</li><li>Completed displays can be packaged into an easily transportable module, allowing them to be re-deployed in other locations, traded with other players, or sold on the galactic market.</li><li>A new planetary dig-site building has been added, serving as a hub for interested fossil collectors.</li><li>The icon for planetary fossils has been improved.</li><li>A small tutorial mission has been added to guide new palaeontologists.</li><li>A new palaeontology section has been added to the guide.</li></ul><p><strong>Fossil Exchange</strong></p><ul><li>A fossil collector has been added to the Space Station.</li><li>Surplus fossils can be exchanged with the fossil collector, allowing players to target specific skeleton components for their designs.</li><li>The fossil collector will barter for items in their collection, allowing individual inventory items to be swapped.</li></ul><p><strong>Relics Expedition</strong></p><ul><li>Expedition Eighteen, Relics, will begin shortly and run for approximately six weeks.</li><li>Rewards include new posters, decals and titles; a living stone suit customization set; the unique Basilisk Crown staff; a mysterious skeletal companion; and the exclusive Living Stone jetpack.</li></ul><p><strong>Stone Guardians</strong></p><ul><li>Fossil beds are now watched over by a vigilant stone eye, ready to protect the bones from those who would exhume them.</li><li>Disturbing the vigilant eye may yield valuable rewards, but comes at the cost of awakening the guardians.</li><li>Two forms of stone guardian await—a huge living statue, and a whirling storm of re-animated rock.</li><li>Huge guardian statues have been added to relic worlds.</li></ul><p><strong>Skeletal Lifeforms</strong></p><ul><li>A new and highly rare skeletal lifeform has been added to some planets.</li><li>Some planets are now home to the elusive titanic bone-worm…</li></ul><p><strong>Quality of Life and User Interface</strong></p><ul><li>Planets in your current system can now be marked from the discovery page, adding a marker to the starship navigation systems.</li><li>Added an accessibility option to increase the contrast in mission-critical UI panels.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause the camera to move erratically back and forth while inside high-ceilinged rooms in player bases.</li><li>Nearby NPCs that have specific unseen interactions will now be highlighted with a marker.</li><li>Added a new water state for ocean worlds with significantly larger waves.</li><li>Various volumetric and other atmospheric effects no longer play on planets without an atmosphere.</li><li>Story details from the In Stellar Multitudes mission now appear in the <a title="Games > Journey Record [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/journey-record">Journey Record</a>s page in the catalogue.</li><li>Reduced the number of corrupt drones that attack player settlements.</li><li>The space station marker is now dynamically offset, preventing the marker from obscuring the station while at a distance.</li><li>Fixed a number of minor text issues in some extractor UIs.</li><li>Fixed a number of minor text and icon issues in shop interactions.</li><li>Fixed an issue that caused companions that were set to use no accessories to have a random accessory assigned after re-summoning them.</li><li>Fixed an issue that caused the starship to too-aggressively lock on to markers when engaging the pulse engine.</li><li>An organic version of the Teleport Receiver has been added for use in living starships.</li><li>Fixed an issue that caused the repair requirements for several living starship technologies to all be the same.</li><li>Lingering on-screen display messages that report pulse drive errors will now clear as soon as a successful pulse drive engagement is detected.</li></ul><p><strong>Save System</strong></p><ul><li>Significantly improved the compression used for saved games, improving filesizes and upload/download times for players in the cross-save beta.</li><li>Created a section for cross-save settings within the general Options menu.</li><li>Players in the cross-save beta are now alerted to situations where uploads are timing out, and can manually adjust how long the game will wait for a successful upload before detecting a timeout and cancelling.</li></ul><p><strong><a title="Genres > Cooking [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/cooking">Cooking</a></strong></p><ul><li>New fossil-related cooking recipes have been added.</li><li>Base storage container inventories are now accessible while cooking.</li><li>Fixed an issue that prevented access to the nutrient processor’s internal storage while on a freighter or the Exo-Skiff.</li><li>Fixed a number of issues while cooking the Exo-Skiff, including progress resetting or incorrect items appearing in various slots.</li><li>Cronos’ grill on the Space Anomaly can now be used by several players at once.</li><li>Fixed an issue that made it impossible to cook jellied eels.</li></ul><p><strong>Abandoned Mode Improvements</strong></p><ul><li>Multi-Tools found in abandoned mode are now always free, but start with damaged slots.</li><li>Settlement-related missions will no longer start in abandoned mode.</li><li>Abandoned space stations now have access to Exosuit, starship, and Multi-Tool upgrade stations.</li><li>Additional salvage boxes have been added around abandoned space stations containing valuable upgrades and inventory expansion modules.</li><li>Purple systems are now unlocked automatically in abandoned mode.</li><li>In abandoned mode, crashed freighter containers and other buried caches can now contain additional valuable upgrades.</li></ul><p><strong>Optimization</strong></p><ul><li>Introduced a number of optimizations to planetary prop rendering.</li><li>Introduced an optimization to dynamic physics groups.</li><li>Introduced a significant memory optimization for nav mesh generation.</li><li>Introduced a number of minor texture memory optimizations.</li><li>Introduced an optimization for loading large bases.</li><li>Introduced a number of optimizations for text display, particularly in the Journey Records pages.</li><li>Introduced an optimization to the various catalogue and guide pages.</li></ul><p><strong>Other Bug Fixes</strong></p><ul><li>Fixed a number of issues that could occur when warping on board another player’s freighter.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause water creatures to be generated for a planet that would never have deep enough water for those creatures to spawn.</li><li>Fixed a number of mission blockers in They Who Returned.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause some bases to become invisible when constructed at the water’s surface on ocean planets.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause <a title="Platforms > PC [22,717 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> players to appear jerky in cross-platform <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [468 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a>.</li><li>Fixed a rare issue that could cause players’ settings to reset in VR.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause NPCs to sink into the floor.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause a softlock when browsing the Exocraft inventory.</li><li>Fixed a rare hang on load when returning to a savegame that was saved while in an Exocraft after playing in multiplayer.</li><li>Fixed a rare crash related to camera shakes.</li><li>Fixed a memory-related crash on <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,135 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>.</li><li>Fixed a number of rare crashes related to mesh scaling.</li><li>Fixed a number of rare maths-related crashes.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause some planetary props to pop in.</li><li>Fixed a number of Mac-specific rendering issues.</li><li>Fixed a rare issue that could cause saves to reach a max size and stop saving on <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,837 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a>—saves can now expand as required.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause multiple ships to become docked to the same landing pad.</li><li>Improved the placement positioning of decorative base building props.</li><li>Fixed a number of text clipping issues in large popups.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause a teleport destination to have two copies of a mission marker added.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could make interactions difficult on freighters that were summoned a long way from the centre of the solar system.</li><li>Fixed a number of issues affecting markers and planet labels when entering atmosphere.</li><li>Fixed a rare issue that could cause empty systems to generate incorrect information about their potential Atlas Stations.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause the galaxy map to incorrectly choose a purple system as part of its path to a distant star when purple systems are not unlocked.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause players to start in a purple system when arriving in a new galaxy, when purple systems were not unlocked.</li><li>Fixed an issue that caused the water effects from the Nautilon submarine to remain in the world after summoning the sub to a new location.</li><li>Fixed an issue that prevented Exocraft laser effects from playing correctly in multiplayer.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause erratic torso movements in Sentinel mechs.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause the ship to hover as if above water when reloading on a planet.</li><li>Fixed a number of inconsistencies in creature descriptions, where creatures would be described as being from the wrong environment.</li><li>Fixed an incorrect texture being used for the Titan expedition in the expedition history screen.</li><li>Fixed a number of decals and posters from previous expeditions being missing from the catalogue.</li><li>Fixed an issue that caused a number of unusable and legacy items to be included in the catalogue.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>No Man’s Sky</em> is available now for PlayStation 5, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,843 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,873 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/275850/No_Mans_Sky/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/275850/No_Mans_Sky/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Store</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Relics (5.6) Update Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="No Man's Sky Relics Update Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B3TWSQHaIMw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[InZoi Devs Remove Denuvo, Say They're "Committed" To Mods]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/inzoi-devs-remove-denuvo-say-theyre-committed-to-mods/1100-6530374/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/inzoi-devs-remove-denuvo-say-theyre-committed-to-mods.1145232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/inzoi-devs-remove-denuvo-say-theyre-committed-to-mods/1100-6530374/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530374">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">InZoi is set to launch in early access tomorrow, and developer InZoi Studio is hoping its Sims-like life simulator can challenge EA's juggernaut right from the jump. After a controversy stirred regarding mods, however, one lead dev took to Steam to announce the removal of the DRM program Denuvo from the upcoming build, in a bid to quell disappointment.</p><p dir="ltr">In a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2456740/view/512953841353752633?l=english" rel="nofollow ">statement on InZoi's official Steam page</a>, game director and producer Hyungjun "Kjun" Kim confirmed that Denuvo will not be part of InZoi's early-access launch after "consulting with teams from around the world to make a thoughtful and informed decision." Kim says that the decision to use Denuvo was initially to prevent "illegal distribution," but that including the program would ultimately not serve the community at large.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4465832-inzoi.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4465832" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4465832-inzoi.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4465832"></a><figcaption>InZoi</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4465832-inzoi.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">"We understand that removing Denuvo increases the risk of the game being cracked and illegally distributed after release," Kim said in the statement. "At the same time, we believe it opens up a valuable opportunity: It allows InZoi to become more freely configurable--unlocking new ways for players to shape new experiences for other players. We believe enabling this freedom from the very beginning will lead to innovative and long-lasting enjoyment for the community."</p><p dir="ltr">Kim also apologized to the community for the controversy, saying they "regret the concern and confusion this has caused within the community, and we’re committed to rebuilding your trust as we move forward in developing the best possible experience." He also reiterated that the team is "committed to making InZoi a highly moddable game."</p><p dir="ltr">The change in direction comes after a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2456740/discussions/0/599648005874810809/">Steam community forum post</a> mentioned that mods for InZoi would only allow for cosmetic mods--skins, clothing, etc. Specifically, the game's terms of service said that "certain content provided by the Company includes elements that you are not permitted to modify or alter at your discretion" and that players are "prohibited from making any modifications, whether in whole or in part, to such content."</p><p>InZoi launches in early access March 27 on Steam. An <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/inzoi-price-and-update-roadmap-revealed-just-before-launch/1100-6530201/">InZoi Online Showcase livestream</a> aired last week, which showed the team's initial plans for the game, including a full roadmap of what's to expect in the coming weeks.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jack Black Reveals One Of His Most-Played Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/jack-black-reveals-one-of-his-most-played-games/1100-6530373/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jack-black-reveals-one-of-his-most-played-games.1145229/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/jack-black-reveals-one-of-his-most-played-games/1100-6530373/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530373">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Actor Jack Black is a big fan of video games, but what games specifically does he get immersed in? In an interview, the A Minecraft Movie star sang the praises of Rockstar Games' acclaimed 2018 game Red Dead Redemption II, saying he played the title for hundreds of hours during the pandemic.</p><p>"It was over pandemic times. I played Red Dead Redemption 2, and I lived in it," he told <a href="https://comicbook.com/interviews/news/minecraft-movie-jason-momoa-jack-black-gaming-history-interview/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ComicBook</a>. "It was not a game. It was like a way of life. I got 400 hours clocked, and it was a lot, and I don't regret any of it. It was so fun. It's beautiful out there, it's an incredible universe they created."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8B1EtVPBSMw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8B1EtVPBSMw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>A Minecraft Movie is just the latest video game film for Black, as he also played Bowser in The Super Mario Bros. Movie. In video games themselves, Black is perhaps best known for portraying Eddie Riggs in Brutal Legend.</p><p>Black appeared in the interview alongside his A Minecraft Movie co-star Jason Momoa, who said he had never heard of Red Dead Redemption 2; this elicited a shocked response from Black.</p><p>"Dude, you never heard of Rockstar Games? These guys are the artists. You have to play it; it'll change your life. If you play one game, that's the one," he said.</p><p>Asked about his own favorite games, Momoa said he chooses to generally "stay away" from games due to what he said was a "pretty addictive personality." He did say he enjoyed Capcom's popular Street Fighter series, saying Ryu and Blanka are his two favorite characters.</p><p>A Minecraft Movie releases in theaters on April 4. It's been a long time coming, as the film has been in the works for more than a decade, bouncing between directors like Rob McElhenney and Shawn Levy before finally finding Napoleon Dynamite's Jared Hess. In addition to Black and Momoa, the film stars Danielle Brooks, Emma Myers, and Sebastian Hansen.</p><p>It's not the only video game movie coming in April, as Sony's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/until-dawn-movie-gets-a-key-update-about-its-story/1100-6528665/" data-ref-id="1100-6528665">Until Dawn film arrives on April 25</a>. In the TV space, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/whos-who-in-the-last-of-us-season-2/2900-6361/" data-ref-id="2900-6361">HBO's The Last of Us Season 2 debuts on April 13.</a> As for Minecraft the game, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecrafts-vibrant-visuals-update-is-a-massive-step-forward-for-the-14-year-old-game/1100-6530266/" data-ref-id="1100-6530266">a major update is coming soon that vastly improves the visuals</a>, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecraft-2-dev-has-a-fantastic-response-when-asked-about-it/1100-6530307/" data-ref-id="1100-6530307">Minecraft 2 is not happening.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo announces surprise Direct, but it's not about Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-announces-surprise-direct-but-its-not-about-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-announces-surprise-direct-but-its-not-about-switch-2.1145226/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-announces-surprise-direct-but-its-not-about-switch-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Scheduled for this Thursday.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-OLED-Model.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nintendo</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nintendo will be hosting a Nintendo Direct presentation tomorrow, 27th March.</p>
<p>This Direct will focus on upcoming games for the original Nintendo Switch, and last for around half an hour.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Why the Switch 2 Needed the Steam Deck" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WBzuCVIuOtM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Why the Switch 2 Needed the Steam Deck</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WBzuCVIuOtM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WBzuCVIuOtM?autoplay=1" title="Why the Switch 2 Needed the Steam Deck">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Why the Switch 2 Needed the Steam Deck. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WBzuCVIuOtM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Again, this Direct will be focused on the OG Switch, and Nintendo has tempered expectations ahead of time. "There will be no updates about Nintendo Switch 2 during this presentation," the announcement post reads.</p>
<p>For those interested in tuning in, kick off will be at 2pm UK time. We here at Eurogamer will of course be watching along and keeping you abreast of the news as it happens. What are you hoping to see there?</p>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Tomorrow's presentation comes ahead of a dedicated Switch 2 Direct, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-announces-timing-of-its-dedicated-switch-2-direct">which is scheduled for 2nd April</a>.</p>
<p>While the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/its-official-nintendo-switch-2-revealed-after-months-of-waiting">Switch successor was officially revealed back in January after plenty of rumours and speculation</a>, Nintendo has still kept most details under wraps. This will change next week, though, with the upcoming showcase promising "a closer look at Nintendo Switch 2".</p>
<p>While that wording is still quite vague, from the earlier Switch 2 reveal we can presume we will hear more about the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-trailer-appears-to-confirm-joy-con-mouse-functionality">Joy-Con's apparent mouse functionality</a>, and maybe even discover what exactly that mysterious button on the right-hand Joy-Con does.</p>
<p>We should also hear more about the games that will be heading to Switch 2. The console's announcement teaser did give us a brief <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-announcement-reveals-new-mario-kart-game">glimpse of a new Mario Kart title</a>, complete with a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/donkey-kongs-new-look-in-switch-2-mario-kart-approved-by-former-rare-artist">fresh looking Donkey Kong</a>, but I am still hoping for more on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-prime-4">Metroid Prime 4</a>.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_0mRMF4x.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A report yesterday suggested <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-reportedly-has-three-phase-launch-plan-for-switch-2-games">Nintendo is going to implement a three-phase launch plan for its Switch 2 games</a>.</p>
<p>In addition to April's Direct, Nintendo has also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-announces-switch-2-public-hands-on-tour">confirmed it'll be holding a Switch 2 "world tour"</a> event, giving the public an opportunity to go hands-on with the console and, presumably, its launch line-up of games.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[War of the Visions: Final Fantasy Brave Exvius to Shut Down in May]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/war-of-visions-final-fantasy-brave-exvius-shutting-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/war-of-the-visions-final-fantasy-brave-exvius-to-shut-down-in-may.1145208/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/war-of-visions-final-fantasy-brave-exvius-shutting-down<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Square Enix has announced that mobile tactical RPG&nbsp;<em>War of the Visions: Final Fantasy Brave Exvius&nbsp;</em>will shut down in May.</p>

<p>In August last year, it was revealed that&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy Brave Exvius&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/final-fantasy-brave-exvius-shutting-down" rel="nofollow">would be ending service that October</a>, and now it's the turn of the&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy Tactics</em>-inspired strategy RPG spinoff to do the same, according to a <a href="https://wotvffbe.com/notice/index.html" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">new announcement</a> on the game's official website.</p>

<p>According to Square Enix, while the studio attempted to "provide an enjoyable gaming experience" for&nbsp;<em>War of the Visions</em>' players, it's become "difficult to maintain a satisfactory app experience", hence the game's impending shutdown.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/war-of-the-visions-final-fantasy-brave-exvius-shutting-down-gameplay.jpg?itok=GHBnxXib 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/war-of-the-visions-final-fantasy-brave-exvius-shutting-down-gameplay.jpg?itok=eU648NzN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>War of the Visions: Final Fantasy Brave Exvius&nbsp;</em>will be shutting down in May.</figcaption></figure><p>As of today, it's no longer possible to purchase&nbsp;<em>War of the Visions: Final Fantasy Brave Exvius</em>' Visiore currency from the game's shop, nor can you make any more Special Shop purchases.</p>

<p>Service will fully shut down on May 29th at 11:59PM Pacific, so you'll have until then to do whatever you need to do in&nbsp;<em>War of the Visions&nbsp;</em>before the game disappears forever. It doesn't sound like you'll be able to play any kind of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/animal-crossing-pocket-camp-offline-december" rel="nofollow"><em>Animal Crossing: Pocket Camp</em>-style offline version</a>, either.</p>

<p>If you've got Google Play Points you want to exchange for items in&nbsp;<em>War of the Visions</em>, you'll be able to do so until April 30th, but any Visiore you've already got can be used right up until the game's service comes to an end.</p>

<p>Just in case you're not familiar,&nbsp;<em>War of the Visions: Final Fantasy Brave Exvius&nbsp;</em>is a tactical RPG spinoff of mobile RPG&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy Brave Exvius</em>. It combines the strategic gameplay of games like&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy Tactics&nbsp;</em>with&nbsp;<em>Brave Exvius</em>' gacha mechanics and general free-to-play mobile trappings.</p>




<p>During its operation, the game crossed over with several major&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy&nbsp;</em>titles, including the likes of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/war-of-visions-final-fantasy-brave-exvius-reveals-final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade" rel="nofollow"><em>Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</em></a>,&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy X</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy V</em>.</p>

<p>You can still check out&nbsp;<em>War of the Visions: Final Fantasy Brave Exvius&nbsp;</em>for free right now on <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.square_enix.android_googleplay.WOTVffbeww&amp;hl=en_GB" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Android</a> and <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/final-fantasy-be-wotv/id1484937345" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">iOS</a>. The game will be available until May 29th (or May 30th, depending on your time zone).</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grit and Valor - 1949's real-time World War mech-stomping launches on Steam today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grit-and-valor-1949s-real-time-world-war-mech-stomping-launches-on-steam-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grit-and-valor-1949s-real-time-world-war-mech-stomping-launches-on-steam-today.1145205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grit-and-valor-1949s-real-time-world-war-mech-stomping-launches-on-steam-today<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>We already have Into The Breach at home</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_kUBpNsD.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Megabit Publishing</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Grit &amp; Valor – 1949 is the tale of an alternate timeline in which the Nazis got hold of mechs and promptly overran the British Isles. As Nic <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grit-and-valor-1949-is-a-real-time-into-the-breach-or-at-least-vaguely-similar-enough-that-i-can-squeeze-a-more-popular-game-in-this-headline">semi-alluded</a> last year, you could summarise the game itself as the product of a timeline in which the people behind <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/wolfenstein-the-new-order">Wolfenstein: The New Order</a> decided to make <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/into-the-breach">Into the Breach</a> instead. Except that it isn’t quite as deviously made, based on the demo, and it isn’t turn-based. Ah, I do kind of wish it was turn-based.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
Everything else here works for me, just about: the rustpunk stompiness of the mechs themselves; the rock-Patlabor-scissors relationships between those mechs and other units, spliced with questions of elevation and cover; the grid-based, rotating maps floating against sepia voids, with waves of fascist scum arriving by chopper; the chunky graphic novel storytelling and kaiju-grade bosses. I just wish it wasn’t a real-time game. Still, that’s an opening impression and in fairness, you <em>can</em> issue unit orders while paused. Indeed, it’s generally better to when you’re aiming special abilities that have a cooldown. Perhaps it's secretly a turn-based game, then? Here’s a trailer.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Grit and Valor - 1949: Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-0k5xkfcayw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Grit and Valor - 1949: Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-0k5xkfcayw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-0k5xkfcayw?autoplay=1" title="Grit and Valor - 1949: Announcement Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-0k5xkfcayw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
The plot here is that you’re fighting your way from Scotland to Berlin to detonate an EMP and silence those goose-stepping Gundamns for good. The campaign unfolds across a node-based map, with certain branches taking you to riskier, more rewarding or easier, less lucrative encounters. During each mission, you’ll need to keep your HQ truck alive while weighing the risks of going after optional objectives, like signal towers that take ages to capture, leaving your mechs exposed in the process. There are also paradropped supply crates that bestow a choice of power-ups, such as repairing this or that mech.
</p>
<p>
The maps are pleasingly cramped. Pleasingly for me, anyway. It feels like you’re presiding over a clash between rival antfarms. RTS fans may yearn for more elbow room. I do wonder if Grit &amp; Valor – 1949 is angling for commute-friendly snackability, which makes its lack of Steam Deck verification a bit concerning. Still, I enjoy the aesthetics here, and I could imagine the fundamentals supporting some denser tactical puzzles as the campaign wears on. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1911860/Grit_and_Valor__1949/">Read more on Steam</a>. It’s out… today!
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Now Lets You Post Beets In The Group Chat]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/playstation-5-update-emoji-activity-card-patch-notes-1851772443</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-now-lets-you-post-beets-in-the-group-chat.1145196/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/playstation-5-update-emoji-activity-card-patch-notes-1851772443<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="d42d18f0d3f41601ed93136fd2b9e751" data-recommend-id="image://d42d18f0d3f41601ed93136fd2b9e751" data-format="jpg" data-width="1632" data-height="918" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A beet appears on a PlayStation Portal. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A beet appears on a PlayStation Portal. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d42d18f0d3f41601ed93136fd2b9e751" data-recommend-id="image://d42d18f0d3f41601ed93136fd2b9e751" data-format="jpg" data-width="1632" data-height="918" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A beet appears on a PlayStation Portal. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>A new update for the PlayStation 5 has arrived and it has two major components. The first is refreshed activity cards that now display more info. The second is the introduction of new emoji, including root vegetables, aka beets.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,196230,197298" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Activity cards, which are neat but still flawed shortcuts meant to help players complete specific milestones in their respective games more easily, now display the full activity info, though spoilers will still be omitted. More importantly for me, a handful of new emoji introduced with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.emojipedia.org/whats-new-in-unicode-16-0/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.emojipedia.org/whats-new-in-unicode-16-0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Unicode 16.0</a></span> have been added to the PlayStation Network. </p><p>Those include Face with Bags Under Eyes, Leafless Tree, and Shovel, among others. A purple Splatter emoji looks like someone murked Grimace for failing to pay back a loan. But my favorite is the beautiful red beet which is sort of the lawful good alignment version of the peach butt emoji. I can’t wait to spam all of my PSN friends with it.</p><p>The PS4 also received a small update this week but it’s much less exciting. “We’ve improved the messages and usability on some screens,” it reads. It’s about time!</p><p>Here are the full patch notes for the PS5 update:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><h2 id="h137474"><a id=""></a><strong>PS5 </strong>Version: 25.02-11.00.00:</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>We’ve made it simpler to view details about activities. Activity details are now fully displayed on cards. Potential spoilers will still be hidden.</li><li>Unicode 16.0 emojis are now supported. You can use them in your messages.</li><li>When you set the parental controls’ restriction level to <strong>Late Teens or Older</strong>, <strong>Communication and User-Generated Content </strong>will now default to <strong>Restrict</strong>. If you have previously set the level to <strong>Late Teens or Older</strong>, your previous settings will not be affected and it will be shown as <strong>Customize</strong>.</li><li>We’ve improved system software performance and stability.</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>We’ve improved the messages and usability on some screens.</li></ul></blockquote><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>